now on to our first presentation
we've all seen the memes right about how
the cloud is just somebody else's
computer funny as it is it also points
to the very true fact that the cloud has
a surface attack area just like all
computers do
when it comes down
to it there's a plethora of challenges
both on the attack side and on the
offense side of things
i'd like to introduce you to christiane
corna who is a penetration tester and a
security researcher and he's here to
talk to us about all the aspects of
cloud security christian we're ready to
hear all about it
thank you thank you very much for the
introduction
uh i'm glad that you are all here today
um i hope that you had a good break
before we
because we'll touch a very tough subject
about cloud security
uh let me share my screen really quick
okay it is all right
um
so
will
speak about offensive and defensive
sides of cloud security
um i'm christian cornea of pentester
and my passion is to break into things
especially let's say hype technologies
such as cloud
and let's
let's begin
let's
see a brief introduction into cloud
security
uh
what is cloud uh many many people have
this uh
question
and i have a simple simple definition
for cloud
cloud is a collection of
of resources that can be accessed
within the internet
uh basically
ip addresses hosts
observers
everything that can
be accessed from the internet from your
pocket especially
within your mobile phone
and
that
you don't have
to connect physical to those resources
there are multiple cloud deployment
models
uh
one is private cloud which is basically
your infrastructure your cloud
deployed on premise and just you have
access to to this
then it's public cloud
which is offered by many vendors
nowadays such as amazon microsoft google
cloud and so on so so forth
um then we have hybrid which is a
combination of private and public cloud
um and let's
take a look at why people are moving
nowadays into the cloud
uh the first reason basically is
mobility
we
we can access the cloud uh from any
device
and from anywhere in the world
um
while we have an internet access then we
have scalability
we can scale our resources very fast
uh based on our needs and requirements
uh then we have uh risk transference
from
um
from a security point point of view
because
we we are not responsible anymore for
some parts some components of our
infrastructure
uh
this case applies when we are moving to
a public or hybrid cloud
when we have a private cloud there is no
risk transference
we are responsible uh entirely for for
our cloud
um
there is a big uh difference between
cloud versus on-premise basically cloud
is like ordering something from a
restaurant so it's already prepared
already done for you
and on premise it's like cooking
the meal yourself so you need
ingredients you need
dishes you need the skills to
um
to make that meal so
yeah that's that's basically an analogy
of cloud versus on-premise
and there there are multiple types of
cloud services
let's walk through some
common
uh types of cloud services we have
infrastructure as a service
such as
amazon ac2
uh
where
they
give us the
um
the servers
the virtualization
all the
the infrastructure
and we can scale that
then we have platform as a service
which is used mainly for
software development like heroku and we
have software as a service
for example slack which
are
basically
uh
all the applications and
uh software that we are using nowadays
uh
like zoom zoom is a software as a
service for example
okay we discussed a brief introduction
into those cloud services but we have
here security risk
risk related to each cloud's
service
we have
basically
different and various risks
for for each one because
each cloud
service
comes with um different responsibilities
for us
uh and different approaches different
features
uh different resources and so on so
forth so they are basically different
um in infrastructure as a service let's
take some common risks for
for this cloud
service
we
we have
some
misconfiguration at the the services
level so maybe we have wrongly
configured uh on file transfer on one of
our server that is deployed in our
infrastructure as a service
model
we have
probably exposed some critical protocols
like
remote desktop
access with anonymous or guest access
uh there are the risk of
uh
explo uh exploiting the
out of dated environment because in a
infrastructure as a service we also have
to to be very careful uh because
we have a much greater
responsibility than platform as a
service and software as a service we
have the infrastructure security
responsibility so we we must be uh
aware that
those are not managed
uh by our cloud service provider and we
manage the
the infrastructure layer
so we must
keep it
up to date
we we must keep operating systems up to
date in order to to prevent
exploitation of
known vulnerabilities that have been
found
on
older operating systems
then we have the risk of denial of
service or distributed denial of service
for network and transport layers because
we are also uh responsible for
the traffic management
uh in a platform as a service
uh the risks are not um
so
um
so higher than
infrastructure as a service because our
responsibility
uh
was
shorter
basically
there is um
a possibility of injection of bacters in
software that we develop through a
platform as a service
we have virtualization risks
um and
a very big issue with platform as a
service
is that there
are
uh
possibilities of exploiting
um
the
the missing access controls
so
some platforms as a service comes by
default with
unrestricted access controls so we must
define
a good
role and access
based metrics
so
we will give people
only the
the required permissions and privileges
that they are
in need to complete their everyday tasks
um
this is this is basically related to
principle of list privilege
um then we have software as a service
disk
which is basically as we described uh
previously
um
is
composed of
all the applications
not all but almost all the applications
we
we see every day um we must be
very careful
uh what code we put on on our software
as a service
model
we because because we we may
place there um some
vulnerable or misconfigured code
and that will permit attackers to
to just gain access to the underlying uh
infrastructure underlying layers
um
of of the model because we just
misconfigured
something or did not uh implement
best practices when it comes to
code development
so we have web-based
exploitation threads
so basically just be aware that um
developing secure applications in a
software as a service
uh model
is our responsibility
then we have also virtualization threads
like in platform as a service
and we have application layer denial of
service because in a software service as
a conclusion we are
responsible for the application layer
let's move to
a more interesting topic
let's see some
black box attacks on on the cloud so
unauthenticated attacks on on the cloud
uh but first let's define
uh the differences
penetration testing on cloud and
security audit on cloud
penetration testing on cloud is
basically the process uh
through which we apply our hackish
methodology
to
to find vulnerabilities on the actual
cloud deployment
and we go from an external
unauthenticated perspective
and we must see
how far
we we can go
when
a cloud security audit is basically um
meant to
to check some configurations
of the
cloud platform
for example
in microsoft azure we can do a cloud
security audit using uh cis benchmarks
and that's just the cloud security audit
uh it's basically done from an
authenticated
high privilege
level
up and we
just
check
buttons and we just check if best
practices are in place for for the cloud
deployment without actually
exploiting those or without actually
finding ways to
exploit those
so
how can we do a cloud security audit uh
it's very simple um
we can do it through cs benchmarks
uh
we can take a look at the csa
cloud controls metrics
which defines some
best practices for
developing a good and secure cloud
and we have some
automation
that can be very very very helpful
for for us uh we have tools and
resources
that can be found on on github or on
this link
um
okay
so let's move into
the most interesting part from from this
presentation uh we have black box cloud
fan testing
um and how can we do that
uh
most common
cloud pen testing
methodologies are and also
let's say bug monthly methodologies on
the cloud
are the following basically we can
enumerate public cloud storage
uh such as amazon s3 buckets google
buckets
of azure blobs
we can use google doors for that one and
we'll
uh have a slide where we'll present how
to to do that with google docs and we'll
actually do that
um and very very important we we have to
search uh
github
repositories and
the internet for
for cloud
secrets leaks uh you can you can do that
with this tool
ethics
um then we have password spraying on
cloud accounts
and of course uh
phishing for admin console access so we
fish users to to get access to their
admin
uh
console um and also we have a method
even if you say okay
how can we fish admin uh accounts for
their access if they have mfa in place
uh it is a very very simple way to do
that we have a specialized tool to do
that to to get also the access token
into the cloud uh admin console even if
the accounts are using mfa and we'll
look at that
a bit later
okay so uh
we
uh we talked about uh
the phishing
on
on cloud accounts to
to get admin access to the cloud console
uh and here we have evil jinx tool
which is a tool
that uh help us
to to do fishing
uh and even to bypass mfa to get access
uh the concept is very simple it will
instead of capturing uh the
credentials it will capture access
tokens so the session tokens of the
users
and we can just copy paste the session
token into our browser and
having all the access we we need for
for the admin console
and how we can do that firstly uh cloud
based
phishing is very simple uh because we
have a lot of domains to choose for
in this example i
took for example three domains that i
found that online that are available for
purchase are very very good um
domains that we can do in our phishing
uh assessments for cloud credentials
um
and then we can just use averagings to
uh to
get
credentials and to get the session
tokens and to bypass the multi-factor
authentication
okay um so
then we have another attack vector very
very
uh interesting which is cloud-based
subdomain stakeholder
basically uh on cloud we have multiple
services okay we we have for example uh
azure traffic manager
which
allows us to
basically make redirects view
logs of the traffic uh do bloat
balancing so so forth uh
we have the storage buckets for amazon
we have the cloud from cdn and we have
some
azure default web domains that is
related to
the azure web development part um
here for some domains takeover
it happens that
our
our targets
uh
have seen name records
pointing
actually to those services
um
without having them
uh
registered so
okay maybe a cname
uh record was left
uh
there
and
we uh
we don't have it uh
anymore
so
so uh yes let's
let's start with with the demo
um
we
will have a domain a subdomain tool to
target to see if it can execute the
takeover over this one
so
let's
see the cname records
for our target um subdomain which is
demo dot dev camp
demo dot online
yes so we have here um
the the subdomain with the cname record
that is point pointing to the traffic
manager endpoint
um
and we can define this traffic manager
endpoint into our azure console
um
to
to take over this sub domain and to make
redirects to any domain we want to
um we can even create a server and make
the redirect there so we'll have
almost
complete control but firstly we must
validate if this traffic manager uh
endpoint is taken or not taken let's
let's check okay i'll copy it here is
the
the azure
console we will go to traffic manager
just a bit okay
it is loading
good so no profiles defined we'll go
track manager and create
wait a bit
come on
okay
and here we'll input our
uh end point
and as you can see uh the traffic
manager endpoint is actually uh
available
the routing method would be performance
this is our subscription
and
we have already created a resource group
and we'll do create
we wait for
for our traffic manager profile to be to
be created
okay it's deployment in progress
with also a little bit for for it to be
successfully deployed and here we are
we go to the
resources and
here is our traffic manager
uh
console we go to settings
uh enterpoints
and click on add new endpoint
and if we have one endpoint defined in
azure okay but in this case we don't
have an endpoint already defined in
azure so we have the possibility to
redirect to an external endpoint we'll
put something like test okay and for
example we want to redirect to
google.com
uh location
no important and odd
we we wait a little bit let's see
where
it is our
here
and we
navigate to the
domain
it is loading
and here we
are actually on the on
the google page it's it's doing
a redirection on on google page as you
can we have successfully take over this
domain through traffic
manager service but also
let me
go back to the presentation uh but also
we have multiple services um just have
to to research a bit uh yes this is the
previous slide
uh
there were multiple cases in which
attackers were able to take over
subdomains through storage buckets and
points through wanna do right now in
order to wrap up the uh demo that
christian performed earlier is to ask
him
for one key takeaway that all cloud app
developers should adhere to
thank you thank you so uh
firstly uh you should take uh
basically questions uh for data storage
um approaches on cloud and
accounts you should have multi-factor
authentication