- Hello and welcome to
Breaking Bad, Passwords.
If you're joining us
live, our speakers are in
the slider discussion answering
your questions right now.
For audio or video issues,
click the technical support button below.
I know like to turn it over
to Hamed Merati and William
Mouton for the presentation.
- Hi, welcome everybody
joining our little presentation
on passwords.
My name is William Mouton.
I'm the Head of Research at
a company called Sense of Security.
We're part of the CyberCX
group in Australia.
My colleague Hamed Merati is also
a senior security consultant
at Sense of Security.
At this point, I would
just like to say thank you
for listening to yet
another talk on passwords.
Passwords have been around
since the dawn of computers.
It's been discussed, well
discussed, complained about
and this talk is not
gonna be about the merits
of whether passwords is
still relevant or secure
or anything like that.
Today, we just wanna discuss our findings
and data that we've analyzed
during the course of
the assessments that we do.
At Sense of Security we do quite
a number of different types
of security assessments, and
we would like to take you guys
through what we've seen over
the last couple of years,
and how we can use that
to hopefully improve
the general state of
passwords in the industry.
Passwords are still
basically the de facto means
of authentication.
It's used everywhere from
small online retailers
to some of the biggest
corporates in the world.
And generally, relies on user generated
or choosing values.
And the funny thing is, in today's world,
the average user has more credentials
than ever before in history.
So like I said, we do different types
of security assessments and
we usually play the role
of the attacker, and
we take full advantage
of the fact that there are
general weaknesses within
the whole concept of passwords.
So, at this point, like I said,
passwords have been around a long time,
it's been discussed over
and over and over again,
over the last 20 to 30 years.
There's been various pieces
of advice given out over
the years from length, complexity.
I like to typically use this
little XKCD image that kind
of explains where we are today in terms
of generating random complex passwords.
But the thing is, it's
not really worked out
the way we wanted it to work out.
Breaches still happen every day.
Password-based breaches
are probably one of
the most common types of
breaches that happen over
and over and over again.
And that's why we decided
to take a little bit
of a look, not just at
the passwords themselves,
the common passwords things like that,
but also password policies,
what do corporates put in
place to try and remedy this?
And where do they stand and the data kind
of surprised us a little bit because,
we had some preconceived conceptions
of what it should look like.
Because typically, we tend
to look at assessments
on a session by session basis.
But what we've done is, for
the purpose of this talk,
we've taken the last
three years worth of data
that we've collected via various
types of penetration tests,
from our red teams, network
pentests, web applications,
every way that we could actually go in
and get access to large
sets of password data.
Typically, those would be in the form
of a compromised Microsoft
Active Directory,
because that's the most common
piece of technology used,
across large corporates, and we set out,
Our initial goal was just to look at,
what do passwords look like.
But we quickly realized that it goes far
beyond just the passwords.
There's a lot of user behavior.
And we started looking at
how does corporate password
policies drive user behavior?
And what influence that
has, whether a strong
or weak password policy
actually have an impact
on the behavior of users when
choosing different passwords.
So at this point, Hamed is
going to take you guys through
a little bit of the password policies.
- Yes, so within our industry,
we have four different
major industry guidelines,
the guidelines and standards.
So NIST, CIS benchmark and
Australian Cybersecurity Center
Information Security Manual or ACSCISM,
which is a Australian
government benchmark and PCI DSS
So when we were going through our data
and we start analysis of the data,
we saw that most of the organization
because they using
Windows Active Directory,
so most of the organization
are using the windows
recommendation and values
as their recommendation.
So that's why we included
Microsoft in our analysis as well.
So just a quick walkthrough
over the different terms
of the password policy.
So we have things like
minimum password length,
which is the minimum
number of characters that
when you choose a password,
you have to comply with that.
If it's eight minimum characters,
so your password should
be at least minimum eight characters.
So the complexity it means
that whether you are allowed
to only have numbers in your passwords,
or is just lowercase, uppercase.
So if the complexity is enabled you have
to have a uppercase lowercase
or a numeric in your password.
The next parameter is
the password history.
So basically what it means is the number
of previous passwords
that the user has used,
so they cannot use.
For instance, if it's 24,
the value of the password history is 24,
the users cannot select
or choose the last,
the previous 20 passwords
of their own, and they have
to come up with a new one.
The next one is the maximum age
or the password expiry in days.
So for instance, if the
password policy has 90 days
of the maximum age or the password expiry,
it means that each three
months or after 90 days,
the users have to change the
password so they get a pop up,
which says that your password
is expired and you have
to change your password.
And the next two parameters
are lockout threshold
and lockout duration.
So lockout threshold means
that after so many or
these many failed attempts, your account
or the user account get locked.
So if it's 10, so you have
only 10 failed attempts.
So after that your account is locked
and the duration means for how long or
for how long your password
or your account is locked.
So if it's 15 minutes
of the lockout duration,
it means that once your account is locked,
you cannot try for the next 15 minutes.
So you have to wait for 15 minutes
and then you can have the next chart.
So the Microsoft what they recommend
for the minimum password then is to have
a eight character password,
complexity is enabled,
the password history is 24,
the maximum page or the expiry
is 42 days, which is a
week more than a month
so it's five weeks, and the
lockout threshold is 10 attempts
and the lockout duration
is if I'm not mistaken,
is 15 minutes.
For the NIST, they don't
really set any restrictions
and what they recommend is to have
a minimum password minimum password length
of eight characters
And there are different
parameters involved here.
Like, they don't say you have
to have the complexity enabled
or disabled, and they don't
force, or they recommend not
to force the users to
expire the password every
like one months, two
months or three months.
So what they recommend is
as long as your password
is not compromised,
and it's a strong password,
you are good to use that
password for as long as you can.
And the next one CIS, which has
the highest minimum password
character length which is 14,
and ISM and PCI DSS.
So we use this as our guidelines
where we started our
analysis and what we saw was,
so this is the password policy.
So what we saw was 41%
of the organization,
they have a minimum eight characters as
the minimum password length, followed by
the seven characters.
So altogether about 63%
of the organization,
they have the bare minimum
of the password length.
So it means that if you
set a default and not
a good password policy,
most of the organization,
they don't bother to
increase that minimum.
And most of the users as we see
in the next few slides,
they just follow the bare minimum.
So it's very important to
have a very good baseline
because most of the organization
and the user they don't
change that behavior.
And based on our data,
the average minimum factor
for the passport across the
different organization is 8.1,
which is again to the minimum recommended.
And what was very
interesting was that 43% of
the organization, they are
aligned with Microsoft and NIST,
and 22% aligned with
PCI DSS and Microsoft,
followed by ASM and
interestingly, only 1% are aligned
with CIS which has the most
lengthy password length.
And for the password history,
46% of the organization
they have the 24 password
as the password history
and 46% of the organization
they are aligned with Microsoft
and CIS benchmark, 29% with
ICM and 8% with PCI DSS
and the rest but they
have different values.
And in terms of the lockout duration,
almost half of the organization they have
a minimum 30 minutes lockout duration.
So it means that if
your account is locked,
you have 30 minutes to
wait and then you can try
and attempt more.
So what is really interesting in this case
is if you have a short lockout duration,
it gives a good opportunity
for the attackers
to perform the brute force
or password guess much more faster,
so they don't need to wait for two hours,
three hours or whatever the
duration is to try and attack.
So they have shorter windows,
so they can attack faster.
And 61% of the organization,
they align with PCI DSS,
60% with CIS and the rest
they have different values.
And same with thresholds
as I mentioned earlier
that threshold is the
number of failed attempts
and 60% of the organization we see
they have five failed attempts
and 24% or almost a quarter
of the organization,
they have zero as the value.
So zero means that there is no lockout,
So and it means that the
attacker, or we as a tester,
we have unlimited number of times to try
and get a password or to attempt to crack,
to brute force the password.
And 36% of the organization
they're aligned with ISM,
only 13% align with Microsoft
and CIS 9%, with PCI DSS
the standard and 42% they have different,
or it could be unlimited.
And password complexity
is very straightforward.
80% of the organization they do have
a password complexity set.
So the users need to have a complexity
in their passwords, like
password one with capital P
and numbers at the end.
And in terms of the password expiry,
so 34% they have a 90
days which is three months
so after three months
the password gets expired
and followed by 60 days or two months
with 16% of the organization
they enforced two months
and 14% of the organization
they have a five weeks
or a bit more than one month
of the password expiry.
And 35% of the organization
they are aligned
with ICM, PCI DSS, 15%
are aligned with CIS,
14% aligned with Microsoft and the rest
they have different password
expiry requirements.
So, our clients, they are
in different organizations
or different sectors.
So we have clients in
government, technology,
insurance, healthcare.
And these are the average values
that we see across our data set.
I'll pass to William to
go through this with you.
- Yeah, so what's
interesting about this is,
like I said, at the
beginning of the slides,
we had some preconceived ideas about
who would be doing it better,
or what we expected to see.
Typically out of experience,
and this is not taking
a swipe at governments,
but government organizations
tend to lack a little bit.
So we figured government
institutions would probably be
at the lower end.
Technology companies are
typically seen as at the forefront
of doing cutting edge stuff.
So, and the user base
is also supposed to be
a bit more tech savvy
than the average user.
So, my expectations was when
we started looking at the data
that government would be at the lower end
and technology companies
would be would be far ahead.
Banking and financial, a
lot of them are covered
by PCI DSS, so they have to align with it,
but I would have expected to
see much stronger policies
in that scene, in that area.
What we ended up seeing was that on the
on the balance of the whole,
pretty much everybody just
when it came to length,
on average, people just
stuck to the default
so that all the Microsoft recommendations
or the bare minimum that
is prescribed to them.
Which is, again after
talking about password
and password security and
the concept of complex
and long passwords and
passwords versus passphrases,
this is surprising to see that
at an organizational level,
it hasn't really changed and
it's still being done either
by default or the bare minimum
that people are required to do.
And all of that stuff is
great and all of these numbers
all makes for great
pie charts but if I had
to put my bad guy hats on,
like I said, we do this
for a living, when we see
password policies like this,
I mean a couple of things
spring to mind for us.
I mean, if we see password
policies with eight
to nine character length, minimum length,
we immediately know that,
there's going to be some
short easy guessable passwords
that we're gonna find.
And again, we do this with
such regularity that we know
once we get in, we're probably
gonna progress through
the rest, we can compromise the rest.
And once an attacker has
actually moved into your network
and getting some form of privilege,
getting access to the rest of
your organizational passwords
are typically easy.
And with short length in
force, it makes cracking
and recovering those
password pretty trivial,
but we'll see that in a couple of slides.
Another thing to considering
is high lockout thresholds.
This aides us if we wanna
perform password spraying
or password brute forcing attacks,
not being locked out greatly
improves the efficiency
of which we can perform those attacks.
On the other side, long lockout timeouts,
has a detrimental effect on companies.
So we can pretty much perform
a denial of service attack
against users by just
locking up their accounts
and having them stay locked
out for an extended period.
Also, one of the components
of the password policies
is the password histories.
So if there's a short history
or not a history enforced,
it creates the ability for users
to start recycling passwords,
alternating between numbers,
letters or just using
one or two base passwords
and just keep on cycling through them.
So overall, it does create,
if your password policy
is not optimal for your organization,
it does create quite
a few gaps with which,
can give attackers the
advantage when trying
to breach the network.
So, password policies typically,
we don't really see a lot of
people talking about them,
because they're pretty
boring and like I said,
I mean, I think people believe
that we understand them
well enough and that it's
a well understood problem.
But, like having the policy
defined is all well and good,
but in the next couple of
slides, we're gonna actually look
at passwords that's conforming
to those password policies
that we've just analyzed.
And the big problem is that
users are typically not educated
and when I say not educated,
I know that we spend
a lot of time with an organization's doing
user awareness training
and putting out flyers
and things like that, but I sort of refer
to this as the mom test.
If I look at my mom's password, after,
she's gone through everything at her work
and educational training,
and I still look at what
she sets her passwords,
and she handles her passwords,
that's kind of indicative
to what the normal non-technical user
on the network would be.
And if my mom is failing at this,
I'm pretty sure a lot
of other people inside
of your organization are still failing,
you know gonna be failing at this.
MFA comes up a lot in conversations,
and we're gonna also touch on
that in a bit and at the end.
MFA is great, but it's not
gonna cover you, for everything.
There's a lot of misconfigurations
that can happen around that.
And then the last one is weak passwords.
that they're still being
allowed by the password policies
that are being defined.
- Yeah, so during our engagements one
of the primary goals
or one of our goals is
to compromise the domain controllers
in a Windows environment or
take over the Active Directory.
And when we do that we
dump a file which is empty,
technical way its empty the a file.
Basically it's a database of
the Active Directory containing
all the information about the
username in Active Directory,
including the password hash, the history
and the membership and everything.
So, when we obtain that
during our engagement,
we try to crack the hashes or
to obtain the clear text passwords.
And these data that we analyzed are based
on the actual crack password that we did.
And what we use for to just
give you an idea of this
is not a difficult task or difficult job.
So in terms of the cracking,
so what we use for cracking the hashes
are its normal PC with four
GPUs and normally because
of the time constraint that we
have during our engagements,
we usually spend between two
three, maximum five hours
in cracking the password.
So we don't spend that much
time because we don't have
that long time during
our typical engagements.
So what we see in our data
is that almost half of the
passwords that we crack,
they are following the eight characters.
So they are eight characters
in terms of the password length
and this is in line with what we saw
in the password policies.
So again, this shows us that if you have
a weak password policy, and
if you set the bare minimum
for the users, the minimum for the user,
they just follow the bare
minimum so they don't increase
that bar that much often.
And almost 60% are, as we
will see in the future slides,
in the next few slides, almost
62% or 65% of the passwords,
they are in the eight to nine characters.
And in terms of the password,
as the password is a more
lengthy like in terms
of the length, it is less
crackable, less guessable,
because one of the things that we do
on daily basis in our engagement is we try
to guess the password to get in or to get
the initial foothold in the network.
So if you have a longer passwords,
it's more difficult to crack.
And in terms of the character
sets, 42% of the password
they have a mixed alphanumeric
means lowercase uppercase,
and a number like password
one with capital P,
and followed by lowercase alphanumeric
like password1 for all
characters in lower.
And the question is does size
of the length really matters?
And the answer is yes.
So almost 60% of the passwords that we see
where the users are using,
they fall on the eight
to nine characters of the
length and it's about 73
of the passwords from
seven to nine characters
which covers the bare minimum
of the standards which we see
in PCI DSS, Microsoft and NIST.
So again, this is another proof
that if you have a minimum requirements,
most of the 72% of the users,
they just follow the bare minimum.
So it's very important to have
a strong password policies.
And so if you Google for
things like weak passwords,
common passwords, so
what you can see in all
of those search results,
all the research shows that
you will see welcome one, password one,
or one Welcome12345678.
But what was very interesting in our case,
or in our research was that we see lots
of patterns based on the company name.
So we see things like if
the company name is ABC,
for instance, is ABC123
ABC@ the current year which
is 2020 or @2019.
And these are the four top passwords
that we see in our industry.
So it's a very good
indicative for an attacker
and as a tester point of view.
So if we want to try or
we want to get a password
during our engagement, so this
is typically what we go for
like we take the company
name, we add the current year,
at sign the current
year, and in most cases,
we will get a hit, or
with things like Welcome1
or Password1, so most of our
engagements we see at least one
of these weak credentials.
And the top 10 base words that
we see are welcome, password,
the current season or the
current week of the day,
so again, this is very useful
for attacker and the tester.
And in terms of the
permutation of the passwords,
so for almost 44% of the
passwords that we see,
the format follows the first
capital and the last number
like Password1 and 21% of the passwords,
they have two digits at the end and 60%
of the passwords they have
a single digits at the end.
And the statistics or the data shows
that the last four digits of the password,
they following a trend,
which is, for instance,
the current year.
- Okay, so now that we've
spent some time on this,
and we've looked at the
numbers and the passwords.
And again, I don't suspect that
a lot of this stuff is new,
I think this ground has
been covered, quite a bit,
but the reality is, we still
see this on a daily basis.
So, what can we do with this?
Some common blind spots that people have
when setting password
policies or deciding on how
to implement password controls,
they tend to focus on
the defaults as provided.
Again, like we've seen
Microsoft probably has
the biggest influence on password policies
in corporate environments, but just
because they provide Active
Directory infrastructure.
But common things that
you need to look out for
when managing your passwords
in your organization
is making sure that you don't
allow users to set passwords
that's contained in previous breaches,
blacklist dictionary words,
trying to discourage repetitive sequences.
And also the biggest
thing that we can say is,
context-specific words
like your organization,
every company does, and I
know this from experience
that there's a company specific password
in every single organization, right?
That is a very, very bad idea,
because those tend to leak out.
And, based on the
analysis that we've seen,
it's typically very
easy for us to get that.
Like I mentioned before MFA is,
in some of the previous
slides, is a fantastic control,
and it's very effective.
The problem is that MFA it
does have some drawbacks.
They are some weaker
implementations of MFA,
but the biggest problem with MFA
is it's not consistently
applied across all interfaces.
You typically find it on very selective,
with people in critical
interfaces on the perimeter,
like your office 365 or your mail exchange
or things like that.
But a lot of other authentication
points on the perimeter
that still do tie in with,
is not necessarily covered by the MFA.
A typical example would
be PowerShell for exchange
or legacy entry points
into your mail system.
Where the web UI does enforce MFA,
those entry points, typically,
we find that the MFA
is not been enabled on them, right?
So, going forward, this is
just some practical advice.
Now, again, a lot of this
is not earth shattering,
but just please keep that in mind.
From a human factor,
ongoing user education and like I said,
I do know that we do spend a lot of time
with our corporate training
and things like that,
but maybe users need to be made more aware
of the actual consequences,
of how breaches occur,
how frequently they occur
and what the consequences
to the organization as well as
their own privacy is, right?
Encourage them not to
use corporate credentials
on public websites.
We see this every day.
We look at public breaches,
which are from random gaming
sites or social media sites.
And instead of us looking
for corporate domains,
we just look for corporate names based
on the password patterns that we see
and you can actually identify
private email addresses
using corporately
associated passwords, okay?
So there's a lot of information
that can be gained on that.
Monitor and inform, you
can also aid your users
in actually monitoring their own accounts,
their private accounts,
to have them notified when
they pop up in a breach list.
Password manager is a
great software and it's
a great recommendation.
But encourage users to use
it in their private lives,
not just for the corporate lives.
Strong password policies,
like we said length
over complexity.
The longer the password,
the more difficult it is
to crack but also, using
less complicated passwords
makes it easier to
remember like for humans,
not necessarily machines, right?
And the thing is, if you
get it right, if you have,
long passwords that are well monitored,
you probably don't need to
expire them that often right?
And that takes away the repetitive nature
of people creating passwords that repeat.
Have MFA everywhere, like I
said, people tend to put it,
leave it where it's
necessary, but you really need
to put it everywhere.
Also on eternal I mean,
having it as a step up,
type of authentication method,
when performing sensitive
operations on the inside
is really a must in today's world.
Also practical, no defaults
or weak passwords like I said,
having company specific
passwords is a big no, no,
because they do leak, it's easy to guess.
and we find them literally everywhere.
And lastly, don't forget that
machines have feelings too.
Service accounts, machine
accounts, devices that you plug
into the network, those
typically do get forgotten along
the way, because they're
not people, right?
You can't educate them
and they rely on people
to set and maintain those passwords.
You need to make sure that
whenever you type anything
that's a machine related
account or device unit make sure
that those password policies,
your policies are treated
the same way as normal human does.
Regular identity audits,
make sure that you've got
that you don't have any
passwords in your network.
Make sure that you weed
out dormant accounts,
monitor for failed
logins, suspicious logins
and even logins from
geographical regions for users
are not supposed to be.
Some of the quickest things
that you can do this week
is just to quickly check your
organization to make sure
that there's no passwords
contained in current breaches.
In the next three months, just
take a look at your policies,
redefine your current password policy,
make sure that it is not just default.
Re look your MFA implementations, right?
Make sure that you've got
strong authentication everywhere
where it matters and then
continue to user education
and implement regular
identity audit as sort
of like BAU your business,
every six months do it.
Yeah, that's it for us.
This is me and Hamed,
I hope you guys enjoyed the presentation.
And yeah, thank you.