- [upbeat music] [Instructor]
Think you're special?
one of the kind? we agree.
The way you pursue your digital
ambitions is unique to you.
It's so as your appetite for digital risk.
Whether you're hyper
connecting your ecosystem,
empowering a distributed workforce,
rapidly leveraging cloud, IoT,
AI or other new technologies,
RSA is here to help you
manage digital risk your way
at every stage of your journey.
So go ahead, be you.
- [Instructor] Hello and welcome
to building cybersecurity
as a shared service.
If you're joining us live,
our speaker is in the
slideshow chat discussion,
answering your questions right now.
For audio video issues,
click the technical support button below.
I'd like to now turn it over
to Erwin Eimers for the presentation.
- Thank you.
My Name Is Erwin Eimers.
I'm the General Manager,
for the Regional Headquarters
in Americas Sumitomo Chemical,
and I basically fulfill two roles
besides heading up the
Regional Headquarters IT,
in the Americas for design
and implement regional shared services
for group companies in the Americas.
I'm also a member of
Sumitomo Global IT committee
called the Global one team.
And there I helped develop
Global IT Standards and Services
and a Global IT
and Cyber Security roadmap
for Sumitomo Chemical.
Sumitomo chemical is a
group of separate companies
in five different sectors
with almost 33,000 employees.
The five sectors we operate in
is the Petrochemical and Plastics,
Energy and Functional Materials,
IT-related Chemicals,
Health and Crop Sciences
and Pharmaceuticals.
There's a long history of
the local group companies
to have independence and freedom.
The reason is they're
vastly different in size
and operating model and HPC
from the sector they operate in.
The Sumitomo Chemical board has decided
that Digital Innovation
is a "material issue" across all sectors
to create value in the future.
And as part of the Digital
Innovation Program,
everybody agreed that
more common platforms
need to be available and rolled out
throughout all the
Sumitomo Group Companies.
Now if you look at structure
of Sumitomo Chemical,
including the Americas region,
obviously we have resources
You see the five sectors on the right.
They each have a Global sector head,
and each of the group companies
has a president that
report to that sector head.
Besides those sectors,
there's also Corporate Planning and IT,
which has a Global head and gets ready,
the Americas Regional Headquarters.
There is also Legal and
Compliance Global Function
that the Americas Regional Legal
and Compliance reports to.
There's obviously more
corporate functions,
but these are the ones
that are in scope for this discussion.
So this is kind of the
situational overview.
There is definitely an increase
in Cyber Security threats,
and this has been acknowledged
by top management,
but also by the group Company.
We didn't do global IT training,
we agreed that the global
standards need to be established
or improved and forced to enforce the CIA.
There is definitely a communication
gap between the Company's,
the Regional Headquarters,
and then the Headquarters
within the sector
as well as between the
corporate functions.
We also need to get acknowledgement
from the group Companies.
Cyber Security issues
that we're going to discuss
this hasn't really been an issue because
every single group Company in our region
has had an issue with Cyber Security,
Some kind of social engineering event
that has made them acknowledge
that this is something
that needs to be addressed.
Now the Autonomy of each
of the group companies
is very important,
because of the very different
sectors they operate in
and different type of
business model products
and customers they have.
We have for instance, manufacturing
and sales of chemical and
organic crop protection
and enhancement products.
We have soil health, public
health, forest health.
We even have manufacturing
plants where we develop
and manufacture automotive products,
car interiors, doors and trims, etc.
We make epitaxial wafers,
resorcinols that goes in tires,
wood adhesive, dyes,
super engineered plastics
with in-flight aerospace product,
Pyrethrum-based pest control products,
that are derived from plant.
So very different business point.
So, what we need is more common systems,
less Cyber Security incidents.
Tricks are we have, a limited IT resource
at the group company level,
because they have traditionally
smaller size companies
that operate under the
Sumitomo Chemical name.
So that means they have the same plan
as the large size company,
but the infrastructure of a
small company in some cases,
it's just the production
plant with 25-30 people
working on it
and IT is a handful of people.
We have some existing
regional services available.
They have traditionally
not been very successful,
the Global as well as
the Regional structure.
There's no less or no
Cyber Security skills
at the group company level.
And as I mentioned before,
the communication between the three layers
is not offload
the buy in from the group
companies for Global Services
it's not very good, just
the group company presidents
have been hesitant to buy in on those
because there's time
different, we keep a hand of it
and sometimes language barrier.
There is a lack of
understanding from corporate IT
about the group companies
business model or industry
and of course, the frequent upgrading.
So hopefully this gives you a
little bit of an introduction
and I'd like to talk about, the journey.
So with this task at hand,
I had to come up with an action plan
and the action plan for me was..
Let's look at the existing
services Globally and locally
and the lessons learned.
Let's really analyze the gaps
and confirm needs on group company level
that's developing the
security improvement plan
because the real focus is Cyber Security.
Lets make sure we get buy-ins
and acceptance and support
from Sumitomo Chemical group level
in a sloutly found in the
different group companies.
But the lessons learnt for me
were issues with the chief services
mainly because they were
infrastructure hosting services,
In privately owned Sumitomo data center,
so they were inflexible.
They weren't really cost-effective
for the smaller group companies.
(coughs)
Plus as I mentioned before,
the outsourcing model
was not really very popular
model by the group companies.
Because it is a..
To be honest, since the focus
really changed on security
and building out common systems,
the existing purpose is
worth addressing debt
and especially for the
group company presidents
CEO fraud whaling was
becoming very apparent
that everybody had some issues with it.
So, the Gap Analysis,
what was interesting if
we look at the existing
services and hosting, etc.
It was really focused on availability,
not much on confidentiality
and integrity at all,
and I believe that's where the
majority of the issues are.
Social engineering again, is not the best.
Deal to get was that so far
10 services either Globally
or Regionally were rolled out.
We're kind of enforced
and that does not create the buy-in.
So we...
We developed the plan,
which really had a need
to improve the Cyber
Security issues to come.
In order to make this
plan to become successful,
it needs to get buy-in
from group companies
as well as Headquarter level,
and therefore it needs to solve problems
for headquarters as well
as for the group company.
what we needed to do was get that buy-in
and so from Sumitomo
Chemical corporate level,
or Global level,
the way to get the buy-in
was tying in whatever regional solutions
we were presenting into
the Global IT roadmap,
creating a three tier responsibility model
where the group company
and regional Headquarters
as well as corporate,
IT had a responsibility.
In this way, everybody's involved,
it's not the outsourcing model
as much for the group company
and also it leaves the operational aspect
at group company level.
That must really be the goal
behind the actual model.
How do we get the buy-in
from the group companies?
For me it was to operate at regional level
not at Global level to create a committee
with the IT leads of
all the group companies
as well as with the president
and federal worker groups with them,
really understanding and
agree what their needs are,
and sometimes also pointing them out,
understand the culture
and coming up with solutions
that will fix the issues
in a way that they don't
feel the freedom to operate
and in a way that they're in control
and that was really by
creating transparency
on solution planning
and future roadmapping.
If we do the approach,
and we have responsibility
at all three levels,
and help with training and
standards to help them,
on expanding wide open.
Of course, the communicate,
communicate, communicate.
Now, what we did really was,
we implemented the Global multi-tenant,
Microsoft365 requirements,
which pretty created me
to be a much more improved
collaboration and information
sharing environment
between the group
Company and Headquarters,
which waited 10 before and it didn't work
because it was fully rolled out
and at least the proposal
was to be fully rolled out
and fully supported and managed perhaps.
In this case, we said
let's implement it jointly
between Headquarters,
Regional headquarters,
group Company IT attendive
and will talk this together
and will come up with
the rules of engagement,
and an escalation path
and also support availability
from Regional Headquarters
which is within their Americas region,
but there was no time different.
Our business hours or
their business hours,
which also fixed an issue for Headquarter.
We implemented a global MSS solution.
It's basically a SIEM service
as a managed service
and as a portal for group Company
as well as Regional Headquarters.
Hopefully that was in the
view of Cyber Security effect.
So we created the responsibility
for the group company
to act on any alerts or incidents,
that they have the
responsibility to report it
and to mediate incidents.
We have the responsibility
as Regional Headquarters
to assist them with it
and ultimately report it
up to the sector head.
We also created for certain companies
who felt the need for it,
to have some remediation services
and forensic services by a third party.
Headquarters really
had just the oversight,
they were receiving the alerts,
they can go into the portal
and they can just carry
out the oversite functions
to make sure that everything...
On a regional level we created
Cyber Security standards
for web facing, internet
facing and websites,
we eventually met the
Global Standard of all
web facing and internet-facing
system or changed standards.
We at regional level will make sure
those standards that are been followed
and we are now even working
on providing pen testing services
if each group company to get insight.
We created regionalized contents
for cyber Security Awareness training
and Phishing campaigns.
So, that is a service
that we do not have course
provided for the group company.
The results of the phishing
campaigns get shared
only with that group company.
Between the group companies
only aggregated for job
will be champions for the Headquarters.
You're gonna leave it
at the group company.
To get details, we just
provide the service.
And this was much more
acceptable for group company
than the way it was done before.
What we're working on now
is to come up with a global standard,
if you will, for endpoint
detection and remediation,
and probably combination of the two
and a service from a third party.
To have an equally designed
Endpoint Protection and remediate.
Because these are services
that group Companies,
can afford to do by themselves,
or even sometimes support the tool..
Most of the implemented tool
they might not have the
people to really operate it.
We already talked about it a little bit
but how we implemented those two
to get the buy-in from the group companies
and three formulas.
As I said the common systems
there was Symantec MSS,
and that has now become
an ADM, Accenture service.
Microsoft365, we implemented
those completely jointly
within Headquarters..
Since these solved an issue on
multiple levels headquarters,
has been covering all
the implementation costs.
They have global pricing agreements
with Accenture and
Microsoft on the product.
So we do it best to charge
and so the group
companies leverage those..
those global pricing,
agreements which is
something they could not do,
Headquarters provides the
regular Microsoft365 support
but in case there is a need for emergency
support then regional headquarters...
So all services, their headquarters
or regional headquarters
is providing from a resource perspective,
those are all covered by the headquarters
if there's third party
costing for license perform,
then those will be passed on to me.
So one example I'd like to show is MSS.
So this is the symantec managed...
Two items implemented is
On the left you see the
group company environments.
They all tend to log to
America's local action point
which is managed by the
regional headquarters
we help implementing that.
The demand service is doing
all the threat aggregation
and consolidation and analysis.
And then sends alerts back in a portal
as well as through
email and text messages,
(coughs)
based on the severity level,
they go through company
the regional headquarters.
In this case, you see
there is the responsibility
on all three levels.
There is operationally no responsibility
or no involvement from group company
or regional headquarters,
and in this case,
we leave the corporate function
to no oversight function.
Regional Headquarters is
really operating in between
and the group companies
still stays operationally responsible,
but can get our assistance.
Regional Incident Response
Plan and pen testing
is something we're working on now.
So this is huge.
And what we're doing here
is we created with the Regional Legal
and compliance office.
An incident response
plan that we implement
at one group company first,
then we do a tabletop exercise
and then we roll it up to
the next group comprehend
each time we do a tabletop exercise,
we complete improvements.
Then will be implement
in all the incident response plans
for each tabletop exercise
to improve the incident response plan
for all the group companies.
This is another step..
So, in summary,
and by the way, if
there are any questions,
please reach out to me
on slider.. available.
So, as a summary, I would say,
given the current needs,
the direction from the board
and the available resources
at the group company level
get services really Were the right answer
to successfully address issues and needs
and wanted at some
level, and individually,
companies wouldn't have
been able to resolve it.
To roll it out as a Global
service from Headquarters
would not have been
would not have traded right.
The lessons learned are very important
to figure out what did not work..so far.
Analyze the gift to need some local level
was really important
because it really make sure we
focus on on the right things
and it also shows that
we're really interested
in your gifts and meet and
love the corporate planet.
The plans have to be prioritized
and effectively list realistic.
Sometimes, large companies like ours,
create a big plan,
create big project teams
and just roll it out all over the globe,
and in this case, we would never
have the direct engagement.
So we have to do with realistic steps
that are the right size
for what we have.
And there has to be that tie
in the spine on both levels.
The solutions need to tie
to the global IT roadmap,
and I'm also part of the global team
either put inside this...
and then of course, the
communication function.
A lot of times the Regional Headquarters
that we created this truly a function
that communicates up and down
to keep that information
flowing from group Companies up
and from Headquarters up.
There was a real need for
improvement in security,
there was effect.
Outsourcing was just not
the right fit in our culture
where it doesn't fit,
freedom or cooperate.
Some common systems and
standards when needed
and also accepted, nobody
disagreeing with it.
And training and testing,
just to provide training and testing
and get the results is good
when a company creates a lot of
value and also accountability
back to the group company.
And then the multi-tier, support model
and communication function we've provided
has really done..
Last but not least,
I would say, the questions I have,
I also would like to ask you
if you are in a similar..
really addressing the issues?
do we really understand what is needed
from a shared service?
Is it the right model?
you'll start pieces,
you want to leave it to company levels?
for pieces he wants to
leave it at profit level?
Are we trying to do too much, right?
Do things right and a lot
of things so much right.
If you can't deliver,
its very hard to get a second hand
and really try to approach it
from group Company president level.
Ts it a service I would buy
from another third party
Is it priced Right?
And and the other piece
how do I know My services?
So I made clear agreements
with all the group company presidents,
.....from time to best measurement,
year from now we'll
look at that just great,
and we can we can discuss this.
So agreements on what success looks like
and how it's being measured is important.
And tivity feedback will be
those repeated conversation,
our present level, and we're proofs of it.
And bring up very valuable information
that I didn't share with group company.
And there are a few minutes left
so please go into slider
with any more question
and this was the end of my questions.
Thank you.