- Hello and welcome to Cloud Safeguarding:
View from Cloud Providers.
I'm Britta Glade, Director
of Content and Curation
for RSA Conference
and I'll be the moderator
for this session.
First a bit of housekeeping.
If you're joining us live, our panelists
are in the slido chat discussion area
answering your questions right now.
For audio or video issues,
click the technical support button below.
I'm joined today by
three fantastic experts,
Myles Hosford is
Principal, Head of Security
Architecture ASEAN AWS.
Mark Johnston is APAC Head
of Security for Google,
and Abbas Kudrati is the
Chief Security Officer
APJ for Microsoft.
Our session and the questions
we'll be exploring today
are based on dialogue and work
that RSA Conference has done
with the CISO community.
Zeroing in on concepts and
questions that have been raised
by this important community.
We've broken our conversation
today into three key areas,
with a few questions that
each of our panelists
will be addressing, with
a goal of equipping you
with some good strategies
and best practices
for Cloud Safeguarding.
I'll start our discussion
today with the first question,
directed to all of our
panelists, starting with Mark
and then Myles, and then Abbas.
Mark, what are the top three
to five security benefits
to an organization for moving
to a public cloud environment?
- Thanks Britta and,
for me, number one has to be
resource optimization, the
ability to remove tasks
that provide high toil, but low business
that value to your organization,
like patching firmware
or underlying computing infrastructure,
or networking equipment that
is not always easy to manage.
Tracking models and benders
and vulnerabilities or CBAs
across your fleet of infrastructure.
This reduces the attack surface area
that you need to monitor,
manage, and protect,
and allows you to optimize
those valuable security
resources and skills
that you just can't get enough of
to protect your organization.
Secondly, resilience and availability.
High availability and disaster occur rate
are really challenging aspects,
and often extremely expensive.
With cloud services,
they're configuration items,
not complex procurement
and finance discussions.
Your ability to leverage
the hyper-scale defenses,
like distributed denial of service,
massive network to connect resiliency,
multiple zones and regions,
business spun up and spun down
with very little lead time
or capital expenditure.
And lastly, those CSPs
have huge investments
in security itself, much
larger than many enterprises
can afford to spend themselves.
You're able to leverage the
native investments they've made
in their platform and the
partnerships they've made
with third party technology providers
to bring some of your existing
technology and security stack
to manage it the way you want to,
as well as leverage some of the
built-in security capabilities
such as encryption standards
and strengths that they bring
to their services consistently.
Such as native logging capabilities
that have always been
traditionally harder on-prem.
Now I'll pass to the next person.
- [Britta] Myles?
- [Myles] Thanks Britta,
thanks Mark, and I'm gonna go
for three benefits also, and
I think my first one will echo
what Mark closed with there
around the investments
that cloud providers make
in their security posture.
You probably hear about being called
the shared responsibility
model potentially,
where the cloud providers are responsible
for hundreds of controls
across the environment
that you as a customer, often
have the key benefit from
on day one of using the platform.
So if you move a proof
of concept application
or a mission critical application to AWS
on other cloud providers
like Google and Microsoft,
you already benefit from those
controls that already exist.
Typically, those controls would be audited
by third party auditors,
giving you the insurance
that those controls meet
your high standards and expectations.
The second benefit that
I'd like to focus on
and it's really one that I
think is fantastic for customers
moving to public cloud,
is the level of visibility
that security organizations
get from their environment.
Now typically, on premise environments,
it's very hard to get insight
into all the different activity
across your networks
and application stacks.
So as developers and
engineers are making changes,
historically, security
teams have struggled
collecting all of those
different data sources,
and analyzing what's
happened in their network.
In the cloud environment,
it's very easy to determine
what's happened, who
performed the activity,
and what was the result of that change?
So for example, if someone
makes a modification
to your network, alters
your firewall settings
to expose vulnerable
service to the Internet,
very often that sort of
activity can be detected
very, very fast and
responded to in real time.
Which takes me onto my third benefit
and something I think you'll hear
from most of the speakers today
around the use of automation
to protect your cloud environment.
Now cloud is essentially
a collection of API's
and because it's API's, you
can move to an event-driven
security model, which can be reactive
and protect your
environment against threats
and incidents as they happen.
So my earlier example of someone
modifying a firewall setting
or changing a network,
if you have the visibility
to detect that in real time,
combined with the
automation and the benefit
from security via API's,
you can essentially
remediate the security misconfigurations
and incidents as they
happen in your environment
and not have to wait
kind of weeks or months
to determine that these events occurred,
like you would traditionally
in an on-premise environment.
Over to you.
(signal sound)
- [Britta] Excellent, Abbas.
- Thank you Myles and Mark,
I think I would be going over
all of the points which you covered
and I think there's a similarity
of most of the cloud service providers.
But I thought I'll share my perspective,
being a chief security
information officer,
the things which I used to more focus on
when I had everything on-premises right?
I'll take an example
of a threat management.
So I had to wait until my
vendor released the patch
and I need to work around
with multiple venders
to fix something if I have threat
or any malware infection in my network.
But today, if I'm using
the cloud-based solution,
it would be a cloud based ADR,
I can use the power of cloud
and get quickly remediated
because they are operating
at a very hyper-scale or speed, right?
When it comes to threat
management, the minutes matters,
so you need to have something which can
be immediatelty remediated
across the board
and we are seeing those examples
of some of the big
ransomwares and malware,
such as Bad Rabbit.
Second one being, being a
CISO, I had a huge challenge
of how do I maintain I
compliance requirement
for a number of regulatory
bodies in my company?
But having now working with
passing those responsibilities
towards the cloud service provider,
they are now taking care
of most of the control
when it comes to the
compliance requirement,
could be ISO 27,001, PCI-DSS,
or could be APRA requirement
in Australia as such, right?
So I can take advantage of
shifting the responsibility of
compliance and security towards
my cloud service provider.
Third, being having the
flexibility of elasticity
and pay as you go, I don't
need to make a huge investment
in infrastructure and security
product right from the
beginning because as you
know, if you buy your security
solutions and we hardly use
a 25 to 50% of the capability
and rest of the capabilities
are not even being utilized.
Under VPN we pay 100% of the cost.
and having those features
now in the cloud,
you pay for the features which are using
rather than paying 100% to those area.
So which gives a huge advantage
to the CISOS saying that
in terms of, how much they
can realize they can use the
investment for something different,
and having that flexibility of
using those built in security
within the cloud service
provider ecosystem, you know,
and last but not the least,
I think we all have agreed on
on spoken about is investment which
cloud service providers make right?
You don't need to worry about
having data center security
as an example all the CCTV
cameras and biometrics and
whatnot, all these things
are now transferred to them.
And Mark talked about a
firmware level security
hand on hand if you ask any
CISO, so how many times do they
do a firmware level purchase?
You will not get the answer as a yes,
they hardly, they ignore it.
And we have seen in the past right?
we have seen lots of ATM which was
targeting at the firmware level.
But now that cloud service
provider is managing your VMS
and everything as the
infrastructural service,
they take care of a
firmware level security.
So you can sleep well
in the night as a CISO.
Right?
Over to you Britta
- So for our next set of
three questions will direct
the conversation to Abbas
and encourage all of the rest
of you to participate in Slido
in the discussion with all
of our panelists who are here.
Abbas how should a CISO
organization staff for cloud
security, what are the various
roles across architecture
engineering and operations
required for success?
- [Abbas] Absolutely.
Thanks Britta.
As we have seen, the
the whole journey from
on-prem to cloud is transforming, right?
I mean, we call it from legacy to cloud.
And we have seen the evolvement
in architecture space,
the tooling, the skills and practice.
And if you look at the few of the changes,
what we see is the
architecture is changed.
But the principle and outcome
still remains the same.
When it comes to roles and responsibility,
the skills will evolve right?
And same thing goes with the control,
the control and tools and
process will also evolve
and also some of the roles
will still remain the same,
some will change and some
roles will be completely new.
As we have seen that now, we
are running a kind of a new
parameter right every organizations
who is now doing a shift
from on-prem to the digital transformation
or to the cloud journey, they
will they will have a classic
parameter as we call it
the network-based control.
And they will there is
another parameter we call it,
which is a modern parameter,
which is an identity-based control.
And that's why we are seeing the evolution
of those variables, roles
and responsibility from a
legacy architecture an
operating model to a
modern architecture operating model.
To give an example, the
security role which has been
shifting now from a manual
resource administration,
which as our admin you should do it.
They are now focusing on
being an author and owning
and more automation part
similarly our network team,
which was focusing on network containment.
Now they are focusing on
containment at all the layers
which includes network application
identity data and whatnot.
Similarly, the development
team, which was focusing more
on security team was more
focused with development team
on a quality check before release,
Now they are working as an
SME in a DevOps process.
And DevOps process in a continuous
evolution based project.
Our architecture team which
used to be more focused on
a project based engagement before,
now they're focusing on a
continuous engagement and
continuous improvement for
the kind of new role which we
are seeing is Business
Information Security Officer
or BISO as we call it, we
are seeing more of a cloud
solution architect, the
cloud security architect,
we are seeing the new roles
popping up based on identity
and access management,
which is ideal specialist
as we are talking about
identity as a new perimeter,
we are seeing a specific security
analyst which are focusing
on cloud based threats and
cloud based alerts, right?.
Before the focus of
security analysts was more
network-centric and on-prem.
Now they need to understand there're
threats coming from Cloud.
So there is a set of skill
sets which are required
on focusing on cloud based
threats and we call it
cloud security analysis in that area.
So these are the some of the
new things and the evolution
of roles and responsibilities
we are seeing
when when things are moving,
when our organization is now
changing, especially for
information security officer.
Over to yo Britta
- Thanks, thanks Abbas.
So for the next question, if
you could address it for me,
why is it important to
understand shared responsibility
when moving to a public cloud environment?
(Abbas laughs)
- Very good question.
I would say shared responsibilty
goes a long way with all
the cloud service provider
what we have here.
But one thing we need
to really understand is
responsibility versus accountability.
And I like the analogy of a bank right?
So, you go to bank to keep
your money safe, right?
You go and deposit in the bank,
bank will take care of the money,
but how you spend is your call.
That's where the accountability
kind of comes in, Right?
So yes, cloud service providers are having
a model based on the
service which you use,
could be Infrastructure as a Service,
platform as a service or
a software as a service.
And the cloud responsibility
keeps changing
responsibility of the
security and other areas keeps
changing based on the
service that you use.
For example, if you are using
just infrastructured service,
then physical layer and to hardware layer
is the responsibility
of a service provider.
And if you are using the
software as a service,
then everything from physical
layer two operating system
layer to application purchase,
all those responsibility
are shifted towards them.
But you need to understand that,
you are responsible for
identity and the data,
the cloud service provider
is not going to take
responsibility of how
you classify the data.
Yes, they provide you all
the controls and technology
in meeting for managing those security.
But you need to define
in terms of what my data
classification is based on
the sensitivity and clarity
How am I going to store it?
Where do I store, archive
and all those things,
including encryption.
And the second important
part is identity and access
management, who you going to
provide the access to them
role of the access control,
or any other mechanism you have.
So you need to really
understand in that area, right?
And you are using those
enriching signals from them.
So if your cloud service
provider is giving you access to
the API's and collecting those signals,
and alerts and pushing it
back in your on-prem Sim,
or a cloud based Sim, then
the monitoring responsibility
also relies, joint responsibility.
There are certain things
which cloud service provider
takes care for you, but there
are areas of monitoring and
alerting, which you need to configure
and use it on your side.
So understand the built in,
of security control which
they provide, but Mark talk
about in initial pitch,
the configuration part, right?
You are still responsible for
fine tuning in configuring
and managing it in your environment
the way you want to use it.
So, yeah, you have the
keys, but how you keep,
how you keep those keys safely.
It's your responsibility here.
Example of should not keep
your keys under the doormat.
You to have the keys to the kingdom,
or keys to the cloud
service provider, tenancy,
what you're using, it's
your responsibility to
safeguard those keys as well.
Over to you Britta.
- Excellent, yeah, it's
big questions hard to hit
in a little short, short segment.
So final question for you in this segment,
which is how can organizations
gain assurance that the
service provider's side of
the shared responsibility
implements appropriate controls.
Are these controls verified and audited
by independent third parties?
- Absolutely.
So, any cloud service
for the given the time
they have to comply with a
number of these regulatory
bodies, the compliance body
in the industry specific
requirement and all.
And we have a principle, right,
we call it, Trust but verify.
Now being a cloud service provider,
it is very hard for, hard
to allow each and every
organization to come and
audit you if they have a
third party security Assurance Framework.
However, there are
organizations giving the example
of Microsoft of course
you have a right to audit,
but you need to subscribe
to that right and,
and go and do the audit.
Otherwise, there's a
concept of trust but verify,
where the cloud service provider is hiding
their independent auditor.
It could be from one of
the big four organizations
or could be a regulatory body themselves,
they come in audit against
all those control framework
could be ISO, PCI, APRA
and GDPR and whatnot.
And these independent audit
report are being hosted
on a public repository site.
To give an example Service
Trust Portal is an example
from Microsoft site where
they can go and download those
assessment report and certificate
which are independently
issued by the third party auditor,
and they can verify which controls are
tested and being
responsible from CSP side,
and which are the control which,
our customer is responsible
for implementing.
If they need to comply to, for
example, NIST 800-53, right?
Thousand plus controls in them.
But if Microsoft takes care of
our route three service
provider in this case,
takes care of 63 to 73% of the control,
but the remaining part
is, you need to focus on
because those controls
I was talking about,
During our shared services model,
they can't be taken care of that
it's your responsibility in the area.
And there are mechanisms
such as the secure scorecard,
where you can go and have a look at which,
is what is the current
compliance for my environment,
or my tenancy or my subscription,
which can give me give me a visibility of
of all the control
which has been passed by
the service provider and
which are the control
which I need to focus on.
So trust but verify is
something, a principle which
all the cloud service
providers are working towards.
Over to you Britta.
- [Britta] Excellent.
Okay, thank you, Abbas.
Myles, I'm gonna bring you
into the conversation here
with the next three questions,
reminding our participants
that all of our panelists
are in the chat area.
Myles a question for you.
For security controls the
customer is required to implement
what sources of best practices
or industry frameworks
can CISO teams leverage?
NIST CSF,
CIS, Top 20,
PCI-DSS, etc.
- [Myles] Thank you Britta.
So yeah, cloud control frameworks.
This is a very interesting
topic that I spend a lot of my
time at the moment talking
with CISOs and security teams
around the region
And I think if we go back
kind of, you know, many years,
the focus of the security
teams was ensuring the trust
and verification as Abbas
has just been talking about,
you know, understanding
that the cloud is secure.
Understanding the controls of
the cloud provider has built
for you and has audited and
I think once an organization
has kind of gone through that process,
then it's really time for
them to start thinking about
how to build their own control framework
that is suitable for the cloud.
So while each cloud provider
will have prescriptive
best practices, that are
specific and unique to the
platform and services,
and unique capabilities,
A sensible approach for CISO I think,
is to build a control framework
which uses a common set of
controls or a common set
of control objectives.
So things like assets and
software should be inventoried,
or data should be encrypted
at transit and at rest.
These are some good examples
of control objectives
that are kind of platform
agnostic or holistic across
technology providers and
they aren't specific to a
particular vendor, but they do provide
a good security outcome.
Now organizations can build a
security standard with these
control objectives that
can be used across their
organization with a single
taxonomy and Nomenclature.
Everybody knows what control you know,
one should be doing.
And these controls then
can be adopted across your
different technology partners,
your different cloud providers,
and also different types of cloud as well,
whether that's the
infrastructure as a service,
platform as a service, or even SAS.
So let's say as a CISO you've
developed kind of a list of
these hundreds Common control objectives,
you don't really mind where
the data in the system lands,
you know, if the business has
it has a business case to move
it on a particular platform.
But what you do really care
about is that those control
objectives are filled and completed, Okay?
So if you have, you know,
that example of data must be
encrypted at rest and in transit.
It shouldn't be acceptable
if one platform you know,
you can't achieve that or
the particular SAS platform,
you can't achieve that
if that's your objective
to protect the confidentiality,
integrity and availability
of the data, then, you know,
we need to make sure that
there's a method to do that or
you have mitigating controls
and a risk a risk management
framework otherwise.
So for organizations following
this kind of control,
objective approach,
where can you get started
with a list of sensible
common control objectives.
Well, first of all, this
will largely depend on your
organization and what various obligations
and requirements that you have.
So those obligations may come
from a variety of sources.
Typically, organizations
will have obligations
from their existing on-premise
or internal policies.
So you may have an access
control policy that stipulates,
you know, all privileged
access must use multi factor
authentication, for example.
You might also have, policies
around data protection,
which mandates what sort of
ciphers and keys and algorithms
are used in your organization
to protect the data.
So there's definitely a set of obligations
that you already have to meet.
Secondly, you very likely
if you're an enterprise
have obligations potentially
from a regulatory body.
So here in Singapore, for
example, you will have the
Monetary Authority of
Singapore, which has the various
guidelines around technology,
risk management, outsourcing,
and more recently, the cyber
hygiene notice to ensure
that you're uplifting
your security posture.
As Abbas mentioned earlier, obviously,
you're in further in
the region in Australia.
There's definitely requirements
coming out from APRA
and other financial
regulators around the region.
From an industry perspective,
you will have obligations
and requirements from things like PCI-DSS
If you're in the payment card industry,
or even HIPAA, if you're
processing healthcare
and medical records.
so another common approach is to
leverage industry frameworks like
the NIST cybersecurity framework.
So the NIST cybersecurity
framework provides 98 control
objectives across five core
security functions of identify,
protect, detect, respond and recover.
So there's going to be, you
know, a really good place to
start for organizations.
If you've collected those
three different groups
of requirements and obligations,
you can start thinking
about your common set
of control requirements.
So there's gonna be a lot of overlap
against those three sources as well.
So for example,
in your
internal policy,
I suspect that you have
requirements around encryption
in your regulatory requirements,
there will definitely be
your data must be encrypted
And certifications like
programs like PCI-DSS
will also require for encryption.
So in your control framework,
you could essentially
have a single control
that says data should be
encrypted at rest and in transit.
Which effectively meets
a wider set a one to many
relationship back to
your control frameworks.
So once you have a well
defined control framework
with holistic control objectives,
it will then be time to
ensure that these controls
are defined, built and
operating effectively
for your platform of choice.
At this point, the implementation
procedure will become
platform specific.
So I've mentioned a couple
of times the example of data
protection of course, you can
encrypt your data across all
platforms that we
talking about here today.
But how you specifically do
that will depend on the platform
that you are choosing,
and also the service within that platform.
So for example, the way that
we do encryption at Amazon
on our Amazon S3 object store
will be slightly different
to the way that we do it on our
relational databases, for example.
So it's important for security teams,
I believe, to not only
provide the control objective
frameworks, but work with
the application teams
to ensure that they have the
procedures and the detailed
out to how to effectively enact
that control in the cloud.
I think it's also important as Abbas,
has mentioned I market
myself a couple of times now
that there is this shared
responsibility model.
So although you may have
your entire kind of control
framework, many parts of
that control framework
might already be completed
by the service provider.
So things like physical security,
potentially denial of service,
you know, physical security of the
data centers and the global platform.
You still want those controls to be there,
but you're not responsible
for implementing them.
So very important to remember that.
And finally, for controls
that need to be implemented
by your organization as part
of your responsibility model
in the cloud, these can often
be split into two different
groups, so preventative
controls and detective controls.
Preventative controls in the
cloud are usually enforced
using identity and access management,
which I'm gonna talk about in a moment,
that really prevent your users
from making misconfigurations
and introducing risk
into your environment.
And detective controls are
typically the result of an event
driven secure posture, where
you're using the visibility
in real time automation
that I mentioned previously,
to detect these events
as fast as possible,
and mitigate them using
cloud native technologies.
Thanks Britta.
- Okay, let's go identity.
My roots are in identity.
So I love I love anything
in and around identity.
So why is identity so important
in a public cloud environment?
What are some best practices to consider?
- Yeah, a good question.
And I think it was really
interesting what Abbas
mentioned earlier around seeing
a shift in CISO is kind of
organizational structure to
start hiring kind of identity
architects or Cloud Identity architects,
because, you notice
it is such a primary control in the cloud.
So yeah, as I previously mentioned,
you know, when we split these
control frameworks into two,
you typically will have your
preventative and detective
control in your public cloud environment.
And let's talk about why
that is why that is so.
So first of all, if you
wanted to build a new system
in an on-premise environment,
you would kind of initially
go into your data center physically,
you would physically rack
and stack the, you know,
potentially the hardware
and your machines you would
physically connect it to the network,
potentially bootstrap in
operating system and the
application technology stack.
And then finally, kind of
add users and integrate that
operating system and
application to your to your,
you know, your wider
Active Directory or your,
your application user base.
And so historically,
identity has been one of the
last things still very important,
but one of the last things to do
in a configurational environment.
Now, when a cloud environment
identity is typically
the very first thing that you do,
you need to sign up to
your cloud providers have,
you know, console a web application,
and then you create users
that can access your service
providers control plane, and
then you permission those users
to access resources and deploy servers and
operating systems and modify the network.
So in the cloud environment,
identity is typically
the very first thing and
it's really critical to get
the rights to ensure that
you enforce best practices
like separations of duties,
principle of least privileges.
So talking more specifically
about some best practices,
then, I think can something
that I see successful
cloud migrations is when
you have a central identity
provider to manage your
users in a single location.
Ideally, you would use this
identity provider across
platforms, and third party
applications, including SAS.
This makes it easier for
your employees to interact
with the cloud, they only
have to remember essentially
one set of credentials.
And there's also benefits
for the security team here.
And that first of all, as I mentioned,
users don't write down
multiple different passwords
or share passwords across
multiple different providers
which might introduce
risks from a data breach,
or you know, potentially one of them.
But also you have the ability
to very easily interact with
your existing kind of movers,
leavers and joiners processes.
So if someone was part of your cloud team,
and then maybe moved roles
or left your organization,
typically it's very easy
then to just deactivate
that resource in a centrally managed IDP,
and then the access to
the cloud environment,
would automatically be revoked.
So there's definitely some
upside and benefits in having
a central identity provider
to manage your users and
resources across your
platforms that you're using.
Of course, another best
practice, very quickly is to use,
make sure that you're
using strong authentication
mechanisms, so strong and
complex passwords and also
multi factor authentication
to ensure that your
users are authenticated securely.
Now, typically, that would
be part of your identity
providers capability also.
So once you have a centrally
managed identity using strong
authentication mechanisms,
I think it's then time for
organizations very quickly
to start thinking about their
authorization model in the cloud.
So many organizations will
typically either consider
a role based access control model,
or an attribute based
access control model.
So if we talk about role
based access controls models
for a moment, that's when
you really define permissions
around the person's job function.
So in an all back model,
you would define the policy
for a particular job function
like a network administrator
Or for a database engineer,
and they would have specific
policies that allow them to
operate in the cloud environment
and access and provision resources.
As a best practice, you would
grant the minimum permissions
necessary for the job functions.
And of course, this is known
as granting least privilege.
Now, one of the kind of the
drawbacks potentially of an
RBAC model is that as you
add new resources into the
environment, the policies
from an RBAC perspective need
to get a lot more fine grained
and complicated to ensure
that even though I'm a
network administrator,
let's say as my job function,
is the
is the resources that I can interact with,
for at the network level,
actually part of my responsibility.
So really, that's where
attribute based access control
authorization strategies can help.
And that's where you define
permissions based on attributes
of the resources tied back
to the to the individual.
So typically, attribute
based access control policies
require fewer policy or fewer
policy maintenance changes.
But what I would say is
regardless of whether you go down
an ABA or ABA authorization strategy,
you should be aiming to
ensure that users are granted
only the required permissions
on the assets and resources
specific to their business
requirements based on the
principle of least privilege.
The next best practice I'd
like to talk about very quickly
is the just ensuring the
privileged accounts are not used
for day to day or BAU operations.
Organizations and security
teams should bear this in mind,
not just for the access to
the cloud providers control
plane, but obviously the
operating system and the,
you know, the application stacks as well.
A very common approach is
to make sure that you have
vault in these privileged
credentials in some sort of
identity store or privileged access vault.
And then when your employees
need these privileged
credentials, they have the
ability to de-vault them
potentially using an authorized
Incident Management ticket
or a change ticket, which
documents the, you know the actual
steps that they plan to take
when they move to the cloud.
Finally what I would say,
is making sure that you're obviously
auditing all of this access.
So for example, when
people are interacting with
the cloud resources, making
changes in your environment,
de-vault the privileged
credentials across your environment
or even using other secrets,
whether that's API keys,
database credentials and whatnot,
from an identity perspective,
making sure that you are
constantly logging and monitoring that.
And I think that comes
with the visibility.
You heard me mention a few
times I know the other guys
also agree that visibility is
one key benefit that you're
gonna get from the cloud environment,
which really empowers security
teams and CISO teams to
have a very proficient security posture.
- [Britta] Excellent.
And you can't talk identity
without talking privacy, right?
So final question to you
would be in and around.
How do CISO teams
protect PII in the cloud?
How do cloud providers provide
the capability to protect
an organization's most sensitive data?
- Thanks Britta.
So yeah, of course,
organizations are gonna be moving
critical systems sensitive
data, PII data to the cloud,
and they're gonna want to
protect that, you know,
obviously from a confidentiality,
integrity and availability perspective,
but also, you know, privacy
concerns ensuring that,
you know, global regulations like GDPR,
or PDPA is around the region are kind of
catered for on that.
So Cloud providers provide
a number of layers,
of controls to protect sensitive data,
typically using a defence
in depth approach.
This can include things
like data classification,
techniques that you can
classify and you know,
your data to determine
what is sensitive data,
what is PII, and potentially
using simple things
like tagging and adding meta data,
but also using potentially
machine learning and
classification services that
allow you to automatically
detect where sensitive data
is inside your organization.
Secondly, in terms of,
you know, defence in depth
approach to data protection, obviously,
I've just talked about
access control and identity.
That is definitely a Key
control when we talked about
ensuring that only authorized
individuals in your
environment have access to the data,
the resources and the systems
that they would expect.
And then obviously, we have
encryption capabilities,
which is sometimes seen as
one of the primary controls
to data protection.
And of course, you want to
be thinking about your data
encryption, both in transit and at rest.
Okay?
And then finally, I think, and
I'm gonna go and touch into
a couple of these in a
little bit more detail.
Finally, from a data protection
perspective, and sometimes
I see organizations over
looking this as a control,
but it's what is your data backup strategy
to ensure that if you
do get hit with malware,
or ransomware, that it doesn't
have the ability to totally,
you know, affect the
integrity and the availability
of your data by you know,
encrypting it and holding you
ransom for Bitcoin, or for
modifying the data in a way
that makes it unusable.
So there's definitely a need
to think about your data backup strategy.
So I wanna like to dive
a little bit deeper,
into encryption in the cloud.
So customers may choose
to encrypt the data
for a number of reasons.
First of all, obviously,
initially, they want to
attack the sensitivity of
the business data or PII,
both from, you know, the
cloud provider themselves,
but also internally in
their own organization,
you know, very common attack
across enterprises around
the world is it an insider threat,
where you essentially have,
you know, an insider with,
you know, over overly
permissive access to a database
has the ability to do large
scale data exportation
and steal, you know,
millions of records of PII.
So you want to think about
controls that have multiple
layers when we talk about encryption.
In addition to just being
a really good controller
to protect and, you
know, implement security.
Also organizations have a
requirement to implement
encryption from regulatory perspective.
So again, if you're a
financial institution,
and your regulatory bodies
would definitely expect that
sensitive financial transactions
and PII is encrypted.
Also, if you're have any industry
certification requirements
like PCI-DSS are you going
through any other compliance
programs, you're gonna have
to demonstrate that you're
protecting data and of course,
from a privacy perspective.
So, cloud providers already
provide multiple layers of data
encryption, you know, as part
of the shared responsibility
and as part of the global network.
So the cloud provider may, you
know, provide the encryption
of the data as it moves around
the global network between,
you know, what the cloud
providers would call regions
and availability zones, and
the global infrastructure.
I would also provide encryption at
certain layers of the network stack.
So as the data is moving
around the you know,
the virtual private network
and the virtual private clouds,
ensuring that the data is handled
and encrypted in an appropriate way.
And also, the cloud providers
may encrypt the data
at the you know, a host to host
level or a virtual machine,
to virtual machine level,
to ensure that it's
encrypted at that layer.
Now, in addition to the
protection and the encryption
capabilities offered
by the cloud provider,
you also have the ability to
you as a customer, to add your
own encryption capabilities
over the top of that.
So typically you would have
the ability to use your cloud
providers native capabilities.
You know, all cloud providers
have the ability to use
hardware security modules
that will encrypt your,
your data at rest, where you
have the ability to potentially
manage the key, the lifecycle of the key,
the administration of the key,
and assign that key permission
across your organization
to determine who can who
can actually access your
access that data.
And in addition to
encryption of data at rest,
you also have the ability
then to go kind of
one step further and
introduce something like
column level encryption.
again, either using the
cloud providers native API's
that they have, or as
Mark mentioned earlier,
cloud providers have a
very extensive marketplace
of third party partners.
So if you want to use the cloud providers,
native encryption, and you
want just to complement
that potentially with a third party,
all you want to do kind of
column level tokenization
data masking and anonymization,
there's a very wide and
healthy partner ecosystem
that can help you.
So I mentioned earlier that
having a data backup strategy
is very important to protect
against malware or ransomware.
That may affect the integrity
but also the availability of your data.
And of course, one of the
benefits of cloud that the
team outlined earlier, is
that you do have the ability
to store data in very highly available,
highly durable locations
using the global network
on global regions and
global availability zones.
You also have the ability
to enforce, you know,
protection settings on your data.
So you can have things
like version control,
or write once, read many
settings or typically known as
WARM, which provides organizations
the ability to protect
kind of critical backups
against deletion for, you know,
time bound periods, or indefinitely
if that's what you want.
And this is a really good
control to protect against
ransomware overwriting
datasets, making it inaccessible
to your organization.
Finally, again, I want
to talk about, close the
data protection question,
is how important it is to
ensure that you as a security
organization, you're leveraging
the cloud native auditing
and logging and monitoring
solutions around this.
So because everything in the
cloud is essentially an API
call that has been logged,
you're going to get very
fine grained transparency
into your data access and
operations on that data,
including encryption operations,
decryption operations, if the
data has been moved elsewhere,
who the data was moved by,
who the data is frequently
accessed by, you know, you can
get very, very fine grained
logging and auditing
across your data access,
which the security team
gets a lot of visibility
and is one again, I keep
saying that visibility is an
amazing benefit on public cloud providers.
So thanks Britta
And then I guess over to Britta and Mark.
- [Britta] Actually, that
was a wonderful setup.
Mark, I wanna pull you
into the conversation now.
And let's talk about visibility.
That was a really good,
really good leverage point
therefore Myles thank you.
Mark, As a CISO, I often
hear that I cannot get enough
visibility into my cloud environment.
And I'm unsure what the
application teams are doing.
Is this true?
How do cloud providers
provide this visibility?
- Thanks, Britta.
And you're not to cut it short,
because Myles certainly spoke out,
the visibility is strong in the cloud.
But you know, we've had this before.
Yeah, it was easy on-prem,
you held the keys to
the change prover board.
You didn't open the firewall
rule to allow releases
to move from environment to environment,
to all the approvals and the security
reviews were completed.
And this is why the business
wants to move to cloud, yeah.
Speed, innovation, competition.
A lot of that comes from the developers,
and the application teams.
And for us in security.
The developers keep introducing new ways,
and new things languages we haven't run
or pen tested before.
Rust, Elixir, Kotlin.
New words we haven't heard.
Libraries, we haven't vetted for.
Production usage some
open source, that we may
haven't included before.
deployment packages, we're
not sure and understand how
to monitor like a Kubernetes containers
or container based workload.
So in part, this is true,
because we never really provided
this somewhere else in the business.
Where we could quickly and
elastically deliver services.
But the cloud is told by default,
to provide the security and visibility,
in a way you didn't
have on-premises model.
Such things as default
identity and access management.
You have logs of all admin activities
and the service accounts and
the communications by default.
Strong identity and access
management can limit application
teams to only do what
they should be doing.
And org policy with a
hierarchical firewall rule.
Protecting the infrastructure,
should not have the
permissions at the application team
to be overridden for
their individual project.
One example of the strong
control that you can have
and management.
Another area would be data storage,
spoken about that with the
PII classification with Abbas
and through what Myles have spoken about.
It's centrally managed,
can be scanned for PII
and sensitive business data.
And the usage and monitoring
of that is all tracked
and logged with data.
Infrastructure logs, creation
of subnets, IP addresses,
VPC's all exist by default.
And networks can easily have
flow analysis or full packet
capture enabled to allow
you to do deeper analysis
of changes in the environment,
or what application teams
are doing and using in
that space themselves.
without the need for specialized hardware,
traditional span ports and
challenges that are associated
with NetFlow devices.
And service accounts.
One of the major bands of
existence that we've had
traditionally in security,
are hugely monitorable
in a cloud environment.
Revocable, understandable,
highly auditable and there's
also a mention of managing
the keys and vaulting.
And IAAM around that.
This is also very powerful
capability, to understand how
your system to system
interactions are occurring,
and monitoring those
application teams norms of
communications with their
systems and services.
And last, but certainly not least,
is there's a bunch of native
compliance and benchmark
analysis that can be built
in, to give you some industry
best practices, that
Myles mentioned earlier.
So Cloud can actually give
you some native analysis
of whether you're meeting
some industry standards
like a CIS benchmark analysis as well.
So these are certain areas
that great visibility
can be added to the environment.
It exists natively in cloud,
and it's a matter of
applying it to a new way
inside the way you operate.
Thanks, Britta.
- Thanks, Mark.
So going back to actually
the very beginning,
The introduction when you
talked about automation,
let's dig a little further there.
Why is automation so important
from a security perspective in the cloud?
And how can it be used to
increase an organization's
stability to effectively
respond to incidents
faster than on-prem?
- Sure.
Yeah, It's a common challenge that we have
and you know constant thing
the cloud is we're moving
faster, which means change is faster.
And the traditional analogy
of a car that goes fast
and needs bigger brakes, it
really isn't just that simple.
You just can't put bigger brakes on it,
it doesn't work like
that, you're actually not
actually creating the outcome you want,
which is to go faster with more safety.
So I'm gonna consider building
security controls in the
cloud to be more like the
anti-lock braking system on a car.
It helps when you make a mistake,
it can lessen or even
possibly prevent the crash
from occurring, but it's
able to detect something
that's gone wrong in the
situation and act on that.
This type of intervention
is only possible,
through automation.
It's too late to retrain the driver,
and they're out of control in production.
How do we detect, immediately
identify and start
to work on remediation in that space?
Automation is key, and it
must be built in from the
beginning so that you're
equipped with those tools.
When the developers go
out building applications,
and leveraging the elastic
services that cloud provides.
The DevOps concept as a guard
rails, not gates concept.
You can't scale to your
security team to meet the many
different inspection points
that you traditionally
had with a UIT to staging or
staging to production release
cycle with those change approval
boards I mentioned earlier.
- Developers now experiment in production.
Release in production with
blue, green, and A, B, and
Canary testing methodologies,
how do you enable that safely?
and manage that, automation
is gonna be key to detect any
anomalous spikes, any
particular challenges,
and responding to that,
while you're actually doing
testing in production?
So where do you start?
Well, actually, it starts
with the power of cloud,
the asset inventory.
Everything in cloud is a digital asset,
a firewall rule, an IP
address, monitoring assets,
resources and policies in the cloud,
we can actually build that
anti-lock braking system.
These are norms that are simply incorrect
for an environment.
Let's go for an example.
Creating a virtual machine.
You can first test if it came from the
sowey or trusted image store.
Is it approved?
doesn't have a public IP address.
Has it been scanned for
the latest vulnerabilities?
Does it need this public IP address,
if it does, is it exposed
behind the load balancer,
the web application firewall
and is it accordingly only
able to be communicated from the
back end IP addresses at that.
This is a very simple litmus test,
to create a mitigation
control for a web application.
And if it was had a firewall
rule of any any to the
internet, we immediately
have a problem and
an anti-lock braking system can kick in
and start to mitigate
that particular risk.
Now, let's talk about some data.
PII is something that we
are furiously protecting
and making sure we monitor and
manage in every environment
to protect our customers.
When you upload data to the cloud,
you can go through a quarantine,
you can only allow to
be uploaded in one place
that checks whether or not
that is the right place,
right information for the right use case.
Should PII be in a public store?
Of course not.
And so therefore, every time
you add information to a store,
you can check with this PII.
And you can check the permissions
if they're public or not.
And this can create that, again,
anti lock braking mechanism.
that continual monitoring
that continual alert,
that will allow you to allow
them to upload much data
as they need to do their job,
but create safety nets and
controls not to mitigate risk.
So in the that two fairly
strong examples of how
only automation could
really solve the problem,
because the scale at which
we build infrastructure,
and the scale at which we move data today,
no human can watch any of that.
Back to you Britta.
- Excellent.
And a final question for
you mark in this segment.
And then we'll bring all our guests
back for a parting question.
"How can the cloud help
me implement security at
every stage of the software
development lifecycle?"
- Yeah, this is a really,
really big question.
And there's lots of approaches
and different names.
Some call it shifting left on security,
bringing security early into the STLC,
the software development
that upset lifecycle.
DevOps, as I've mentioned just prior.
Making everyone accountable
across both development
and operations for
security being built in,
or building cloud native,
moving from a traditional model,
to a cloud native security model.
What are you gonna need to do?
Well, as a seesaw, probably
a little bit of everything.
That's strategically moving to
an improved security quality,
no matter what you do.
And building an environment,
that will migrate most of
your services to in the future
that supports these principles.
Which is likely to be cloud-native
So how important is it to do this?
So one of the state of
DevOps reports or DO reports,
it was found that high
performing organizations,
were doing 50% less time,
remediating security,
than low performing organization,
when they got this wrap.
So it's extremely important,
in that resource optimization
and in the ability to
improve the security posture
of your applications and
the systems that you run.
So shifting left in
security review process,
too early in the system
development lifecycle,
requires several changes,
but not all of these are
significant deviations
from the norm.
You should get information
infosec and vault
early in the software design.
The infosec team should get
involved in design phase
for all projects.
When it begins a review can
be added as a guiding factor
for releasing the design
to a development stage.
You can develop security approve tools,
providing datas with
pre-approved libraries
and you know code packages that have input
and pre determined approval
from the security team
to standardize develop a code.
This makes it easier to
review the differences
instead of the core which
you know can be reusable.
You can develop automated testing,
the cloud's really good with this.
Using that asset management
database I spoke about earlier.
Changes in the environment can trigger,
scanning and code reviews
Building security tests into
that code can be continuously
tested scale without
requiring manual review,
and identify common
security vulnerabilities,
earlier on in the
lifecycle for mitigation.
So how does cloud really help?
This is web platform as a service.
And containers really show the strength.
Cloud brings the same power,
to development teams and the
security team with these services.
One great example is something
called, the service mesh,
or like open source products such as STR.
Imagine you can secure
every call to every service
with mutual authentication
and limit these communications
only to the right services,
they're approved to talk to
the other services without
changing the application.
That sounds like a
fantastic security tool,
you can apply across your
container based services
to get telemetry, observability,
apply security in transit,
and understand the norm of communications,
to give an understanding
of what is talking to what,
when is it allowed to?
And is there anything abnormal
happening in the environment?
This is not just about
the operational security,
it's also about the supply chain.
So by protecting interaction
to containers is only one part.
The next is making sure
your images are trustworthy.
So how do we do that?
We must make sure the supply chain,
has security and compliance
pegged in from the beginning.
We do two main things here.
One we're very familiar
with, vulnerability scanning,
container vulnerability scanning.
Lets you quickly understand
potential threats and
identify issues as your
containers are built and stored
through the container lifecycle.
The infosec team is a critical
tenant in managing that
container image and the vulnerabilities
and packages that exist.
And the ability to remediate,
and secondary monitoring
binaries executing
with binary authorization.
Open Source capabilities
exist for this to provide
the services you can use in the cloud,
to to provide this level of capability,
in the supply chain and
operational observability.
So, I think that one's
addressed the question
and back to you, Britta.
- Excellent.
I'm wanna bring all of our
panelists back now into the room.
We've been drinking from a firehose,
this there's been a lot
of really good material
given between all of our
all of our presenters.
I'd like you to address
this last question.
Myles if you can start
and then Abbas then Mark,
you'll have the final words.
"What are three key next
steps for a CISO organization
to consider when moving to the cloud?
Myles.
- [Myles] Thanks Britta.
So the the first one for me,
and I don't think it was
addressed actually through
the previous slides,
but how important it is
for a CISOs organization
to establish a training
enablement and certification program
for public cloud security.
And one of the reasons
for that I find is that
most organization, the
cloud journey is obviously
driven by a business demand.
And then, you know, a business requirement
to move to the cloud for whatever benefits
that they're trying to drive.
And typically, there will be
some sort of cloud working
group or cloud center of Excellence,
which is largely an engineering team
or an application team driving that.
Unfortunately, sometimes the
security team is maybe not
initially part of that
cloud working group,
or that kind of cloud
center of excellence.
And maybe the security
organization hasn't had time
to fully adapt their,
you know, existing tools,
capabilities and processes
and even thinking around
security for the cloud.
So I think as CISO it's very
important to ensure that
you have a line of sight on
skilling up and you know,
rescaling the team on the new aspects
of security in the cloud.
Now, yes, there is gonna
be existing tooling
and existing control
objectives and principles
that you're gonna bring with you.
But as you've heard from
all three presenters today,
there are slightly different
ways of thinking about that.
So my first consideration
for a CISO team is to look
inwards at your own organization,
and evaluate what actual
capability you have
around public cloud security,
it's gonna be very difficult
to do the rest of your job
functions, whether that's
architecture reviews,
engineering, security operations,
if your own organization really
doesn't fully understand,
you know, the public
cloud security principles,
and also what the objectives
are of the business teams
that are moving to cloud.
So for example, if your
organization's ambition this year
is to migrate everything
to a cloud provider
and do kind of all in and
close the data centers,
your security capability
and enablement plan.
will look very different to
an organization that's just
trying to get started with PLCs and
maybe non critical data and systems.
So I think the first one
is to is to establish
a training and enable
but similarly on that,
sticking on that suggestion for a moment,
I would also look inwards
and have a look at,
who within your organization
is the single threaded
leader for cloud security.
So if it's kind of a little bit of a
hobby of everybody's
job, that's, you know,
maybe okay for now, but what
I do see with organization
that where cloud security
is a second class citizen
or it's not someone's full time job,
then there's no real
ownership over driving some
of these strategic programs
that you're gonna need.
The second consideration that I would say,
is that organization as I mentioned,
kind of in length in one of
my in one of my questions
was around how important it is to
build a control framework for cloud.
So for example, if an
application team kind of
puts their hand up and says,
We wanna move to cloud,
security team, what do we need to do?
I think there needs to be
a very clear defined set of
obligations and, you know,
control objectives that need to be built.
I do see a lot of customers
spending a lot of cycles
and when the security
team kind of, you know,
being really challenged when
there's no real clear path
forward, or clear set of requirements
for the application teams.
Now in most organization,
the application teams
are very willing to build
those control requirements
into their application technology stack,
but they need to be defined
first and really kind of,
you know, confirmed
with the security team.
Then I think a CISO should
also take that a step further.
So a really good place to
start is to have a well defined
control framework that all
of the application teams
across your organization are aware of.
It's been communicated,
it's been agreed upon.
But in addition to that, as I mentioned,
the actual control implementation
or the control procedures
that are specific to the cloud,
I think successful security
teams actually go that
extra mile and work kind
of hand in glove with the
engineering teams to come up
with solutions to actually
ensure that those controls
objectives are embedded into
the applications development lifecycle.
Mark talked about shifting security left,
and you know, DevOps
principles around that.
Now, I think, you know, the
security team can really
lean into the engineering
and cloud working groups
that are providing subject
matter expertise as to how
those control objectives
really can be built into,
into the pipeline to
ensure that those controls
are constantly audited or prevented
or detected in real time.
Then the final consideration
of the three that I would say
is that organization and
particularly security teams,
really need to embrace the
visibility and automation
benefits that you get in.
If you don't have real time
visibility into your control
framework, or if you don't
have a real time security
operation set up where you're
have immediate notification
when, you know, a high
risk event is occurring
in your organization, then
I think there's a little bit
of work to do for you as a security team.
As I mentioned many times
the visibility that you get
not Just from the, you know,
the native control plane,
but across all of the logging
and monitoring solutions
available to you in the cloud,
really does allow you to
build this kind of fully
automated real time responsive
Security Operations center.
In addition to that, not
just detecting these alerts
in real time, but also
firing automatic responses to
essentially self heal or self remediate,
these incidents as they occur
is a very powerful position to be in.
So just to recap;
Training, Enable your
teams be prescriptive
of your guidance,
Automate as much as possible.
Thanks Britta.
- [Britta] Excellent, Abbas.
- [Abbas] Thank you Myles
and thank you Britta.
So being a cybersecurity
practitioner and being a CISO,
I always like to think from a
risk management lens point of view.
Yes, controls are required,
but they are secondary for me.
So as CISO, now that
decision has been made
that now we need to move towards cloud.
So what is my risk management focus now.
I have to focus my,
I need to shift my focus to three areas.
First, being identity, second
being information protection.
And third is my device management.
So my cloud security strategy,
which I'm building now,
from one frame to the cloud,
my entire strategy or from
risk management point of view
will be running around these
three legs, as I call it.
Right?
In terms of identity, identity
becomes my new perimeter.
So how I'm going to focus
on management identity
with multi factor authentication
in terms of strong
authentication, or even going towards
a passwordless journey, right?
And how I'm going to manage the
least privilege access management role.
When it comes to Information Protection,
now that I have my data shifting from
my on-prem to the cloud,
how do I manage my information,
in terms of sensitivity, criticality,
we talk about the backup,
we talk about encryption,
who has access to what?
Where are where am I storing those data?
the geographical location, the tenancy,
the jurisdiction within which
country am I hosting those
data, all those things have
to come up as a apart strategy
I need to have a information
protection strategy,
apart from my identity strategy.
The third being device which
is on the threat management.
Now that my employees
are working from home,
working from remotely
taking advantage of cloud,
as an opportunity for especially
in this Pandemic situation,
what controls do I need to think of,
or what strategy do I need to think of,
of managing those device?
Or am I going to allow my employee to use,
or bring your own device?
Or am I going to allow,
how do I manage the handheld device?
What kind of threat protection
do I need to put on them?
So my strategy will shift
from focusing highly
on network centric, which is internal,
to a more cloud centric in
defining in this three area.
Identity, Information
protection and device.
The second second point is;
I keep on talking about
identity and we have
spoken enough about that.
Identity is a new perimeter, right?
I can no longer focus on
having everything behind
the firewall on Network centric.
So now I need to start thinking
from a zero trust network
to architecture point of view.
Zero trust, as I say,
it's not a technology,
it's a strategy and it's a journey.
So from zero trust point of view,
I need to focus on my
core three principles,
which is a trust no one
and verify everyone.
So the healthy signals
which I am collecting
from my identity and my
and my device management,
I need to verify each
and every signals because
that's how I'm going to
get an assurance whether
the person or the device
which is trying to access my
resources is the right and
healthy in terms of the signals
are good, the device is managed,
already meeting my compliance requirement,
the identity which they are
using are not been compromised,
and the identity which are
being used are with the correct
security features on them.
So trust no one, verify, everyone.
The second one, my
principle which I will go
and focus on my identity is my,
I call it a least privilege, right?
That's another the part of my strategy,
as I talked about in the first option,
least privilege talks about
not giving a standing access
to anyone in perspective of what role
they have even the admin,
they should have something
like just in time, and
just enough access isn't
based on the need,
or we call it a role based access control.
Right?
So that's what I need to
focus on when I'm building up
my identity based perimeter.
And the third principle
which are following my second
recommendation is having the,
assume breach mindset, right?
I have to have a defensive Layer in my,
in my control framework,
as Myles was talking about.
So in case my first control is breached,
what do I have as second
control to protect my data
from getting exfiltrated.
So I need to constantly work from
an assumed breach scenario.
Those are my top three, within
my second recommendation.
And the third key takeaway
for CISO was trying to move
towards cloud and we had a meeting had
a lot of discussion on shared model.
So I want to reiterate that
particular thought steps that
understand the shared
responsibility and the shared model.
Implement a good governance, usually,
the things I would go one level up
in terms of roles and responsibility.
So as a CISO, I had a team
who was managing the network
security, the access control and whatnot.
But when things go on cloud,
there are a number of tools
and security features which
are provided by your cloud
service provider.
Now, there's always tug
of war between the team.
That which teams should have access
to which security tool
brought in by my CSP.
Is it the network security team?
Is it the IT security?
Is in the information security?
Is it my softie.
So have a clear definition as the CISO
that now that we are we
are moving things on cloud
and now we have the cloud based
security tools and control,
which team is focused on risk
for visibility point of view,
which team is going to focus
on managing and reviewing
and monitoring those particular dashboard?
So, having a clear line of
responsibility will go a long way
for CISO rather than going back and forth.
Right?
And also understand,
the shift in the role,
shift in the role for the
security that they are no longer
doing things manually,
there is a heavy reliance on
automations and artificial intelligence
and MLS and whatnot over the cloud.
And the shift also is
focused of initially,
the net of security was focusing
more on being an author,
but now they are shifting their focus
to being more of a governance
role they're taking.
And as our Mark talking about
the software development
life cycles in AGPT.
So that's also comes into
your governance models
that how your architecture
teams are continuously
being involved, the security
is been embedded right
from the beginning or from
the design point of view,
right with the design judgment
discussion to all the way
from the testing point
of view, at every stage.
So, three recommendation;
Understand the risk management,
have a risk management lens
controlled as the secondary,
Focusing on identity based
perimeter, which is a zero trust.
Trust no one verify everyone.
Least privilege and assume breach,
and third is a shared model,
and good governance should be in place
whenever you're moving on the cloud.
Over to you, Mark.
- [Mark] Thanks very much Abbas.
I think of this like moving house.
We don't do it often and when you do it,
you really want it to be right.
Rarely do such fundamental
shifts in technology,
that change the IT landscape come around.
centralized computing with a mainframe.
Decentralize with clients server.
Virtualization making efficiency
out of Central resources
and now containerized micro services
and edge computing extending this,
each improving the
efficiency of the product.
Direct constance in this for security,
safe storage of data,
secure communications,
Identity and Access,
operating systems and binaries.
These haven't changed.
With each evolution, we
seen more abstraction,
the underlying complexity and
higher automation throughout.
The common aspects being speed, and code.
Cloud is an overlay on this.
Use it to augment your business needs.
This could be bare metal for now,
or going completely serverless
on the other end of the scale.
Either way, get your
teams closer to the code.
Embrace extreme automation.
Own code and systems that
developers should never touch,
like the standard operating environment,
of a VM or a container image
or cryptography libraries
that only security experts
should really be understanding.
Abbas spoke about zero trust.
I think this is very important
when it comes to cloud.
Wholly access and manage
those credentials now that
identities the real perimeter,
wherever you're accessing from.
For me, two factor
authentication is mandatory here.
It's now cheap, scalable
and easily appliable to your
organization, pleased do it.
And CIS benchmarks is a
nice starting ground for
understanding the security
posture for what really is
gonna be a multi cloud world.
Of just like each database
is different in the way it
operates each cloud provider can be also.
Do the education study and
research to successfully
mark controls?
I would say the CIS benchmarks
is a nice opening door
and tailored it to your particular needs.
It's there for most major
cloud providers today.
That's it from me.
Back to you Britta.
- [Britta] Excellent.
Well, attendees, you just
got a wealth of information.
I hope you were taking good notes.
I hope you were chatting
away with our panelists.
Very smart leaders in their field.
Their contact information is here.
Feel free to engage with them.
We thank you for joining us today.
And panelists. thank you very much.