(upbeat music)
- Hello and welcome to get
the freaking basics right!
If you're joining us live our speakers
are in the Slido chat discussion answering
your questions right now.
For audio visual issues,
click the technical
support button below.
I'd like to now turn it
over to Daniel Kroiss
and Robert Lamprecht for the presentation.
- Hi, and good afternoon.
I hope you all can hear me, all right.
So we're pre-recording this from Austria
and it's now about late at night.
So good night also from us.
Yeah, my colleague, Robert and
I will now give you a little
bit of our insights that we've
gathered over the last couple
of years within the field
of security within EMA
within Europe and border
regions of Europe.
And we wanna get one
message across to you,
which is we think we still
should work on the fundamentals,
we still should work on the basics.
But before we dive right into our talk,
I wanna give a quick explanation
to the obvious elephant in the room.
Because most people have
you that know KPMG usually
as an auditor, and this should
not be an advertisement.
But this is an actual team
photo from an office party
somewhere around four years
ago when KPMG in Austria
where Robert and I are
based, actually remodeled
their cybersecurity
advisory team and a bunch
of crazy tech folks got
let loose on this very
innocent audit cheap people.
And it has been one hell
of a ride ever since.
And actually, one wouldn't
have thought that working
for an audit company
in an advisory capacity
in the field of cybersecurity
could actually go that well.
But enough about our employer.
This is Robert and myself.
My name is Daniel Kroiss.
I used to work for a start
up somewhere in Vienna
just doing web development stuff.
And then after graduating from university,
I started working in a
security team for a bank
leading a small team there, as well.
And about four years ago, I joined KPMG,
as security advisory team.
In my day job usually,
I'm in charge of all kinds
of different projects from
security architecture,
security strategy.
And in the past, I've been
doing technical security
assessment, red teaming,
OT security, engagement,
those kind of things.
And by design, we get called
into quite a lot of incidents.
And this is what we will speak off today
in this talk and give you
a little bit of insight
of what we have seen and what
we think is the next steps
that should be taken for
security-minded people
in the company.
But before we dive into it,
Robert please introduce yourself.
- Good evening, everyone.
My name is Robert.
I'm now 16 years now with
KPMG in the role of a director
and running the security folks in there.
Before I was working with IBM
under Global Services role.
Primarily I'm focusing on
some security strategy parts
and incident response type of work.
So whenever there is a
hack attack or some things
like this running into the
enterprise and checking
how to get out the attackers,
and of course also wearing
some more or less assurance
hat or audit type of hat,
I'm also doing quite a
lot of attestation work.
Checking IT data centers and
service providers globally
doing some SOC 1 or SOC Type
2 kind of reporting thing.
- And of course, for Austria he's typical
he's a mountaineer.
But the two mountains we will get later on
in our presentation.
First, usually when we
would be on site with you,
unfortunately we cannot be on
site with you in Singapore,
which we would really love
to be, but I would want you
to give us an indication
if those kind of things
would sound familiar to you.
Because these are actually some things
that we've encountered in our
previous work a lot, actually.
And I stole this graphic
down there from somewhere
on Twitter, but it happened
to me multiple times,
both of us multiple times
within our engagements.
When we got called into incident response,
and we were asking, okay we
understand what happened,
but how's the shape of our infrastructure?
How good is our infrastructure?
What's the security health
of our infrastructure?
What's the basic hygiene look like?
And we fell over the most obvious question
like how many assets do you have?
And depending on who you ask,
you get a pretty broad scale
from 4,800 to 9,000 and something.
So if you consider that is a
lot of gap in between them.
And this is actually what we find a lot.
So know your assets, not
so much in most companies.
And this has been really bugging us.
And yeah, the second
point we also have seen it
so many times, and I'm sure
you've seen it as well.
There's an infection
spreading just everywhere
in your network.
And the hardest part is
telling friend from foe really,
and this is really when you
don't know what your admins
are doing and if this
is legitimate behavior,
this really kills you when
time is of the essence
in terms of an incident response.
And even worse is the next point.
Unfortunately, this is so
bad that I couldn't find
a proper meme to go with it.
But I've had this so many
times when we were at clients
on site that the question we had to phrase
after looking at some of
the previous little ability
scanning results was not so
much, the question that we tried
to answer like how the attacker got in
or how the attacker spread,
all of a sudden didn't be relevant anymore
because it was just so horrible
and there was so much stuff going on,
on the inside within the perimeter,
that it was just a matter of like how easy
it was for the attacker to spread
and not if he could have spread,
or she could have spread around.
And last but not least,
for most companies,
we've been working in an
incident response capacity.
There was pretty much admin
credential for everybody.
They were handing out admin
credentials, admin accounts,
like t-shirts at the baseball game.
It was incredible.
Just like you won an admin account,
you won an admin account,
and this just kills you
in case of an incident.
Because if you have 1,000 admin accounts,
local admin accounts on machines
that are just laying around
for the attacker to pick up,
this just kills you in an incident.
And as a consequence of
that and like after our
incidents we tend to do
our internal debriefs
and the funniest things
always happen when it becomes
public or even if you talk to management
or some of the people in
charge at the companies
that we work with.
We've got three very
significant statements
that just are bugging us and the first one
is like my favorite.
And I've read it now in
the last couple weeks a lot
in the media again when
there were like bigger
security incidents all over Europe.
And like the CEO goes
on camera and says like,
"but we've done everything we could.
We are ISO certified
and we're so compliant.
Still, we got hacked."
This is the first thing and Robert and I
are always sending back
and forth the articles
of newspapers where it
is, it wasn't there.
And we're just laughing
because it's like yeah,
you did, right.
But more on that later.
The second thing usually when
we come in the first thing
that people, especially
management tell us is like,
"yeah, but we've spent so much money
on that latest shiny tool.
Why is that not protecting us.
We have antivirus, we've
bought this new firewall."
And again, this is also a
very common mistake we see.
And the third one is, and
we've had this happening
to us also, in a previous engagement,
when we were having this
discussion with a lot
of folks at the company,
And we were having this big crisis meeting
and at some point, some
guy from the CISO office
gets up and says like, "yeah,
we know all those risks,
but everybody accepted them."
And this has also been a huge problem
for companies that we've seen.
And yeah this is actually
where last year at the RSA
Conference in San Francisco
Robert, and I got to talk
and like "hey, maybe we
should do a talk about this."
And like, what is it with those things
and why do they keep
still happening from us.
And this message is that
we're trying to bring across
in this talk is really a very basic one.
And we have to focus on
the fundamentals first.
And this is actually the
thing I wanna raise next
and go into more detail.
What we still see and
this we see quite a lot
and coming from an audit
firm, we can really
tell you stories about this,
but compliance is related
to security but compliance is not security
and security is not compliance.
Those two are in relation to each other,
but they're not the same thing.
And we've had it so
many times and a policy
does not fix a technical issue.
And this is very important
thing to say it out loud
because there's so many people
writing awesome policies
in what should and shouldn't be done.
But like if nobody ever reads the policy
or if it's not enforced,
this is just like walking over a crosswalk
with the red light then.
Yeah, it just happens that
people cross the policy then.
But it's fine documented and
it looks really good on paper.
The next thing, there's
usually two types of companies
when we get called in.
Either the ones on the left hand side,
which are more than the other ones,
but the other ones are more significant
on the right hand side.
On the left hand side,
we have those companies
that try to just solve
every problem with a tool.
And just every problem,
they have to buy a new tool,
they put it in their data
center, they plug in cables,
and be done with it.
This has been happening so often,
that there's actually this
joke that people sometimes make
about some projects are just robots
to produce hot air and to blink.
They have two lights, blink, blink.
And the other thing is,
and I really enjoy reading
those little Bobby comics I
recommend you to check them out
is if you don't spend money on security,
we will guarantee you that
you will not see any attacks
because you cannot see them,
which is terrible in itself.
But this is how security is still done.
And a lot of companies and there are some
that get better at this.
But still, budget cuts,
especially in a recession still
also affect security, when
you should actually spend more
money on security and this
is still a huge problem.
And the next thing, I really
wanna say this out loud.
And this is really
important for me personally,
because a lot of people not realize this.
Accepted security risk, it's fine.
A company has a certain risk
appetite and that's okay.
But this is really important.
If you take home just one
thing from this presentation,
I would recommend this is it.
Know that your accepted
security risks are still risks.
They can still be exploited by attackers.
And you still have one
hell of an attack surface.
And you have to be aware of this.
Because there's so many
companies where everybody accepts
a risk here a risk there
and so forth and so on.
And this culminates to
quite a big, big, big,
big mountain of risks, and
those can still be exploited,
and attackers will not
care if you accepted them.
And this has been a really,
really painful process
for a lot of companies
to learn and this is why
we've put it on a slide.
So where do we go from here?
Our house is on fire.
What do we do?
And after an incident,
of course what you do
during an incident it's
clear you have your incident
response processes, and
you have excellent support
and KPMG or competitors
are happy to help you
through your burning house,
but what do we do afterwards?
And we suggest a simple approach.
Let's focus on the basics
first and then worry
about all the other stuff.
And there's really three
key things that we want you
to get right.
And if you do that, you
still can get hacked,
but you will make it a hell
of a lot harder for attackers.
Apply critical patches.
All of these patches,
all of these problems
are known problems.
This is nothing new we're telling you,
but we just have to get it done this time.
The same with network segmentation.
WannaCry, NotPetya all of
these malware outbreaks,
all of these ransomware
outbreaks really showed us
how many companies are still
having trouble with this.
And there's so many that
are still having trouble
with this we have to
get this done for good.
We have to put it into the
state of the art network
and fix your privileged accounts.
Last but not least, you have to restrict
who owns elevated
privilege in your company.
And Robert will go into that
a lot more into detail now
but these are three things that
if you have no other things
that you can do, you really
should focus on those.
But now, Robert.
- So we are on slido.
If you have any questions,
feel free to put them
on Slido and we are happy
to answer your questions.
So having heard all the
things that Daniel told us,
let's have a look what the
basics are and how we can tackle
them in order to get things right.
And the first essential
part as Daniel mentioned,
was apply the critical patches.
So this time, definitely for real.
Get your boots on the ground.
It's enough already being
said so we should get
our hands dirty, and apply those things.
So applying those patches
throughout the whole
infrastructure, we know
it's a tough type of thing
because everyone complains and tells us
that it might be difficult
to leverage those things
in order to increase the
security but the patches
you're applying definitely
throughout the landscape,
protect your business,
they protect your customers
of course, they obviously
protect your data
and finally, they protect your job.
Because it's your job to do the things.
It's your job to assist the executives
and to act with due care
in order to safeguard
the whole environment you're operating in.
Some of the excuses we hear
quite often are, we cannot
patch everything it is too complicated,
things might get too difficult
so we better don't do anything, right.
Enough with all these excuses and so on.
So it's definitely time now to start off
with the things that you can patch.
The Pareto principle which
is something doing 80%
or covering 80% by 20% of Mart Ford
is an Oldie but a Goldie.
It still works, it's still
something that you can leverage,
you decrease the risk and
you decrease the overall
vulnerabilities for a
whole enterprise footprint.
Definitely one of the essentials is here
to prioritize right.
Therefore start off 50 assets
that are of your importance.
The assets that have the most contribution
to your business processes
to your enterprise
and the vulnerabilities
which are critical at risk.
Meaning everything
which has a score higher
than seven in the CVA rating.
That's definitely something you can use
to prioritize your things.
We know manually, you cannot
cover all these things.
So therefore, automate as
much as possible tools.
Windows like Microsoft have
the SCCM or in the Linux
and Unix environment
there's is Puppet or Ansible
available that you can use.
And please do us a very big favor.
Don't forget the network infrastructure
and because of the whole
digitization and the spread
of new devices being involved like IoT,
also include them and apply
the patches there as well.
Last but not least one learning for us
in our cases was don't trust the IT guys
if you ask them did you patch everything,
because the answer will always be yes.
Make your vulnerability
scanner be your best friend
to check effectiveness
because one case we had,
there was WannaCry.
The company we were supporting
before was actually saying
"we applied the latest patches,
but they didn't actually
restart the system in order to make
the patches become effective."
This is definitely something you can check
with vulnerability scanners.
Daniel.
- So here's an odd thing,
but this is a CISOs tale, and
we've seen this a lot of times
happening within multiple companies.
But Robert is the mountaineer of us,
but I will tell you
something about mountains
as for Austrian presentations.
Don't mind the numbers
on there they're just
for exemplary purpose.
But on every side of every
vulnerability management program
when a company hasn't
been doing this, right,
and this should be a message
of encouragement for you.
You started off somewhere, didn't you?
Round about what they
had and then you round
about what the probabilities were, right.
And then they started off like,
"hey, let's do vulnerability management.
Let's get everything patched, right."
And at some point, they're
looking at the numbers
and like, "this is really bad.
What are we going to do?"
There's so many vulnerabilities,
and they have spent quite a lot of money
on this new fancy tool, and
they go further with it.
And then there's the point where the CISO
actually, or most of the
security team is like,
"oh, I should probably look for a new job
because this is bad."
And here's the message of encouragement.
There's a peak and you have to get there.
This is painful process
you don't know really
where this peak is.
Because it might be the case
if you're in a bigger company
and we've seen this happening,
you find a couple hundred,
you find a couple
thousand servers somewhere
and all of a sudden
your vulnerability score
increases or the number
of vulnerability increases
by 10 times and this is just what happens.
You gotta accept that this
is the technical depth
your company has raised.
But once you get to this
top, you can actually be glad
because it won't get any
more worse than that.
And this is a good way
you can tell a good season
apart from not as good
season because this person
actually goes in and
gets their hands dirty.
It's like okay, now we know how bad it is
now we have to do
something about it, right?
And this process will be hard.
I'm not gonna make you
any illusions about that.
You will have a very slow
start and this will be really
tedious process at the beginning.
But once you start working on it,
and once you get also
the IT folks convinced
that there is a way of going
downwards on that mountain,
they will start working with
you, they will be reluctant
at first maybe, but you
will get them there.
And they will actually
realize that this is not
as hard as they thought.
And this is a critical point.
As soon as you get to the point
and you get the IT folks to realize
and the business folks realize, okay,
this is not as bad as we thought it is.
You actually get down that
mountain faster and faster.
And all of a sudden, you're in the point
where you can start thinking
about accepting risks again, right?
This is the point somewhere in this area
is the point where you actually
have a decent risk state.
And you can actually think about okay,
this might be the last 10 15% of my assets
that might be somewhere one
or two that I could accept,
but definitely not before that not as long
as you're somewhere up on that mountain.
That tech surface is just too
big and just really prepare
for one hell of a mountaineering tour.
And, Robert I'm sure will
tell you in another session
or if we were in Singapore
a lot about mountaineering.
I cannot about mountaineering
though (laughing)
but Robert, please.
- So if you have any questions
about the mountaineering
of the CISO feel free
to reach out in Slido.
And we're happy to answer your questions.
But moving forward,
what are the next issues
that we need to tackle in terms of patches
and the like?
One of the most difficult
parts that we are seeing
is the technology lifecycle management,
because it's one of the biggest unsolved
challenges and complex
things in enterprises,
because of the size and the
complexity of the enterprise.
It can cause actually a lot of headache
to you if you don't
tackle these things right.
And if you don't do these things in order
to protect your environment.
We know that the time the
enterprise moves along
and the enterprise develops,
some things will remain
and you don't wanna touch
them because they're unstable
and they provide valuable
contribution to the business.
But I assure you that you
wanna pay the interest rate
of the technical debt
you're amassing over time.
So that is a question that
you need to ask yourself.
However, we strongly advise
you and this is also what our
experience has shown us.
It is better to pay up now
and tackle the things
at the very early stage
and look after decommissioning
and phasing out the old technologies,
reducing the attack surface
and reducing the likelihood
of attackers being successful.
So, in addition if you have
this lifecycle management,
if you are aware of what
you have in your enterprise,
you also have a certain
visibility and you are improving
the visibility in your
enterprise to see what assets
you have and to see what is going on
in your network and amongst your systems.
So, therefore technology
lifecycle management
is definitely an essential part.
So, our strong advice is
get rid of the old stuff,
move it out of the enterprise and prepare
some technology lifecycle
management plans.
Another thing that comes to our attention
over the past few months is definitely
the network segmentation part.
Now, this time for good.
I think even religion has told us now
that the earth is not flat any longer,
and so shouldn't be your network.
So you should definitely
make sure that your network
is not any longer a flat type of network.
That is something that
we have learned probably
in the past, but it's something definitely
which is not any more valid for present
and for the future.
Therefore, in recent
cases, micro segmentation
would have saved enterprises
in case of ransomware outbreaks.
If you have encapsulated those,
if you have have protected
the crown jewels yeah,
we're not gonna give you
another talk about the
crown jewel type of thing,
because you've already
heard about this quite often
but the network segmentation
is definitely something
that is for your business
and for protecting
your intellectual property,
your customer data
or your sales data.
Something that is
definitely here a key part
is when segmenting the network
or splitting the network
apart, to have some separated things
and to have some so
called Tier 0 environment
which is for your privileged accounts,
workstations and admin users.
It is definitely something
of your safe haven,
if you have an attack
if you have an outbreak
where you can move backwards
and start off there
to deploy some new, trusted environment.
Moving along the journey and talking
about privileged things
also comes into our mind
the handling of the privileged accounts.
But over the time, we have
seen the privileged accounts
are spread amongst the whole
enterprise for instance,
that some type of service
accounts running with domain
or admin privileges.
This is something definitely
attackers are looking after.
So therefore it is
essential part to separate
the privileged IDs from the user IDs.
Yeah, we're not gonna
do another tool talk,
but definitely it can help with tools
to circumvent these issues.
And if you have some budget constraints,
some self developed
wrappers and other things
can help you in order
to tackle this issue.
As we are now in the year 2020.
Definitely we cannot avoid
multi factor authentication
any longer for privileged accounts.
It is a so called must
that we need to establish.
Definitely we can.
It's a good argument also
to get rid of text messages
as the second factor if you've introduced
multi factor authentication.
But as long as you have a second factor
it definitely protects you.
And finally, when it
comes towards protection
of those privileged
accounts, it also makes sense
to enable those privileged
users with an own workstation,
or a ritualized workstation
to have some just in time
privileges in order to
avoid lateral movement
and to detect this lateral
movement amongst the enterprise.
So our house is on fire what
we have heard at the beginning,
but what do we do from now?
The things we have mentioned
and explained to you before,
try them at home and get
the freaking basics right!
We definitely didn't
tell you some new things
because these are things we
already heard in the past
but still, enterprises
don't apply the basic cyber
principles and basic cyber hygiene.
So applying the patches, fix
this network segmentation,
and clean up your privileged
accounts in reality,
in order to make sure you have
a safe and sound environment.
These things I said are not new.
We never did traditional
security in the past, right?
So we know all of the
things that we have to do.
So let's do them now.
And let's protect our
enterprise for safe business
in the future.
Thank you very much for your attention.
If you have any questions,
just drop us again,
a note in Slido and we
are happy to answer them.
Daniel, and I would like to
thank you for your attention.
And with this takeaway,
and with these highlights,
we hope that you have
the ability to strengthen
the security of your enterprise.
Thank you very much, and have a nice day.
- Thank you.