- Hello, and welcome
to Getting the Security
and Flexibility Balance Right
in a COVID-19 World.
If you're joining us live our speaker
is in the slide or chat discussion
answering your questions right now.
She'll also be participating in the live
Ask the Expert round table on this topic,
right after this session.
For audio video issues,
you can click the technical
support button below.
I'd now like to turn it
over to Magda Chelly,
for the presentation.
- Ladies and gentlemen thank you so much
for attending my talk today.
I will be discussing Getting the Security
and Flexibility Balance Right
in a COVID- 19 World,
where things are changing
and disrupting the way that security
is perceived and
processed and implemented.
So let me give you a
little bit more insight
about my experiences nowadays
working with various companies
across the world
and in particular in Asia Pacific.
But before that,
let me give you a little bit
more perspective about myself.
So, I am a telecommunication engineer
with a specialization in cyber security,
and I have been working
as a chief information security officer
for like I mentioned
a variety of companies
across different industries.
What I have as well noticed is that,
different perspectives
bring different questions.
And therefore please do not hesitate
to ask me any questions
like Casey mentioned.
You probably see and read nowadays
variety of news about cyber security,
and one of the main areas or approach
coming back from the general public
or your business stakeholders is,
that they might not understand
what exactly is happening
for the business nowadays
and how they can tackle those
particular new emerging risks,
knowing that they are not in our field
or they are not cyber
security professionals.
Within those questions,
might arise very simple ones,
like are the cyber attacks
increasing during COVID-19 pandemic?
Or, what other changes that my company
will actually be faced to
or faced towards within
risk again pandemic,
knowing that I needed to shift
in a digital transformation very quickly?
As part of Asia Pacific,
where I am familiar
with in terms of region,
I noticed that,
the digital transformation
that had been adopted by companies
is very much related to a sense of speed.
We need to go
and allow the productivity to continue
for our employees,
and very often,
that digital transformation is not driven
by let's say the regulatory requirements
or eventually by the cyber security team
involved from the
beginning of the project.
Therefore in particular within the certain
I would say environment like
nowadays with the COVID-19,
we see that need into going
in that transformation very quickly
and unknowingly raising
new emerging risks.
And as part of that,
I'm sure you're aware cyber
security professionals
with the emerging and
increasing cyber attacks
and as usual,
the weakest link is the human factor.
And with additional COVID-19 themed,
phishing attacks,
malware banks attacks,
and even fake social medias
as well as vishing attacks.
We see that our enterprise
attack vectors are increasing
and we do not have eventually
that much control over,
especially when we're talking for example
about vishing attacks.
And here, I would actually add one point
that I consider extremely important,
when I discuss this
with chief information security officers
as well from other organizations,
we have seen new policies mentioning that,
you know, passwords should
not rotate for example,
or that we change the way
that we literally have
our policies nowadays.
But if your employees
are working from home
and eventually working
from their own devices,
they are using those devices
to perform business activities,
and eventually even if you had
employed management in place,
you might still be exposed
to different risks in our loops.
And as such one of those scenario is,
and normally always
using the same password
using the passwords with them,
their social media accounts
and the same password with
their corporate accounts,
and you don't have control over that
because the employee has
the freedom to do that
and using especially their own devices.
So this is an example of scenarios
that definitely is increasing
within the COVID-19 pandemic.
But as such again,
I think there is a certain
level of perception
from the security professionals
that you have control,
because you would have
implemented certain controls
over people process and technology
that you'd reduced your risk.
You have your proper comfort zone
which you have been operating with
and you believe that that might still work
even if your employees
are working remotely.
Well yes, in a particular case,
but let's again,
go back to the fact that your employees
are working from anywhere
towards insecure networks
or even just working from
a different environment
that they will or have been used to.
As an example quarantining hotels
or quarantined in other
environments besides
or in addition of their own houses.
What they will do as a very simple example
is that they will use their email
to communicate with businesses,
to communicate with different stakeholders
including eventually cold clients.
And as one other risks, you know,
and I would say different
scenarios that happens
is that if the employee is
facing any technical challenges
by communicating through
the corporate email,
they will use their personal email
and this is again,
something that realistically happen
comparing to our comfort zone
where we think we have
our very good controls
in place across our environment
within the corporate environment.
We actually are not seeing
or not addressing those
new emerging risks.
That again, within the COVID-19
are increasing and growing.
What happens if your employees nowadays
are sending emails,
not only with confidential information
back to the customers
using their personal emails.
And when the slide that
you see on the screen
I'm just bringing up those simple examples
of COVID-19 themed attack.
And if you want to raise
awareness with the mere employees
which is again,
a risk that is increasing
nowadays with the COVID-19.
A simple newsletter bringing that example
will not be enough,
because of the example that I gave you.
They might use additional
channel of communication
in order to overcome any
technical difficulties as such,
let us say in accessing
the corporate resources
or eventually just the fact that
they are using a different laptop
or they newly joined your organization
and they do not have access
to the corporate email.
Having a perception of perfection
or thinking that you have a control
over your corporate environment nowadays,
is not any more effective.
And when I mentioned the effectiveness
or some examples of scenarios,
I was lucky to think as a
cyber security professional,
of the different perspectives
of business stakeholders,
because at the end
even if we as security professionals,
we would like to address
all the cyber risks properly
and address those risks come of course
by either treating them
or transferring them or accepting them.
We actually need to understand
that its still resides within
the business stakeholders,
as business decision makers
to take the right decision.
And usually their perspective
or their questions are different.
They questions might be
related to eventually,
how are they exposures,
but not exposures with them.
Okay, they are new technical risks,
but they wont like to
associate financial loss
to any new emerging risks
and what that might
mean today on business.
And the reality is that
we as cyber security professionals
we still do not know how
to address that problem.
So if our environment is changing,
and our corporate boundaries
are not any more present,
like we have seen previously.
We are not able to adapt to that
as quickly as the business change
with the digital transformation,
including something that is very new
for especially cyber
security professionals,
which is risk quantification's.
And then we try to bring that
as a very important key process,
and show how to ensure
that your business stakeholders
are able to address the new emerging risks
within the COVID-19 pandemic
and especially post COVID-19 pandemic,
because we will see a great shift
and you as cyber security
professional know that very well,
about how to translate that
into business risk
and how to ensure that you deliver
a continuous cyber risk
assessment when it comes
to shifting continuously
businesses provide,
especially with uncertain environment.
And when I say uncertain environment,
we actually are in very
particular scenario
in general for businesses.
We're now talking about,
what I would say in a
like, you know, event,
we're talking about a
continuously changing
uncertainty within the uncertainty.
We are unable to have very
clear visibility of when
and how the new coming
waves of COVID-19 pandemics
will affect our work,
will affect our environment.
And as a cyber security professional,
this means that we will have
waves of employees continuously
working from the office,
then will be asked to work again remotely
and then again will eventually
come back to the office,
and again, come back and work remotely.
What that means in particular,
is that, yeah, you perhaps know,
and you might think that
we have this boundaries,
we have the controls
that help us enable the corporate controls
across our environments
and that should be enough.
But I believe,
that we have still a very big gap.
Not only from the security perspective
with our business stakeholders
and how do we present our cyber risks,
but as well,
understanding the gap between
us cyber security professionals
and what the end users are doing
and what the end users are expecting
and in particular our employees.
Because whatever we implement nowadays,
we need to implement it
to ensure a certain
level of effectiveness.
And when we're talking
about effectiveness,
we're talking about,
our employees ensuring the right process,
our employees being aware
of the right security measures
that we have in place,
in our companies with our organizations.
And one of the very famous
I would say model around
risk quantification
is The FAIR Model.
And the factor analysis
of information risk
is the only international standard
that helps quantify the
information security
and operational risk,
which is again something
that I have very rarely seen
implemented by changing
information security officer.
So when it comes to ensuring
that quantification model,
let me tell you an example
of how it can be
extremely relevant for you
to help the business
migrate over an environment
that is raising uncertainty.
You have your risk register,
you have your risk
management process nowadays
implemented within your organization.
And you're addressing
those risks in a way,
for example following certain
international standards
making sure that you have
visibility of maturity
and eventually adding the
percentage of implementations
and using that as an important way
to report to your board,
to your business stakeholders,
to C level executives depending
of how you report nowadays.
However again, if the business
is within an environment
that is changing very quickly,
you might want to take
a different approach,
the quantification of risk might help you,
bringing up three or five
or even 10 risks, you know,
it was an extremely important
and critical for your business
helping to understand
what those scenarios are
bringing to the business
or how those scenarios are
impacting your business
and then clearly describing
that impact to your business.
So now your telling me what
I already knew Magda, right?
Because we're doing that already.
I am gonna show you some
examples for the COVID-19
and what factors or what criteria
you should be taking consideration.
Again, going back or going
out of your comfort zone
as a security professional,
and taking consideration
some business factors,
some regulatory requirements,
some shifting areas around
the risks within the COVID-19,
but as well as from the
compliance perspective
and privacy perspective as well.
Individuals and organizations
are fighting COVID-19
as I mentioned,
we would probably have different waves,
and that means,
different shifts across the organizations.
Not only having that visibility
about social distancing
that we have in certain countries nowadays
CROSS Asia Pacific.
We might continuously
have different arrangement
across working habits.
You're employees might face
different crises communications,
different travel restrictions,
especially if you operate
across different countries.
That means, that your remote
working controls nowadays
might need to adapt.
Again, imagining environment
where your employees are
going back a certain time
then going out of the office,
you still need to hire new employees.
The old employees on boarding,
my place, new risk
and therefore new challenges for you
as cyber security professionals.
Go out of your comfort zone,
where you have control
over your environment
because nowadays with evolving risks
that are changing,
you don't have any more that comfort
you're actually in need to build
different risk management process.
And that risk management process
need to take in
consideration and certainty
within the uncertainty.
As you have seen this model of, you know,
going into different shifts of risks,
I would add a different level of again,
things that eventually you are aware of
and we talk about shadow IT,
but the shadow IT goes beyond.
We are talking about
unsecured home networks.
We're talking about employees
working from quarantined entities
or environments like hotels.
And then here,
you will tell me,
"But Magda we have or we
are using virtual pilot
and that works.
Again, we have proper controls in place."
That's right I've seen choice.
And well, I will tell you,
"What will your employees do
if you're actually VPN
will not be allowed within
that particular unsecured network,
because the reality is,
that nowadays certain public networks,
WiFi networks in particular
within shared environments like hotels
or other entities do
not allow VPNs to work.
And therefor again,
you might know those kind of scenarios
but the scenarios are shifting.
The scenarios that you need
to rake in consideration
will need you a cyber
security professional
to have visibility of the major high
and critical risk scenarios,
taking in consideration,
the shift and risk profile of companies.
The risk profiles as I mentioned,
as an example,
traditional VPNs not working
for your employees to connect,
raising a different way of working.
Your employees might be exposed
to additional network risks
or just cyber risk,
but that was only challenge
that I want you to think about.
The other challenge in
this particular region
is new privacy law,
new laws sorry,
that include the fact that companies
will need to implement
additional technology
to monitor social distancing regulations
or requirements within the regulation.
And as such,
one really interesting
is the fact that in some countries
we might not only have new privacy laws
including data breach regulations,
which this is not
something that is changing
but we might have again,
laws that it needs or required
to implement CCTV cameras,
every where within your
organizations environment.
And while we are talking about that,
if your organization is
implementing new technology,
we as cyber security professionals
we know that this requires
a risk assessment,
this requires some controls
and we probably are taking
that into already consideration
within the traditional
boundaries of our business.
But, if your business
nowadays operate in countries
where those laws are enacted
or enabled very quickly.
You might find yourself,
operating in an environment
where your business stakeholders
took the decision to implement CCTVs
across the business organization,
without that particular assessment
and without knowing
of how your cyber security controls
are efficient to implement.
So here, as you can see,
I'm trying to describe
a way of how to ensure
that you have visibility
of new emerging risks
with the current challenging environment.
So again, the funny thing about the slide
is out of your comfort zone
and try and focus on
quantifying risk across
the new emerging, new scenarios,
that might relate to uncertainty.
When I mean uncertainty,
it might be three, five 10 new risks,
within the environment.
And those risks are not taking
the traditional business perimeter
in consideration anymore.
We are actually working nowadays
without boundaries anymore.
So what I'm adding nowadays again,
I'm adding for you a
different perspective.
Try to ensure that you work very closely
with the other teams
in collaboration with the privacy team,
with the compliance team.
And don't feel that we as
cyber security professionals
we like that kind of collaboration
and ensure that you have
a proper communication
with your employees in general.
As a cyber security professional,
and especially as a chief
information security professional,
especially when you're global reach,
ensure that you're still are reachable,
because your new emergency lines,
not only will require you to take
in consideration this very particular
new risks you now use
that you will need to quantify,
but as well as that
you've taken consideration
of reality versus your perfect, you know,
a simulation of your control today
that you have implemented
within the traditional
approaches of cyber security.
I mentioned the fact
that certain environment
might not allow your VPN to work,
your VPN might face technical issues
and therefore make ways to situations
where your employees will use
additional channels of communication
including their personal emails
to communicate with clients,
to communicate with colleagues.
That particular true scenarios
what might raise risks like data loss.
And again, please feel
free to ask me questions
I'm available live.
So do raise some of the challenge
that you're facing,
I'm more than happy to address them.
The other of course approach is,
or risks that we see is,
raising risks where
COVID-19 themed attacks
which you're familiar with.
But again, if your employees are using,
bring your own device
then actually might not
have the same controls.
You might have say saying some
additional business interruptions
because they just on boarding,
they are new.
So, very important new
cyber risk assessment
is go out of your comfort zone
and go again,
I'm repeating myself
that's very important.
Have your top three, five, 10
new emerging cyber risks know use
and then quantify them.
Now you tell me how do we
quantify such new emerging risk
if you don't have data related to those?
Because of course,
when we're talking about quantification,
we need to take in
consideration proper data,
will ensure that we have a certain model.
We're not talking about,
"Oh, we will have an attack
from cyber security perspective.
This is how I see it
will impact the business,
approximately I might impact the business
with 10 million of loss if that happens."
No again, try to ensure
that you work closely
with the privacy team
or a compliance team
and have a visibility of how,
your business might be interrupted.
And when I say interruption here,
I forgot to mention that
you need to work as well
very closely with your IT team.
And if you work with your IT team,
eventually you might understand
a little bit further
how long it takes to
recover your business,
if that happens.
And if you have a clarity
about your business
or your cyber risk scenarios
then you decide,
very clearly what are your factors
that you will take in consideration
to molder your business
risk quantification.
Then, only then,
you will be able to very clearly
understand the business impact
especially during the COVID-19 pandemic
and especially after
and post the pandemic,
because again, we're not
talking about one way,
we're talking about an environment
that is going through
different ways or uncertainty
and therefore we assign
the strict previsions
we need to adapt to those risks.
And as I am very conscious of time.
I don't have more than 13 minutes.
I would like to again,
to focus on data,
which is very important
nowadays and human.
As cyber security professionals
we need to really
increase our capabilities
within those two points
not any more boundaries
or traditional corporate environment.
And we need to understand
that if we don't communicate
with our employees,
we are not effective
because they will always find way
to ensure that they work
and therefore they perform
their business activities,
even beyond your boundaries,
beyond your traditional
channels of communication.
That's the reality.
And I believe we still lack that
actually consideration with
our risk management process
that is taking traditional approach.
So my point today for you is,
again, ensure data driven spirited.
Try to focus on the data
and the human with a
zero trust in the future,
that obey the approach, you know,
anymore taking the traditional boundaries,
but also a continuous
cyber risk assessment
and that continuous cyber risk assessment
is not by having a very long risk register
with technical scenarios.
Just try to ensure that
you have continuously review
three, five, eventually 10,
and 10 I think is already long,
risks scenarios that you try to quantify.
When you quantify those
particular risk scenarios,
you take in consideration,
factors that are important
for the business,
privacy regulation or regulatory fines,
licenses for your business,
you work very closely with
different departments,
business interactions
when you work with your IT
and have visibility of
how long they will take
to actually recover from
certain business interruption.
So have visibility.
And of course that visibility,
not only closes the gap,
with reality of your
employees working differently,
but as well helps you to communicate
with your business stakeholders,
being realistic and bringing some dollars
to your cyber risk scenarios.
Well done, just approximative data
that is related to...
Oh, I think we have seen this data bridge
or the cyber attack we'll
leave in our industry
for the particular loss.
No, if you're taking
consideration something
that is realistic for your business,
it will speak to a business stakeholder
and they will understand,
they will understand that the employees
will find ways to work differently,
where you as a business need
to take in consideration
different factors and that might lead
to certain level of again,
losses indoors to the business.
So as a new approach,
again, taking a data-centric approach
is extremely important.
Improving authentication in
communication with the users,
no matter what you actually have in place,
remember your end users might
be your cyber champions.
Stop, remember that,
that education training is very important.
Having something that is
just send over newsletters
every week, every quarter
is absolutely inefficient.
I have worked with organizations
where the employees don't even know
that there was chief information security
or a security department because of that.
Make sure that you are reachable, how?
By first, next week identifying
your new emergent risks
and making sure that you
have the right controls
for those emerging risks
that are beyond your traditional way
of doing cyber security.
They do not have any more perimeter,
they are raising realistic risks
compared to whatever you
thought was previously.
In the next three months,
ensure that your approach
is taking in consideration
and non-perimeter based security.
As well, with not only a data driven,
as I mentioned in those are big concepts,
but practical approach,
focus of a example on a data
loss prevention strategy,
rather than just ensuring some
tools for a VPN connectivity,
because eventually, as I mentioned,
if your organization
working within countries
where your employees are working
from quarantined environments
they might eventually
face technical issues.
So how do you ensure that your trust of?
But again here,
ensure that you talk
or discuss with your employees
in a way that they understand,
in a way that they feel you're reachable.
And then within the next six month,
have a cyber security strategy
that takes in consideration again,
data and human.
Humans are the weakest link,
but we don't change it.
We keep on talking about without
really taking the actions
and actions are two in particular.
Have a simple communication,
coming back to fundamentals,
even by explaining very,
very, very essential things.
And two, talk with the employees
as some security professionals,
because if they don't
feel they can reach you,
nothing will change,
it is a cultural change.
And that's where I would
like you to remember.
So thank you very much.
I'm conscious about time.
I hope you learned something
that is very viable for you today.
Please reach out with questions.
I'm happy to answer.
And again, one last point,
go out of your comfort zone
because we are changing,
we're not anymore within our perimeter
or our traditional environment.
Thank you again,
this was Magda Chelly from Singapore.