- Hello and welcome,
to Hacking People's
Mind When Threat Actors
Master Social Engineering.
For audio or video issues,
please click the technical
support button below.
I'd now like to turn it over to Tal Dawson
and Donna Peleg for the presentation.
- Okay, hi everyone.
So, welcome join me
into our session today.
So what are we gonna discuss
about are a couple of recent things,
such as the recent changes
in the digital world,
this is all part of what
we're just seeing across
the entire world is part
of the COVID-19 dynamic.
We're also gonna see
how threats are changed
and how they adapted to the
recent pandemic that's going on.
Usually coming from the
social engineering aspect,
we gonna go on a small deep dive into few
and different facts and of
course by the end of the session,
we're gonna present you
with some countermeasure
and useful tips on how
to protect yourself.
So, going right in, we will cover threats
from different types of scopes.
We gonna go into the web type of threats
and we're gonna touch on
desktop network RAT malware
of course, Phishing and Smishing
and how spoofing is part of this.
Later on, we gonna touch
on the mobile domain,
when we gonna discuss one
of the most prominent cracks
in that space, which is
the Mobile Overlay Malware.
This is a really advanced
and we have a really
cool demo to show you.
This is relevant for the
Android mobile operating system.
And of course, we gonna touch
on how social engineering
which is our major theme
in that presentation
is being involved in any
of digital transformation.
So digital transformation is accelerated
and why it's accelerated?
Well COVID-19 was is actually
one of the major reasons
of why a lot of businesses these days
are going into digital,
right, even businesses that
didn't have this before,
they're just going in adding it,
whether it's like in these
domains you're seeing here
in this slide where like,
insurance, telecommunication,
transportation, online banking
was already there, right,
but it's just expanding and
going more and more difficult.
So we're gonna see how
threats are being impacted.
So when we see rise in threats
so we see them usually happening,
as I said, part of the
digital transformation
and when decelerating
and threats are just important targets.
Of course when there is a holiday season
and what we see just right
before it was a major rise
in threats targeting,
usually if we're talking about fraud
and users around the world,
we see a major increase that as well.
And, of course, the COVID-19
when everyone was working
from home right now,
it's one of the major
reasons of the attacks
that being, you know, rotor,
and that they actually adopted
this to this time.
So how COVID-19 changed
the threat landscape?
So first of all, as I said,
the digital transformation
basically accelerated and
now a lot of new businesses
are opening up digitally,
which means that more
of more brand X doors
are on one death and delivery.
And once there are a lot
of unsecured businesses,
for example, when a business
just, you know, go offline,
with a new platform new online platform.
These businesses made it so fast
that they didn't have the right
security measures in place.
So a lot of track tours are
knowing that and they're looking
for these targets, these
new targets are you know,
to actually placing their targets
but what else we know
is that a lot of people
are now working from home,
actually increased the unmanaged
the amount of unmanaged corporate devices
that are now can be found worldwide,
whether there was a business
before COVID-19 that you know,
came to the office and just use
their own corporate protected,
let's put it this way.
Devices these days, a lot of
businesses tell their employees
okay use their own computers.
And this is a serious, you
know, an open up for, you know,
for threats basically,
and vulnerabilities of course to go over
these unmanaged computers
designed to manage devices
and just target them
and of course, due to those two reasons,
what we see is the attacks in magnitude.
I mean, the magnitude of
these attacks of course,
is just rising and rising,
especially when we saw
we were in the first wave
of COVID-19 around the world.
And of course, we're
gonna see in that session,
how the attacks are
actually adapted themselves
to these time, so I'm not
gonna stay here too much.
And we'll just go deep diving into this.
So I wonna start with Desktop Malware.
So in Desktop Malware we're gonna discuss
the top noticed threats
that we're seeing recently,
usually coming from our
perspective from our labs.
So the first one is Remote Access Trojans,
then we're gonna touch on a little bit
about Information Stealers
because they're really popular.
And we gonna end up with Banking Trojans,
which not going in.
So what we see in the Remote
Access Trojans domain,
we have let's put it this way.
Three types of tools that can be gathered
as part of a taxing deathmatch.
First one is tools that can be purchased
on dark web for example.
There are plenty of commercial tools
commercial remote access Trojans
are being sold over there.
They are the ones who have been modified
for malicious purposes as
part of their legitimate use,
for example, a malicious interviewer
or a malicious you know,
an abused interviewer
that was incorporated
into the usage of malware.
And of course, there is always
your social engineering attacks
that involves remote access
tools legitimate tools
such as TeamViewer, LogMeIn,
and all the ones you're know
from your day to day.
So, I'm gonna take one example
the one I said the first one
I gave with a commercial fun
when we see an organized threat actors
being leveraging the
tools into their course
which, in our domain in our space,
what we see them is they
wonna get information
and of course they wonna get money.
So how are they operating,
they actually being leverage techniques
coming from advanced
persistent threat groups.
And these groups of activating
the remote access Trojan,
so they're starting with
a reconnaissance phase
when they're looking for prey,
someone that will be easier to you know,
loot for and get into the organization.
Usually they will send
some kind of an attachment
with malicious macro, download threat,
from that phase, they will, you know,
look up on their lateral movement phase
when they're gonna
actually go to the person
who holds the, you know, for example,
the key for the money of the organization
usually a financial officer
or financial analyst
has a you know, the
credentials and the ability
to login into business
account over the business
logging financial
accounts over the weather,
online banking, of course and
from that point the fraudster
will start to do is steal
espionage email try to monitor
for sometimes it could even take weeks
until he finds the right target.
And from that point,
it can be used by social
engineering techniques
to do many types of attack backwards,
whether it's to take out the money itself,
or conducting a business
email compromise, or whatnot.
So this is one thing we're seeing,
and we're seeing an
increasing these attacks.
For example, here we have
stats from our lab of Nanocore
Nanocore is very popular
during these times.
And we see the rise in
infection during around COVID-19
you know, was just
dropped within the world
taking effect in a other
than that, you see also
threats in social engineering
attempts to deliver them,
such as infrastructure as of course
that join the RAT session
that we just covered
of different forms coming
from the wolf organization
coming from the SBA is there just think
they are gonna send some stimulus attack.
But this is basically
gonna be some practice
in the attachment, as I said,
embedded in a Microsoft Office document
as a malicious macro, and
there's the modern board.
Now I'm gonna touch like
another popular backdoor,
which is Remote Overlay.
Remote Overlays the stop case
of attacks that we're seeing
as part of the remote
access plastic Trojans,
as I just lay, what this is different.
It's basically what you're gonna see
in the short video that has here,
that in this attack what we know
is that the attacker will
show after infections phase,
the attacker will show
different screens to the user
in order to steal second
factor authentication,
one thing, password
and some other manners,
you know, multi factor authentication.
So here we have in this demo,
we have a reconstruction
of a Remote Overlay malware
that we did in our lab.
On the left side of the screen,
you see the fraudsters screen.
On the right side of the screen
you see the victim screen.
And in this in the right
side, you see some fake screen
that's actually blocking
the user screen telling him
that there is some kind of an
update that's been going on.
In that case, our victim
logged in into some kind
of a cryptocurrency
platform that he you know,
just wonna check out his
balance and stuff maybe money,
but this time, the fraudster
are actually taking control.
So you can see on the
left side of the screen,
there was a planning options
that we have reconstructed,
and you can send the victim,
many types of second
factor authentication,
that the fraudster just customized.
So that's that that can be
done in order to, you know,
ask the fraudsters for
different types of NFA
what's you're seeing
now in the current slide
is an abusing zoom meetings,
we noticed in the spirit of the COVID-19
zoom is probably most
one of the most popular
meeting applications worldwide.
So here in that case, we have
research an interesting case
of remote overlay network,
which the actual malware
doing DLL hijacking.
DLL hijacking is unique when you can load
and take an original binary for example,
in this example, the
original binary was zoom
and loaded With a malicious DLL file
that actually being loaded
up with the malware itself,
that's causing a lot of
other security vendors,
anti viruses and so on to just, you know,
not being able to remove
that threat or mitigate it.
Really, though that's this is
one of the popular techniques
that we're seeing worldwide,
usually being used with a sort of malware
it's not limited
to this specific attack
something with this.
Moving on, before I wrap up this session,
I mean, this section employ,
we see another attacks
being abused and delivered,
COVID-19 with social
with advanced social engineering effects.
These are the notorious examples of things
that we just uncovered a few months ago
as it was returned and made a comeback.
We didn't see this malware,
hacked or operated things
2017 and it just came
back with a tax bill.
So carry the tax was usually
Australia, New Zealand
was the target that we saw.
And Emotet when we actually
were able to deliver
to be able to actually spot
attacks that were delivered
in Japan using a customized
social engineering attack,
we also were the ones
who report that well,
so these actors that are spreading
and continue to spreading
financial malware,
these ones are basically still operating.
There's still using different types
of social engineering attacks,
usually around these times
around these pandemic
and they're doing is pretty
much let's put it this way well
for their own profit.
So from this point, I'm gonna
hand over to Donna Peleg,
which she can go into continuing cover.
- Okay, thank you Tal.
So I'm going to discuss
some phishing threats
and mobile threats and
then we'll, you know,
summarize and run out the session.
So, if you talk about, you know phishing,
it's something that is a very old threat,
and people thought it would go away,
but it's here to stay.
And he talked about social engineering
and let's say social engineering kingdom,
then phishing is this kingdoms King.
So what we see is basically,
first of all arise in phishing sites,
we see a growth in top level
domain with registrations,
so it used to be just.org.com.
Now you have dots TV dot space,
very unique TLDs top level domains.
We used to tell our grandparents
that in order to stay safe
from phishing sites, you
need to base basically
have the padlock in the browser,
you need to have the HTTPS
at the beginning of the URL.
And so basically, now we know
that it's almost no longer,
you know, even relevant
fraudsters and attackers
are starting to use SSL certificates
in their phishing sites.
So it's not necessarily
means that the site
is the communication is safe.
We also see a boost in phishing kits
with facial randomization folder.
So what it means is they just
create one phishing attack
they hack into just one legitimate domain,
and they plan their special
key that actually changes
its folder at the end of
the URL changes the folder
and creates a lot of unique URLs.
And we're talking about
a significant amount,
such as, you know, thousands
of URLs just from one
phishing attack and
this is basically going
and staying under the radar,
and is able to overcome
a lot of security measures and products.
And of course, we're also
seeing the statistics
of the previous quarters.
What we see and what we
expect to see basically
is that we still don't have the
current quarters statistics.
So this is 2020 queue and
we are definitely expecting
to see a significant
rise due to this pandemic
and this period that we are currently on.
So, if we're talking about the pandemic,
we say that people are
leveraging everything
that is going on around right now.
So people are around the
world it's a global issue
are very very you know,
they have an existence
existing a general fear
and financial concerns
that they don't know when and if things
will actually figure out
and they are also utilizing
the financial fear of people
if they going to come out
of this very tough situation,
so actors are basically trying to imitate
first of all governmental
sites that offer relief,
money relief, which is of course fake,
they are also imitating
online banking sites,
which is something that we
already know and familiar with,
but now they already started targeting,
working from home themed
sites and platforms,
and you're gonna see
some of that right now.
So if we talked about the
financial part, and here it is,
this is an example of the
UK Government relief page
is of course completely fake.
And you just they asked for the credential
so they can pay back your
money and people fall
for that because they are very scared
and are very concerned with
their financial situation.
We are also seeing a
lot of online sessions
or online meetings applications
are being targeted.
So for example, Cisco
Webex is very much used,
and it's very common.
And we see here an email advising
that there are some vulnerabilities
and you should update
it and then of course,
a completely fake and phishing page
to enter your credentials there.
So here you're also entering
your organization credentials.
It's not just your own
private credentials,
and they can infiltrate your
organization's using that.
Another thing that you're seeing
is in phishing attacks targeting
the organizational systems,
so here it is they're sending an email
allegedly from the IT of the company.
This is from the help desk
but of course completely fake
advising to logging to the staff portal
also way to get to your
organizational credentials,
and here it is this is, I
think the most interesting one.
So here they are talking about the fact
that we have lost the
colleague to the deadly virus,
which is of course completely fake,
but they're trying to do
whatever they can to scare people
and you know, make them
fear for their lives.
And this is social engineering
and it's best Of course,
and then they are
targeting 360s environment
that is also for to phish the
organizational credentials.
Once you enter your credentials,
you're being passed on to this page.
And of course, you're not being lumped
into your organization's system.
Now we're also seeing increase
in Smishing and Vishing attacks,
so smishing is basically phishing
attacks delivered by SMS.
And of course, here we also see
how they were affected by the pandemic.
Here it is, the Red Cross
is providing surgical masks
and of course, completely fake as well,
breaking news, banks may be closing.
So again scaring tactics.
And also here again,
they are promised to help
their citizens to to combat
the COVID-19 results.
So this is about the phishing,
I'm going to move on
to the Mobile Threats.
And the main one, the
star of the mobile malware
will be the Overlay Malware for mobile.
And the thing is that
everyone is are vulnerable.
So if you have an app,
you're vulnerable to being
targeted by this mobile,
and it's a global thing, very common.
And we see that these are
the main or several families
and these are the main one
that are targeting around the world.
I'm going to show you just a short demo
of ExoBot which is one family
of the mobile overlay malware.
So this is what you're going
to see on the victims end.
And what you see here is that he's opening
the flash application of course,
there is no flash player for Android.
So this is a fake application
and it basically what it should do
is just a malware to run on that device.
So what will happen is that
the malware will monitor
for the victims actions, and
he will wait that the victim
will open a targeted application.
Here in this demo, we're using
the cryptocurrency platform Coinbase.
Now you see a window has just came up
and it's covering the
legitimate application.
This is a fake window, asking
for the victims credentials.
And this actor is really smart
and he's taking into consideration
that we're all human and that
we sometimes make mistakes.
So what he will do is, he
will ask the victim to enter
his credentials twice, here it is,
it will basically shake it and advise
that the credentials are incorrect,
and there are typos there,
and the user will enter
his credentials once again.
So for every victim, he has
two instances of credentials,
just to make sure that the
perfect fraud is being conducted
and he just get away with it.
So this is what we see on the victims end
and as soon as he enters his credentials,
the overlay screen disappears,
and the malware is just wrapped up
and now you see you're able
to see that legitimate app.
So moving on, let's talk
about how it looks like
from the actors perspective.
So of course, for every malware,
there is a command and control panel
to be able to see what
the actor has obtained
and who fell for his attack.
So this is the CNC one of the malware.
And I'm just trying to present that.
Okay, so this is the login screen.
So if you have seen it
somewhere along the way
old command and control panels,
you know that this is a
very much advanced one,
it's very unique, it looks really good.
The previous one when,
if you ever seen one
looks pretty bad.
So they are getting more
and more sophisticated
and up to date and the
design looks really good.
And here it is project news.
Once you're logged in, of course,
this was already constructed
in our lab by our researchers.
So you have project news,
which is updates and it's really cool.
You have statistics divided by country
and language and tags and whatnot.
And, you know, you can even
make a KPI presentation
for your boss.
So which is the actor
itself, but it's really good.
It provides a lot of
information here you can see
all the common applications
that are installed
on the victims of your malware,
so you can know what are
the most common applications
that are installed and that
you should maybe imitate
or consider for your next attack.
Here you can see all the applications
that the malware is targeting.
And so today, you don't need
to know how the app looks like
you don't need to know
how to create an app
or anything like that.
You just need the money to
purchase the correct kit
that will provide you the option
to just tick the checkbox
on whatever application
you want to target.
And there it is, everything is ready.
So you have in the screen
all the overlay screens,
the applications that they are targeting
the credentials that they
are asking for, pretty good.
And here you can see the Bot details.
So bot details is actually
the victim details
and whatever victims that
fell for this attack.
You can see all of these details here.
It's really cool.
You can see he's platforms
the versions that he's using
consider things here.
And of course, you can see the credentials
that he has submitted so you can use them.
Another cool thing is
that you don't just get
the credentials and steal them,
you can also bypass the
two FA the two FA stage.
So the OTP, the one time
passcode and all that.
So what they actually do is
they intercept the text message
that is being sent to the user.
So once they get the credentials
and they obtain them,
they try to log in on their end,
the actor is trying to login on his end
to the legitimize application.
And then an SMS is sent
to the legitimate person
and the victim for you know,
to make sure that is
the legitimate person.
So what he can do is basically
he can control his device,
and you can lock his screen
and actually present
him this Android updates
completely fake screen
and the user is not aware
that's even got a text message.
You can use this device the
actor can use the user's device
and then delete it and there
it is the perfect fraud,
got the credentials data
to FA and make that frauds
and finished that.
So moving on, we talked
about COVID-19 changes
and we know that there
were a lot of threats
that are, they were being used before
but they have now advanced
and again taking advantage
of this fear and
everything is going around.
So we see a lot of ways to get out
graduate of Coronavirus
and stuff like that people
are falling for that course.
And one thing we see is
the Ginp Mobile Malware
that actually started
as just an SMS stealer
and has now advanced to target
a lot of banking applications
is basically reusing Anubis
code that that leaked earlier
this year, and now has the
capabilities of malware overlay
and additional more and
we're going to show you
what it looks like.
So they are actually trying to sell us
that this is an app that
will help them identify
who has the Coronavirus around them.
So if you can just pay a small amount,
and we will let you know
who was infected around you,
of course completely fake,
you enter your credit card credentials.
And there it is, they
just got your credentials,
and this is not the amount
that you're actually
going to lose, you're gonna
lose a significant more amount,
now that they can commit
the account takeover.
So we talked about all these threats
and everything looks really really scary.
But we can do a lot of
things to address that.
So one thing is to leverage
AI solutions and mechanism.
So if we talk about AI in
a really high level manner,
these are a lot of mechanisms
and engines that we can teach.
So for example, in this
slide, you can see the apples,
you provide the engine, the
apples and you tell them
these are apples.
So you teach that and then this machine
or this environment can identify
the next apple in line because
it's now familiar with that.
So this is a very high level of course.
But now let's talk about
how you can actually use
that to check out all the threats
that we talked about, or
at least some of them.
So for example, we talked
about Remote Access Attacks.
And we know for a fact that
you know, remote access,
the mouse movements will be
delayed, there is a short delay.
So for example, here, if
you take a look to the left,
you can see a regular mouse movement
or regular computer what it looks like
everything is very,
looks like almost a line,
very crowded lets go this way.
And if you look to the right,
you can see that the dots
are really not connected.
There is a significant delay
between the mouse movements
and this is one indication
that this is the person
that is using a different machine
or reusing a remote access
to the legitimate person.
Another thing you can do with AI
is you can actually compare
the code of phishing attacks
and see or potential phishing attacks
and see there, if there are things
that are you know, raising any flags.
So for example, this is a
hijacked website to the right,
this is the domain and on this domain,
you have the left the page to the left,
which is the full attack targeting
a significant targeted organization.
So, you can actually
understand that these themes
are very not related at all.
And if you have a legitimate
general site, you know,
that the theme will be very, very similar.
Another thing we can do is identify usage
of legitimate logos
so you can identify that
and that's, you know,
just the tip of the iceberg.
So if we talk about what we need to apply,
so for the next week,
you should start looking
for the blind spots
in your security process
and existing solutions.
There must be some of them and
you just need to take a look
and you know, do some brainstorming.
In the first three months
of this presentation,
you should assess the
threats of your organization
is likely to experience
and financial losses,
define a protection strategy
that will reduce cost
and friction to your clients,
you can, you know, get some
help from external companies
and services that's also really good to do
and within the six months,
you should select a seamless
omnichannel solution
based on AI and machine
learning with combination
of customized jurisdiction
rules of security protection.
So with the omnichannel here
is really a major thing.
We need to make sure that
the user journey in total
is you know, we are aware of
that and we will make sure
that we need to identify
this is the correct process
that is being done and no
one is trying to tackle that.
Another thing is just
to continue to assess
the average changing threat
landscape and associated risk
as you see it's constantly changing,
and we need to make sure
that we are up to speed
and are protecting our
employees and clients
and someone else.
So, I'm gonna wrap up right now.
This is our recommendations
and thank you for your time.