- [Announcer] Thank you special,
one of a kind, we agree,
the way you pursue your digital
ambitions is unique to you.
And so is your appetite for digital risk.
Whether you're hyper-connected
your ecosystem,
empowering a distributed workforce,
rapidly leveraging cloud, IOT, AI,
or other new technologies.
RSA is here to help
you manage digital risk
your way at every stage of your journey.
So go ahead be you.
- Hello and welcome to
Intelligence Sharing
for Critical Infrastructure Resiliency.
If you're joining us live,
our speaker is in the Slido discussion,
answering your questions right now.
For audio technical issues,
you can click the technical
support button below.
I'd now like to turn it over to John Lee
for the presentation.
- Hi, good morning from Singapore.
Today, My part will be
on information sharing
and how we can use it
to increase the resilience of
our critical infrastructure.
As we know, we live in a
digital connected world
and also amid suspend dynamics.
We also share our information
in our daily lives,
and in business as well.
So governments and military have done so
for the longest time.
So intelligence sharing is crucial.
It helps us to confirm our hypothesis
and act in a certain manner
that we can protect our interests
and further our objectives.
So there are three topics I like to cover.
I will start with operational technology
and explain why this is
important to ensure its security.
Next, I'll talk about the
importance of using best practices
and a structured approach to
secure operational technology
and ending of a case discussion
on information and intelligence sharing.
So operational technology
as defined by Ghana.
These are the hardware and software
that the techs have caused a
change to the direct monitoring
and control of physical
devices, processes,
and events in the enterprise.
They keep our industrial
processes from running,
such as (indistinct) and power
stations, smart factories,
building automation, systems,
oil and gas installations,
healthcare, transportation,
our baggage handling
systems at the airport,
water treatment plants, and many more.
OT or operational
technology is the technology
that interfaces with our physical world.
And that includes ICS or
Industrial Control Systems,
Supervisory Control and
Data Acquisition or SCADA
and distributed control systems.
Now ICS comprises of computers,
both mechanical electrical
devices that perform automated
or send automated control
of equipment in industries.
And these are used by
critical infrastructure
to control its operations.
ICS have embedded cyber
devices that operate
the industrial processes.
So example, a boiler as a sensor
that controls the temperature
to prevent overheating in the plant.
So the sensor is linked
to a computing device
for monitoring and control.
So at the moment it takes
a rise in temperature,
you will take steps.
The safety systems will
turn off the boiler.
So another example of
operational technology
is our ships at sea, where
before the navigation
was using manual chats.
But now GPS electronic charts are used
to control the navigation
or the route of the ships.
So therefore it cannot be overemphasized
this extreme importance
of critical infrastructure
that they keep on going
as they provide services to the country,
our industry that feeds our economy
and ensure that our daily lives continue
to have the basic needs.
So the impact of a breach
to critical infrastructure
can disrupt our lives
and cause physical harm
to our citizens and impact
our financial systems
and the economy.
So this is a diagram of
the interconnected world
in Industrial Control Systems.
So in the seventies and eighties,
ICS or industrial control
systems are at get,
they are not connected to the internet.
That's you don't find a
cyber breach that often.
So a security breaches
are to physical means.
OT systems, that back
then were built to be safe
and reliable with the
required functionality.
But we are seeing more
and more interconnectivity
from the 1990s.
So with the integration of IT components,
this allows the ICS or industrial devices
to leverage software, to drive
data collection and analysis
resulting in smarter machines.
But the flip side is that
vulnerabilities are introduced.
Malicious actors can use the ID network
to gain access to critical OT assets.
Security was not a concern in the past
due to the separation of
the ID and OT network,
but it has become an
increasing concern now
because of the numerous
breaches that have happened
in the last few years,
in the last 10 years.
So in 2014, a German
Steel Mill, a cyber attack
or cookware adversaries
use spear phishing tactics
to capture user credentials.
So the captured credentials was used
to connect to the OT network
to the business or IT systems.
So massive damage was caused
resulting in the blast
furnace being shut down.
So some of the attacks on
critical infrastructure,
they include the Iranian Nuclear Plant
that was infected by a malware
that specifically targeted
a brand of equipment
that was being used by the facility.
And that impact was that PLC's
and connected centrifuges
were destroyed by setting
back their nuclear program.
So another example in 2012,
a targeted malware was used in an attack
on the Saudi National Oil Company.
The wiper malware, infected
30,000 workstations
and deleted the files rendering
the workstations nonfunctional.
So another target included
Ukrainian Power Grid
happened in 2015, spear
phishing emails was used
to load the malicious payload
known as the black energy malware.
The SCADA system was compromised
and IT infrastructure
systems was destroyed
that by impacting more than 200,000 homes
who were left without any electricity.
So imagine if that happened in our country
so that will have a
disastrous consequences.
So in 2016, another blackout
occurred in the same country
likely to be caused by
the same perpetrators.
So another example in 2017,
that impacts safety
instrumentation systems
of a Saudi Petrochemical
Plant, which was the target.
And that caused the plant to shut down.
So that hackers are learning
and adapting their methods
to target critical infrastructure.
They are using sophisticated
methods and tools.
According to MITRE,
there are 94 APT groups
that were largely responsible
for all the high profile attacks.
There was an alert recently
this year by the Cybersecurity
and Infrastructure
Security Agency, or CISA
about Natural Gas Facility in the U.S.
that was hit by ransomware.
The delivery of the payload
was though an attachment
from a spear phishing email.
So the ransomware payload
costs a loss of availability
on the OT assets such as the HMI,
Historian, Polling Servers.
As the data, the OT
network could not be read
or aggregated from these devices.
It led to a loss of visibility
by the human operators.
So this led to a two day
shutdown of the plant.
So another example of a tech
on critical infrastructure,
Israel Water Facilities suffered
a cyber attack this April.
So six plants were targeted.
Data was wipe out, and one
of the plant had to shut down
because the pump was compromised.
So the danger here is if the adversary
could compromise the systems
that control the level of
chlorine added to the water,
it could let the poisoning
of the consumers.
So cyber attacks on
critical infrastructure
is one of the means that
nation state actors,
they will use this to soften the target
and pave the way for further
attacks that may follow.
So in a survey by
Ponemon Institute in 2019
out of 701 respondents.
So OT, cybersecurity is lagging behind
its enterprise ID counterpart.
90% have suffered at least one
attack in the past two years,
60% are concerned that an attack
against the infrastructure
would have huge impact of operations.
And 62% mentioned a set
identification, both OT, and IT
is important.
So OT asses are crucial,
and its protection
needs to be prioritized.
80% felt that sharing threat
intelligence is important
as this will help increase resiliency.
So I'm going to cover this model,
the Cyber Security Maturity Model
from the department of energy.
So given the vulnerabilities
that we've just heard
and the maturity level OT operators,
which is lagging behind the enterprise IT.
The very first step we need to do is
to understand the areas that organization,
your organization needs to focus on
to protect the infrastructure.
So objective of using this
model is to do an assessment,
to identify the current
state of the OT security
and the gap will be the difference between
where you need to be
and its current state.
So in order to achieve that future state,
you need to have the capabilities
and these are defined using the
model to do your assessment.
And the value of such
a model is a framework
that many models out there.
So one of the benefits of using this model
is sharing of best
practices and information.
You can benchmark against
other organizations
within your sector
strengthening your
organization capabilities
with the assessment.
You know the areas that
are weak and managing risks
by prioritizing areas
that you need to focus on
in order to achieve your future state.
So the assessment is done and involves
evaluating 10 domains.
So the domains presented
on the left hand side,
risk management, asset
change and configuration,
identity and access control,
threat and authority management,
situational awareness,
event and incident response,
supply chain, the dependencies,
workforce management,
cybersecurity architecture
and cybersecurity program management.
So in the assessment each of
the domains where objectives
and practices related to the objectives.
So the evaluation or assessment
will be on the practices
that are currently being
performed in the organization.
So the practice will determine
the current maturity indicator level
for each objective within the domain.
So for example, threat
authority domain objective two
has given their, a practice
D is being performed
in the organization, which
means a tread profile
for the function is established
that current practice characterize
this potential tractors,
motives intent capabilities, and targets.
So in order to achieve a
practice, the maturity level,
the organization need to
meet the prior practice
such A, B and C,
which is identifying internal external
sources of threat intelligence, gathering,
and interpretation of
the strategy information
and implementing controls
to counter threats
at different levels among
relevant to the organization.
So the model will determine
the level of preparedness
of the critical infrastructure
in dealing with the OT IT threats.
So it is a framework for critical
infrastructure protection.
So it is also important to recognize
that there's no silver bullet,
but this is one of the ways
to increase OT cyber resilience.
So this example is the assessment
for the risk domain is risk 1D,
so that refers to objective
one and practice D.
Practice D is managers,
objective one is managed
cybersecurity, practice D,
that risk are recorded in a risk register.
So as with the threat example,
which I gave in the previous slide,
to attain practice D,
preceding practices A, B, and C
you need to be fulfilled,
which is you need to identify cyber risks
and document down the risks.
Risks are mitigated, accepted,
avoided, or transferred,
and you need to have
regular risk assessments
performed to identify risks.
So we know that legacy operational
technologies is insecure.
So in recent years, more
and more manufacturers
are working to include security elements,
given the increasing
connection to and use of
IT technologies in OT to drive
performance and productivity.
So to secure operational technology,
there are two things that are needed.
First, you need to access the
current industrial systems
operating environment,
understand the gaps.
And so we discussed the
C2 M2 maturity model.
So using that model allows
you to identify focus areas,
to help prioritize this remediation.
Second sharing, or receiving
threat intelligence,
both internal and external
helps in increasing maturity
and managing risks.
So I will touch on some of
the vulnerabilities of ICS
and covered intelligence cycle
before going into the case discussion.
So in our research by ABI in
2019 on utility cybersecurity,
it was mentioned that by 2023,
connected utility
infrastructure will double.
So the increased connectivity will expose
the companies to cyber threats.
So industrial IOT devices,
such as smart meters,
great your energy efficiency
management systems
will be used.
So this digital transformation will see
many other critical infrastructure sectors
adopt technologies as well.
So that enables smart infrastructure
due to increasing competition
and changing consumer needs.
So some of the vulnerabilities
that we are seeing
are poor design of the OT infrastructure.
So these do not consider security.
It is needed to have a
security architecture
and OT environments because
the landscape is diverse.
There are multiple vendors,
equipment, and devices,
each running, they are
proprietary protocols.
So having architecture view
will help decision makers,
understand the trade off in
making architectural choices
that will impact security and allow
you to implement controls,
to compensate for the lack
of the security design.
So initially the OT that works with safe
due to physical separation,
but you cannot assume that,
given the digital transformation.
So it's best to say, get the ICS networks
into enterprise zone,
control zone and field zone.
And strong boundaries must be
established between the zones.
So this allegation of the
network in the OT infrastructure
allows a follows the
principles of defense in that.
So industrial control system
protocols are also not secure.
So they are used for
connecting devices and systems
amongst the different vendors,
such as a generic HMI solution
can connect to a Siemens
or Rockwell automation PLC.
So from a security perspective,
these protocols also unencrypted
and they do not have integrity checking.
So which leave them open to
replay and manipulation attacks.
And it makes it very dangerous
because more and more of these
systems are getting connected
to the internet and they're
available via the internet,
via modem for the vendor
to provide remote support.
So another vulnerabilities
that ICS management.
So it's important because most
of these, we see the IP wall,
they have good control systems
in identity access management,
but not so for in the ICS world.
So it's important to
prevent unauthorized users
from assessing trusted systems
and preventing your authorized users
from making unauthorized transactions,
whether intentional or unintentional.
So another vulnerability we are seeing
is devices in the field zones
have weak authentication,
and this runs into danger of adversaries
that can do it many that the mean attack.
So we are seeing that due
to industry 4.0 automation
will increase and brings
more interconnectivity
between the IT and OT networks.
So it's important now to take steps
to secure your industrial
network and your applications.
So most of the networks are designed
following the Purdue Model Architecture.
So this was developed
second industrial networks.
So it's one of the good
OT cybersecurity practice.
So the field zone is
where level zero and one,
and contains physical processes
and devices that are used for sensing
and manipulating the physical processes.
So you will find censors
analyzers actuators in this zone.
So the timeframe for
connection is in terms of
milliseconds to seconds, and
IT cybersecurity solutions
rarely ever apply in this zone.
So control zones are level two and three.
So what these systems
such as SCADA, HMI, DCS,
and the timeframe is in minutes.
Manufacturing operations
systems at level three manage
the production flow to
produce the desired products.
Requirements for control zone emphasizes,
safety and reliability.
And these devices in this zone
are not updated frequently
because the network in OT
you cannot stop a process
from the operations will be impacted
if you stop the process to update.
So few cyber security
solutions from the IT world
can be used in this zone.
So level four is the
enterprise or IT zone.
And these where the
business systems manage
the business related activities
for the industrial operation.
Since IT solutions do not
really apply to OT network.
There's often a lack of
visibility in the OT network,
and that can pose challenges.
You cannot protect what you don't see.
So of late, they are good OT
network monitoring solutions
that can identify the
assets of OT network.
This will help OT operators
to assess the threats
and vulnerabilities of the connector,
assess the are being identified,
using the C2M2 framework
that we discussed before.
So next I'll touch on
intelligence sharing,
before going into the case discussion.
So intelligence, as we know is important,
we can help the organization
to detect, protect,
and respond to threats.
There are two cycles that
I'll cover or two models,
the intelligence cycle
and the F3EAD cycle.
And I will sum it up because
both can inter operate together.
So generally you have
intelligence requirements
and the strategy that it
could an operational level.
So the strategy element looks at,
who is targeting your organization
and why they are targeting
your organization.
And also where these
threats are coming from.
The tactical alignment looks
at details of the threat
and the timing that these
threats are executed.
So operational expects a
look at how the threats
can reach your target.
So the important thing is
that threat intelligence
must be actionable so that it can increase
cybersecurity executed.
So the intelligence cycle
starts with mission.
So planning is setting the
direction to achieve the mission
is your first step.
And that includes identifying
intelligence requirements
based on your needs.
So data is collected
next from their sources.
This includes acquiring
provisioning of the information
to be used in the next step.
Collected information is
that converted into a format
that you can use, or the
analyst can use for processing.
And a next step is the
production of the machine
involves analyzing,
evaluating, interpreting,
and integrating all the information
that you collect into Finnish
Intelligence Products,
which is disseminated to the consequence
or to your stakeholders.
So this cycle F3EAD is used by military
and organizations.
So it's an alternative to
the intelligence cycle.
It combines operations and intelligence.
The first three steps are operations,
and last three steps
are intelligence phase.
So getting actionable
intelligence from the partners
and peers can help your
security operations find, fix,
and finish the incidents.
So if a threat is found,
the organization needs
to respond to the threat.
There should also be
playbooks to deal with known
and unknown threats.
Solution deployed is to ensure that
the threat is remediated.
So this is the operation phase.
So following this phase
is the intelligence phase.
So this is where
information can be exploited
and analyze for utilization
by the community.
So information collected from the incident
will be enrich so that it's contextualized
and maybe shared with the wider
community and stakeholders.
Intelligence requirements
can be strategic,
tactical and operational,
and combining both the intelligence cycle
and the F3EAD cycle covers
the three categories
of threat intelligence.
So threat intelligence
needs to deliver value.
That's the most important thing.
So it must be contextualized
to your tactical profile.
So every organization has a check profile.
So we talk about the strategic
tactical and operations,
needs of the organization.
So articulation of the impact
of the threat to the consumer
or to you as a consumer, the
intelligence is important.
So it will help you in decision making
and assessment of the
risks from the perspective
of the organization.
So to sum up good threat intelligence
can help organizations prevent,
detect and respond better
when the threat occurs.
And a recommended action to
take is just as important,
if not the most important.
End this with a case discussion
on intelligence sharing,
in the ISAC or the Information
Sharing Analysis Center.
So there are various
sources of information
they share with both the OT-ISAC.
So the analyst will take this information
and contextualize it into
relevant intelligence.
And the information can be from
public and private sources,
government sets threat intel
vendors, dark webs regulators
and other partners also share information
about incidents and vulnerabilities.
So member sharing is important
because they provide use cases
for the other companies within the sector.
So members can create forums
for further threat discussion.
Request For Intelligence or
RFI may be created by members
to request the OT-ISAC analysts
for further information.
So this can be general or
prioritize intelligence.
GRF supports up to 10 ISACs and ISAOs
and cross sector sharing
also helps to paint the overall picture.
So OT-ISAC members are provided
access to a secure portal,
and it can be assessed to the
web browser or the mobile app.
And members participate in events,
such as bookshops, training and seminars
to share best practices
and receive information
on OT and IP security
threats that are relevant
to their sector.
So OT-ISAC analysts also
conduct monthly track calls
for its members, and they
talk about topics of interest
to the members.
As soon as we see
feedback from the members,
because I think that is
the most important thing
to have a vibrant
communication between the ISACs
or between the analysts and the members
so that members can bring
out the areas of concern
that they see in their OT environment.
And they must also engage in
discussions among themselves.
Sharing of threat information is following
the traffic light protocol.
and TLP red is where sharing on the call.
Information shared cannot leave the group
that is shared with and
TLP Amber is for sharing
between the parties on the call
can be shared with members
of the organization
or service providers that are helping them
with the OT security, but
not outside this group.
So to TLP green is sharing
with the OT-ISAC community
at large.
TLP white is sharing with the public.
So next I'll run through the OT-ISAC
incident sharing process.
So the entire process can be completed
within one or two days,
depending on the
criticality of the threat.
So members that receive
early warning of the threats
can take the necessary
action to protect themselves.
So it starts with a
member sharing information
about an incident or
threat with the OT-ISAC.
So that may include details
of the incident TTPs and IOC.
The information shared is vetted
by our entities contextualize anonymize
no attributions will be made to the member
who shed that incident.
As the details are anonymize.
The analyst may contact,
the member who share
the information to collect more details
or clarify the incidents.
So as you can see that the incidents,
the information they shared
is carefully vetted because,
we do not want to spread
false information.
And intelligence really that is vetted
is then disseminated to
the OT-ISAC community.
So if relevant to the GRF
cross sectors community.
So next I will talk about
what are threat intelligence?
So this is the pyramid of
pain that was introduced
by David Bianco in 2013.
So he measures the usefulness
of threat intelligence,
and he lists out the top
indicators that are shared.
So from bottom to top, it
also defines the effort
of the adversary to change the tactics.
So for instance, your hash
values and IP addresses
at the bottom.
So these are easy for the adapter,
for the adversary to adapt and change
to deceive the defenders.
So you block the IP
address that's malicious.
The attackers can also
spoof another IP address.
And as we go up the chain,
it becomes more and more
difficult for the adversary
to adapt and change their methods.
Domain names use by adversaries
also at an active life
before they are discovered
and blocked by the defenders.
So the higher up the pyramid,
it becomes harder for
the adversary to adapt.
So you blogger tools
even force the attacker
to look for another causing
amount of pain to them.
At the top of the pyramid is
the TTPs tactics, techniques,
and procedures.
So these are the behavior
of the attackers.
So we detect and block the
TTPs used by the attacker.
You force the adversary
to modify their methods
and behavior.
So this is the most effective.
Of the ISAC members can
share any of these indicators
together with the details of the incident
impact information actions
taken and mitigation strategies.
So at end of a case study
is example of a incident
shared by a member of the ISAC.
So a member reported an
incident that was uncovered
during a security assessment
of the infrastructure.
So internal server,
there was not authorized
to external communication
was found trying to do so.
So further analysis was done.
And a compromised application
on the server was discovered.
So that application, was
trying to send a beacon
from the infector server to an attacker
command and control of C2 machine.
So this is a common
attack used by adversaries
who installed Trojan
on the victim's machine
were called back to the C2 server
that would distribute
the malicious payload,
which can be malware or ransomware
and drop it on the
machines of the victims.
So in this case, the attack was stopped
and the compromised application
was stopped, was cleaned.
So MITRE attack tactic
use command and control.
Techniques use our exploitation
or commonly used ports,
80, 443 using a common
and control protocol.
So mapping to the F3EAD cycle,
starting with detection
of the suspicious traffic
to the firewall logs.
The offending application is removed
with restriction placed
on the victim machine
before assessing the internet.
So IOC of the incident was gathered,
remembers details anonymize,
threat alert was produced
and disseminated to the community
following their TLP protocol.
So this prevented the
same chat form exploiting
other members.
So I'll end with a key
takeaways from this talk.
So in the short term,
you need to understand
how the idea of OT department
function in your organization.
So in the poll that we conducted,
there may be some that express
joint ownership of OT and IT
in the company concerning
security, budgets, and management,
but however it and OT security
needs have to be holistically considered.
So both IT and OT must
work seamlessly together.
So in the medium term, you can do
an asset inventory of the OT and IT asses
such as equipment, devices and processes.
You cannot put that in what
you do not see or know.
So in the longer term, use a framework
like the Maturity Model to
do a security assessment
of your critical infrastructure remediate
the high priority risks.
So in summary, we can minimize the impact
to our organization if we prioritize
the protection of our critical assets.
So there are many ways to
increase cyber resilience
of your infrastructure.
And information Intelligence
sharing is one of them.
So Global Resilience
Federation is based in U.S.
supporting Penn high ISAC and ISOA.
OT-ISAC it's the latest edition
set up on 1ST October, 2019,
headquartered in Singapore
and support the OT operators
in Asia Pacific.
Is a partnership of
cybersecurity agency, Singapore,
but it's managed independently.
I've come to the end of my presentation.
I wish you a good day, enjoy
the rest of the section
and stay safe.