- [Announcer] The Vendorpedia platform
is purpose-built to automate
the third-party risk lifecycle
with three core capabilities:
assessments and due diligence,
global risk exchange, and
vendor chasing services.
- Hello, and welcome to "It
Hurt Itself in Confusion:
"No distribute scanners
and stealthy malware."
If you are joining us live, our speakers
are in the slider
discussion area right now,
answering any of your questions.
If you have any audio or video issues,
please click the technical
support button below.
I'd now like to turn it over
to Liv Rowley and Mathieu
Gaucheler for the presentation.
- Hi everyone, good
morning, good afternoon,
good evening, wherever you may be,
and thank you all for joining us
for "It Hurt Itself in Confusion:
"No distribute scanners
and stealthy malware."
Again, my name is Liv Rowley,
and I am a threat intelligence
analyst over here at Blueliv.
- And I am Mathieu Gaucheler,
I'm a cybersecurity analyst
over at Blueliv as well.
- So what are we going to
be chatting about today?
First off, we're gonna start with
a brief introduction to
no distribute scanners,
or NDSs, so, what are
they, how do they work.
Next we're going to talk about
the different types of NDS services
that we find available in the
cybercriminal underground.
And then we're going to
talk about how these NDSs
are used by cybercriminals
to commit cybercrime.
And then we'll wrap this whole thing up
with some key points for you
all to take away with you.
Okay, so, let's talk about
Scan4You and Dyncheck.
Okay.
Imagine that you are this
man here, Ruslan Bondars.
And it is a lovely day
in May of 2017 in Latvia,
and suddenly you get a knock on the door.
And you are picked up by law enforcement,
extradited to the United States.
What was your crime?
Let's talk.
So, Bondars here and
his partner were running
a no distribute scanner, or
an NDS, known as Scan4You.
Scan4You was branded as
"VirusTotal-for-Crooks"
by the media, which I really like,
because I think it
actually does a great job
of explaining what these services are.
Scan4You was available,
or was online rather,
for eight years, which is
a lengthy period of time
for a cybercriminal service.
Typically the underground
is pretty volatile.
And by the time it was
seized by law enforcement,
it had 30,000 registered users.
So how does this story
end for Mr. Bondars here?
Well, in the US he received
a 14-year prison sentence.
Obviously, that's quite a lengthy time,
and that really should show you
the impact and severity of these services,
and the role that they play
in facilitating cybercrime.
So where does that lead us now, right?
There are many different,
well, there's a handful
of different no distribute
scanners, or NDSs,
that are currently available,
which we will talk a bit about later.
But kind of the top dog of the
NDSs right now is DynCheck.
So, DynCheck is popular with both
Russian- and English-speaking
cybercriminals, as well as
tons of people from other
linguistic communities as well.
The site came online in 2016,
which meant that it was very well prepared
to take over from Scan4You
when that was taken offline.
And DynCheck offers full
static and dynamic scans
of malicious files, and we'll talk
a bit about what that means later.
Okay, so, "No Distribute Scanners 101."
What are these?
So no distribute scanners, or NDSs,
and they're also sometimes
known as counter AV as well.
They are standalone websites.
And by that I mean that
they aren't part of a form,
or a software that you download.
It's actually a website that you access
and they have API access as well.
What they do is that they scan
potentially malicious files
against dozens of different
antivirus products,
and then generate a
report that is given back
to the person scanning the file,
telling you whether and how that file
might have been detected.
So the key here on what differentiates
it from something
legitimate like virus total
is that there's no feedback loop.
So cybercriminals have
disabled the feedback loop
between the anti-virus product
and the anti-virus company
in order to ensure that
this malware stays stealthy
and secret for as long as possible
before being used in a campaign.
So the takeaway there is
that these cybercriminals
are really using security products
to help themselves improve
in their cybercrime.
NDSs are advertised to cybercriminals.
They're actively promoted on forums
and they're cyber-criminal products.
So here we have an example of one NDS.
This is Cyber Scanner.
And you can see it's pretty intuitive,
kind of user friendly.
You can just drag and drop
your file right into the site,
it'll scan it and it'll give you a report.
- So here you have an example
of a little more
complicated setting panel.
This one is from Scan Haven, I believe.
You have a lot of options.
For example, you have the
choice of which anti-virus
you want to test your malware against.
You can see you have (mumbles),
Avast, Avira some of them.
Depending of which one you
wanna test your malware against.
And you have also several
options like enabling internet or not.
Deleting the zone identifier.
Disabling the user access control.
All of these little parameters and options
are made to a lot of factors.
To have a more finely-tuned
control over (faintly speaking).
NDS is going to be actually closer
to what they could encounter in the wild.
This is what this setting
panel is made for.
If you take a look at the
DynCheck settings panel,
you see more of the same options
maybe even more specific.
For example you can use DbgView
to see how Windows reacts to your malware.
Or even enable object
linking and embedding.
But one of the most
interesting features for me
the connection enabling or not.
You can choose to block in completely.
White listing a few handful of sites.
For example your command control server.
Or fully enabling internet.
Fully enabling internet is actually
kind of a cross especially in Scan Haven.
I don't know if you see
there was a mention saying,
"If you enable there to find
(faintly speaking) distributed
"is that because a lot of AV products
"actually use cloud computing
"to do some more heavy lifting operation
"like sandboxing to analyze some files."
That's what NDSs don't want.
They do not desire that because
this would distribute the file
of the redactors stop paying
them not to distribute that.
So that's kind of the problem here.
Okay let's take a look at
the different NDS services.
First and foremost we need to
do a little bit and explain
what difference between
static and dynamic analysis, actually.
So this stems from antiviruses
and the way they analyze files.
You have a static analysis,
which is basically an overview,
an inspection of the format of your file,
of how it's made, what's inside.
For example, is there any string patterns
that are indicative, like
you have on the right,
you have a rule made to detect
an OS X malware named HiddenLotus?
It's basically just
going to open the file,
search for some patterns,
string patterns like this,
and then give out if they are here or not.
It can also inspect the format,
seeing if the, for example,
the portable executable is signed or not,
or if the entropy is considered normal
or not in the form, in the file,
which could indicate, for example,
that the file's packed or maybe encrypted.
On the other hand,
dynamic analysis is really
about executing the sample,
as opposed to static analysis.
And then taking into behavior,
monitoring its behavior,
maybe analyzing the process memory,
or even invading an entire environment
and then running a sample inside
to have a better view of what
it's doing and its behavior.
These are really the two
different ways to analyze,
two different types of
analysis that we can outline:
static, in which you do not run sample,
and dynamic, in which you do.
- So we mentioned earlier
that once you upload your
malicious file to an NDS,
it'll generate a report for you.
So here is an example of one such report.
This is a report of a static scan
of a malware known as Bore,
which is an information-stealing malware,
and this report is from February of 2020.
This report was actually
shared by the threat actor
who wrote Bore, who was trying to sell it,
and so this is used as
a marketing material.
So here you see that Bore
was only detected by one
out of 31 different AV
products on Dyncheck.
And here's a close-up of that detection,
and it actually shows you the signature
that triggered detection here.
And here we have the dynamic scan report
for that same malware sample.
So here, it's actually a truncated report.
We had to cut some stuff out.
But you can see that in this case,
Bore was detected by three
out of 23 different AV products.
So detection has gone up slightly.
And here's a closer look at that.
So one of the interesting
things about the dynamic scans
is that they tend to include screenshots
of the infected machine
after the malware has been executed,
so you can see what this might look like
from a victim perspective.
In the course of this research,
we looked at about nine different NDS's.
I say nine because this underground
landscape is pretty unstable,
so some of the NDS's would go offline
or they would change names
or they'd be bought by somebody
else, something like that,
but we really, we looked
at nine different services
that existed at one
point in time at least.
All of these services offered API access,
and all of them offered
static scans as well.
Only two of the nine that we looked at
offered dynamic scans,
which is a little bit curious,
unless you start to
look into how, actually,
these scans are being conducted.
- So to answer that question, what we made
is kind of a mock-up
of the possible architecture
these scanners are using.
Keep in mind, this is nothing more than
an educated guess to answer that question.
Why is there so few dynamic scanners?
Well, let's jump right into
the possible architecture
of static scanner.
You have your classic front end,
which we'll not detail,
communicating to the back-end server,
transmitting the sample,
in which like your software
that we'll call the NDS controller
is going to receive the
sample, store it somewhere,
then the use command-line
interface to actually order the AV
to open the file and search for
some incriminating patterns.
As we say, this is static analysis.
You only need to open the file.
After that, it will return
results of the scan,
and then the NDS controller
will return the result
of the scan to the front end.
Okay, so far, so good, right?
This architecture is
pretty simple to program,
pretty scalable.
It doesn't need a lot of computing power.
But if we take a look at the architecture
that would be needed
for a dynamic scanner,
we run into several problems.
So the beginning is the same.
You have your front end transmitting
to the NDS controller on the back end.
But here, you run into your first problem.
You cannot run a malware sample
into your back-end server directly
because it's a malware.
If you do it, you're
going to get infected,
and possibly lose some very
important pieces of information.
So what you need to do
is actually run this
into a virtual machine,
because, and this is also another reason
for the virtual machine,
you cannot have 50 different
AV software solutions
running in your back-end
server in the same machine,
because they're going to
contaminate each other's analysis.
You need to have them all separate,
meaning that you need,
for 50 different AV software,
you need 50 different virtual machines,
which is going to cost
you a lot in overhead
because you need to
simulate an entire system.
So this is already the first problem.
The second problem,
if you're familiar with a virtual machine,
is that you know you're
going to need a snapshot
to revert back to.
A snapshot is basically a state,
a picture it takes of
a system at instant T,
that you're going to revert
back for each analysis.
This way, they won't be
contaminated by previous ones.
So, and the problem is
that when you cross this
with the problematic of
having an AV software
that needs to be updated
because your customers, your
financiers that pay you,
are paying you for an invasive service,
you need to have your AV
software updated daily
to be efficient at least.
So you need to come up
with some of the mechanism
to every day churn out a new snapshot
with an updated AV software,
and need to do that for all,
maybe the 40, 50 virtual
machines that you have,
and make it into the new daily snapshot.
So the AV scanners are something
that require more computing power
and that are way more difficult
to manage and administer,
and also different RAM,
because you need to
come up with that system
of dating the AV software every day.
So this is partly the
response of the answer,
why we think, actually,
there is so few dynamic scanners,
and this something that
actually has a big impact
on the price, as my
colleague is to demonstrate.
- So we identified three
different pricing models
that are used by these
no-distribute scanners,
and the first are free models.
So some of the scanners
are just available completely for free.
Those were always static
scanners that we identified,
and they appeared to be
supported by paid advertising.
So they would have like ads on them
that would say something like, "Hey,
like do you need a crypter?
Like come check out our
crypter." Something like that.
Then we have the paid model,
So typically,
a site that is a paid-for site will offer
both of these models.
So we have single and bundle scan pricing,
and just a normal subscription model.
By single and bundle
scan, I mean either paying
one price for a single
scan or paying a set price
for maybe 10 scans or 25
scans or something like that.
Subscription models tend
to be more flexible.
They may offer you, you know,
a handful of static scans
and a different amount of
dynamic scans and API access,
and it's good for a week,
or something like that.
And they offer different
combinations of things.
So for the single and bundle scan pricing,
there's really a huge
variety of pricing models
that are out there.
So for instance, for Dyncheck,
we found that to do one static scan,
checking against one AV product,
it cost data at one cent.
And it can go up from there, with the
dynamic scans costing more
than the static scans.
The subscription models, those also have a
giant range in pricing, depending on the
different features that you want
or for what length of
time you want it for,
but for Dyncheck, which
we are looking at here,
there's everything from 50 to
nearly 300 US dollars a month.
So, how are these services advertised?
These services are most popular,
or most popularly advertised, at least,
in the Russian-English language
cyber criminal underground,
so typically on forums.
Here we have a snippet of an ad for
ScanHaven, which was actually
recently rebranded as
CheckZilla, and they say "at ScanHaven
you can scan your file
on 39 fully licensed
anti-viruses which include daily
automated database updates."
We also have a screenshot
here of an ad for
Spyral Scanner, which is a static scanner.
And you can see it's got this kind of like
mysterious graphic, and you know,
the red writing and stuff,
and this is especially common on the
English language underground, using these
kind of flashier graphics
to grab attention.
- So, let's take a look now at
what is the role, actually, of NDS's
in the criminal landscapes,
our criminal landscape.
First we're going to examine
how NDS is directly used
by malware developers.
So, to talk about that
we outline the sort of
different stages in the malware life,
possible stages I say
because not all of them
have to present.
Development, advertisement,
and exploitation.
Of course, not every malware developer
is going to advertise his product.
Also we know that some
cyber criminal gangs
such as (mumbles)
had their own noticeable scanner.
And we as a research community are aware
that modern cyber criminal gang
uses NDS for their activity.
So, with that in mind, let's jump right in
to the development.
When you develop a malware using NDS
to make it more undetectable,
you're going to run
through that kind of cycle,
meaning you're going to test your malware,
analyze the output,
if it's not detected, well, hooray,
you have a great malware.
If it is, you need to identify
the cause of detection,
remedy it, and then
test your malware again.
Now how would that look in real life
with a concrete example?
Now, let's say I'm malware developer.
I program my malware, I
submit it to Dyncheck,
and I see this result.
Avira Internet Security
detecting my software,
my malware with this signature.
I can go on Avira's website
and see if there is any information
about signature online.
There is, and it tells
me that it's a signature
that is supposed to be triggered
when the software modify the MBR
or when it makes a copy of itself
in these two different files.
This way, I can inspect my malware.
Is it checking something in the MBR,
modifying it in any way?
Is it using these two paths?
Are they hard-coded in them or not?
This is the kind of question
it should be asking.
Another very good way to
escape static detection,
of course, are crypters.
So here you have a example of legitimate
and also totally,
the tools that ought to be for criminals,
only to hide malicious intent.
You have Themida and Spartan Crypter.
These two are very useful
to escape static detection,
meaning that they will
encrypt your malware
in particular step at the beginning.
When you execute a nearly
created executable,
the step will decrypt the whole thing
and then execute a malicious payload.
So this is how this would work,
how you would escape detection,
the static detection at least.
Now if you come to actually
finishing your malware
and you want to sell it,
a crucial part of that is
actually advertising your malware.
So what people usually
do is that they actually,
they show an example
of one of the malware running
against an NDS, and saying, "Look,
my malware is a quality product.
It's only detected by
three security vendors
out of 45," which is
pretty good, in my opinion.
Here you have some screenshots
of people selling or advertising, rather,
a information stealer.
You have KPOT, you have Borr,
you have DiamondFox and Oski.
So they go on marketplaces and forums
and actually advertise the product
by linking a link to the analysis.
This is one way to advertise your malware.
Last but not least, using an NDS
to actually monitor the
AV editor's response.
This is something very important.
After you develop your malware,
after you choose a site or
not and you did it, actually,
you are going to actually
exploit your malware in the wide.
To do so, NDS's have two
very useful features,
which, the first one is periodic scans,
meaning, for example,
a threat actor is going to be able to scan
each piece of malware every five days,
and every five days,
he's going to be assured
that his malware is still undetected.
This is something that is
very powerful, in my opinion,
because it allows threat actors
to constantly stay ahead of AV vendors,
meaning that if there
is detection one day,
they can circumvent detection quickly
by identifying the cause
and then churning out a
new release of the malware,
and set it again or use this new version.
This is something that allows
them to stay ahead of the game
that malware editors have
been playing for so long.
Another feature, domain check.
If you are about to launch a campaign,
the last thing you want
is use a C2 that is
already blacklisted, right?
So domain check allows you actually to
check a certain list of URLs
or host of domains
against blacklists that
antivirus vendor uses.
This way, you can be assured
that your campaign's not going to fail
because your C2 is already
blacklisted somewhere.
So let's take a look now
at some less obvious actual uses of NDS.
NDS integrated into crimeware tools.
So, if you look at your right,
you have an example,
a screenshot, sorry, of Cyber Seal,
a crypter that embeds CyberScan in it,
which is NDS, meaning every time
you're going to actually
encrypt a malware with this,
the result of this encryption
is going to be automatically
checked against CyberScan
to see if it is statically
detected by AV vendors.
In my opinion, this is incredible option
which allows threat actors actually
to streamline the process
of encrypting something,
and then checking if the packed result
is actually something detectable or not,
see if something
potentially is very harmful.
This is why every NDS we
surveyed actually have an API,
an application programming interface,
the cells for automation
and integrational tools.
At the center of your screen,
you have a screenshot
of Dyncheck's GitHub,
which have PHP resources and example
to show you how to use their API.
Last but not least, NDS.
Some NDS, we know that Scan4You did it,
and now its successor in term of scale
and successfulness maybe,
is Dyncheck.
They actually propose to be
the back end of other NDS's.
So actually, it's on
Dyncheck official website.
You can actually become
partner distributor
if you wish to have your own NDS server,
NDS service, and you do not
want to be at your back end.
You can actually ask
Dyncheck to do that for you.
Let's jump to key points.
What do you guys remember
from this presentation?
So antivirus is not a
panacea against malware.
This has been said, but this
will be never said enough.
Although we must
remember that these are scans
that are not made with the
internet enabled, usually,
meaning that the whole
cloud-computing aspect
now present in AV vendors
will not be taken into
account through its analysis,
making analysis little bit less real,
as will be in the real world.
So if you could excuse the typo.
Antivirus doesn't stop all threats,
and threat actors are actually monitoring
what AV vendors are doing.
- Another takeaway from this
is that it's important for us
to identify the big players
in any type of cybercriminal
ecosystem, as always, right?
So when we look at different
types of cybercriminal services
that are available,
it is important that
we keep NDS's in mind,
and identify who are the major
sites and players out there.
That was, at one point, Scan4You,
which again, was taken down.
And now, I mean, you've
heard us mention Dyncheck
multiple times in this presentation.
There are others as well.
But this helps us better understand,
as researchers and defenders,
where to invest our
time and our resources.
And finally, malware authors
are giving us a very interesting gift
when they share these AV scan results,
or when they share these
NDS scan results, rather.
We're allowed to take a
look at these and say,
"Okay, what is bypassing antivirus?
What is really getting
through the cracks here?"
And it can allow us to better identify
what's really an up-and-coming malware,
what's really potent,
and what should we prioritize
being prepared to defend against?
So thank you everyone for attending today,
and I guess we'll open
it up for questions now.