- Hello and welcome to Security Basics,
Burn It All and Start Over.
If you're joining us live,
our speakers in the slideshow
chat discussion area
answering your questions right now.
For audio or video issues,
click the technical support button below.
I'd now like to turn
it over to John Strand
for the presentation.
- Thank you so much.
I appreciate it.
And this is a quick presentation
that you kind of feel in the
industry for quite some time.
But I think it's hard for some people
to identify exactly what the problem is.
And the problem is that in security,
we're being told what
actually should be done.
And there's a lot of
very, very solid questions
about whether or not what
we're doing actually works.
So I talk a lot about loops.
We get into bad traditions
of doing the exact same thing
again and again and again
and we constantly get these questions.
Anytime you're working in security,
What is the best data loss prevention?
What is the best antivirus?
What is the best threat intel feed?
What is the best firewall?
And these get into these
patterns and chiasms
of us doing the exact same
thing again and again and again,
and somehow expecting different results
in that overall process.
And that's a quote that's generally
attributed to Albert Einstein
and that's the definition of insanity.
So in this presentation,
I want to walk through
what are some things you organizations
should actually be focusing on
if you want to stop an attacker
from actually breaking in?
Now, this isn't meant to be exhaustive.
This is just my quick 30 minute overview
of what I think people
shouldn't be focused on.
There's still all the standard motherhood
in apple pie type things
that you should be doing.
But these are the big ones.
And I'm going to start off
with the biggest, passwords.
Whenever it comes to passwords,
we have tremendous issues
in the industry as a whole
in understanding what the
effect of strong passwords are
and actually stopping attackers.
Unfortunately, whenever we're looking
at password complexity,
many organizations have requirements
such as greater than eight characters.
Upper, lowercase, alpha,
numeric, no dictionary word.
And if that's your password
policy, it's full of fail.
It's very, very difficult to actually
have a secure organization
with that password complexity policy.
You cannot fix this in many
organizations because politics.
And people say well, compliance.
I'm going to blame PCI for this.
PCI says the minimum password
requirements are seven.
And they do that for a
lot of legacy systems
and reverse compatibility but
it's incredibly problematic
especially if an organization's
trying to meet the minimum.
So let me give an example
as far as why meeting
minimum is so problematic.
This is a slide that I
present on all the time.
It's the NIST Greenbook from 1985.
So I want you to take a couple of seconds
and I want you to think a little bit
about what were you doing in 1985?
Some of you that are at this session,
probably weren't even alive yet.
Some of you were just very small children
and some of you had boom boxes and Furbies
and what do they call them Teddy rub skins
and all these different things.
So kind of mentally setting that stage.
But if we look at the password
complexity requirements
from the NIST Greenboo.
In 1985, they have this paragraph .
It says L is set for six
months and 12 months.
P is set for one in one million.
And that's an acceptable probability
for guessing a password and R
is set for 8.5 guesses per minute.
And it says at a guests rate
of 8.5 guesses per minute.
The guests rate possible
with a 300 baud modem.
The password change
policy for an organization
with an eight character password
is once every six months.
And then it comes with this recommendation
that says how long our
passwords should be,
and you have, how long it's going to be
in a month on the left hand side
and then how many characters?
And it says eight or nine password
or eight or nine characters
for that password.
This is a password complexity
document from 1985.
And unfortunately,
many organizations never
progressed beyond this.
So we need to find a way
that we can start progressing
beyond these core fundamentals
that we get from many compliance documents
and many of the
conventional wisdom cedars,
and the industry telling us what should
and should not be doing.
Another example is antivirus.
If you're looking at
traditional antivirus,
there are a number of different ways
to actually bypass these different tools
that we rely on every single day.
It's very easy to bypass things
like antivirus, data loss
prevention, firewalls,
and it's a lot of smoke and mirrors
on how you can actually successfully
implement these things
in your organization.
And that's driven by many vendors
who like to put forth the narrative
that they are finally the silver bullet,
that if you're just running their product,
then you're going to be able to be secure
against any level of an attacker
that will be targeting your organization.
And I want to make it very
clear that, that is not true.
Every year at Black Hills
information security,
we do a presentation called
sacred cash cow tipping,
where we go through all
the major endpoint vendors,
and we bypass those vendors
usually the night before the presentation.
And we take, usually it's
like the top 10 or 15.
And we come up with bypass techniques.
And we have previous bypass
techniques and previous sessions
that we've archived on a number
of our different websites.
But if you're running
any of these products,
whether it's a next gen product,
if you're running something
like silence, or crowd strike,
or any of these other
tools, they're great tools.
But you need to understand
that they can be bypassed.
And if you understand this,
this actually creates a fundamental shift
in your thinking on computer security.
Because if you're just
relying on a vendor,
one single vendor on the
endpoint to keep you secure,
you're going to be running into trouble,
because that particular tool can in fact,
be bypassed relatively easily as well.
So if we're going to move forward,
we need to move beyond
just looking at single point solutions.
Like antivirus data loss
prevention, firewalls,
threat intelligence feeds,
and we need to start
leaving these things behind.
And if we were going to put these things,
and we were going to change them,
and we're going to do it new again,
what would we actually do
that would be maybe a change on a theme,
not completely changing
everything that we're doing,
but trying to change
things up a little bit.
So we can get out of these bad
loops and these bad patterns.
So I'm going to start with some things
that are relatively unpopular.
Let's start with Internet White Listing.
Now anytime I mentioned
Internet White Listing,
it's very common for people
to pull out the pitchforks
and the torches and the
angry mob that you see here.
And they'll say yo,
your presentation is bad
and you should feel bad.
However, I want you to take
a couple of steps back.
Internet blacklisting will not work ever.
The only thing that it does,
is it shows that an organization
is exercising due diligence
to stop their people from
going to bad websites
while at work for actually stopping
legitimate attackers, targeted attackers,
standard blacklist is next to worthless.
And we know this because we do anywhere
between 450 to 550 security
assessments per year.
And the organizations that are just
using traditional blacklist techniques
are very, very easy to break into.
Specifically, you're going to want to look
at the uncategorized list.
Now, the uncategorized list
might have different names
for your web application proxy vendor
that you're actually using.
And the uncategorized means
that your web proxy vendor
has never seen this website.
They haven't categorized
it as a news website,
a shopping website, a
social media website,
they've never seen it.
And I want to make it very
clear that a force point
or Cisco or somebody
that's a very large vendor
has never seen a website.
That has a website you do not want
your user population going to.
And if you uncheck that,
and you don't allow your users
to go to the uncategorized websites,
you can allow them to go to
the standard news websites
and the shopping websites
they would go to,
but as soon as you start
restricting uncategorized,
it makes it more difficult for an attacker
to actually break into your organization.
Yes, you can do this.
Trust me, it's not that hard.
And the vast majority of the sites
that fall into uncategorized,
once again are not websites
that you ever want your
user population to go to.
And this is not a new idea.
In fact, Marcus Ranum,
was talking about this
13 or over 13 years ago,
he was talking about a numerating badness
is a dumb idea in computer security.
It was not smart then and
it is still not smart today.
We need to get away from dealing
with traditional blacklist technologies.
So let's play a game.
If we're going to look at this
as kind of a thought exercise,
how many websites do your legitimate users
are legitimate websites do users go to?
They go to 200? Say 500, a 1000, 2000?
Find out.
On your day to day basis,
you're going to find out
that the vast majority
of your user population is actually going
to the exact same
websites again, and again.
Human beings are definitely
creatures of habit.
I probably have about 20 websites
that I visit very regularly.
And I don't spend a lot of time
just clicking on random
links, like find about
but find more about mortgages in your area
and they show a picture
of a cute little puppy,
and everyone's like, I'm
gonna click on that puppy.
You don't really want your users
doing that type of casual web surfing.
But if you look at where your users
are going for legitimate websites,
it's not gonna be very many.
And let's say hypothetically,
that you just allowed users to go to them,
like you popped up something and it said,
hey, you're going to a website?
I haven't seen it before.
Are you sure you want to go, yes or no?
They click yes.
Even if you allow the
ending to run the asylum,
you would still be far more secure
than a blacklist approach.
Why? Because attackers will
take advantage of websites.
They'll try to create
websites that look legitimate.
They're going to try to set up
command and control websites
with names that you know will
blend in on an organization.
And we can actually take advantage
of those to gain access
to your environment.
But if you're just restricting
it to where people go,
or you're shutting off on
categorized once again,
it drastically reduces your
overall exposure to attack.
For filtering, here's
just a quick example.
We have categories like adware, alcohol,
anonymizer, art, gaming,
but here's the big one right here
that says uncategorized in
the lower right hand corner.
You want to make sure that your users
can't go to the uncategorized
website category.
So let's move on to something else
that people get really uncomfortable with.
Application White Listing.
This is another category
of security implementation
that people just run away from screaming.
And they run from it screaming
because they think it's hard.
And they believe it to be hard
because of one simple thing.
Because they believe that
application white listing
is exclusively about
filtering on file hashes
We're going to go through and identify
every single application
and every single dynamic link library,
every shared object library
and every single system
on your environment.
And you're only going
to allow those through
and only going to allow those to execute.
Well, you could do it that way.
But there's actually better
ways to go about doing it.
In fact, one of the ways
I'm going to show you
on the next slide is
actually fairly simple
to implement as well.
So instead of getting away
from this binary viewer,
we have to do it this one way with hashes.
We can open it up a little bit.
We can actually do this based on directory
which is what I'm going to show you.
And you're going to have people
in the security community they'll say,
Well, I can bypass
application white listing
if you're allowing it by directory.
Yeah, they probably could.
But it is far more difficult
than just allowing everything
to execute on your system.
So let me show you.
So here's the default rules
that Windows 10 creates an app locker.
Within app locker, the default rules
will be everyone can
execute all the programs.
You can see it here,
it says Program Files.
And if you have older systems,
that can be Program Files, x86.
Everyone can execute all the
files in the windows directory.
That's where your operating
system files exist.
And then the administrator
can execute anything
anywhere that they want.
Turns out that this
particular set of restrictions
just on directory is incredibly difficult
for attackers to get past.
Now there are techniques
like ASR evil great attacks,
actually exploiting specific applications
and the vulnerabilities.
But your drive by downloads
become far more difficult
because they're going to try to land
and execute and temporary folders
and temporary folders
like temporary Internet folders as well.
This is the easiest way
to implement application
white listing or allow listing
as some people are calling it.
I'm an advocate of that as well.
This is a way that we
can actually do that.
And we can implement it in
a way as far as baby steps.
We implement allow listing on directories.
And as we get better, maybe we can move up
to digital code signing certificates
and publisher verification.
We don't have to jump straight
into validation of hashes.
And ultimately, whenever
we're looking at security,
it's all about architecture.
If you look at the history
of structural engineering
and architecture,
it has a history of failure.
It has a history of understanding
the failure points for
every single component
that you put into an architecture.
Every beam, every column, every door,
everything has a failure point.
And structural engineers
design their architectures in such a way
that there's overlapping support
that doesn't create
failure in just one place.
We have failure points,
we develop mitigations,
we identify weaknesses
and we develop mitigations
for those weaknesses.
And we have that overlapping
field of visibility
and that overlapping field
of structural support
and things can get better.
Let's take a couple of seconds.
Let's talk about compliance.
James and Kelly Trollope
on enclave security
are the main people behind
the 20 critical controls.
And they have some amazing spreadsheets
that will help you implement
the 20 critical controls
and do it in an easy way.
So if you want to just google
enclave and audit scripts,
audit scripts 20 critical controls,
and they have things like
master mapping documents
that will map the 20 critical controls
to every single audit framework
on the face of the planet.
The reason why this is
in this presentation,
is I run into organizations
all the time that have five
or six audit frameworks
that they have to be in compliance with
and they go crazy trying
to keep them up to date.
With the 20 critical controls,
we created these years
ago at the Sans Institute.
We wanted to create a Rosetta Stone
and that's really what
James and Kelly have done.
So you can map to the
20 critical controls,
and then it automatically maps
to all the other frameworks.
So check that out.
Speaking of mapping,
the Mitre attack technique
matrix is monstrous.
Because now we're starting
to develop a taxonomy
of what attackers do.
And what I recommend that people
do is do threat emulation.
If you look at vulnerability assessments,
many times vulnerability assessments
will only hit like two squares
out of the entire Mitre
attack technique matrix.
When an attacker gains
access to your environment,
they're going to do all kinds of things
like password spraying, lateral movement,
they're going to try to execute
code on a remote systems
and pull data out of the environment.
And with the Mitre
attack technique matrix,
you have the ability to look
at what you can actually
prevent in your environment.
And if you do emulation
with tools like Caldera,
or tools like Atomic Red Team,
or commercial tools like size
which makes it very easy to execute,
you can actually start emulating
what a real attacker would do.
And all the time
techniques that an attacker
would run through,
and you can start doing a gap analysis
and so far as what your
organization can detect.
So check those tools out.
Firewalls, another
semi-controversial thing.
Why is it that your computers
are more secure at a coffee
shop than they are at work?
You see, whenever you go to a coffee shop,
your computer recognizes
that it's in unsecured open network.
So it throws this firewall up,
and it doesn't trust any of
the other computer systems
in that coffee shop.
But whenever it comes
to work, it's just like,
ah, shut the firewall off
anyone can connect to me.
You need to start treating
your internal network
as hostile because it is hostile.
There is no good reason at all
for all of your workstations
to talk to each other ever.
Let me explain.
So if you look at your standard exploit,
the attacker delivers
a client side exploit
or a drive by download and compromises
one computer system on the
inside of the environment.
Then an attacker or a pen tester
is going to move laterally
to a whole bunch of other workstations.
We do this because we take our credentials
and move from system to system to system.
And we do this specifically,
because we're trying
to escalate privileges
to get the main administrator.
So I'll move with psexec, pass-the-token,
remote desktop, pass-the-hash
and the whole goal of me doing this is,
is to gain access to those systems
to try to take over the entire domain.
And most of the time,
organizations are not able to detect
this type of lateral
movement unfortunately.
However, if you treat
your internal network
as hostile once again, because it is,
then it makes that lateral movement
far more difficult for the attacker.
They'll gain access to a system
and maybe they're locked into
one specific business unit.
Or maybe you have your
host based firewalls
enabled in your environment
or maybe your antivirus
which has a firewall you
can remotely manage that.
You can put on a number of rules
on your firewall that say,
your workstations can talk to servers,
your server subnets, helped us subnets,
administrator subnets
can talk to workstations.
But workstations cannot
ever talk to each other.
That's the type of firewall rules
that that we need to
have in our environment.
Because if we do that,
some magical things occur.
As soon as we gain access
to that one system,
as soon as we start doing
lateral movement with psexec,
past-the-token, WMI, remote desktop,
all those firewalls are
protecting those systems.
Not only are they
protecting those systems,
but they are also serving
as points of detection
of that lateral movement.
So if we tie this back to the
Mitre attack technique matrix,
there's an entire column
of lateral movement.
This would deny the attacker,
the vast majority of those techniques
that deal with lateral movement.
Now, once again going back to passwords,
we started with that as
one of the key things.
The only thing that matters
when you're dealing with
passwords is length.
You'll get into these long conversations
of upper or lowercase,
alphanumeric, special characters,
don't allow dictionary words,
don't allow this don't allow that.
The only thing that
matters is length folks.
Make your password 16 characters long,
allow people to use dictionary words,
but keep the upper, lower, special case,
numeric numbers,
and your passwords are
going to be far more secure
than a shorter quote unquote
more complicated password
that they would have in place.
You see, if you actually get to the point
where you don't allow people
to use dictionary words
and you're using in
requiring upper, lowercase,
alphanumeric, special characters,
your users will start keyboard patterns
and when they do keyboard patterns,
they'll actually coalesce on a
handful of keyboard patterns.
And you'll have like far less entropy
and your overall passwords
than if you just let people come up
with passphrases on their own.
Next up, let's talk about
two factor authentication.
This is one of those things
that we're starting to see
implemented in organizations.
I'll be it slower than we would like.
But two factor authentication
will absolutely shut down many attackers.
Now there are bypass techniques.
You can run things like Evilginx,
you can run things like credit king
to try to intercept that
two factor authentication,
but it will make the attack
far more difficult to gain
access to an environment.
So try to implement this.
It can be via SMS notification,
even though people say SMS notification
for two factor is horrible.
It's better than nothing.
You can use Google Authenticator,
you can use duo,
there's a ton of different
technologies that are out there.
And you might get some pushback
in your organization as to whether
or not you should do this.
And I would encourage
you to share the article
from Teen Vogue that says,
two factor authentication
is very important.
If we can't meet a security standard,
can we at least meet the
Teen Vogue standards?
And come on Teen Vogue?
Let's talk about smarter logging.
So if we're looking at logging,
I'm gonna set you up a quick trick
that you can set up in your environment
that's going to detect
your next turtle assumed
compromise assessment or your pen test.
Here's what I want you to do.
I want you to create a
user in your environment,
give it an obvious name.
In this situation,
I called my user admin ADM administrator.
Try to be right on the nose
that this is an account
that's called the administrator account.
Then, I'm going to disable
all the login hours.
So you can't actually log
into this account ever.
And then you set up alerting in your SIEM.
That if anybody ever tries
to log into that account,
they will immediately generate an alert.
And this is what it looks like.
This is a tool called
domain password spray
but bold Bullock or daft hack.
It automatically pulls
down a full user list
of every single user
ID in your environment
and then attempts a single
password against that account.
So you can see here,
it says, it's password spring
with password of probably spring.
What is it 2017 in the screenshot.
And it's trying every single user account.
Just by simply trying to authenticate
to that account automatically,
it can generate an alert.
And when it does, you could do something
like lock that workstation down.
This is an amazing bit of cyber deception,
where you can set a tripwire
that will absolutely attack or not attack,
it will detect an adversary
that is attacking you very
quickly post exploitation.
Why? Well, we're setting this trap
in a place where adversaries go.
Password spraying is in the bag of tools
that almost every single attacker
uses against your environment
and every other environment
every single day.
And if we set this up internally,
it is one of the tricks that they use
to try to move laterally
and you'll be able to detect
that lateral movement immediately.
Once again, tying back to the
Mitre attack technique matrix.
Also, with logging use Sysmon.
I cannot stress enough just
how incredibly worthless
standard event logging actually is.
In fact, if you look at the
Verizon data breach report,
something like 1% of all the
breaches that they worked
were detected by their SIEM.
And that's because there's
no event ID that says,
event ID 666.
You've been hacked, it doesn't exist.
But Sysmon gives you amazing fidelity
for free out of the box.
So here's an example of a Sysmon log.
We have the process ID, the
executable, the full path to it,
the file version, the
description within that file,
what that product is,
what the name of that particular file is.
We also have the hashes
of that file that executed.
With this, we finally
have the level of logging
that we've always wanted
in computer security.
So please do me a favor,
start logging Sysmon.
All of your major sim
vendors will support it.
And you might get into
an argument of well,
would we be logging
too much at that point?
Look, most of what you're
logging is garbage here.
Another exercise.
I want you to look at the logs
that you're collecting right
now in your organization.
What percentage of those
logs have an alert,
a signature or a report
associated with them?
You're gonna find out that probably 95%
of the logs that you're
collecting have no alert,
have no report, have no signature,
you're just collecting and storing them.
Like some twisted hoarder
who has garbage all over their house
with long fingernails and talks to aliens.
So you need to get away from
being an infosec quarter.
Instead, you need to start
logging the right thing.
So log the things that matter
and Sysmon is absolutely
something that matters.
So when we're talking about
these different things,
it seems like it's difficult.
And there's this analogy
that people talk about all the time.
How do you go about eating an elephant?
Well, you shouldn't try to go
to straight implementation
right off the bat.
You don't want to jumps to hey,
we're gonna implement
carbon black everywhere.
We're gonna try to implement
tripwire everywhere.
You will see a lot of organizations
that try to jump to implementing
a full security posture of hash based
application low listing.
You see organizations
that try to jump straight
to do full segmentation and isolation
on every system in one shot,
take it apart piece by piece,
roll out your security implementation
with different networks, business units
and geographical locations.
Roll them out, start
with your security team,
move to the administrators,
move to help desk,
roll these things out
slowly in your environment.
And you're gonna have a much better time
implementing them as a whole.
Protect yourself.
One of the things I also recommend
is you need to protect yourself at home.
Especially whenever we're
looking at the world of COVID
that exists today.
We're many of us are in
fact now working from home,
and we may be accessing our
organizational resources
from a personal browser.
You have to protect yourself.
Look at things like Adblock Plus,
OpenDNS at home,
keep your systems
patched, use a passphrase.
Don't run strange programs.
Yes, Microsoft antivirus is just fine.
Never talked to anybody
who says they work for
Microsoft tech support.
But you all know that.
What I encourage you all to do
is share the simple ideas on this slide
with your friends and your family.
Share this idea with your children
and nieces and nephews and grandchildren.
So we can start getting better
at securing not just our
organizational assets,
but us as a whole.
Because here's the deal.
If you look at computer security,
computer security is not
just a corporate problem,
computer security and
the problem that we have
is an education and awareness problem.
And we desperately need our education
and our awareness to extend far beyond
the boundaries of the
organizations that we work for.
And it has to start going
to friends and family
and all of you that are listening
and watching this video right now,
you are the pointy edge of the spear.
You are the best and brightest
in computer security.
And it's incumbent upon all of you
that are watching this video
to go forth and try to teach people
how to be secure not just at work,
but in their everyday lives.
Because if they're not secure at home,
they're not going to be secure
in organizations either.
So the apply slide moving forward.
Let's stop doing this standard
things that we've been doing.
The traditional defenses,
the SIEM, the AVs,
the standard firewalls just
on the edge of our network,
they get out of date quickly.
Let's start trying to
fix things like passwords
with longer links and let's move
to two factor authentication.
Let's look to what actual attackers do
and let's start emulating
what those actual attackers
do to stop those attacks.
Let's use Mitre, let's use Caldera.
Let's use slide, let's
use Atomic Red Team.
Improve your logging and set some traps
in your organization as well.
That's what I'm ultimately
asking all of you to do.
This was a quick presentation.
And I just want to say thank you so much
for sitting through this
presentation and listening.
My email is john@bhis.co.
I'm on Twitter because
everybody's on Twitter.
And yeah, even at my phone number.
If you have a question,
don't hesitate to pick
up the phone and call me.
So once again, I want to
say thank you very much
and I hope you have a
great and safe conference.