- Hello and welcome to Small
Cells and Smaller Devices
Using 5G to Solve IoT Device Security.
If you're joining us live
our speaker is in slider
right now answering your questions.
For audio or video issues,
click the technical support button below.
I'd now like to turn it
over to Senthil Ramakrishnan
for the presentation.
- Thank you Rita and thank
you everyone for joining
this session.
My name is Senthil Ramakrishnan,
and I am part of the AT&T
business organization,
specific in the IoT organization.
Thanks again for joining
and as Rita mentioned,
if you have any questions,
or any of the discussions
you'd like to have
reach out to our slider.
Over the next 30 minutes,
we are going to be talking
about IoT.
Some of the security
challenges that IoT deployments
face today, specifically
on the device side,
and then we will focus on how
5G and some of the 5G network
capabilities will help solve
some of these IoT challenges.
And again, we're gonna
be focusing specifically
on devices and challenges that they face.
So we'll start off by
talking about what is IoT.
This is a term, this is
another industry buzzword,
that probably everybody
on this presentation
or the sessions have heard.
IoT or internet of things
really is just a network
of connected devices,
devices that are deployed out
in the field that are
collecting information,
in terms of information
and sending it back
for post processing, by applications.
These applications might then
take some acts, some decision
and then force some action
through some random control using
the same devices themselves.
So there's been an explosion
of IoT in the last few years.
Today, I think the estimate
is around 2.5 billion devices,
IoT devices deployed
globally on various types
of connectivity.
The growth is expected to be
much larger numbers anywhere
between 20 to 50 billion
IoT devices over the next
five to seven years are expected.
That's a huge group, but
the thing we have to realize
is not all IoT devices are
the same, and we'll start off
with something as simple
as the connectivity piece.
When IoT was starting
to grow a few years ago,
about there were 70 to
75% of these IoT devices,
were expected to be on Wi-Fi.
But as these devices
started getting deployed,
mainly because Wi-Fi is
cheap, is easily available,
easy to deploy.
But what was happening was
there is no inherent security,
built with Wi-Fi and
enterprises were starting to see
that IoT deployments were very vulnerable
when they were using Wi-Fi.
And so cellular IoT
started gaining traction,
and it's going to continue
to gain traction as well.
So today, it's nearly around
10 to 15%, and that's expected
to grow up to 25%.
And with the advent of the
introduction of technologies
like LTE-M, Narrowband IoT and 5G,
that traction for cellular
IoT is gonna continue...
Now, before we jump into the
challenges that IoT brings,
let's talk about the IoT architecture.
Very simply, you can break
it down into three layers.
One is the device layer,
the connectivity layer,
and then the data and application layer.
The device layer is any IoT
device, could be something
as complex as a smart
building or a connected car,
or it could be something as
simple as a temperature sensor
or a flow sensor out in the oil field.
So, all of these IoT, all of
these different types of IoTs
comprises this layer.
Now, a lot of these devices
have connectivity directly built
into them, but some of
them also have a gateway
in between that these
devices are talking through.
The next layer is the connectivity layer,
or the connectivity layer is
essentially the transport layer
that is going to carry
the data from your device
to your back-end application.
And this could be cellular,
I'm talking about Wi-Fi,
it could be wireline, satellite,
all types of connectivity,
it could be private,
public to wide range there.
Now, these networks of
carrying this data back
to the set of platforms or
applications that are sitting
in the back-end, and these
platforms and applications
are broken down into three.
There's an application
enablement platform,
which is essentially the Azure, the AWS
and any of the Google's, any
of these cloud providers,
where you can run your application.
The second is your connectivity
management platform,
which is what you use to manage
how your devices connect.
And the last one is the
device management platform,
which is what you use to
manage your devices itself.
And you put all of these
together and you get
the IoT ecosystem.
Now, where are we with
IoT in the real world?
The IoT is essentially
everywhere you look,
any industry whether it's
some of the older industries
like manufacturing, industrial
to newer industries,
like drones, agriculture,
wearables, healthcare,
any essential industry today
has some type of IoT deployment
available.
And the rate of deployment
is continuing to grow,
because at the end of the
day, the more data you have,
the more educated decisions
and actions you can take
and IoT is gonna enable that.
So really, the application
of IoT is very widespread,
and new applications are
coming out as we speak.
Now, let's get to the interesting part.
Now we have a good northeasterly
introduction to IoT.
Let's try to understand what
the security challenges are.
Now the first thing to really
understand is IoT is very
different from IT.
We're gonna spend some
time really understanding
what those differences are,
because those are gonna
define what the threat vectors
and the security challenges
really available.
Now if you look at the same model,
where we have the three layers,
the device, the network,
and the application, you'll
see that there's a way
set of vulnerabilities and
compromise that can happen.
But the challenge with IoT is
that, although you can secure
your back-end application,
because it's really running
in one of the cloud
providers, and we have a lot
of solutions out there.
And it's connecting or and
you could connect using
one of the more secure
connectivity options like cellular,
when you come down with the device,
that is where the challenge arises.
Because most IoT devices
are going to be really
low powered devices that
don't have a lot of processing
or memory capability on them.
So the ability to add
security capabilities
to these low power devices,
is a big challenge.
The second is that these
devices are very cheap,
so you're not gonna be able to
add cost to it by increasing
security capabilities on them.
So that's probably the
number one challenge
or security gap for IoT is
the device and its ability
to be secured by itself.
So let's talk how that
impacts IoT security.
So let's talk about volume.
Let's take the example
of a car manufacturer
as an example enterprise for this IoT.
So a car manufacturer will
have multiple IoT applications,
it could be something to monitor their
industrial manufacturing
plants, asset tracking,
worker tracking, it could be
the connected cars themselves
that are offering as a
service to their customers.
So there's gonna be a
large volume of IoT devices
that are going to be
deployed out in the field,
and all of these devices
are going to be different.
They're gonna be deployed
in various environments,
in various geo locations,
and each of these devices
are gonna be different
in sensor that is sitting
and measuring the temperatures
inside your factory,
or the critical component in
the factory is gonna be very
different from the sensor
device that is inside your
connected car.
So there's gonna be a wide
variety of custom devices really,
that are deployed out into the field.
Now the challenge this
raises is that you cannot
have a singular or common
security solution that can be used
to secure all of these devices.
Now we talked about these
custom devices, and that extends
really both into the
hardware and software world.
Because you're gonna have
custom hardware built
either by a tier one or you're
buying it off of the shelf
and putting it together,
like a system integrator
type model.
And the software for IoT
is completely different,
because real time operating systems,
there's not a lot of use of
standard operating systems
like Windows or MacOS, or even Android.
These are very real time operating systems
for smaller devices and then
Unix and Linux meetings across
the rest of the ecosystem.
There's a lot of effort to
try to unify that, but even
today, it's very split, very fragmented.
So again, the challenge
that this brings forth
is how do I manage these devices?
How do I maintain the security
lifecycle for all of these
devices?
That's very difficult.
You can't use your standard,
device management solutions
that you use for your IT
devices, your laptops,
your phones, none of those
are gonna work in this case.
And then device access
is another challenge.
IoT devices are gonna
be almost like a deploy
and forget type model where
the device is out in the field.
And in lots of cases, a lot of
verticals like smart cities,
these places are available
in public spaces,
can be the Smart Lighting System, etc.
That has connectivity back
into the cities IT systems.
And now, these devices could
then be easily accessible,
and if not secured properly,
easily compromised,
which would then allow access
back into the interfaces,
and to systems and back-ends.
So, in a traditional IT
system, the risks are really
data loss and compromise of
data and leading to some lost
revenue and resources.
Like with IoT, those risks are
amplified because depending
on the vertical that
has also impacted life.
Now, you could take Thomas
driving as an example,
even something as simple
as industrial systems
could be compromising me
to malfunction and in fact,
work and safety in that location as well.
So IoT brings some unique
challenges that are exacerbated
by the inability to fully
secure these devices.
So how do we go about
securing these devices?
That's what we're gonna talk about next.
So what we recommend really
is a multi-layered approach
to security, you have these three layers,
and we have to have security solutions
in all of these three layers.
We have to have threat
management that looks
at the ecosystem end-to-end.
But the problem, as I was
talking about earlier,
is that these devices are
not able to have a full
SWOT of security solutions
deployed normally.
Today most of these security
solutions are sitting
at the very end, on the
opposite end of ecosystem,
meaning they're all sitting
at the data application layer.
So these devices are
essentially open and vulnerable,
and all protection are made
to the data that's coming in
at their application layer.
And that obviously is not a good solution,
because that is a weak
link in the entire chain.
So this is where 5G comes in.
5G brings about a new set
of capabilities that allows
the enterprise to bring
security solutions closer
to the device.
So even though the devices
continue to stay low powered,
and possibly insecure,
your ability to bring
the security applications
and security solutions
at the edge of the network
allows us to provide a better
risk level to your enterprises.
Thereby even though that
is some security issues
in the end-to-end solution,
your risk is now at a much more
acceptable level and so
you can be more confident
in deploying your IoT
solution into the market.
So I'm gonna stop there and
feel free to send any questions
regarding IoT and IoT
security wireless via slide,
and I'm going to
transition over to 5G part
of this discussion as well.
So let's talk about 5G and how
it's going to help the issues
that we talked about with IoT devices.
So what does 5G bring?
5G, again, is another term that
we're hearing in the market
every day, and how is it gonna help IoT?
I want to point out a few
capabilities that are gonna
be important from a security
perspective later on.
First one is ultra low latency.
5G is gonna bring less than 20 millisecond
round trip latency between
your device and your back-end
application.
Well, that's important
because today, on 4G LTE,
that latency can be anywhere
between 75 to 150 milliseconds
depending on where your devices.
And latency is important,
we'll talk about it later.
The second one is reliability,
your ability to support
mission critical devices when
they're out in the field,
reliably and high availability
is very triggered.
It's important from a
security perspective as well.
Next one is we talked about
the volume of IoT devices.
5G supports massive IoT, where
you can have a very large
number of IoT devices in
very dense deployments
because of small cells
and other capabilities
that 5G brings.
And then some IoT applications
or verticals require
ultra high bandwidth as well, so 5G brings
that to the market as well.
Continuing, when you compare 4G to 5G,
5G is an instance transformation,
that means from the devices
through the network all the way
to the back-end, everything
is completely changed.
We talked about the radio access part,
which is the low latency,
the ultra high speed,
massive densification but
it also brings some other
capabilities that we're
gonna jump into next.
So two things that 5G
really brings to the market
when you look at the
architecture, two massive changes
that are brought about in 5G deployment.
First one is virtualization.
Moving from 4G to 5G,
we're essentially moving
to a software defined
network based architecture
for the entire 5G network.
Now this is groundbreaking
because this SDN based
architecture allows us to
do some very critical things
with respect to security and resources.
And we'll talk about that next as well.
The other change that 5G also
brings about is the separation
of your control and user plane.
This is called CUPS, Control
and User Plane Separation.
And what this does is it really separates
the network management capable functions
from the user functions
meaning the actual data
that is being carried between the device
and the back-end application.
Now, this is important because
from a security perspective,
now you can have separate
security policy for your
control plane as well as your user plane.
And that is important because
these devices will be using
the user plane, and
having the ability to add
security policy to it becomes critical,
because now you're adding
security layers and helping
protect that vulnerable.
The other changes which
are just as important,
is this move from a
centralized network core
to a highly distributed network core.
So that plays into the
high reliability and high
availability feature like 5G.
The other important
and very important part
of the 5G network is the
addition of the edge.
Now we talked about how today
most of the security solutions
are running at the end of the
IoT ecosystem, which is really
the application in the data.
Now, the addition of
this edge to the network
has two things, one is
now you're able to add
network security capabilities,
this is the network itself,
those can be added to the edge.
And you can also bring user
or device security services
to the edge as well.
As other improvements to the
5G technology, which includes
increase or the add and
user friendly encryption
of the traffic, and also
some subscriber privacy
and identity changes as well.
So overall, the 5G evolution
on the 5G advancement really
brings protections to the network layer,
and that fixes some of the vulnerabilities
that were uncovered in 4G LTE.
Now this is separate from
what we're gonna talk about
in the application layer, which
is what is actually really
to protecting these IoT devices.
We talked about, the
Subscriber Identity Privacy,
we talked about some
additional security functions
that are introduced into the network.
Some verticals in IoT really
have devices that are moving
around, in many cases,
moving networks as well.
An example is, containers,
tracking containers,
refrigerated containers.
So in these cases, you're moving networks,
you're moving geographic
locations, and so 5G brings
around security when you cross
network boundaries as well.
And other change to the
5G security architecture
was the introduction of domains.
They've really created a
hierarchy within the architecture
when you have a network
access the security domain,
which is really how your
device is authorized
and gets access into the network.
You have a network domain
security which is how,
which is some of the
things we talked about,
which is how the network itself is secured
with the communication
between the infrastructure.
And then two important things
is the user domain security
from the application domain security.
This is where the user traffic,
and the application traffic itself
are able to be secured
by additional services
that came into this.
Now let's talk about the user
and the application domain.
So two things that really,
really stand out to me,
one is network virtualization,
and edge based security.
Network virtualization really
means most of the network
components are SDN based.
So now, what you can do is
allocate resources based on need
for each of these network infrastructure.
So essentially, you could
create a slice throughout
the network, end-to-end in the network,
and dedicate that slice
to specific IoT use cases,
we'll talk about that later.
Edge based security, we
talked about it moving
the applications and services,
specifically device security
applications and services,
as close to the device as possible is now
a feature that 5G networks are principled.
So, slicing.
Now, as we talked about
all the different verticals
with IoT security or with
IoT, you'll see that not all
of these verticals are the same.
Economists levels might
require high bandwidth higher,
low latency and high security.
But as industrial type
deployment which does not require
high latency or high
throughput would still require,
security policy.
And so each IoT vertical might
have it's own requirements,
and so with virtualization,
we're able to take the network
and slice it into different
network slices so that you can
use those and base your
resources on what is actually
needed.
And so in this example, we're talking
about a transport layer,
where we have low latency,
high bandwidth and high security.
Same thing for healthcare,
but you might not need
high bandwidth in the healthcare scenario,
so standard bandwidth could be used.
So, slicing is important for
devices, because now you can
take insecure devices
and put them on a slice
where they will not impact
other devices that are doing
mission critical capabilities.
Likes of healthcare, for example,
devices that are insecure
can be put into say
that a healthcare slice
that does not cross into
other mission critical
and insecure devices.
So that's why slicing plays
a very important role.
Next, when we get to security at the edge,
this is where some pretty
interesting things can happen.
So over the past decade,
really, we've been talking about
moving applications to the
cloud, it was easy to do,
it's cheaper, it's standardized,
you can go build your
applications to have them move around,
move them around to different clouds.
So that move to the clouds
has been very popular over
the last decade, but now with
the introduction of the edge,
that is this new
decentralization of the cloud
that is happening.
You don't have to move your applications
or keep your applications in
any high latency scenario,
when the edge allows you
to perform those actions
much quicker.
So I want to introduce two
terms, decision latency,
and actions latency.
And it's important in the
IoT security use case,
because when you have things like AI
or machine learning based
threat detection running
at an edge, and you identify
and compromise device
or a scenario, which needs
to be a security scenario
that needs to be rectified immediately,
you have that low latency,
and that low decision latency
to be able to get that
data and make that decision
and then take action that
you're not sending data
all the way back to the
cloud, before you make
the decision and then take that action.
And you have multiple edges
in the 5G world as well,
you have a mobile edge,
which is at the center
of the network.
So that's could be even
deployed on premise,
you have a network edge,
which is within the network
or inside the network core as well.
So depending on your application,
depending on your latency
to see requirements, you could
run your services in either
of these entities.
So examples of security
IoT security services
that can be done that is device identity,
like when you have things
like Narrowband IoT devices,
which have very low bandwidth use cases.
And so you can have a very
heavy authentication algorithm
running all the way back to
the cloud, before you let
that device onto the network.
I just want to wake up five times a day,
and send two kilobits of
data, that's my use case.
But I still need to be secure,
so running some of these services,
these authentication device
identity services at the edge
allows you to do that.
So again, depending on your
application and services,
you have a lot of areas where
you can deploy these security
services.
And this is just an
illustration of that security
at the edge.
When you have a very
type of device deployment
for your IoT ecosystem, you
could use the edge to set up
device adapters, so at
the edge application,
your security application,
could opt to any variety
of devices, without having to
worry about protocols, etc.
So again, we're taking away
that challenge of an idea
of devices.
We're taking away the challenge
that all these devices
cannot be managed by a single application,
because now you're moving
those applications more
to the cloud.
And you can also run these
device adaptor services
at the cloud as well .
Now, we were all familiar
with the zero trust security
model, and because of this
virtualization network slicing
the ability to use the edge to
limit access to the back-end,
you can now deploy this zero
trust security model much more
simpler and much more
quicker with with 5G.
Now all your devices do
not have to talk back
to the back-end application,
you don't have to open up your
firewalls, to 10 20 million
devices that are out
in the field.
You can now limit that to a
small set of edge based devices
or edge based gateways,
that are communicating
to your back-end.
These obviously, these edge
gateways are a lot more powerful
and can have a lot more
security capabilities
and services event.
So, we have a table that we
looked at in the beginning,
and we take a look at that
same table and compare
it to what 5G can do.
So the large volumes
and the different types,
we talked about using
network slices to divvy up
how those devices can connect
to the network more sources
that can get access to,
we can use device adapters
and edge based solutions to
manage all of these devices.
And of course, you can
reduce your risk again,
by enabling network
slicing, and then enabling
security capabilities at
the edge on the system.
So you put all of this together,
and what you have is an
edge based, virtualized,
automated security control
capability that you can deploy.
With the advancements in machine learning,
and threat detection that
are happening in the industry
today, moving those closer to
the device, and using those
to protect the device before
they can impact anything
on the downstream and any of
the services on the downstream
becomes very important.
And enabling that zero trust
environment is also critical.
One thing we all have to remember is that,
at the end of the day,
even though 5G brings
these new capabilities, it is
still a shared security model.
The network is still not
going to be able to protect
the entire ecosystem.
So we must ensure that we have,
that we take responsibility
for the entire into an ecosystem,
and ensure that that is
influencing the insecurity
before we can deploy.
And that's my last message
for your takeaways,
for this session.
So before you start looking
at what IoT deployments
you're ready to make, the
first thing you need to really
understand is how
significantly different IoT
is from existing IT systems.
That understanding is
very critical to ensuring
that you are able to
identify the security gaps,
and the risks that IoT
brings to your investments.
Understanding the capabilities
that 5G brings to the table
is important, because the
5G is gonna be an essential
tool that is gonna help you
secure your IoT ecosystem.
Once you start and get into
the architecture stage,
take a look at your
specific IoT deployment,
what its security needs are,
what the network capabilities
if it requires and then
define what the IoT solutions
that can be used to deploy.
Like, you have to perform
a risk assessment first
to understand what the
risk this deployment brings
to you're own enterprise.
And then based on the security
solutions you're deploying,
you can then define what the
acceptable risk level is.
And that's going to
depend really on your cost
and the capabilities.
Then once you deploy, you
have to continue to monitor
and manage the security
of the entire ecosystem,
and 5G again, that user
domain or application domain
allows you to continuously
improve your security policies
that you're applying to your devices.
Now you can also run testing
and audit capabilities
at the edge as well, so a
lot of capabilities there.
That's the presentation, I
do hope that the presentation
has been useful for you.
Please reach out to me via slider,
or if you have any additional questions.
And my social media, a tag is
available too, so feel free
to contact me if you have any questions
outside of this session.
And again, thank you
for joining the session.
Great to have you and that
was interesting, thank you.