[Music]
welcome everybody thanks for coming i
know it's lunchtime um hopefully we'll
get a few more people in here but if not
we'll still have fun so
welcome to my talk uh quick overview of
what we're going to be talking about
today
a little bit about me uh it's my third
time presenting at last con one of my
favorite conferences so super excited to
be here been doing this some way shape
or form for about 17 years started off
as a full stack developer 17 years ago
we didn't call him that just meant i did
everything from fortran to delphi to
databases to middleware and everything
else
super passionate about appsec devsecops
you know everything that i do kind of
core to my philosophy on appsec and
devsecops what this talk will be all
about today is developer enablement
i'm a big believer that when the secure
path is the easy path
it's the path that will be followed and
i always joke that we have to make
security
easier than going to stack overflow
because we all know how well any of us
can develop without stack overflow
a couple of fun facts married my high
school sweetheart still with her three
lovely kids i love hiking playing video
games play guitar i'm super excited
right now big final fantasy 14 fan we've
got a big expansion drop it in a couple
of weeks and amazon is finally launching
the tv series for will of time so if we
have any big fantasy book nerds i'm
super excited about that
so my thesis for today and this kind of
ties in a little bit to what jeff
williams talked about earlier i'm
convinced he stole a little bit of this
from me um
believe that shift left is an outdated
sentiment um and it's no longer relevant
it has developed into a culture that
primarily exists to punish developers
i'm a big fan of this for champions as
well right i'm thoroughly convinced that
appsec champions is just a way to punish
developers for taking an interest in
security and i think there has to be a
better way and that's what we're going
to talk about today
so i guess just show of hands right how
many of you all are developers
ish one okay how many of you are on a
security or appstack team
okay all right so hopefully everybody
knows what the software development life
cycle is right there there are many like
it this one is mine um you know we've
seen a hundred different variations they
all say somewhat the same thing right
it's everything from requirements to
design to coding testing deployment
maintenance etc i mean we've tried to do
a pretty good job as we move to agile
and devops of creating new sdlcs right
and we've all seen the little infinity
signs and we try to wrap security around
it and many of us have probably even
created some of those in our careers but
at the end of the day right we end up
usually representing it linearly just
because it's easier to to talk about it
so
let's talk a little bit about shift
shift left right let's make sure we all
start on the same page
traditionally where many of us start
with appsec is with penetration testing
and that's still where the market
largely sits today in order to
penetration test our applications
generally have to be live um many of
them have existed for many many years
are very much in the maintenance phase
of the sdlc and so right we've all seen
the scary pictures and the slides of how
much
more it cost us to find and fix
vulnerabilities when the app's already
deployed versus finding and fixing them
early on right so this whole shift left
thing is really all about how do we get
from doing security mostly pin testing
here in the maintenance to ideally doing
security over here in the requirement
space
and having you know secure requirements
right i'm a big believer that security
as code is going to save the world
but right everything we normally talk
about is all how do we do security at
the requirements phase
so i mean this kind of ties into what
jeff said a little bit earlier too as
part of this talk i decided to go out
and just research you know where did
this whole shift left thing
come from uh what are its origins what's
its history and what i found was it was
introduced by larry smith in 2001 and a
little article which i've listed here
i was really surprised when i looked
this up right i thought that i was going
to find an article about pen testing and
getting security into the requirements
phase right we've all seen our vendors
talk they all talk about hey we give you
an ide plug-in right this is shifting
left we're giving it to the developers
and that's really what we talked about
today was security same thing even if we
talk agile and defsec ups right it's all
about how do we take x tool and how do
we put it into our devops or our ci cd
pipeline and it's focused purely on
automation
well this this paper really surprised me
because it wasn't about pin testing at
all it was written by a qa guy who was
talking in 2001 20 years ago about
taking qa tests
and doing security testing
via qa testing and doing them earlier in
the software development life cycle
right and this is a direct quote from
this guy bugs are cheap when caught
young you can catch bugs earlier by
making qa a part of your development not
just part of the release process right
you know
go to any devsecops talk today right and
that's what people like me are going to
be telling you so again this really
surprised me 20 years ago we had this
idea
right so you know where did we go so
wrong
um you know this is another quote you
know directly from this article by by
this larry guy uh i'm not gonna read all
of this but you know it's
he's saying that there's downsides to
this method and that your security work
is going to go away it's going to look
like you're doing nothing and you need
to level set with management first to
make sure that you don't get fired for
being so good at your job
which again is absolutely phenomenal how
closely this ties in you know to what we
talk about today with devsecops
so josh everybody loves shift left why
do you hate it so much
well
primarily first bullet here security
responsibilities are giving to
developers without any thought regarding
the impact right so we take complicated
security tools that are designed for
security people and then we give them to
the developers and we expect them to to
use that right we go out and we buy
training right i kind of got booed a
little bit here two years ago at last
con because i made the boat statement of
uh appsec training is not working right
you know sql injection we were writing
books on sql injection in 1995 i've
given countless developer training
classes we're still making the same very
very basic mistakes right i kind of
chuckled in jeff's talk yesterday for
those of you that were there when he was
talking about instrumentation
right and he did the sql injection
example where he said okay if you're
using this method this method and this
method that's bad let's flag it let's
block it right and then he made the
statement of if you're using a prepared
statement let's let that through because
you're secure if you're using a prepared
statement
that's not true we could use a prepared
statement and we could use it improperly
i've seen countless times where you know
developers just take a dynamic sql query
and they just wrap it in a prepared
statement and they don't actually
parameterize any of the queries well
guess what you have zero of your
protections at that point and you might
as well just be executing just a normal
query
um shift left in my opinion has been
poorly implemented
we're punishing our developers right you
know for those of you in security i'm
sure you've gotten pushed back from your
developers plenty of times you know why
should i fix that hey what the hell does
c surf actually mean can you even
describe it to me um this tool is really
hard for me to use it's um
you know i love to pick on
like secure assist and similar tools
right because to security people they
sound absolutely perfect on paper hey we
can prevent vulnerabilities as the
developer is writing them
and just squash them in their tracks
right but the end result of that what we
don't think about is that impact to the
developer in that we are preventing them
from writing code
i spent many years working for ernst
young and we had this study that was all
about multitasking and the whole idea
was nobody can multitask
and every interruption that we have that
takes us off of a focused task
it takes the human mind 22 minutes on
average to refocus on a particular task
so you know every email we read right
we're losing 22 minutes of focus this is
why we all have add now
and so when we have these type of tools
right every time we stop the developer
from writing code we're effectively
eliminating 22 minutes of productivity
so again getting back to this message of
we're punishing our developers
whether we're instead of enabling them
and then right developer performance
reviews do not include security right we
want we love champions we talk about
scaling our appsec program by taking
developers and again you know punishing
them and part of that is we very rarely
make security part of how they're scored
and graded on their performance so we
want to tell them hey you know you need
to take instead of doing 100 of your
time on development and writing features
and doing this cool stuff you're not
going to spend 75 percent of your time
on that and 25 doing security but oh by
the way we're not going to give you a
cool title we're not going to give you a
pay increase i mean we're not going to
change how you're reviewed in your
performance criteria so you know good
luck meeting all your targets but now
you have 75 of your time
so long story short right i think shift
left is great uh conceptually but i
think you know in getting back to larry
smith's article right we had it right 20
years ago but just went incredibly wrong
along the
way that's all great let's talk about
solutions
um
i first ran across this concept of the
inner loop a few years ago this was
actually brought to me by one of my
financial services clients um who had in
my opinion a very great idea but again
they kind of translated it to shift left
and and went really wrong with it so uh
inner loop you know inner loop outer
loop is something you can google right
um you know a lot of this content came
from mitch denney who was a developer
from microsoft and in his original
article this link won't actually work
you'll have to use the wayback machine
because the site's no longer live but he
wrote a blog post that was talking about
how they write code at microsoft
and using this concept of the inner loop
now the inner loop is it's nothing i
created it's nothing microsoft created
it's been used for a very long time
everything from software development
project planning automobile
manufacturing the list goes on and on
and on right you know the only novel
thing we've done here today is we've
adapted it to work for application
security
so what is the inner loop essentially
and you'll have to forgive my uh my
graphics i don't work at ey anymore so i
don't have cool designers so i have to
work on
what the powerpoint designer builds for
me so
it's basically
all of the activities that occur
from the time the developer starts
developing
until they commit their code to a local
get repository so everything that occurs
after that push to the local get is
considered the outer loop so basically
you can think of this as the developer's
local development cycle
so to kind of help you you see this
visually right you know we
kind of break this down into a software
development life cycle we have lots of
inner loops
and one outer loop so here on the left
right so i guess first of all we've got
preview steps right because there are
security things that happen before we
start developing we talked about you
know doing security in the requirements
phase you know threat modeling
architecture reviews things like that
that happen prior to development right
we want to be clear that those are kind
of out of scope for this conversation
because they happen prior to any of the
development actually starting
on the left-hand side we've got the
actual inner loop which is what we'll be
focusing on today the inner loop
consists of coding
building
testing and committing right nothing
crazy here we're not setting the world
on fire um you know here in the middle
right we've got a pull request
to push our code out to
you know some other source code
repository into our bucket or azure or
wherever we're storing our source code
right and once it goes there we enter
what we call the outer loop
and then within the outer loop right you
know again you know just to kind of try
to simplify this a little bit right
there could be lots of inner loops right
we're not writing waterfall you know
type code anymore we've got a lot of
developers writing and pushing a lot of
code so typically we're going to have
you know many many many inner loops that
are going to be pushing code into this
outer loop
and if we look at it a little bit more
linearly
you know you've probably seen similar
diagrams to this before right and i'm
just trying to take a you know kind of a
kind of an apsec architecture here and
just kind of draw the line on where the
inner loop and the outer loop actually
is so again you know nothing novel here
right we've got you know our user
stories and sprints up here in the top
left right once we've got our stories
which hopefully we have security stories
too we go into our threat modeling and
architecture reviews hopefully we're
doing that before we write code then we
get to coding
then we get to pushing our code to
source control right then we get to our
build system which is where we do all of
these other things that we hear about
everything from static analysis right
we've got all of our automated testing
this is what your vendors are telling
you to do hey let's take all of our
tools let's put them in your pipeline
let's create bottlenecks to your release
all of this good stuff but right we've
got our sass or dash or is security is
code qa testing you know whatever
acronym it is you're using for all your
security testing this is probably where
it lifts today right after you've pushed
your code into your build system and
then it flows and right your flow
probably looks a little bit different
but some sort of change management to
get the code out there all of these
defects hopefully go to some sort of
vulnerability management you know maybe
even jira and given that information
back to the developers short feedback
loops all of that good stuff
right so
right here this green box at source
control where we've done that pull
request to push our code
that's where the outer loop starts right
you know if we get back to you know this
slide here once we've got the pull
request we're entering the outer loop
so so really the key takeaway here
is
probably most if not all of any security
testing that you're doing today is
happening
here
and it's happening in what we're
referring to is the outer loop
right and so what i want to convince you
is to do security testing in the inner
loop
so how do we do this right there's a
couple of things that you need to
understand about this inner loop model
first right and this is where we tie
this back to that developer enablement
right so some key tenants of the inner
loop right that have to hold true
first
is the inner loop execution has to be
fast as possible
right raise your hand if you think any
of our security testing tools we have
today are fast
all right all right
and what tool is that
now secure okay all right
for this we do what we call smoke test
okay so it's designed to
in five
okay
that's that's a fair argument
all right and the second key tenant yeah
[Music]
one of the things that we'll talk about
is the qa testing aspect of that which
is where the smoke testing comes in you
know and kind of how that fits into both
the inner and outer loop and that is one
of the things that we can do in the
inner loop is a minor spoiler
so the second key tenant is feedback
time should be minimized but quality
optimized all right so again right
you've all heard about the developer
feedback loop and you know the amount of
time from the time we test until we tell
developers there's a problem to the
amount of time that it's actually fixed
right what jeff referred to as the mean
time to resolution
then finally
tax should be minimized waste should be
eliminated
right what is tax what is waste well
there's some handy definitions here that
you can read but essentially tax is any
activity that does not provide um
customer value or feedback right it's a
necessary evil right it's something that
we have to do but we need to minimize
that and waste is just like tax except
they're arguably unnecessary activities
so you know if we think about those four
phases of the interlude coding building
testing committee there's only one of
these that actually builds any business
or customer value
that's coding
right everything else building testing
committing is just supporting that right
it's not adding any value to to what we
do
but building and testing we have to do
and they provide feedback to us right if
we try to build our code and it doesn't
build well our compiler gives us
feedback and says dude something went
wrong you've got an error on line 157
you need to fix it right same thing with
testing right testing is all about
giving us feedback about the code that
we wrote
committing
is a necessary evil right it doesn't
give us feedback it doesn't really
provide value it's just a way for us to
get our code from point a to point b and
it's something that we have to do right
and the inner loop model would argue
that that's a waste
so
my argument here is that conventional
appsec tooling introduces large amounts
of tax and waste
and just like real life right you don't
want to pay a whole bunch of taxes
right same thing an inner loop right so
how can we
do appsec without creating
a bunch of tax and waste
so what i'd like to do now is just kind
of have some thought
exercises and you know when we started
building this at ui you know this is we
had a lot of conversations around this
because you know a bunch of smart people
uh people who've been consulting for 10
20 years right many of us uh you know so
actually you know many of us came from
aspect security you know working with
you know bright minds like jeff williams
and dave wickers um you know ey actually
bought aspect security in 2017 um and we
built out ey zapsec program so a lot of
just very smart you know founders of oh
wasp and such you know working on this
and just kind of thinking okay well
let's start taking some of these things
we do in apsec and just try to answer
the question of
is it a good inner loop activity so
instead of saying right because the
difference here is today we say all
right well how do we shift left
cool well let's take um pick your
favorite or least favorite sass product
um that has a developer ide integration
so we're going to give it to our
developers good job we've shifted left
we wrote a wiki for our developers that
they're never going to read good job
we've shifted left but have we really
actually moved the needle
we haven't right
we've really just burdened developers
so let's talk about static analysis so
um love to have some interaction here
right so you know using the concepts of
tax and waste and the things that we've
introduced today
do you think static analysis would be a
good activity for the inner loop
any any thoughts if it was fast enough
if it was fast enough okay
any other thoughts or opinions
it generates a fair lack of false
positive false negatives
all right
i wouldn't in its current form because
the majority of sac analysis focuses on
finding lots of things all at the same
time
if
from a conceptual standpoint if you
could look for one thing really
accurately in that interlude
and
and do it then it would make sense to do
that one thing that's not really how any
of the commercials are structured
they're structured in an
assessment-centric approach if you could
do it in an atomic approach where you're
looking for one thing and you want to
eradicate that one thing at a time uh
then then that would make sense for the
interview but i don't think any of the
tools today
are organized that way to make it make
sense
yeah yeah i'd agree with pretty much all
of that right so and again there's no
right or wrong answers to any of this
this is really just thought exercises so
uh i would argue static analysis is not
a good inner loop tool right because the
long scan times lead to
tax
false positives are an absolute waste
um you know it takes considerable
expertise to actually run the tools and
configure them properly which is an
additional tax we have the scan
configuration itself which is even more
tax right so if we measure the amount of
tax and waste that this tool would
generate um you know i believe that it's
not a good fit for the inner loop
what about dast
any any thoughts on dust
it's kind of the same thing right
so you'd have dest
first of all it has to be a web app and
it has to be running
right we can't just pull a rip cord on a
source code repository or something and
have it go out or take a look at our
pull request the app has to be deployed
and configured and running right i
love picking on das tools just because i
hate
the messaging uh around them and the way
the vendors present them right i've been
doing this long enough i'm jaded on just
about every tool but um
when i talk about defsec ops right and
this is another talk right i think i
talked about this here three years ago
right i always frame it i used to frame
it as comms right now i'm a big fan of
the calmer methodology from the scaled
agile framework of culture automation
lean measurement and what is it recovery
um and to me i believe that all five of
those key pillars apply to devsecops and
appsec at scale as well right and so if
the only thing that we're doing with our
tooling is automating it which is what
many of our vendors are doing then we're
only hitting one of those five key
pillars of devops or devsecops right and
again getting back to this message of
not adding a lot of value and every das
tool out there today now has an
integration into
the build pipelines right and they all
advertise that it's a def sec ops tool
because we can scan your application as
part of your deployment process well
most of the organizations that i've
worked with in my consulting career are
not at a devops level of maturity
where they can do an automated
deployment to an ephemeral server
you know and configure authentication
and access control and things of that
nature right and if you're not at a
level of maturity where you can do that
it really doesn't make sense to have das
even in your pipeline at all because
otherwise you're still just doing the
same thing which is you know configuring
it to run against a static host with
static credentials or something of that
nature
um we do have you know compared to sas
less waste in our output
because the results of dast are more
accurate right so so that is kind of a
small plus to it we do have varying scan
times right you know i've worked with
clients that had scan times of a week
with das tools right and that doesn't
make sense in anybody who says they're
doing agile and the resource can results
can be inconsistent right that's another
common flaw with these tools is you run
a report once and you get a set of
findings and you run it again and the
findings don't match from report a to
report b because they're dynamically
generating you know the malicious input
that it's sending into the http request
so sometimes you hit these edge cases
right or maybe one time you know it
sends that perfect cross-site scripting
test and gets a result but the next five
scans it doesn't and it looks like you
fixed the problem but you really didn't
and so even if tax and waste were
minimized
we've got to have the app deployed so
typically that's going to put us into
the outer loop with dast
all right manual pin testing
no right it's uh we're not anywhere
close with manual pin testing um
what about software composition analysis
any any thoughts on software composition
analysis
good the best time to identify a poor
choice is right after you made it not
two months after you started using it
yeah
so
uh kind of when we wrap this up here in
a little bit right we'll see software
composition analysis is an item that can
exist in the inner loop my problem with
it is that's not how most people are
using it right most of the tools that we
have today right they're being deployed
in kind of a scanning mode you know
where once a day or once a week or when
a new cve comes out right we configure
white source sunotype black duck or
whatever to go scan a bunch of our
applications and tell us if it found
that particular thing right it's if
we're running them very uh reactively
another big thing with with the sky
tools is it's difficult to determine the
actual impact uh and i hate to keep
referring back to jeff williams talk but
he made a lot of great points right and
especially in my high maturity clients
particularly in the financial services
space
right they they push back against these
type of tools because their developers
have been doing apsec for a long time
and so when security comes in and says
hey did you know this library that
you're implemented has a cv it has a
cvss score of 10 in the cve in it you
need to update that
well developers are generally smart they
don't say okay cool let me go take a
month and re-architect my app or however
long they say
well am i actually using the vulnerable
library
um they're the vulnerable code right and
how many of you in this room have read a
cve before
right almost everybody
most the time a cve does not tell you
how to reproduce the vulnerability
and it doesn't tell you where the
vulnerable code is in the library right
it's it's basically a black hole and so
you're telling developers that you have
a problem in a library and you have to
go and you have to patch it and you have
to update but we have no way to prove to
you whether or not you're actually using
that vulnerable code
right and in what world does that make
sense
it really doesn't if you're a developer
right so getting back to punishing our
developers
we have had a lot of really cool
innovations in these tools in the last
year or two but not a lot of people are
using them right and this is where the
interloop stuff comes in right so for
one
a lot of these tools can now do kind of
this real quick scanning as you make
changes to your library right you know
so if you go out and you add a line to
your pom file you know for your maven
build or if you go get a nuget library a
lot of these integrations can now say oh
hey did you know that that library that
you're pulling in right now you know has
some key concerns right maybe you should
consider using this version um that
doesn't have these issues right would
you like to do that instead yes or no
cool let's let's swap that for you right
that can be very valuable
um and also you know some of the newer
tools right now i love this right we'll
actually do pull requests for you so
like snick has a new feature that's been
added recently where if you have snick
and it's kind of outer loopy but if it's
in your ci cd pipeline and it detects a
vulnerable library that has been pushed
in that pull request
it will actually break the build
put in the new library for you and then
create a pull request and send it out
for you to approve and if you approve
that pull request
it'll actually update to a
non-vulnerable version of that library
for you right now it's a little scary
because you know who knows what other
issues that can introduce you know kind
of like i asked right you better make
sure you have a high maturity in qa
testing you know if you're going to do
something like that right so you can
catch those issues if it does
you know bring in some unwanted features
or something like that into your code
uh security is code um is anybody i
guess kind of show of hands right who
who's familiar with securities code
okay not too many so
to me
security as code is really
doing security
inside of our qa test right it's kind of
the simplified version of it um
again this could be a whole other
conference talk but you know to me it's
much deeper than that right because it's
all about how you know we take security
requirements um and one make sure we're
doing them making sure we have them uh
having agreed upon security controls
that can enforce and implement those
requirements for us the qa test case
that then validates that that control
has been implemented
and then you know the actual test case
executing right so to me this is part of
the key of defsec ops right you know
this gives that traceability from
requirements all the way to test to
reporting and most importantly it
focuses on the control as opposed to the
vulnerability so um
i love using cross-site scripting as an
example of this right because you know
if a ciso comes to me today and ever
asks hey
can can you say with confidence that
there is no cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities in this application
right never in my career will i be able
to say with a hundred percent certainty
no there are not cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities in your app right i can
say some fluffy stuff like hey we did a
pen test and we didn't find any or we
ran a tool and we didn't find any but
does that mean that there's not any
it absolutely does not right but with
security as code
we can agree with the cso on a control
that would prevent cross-site scripting
um
so let's say you know it's a i don't
know a library or you know maybe the
whatever microsoft calls it now right it
used to be the anti-xss framework inside
of.net right we can agree on
compensating controls that prevent that
vulnerability
well then we can use security as code
to prove that that control has been
implemented and configured properly
and validate that the developer turn
those controls on and they're using them
right and this has a lot of downstream
benefits right for one we're looking at
controls not hunting an endless list of
vulnerabilities that we'll never catch
up with um
but further
right if cso comes back and asks that
question about hey do i have cross-site
scripting vulnerabilities i can look at
the test results and i can say with
confidence that
we agreed on this control to prevent
cross-site scripting and i can show you
with 100 certainty that this control has
been implemented and configured properly
so we're theoretically safe from
cross-site scripting right and it also
takes the burden off of some of these
other things we do right if we if we
agreed on a security control and we
proved that it's there do we need to
test for cross-site scripting in a pen
test anymore
probably not right do we need to
configure our sas tool to look for
cross-site scripting
probably not right it's just going to
give us a bunch of false positives
anyway because it's probably not going
to detect your library um so it's just
going to be a lot more tax and waste so
that's kind of a quick intro to security
as code um but you know to me that's
it's going to be kind of our lifesaver
in the next few years with devsecopt
so
uh securities code right it can be in
both the inner and the outer loop right
because some of if we think of qa
testing
it depends on the type of qa test that
we're doing right you know to your point
about smoke test right if we're doing
you know unit test functional testing of
security controls well yeah those can
absolutely be in the inner loop and the
developer can run those locally but a
lot of our tests you know integration
test and end test etc you know typically
our app has to be out you know deployed
or you know with all of its other
controls out there right so that kind of
by nature has to be in the in the outer
loop
um and then we can even execute these as
a pre-commit hook so you know if we
think about that shift from the inner to
outer loop you know we can use security
as code as almost a quality assurance
gate from getting from the inner loop to
the outer loop
all right so let's let's talk a little
more about how we can actually use this
in the real world
so first i'm gonna have kind of again my
background being big four and ey this is
kind of my
fluffy buzzword slide right so you're
performing security inside the inner
loop drives a shift left culture and
shortens developer feedback loops to
release code at high velocity by
leveraging secure by design principles
and i would challenge you to find
anything more buzz wordy than that here
today
all right now again all our big four
you're gonna see some slides that have a
lot of words and really crowded content
here right but really what i want you to
walk away with is
that i'm not saying move to the inner
loop forget the outer loop forget
everything you've ever learned about
shift left or anything of that nature
right what i want you to walk away with
is that the inner loop and the outer
loop
can work together right and we we need
to do you know testing and security
activities on kind of both sides on of
that fence right so we want to focus on
you know putting controls and testing
into the inner loop where it makes sense
right because that's our most cost
effective place right is we all know
through shift left to do our security
testing but what i want you to do
is think about it before you do it right
you know take that step back think about
the developers
think about how much tax and how much
waste that you're introducing
by putting that security activity into
the inner loop and then question
if that's something you should be doing
and how much value
you're actually providing to your
organization
and scalability right outer loop testing
is difficult
to scale
again back to jeff williams talk this
morning right we've only got so many
tools they have a lot of problems we
only have so many security engineers
only so many apsec unicorns
only so many champions um etc right and
everything we do in the outer loop is
going to cost resources you know
regardless of whether that's you know an
engineer to integrate it into our 700
pipelines are creating a bunch of
jenkins files that the developers are
going to delete or change anyway or
you know even just impact to our
pipeline right because every one of
these tools we put into our ci cd
pipeline introduces a bottleneck so any
of those that we can do in the inner
loop right we can start removing those
from the outer loop
and then we want to empower development
teams so again getting back to developer
enablement when the secure path is the
easy path right i'm a big believer that
it's the path that will be followed
however we as security practitioners
often make the secure path the most
difficult one right you know to the
point where developers are trying to
disable our tools or take them out of
their pipelines or they're questioning
our results right because we're
introducing impact to them
often without any value right so getting
back to our analogy with software
composition analysis right we're asking
them to spend time fixing issues
that actually aren't an issue at all
right and then we kind of get all pissed
off when they push back at us and don't
want to fix these problems right um you
know one of my favorite interview
questions you know that i ask every
single person that i interview for my
organization
is around sql injection right we talked
about parameterized queries early on in
this talk
and the question i always ask them
especially in pen tester roles is
i assume you've done a pin test and you
found a sql injection vulnerability and
you're sitting there at the readout
table with the development team telling
them about all these problems you found
you're beating up their app their baby
and then you tell them the same thing
you know oh wasp or that we've said for
25 years right hey i found a sql
injection problem you know you need to
use a prepared statement parameterize
query to fix this and you're good so go
do that and have a good day
well what if the developer says
well
i'm not dumb i took that training class
i read that owasp site i'm using a
prepared statement
right well as as the pen tester
what's your response to that right and
the vast majority of the time from pin
testers they jump they jump to an answer
like well i'm gonna pull up sql map
right there in front of them and turn my
computer around and show them that i
exploited it so they're not doing that
right and it automatically turns into a
combative situation right and really the
answer that i'm looking for with those
interviews is for somebody who can think
outside the box right who understands
this stuff at a deeper level than just a
quick obos particle um you know because
the obvious answer is they didn't use
that prepared statement properly
right and i've seen this time and time
again in organizations right if you're
not actually parameterizing those inputs
that prepared statement does not fix sql
injection right so you know i'm looking
for pin testers who can take that step
back right try to work with them to
figure out
what they're doing wrong and then help
them fix it right as opposed to
immediately turning it around into a
combative situation
so inner loop testing right to do enter
loop right right think about
self-service security we're doing this
fairly well today right a lot of
organizations have been embracing
self-service security for a very long
time but take it to the next step right
and make sure that the tooling is fast
and it's accurate right and that's not
something we do a very good job of today
secure by design right this one's kind
of a free space right if you're doing
secure by design you're pretty good here
and then rapid developer feedback loops
right so the short the quicker you get
this information back to the devs right
you're better you know outer loop
testing focus on automation first um but
again don't forget about all those other
letters within comma as well right you
know make sure that your tests are lean
that you're actually measuring things
right that you're actually driving
culture and it's not just automation for
the sake of automation
focus on depth and rigor right we can't
get depth and rigor in the out in the
inner loop do it in the out in the outer
loop instead
and then security control testing so
again you know in your culture focus on
you know really just the shift away from
you know how many vulnerabilities can i
discover to you know what are the
security controls that we need to have
in place
um
right because i mean we've all run
static analysis tools before i've run
them and they come back and say hey you
have 60 000 vulnerabilities then we've
got to triage them we put them into a
pdf report we give them to people they
never fix it maybe even worse we've
listened to some def sec ops talks
before um and we try to take those 60
000 vulnerabilities and put them into
their jira system um and tell the
developers that they're defects and to
fix them right and again we're not
enabling developers at that point we're
pissing them off
but at some point we have to stop
chasing vulnerabilities we're never
going to win as long as we're chasing
vulnerabilities right so we need to have
this paradigm shift where we start
thinking about security controls how to
implement strong controls how to
validate that they're there and then
report them in a way that makes sense
right
and a great example of this is
cross-site request forgery
um you know cross-site request forgery
for one
most people can't explain what it means
anyway let alone to a developer so every
time we put it into a report we probably
put it as a low
right and the cso says hey what's this
sea surf thing why is it a low what's it
mean i don't know but it's a low so you
don't need to fix it anytime soon uh
right that's what i've seen time and
time again throughout my years in
consulting well
did you know if you have to comply with
pci
and you have a cross-site request
forgery vulnerability in your
application you are not in compliance
with pci
that's pretty scary right so now instead
when we have that conversation with the
cso if we can present this data in such
a way you know to show that hey we've
got the c surf thing and we can't really
explain it to you but now it's a
critical and it's a red on this pci
report because we're not in compliance
with pci so we really need to fix this
guess what you're going to get the
support to squash that vulnerability and
hopefully figure out how to get some
anti-sea surf controls throughout your
applications
all right so you know what tools you
know do look good
in the outer loop and this is going to
be all the stuff
that you already know right this is all
the tools that you're already using
today right static analysis again
great tool in the outer loop poor tool
in the inner loop same thing with dast
right software composition analysis you
know right there is some inner loop
functionality there but today largely
exist in the outer loop
um even i asked
right it's we've heard for a long time
that iast is going to save the world um
but you know to really get value out of
a lot of these is tools right we can't
just go out and buy an eye ass tool and
dump it into our environment and scan
and get good results right you know they
rely on instrumentation and they rely on
us exercising the application and
calling that functionality so in other
words we have to have strong qa testing
you know within our applications in
order to have good results for my ass
which you know again you know take even
take something new and cool and
innovative like i asked and kind of puts
it firmly into the outer loop
and then manual pen testing right it's a
manual activity it's always going to be
in the outer loop
so so what are some cool things that we
can do in the outer loop or in the inner
loop you know to kind of move the needle
on our program and make things at least
a little bit better for developers so
these are just some of the things i've
come up with you know you might have
more again this is a thought exercise
more than than anything right you know i
don't want you to walk away and say hey
i need to do all of these things and
implement them today but just you know
whenever you're thinking about
introducing a new tool or a new process
or anything into your security program
you know to just step back think about
this inner outer loop and think about
the impact that you're going to have to
your development teams and then make the
decision based on that right that's what
this is all about but get get pre uh get
commit pre-hooks you know can be a great
inner loop activity right that doesn't
mean take all of these outer loop things
and cram them in as a pre-commit hook
and execute them before that pull
request you know gets accepted or or
whatever right um you know
lightweight testing generally you know
the smoke test those qa style test cases
right those very fast accurate you know
millisecond um you know qa tests that we
can run to validate controls at that
point
all right lightweight software
composition analysis so we talked about
how we do have you know some of these
products now are introducing features
where they can test so they look at your
pom files when you drop a new library in
there you nougat chocolatey your npm
whatever it may be right and when the
developer makes that change to that
configuration let them know at that time
that they have introduced a library that
may have
a vulnerability in it and that there is
a safe version available that they can
use right we're not introducing tax
we're
arguably not introducing waste
and it's a change that they can make
immediately without having to
re-architect their app hopefully
continuous security lenders spell
checkers right to be clear i don't think
these tools are here today right you
know getting back to you know our
earlier messaging about um
you know taking the developers out of
the moment losing 22 minutes of
productivity every time we interrupt
them
you know while they're writing code etc
but i do think there's future here right
we've come a long way with just kind of
you know machine learning and you know
auto complete type of stuff you know in
gmail now i can pretty much open gmail
and hit tab 12 times and have a pretty
bloody good email that i can just hit
send and i didn't have to write any of
that myself right it just did it all for
me um github has i don't remember what
it's called right but they have the new
autopilot thing you know where it's you
know going to save the world and write
code for you right and i don't think
we're seeing that yet we're seeing it do
a lot of weird things but there's a
tremendous amount of potential there so
you know i think as vendors kind of pick
up on this and write tools that can you
know do you know things like you know
solar sonar lint um you know secure
assist those type of tools right as
those tools mature get better um and can
actually make you know quality
recommendations without interrupting the
developer
this could be a fantastic inner loop
tool but again i don't think we're there
today um every organization i've worked
with that has used those tools um the
developers have fought them and disabled
them because it's too impactful
and then security is code so again
getting back to that lightweight you
know qa testing of security controls
again not scanning for vulnerabilities
not running scanners but instead a qa
style test to validate
if our agreed upon controls are in place
it is another fantastic introduction to
the inner loop
so in conclusion right couple couple
takeaways here right so first of all
there is no right amount
of tax and waste
this is going to be different for every
organization right and you'll have to
work with your teams to figure out what
that right balance is for you right a
lot of my background has been in working
with large financials um and a lot of
large financials have no problem saying
all of our developers are going to run
sas and they're going to get over it and
that's an appropriate amount of tax and
waste for us right so um you know just
just know there is no right or wrong
answer work with your teams figure out
what's impactful and what's not
and always you know focus on reducing
that tax
and
eliminating waste right so if you have
wrote out a tool if you are using them
today you know start to think about that
impact that you're having on your
development teams and what you can do to
make those tools easier to use
faster
more reliable right picking the right
tool
for the right job
um you know an insecurity is code and
things of that nature and when you pick
that right tool for the right job you're
going to be minimizing that tax and that
waste
and then again continuous improvement we
talk about a lot in any devops talk
right and from a devsecops perspective
you know continuous improvement is going
to be equal to continuously reducing
that tax and waste and your developers
are only going to be thankful that
you're taking some of these painful
things away from them
so that's all for me any questions
thoughts uh is this
garbage
good thinking what do you think
awesome
all right
well thank you very much for coming and
i hope you all enjoy the rest your time
at last con
[Applause]