this is uh my email you can try to reach
me there i will honestly say i'm in the
middle of not one a bankruptcy and a
lawsuit so i'm not really responding to
email all that much these days but if
you say it's important or you have a
quick question feel free to send it off
and i will try to get back to you
i have to actually read you these
disclaimers according to the california
bar association
if this presentation were legal advice
it would be followed by a bill
standard lawyer joke
no attorney-client relationship is
formed by the fact that i'm giving you
this talk
and
everything contained herein is for
educational purposes only
it is halloween
and i was gonna try to wear my deadpool
costume
um
and i have after i put this thing on
i realized there was no way you can
actually see and i have no idea how ryan
reynolds did this for hours and hours
and hours so
sorry deadpool
oh wait wait i have a picture i'm having
trouble with uh powerpoint again did i
mention i'm not a powerpoint person
i should have kate do this
i can click in the middle thank you
um this is deadpool i thought deadpool
was appropriate because we're gonna talk
about insurance interns it's all about
pools that was my connection i put the
costume on this morning
oh my god it's hot
and i can't see out of it so sorry i'm
not in halloween costume sorry you don't
have a
female version of the deadpool so let's
talk about
um
risk and cyber insurance and also uh one
other slight disclaimer as i was
re-preparing for this i realized that i
have stacks and stacks of paper there's
tons of actual
minute details and differentiations in
this area of insurance and law so i'm
gonna actually have to refer to notes
and because it would they wouldn't all
fit on the slides
and if i get something wrong again full
disclaimer no turning client privilege
created um i actually was mostly a cyber
security professional even though i got
my jd back in 1995 i didn't go back to
it was always like my side hustle right
okay you're the
you're the ids biz dev person hey can
you look at the contract but for the
last five years i actually have been
doing law and
this area of cyber insurance is one that
even i wouldn't touch
so
most of us have a concept of insurance
right and the whole point of insurance
is to
identify the risks that's like step
number one it's super important that's
where everybody who is in software
development compliance
risk management needs to participate and
assist your client or your company in
understanding the risk and then
on the insurance side we have some
methodologies that we can attempt to use
to manage that risk and they generally
fall into the four categories we can
accept the risk that's again where it's
incredibly important to try to have
actual good data facts and figures to
assess that risks if you're going to
accept it you want to know what it's
likely going to cost you
you can try to avoid it putting in a
mitigation
or a remediation
and you can try to mitigate the risk
through some internal processes controls
or you can try to transfer it so
insurance falls in the area of
mitigation and transfer that's what
we're trying to do with our insurance
coverage we're trying to mitigate and
transfer the risk
um
now there's also
uh just like
cyber security the insurance world is
full of its own lexicon
and it is even to someone who actually
knows how to read legal documents it is
highly confusing
uh the notion of a first party risk
versus a third party risk is incredibly
nuanced and easy to confuse
my shorthand for it and we're going to
go into it in more detail
is
first party risks are things that happen
to you because of you
and third-party risks are things that
happen to others because of you so it's
all about you know what happens to us
but that nuance around because of you
can be very subtle because because of
you could mean you chose this vendor
instead of that vendor oh my gosh can
you imagine if you're in retail and you
have a pax point of sale system right
now with the fbi knocking on your door
okay that's my nightmare fbi knocking on
my door which did happen to me a few
times at first point is actually my
biggest nightmare they're nice guys but
you really don't want them knocking on
your door
so there are some risks under insurance
that you cannot wave transfer and
mitigate or avoid so it's really
important to understand those and to
know that this is something you're going
to have to deal with internally as
opposed to try to get your cyber
insurance provider or your vendors to
help you with and the first one and this
is actually we're going to go into a lot
of detail about this it's a very
esoteric area of law
um called work product privilege
and the failure to create the proper
control group
and so if you ever hear work product or
control group my advice is to leave
immediately because you're about to go
down a rabbit hole and you may end up
you know that 24 hours that dan was
talking about it's going to turn into
28 hours in the day you're going to be
working
and the second area of risk that can be
transferred is remediation you can't say
but if i make a mistake even if it's a
genuine mistake um you cyber insurance
company have to cover my remediation
costs
except in a very rare exception
the insurance company is only typically
obligated it's a contract principle to
put you in the position that you would
have been before the incident so they're
not going to help pay for all the
remediation costs that your
forensics team might turn up as
desirable
so
for most of us in software development
or in compliance service management that
means the cost associated with fixing a
vulnerability is on you
and
the cost associated with figuring out
what that vulnerability is might also be
on you
so it's not it's important if you're
help trying to help your ciso or your
general manager understand where you
think the line is in your risk level
it's important to really realize some of
these costs are always going to be on us
and that's easy to forget when you're
talking to insurance people
there's one tiny little exception which
is that your cyber insurance might cover
replacement of physical hardware if it's
actually damaged by an attack and
believe it or not this actually does
happen
um
it's not
in some of the more sophisticated
attacks we've certainly seen where
people
figure out what your what your wide area
nexus access controller is and they'll
try to either overrun it or damage it
i've got a case actually right now where
that actually probably happened and um
this was one area we were able to go
back to them and say no no you need to
you need to pay to replace that but it's
something we forget easily forget um but
it can be it can be part of your
coverage
okay now here we get into the long
incredibly boring parts of cyber
insurance but they're also kind of
important to understand
so
i have this giant list of them here and
i'm going to just give you a couple of
highlights and
i think i put these in the notes in the
slides so you can refer back to them
um and if not
somebody will remind me and i'll put
them in the notes and the slides all
refer back to them
so we have um vendor acquisition now
vendor acquisition is not
the third party risk that you might
think of under your pci dss it's not
doing third party assessments or
requesting risk assessments from the
vendors you're going to hire
this is hiring the people that are going
to help you if you have an incident
and so that is an example of a cost that
is typically covered under your cyber
insurance policy
legal representation
for regulators
and there is a big nuance right now
about pci how many people here deal with
pci
yeah there's a big nuance right now with
um because
most cyber insurance covers
regulatory
and the representation against with
regulatory committees and fines
so
that would be hipaa is a clear example
if the ocr the office of civil rights
who is actually the enforcement body for
hipaa comes knocking on your door and
you need to hire a hipaa specific
attorney and then they maybe they fine
you that is an example of a regulatory
service and a regulatory fee you may
have there's an argument right now
around pci because pci
is technically not a government
regulatory body it is a vendor
association there's a recent case where
the pci
the piece the pci fines and they do call
them fines visa calls them fines
where they actually went back and looked
at the merchant agreement and they
decided they were assessments
not fines
not covered
um so if you deal with pci
very important that you make you let the
folks know who are dealing with their
cyber cyber insurance
um to carefully look at their merchant
advance their merchant their merchant
agreements
and make sure that they're not they're
being tagged as fees not not assessments
and i don't know who knows what's going
to happen there um i feel sorry for the
people who pay insurance and think
they're covered and then end up having
to pay twice but that's the way the law
works it's constantly moving um it's a
marathon not a sprint
uh so uh specific regulatory fines like
we're all wondering what's going to
happen with the latest ransomware uh
with colonial pipeline they're certainly
going to be assessed probably ferc
um
a federal
regulatory energy committee and nerc
nuclear whatever they are they're
probably certainly going to be fined
under um nercsip and we're going to look
and we're going to we're waiting to see
whether that is actually covered under
cyber insurance that'll be that'll be a
very interesting one
notification cost if you have a data
breach or if you have a contractual
obligation
for notifying you can typically get
those that's an area of coverage that
you can elect
pr costs
you can actually
get a crisis pr
vendor and they will pay for the cost of
that
then there's the cost of credit
monitoring services this has become it's
become fairly commodity now um but
almost all of that is usually covered
under under your cyber insurance
incident response costs
that's again not your internal ir your
internal ir is on you your internal
project and reports done with your human
beings are on you but if you need to
hire outside ir you can you can have
those ir costs covered
and we talked about damages to physical
assets ransomware payouts we're going to
talk about ransomware payouts a little
bit later in a little more detail
because again
it is whenever there here's a here's a
fundamental principle of insurance
it's you know it's right back to um
berkshire hathaway right you want to
take in more than you pay out well
what's gone up crazy insane
unpredictable
is ransomware is one of those
um and it's been a lot associated with
the pandemic associated with work from
home new
and new attack surfaces being opened you
know people under more stress they're
maybe not being as careful and paying as
much attention
and
you know kids having access to your work
computers all sorts of reasons why it's
gone up
because it's going up so much what are
the insurance companies looking to do
they're looking to avoid
so they're pulling out the fine details
associated with ransomware payments and
looking for all sorts of ways to avoid
paying on them and we're going to go
through a couple of those examples um
later in the talk
and then lost income so
um
these are just kinds of areas of of
coverage that you can look for in your
cyber insurance there's also different
policy categories under which these
might fall so you might think for
example if you've got general business
insurance and you have business business
disruption insurance that oh i don't
need lost income and my under my cyber
security policy you would be wrong
um because there are
the way cyber insurance works is there's
you know there's underwriting and
there's policies and then there's
exclusions and there's caps and limits
and all sorts of things and you have to
be very very careful about what is
covered under what and again because
because of the costs associated with
this more and more we're seeing
insurance companies actually fighting to
try to not pay this actually also
happened in the very beginning oh i said
i wasn't going to talk about acquire
fraud
i'm going to say it anyway um in the
very beginning when ach wire fraud first
started happening
i did okay wait
here we go
somebody gets a chocolate bar
um
um so
kate won't eat them it's got sugar in it
so so
there there's always a fight whenever
there's a new level of
payout anticipated you can expect that
your cyber insurance company is going to
fight and this is just we had we also in
the industry when
you know 20 years ago there may be three
organizations that you could get cyber
insurance from you know marsh aig and
and one other now there's probably about
60 vendors out there that are
writing policies most a lot of the big
policies are still underwritten by you
know european
reinsurance risk category companies but
anytime there's that much competition in
there it gets very fragmented in terms
of the actual underwriting and it's
difficult to understand
what you actually have
so let's talk a little bit about
network security insurance specifically
and this is near and dear to my heart
because i just got my first malpractice
insurance policy and ninety percent of
the policy language was all around
network security
and they even asked you specifically if
you used an exchange server
and i'm like well i got lawyers yeah
maybe they still do use exchange servers
on prem exchange servers um
lawyers and government that's probably
the only place those still exist so
i actually tried to read it
and remember i am a professional i
actually understand cyber security and i
got about halfway through it and decided
that this was just
i wasn't going to buy it and so it
wasn't worth my time i spent an hour and
a half trying to read it and i decided
it wasn't worth my time
this is an area where the lingo
and the
um specific underwriting clauses can be
highly confusing
so when we said in the very beginning
there's first party coverage first party
coverage is for causes and events and
actions that you do to yourself
and then there is third party coverage
so third party coverage is when you
think that you might need to protect
someone that your causes actions
might
impact
so
if you are
a um a billing solutions provider for
example
and you send out a lot of messages and
you accidentally send malware to one of
your customers that would be an example
of a third party risk that would be paid
for under your third party coverage
the um
and this is an area
of
of growing concern especially as the on
the regulatory side as people are
looking at you know dss and this the csa
start
all looking at how do we how do we
require third-party risk assessments
from our vendors
then our third parties are actually
thinking potentially of coming back to
us if we cause
um
an accident or an event to harm their
system
and you can get all sorts of coverage
there
again with that pci dss read the
language very carefully
make because that is going to be
coverage for
um you causing a problem somewhere else
it may not cover your own actual loss
breach response is another area that's
there's been um a lot of talk and a lot
of coverage about lately it used to be
fairly reasonably priced but the
underwriting is getting much more
sophisticated now so they're actually
going to go back and look at you know
what type of data do you have who are
your third parties it does help
if you have um
gdpr experience and you've done a true
privacy assessment and you can show some
actual data and some actual policies and
procedures around that you might be able
to get
a lower cost or a lower premium but it's
still a very nascent area of law and
it's uh
then the coverage is
highly variable except the notification
and the
and the um third-party monitoring those
are pretty standard features now and you
can get them at fairly reasonable prices
um
and then and then there's like the first
party coverages that are the more
esoteric components um are you being
extorted
so and ransomware by the way is now
sometimes being called out expressly
separately from network instruction so
network distortion would be a ddos the
old ddos attacks right you're going to
have a big game in vegas we're going to
ddos your betting site and that's that
would be considered a network extortion
ransomware because there's no
pre-notification
isn't technically extortion because it
comes afterwards
um
so
then there's dependent business
interruption insurance that is if a
um a third party provider to you
causes an interruption in your system
and
and of course some system failures
digital asset laws cyber crime again
another area if you are worried about
[Music]
business email compromise or a potential
malware getting into your system through
a phishing attack
and you have to look at those carefully
because they're separating out now
typo squatting
may be considered may not be considered
a cyber crime it may be considered
something else so you've got to very
carefully look and walk through these
scenarios you have in your organization
to understand if it's actually going to
be covered or not
and then there's reputational harm which
again
and if you're you know if you're l'oreal
or um a half a big personal brand might
be something that you want to cover but
if you know that'll depend on your
marketing team in their organization
um i guess the net net of all this is
it's really complicated
and if you feel
if you feel like this is something an
area that your organization
needs and is not um
thinking about carefully it's probably
worth bringing it up
right now because policies are being
reviewed and drafted there tend to be
you know annual boundaries annual
contract boundaries so right now is the
time to bring this up and say hey i just
went to this talk they talked about how
things are changing like crazy in cyber
security insurance so maybe it's time to
review our policies
um then just for fun
just so you can sound like an expert um
you can say really you can use some of
the the cyber insurance lingo
so we have
um all sorts of
special languages
business insurance cgnl
um
eno
criminal acts and fidelity
commercial property and then of course
cyber and you're sitting there going why
if there's a cyber insurance category
are we looking at all of these other
areas of coverage well
because
you might actually have some remedy
under these
more traditional standard
clauses even your commercial general
liability and like i said
a data data publication to the dark web
was considered a publication
and we had and we had a client get
recovery under a cgnl policy
so don't ex if you're
informing or communicating with someone
just remind them to go through
everything so
this is my checklist
um of things that i do when i actually
try to review when i review our tiny
little company's cybersecurity policies
and we deal with financial data and
information so we do actually try to
take this seriously
um
there are
there are some important aspects of
things like sub limits
and the new one that's come out that's
relatively recent is new or should have
known so you
this is what's important
in
for the actual practitioners because if
you have a an application risk
or a compliance risk
or
um
internal tech debt that has identified a
cybersecurity risk that ends up
causing a breach or a liability in the
future
your insurance company
may have a new or or should have known
exclusion and you may not get coverage
for
that and this is this is kind of recent
but as we see more and more
standardization especially coming down
from the federal government
i think it's important as practitioners
that you be aware of this and be aware
of
you know keeping your data
and communication paths all the way up
to the cfo or the finance person whoever
is in charge of this
um breach of contract exclusions they're
i
really tried hard to wrap my head around
this but effectively
it says it's saying
that if
if wow i lost it
if if your act would have caused you to
breach a contract if your act or a
mission would have caused you to breach
a contract then it's not an insurable
event
so this means that you actually have to
look at your obligations
this happens a lot in in disclosure
requirements for data disclosure
requirements you have to go back and
look at your obligations and make sure
that it doesn't conflict with your
insurance policy
this sounds like a lot of work doesn't
it who would really want to do this
yeah
nobody fortunately there's professionals
out there
who can do this for you
but this is the whole point of these
kinds of checklists are to enable you to
issue spot and identify and bring them
bring things up you know only it's
impossible for any of us to actually
solve these problems we just need to
make people aware and try to make them
think about
whether or not this is important for
them
um war exclusions so you wouldn't think
you wouldn't think that that would have
anything to do with cyber security
however
um
the their the language that's being used
now when we talk about some of these
data breaches in terms of them being
state actors cyber terrorism
there is discussion
that in fact cyber incidents
may end up under the war exclusion in
your insurance policy so again if you're
at risk for being targeted from a state
actor
then you probably need to look at that
exclusion provision carefully and make
sure it excludes
cyber
um
territory limitations those are pretty
straightforward and then defense costs
now all of these all of these clauses um
have
yeah it's a lot of work um all of these
clauses are going to have
sub-limits deductibles co-limits and
caps
and
it's you almost have to make a venn
diagram and map them out and see and
determine and capping is you have to be
very careful
across because sometimes capping is only
under a single category and you need to
know if the caps stack
if you have if you have coverage under
potentially under two sections of your
policy if it's capped in a
is that a max cap
or is that a cap additive cap or is it
the aggregate of the max cap and it's
it's very important to actually just
build out in an excel spreadsheet and
tack this all up and add it up
my strategy if you're ever asked to
opine on one of these is pretty
straightforward and simple
i started the exclusions
i write down every single exclusion
and then i try to map that back to the
real world because of course the
exclusions are written in insurance
language
and but mapping that back to what is the
application risk what is the compliance
risk what is the policy and procedure
risk um that's
where your knowledge of how things work
is very important because lawyers can't
draft that and these most importantly
these insurance policies are written by
insurance lawyers
and remember they all still work on
mainframes
so you can take this from a policy that
if you ever get involved with it that's
that's the most important thing that's
where i start
the second thing that's important and
this is also where you and your teams
are important for the organization is
you want to build your relationships
up front and right now is the time to do
it
a lot of a lot of times when i get
called in on a forensic situation
my hands are tied because the insurance
policy says you must use vendor a
if you have any and this if you have an
existing relationship or a vendor that
you like
you have to pre-negotiate it now to get
it on an approved vendor list by your
insurance company or you won't be or
you'll have it's not that you can't use
them it's that you'll have to pay for it
yourself
and
these relationships especially if you're
an organ in an area of risk any kind of
financial data health data
now energy if you're in any of those
sectors that are being targeted you know
how important it is to be able to work
with people that you know and trust
so explaining to your cfo who those who
those organizations are that you trust
and getting them pre-approved in advance
is critical i actually had to help a
friend to do this just recently
um
they had a ransomware attack through
their cloud provider
and
they this is a large
very large organization
they had no plan they didn't even know
where to start on the vendor list um
fortunately she had me so
we were able to come up with a quick
vendor list and negotiate and get those
contracts in place but the challenge is
if you wait until the incident is
happening
then you're making decisions in a rush
and when we and we're going to talk
about privilege and work product in a
second and i'll show you why it's so
this
this and figuring out your exclusions
are the two most important takeaways
from this meeting
build those relationships in advance get
them pre-approved by your insurance
vendor
um
i don't know we probably can skip this
negotiating tips it's a slide in there
you're probably not going to have to
negotiate a cyber insurance policy feel
free to give this to your cfo or your
general counsel if you happen to have
one
and
it is
there is a lot of horse trading going on
right now i'll just give you the um
what we're seeing
is deductibles are double doubling
so then the level you they're your
threshold deductible especially for
ransomware they're going they're
doubling for sure if you've got a two
million dollar
deductible today it's probably gonna be
four
and you're gonna pay two to three times
as much for it
that's how bad the ransomware
business has been lately who knows how
many average days um your systems are
down in ransomware
i i read i got 21 to 23 but i'll give
you 37.
um so here
i have way too much food in my house and
i'm traveling so it's coming here
yeah they're healthy sort of
um
so if you're going to be down or part of
your system is going to be down during a
ransomware attack for 21 to 37 days
um
you know what's your backup plan for
that
and
you know we've all i mean how many here
how many people here have ever actually
done a backup
how many people have done a restore
right
exactly um even and if you're depending
on your third-party provider your sas
provider to be your backup and restore
person they can show you all the log
data that you want yeah you're
successfully successfully successfully
successfully you know that is worth
the cost of the paper to print it when
they can't actually restore it it's also
one of the biggest challenges with
ransomware attacks is you have to do
incremental restores right because you
got to figure out when the ransomware
got into your system they don't
hit you the same day the malware shows
up in your system you've got to go back
and find where it is on that restore and
then you've got to be able to do
incremental data updates with avoiding
the executables and that's something
that we've
i'm lazy honestly um my backup restore
strategy is dump the whole drive
uh if you have to do if you haven't done
a tabletop and plan for an incremental
restore it's definitely something you
should be talking to your ita teens
about
now we get into the fun legal stuff that
all of that was preparation for the fun
part of the talk
um
handling an incident so the very first
thing that you have to do if you have a
cyber incident is form
this is a legal thing form something
called a control group
if you don't form a control group
anything you say or do will come out
and control groups are very specifically
defined so this control groups are a way
of implementing
the ability to state to a judge that you
have privilege and work product
privilege and work product are actually
legislative or statutorily created
rights
and they came out of an old english
common law
um
principle
was that a wife could not testify
against a husband
so when we talk about privileges they
really come up more out of the criminal
law context and they're very restricted
in civil law
but there's they still do exist so you
have to be very very careful or you're
going to
break your privilege and your work
product will become
readily available and
in
the cyber space especially in insurance
where we're mostly talking about
forensic reports
the law is all over the map
so we have to go to the
the lowest common denominator if we're
going to have any hope of trying to
protect information that occurs
during
a cyber incident
the second thing that's really important
um
is that a a lot of policies
have an exclusion
that coverage does not start until
they're notified
so you have to form your control group
really quickly which is typically going
to be run by
your your attorney your general counsel
if they're there or your outside counsel
who you're going to hire specifically
for
this incident you're not going to go to
your general outside counsel your
contracts person or your compliance
person or your workforce your your hr
lawyer you're going to hire a specific
likely separate firm
specifically for this incident
and then
somebody has to know where the policy is
and somebody has to know who to call
and you would be shocked
at how many times
especially if the policy's just been
rolling over
and nobody knows where it is and nobody
knows who to call
so just like we have you know when we
have to when we have our call trees um
on our cyber incidents for internal
communications somebody needs to know
where that insurance policy is and who'd
call
and then the vendor selection part of it
and again i mentioned it earlier it's
really important to get those
relationships and
it's october if you have a favorite get
it to your cfo now
it's very important to
discuss that and sometimes your outside
counsel can negotiate for you
your outside counsel
is going to have to hire the forensics
person
this is the craziest thing
you don't get to hire your own forensics
team
because that breaks that breaks the
privilege rules and it'll come out and
we'll go over a couple of cases and look
at how the court thought about this
and then hopefully and then there are
terms and conditions around payout we're
going to talk about ransomware and we're
going to talk about some of the some of
the exclusions that have arisen in
ransomware
um
and why it's important to
follow to get that insurance company
involved early but to have them
controlled and managed by outside
counsel
so a control group
is
a limited number of individuals who are
allowed to communicate under privilege
so privilege covers communications
work product
covers
in our
situation typically forensics reports
and analysis
covers
activities
the work product can you you can all
imagine what's the work product every
person who's about to sue you wants to
get their hands on
somebody say it please it's the intern
yes exactly it's the internal forensics
report it's your ir report
and if you've started
an ir
investigation internally earlier with
your own staff
that is not privileged
that's ordinary course business
operations
so if you're on one of those teams
don't put your opinion in it
do not write down your opinion just
state the facts oh this port was left
open oh this patch wasn't done
oh that credential was compromised just
the facts
no opinions
keep those to yourself or to your
husband under attorney client privilege
um now if your husband's not an attorney
just keep it to yourself
don't be offended if you're not in the
control group the control group has to
be a very very very small number of
people and it has to be very very
limited so it is
it is very likely that you are not going
to be in the control group i get ciso's
asking me why i want to under the
control group uh you're not an officer
and they don't want you in there um
probably i'll see you no too much um so
they don't you're not going to be none
of us are going to be in the control
group
so don't be offended
and then the other problem is sometimes
your organization wants to get ahead of
things and they start
wants to get quickly going on they want
to start their mitigations and
remediations
and they don't wait until they've had a
demand
or
the anticipation of litigation has not
yet arisen it's it's
you know
and this actually turns out to be
important into whether or not
these this outside forensics report with
opinions can be can be covered under
privilege and the last thing is
it only works here
if your data breaches in germany
sorry if it's in china well forget it um
we know
only the united states but you know
canada mexico
no other there's no other
legal
framework that we that we know of that
actually has this concept so
you know
it doesn't mean that it's not good
practices and procedures to follow
uh um a policy around privileged
communications and a control group but
just don't be upset
if you get an international
um claimant and all of a sudden all your
hard work goes for nothing
okay
so
uh it's an evolving framework i'm gonna
give you two use cases and we'll play
you spot the difference
and
um it does not protect facts and again
that's why i said those early
investigations those early reports you
do just stick to the facts
um
so here's two recent cases uh one of
them is capital one we all remember when
they had that you know open s3 bucket
why do people
put why do people put unencrypted pii
out there anywhere ever anymore come you
guys are upset guys isn't it easy to
tokenize or mask or
am i dreaming i always look at those
vulnerabilities and go how are we how
are we still doing those how are we
still having those
and then you know really you left an
open s3 bucket
really
um but anyways capital one did it uh
with a whole bunch of mortgage
applications where people of course
gladly gave up you know their bank
account data their social security
numbers their firstborn's child's name
and uh
et cetera but i think it was about 70
million records that were breached they
had uh
60 lawsuits filed in the first month
so
what capital one did
is they hired a separate outside firm
the outside firm got a separate
forensics company
they had a specific work scope here's
another trap if you already have
a deal if you're if you're a mandiant
customer on a retainer
that ain't going to be privileged
anything done at the end of that is not
going to be work product
no
you have to have a separate one and a
special one and it has to be written
specially
specifically for this incident
specifically in preparation for making
decisions about litigation and
litigation strategy
so they had they hired an outside
specialist firm
they um the specialist firm hired a
separate forensics company
they wrote a specific scope of work
they
they dock signed and marked and tracked
everyone who got a copy of the report
so they could show the judge these are
the only people who had this report
and
so there were a couple of other factors
as well
but effectively the judge said in that
case
we agree
this is work product and p prepared in
advance of litigation they went through
a 10 step a 10 step analysis there's a
really good aiken income article linked
right there if you're interested in
reading it now let's compare and
contrast that with what happened to a
law firm
named clark hill
who has a practice in
cyber security and breach notification
and management
you would think oh no brainer they're
going to get it all right
well you obviously can tell
i love poking fun in my own industry
clark hill
failed to get their report covered
for
for a couple of really important reasons
and number one
they did not create a unique scope uh
instead of work and they did not have it
uh controlled they did not control who
got access to the report some law firms
that i know now are so anxious about
this they don't even want these report
they don't even want to receive the
reports in writing
i'm occasionally asked to read the
report
over the phone or over zoom but not
actually deliver a written report
they're the client not my call it makes
my job a little bit harder fortunately i
like listening to myself talk and but
it's uh you know it's and we're in this
highly variable but can you imagine my
reports tend to be short you know like
under 10 pages can you imagine
going through an actual ir report with a
bunch of log data or audit data in it
over the phone and reading all of that
out
um
again facts are not protected
but
they um but the goal is to try to get
the entire report covered and that's by
by its nature it's going to contain some
facts so clark hill
a law firm
that specializes
in cyber security data breach
notification and services
failed to protect
their forensics report
as work product and privilege
the the litigant got access to their
report and why are these supports so
important right what are what is
everybody hunting for this is these are
civil cases
they're hunting for evidence of
correct
negligence which is also a term of art
and in our industry what are some of the
factors that our people are looking for
at negligence it goes back to that new
or should have known
you know
were you uh you know were you unnoticed
was there did microsoft have a bulletin
out saying maybe you should patch the
system did oracle did are you running a
cve program now
i and the number of times i have tried
to explain to attorneys and judges
that the failure to patch
is not
negligence per se
um and i've done it until i'm blue in
the face i still don't know that people
understand this you cannot always patch
period
it's
every retail industry is already locked
down on their it now you don't make a
single i.t change from now until the end
of january
you don't change a port you don't change
you don't open up a new firewall you
don't change a configuration option in
aws or azure it's a lockdown a critical
patch comes out
you're probably not going to do it
you might try and you won't even put in
a mitigation you won't even put throw up
a laugh and try to protect it in line
with a waff why
when does retail make all their money
right now you got to be on and active so
there are absolutely perfectly valid
reasons why you may never patch
so it's not
in my opinion it's not negligence per se
but you have to try to explain that to
someone and that's where these reports
come in right they're going to put on
all the all of the rationale
why
what you did or did not do was not
negligence per se and not
um
so that is very very artful crafting of
analysis of the facts and crafting and
you don't want that in the hands of your
opponent
um
okay ransomware
this is a big topic and we're already
getting a lot of litigation around it
actually very sadly
um the first wrongful death
due to ransomware litigation
is going to trial next year
a hospital
was undergoing a ransomware attack they
didn't have the automated monitoring for
fetal heartbeat and
a baby
as often happens more than you know
happens in pregnancy cord wrapped baby
went into distress it was missed
um
the claim is because the hospital was
under a ransomware attack and they they
didn't have enough staff to do the
individual level of monitoring
and
um
that the individual wasn't told that the
hospital was under a ransomware attack
i don't even know that the hospital knew
at the time the incident occurred that
there was a ransomware attack so
but you know this is getting more and
more serious right we all know hospitals
are targeted um
you know you read these horrible stories
of the older nurses having to run around
and explain how to hand chart vitals
okay everybody here could do that right
everybody here could like take a graph
and put three points on it and trend it
it's a little bit it's a little bit
mind-boggling to me that basic skills
like how to plot and graph on a piece of
paper is not taught anymore
um so
these are these are becoming very
serious and we're going to see of course
when bad things happen
it's the american way to
um hold somebody else responsible
we're like the largest country in terms
of hold somebody else responsible
so
we're going to expect more of these so
if you're involved in one of these
ransomware situations um
[Music]
you've got to think even more carefully
than you do in i hate to say it in an
ordinary you know like pci dss problem
but you're gonna have to think a little
bit more carefully and there's a couple
of other subtle differences
um
associated with ransomware you may want
to have a separate policy for your
ransomware you absolutely
need to get
a lawyer who is knowledgeable about
ransomware
specifically involved and we have a
pretty good one up in dallas named sean
toombs and you've got to get a lawyer
involved because
there are
some new swizzles so first of all
there's a case right now that's being
argued or maybe it'll settle i don't
know where the insurance company said
um because you paid the ransomware
through
bitcoin that was a voluntary payment
we aren't responsible for it
so
how much does your and you know
ransomware you're usually you're
completely down you know if it was me
and i was ransomware i'd go to my
insurance company and say look i've got
business uh interruption insurance and
it's costing me you know a million
dollars a day so you know you can either
pay this 250 000
bitcoin ransom or you can pay me you
know my million dollars a day
but you've got to have somebody who can
go and make that argument and make sure
you get it in writing and make sure you
get um get what you're paying for
the second thing and this is very new
is
if you get a ransomware attack and of
course you should involve law
enforcement and the fbi but if you are
the fbi
and law enforcement are going to say
don't pay it right they don't want to
create the the they don't want to
habituate clients to paying
they want to not pay we just had a big
discussion of this in my women's so
group um you know would you or would you
not the one gal who was a sister who was
a former fbi agent of course she was on
the no pay side
um
but you know it's a business decision
it's a business decision whether you
make it or not you need to control that
decision don't let law enforcement push
you around they should be there to help
not to hurt but
um
if
you do make a payment and this is really
hard you have to go check the sanctions
list
and that means you're going to need
somebody who has deep intimate because
they're all done over cryptocurrency
right you're gonna have to have someone
who has deep dark web
black web knowledge of where that
bitcoin wallet might actually reside
because if
that is going to
a country
or a person everybody knows about the
the sanctions let's write the ofac list
it's public you can go you should go
google yourself make sure your names and
accents are on there um
if you make a payment to them
you may not only be denied coverage for
it you may face federal liability
and the european union um i can't
remember i read this but the european
union has also stated that they're
creating their own
um no pay list
sanctions list so if if you're an
international company you're not only
gonna have to check the us you're gonna
have to check with the with eu with
interpol
so this is rapidly evolving like who
would have thought we need to check the
ofac list on a bitcoin wallet that we
probably don't even know where it goes
um but you do you used to have to you
least have to show
that you you attempted to follow the law
um
so this brings us back to um my final
slide which is no before you go
the
pre-preparation
just like you do in your regular
incident planning pre-preparation for
dealing with your cyber insurance is a
must
and unfortunately because of the
cyclical nature of cyber insurance it's
probably
a must right now because you're probably
going through that analysis and
negotiating with them right now so we've
got a little checklist here for you
um
and uh again we're gonna post these
right kate
we're posting the slides
yes we're gonna post the slides so you
can take it i've got some additional
checklists in the notes sections um
hand it off give the whole presentation
to your cfo my only request is you do
not ask me to do anything
um because a i'm not an expert in this
area and you really do need an expert if
you feel like you need an expert i'm
happy to make introductions but i am not
an expert in this area and um i'm not
answering my emails right now either but
hopefully tuesday through thursday i'll
get a little break
yes yes you do raise your hand if you
would like a copy of the deck
okay we will figure out how to get a
copy of the deck out yes we can post it
with the whatever if worst comes to
worst um you can get it from me
any other
questions who wants to become a lawyer
but um
yeah that's at the very beginning
self-insurance and you may be into
forced self-insurance um
as i said earlier because deductibles
are doubling and premiums are
quadrupling
so
that's that's an internal business risk
decision and i think you and it's and
it's
highly specific and highly individual
but absolutely we talk about that all
the time have i got a good enough
compliance program do i have enough
understanding of what my actual
actual risk might be or my theoretical
risk might be
in order to self-insure
if you're a large company like
a lot of the larger companies
i know they do that but if you're a
small company
and a single incident could take you
down
um and
we know this happens
then
figuring out at least you know um
some reasonable amount of insurance even
if you're going to be paying you know 50
60 000 a year for it and figuring out
some reasonable amount insurance at at
least let you get this through this and
try to reset is probably appropriate so
for small medium businesses i highly
recommend getting some form of coverage
um
otherwise you're going to be calling me
and trying to have me help you do some
forensics reports so you can try to
blame somebody else and get the money
from them you're one of your third-party
providers but that's a long haul right
you've got to be you've got to have
enough staying power to make it through
that entire process which is going to be
multi-year
it's just going to be multi-year
um unfortunately it's the world we live
in
it's it's not it's out of it's
predominantly out of our control i do
highly encourage you to think about
self-insurance but for small medium
businesses i recommend you know at least
some at least enough coverage to keep
you running um for a quarter
yes sir
um
what are some major
differences in what you present when
it's applied to say
not proper estate
state entities are usually self-insured
um
i don't even know if they can get
commercial insurance for this maybe they
can some of the sub-state entities
non-profits there i believe there are
some specific insurance companies that
focus specifically on non-profits and
they try to risk pool so they can offer
lower premiums
and
and i apologize i don't know i don't
know about state entities i don't know
if they have the state entity for sure
you should be able to through the
comptroller's office get access to a
preferred vendors list
and if if if you can get insurance i
would definitely check with the
comptroller
yeah
we've been using before
we buy our
yeah you know the ransomware as a
service
is you know up and coming
and that means that
that means that everybody is you know is
a potential target right because they
can spray and play
against a large a large number of
domains and usernames
and you know and i'm still surprised at
you know nobody in this room would ever
share a password
with their work environment and their
personal environment i am shocked at how
many organizations still don't have that
as a requirement and then even if they
do listed in a policy they don't
actually go ask people
or they don't give them a tool like
keeper a lastpass to enable them to have
strong passwords
um
it's it's still back to basics
so insurance is great
but remember it's insurance
make sure you're doing your basics first
right
well thank you all anybody else i have
lots more kind bars
if anybody else wants a kind bar
and um again uh if we can't figure out
how to make this generally available
through an email list or something
through the conference uh hit me up if
you don't have it by monday next by
monday
november 7th hit me up on email and i'll
email it to you directly
along with lots of other fun reading if
you're really interested so indicate
your level interest basic medium high
and i'll send you a pile of other stuff
thanks
[Applause]