[Music]
so my name is jeff williams uh i am
so
so this way so i'm on the national
champion 15 over basketball team
i'm a accomplished boomerang designer
and thrower
and i'm also the cto of contrast
security i co-founded in a few years
back
i've been involved with oas for a number
of years i got started uh
really early i
consider myself one of the founders of
oas
uh
became the first chair of owasp so i was
the first global chair of the
organization and i was that for the
first 10 years i wrote the os top 10
wrote web goat contributed a lot of
different projects to os and i'm still
i'm super excited to see how osp has
grown over the years
uh i'm incredibly excited to talk to you
today about instrumentation
the idea of instrumenting software to me
is just amazing
and i want to try to expose you to the
power of what we can do with
instrumentation
in this talk and uh and get you excited
about it so let's jump into it i'm going
to do some a few slides and some
demonstrations to show you how you can
use instrumentation today
i always try to start out and talk with
some facts about appsec i don't know not
everybody hears you know does appsec
every day so i thought it's useful to
just like set the stage these are facts
that we gathered from our customer base
we've got tens of thousands of real
world applications that we monitor for
application vulnerabilities we look at
libraries we look at
uh attacks in the runtime environments
and we bring all that data together and
we publish a report that's got some of
this in it but
when you look at these numbers
you should be concerned
who here banks online
okay there's some people to raise their
hand and some other liars
there's
because it actually doesn't matter if
you use the bank software itself your
data is already in the same software
that other people are using you're just
not using it
these numbers are not fantastic
this says
you know we've got uh on average like 30
vulnerabilities per app
can you imagine if we were building
airplanes
and every time we did a safety check we
found 30 safety problems that would be
ridiculous nobody would fly but we
tolerated in the software industry for
some reason
uh we've got a lot of open source
library problems that's layers on top of
that
you should know by the way though
most open source
never gets called
only seven percent of the open source
code in an application actually ever
runs
and we measure this at runtime using
instrumentation we measure this exactly
so we're sure that we've got the right
answer here it's really kind of amazing
um
the biggest challenge i see with this
this the left side of this page the
vulnerability side is that you know i
wrote the first os top 10 in 2002
and we haven't really changed the game
it's the same vulnerabilities in there
today
i thought you know we'd write the os top
10 we'd work on it for a few years we'd
fix some of those things we'd raise the
bar and we'd issue a new top 10 with
different stuff in it but it's you know
we're almost we're 19 years later it's
still the same stuff in there
that's an indictment of
of apsec i love oas but i love all the
cool things that we've built and done
but
we are not changing the game yet i'm
doing a keynote tomorrow morning where
i'm going to zoom out and talk about
that picture
and dig into that problem but this talk
is really much more technical um
i also wanted to say we're also under
attack most organizations don't have
good visibility into who's attacking
them and how they're being attacked and
which systems are being targeted i just
want you to know that it is happening
the average application that we protect
are are attacked
13 000 times a month
that's that's a big number i mean that's
a lot of attacks so if you combine these
two sides of this we've got a lot of
vulnerability and a lot of attackers
it's not a great situation that we're in
so something has to change
but today's talk is about
instrumentation
so who can give me an example of some
any in any kind if they're not in
software but like in any kind of thing
what's what's instrumented
yeah sure like your car's got
instrumentation right it's got
speedometer it's got you know tire
warnings and out of gas indicators all
kinds of instrumentation right you
wouldn't drive without that stuff
right
what's some other things that are
instrumented
okay that's really interesting right
i don't know if they're actually
measuring them directly
but you do get it i mean i mean they
probably are
but like i think of instrumentation as
being like you know directly anybody
wearing a apple watch or a fitbit or
something guess what you're instrumented
that thing probably knows you're sick
before you do
instrumentation is key like think about
the modern industrial factory
it's instrumented for vibration and fire
and temperature and sound and everything
that could go wrong
they know
when a machine is going to break
before it breaks because like the
vibration in the factory changed
they would never operate their stuff
without instrumentation would be crazy
because they would never be able to
figure out what's going on inside those
complex machines
so software is the most complex thing
that we have ever created that that
exists
and it's barely instrumented at all
log files are terrible instrumentation
if you've ever looked at log files they
don't have the right stuff in them they
don't have uh you know they've got
exceptions from you know errors that get
thrown but log files are like after the
fact they're not real time they're you
can't decide to turn on some sensors and
off sensors it's really not good now
this here
is
the 9450
this is an instrumented basketball
and i like using basketball examples uh
because i play a little bit so
uh this thing
measures your dribble speed the arc of
your shots the rotation of the ball
everything and gives you cool dashboards
and it gives you feedback on how you're
playing
in a way it can replace the coach
and in an industry where we've got a
massive shortage of experts in
application security and lots and lots
of players out there writing code
we could do with some things that help
force multiplier to help our coaches
like imagine if you give a bunch of
players this ball and they can go
improve their skills get measured by
their coach and their coach can be more
strategic giving them specific things to
work on
based on the data that's what we can do
with instrumentation we can empower all
the apps experts out there
to
teach their teach their players a lot
better
so
the good thing
about software is that it's really
malleable
we can instrument software easily
this is a little diagram that shows how
the instrumentation engine in java works
it's pretty similar in other languages
um
but you start with the original code on
disk so imagine you've got a binary some
war file or a jar file executable jar
file something
what normally happens is the class
loader loads that code straight into
memory
and then
that's the code that runs
is exactly what was a copy of what was
on disk
but the instrumentation api allows you
to intercept that process so as the code
moves from disk into memory you get a
chance to insert sensors in it
and you can insert you know whatever
kind of sensors you want to measure
what's going on in the application but
you can instrument it as it loads
that allows you
to add security sensors to this to this
code so that you can see what's going on
inside the application from within this
is exactly the same technique that
companies like new relic and app
dynamics use to do performance
measurements
as the code loads
instrument it they put timing in timing
sensors into it well we're gonna put
security sensors into our code so that
we can watch security working and not
working
anyway so this technique has been around
for like 20 years it's super proven uh
it's
it's just a little tricky to use
but i want you to imagine
doing a pen test
with instrumentation it's almost like
having a friend or an agent inside the
running application who can tell you
what's going on
so
you know normal tests you're blind right
somebody once described pen testing to
me is like trying to figure out what's
wrong with the water heater by staring
up the shower
and
it's a little bit like that you don't
have a ton of information coming back
right so
what if you had a buddy inside the water
heater who was telling you what was
going on as you did your testing you'd
have a lot more visibility and that's
what we can do with instrumentation
imagine sending a
a pen test request into it like maybe
you're using zap or something maybe you
send something into an application and
not only do you get the http response
but you get a whole bunch of other
information like what route was executed
what configs were accessed what back-end
connections got used maybe show me the
sql queries that got executed during
that request
tons of information whatever you want
you can get it with instrumentation
so
to me this is it's critical
to moving forward and
insta i feel really strongly about
instrumentation because it tests the
runtime reality of an application
it's not testing like the code in a
source code repo somewhere that's like
you know
doesn't have the app server and the the
runtime in it uh it's not fully put
together like we're testing a real
application with real data real config
real back-end connections so we can get
all that context and context is what
leads to accuracy
and as i'll talk about tomorrow accuracy
is critical
to getting absec right
if you're not accurate then you have to
have experts involved and and if you
have experts involved
like me it's never going to scale
i'm the problem
dave lindner here the problem
um
so
that's a little background on
instrumentation everybody with me so far
okay i'm gonna demonstrate
instrumentation but it's i i used to do
this with code examples but it's hard
because instrumentation code is a little
complex it's writing code to
instrument other code
so it's just a like it's kind of meta
so i put together a library this is an
open source free and open source project
that anybody can use you can download
it's on github
and
it allows you to to build your own
instrumentation agents
not using not writing code but
configuring the sensors you want to put
in via yaml
so it's a very powerful way to write
sensors that anybody can do
and i do think of instrumentation by the
way like like a multimeter kind of thing
like you're actually sticking these
probes into the methods in your
application and we're going to snapshot
information out of those methods and use
it to make interesting
decisions
so
i should say my company contrast
security
uses instrumentation in our products
we build i asked and rasp and we'll talk
about those a little bit more
that is a commercial product and i'm not
talking about that here
this is a free and open source library
that anybody can use anytime i want to
be really clear like this is not my
product or anything this is a separate
thing that i built on the side
and made free for everybody because i
want everyone to experience the power of
observability in doing application
security
okay
so
i'm going to demonstrate this rather
than you know i have slides here uh but
it's i think it's
more interesting to demonstrate these
things
so i have a little application here
called ticketbook it's got a bunch of
interesting
vulnerabilities in it and some other
things i'm going to use it
with instrumentation
so
i downloaded the jot library so i've got
that here
so you can see i've got oh i'm in my
jaws directory
so you can see i've got my uh
what in the hell
hold on
i'm in the wrong place i'm sorry about
this
okay
much better so you see i've got my jot
file here
so i'm going to run
uh
i'm going to i'm going to tell java to
use this this uh this chat file so i've
got a uh
i'm going to set an environment variable
this is all you need to do to tell java
to run with an instrumentation agent our
instrumentation agent is jot
okay so we're running with this 0.9.1
and then i'm going to tell it what jot
file to use in this case i'm going to
use this
usql untrusted sql jot and let's take a
look at that
um
say again
oh
when i type oh john r jesus
okay
thank you i was panicking there for a
second so okay so look this is a
ridiculously simple sensor
all we're doing is telling java i want
to put a simple sensor in these four
methods boy that's really small isn't it
these four methods
uh
and
you can see
i'm excluding this prepared statement
the reason i have to do that is because
prepared statement extends statement
and so naturally jot will instrument
that because it extends one of the
methods there so i'm going to exclude
that one because that's safe but i want
to see anytime anybody uses those
unprepared statements because they might
be insecure so this is just a simple way
of finding these things and i'm going to
capture
the bottom line is the capture and it
says i'm going to capture the args
that's the arguments to that method you
can capture different things with uh
with jots you can capture the object the
args the parameters
and you can it's actually a spring
expression so you can call methods on
those things to get other data out of
the application so again like a
multimeter we're going to shove it in
we're going to capture a little bit of
data and we're going to pull that back
and use it for something so now
when i run my application
i just run it normally
and you can see as this application
starts up
jot kicked in you can see it
instrumented certain classes
as it starts up
and
then we use the application normally
so i can just click on a few a few pages
here
and
put in some data
and contrast is in the i'm sorry john is
in the background watching this stuff
actually i'll put last con in here so we
can see this
so
you can see for each of those queries
jot has logged the actual
unsafe query here you can see it gives
me the the rule that that was violated
the
exact line of code
and you can see the full query here
so just imagine that you're doing a pen
test
and you're trying to find sql injection
uh you know it's really difficult to
know what the queries are and everything
so this is really useful information in
that context
you can use jot for anything doesn't
have to be just for security you can use
it for you know regular debugging
incident response like whatever you need
to know out of an application you can
quickly throw in a jot and start
gathering that information so that you
can see what's going on inside the
application
that's the key that's why this is you
know it's a java observability toolkit
it's not the java security observability
toolkit
um
everybody understand this simple example
okay let's do something a little more
interesting so um
let's look at uh encryption algorithms
right so i've got another jot here
ciphers dot jot and this is a little
more interesting so this only puts in
one sensor
that
goes into the cipher.getinstance method
we're going to capture the name of the
cipher like des or triple des or aes or
whatever
and
then we're just going to create a report
so the other half of the you know jots
have sensors and reports that you can
create so the first one didn't create a
report it just dumped stuff out into log
but you can also save it up over time
and create a report so
this will show us where encryption is
done in this application everywhere
which is actually pretty interesting
because we're looking at the whole app
it's not just the custom code it's all
the libraries all the frameworks the
the app server and the java runtime
itself
all those things can be doing encryption
so
again all i have to do is just you know
click through these pages
to uh see if any of them do encryption i
know these some
some of these ones down at the bottom do
so i'm just clicking on these these
pages like and this is actually
i think a really important message here
is that i don't have to know anything
about security in order to to do this
all i have to do is just use the
application normally
so
i blow it what did i do
did i i didn't set my variable i didn't
send my agent
i'm sorry i'm really having a bad time
today ciphers
now i run the application normally
and let me just click on these things
quickly and you'll see
still loading
so
uh
when you can use instrumentation to
empower regular developers to do
security checks
it's a huge advantage because there's
way more developers out there than there
are security experts
okay so here's what this is supposed to
look like
so you can see in just a few clicks i
found a ton of uses of all different
kinds of encryption algorithms right
single des
single des with
you know different modes triple des aes
password-based encryption and so on and
if you use this on real-world
applications you'll see encryption all
over the place you can do the same thing
with hash algorithms
and see you know we are never going to
be free of md5 and sha-1 people can talk
about it all they want but it is
everywhere hundreds of places in the the
java typical java stack
it's never going away
so again this is this is another
powerful way of using instrumentation
to get
interesting security information out of
applications
so i'll switch to this slide here real
quick
if my screen will
there's like a
five second delay between when i switch
the screen and when it actually slides
over
so i just wanted to point this out
because this has a few more details on
what you can do in a jot if you look at
the top up here you can see
you can specify the captures
in a really powerful way all of those
are
spring expressions which allow you to
you know take the value that was
returned but if the if like the first
parameter for instance if that's a
complex object you can call methods on
it you can call methods on that
and you can extract exactly the piece of
information that you want so like where
all you do is have to get your probe
close
and then you can use methods to to
expand from there and get the data that
you really are are looking for
okay
now let's do my favorite example
so
this one's about access control
so i'm gonna
do this first
and then let's take a look at it
so
access control is one of the hardest
things to test it was when i was doing a
lot of pen testing it was kind of my
specialty is i would focus in on
authorization and i always found
interesting flaws and gaps because
nobody tests it it's really hard
and so uh
you know imagine if you're testing an
application as like you know
joe
well you've got a role and a certain set
of access to the application you're
you're viewing it through one lens but
there might be a dozen different lenses
to view that application through and
each one might have different access to
the app so when you pen test it from one
point of view you're really only testing
that
code
we want to test the whole application so
how do we how do we do this how do we
find out what all the access control
checks are well we can do it with jot
i mean this would take you know
a lot of time certainly days to figure
out how to do this on a pen test or a
code or view
we need it to go faster than that so
with this
i'm gonna put in three route three
sensors the first sensor tells me the
route
that's like the attack surface for this
application right so i wanna know the
url that i'm coming in on the second one
tells me the currently logged in user
and you can see
uh i i call the ser on both of these i
call the service method i'm
instrumenting the service method which
is like kind of the main entry point for
java apple java ee applications
and
the parameters to the service method
are the http request and the http
response the first one is the request
and so when i call p0 that's the http
request and on that i'm calling get
remote user
so again i'm like sticking a sensor and
i'm using it to get the information i
want so now i know the route and the
user
and the last sensor
is the current
role like the role check that i'm i'm
checking for so i want to know anywhere
this application does
an is user enroll check and i want to
know what role they're required to have
at that point in the code
okay so that all seems a little esoteric
this is not hard to build right it takes
a few minutes to set up these these
rules and then i've created a simple
report one is going to be a test
coverage matrix and one's going to be an
axis control matrix and i'll show you
those because it's more exciting that
way
so
we're adding a by the way the
performance
implications of this instrumentation are
almost impossible to measure i've tried
so i'd run like a million requests at
this and test the total elapsed time and
compare the difference we're in we're
set we're putting in some lines of code
directly into this application that
don't do very much
so this is really really fast
okay so
uh
what i'm gonna do is just use this
application a little bit i'm gonna click
around on a few pages here and we'll
take a look at the uh the test coverage
matrix here
so
just by clicking on a few fields you can
see
what i've tested as guest
right
now there's a few pages in here that uh
will allow me to change my role so i can
switch to user a
and hit a few pages
i can switch to user b here and hit a
few pages
and you'll start to see
now i'm building out my test coverage
matrix and i can see exactly what user
i've accessed which pages as hey that's
pretty cool now i know exactly what i've
tested and what i haven't tested
uh that's not something that you
typically see in
in tests
but we all started also started building
this access control matrix and these
these access pages at the bottom have
this so i'm just going to click on on c
d and e here
and these pages do access checks
and they look like this
so you can see that page a
checks to see if i'm currently in rule a
page b checks for role b
page c rule c that all sounds good but
where's page d
it's not there right and if i look up in
my test coverage matrix you can see hey
i actually hit that
as user b
so it looks like maybe there's an access
control test missing
in that page right
i don't know the access control is like
one of those things some people might
call business logic like there's no
right answer here maybe page a is okay
for everybody to access
i would prefer to see it do an access
control check for like you know guests
or anyone or something but
it might be okay
but this is what observability is all
about we're taking something that's
hidden inside the application it's
buried in the black box
and we're making it observable from
outside the black box
and there's really not much that we
can't do this with
you can see also page e has three
different access control checks in it
that might be fine some pages render
that way like they view differently
depending on who you're logged in as
that's cool
but this is just a real easy way to
expose the access control matrix for an
application
everybody with me how long did this take
me to generate
maybe if i'm in like yeah like if i had
a if i had a script that just ran
quickly through all the urls on this
site it would have taken me you know 30
seconds right so we can build this stuff
really fast i can take that access
control matrix and show it to somebody
on the project who should know and say
hey does this look right like why is
this admin page have no access control
check on it
and they'll probably say oh yikes yeah
that's a mistake we need to fix that
we've done this at scale like if you
look at apis this way
you'll find all kinds of apis that don't
have the right checks in them
they don't follow the pattern and this
is a really fast way of finding that
stuff
any questions on what we did here
okay
uh so let's do one more thing here
just to give you the full power of uh
instrumentation
i want to show you an expression
language injection example
who here's uh not familiar with
expression language injection
okay there's a few people that's fine so
it's pretty simple expression language
is a way for developers of taking data
out of their application like some
complex object like uh
you know a user object or a
business object of some sort and pulling
that data out and rendering it in the ui
without writing a ton of code it just
gives you a very shorthand notation to
grab that data and format it in the way
that you want in the ui
so
unfortunately many frameworks
particularly in java have gone nuts with
this like spring and struts have
expression language everywhere and so
every once in a while
some data flows through the application
gets into an expression and gets
evaluated now normally that's fine like
if i type in you know last con here
this actually flows through the
application it happens to go through an
expression evaluation but it's not an
expression so it just returns the same
thing but if i actually sent in an
expression
like
one plus one
that code gets run
in the server and i get a two back
right so understand like
that's dangerous if you're a pen tester
or a hacker your spider sense probably
just started tingling because you're
like oh my goodness that you can't let
anybody control the code that's running
on your server so then you can start
expanding on that concept you can say
like oh what if i sent in something like
math
dot max
four comma six
or seven whatever
you can see quickly like oh hey i can
also call methods
that's pretty scary and you know a smart
attacker is going to do something
they're going to say oh well hold on let
me just take over the whole server i'll
put in like runtime.getruntime
dot exec
something like open dash a
calculator
that looks right
and so when i submit that
that actually runs
a program of my choosing on the server
it happens to be my laptop it's all
running on my laptop here but normally
you know they would be running that on
your server inside the data center
and they could run whatever they want
not calculated they would take over your
whole system and do whatever they want
probably
uncreatively mining bitcoin or something
instead of like stealing your business
data which would probably be worth way
more to them but
uh
so that's expression language injection
so
what can we do about that with
instrumentation
well
let's look at this uh this jot
so this
it has a couple extra things it has that
same route thing that we looked at
before don't worry about that the
important sensor here is this one
this
instruments three methods
the
the value expression.getvalue
that's the actual expression language
engine like that's what's going to
evaluate this
and what we're seeing here is if we're
inside the scope
of a value expression
then we're going to
prohibit the use of
process builder and socket you could add
other things like creating files and
whatever you wanted in there but you're
saying
we're creating a sandbox around
the value expression
method
so that you can't just run arbitrary
code inside an expression and what the
thing that does it is that exception
line at the bottom if we ever see a call
that matches this we're inside the scope
and we try to do something prohibited
we're going to throw this exception that
says hey we detected an attack and we're
blocking it with jot
so
let's give that a try
i'm going to change my jot here
by the way you can combine all these
jots together you can just point it at a
directory full of dots and run them all
at once
uh so you don't have to keep switching
it's just easier demo wise to do it this
way so
run my application the normal way
and
wait a second for it to deploy
and let's try that same example again
i'm going to cut and paste this i can't
type it so
uh you'll notice the app still works
just fine right we can even evaluate
harmless expressions
because we're not doing the prohibited
things but if i try to enter that
malicious expression
and do a runtime.exec inside there
then jot will stop it and you can see i
got a sensor exception we blocked it you
can even see in the stack trace here
if you if you drill down a little ways
you can see here's our value expression
and inside that scope as you read up the
stack trace you can see inside there we
tried to call a runtime.exec
okay
uh or processbuilder is actually what we
banned which is the underneath the hood
of runtime.exec
anybody with me
okay
it's a five second count while i switch
back to my slides okay there we go
okay so this i'm going to publish these
slides so you can you can have them uh
if you're interested
i did want to show these i just added
this to jot is you can add sensors to an
application
and it's a little bit like putting
cameras up in a bank right like you just
put a camera in you know the right
places and then
uh every time somebody goes through
the bank
you can get a little chart of their
progress so like this this shows one
thread of execution through the software
and i can put whatever sensors i want
here right this one i just kind of threw
the kitchen sink at it i said give me
everything i know you can't read that
because i can't even read it from here
so that's a bad sign but
trust me when i say this this goes
through and says uh like
you know
the top call is basically a get
parameter call and it says hey i just
got like the name parameter and then
like going down a little ways you'll see
another call that says like runtime.exec
or sql statement.execute or
an expression language evaluation or
whatever and like
this isn't it doesn't have any smarts to
it this isn't trying to detect
vulnerabilities or anything this is just
creating observability
okay but with this you can easily see
like oh like that first one is a sql
injection the second one's expression
language injection the third one's
command injection and by the way under
the hood in command inject and any time
you call runtime.exec
java creates a whole ton of
ciphers like all of them
which is just kind of weird but that's
the kind of thing as you you start to
use instrumentation you'll see weird
stuff inside your applications that you
didn't know was happening
socket connections out to the internet
that you didn't know were happening like
phone home stuff all kinds of things
that you just didn't know
now this idea i think is really powerful
most security
vulnerabilities are reported to
developers through pdf reports
this is not the ideal ideal way of
communicating with developers just want
to check my time here
um
it's a little better
if you know 300 page pdf report is not
the right way i want to ban pdfs from
security forever by the way
uh
it's a little better if your results are
in a dashboard
somewhere that's better
even maybe better if they get into a
jira ticket and get reported that way
but still there's a lot of extra steps
there for developers
what if we could communicate with
developers the way that they want to be
communicated with
like right through a failed test
well imagine we just you know we use
that expression language thing or you
know another jot we could easily fail a
test case
if that test case when it runs it causes
a runtime.exec to happen
you could throw an exception and fail
that test case
and
report it right to the developer right
through their test run like this will
show up in their ide naturally you don't
need a separate security vendor's ide
integration to do something this is just
naturally going to fail
the test case and give them the results
that they want they'll
they will fix this right away
because their test failed
and they won't check it in until the
tests pass
so i think this is a really powerful way
of communicating with developers i wrote
a whole article about this on linkedin
if you're interested to talk about the
pros and cons of this but i want you to
think about how security can do a better
job of working with developers
this is just one way
we did this example of expression
language injection already
and so
i want to zoom out a little bit uh
what we just did
is called i asked and rasp so i asked it
stands for
interactive application security testing
that's a gartner name that doesn't
really mean a whole lot what it really
means is
that you've found a vulnerability using
instrumentation that's it that's what i
asked is using instrumentation to find
vulnerabilities
and it's got a lot of advantages over
things like static analysis and dynamic
analysis
interactive analysis works from within
the application it has a bunch more
context
than those other tools right it sees
that whole
real world app reality the runtime
reality i talked about before so
it's much more accurate at finding
vulnerabilities because it only can
report what it actually observed
observability right
um
and
we just built our own ios
right we detected some vulnerabilities
using
instrumentation you can build your own
iest with
with jot
uh there are products on the market that
have you know a bunch of more
complicated built-in rules contrast is
one but this concept is available to
everyone right now
rasp
is pretty similar from a technology
point of view but rasp which is runtime
application self-protection this is
using instrumentation to detect attacks
and it's weird in our industry that
forever
the the vulnerability people have been
totally separate from the attack people
but really attacks and vulnerabilities
are pretty similar under the hood right
i think of it like you know
vulnerability is like an open window in
your house
and
the attack is somebody climbing through
the window and stealing your stuff it's
all about the open window
but the technologies are very different
how do we detect attacks today
if you're not using rasp
see again
they right they well yeah they have to
try to to actually attack you which is
true of rasp as well
um
but the way we detect them is at the
network perimeter
right with a waff
and why is it noisy because a waff has
no idea what it's protecting
raps overblock and under black and it's
never going to fix that because they
don't have enough information
the information they need is inside the
app
waff doesn't know if that parameter
coming in is a comment
that's
you know not harmful
or something that's going to go right
into a query that goes to your database
but with rasp we can protect it at the
right place where we have all the
context to say hey that's definitely an
attack you can even feel like if more if
you used a more complicated jot you
could analyze that the whole query and
say hey the attacker's data just changed
the meaning of the query
that's what we're going to block
so these technologies i asked and rasp
are really exciting they're in pretty
wide use in big companies but i still
think there's a lot of people that
haven't really experienced them
the shift that we're looking at here is
moving from this outside in model where
we're using scanning and we're using
firewalls to a model that works from
inside the running application
and
it's an observability approach it's
directly measuring the running app so
it's more accurate when it's more
accurate we can get rid of some of the
experts like me
out of the cic pipeline where we can't
be
it's a real-time technology
so you know these jots that we just
wrote they're working like right as we
were working
that's really important because you
can't have a scan that takes three hours
to run inside of a ci cd pipeline that
has to finish in 15 minutes that's just
math
so
there's a number of advantages to this
you can put this instrumentation out
there it can just
run in the background developers don't
even need to know it's there until it
detects something so in a lot of ways
it's like you know guard rails
that will just make sure that nothing
goes out of bounds
no extra steps
and ultimately
this technology will allow us
to
build pipelines that do all the security
checks that we need like whatever you
want to check you can check it with jot
you can check it with i asked
and you can build a pipeline that's
that's really strong
you can add tests for whatever you you
know whatever your security controls are
you can add tests for that build a
strong pipeline that'll allow you to
push code into production at whatever
velocity you want to go
that's a real carrot that you as a
security person you can take to the
development teams and say hey let's go
this direction let's work together to
build this pipeline so that it's strong
enough so that i'm sure that it's safe
enough to go into production and you're
happy because it can go as fast as you
want to go
that's freedom
so
ultimately i think that's the key to
devsecops
is
to
changing the work from what we do today
which and i'll talk more about this
tomorrow in my keynote but like
you know the work of appsec today is
it's kind of all over the place
to work that focuses on this
allowing teams to push code into
production at super high velocity with
security
and the results that what we've seen
are spectacular
if you look at the blue line here sorry
the red line here that's what static
analysis
produces so
that says
this is a mean time to remediate charts
so how long does it take you on average
to fix vulnerabilities
and if you look at the red line this is
the median
to close a vulnerability is 121 days
it's like four months
that's a really long time and a huge
window of opportunity for the attackers
if you look at the blue line there
that's uh
what i asked
can produce you get much faster feedback
in fact if you wanted to look for a
definition of
of shifting left and again i'm going to
talk about that tomorrow shift left is
c shift left
is uh
not the be all end all solution but if
you wanted to uh
get more efficient closing of
vulnerabilities this is a chart that
shows that
and for our best
i asked users the one that i've been
using it for a while you can see the
numbers get really good 75 percent of
vulnerabilities closed in just eight
days that's a real difference
something really uh changes in your in
your company when you can do that
so that i'm just gonna that's
the end of my remarks
i want to point you to a couple articles
if you're new and getting started in
application security i'd love for you to
read this article on how to
vulnerability
it's a i spend you know 15 years doing
consulting writing finding
vulnerabilities writing up findings and
i got a lot of experience in doing that
so this is a tutorial on how to write up
a great finding to make sure that
you communicate effectively and don't
burn down any bridges
the second one is a broader article
about the future of appsec and uh
it
it talks about how do we build security
in a software factory so it's actually
repurposing the machinery of a software
development
organization
in order to also produce security so
it's a little different view on you know
kind of the traditional approach to
appsec but i encourage you to read it if
you're in the field
so that'll stop uh
and i'd love
to hear any questions i think we've got
a few minutes
left
so if anybody has any questions about
anything related to apsec i'd love to
try to field them stump the chump time
yeah
can you talk about emerging avm and
appset so that you can basically have
one certificate
yeah
so the question is about merging
application performance management like
tools like new relic and app dynamics
and data dog and things like that with
instrumentation based apsec tools like
contrast and others and
uh
in principle it's a reasonable idea
because then you only have to add one
agent to an application to to measure it
really you can run
two agents side by side they don't
affect each other because it's like you
know
one's putting in you know one kind of
camera and the other is putting in
another kind of camera and they don't
really conflict with each other so we
run side by side with new relic and app
dynamics and all those but i do think
that the future is likely that you'll
just use one agent and get all of that
i'll say that just in terms of the
market like in terms of vendor company
wise
there's
there's plenty of work for a security
company to do to focus on like
instrumenting
for security and there's plenty of work
for a performance company to focus on
instrumenting for performance and
there's there's not a lot of synergy
between those two activities other than
the fact that they they use the same
underlying technology
so i don't know if it'll happen actually
it might happen it might not i don't
know
[Music]
is
yeah so i mean uh you know if if code
demonstrates a problem that's you know
like one of the os top 10 or one of the
things in asbs like it violates one of
the things that we expected to do i'd
call that a vulnerability some of them
are critical some of them are
not
i tend to focus only on the like
critical and high stuff because most
people don't get through that and it
seems foolish to me to focus on the
mediums and lows and stuff before you do
the highs and criticals
yeah
there is a weird distribution of
vulnerabilities by the way like some
apps have a
have a ton
of vulnerabilities
and uh
you know some have very few
so
the distribution is not like
that flat
questions
that's a fantastic question now jot
doesn't well you could put sensors in
jump but it's not designed to solve that
problem but contrast for instance
we use instrumentation to measure not
only exactly what
libraries are there
in the real assembled running
application which is like the first
thing you got to get the right libraries
and if you're just looking at the source
code repo
you've got a bunch of libraries that
don't ever run like test libraries and
stuff
and you're missing a bunch of libraries
that are in the app server and the
platform and things really important
libraries but you don't see them in the
source code repo
but if you're scanning the actual
application you see all the actual
libraries that are there and so that's
the first part the second part is we
measure exactly what methods are used in
each of those libraries and that's where
we get this data is when you actually
measure it
only seven percent of you know all that
code so here's how i break it down
the whole application is a hundred
percent of the code
slice off twenty percent that's your
custom code
and then of the remaining eighty
seventy 74
is unused open source and six percent is
used open source and i say six
i said seven before it's six if you're
looking at the code for the whole
application it's seven if you're only
looking at what percentage of the open
source code of the 80 use
that's why that number sounds like that
but
i consider most of the findings that
come out of some of the other vendors
tools false alarms
because
in many cases
no code in those libraries runs i think
it's more than 50 of the libraries never
run at all
they're just a
transitive dependency that's required so
if you've got like you know library a at
the top and it brings in b c and d
and d brings in uh
ef and g
like if you never use a a feature in b
you're
you're never going to see the
the any of the code in ef and g run
so there's tons of those and if you
report vulnerabilities in that stuff
you're you're reporting false positives
that's not dangerous
in to your question earlier it's not a
vulnerability if it can't be exploited
so
that's why it's a key capability to be
able to know what open source code
actually runs
but yeah open source
software supply chain stuff really
important
one quick note on that software supply
chain topic because it's you know it's
really important in the biden cyber
security executive order and uh you know
nist initiatives and so on
i think of four things when i think of
the supply chain i think of first the
code you write
and even though it's your organization
writing that code it's really part of
the supply chain it feeds into the final
product right
the second piece is
code that you
import that's your open source libraries
certainly really important piece
third thing is code you run
that's like your sas the apis you're
using uh you know products that you
bring in it's another whole bunch of
code that feeds into your supply chain
and then the last thing and this is
really
under focused on but solarwinds just
shown a bright light on it it's the code
that you write with
and
that code
is really important it's all the stuff
that you use to build your product and
if you're one of your developers gets
hacked
the attacker's got a
four-lane highway straight into your
executable that goes either into your
production or your customers production
environments and really hurts people
that's exactly what happened in
solarwinds and it can happen to
everybody everybody is solar winds sorry
your development environments are not
locked down
their developers are downloading tools
off the internet they're running
libraries i don't know if you've ever
watched a
maven build anytime recently but it
downloads the whole world
before it starts running
so you know just
be careful i think you should start
putting initiatives in place to lock
down your development environments
so that attackers can't use that as a
pathway into your production
any other questions we got like uh
three or four minutes left
so when you say just
when you say developer isolation do you
mean like keeping them out of production
environments
[Music]
sounds like an interest i'd love to talk
to you a little bit more about that but
remember if developers are writing code
it doesn't matter like i think of it
like east west developer communication
doesn't matter that much
if they're downloading stuff from the
internet onto their machine
and running it there and their machine
gets compromised
then the attackers can use that to
commit code into your pipeline
and now your product is compromised and
then when your product goes into either
your production or customers production
environments
it's
compromised and they can use it to
launch you know attacks from there
[Music]
not really
it's it's really early i mean you know
somebody's going to make a startup and
make a billion dollars i don't know
i'm already busy
[Laughter]
i'm just dropping dropping ideas just
laying them out there just millions of
them
yeah okay
any any thoughts on uh instrumentation
anybody want to try it who's going to go
take a look at john i know not
everybody's a developer but you know i'm
going to want to give it a shot
okay let's see some very quick hands
people go
uh that'll be awesome let me know how it
goes and if somebody wants to build the
you know net observability toolkit or
the ruby observability toolkit uh
you know it it's not really a tremendous
amount of code
uh so it'd be awesome i'd love to work
with you on that
okay thanks everybody i appreciate it uh
please do stop by our contrast booth and
uh say hi to uh my friends david and
adam here and the folks in the booth be
fantastic
thanks