[Music]
okay
good morning
thank you for coming to this session
um
so my colleague as you see there are two
people here
my colleague uh maureen is here sit at
the front he has provided a lot of input
to this talk
since he has another talk at the last
count we have decided for me to give
this talk but he has agreed to answer
all the questions
uh okay
we're going we're going to partner
okay
security while skating hijab that's our
problem
so one day
i met with a
product owner
i mentioned to him i have
not seen new security activities
recently what's happening
and he said we have a new process
he is kind of excited that kind of
yeah he's a welding
i said what's that he said save
and then i say
save
s-a-f-e
i slowly expelled out he said sure yeah
save
safe shouldn't you do more security to
be safe
so what's going on here what's the
problem he wants to be safe and that he
didn't have time to do security
activities
it turned out
he's talking about this
safe
the skilled agile framework
and
but i was thinking
about this
to be secure to be safe
so um
not only i don't see new security
activities which they
have planned to do
but also we're not even talking about
the same language so as security
professionals what do we do in such
situations
my name is karen and i have worked in
the security and the privacy for for a
long time
currently i'm a principal
security architect
it's weird i always want to learn here
but the voice will change
so i'm a principal security architect
with
palace
more specifically i'm working with our
cloud production
cloud protection
business line
as we know um
there's some trend in the past uh two
decades
they um
the important thing is the technology we
all know right the technology
innovations
has
changed our lives everyone's lives a
great deal so this has created
high demands
for quick deliveries for continuous
deliveries of products with live trend
on the one hand
to meet these demands
the software security the software
development process
kind of went through
a lot of many transformations
you may
have different transformation
transformations that you may be using
different frameworks
than we do
but we have went through from
agile development model you know from
waterfall to agile and now we're moving
to scaleio maybe you are doing something
similar not necessarily the same
same framework
on the other hand
as we know the cyberspace is quickly
expanding
and
at the same time we see a
great increase
of malicious activities especially
since last year because of lockdowns
everybody worked from home
and
at the same time
the software composition become more and
more complex all these
made the software security more and more
important right so we have to expect the
software
development process is changing and the
security becomes more important
then as
security practitioners like us like all
the people in this room
um we really don't have any choice but
join the journey of
what is changing right join the journey
of the software engineers that has been
going through
so the question is
how do we do that
how can we
go along the journey and be the guard
wheel without being
road blockers i've been
i've been told i'm the road blocker you
break your block releases how do we do
without being the goal bloggers
so in this talk we will share our
experience and the lessons learned
in adopting our security process
to the evolving
software development
activities
so um we will talk about at each
stage our challenges
our challenges uh facing the change of
the software process and
how do we adapt what changes are we made
to work out to the software process
and another thing is the journey
continues
we're not at the end of the road right
and
what additional work we still have to do
as we mentioned earlier you may be going
through different transformations you
may be using different frameworks then
we'll currently use called safe a nice
name
however what we learned
what we learned from our experience
not only will help us
um toward future changes hopefully
this will be helpful for you as well
um
so let's
start the
journey
so um
the division the business lines i'm
working with at palace
we provide security products
and services to our uh customers
so the software security is is critical
to our business
so we do take it seriously and um i
understand from then talk to this
morning not all the companies
uh
treat it seriously but
we're a
security company and uh to so too many
security uh activities we do have a
software security insurance plan um so
we we have
we we do have um software products and
also hardware products so we have
firmware and we don't talk typically say
application security software security
so um we have insurance plans which
include a set of security activities and
also monetary security requirements then
we have tools we have trainings and so
on so forth
and so um
and then to support that
we have a
software security community
they are they
security champions within the community
they are not
full-time security people and they are
like people like maureen they are
security champions they are within the
product team
like for example maureen
he's a software engineer he's also a
architect and his swamp master his
technical lead and importantly he's a
security champion so all our security
champions are within the team
so in the past
um
most of our product lines
use uh waterfall models
probably is true for someone some of you
that's in the old days
so the product development life cycle
looks like this right and you have uh um
we start with big right and then you
answer ifps
and you you launch normally product
launch is a big deal and then you do
study you develop you and then your
acceptance you end up with operation or
you
if the customer operates themselves that
you have a warranty period right so it's
uh most products go through this process
and uh
so at each stage there's a formal
process to decide if or not we can go to
the next stage
so the and a lot of things are very
formal the documentation and the review
and i remember
in my younger days so you have formal
technical review for each stage
and then our security plans were defined
accordingly um
and at each uh stage of the product life
cycle
we have various security activities you
have to perform
and then before you go to the next stage
all these activities have to be verified
we have total about 50 security
activities in total
so the plan actually worked in the past
and then as we mentioned from the
beginning right due to the business need
of
an industry industry trend for
continuous delivery so the product lines
have started to transition
into
agile process
look like that right and as you you know
that is an iterative approach
it helps to deliver values to customers
faster and reduce the the risks for for
each
deliveries um so the agile teams they
will work on in small but consumable
increments
instead of making big releases
every six months a year or two years or
even more right so it is an iterative
process
as you can imagine
the um
our previous plan which follows the
waterfall model which does not fit in
this small quick cycles very well right
and how do we the question the challenge
for us
is how do we map our rich set of
security activities
um
through this actual process
that's that's the first transition we
had
so we had various uh challenges
in in the past
a product team is typically organized by
components of the product when i see
product products that include services
we also have cloud services
or a solution right
and uh
so the team is um
it's it's larger and each team could
could be responsible for uh several
related components for example you could
have a team which worked on the
server-side components and then another
team which focused on the client side
and then
with this ideo in order to fast move
around
they the team has reorganized
into smaller
swamp teams
so
so each teams
at
each uh
period in time
and
well in azure i mentioned i haven't
mentioned that in each loop what they
call the sprint right they and the
small team will focus on a particular
small feature to deliver as quickly as
possible and in order to do that
the the team may touch more than one
component
so it's a complete uh reorganization you
can think of as before it's more
functional my server my component my
database is more functional now we have
cross-function notes but it's a small
team just focusing on one feature and
which may touch different components
with this change we also have a larger
number of teams than it was before you
can imagine before we have two teams now
we may have five which in parallel
deliver different features
and at the same time
they uh we saw um with those quick
cycles that uh sprint and it typically
it's
last one to four weeks so it's very
short cycle instead of six months one
year or two years in the old days we
plan really on year day basis right now
we have to plan for these very short
circles
and then engineer manager just told me
karen we cannot do all these security
activities you have 50 of them how do
you expect every strong team to do all
this in every small small circle in
every sprint
what do we do right and
so um we did several things
um first so we uh we broke the fixed
boundaries in the model waterfall model
and we re-oriented
the
security plan
for continuous assurance
we want to make security as part of the
engineering process
so that's what we wanted to do
practically um
during
during the transition
and they focus on deliver features we
have to realize
all not all the features that are
related
to are relevant to security uh for
example at the time we're also making
transition
of the the user interface in the old
days
and then we have ux design team some of
the uh delivery some of uh some of the
screens that um they are working on um
purely changing the user interface
from uh the traditional interface with
the buttons to the more modern
interface without changing any of the
flow so for this work we really don't
need to uh to do the uh
activities right so we realize not not
every venture spring and every strong
team need to go through all these
activities
so
the the first thing we actually did
was
to reorganize
how we express the security activities
we need to do and we basically um
to fit the
skill that style we grouped
the activities as i mentioned the
45 50 of them into about a dozen agile
stories we follow basically the same
style as the team used to express
the uh the tasks need to be done group
them into
into stories
so remember i mentioned the engineering
manager told me
he's the
the head of a product line and he said
we can't do this right and uh what
happened is we actually brainstormed
together and to try to figure out
how to make the security plan works for
continuous delivery and
i was thinking
last night this is actually important
part the security team you don't have to
work by yourself
you really want to involve with the
engineering team together
so um
we we actually
brainstormed a few times and we come out
a uh decision tree you don't see it on
the slide so i just started last night
we came out of a decision tree so it's
basically saying uh if the decision tree
asks a sequence of questions just like
the older engineering design right
and in this
um in this task
relevant to security or not right and
then you decide and i said okay this
pure ui work i want to change the color
and the location of the button right
that's not relevant so you don't need to
do the security stories now we're
creating the stories right and then you
go to the next question
does this work change the architecture
of the product or not right and then you
you look at this work it does it's it's
fixing a bug it does not change the
architecture so you know you do not need
to do
the security analysis of the
architecture okay so it's a sequence of
questions
and we had a team to to try it out and
eventually
with the help of
this the
engineering manager um he said well
there has to be an easy way a better way
for my team to use right than looking at
this flowchart
so we
developed a tool which still asks
questions
and they
they swam team especially the security
champion of product owner depending on
the team so team operate differently
they will just go through the tool and
answer the questions and then at the end
it will generate
a security stories that needed for this
particular uh script but for the tasks
they need to do so basically the tool
help the team to define their objectives
and then to create a relevant
certificate it's not all of them you
don't have to do all of them and you
only need to do the ones you need and
then we have a dashboard too
for
monitoring yeah so another thing we
figured out is uh
okay
so i'm not going to talk into details
about that it's basically like that
right and you group all the
detailed activities into stories and
then during their sprint planning and
then they can
use the tool to find out what stories
they need what security stories you need
to do and then you you plan for it and
these activities are not equal some of
the activities for example security
architecture risk assessment and
monetary security based security
requirements
for these activities you want to do them
as early as possible because
because it
you need to go through them to identify
the issues and then identify the work to
be done and if you do do that too late
and
you may have to rework it may generate a
new new security issues
so we want to do this especially we
focus on risk assessment that has to do
as early as possible and
we really
then mentioned this morning and one of
the mistakes he's saying is
that you have to do the security and
uh
he's not considering the other aspect of
product
and for us uh
luckily we have been doing that right
because we are embedded in the product
lines when there is a vulnerability for
example to be fixed
right
very often you may have more than one
and what you do how do you prioritize
them you do risk assessment there's a
vulnerability what is the risk or what's
the impact to our product right so those
that has to to be done um uh early
um
yeah i've even talked in the past about
risk
importance of risk assessment
so
now we have tried to align um our
security plan
through the engineering process which we
moved to agile and with these changes
it
well it seems to be working right and so
we had that for a while
and then the engineering
they um they worked in the igl process
they found
some other issues
with the process
it's mainly
related to the scalability of azure so
as i mentioned that before we have two
three teams and with agile
a little more teams
more squam teams
now because of the um the
various reasons and the product and
become
more bigger and more complex we have
more customers we have more work to do
we have more people and
now
they um for one product line we can have
12 20
swarm teams
then it becomes impossible
to
coordinate about a dozen or two dozen
teams
together there's dependencies
remember with uh they're all focusing
delivering new features they may be
small they deliver very quickly but a
feature can touch
multiple components and then you'll have
one dozen or two dozen teams
working in parallel they are touching
the same components who will do what
first it's become impossible to
resolve the dependencies
another problem is state
so there are shared resources that all
these teams using for example the
platform the security documentation and
the marketing and uh
it's very hard to get commitments
from these shared resources because all
these teams are competing for shared
resources
and
then
it's also difficult for management
to have a visibility of future resources
future future releases right as before
it's it's fixed now you have all these
teams trying to make release what's
coming when it's coming it's more
difficult
so um that's why
safe come to rescue
uh in a sense and so they
our um
business line has decided to adopt this
process as you may you heard earlier
it's called safe it's a skilled agile
framework
so this framework
is um
the goal of this framework is to help
agile to scale and which uh can be at
the enterprise level what you see is
they call it essential so that's the
basic setup and they have another they
call it enterprise
uh agile safe that basically you have
another layer you can have coordination
between different product lines
but let's talk about just safe
and uh so within the the
the product line you'll have a number of
swamp teams right you can have a dozen
or two dozen and then uh someone had to
coordinate this work and they call it
release train engineer and there are
other roles i'm not going to to mention
um but the safe
safe they have the concept it's called
agile you will see agile release street
on the top of the slides
so it emphasizes continuous exploration
and continuous integration and a
continuous deployment
so agile release training also called
art
okay
so
the
the progress of this train this art
is defined
by something they call the program
increment that's what you see the
the bigger uh
yellow bars that's called a program
increment
so the program inside each program you
increment you can have iterations on
your code sprint
and you can deliver as many as often as
you want but everything
[Music]
every feature has to be split and split
until it fits into
api the program implement that we call
pi and at the beginning of the pi
there is a
pi planning activity it's called pi
planning that's when everyone involved
in this art
will get together to do the planning
and so they
the art can have 100 or 200 people they
were from it's all the stakeholders from
developers
to business owners and everyone
in between and product management system
engineer and the business owner and the
marketing and product owner and everyone
get together so with these pi plannings
objectives
are committed up
defined
for this pi
objectives are defined and committed you
have to commit to these objectives and
the details plans are made they made
details plans and they resolve all the
dependencies of all the different teams
who will do this first so you don't bump
into each other
so um everything is
all the scalability issues that we
mentioned earlier are resolved during
this pi training
so everything is time boxed it's fixed
how long the pi is it's typically eight
to twelve weeks and then within it you
have springtail
three weeks let's say everything is is
fixed
now
these all the product teams start to
move to here
now as you can imagine a search
structure will present new currencies to
our security process right that's why
your you we had a conversation you heard
at the beginning right we have a new
process that's why we're not doing new
security
activities
so uh
there are several challenges so we just
list a few of them as i mentioned
everything is time boxed and people tell
me it's not possible to finish your own
security plan for every pi
or some other people saying how can you
tell us to do all these security things
within the pi right
and that that's one problem that's the
time box the other problem is
the
with the skilled agile
they it's a value driven process
so uh
that they the goal is value that's the
the biggest thing for azure is value you
want to deliver values as quickly as
possible
so i have security champions as i
mentioned that they're all in different
product lines different product teams
right the security champions
they they told me we cannot justify the
business value
for security activities
what does he mean
you know when they do the bipi planning
you have different activities the way
they prioritize is by business value and
he said we cannot justify and then the
security stories
are pro prioritized lower than other
activities right than other stories and
sometimes push will push from pi to pi
that's why the product owner is saying
every time before pi planning and i said
well remember we said we need to do
these security stories and he said i'm
sure i will do it right and after the pi
planning i said you know uh which
iteration you're going to do and he said
unfortunately it pushed to the next pi
okay so it's a priority spell over
another thing is uh it's more of the uh
engineering uh issue in in the past with
agile the teams they uh they use a
concept that well they use a feature
branch uh branch meaning the software
branch right and then they will do their
security stories on the feature and
before they merge into the main branch
but the safe recommended to use what
they call um
trunk based
development so you have a main track
basically as soon as your code is ready
you push to the main tracker they have a
reason for it right so
in this way you can do the system level
testing integrating testing as
frequently as possible as quickly as
possible in order to identify problems
right if you you integrate you merge
later
when you
identify the problem it may cause rework
and the redesign will cause design and
cause delays
that's why
you want to
push to the main trunk
as early as possible so that's also
means for the security
story security activities we need to
perform on the main trunk that means we
need to automate in our pipeline which
we're not there yet
now what we do
of what we have been doing to address
these challenges
um we have done a couple of things
since we uh since the teams moved to uh
safe
first we involve our security plan again
remember the first change is we
reorganized into security stories
and so we actually updated the stories
they using the safe language
and
we
also
provide a better clarifications
and what needs to be done how you do it
what other tools are available
and
with with the safe language
we safe we actually tried a couple of
things
initially during
safe training
the trainers we
in the safe training they don't mention
about security right you can imagine
um so we ask what do we do about
security the recommendation was
treat them as non-functional
requirements
we actually tried
and also it works in theory right for
every push and then you
you will finish all these
activities
um
but it didn't work um in practice
because for
it's the business owner who prioritize
all the stories or the tasks
and then they prioritize non-functional
requirements lower than functional
requirements you can imagine right and
the functional requirements they see
value right non-functional requirement
and they don't see that clearly
so it didn't work out well and
however from long run and if we had more
tools automated the non-functional
requirement could be a good place
because you can say if the acceptance
criteria you have to finish all these
non-functional requirements
but at least at the beginning we tried
it didn't work
and if you think about safe is about the
value
in order to go
go along with the advantage driven
process
we started to look through our security
plan right we have all these stories we
look at this security plan and um
then we and then we've identified things
we can call them
enablers so enable us in safe
activities for involving architecture
improve infrastructure and for
compliance
so we use
and it turn out that most of our
security stories can be treated as
enablers
for example instead of tricking
to assess static security testing as a
story and we make automated sas
as an enabler because enabler provides
value for the infrastructure for the
present and the future business features
they are pro they can be prioritized
much better so this address the value
value proposition problem and as i
mentioned earlier because of the main
function because of all these quick push
we need to um
focus
on automation
so that's more of the
security scans
we want to put the security scans in
the testing into the the pipeline and at
the meantime we want to provide
better security guidelines
for um for using these tools
we're also building a security templates
for pipelines
this is a work in progress
because we have
many different product lines
each product each product
they use
different languages even within a
product and use different languages and
then they use different frameworks
and they have different pipeline
technologies some use it lab as the news
github some use team city and
there's some usage
there's many different ones
so it's still working progress in terms
of automation into different
different pipelines
uh
so the question is can we automate
everything
right that's ideally uh that's what we
want to do practically not everything is
automatable
and i remember ben canel was giving a
talk always talk as online talk last
year and talk about things and not not
about human people yeah um so
aligned with him there's certain things
that are not automatable
at least with current technology you can
see oh we'll have a.i
that will automate these but it will
take time and believe me i worked on it
for many many years
so they
for example the security assessment
when i talk about security assessments
it involves identify your business
assets your supporting assets you do
threat modeling and you assess your risk
and you make management decisions
just think about this this and at least
for now it's not automatable with the
future technology you may be
able to automate some parts of it
and then we have a set of monetary
security requirements you want to check
your compliance that is not
automatable and maybe some part of it
you can code it that that's what i want
to do but we're not there yet
so
another thing is we really push to
identify security issues as early as
possible
they um i'll tell you a story uh once
they um appeal
um asked telling me we have a new user
flow to make it
um
more user-friendly users
more convenient for users can you look
at it
if um
if it cause any security issues
so
we look at it and did a very quick
analysis
and then we realized that it brings some
medium risk it's not high risk but
bringing medium risk but if you think
about it it's just trying to resolve
solve some
use cases not major use cases then it's
not worth it to bring the median use
case
and he'll accept it and decide not to do
it but imagine if you do such risk
assessment at the end you you you
already spend
your resources to do the work and then
you realize it's not worth it right so
you want to do the
identify security issues as early as
possible then particularly with safe or
how do you do it and maureen suggested a
couple of
opportunities you can use a research
spike that's what you typically do at
the beginning right so that's a perfect
place you can do your exploration to you
do your analysis for security risk
and if you identify
new issues if you can plan into the
current
um
pi or the work period or whatever you
call and you can do it otherwise you
talk with people you make changes
and you may change the scope or you you
they find you decide you
you push to the next pi and also the
same as the concept of continuous
exploration that's also an opportunity
to do security analysis
so it's important to build security into
your process again you may be using a
different process the one we usually do
the thing called pi planning right in
safe you have pi planning those are the
vertical bars you saw earlier so we want
to create security stories
using the tool we have before and during
the pi planning right and then talk
about security other pi finding and then
you plan your capacity for security
worker during the peer planning
and then for finding the capacity and
our product teams are very creative they
know how to do it and they can they may
plan the capacity for security worker
directly and
they may reserve some they preserve some
capacity for dealing with unknowns
that's the
that's a good place also to um to do the
security work
and then um
and also um
when we talk about a release train level
they typically also reserve some
capacity for pure 100 million work that
is not controlled product owner
that's also an opportunity
so with these changes the security is
well embedded into the engineering
process
um
so
the journey continues we still have
order uh to do and uh um because
they the
engineering process has changed
and it will change
right it will not stop there so we
cannot stop evolving our security
process we have to go along the way and
for example the maturity of our security
champions as as you uh
uh so we do have trainings right and
another thing is as you all all know
there's
um
there's a lot of they call it a great
resign
right since cohen a lot of companies
you know have people changing uh
changing places
um people resign here and go to other
places and we are not isolated
especially our security champions
they're they're really really good and
it's very easy to be grabbed by other
companies then we have new security
champions we have continued continued
learning
so
that's not um yeah that's a continuing
process and we also want to continuously
improve our process in terms
especially in terms of automation
guidelines and and the tools there's so
many security tools and we have to
evaluate them and
figure out and test them and figure out
how to integrate in in the pipelines
okay so um
yeah
so uh what what our takeaways um i think
today uh to think back i think it's
very important to work closely with the
engineering team
and that
in the uh
many of the things is
in my experience is really
resolved by working with engineer
directly and um
and also with not just the people like
mooring by and if he can do everything
and you also want to work with
engineering managers product owners
which is
very important because product owner
will
prioritize the tasks
and
we want to embed the security in the
engineering process that's what we said
earlier and automated security tasks as
much as possible
and as security people just be friends
with engineers and product owners
and
be persistent
be patient and be helpful
thank you
[Applause]
sorry i talk longer than i suppose okay
questions
and a marine can answer okay
earlier
you're talking about generating a set of
stories
do you have a concrete example or were
those cards on the previous page the
examples like generate a sas story or
security or was it was it something a
little bit more connected to what they
were building like
i could talk about
the project
i can talk about it if i want to show
you i have to connect to vpn
i can't do it
it's everything is online but i can talk
about it right so initially when we
first changed to agile right and um
they uh
so uh the the story would be uh
let's see uh
a
risk that's you know the the security
scam you will say it's a purely ideal
way you will say as a product owner i
want to see my product go i want to see
the product go through they uh they
static security assessment tools i want
to see the report and then you know
definition of done is they the result
there is a result and the height and the
critical risk that has been uh has been
addressed
yeah so it's that style
and
then um
and then with with the safe with skilled
agile we change the style again for
example uh but the same the same task
right you need to do the security scan
we change it as enabler when you have
enabler you don't need to say as a state
holder i have to do something and then
we can change the story into um enabler
story it will say build sas tools into
the pipeline and then you scan it every
time you push and then these are the
tools that you can use and these are
here are the guidelines
yeah
yes so basically
so the stories were called subclass so
it depends the scale
it would escape
like since we are doing continuous uh
featured tvs so first they are mostly
sub tasks for a single story and
depending on the feature what kind of
changes you're doing
if the tool would create the task for
your income sas you need
stories that were applicable to that
team whatever work that team was
assembling um yes so again um
every generally in uh jira terms it's a
bigger thing right okay so but in terms
of uh for features small features we are
talking about stories with subtasks
something which can fit into within a
single string
uh but if you are doing it for something
like a new component for which you need
to do all the setup for a set of the
pipelines or dash directivity in that
case yes we can go with separate stories
but then he's speaking for a particular
feature we end up creating a single
story with all the subtasks for perform
the sas for this and generally with all
of those things now automated
you don't need to do much over there to
perform for the finger single feature we
are just running the jobs making sure to
run verify the analysis and do the
features over there based on that so
based on the since we are doing
and that's the difference between the
uh the
waterfall versus agile and even within
entire continuous delivery where you're
delivering every small features over
there so the scale of the security
activities you need to perform they are
also used a lot right so i think you're
doing small tasks rather than the bigger
stories whichever speaking episode i
think one of the things i found a little
fascinating
and maybe this is somewhere you're going
in the future and
a problem that i'm faced with right now
is i have
650 different engineers globally spread
across
and
what you're describing i would put under
my security epic for whatever pipeline
they're doing they have to enable these
hygiene activities
inside their their product that they own
but what i started to hear a sense of in
your talk that i thought was very
intriguing was when you had a tool that
was generating this
and that two
the non-pro the description about
non-functionalities that's the exact
same approach i'm doing because i'm
creating standard non-functionals
for program owners and teams to consider
from a large menu especially just like
the the oauth
validation screen
and say which ones are applicable to you
each time and pop them up the fact that
you have a tool that helps screen and
identify i think that's a very powerful
very powerful concept but this ties to
like a very specific thing like
authentication
here's your abuse test and
misuse tests that should come along with
your authentication requirements
and i think over there the same three
that the client was mentioning that is
helping around because
uh for every we are talking about like
15 to 20 swim teams i mean it's
difficult for karen to
monitor all of them saying okay make
sure you're doing all those tasks or not
right right so for those with those the
same kind of people saying okay
what kind of changes you're doing and
based on that rule tells okay yeah this
security is incredible for you make sure
you do that kind of thing so that is
everything a lot over there especially
like the size you're talking about i can
imagine how difficult it would be over
there to apply that right so we are
talking about the art of like 200 people
and we
before we moved to safe uh it was being
very difficult to manage with safety a
few things require improve like the
visibility uh not not within just in
training but also at the management as
well as across the shared resources i
think that solved the issue a lot for us
uh and with the security part over there
getting integrated with that
it's it's yeah
it correct the stories and you see the
status that you can do
and i cannot uh yeah let me finish this
i cannot emphasize more
of working with engineering team
directly and i'm sure you all have
security chemo so when i started a
couple of years ago we have over six our
product plan i mean our business line we
have
over 600 engineers
and i'm the only person full-time
security architect and then uh we have
another person just two of us
just imagine how do you cover this right
that's why we
we have security campaigns people like
maureen who helped a great deal
otherwise you know two
um two people and over 600 people 100
years and now we have we're lucky we
have a few more uh people but in still
just
barely one percent of full-time security
we fully rely on our
security champion program