all right it looks like it's about two
o'clock uh there's a break at 2 45 so if
i don't get going you don't get a break
right so i better get going
my name is jason kent i'm a hacker in
residence at a company called sequence
security we do automated attack
mitigation
and we do api security strategies that
include things like you publish a spec
we check spec informants
with traffic that's live
so i spend a lot of my time looking at
customers and watching my customers get
attacked
and we spend a lot of time trying to
figure out well how is it that they
figured out
to attack that end point
sometimes it's easy it's just the
trailing slash on an endpoint that they
didn't realize was on
sometimes it's a little bit harder in
that it's a p12 file or it's
you know some other thing that was left
as a default install whatever that might
be
so like i said my name is jason i've
been doing this about 20 years i threw
my first angry tick mark at a website in
about 98 99 somewhere in there
um i've spoken actually at last con
quite a few times and typically when i
come here i'm here to talk about a
responsible disclosure that i just
finished
this time it's going to be more of a
i submitted a responsible disclosure and
they told me it isn't
and now i get the court of public
opinion to tell me if you guys think
it's uh worthy of a responsible
disclosure and i'll show it to you
uh here in a bit
like i said i do a lot with bots
i do a lot of like
hype sale type bot work so sneakers ps5s
that kind of thing
keeping all of those guys at bay and
trying my best to to make sure that we
understand that they can't be buying
everything we we should be able to buy
everything right
all right so
the whole concept behind this talk was
i was i was chatting with one of the
people that works in our marketing
department and they were like all of
these things that we see come from
too much information inside of the api
responses and i was like you know what
that's not a bad talk track so we're
going to call this tmi api
and what it is is this apis that are
easy to get to
uh that are talking way too loud so
you'll be able to see
interesting error messages you're going
to be able to see things like routes
endpoints stuff that we thought was hard
to do with api is actually pretty easy
to do with apis because of mistakes
and so we're going to go through that
i'm going to talk about how people find
apis
i'm going to talk about the api top 10
mistakes that i actually see live
problems right this a lot of this comes
from
my customers this isn't really a
schadenfreude talk though i do throw a
bit of that in there
and i've done that in the past this is
more of a here's what real live attacks
look like and if you're worried about
attacks you may be worried about these
things
who are the attackers um and then i'm
going to go through a bunch of examples
of things
so how do people find public apis well
dns searches are pretty easy right i can
just look for api dot and then whatever
top level domain and i'll probably find
something i can probably also find dev
dash api or
something of that ilk
so dns searches are going to go
pretty well we're going to find a lot of
public apis through that
what we're starting to see now is more
instrumented tools that can go out and
find things and
if you guys have been paying attention
to the space at all kite runner came out
in april
kite runner is this neat new tool that
does content discovery um it goes and
finds apis and it actually says here are
all your api endpoints here's the ones i
got a 200 off of etc and so forth
but really the power behind kite runner
is this massive word list that they have
all of the slash swagger endpoints all
of the um you know different kinds of
api endpoints that you probably
don't want people touching um are loaded
as part of kite runner kite runner's
word list asset note is who put this out
and their word lists are available so if
you guys want to you know run kite
runner yourselves or build your own
um you know you can just use their word
list as part of it
the other searching for public apis that
happens
is people that are doing things like bug
bounty searches where they're looking
for very specific things that they know
almost every company leaves on
right so your
wp-admin file on a wordpress site or
xmlrpc.php on a wordpress site these are
really common attack locations we see
uh attack automation constantly banging
on these things
and what's interesting about it
especially in a bug bounty i mean i
actually had somebody in pakistan send
me a hey you left your
xmlrpc.php file open it's got
pingback.ping on it
on a site that had nothing to do with
anything and i didn't care
and i replied back to him and said okay
i'll take it off and he's like where's
my money
right
we weren't registered in a bug down
anywhere real important that we be
registered in a bug bounty if you're
gonna go try chasing somebody up for
money
but there it is
some other ways that we find all this
stuff right just messing around with web
applications
look at your email anymore right buy
something from anyone you're going to
get an email that's a purchase
experience email that says thanks for
your order and here's your tracking
number and all that and if you look
you're calling some api on on someone's
back end that's part of that experience
company
so just looking at
the stuff that you do every day is going
to lead you down this path
mobile applications there's a couple of
different ways we can get api endpoints
out of them
you can instrument burp right you can
and i'll show you guys how to turn on
burp and what you need to set it up
uh to
intercept your phone
in case you want to look at your mobile
applications
as well as you can take the apk files
from the
android install
and you can take them apart right
there's a bunch of apk tools that are
out there that'll give you lists of
endpoints so finding the public
endpoints is not that hard
there's a site called api's guru
apis.guru
that has
api listings if you want to try to go
see if your company's up there and
github is another one and if you haven't
used bigquery to query into github i
recommend that you go look for kite
runners
their landing page and asset note
they'll take you through how to use
bigquery to query github and it's a
really interesting thing
if you want to go look for
api keys or passwords buried in github
bigquery will get them out pretty fast
same with you know swagger files and
that kind of stuff that's why
kite runners out there
so we're going to
talk a little bit about the owasp api
top 10 and some of the mistakes that i
commonly see
in my customers i spend
a lot of my time taking an adversarial
look at how
their
transactions are flowing
i've got a lot of retailers that i'll go
look and say okay
when i sign up for your registration
page it tells me whether or not my
account already exists
if my account already exists and i know
my account already exists then i can
just sit there and enumerate accounts
right that's leads to account takeover
and so that's just a simple error
message that is something that needs to
be you know fixed so those are the kinds
of mistakes that we'll talk about
we'll look at the attacks that come
after you've made those mistakes
um and then we'll try to figure out what
are these attackers doing
and why do apis enable this attack
automation
so the biggest mistakes the two biggest
mistakes that we see
our authentication and authorization
makes sense the top two in the top ten
um but in reality what it looks like on
the back side
uh is things like
authentication headers not actually
functioning correctly um and so in my
disclosure that i made to this company
called lithium
i said listen i can just take the
authentication header out
and be authenticated and they said not
that's normal right and i went
it's not quite normal especially since
your multi-tenant platform and i can use
my authentication from one tenant
to go to the next tenant right
and they were like
public data totally normal
and i said all right well
after 90 days i you know kept bugging
them and finally i just wrote a blog
post about it said i'm just going to go
tell everybody about this
um but authentication and authorization
are difficult concepts
because most people
don't try to roll their own which you
shouldn't
um they try to grab something that's
going to work for them and oftentimes
they set something up wrong to use that
piece
so if you're authenticating off of some
other api using saml using something
else
and you don't have that set up correctly
if you're not checking for the headers
on the on the other side then
authentication is really not actually
needed
error messages are going to change the
way we look at things
i was talking to some guys last night
and i was saying that the state of api
security is right about where web
security was in 2009
um we are aware it's there and we got a
whole bunch of crap coming right
remember 2013
we started to see a lot more breaches
and absec related stuff we're starting
to see more and more api related stuff
now
you guys familiar with brewdog anybody
know who brewdog is
yeah they got beer
and an open api that has bad
authorization on it and if you want to
go just generate unlimited coupons and
have all the beer you want you can
right
this is where our api security is
error messages are going to tell us a
lot and when i used to teach
developer training classes security
classes to developers i would tell them
go find one error message you like
and make that your only error message
it confuses attackers it confuses the
people that are there and you don't want
to provide them any help
and i'll show you a few examples of this
as we get going
um
default or vulnerable components left on
right
how many of you guys
have a wordpress site or have used one
in the past
right so you can go to wp-admin and
there's the admin page did you know you
can change that location i mean that's
security by obscurity but it definitely
if i don't know where the admin page is
i cannot log in right
and that makes that a lot easier
there's lots of default components that
get left on in apis as well
and it's stuff that we have to
kind of take a consideration for
so
by far and away the biggest attack that
i see at my customers is account
takeover
uh it's usually happens through some
kind of credential stuffing attack but
sometimes it's completely validated
results
how does somebody get a valid list of
credentials for your site
any ideas
you can buy them yeah
um
you can buy them from a bunch of places
that process of generating those lists
is called cracking
so if you google the term cracking
you're gonna find a bunch of sites where
there are credential lists that you can
buy
but what you probably don't know is
there's tools that are already built to
go attack your site those lists are
sitting in a config file that you just
load onto the tool and run
and a lot of my retail customers have
these problems because they have rewards
programs
or they store purchase informations to
make purchase faster right so your
favorite pizza place if you can log into
it and hit buy now
your credit card is stored there and
it's going to perform that transaction
so
you end up with a situation where
account takeover
actually turns into fraud right or theft
so we see this a lot rewards programs
were getting hit right before covid
really heavily
and then as kovit came along
we lost that
we don't see as much reward program
problems
because most of the retailers we worked
with required rewards to be spent
in-house and all the brick and mortars
closed so
that
that started to wane but what we are
seeing a lot of is
purchasing right somebody getting logged
in
and buying things
we also see a lot of inventory control
or what we call seat spinning
in in our customers and what all this is
is somebody going in and saying add that
to my cart depending on how the back end
of that application works it may lock
that record and it may lock that item
or it may not it really depends um
seat spinning the idea behind seat
spinning originates from
credit card fraud does anybody here ever
had their credit card stolen and they
end up with airline tickets being
purchased
so this is how it works
i advertise on facebook that there's
a 400
flight to somewhere in europe and first
class
sounds great does anybody here think
they're getting that ticket if they buy
it
good
so
what's actually happening is there's
somebody sitting on the airline website
holding a seat
they put that advertisement on facebook
somebody goes and buys it
sort of
they just scrape the credit card
information and then go buy the seat
that's how you ended up buying a bunch
of airline tickets
but what the attacker then is going to
do is try to transfer that ticket out of
their name or
they've purchased it for somebody that
they already know
everything for
but seat spinning is just that concept
of i've got it locked i've got this item
of the
inventory locked up and then i'm going
to do something with it later
the biggest financial benefits that come
out of these attacks are usually things
like gift cards or credit cards
sometimes it's rewards points like i
said we're seeing that kind of decrease
um but gift cards and credit card
purchasing are you know by far and away
the largest pieces of fraud
i have a customer that has a gift card
test endpoint where you can go see what
your balance is
and we've actually watched people go in
there
put ten thousand gift card numbers in
just by sequentially guessing
when they get back hits that say that
there's value on those cards then they
start hunting for the accounts so that
they can transfer the money off
so being able to get onto those
authentication endpoints get on to those
gift card endpoints
means something is going to happen
and then the last
reason why we're seeing higher amounts
of the tax on apis especially with our
client base
is hot stock items
anybody here shoes do shoes
any chefs in the crowd
cop a lot of shoes no right um if you
look up chefs you're gonna find cook
groups
um and these are people that are trying
to buy shoes and then sell them on ebay
they're 15 year old kids that live in
their parents basement they make 200 000
a year
reselling brand new sneakers
right it's a crazy market and it's
really interesting to get involved in um
the reason that these things are working
is
everybody's trying to fight this bot
problems they do stuff like
put the regular users in a waiting room
right anybody here try to buy a ps5 or
done the waiting room trip
right you're standing in line like it's
the 70s and you're trying to buy gas
right like this isn't how it's supposed
to work the internet's supposed to go
way faster than this
um and inner
apis do go way faster than this
we see a lot of
times customers will come to us and
they'll say all right well when we do a
hot stock drop the first thing we do is
we shut off our mobile app
because we can't instrument
the mobile app to understand you know
with any kind of telemetry to understand
is that a bot or is that a human so we
leave only the website up
which is kind of an odd thing do you
know who knows how to get out of line
faster on a website than you do bots
that's who
um
if they leave the apis up
apis are meant for speed
right this is computer to commuter
communication so the bots are going to
win there
too so
if you ever want to figure out how do i
beat the bots uh there's a
interesting um article on this where
this guy
does what a bot does you know he's got
50 tabs open on his computer and he's
got all these accounts and all this kind
of stuff
and he ended up buying a ps5 that way
i did a very similar activity where i
sat in front of my local police station
creating gmail accounts using their free
wi-fi
and
to become a bot as a human is really
crazy
to go to the last talk that was in here
the automation is important right
instead of trying to do it one at a time
all right so
we've covered why automation may be
working on your api right
authentication authorization issues
errors
possibly forgotten endpoints
and maybe assumptions of how users
should work
so
this is a this is an example of an
authorization problem
i'm logged in
to fitbit
i'm going to pick on fitbit a lot
because they're using this company
lithium's platform
and that's where my
that's the problem that i found
so you can see here uh i'm logged in
and then
i can search for
myself or other users and so if you look
at this weird string that's down here
this is actually the request
to look at my profile
except i've changed out
select splat
and
i'm looking at profile id one
what's profile id one going to be
if it's not zero
this is gonna be the admin right like
it's gonna be the first account that
gets built
um and so what i wanted to see was can i
actually pull the data for user one
logged in as myself right this is how an
attacker is going to look at your site
when they land on it
and sure enough author id one
um it says
lithium admin
uh as the user account
so is this an authorization problem
right i just
looked at someone else's profile by
guessing it right
i probably shouldn't be able to see this
profile
though when i reported this to lithium
they said no that's normal
but in reality what's happened here
is i sent that request in
all of this stuff up here
where it says lithium session id
is the authentication token that i'm
passing
it's a platform authentication token
it's not just for this particular tenant
and so i was able to go look at
the other things on there
that are in the platform and we'll come
back to this in a sec
one of the other
problems that i see a lot of is this
exact example
you'd sign up for something
and then go back and try to sign up
again and put your email address in
again
somewhere it's going to tell you that
account already exists
um and this is up in this uh error
message here or down at the bottom there
it says email exists
this is how an attacker is going to
enumerate all of the user accounts in
your environment right
so if you see a single ip address
trying 10 000 usernames and generating
this error message a lot
that's somebody that's trying to figure
out the accounts right
so what's a better
solution here
a generic error message
is better
being being that i had to go through
this the best thing that you can do is
require all these fields because that's
going to tie up somebody that's trying
to attack you right
but they're going to figure out an api
endpoint that you have anyway and use
that
so something went wrong is a better
better way to do this
um
most applications have routes folders
now you can go find the routes it's
going to tell you where everything is
anybody here run a dynamic application
security testing tool a dashed scanner
like qualis or any of those tools
see some heads nodding
you can't scan an api why
no ahrefs right i don't know where the
next thing is so i have to give it some
kind of information in order to figure
that out
a lot of the scanners now are accepting
spec documentation and they just want
you to point at it right so you have
some public repository somewhere with
your specs in it and we point at it
um there's some danger that goes along
with that as well
but we are seeing more and more data
that comes out in this stuff and like if
you look at this this is chow now we'll
take a look at these guys in a bit
um there's an awful lot of data about
each one of the profiles that's in here
gps coordinates addresses
their membership level inside of this
environment
there's a lot of potentially if there's
a competitor wanted to look at this a
competitor could go scrape this and
you know really bear competition against
them because they would know everything
about every client
now as this is chow now has anybody here
used ciao now or do you know
did any of your favorite bars that have
a really good hamburger suddenly have a
way to buy it and deliver it to your
house
that's probably chow now or toast one of
the two
um and this is how i found it my
favorite burger place down the road
during the pandemic i said how do i get
my burger
and they said well we got an app
and i was like oh really
and then i had two problems
one of the other
really odd things that we see and if you
watch it's funny if you watch any of the
youtube videos on how to do api security
testing or anything like that
they're going to tell you always look
for
you know
lower version numbers
if v15 is available v1 for sure is out
there two or three
i've had customers come to us and say
we're being attacked i don't understand
how they're getting to this end point
and it's just got a trailing slash they
didn't realize that they had left that
endpoint open
and they have to go in and you know turn
the endpoint off
but there's a lot of obvious endpoints
that are out there
login etc um that you're going to see a
lot of traffic on it's the
endpoints that probably shouldn't have
any traffic on them
that are going to tell you where the bad
guys are right and a lot of times you
can just scrape the ip addresses of
the weird traffic that's coming in and
just go block it
right if you
really want to be like that i tend to
send people to this deceptive responses
so they spend all day thinking they're
on some site that they're the admin on
but they're not
i prefer that
i pick on wordpress a lot because
i have customers that have built entire
ecommerce platforms out of wordpress
and when they tell me that i say
that's an interesting choice uh and as a
minnesotan and somebody from the midwest
whenever you say interesting
uh that usually means bad
right
um but it's a really weird way to do it
one of the challenges
is that wp json file gives you all of
the endpoints that are available the
authentication that's available to them
what kind of methods you can use it just
goes on and on and on it's like a
manifest of how to attack the thing
if you've got
xmlrpc.php open
then i can turn you into a proxy
endpoint
and
i know that you have that just by simple
testing right and i'll show you guys how
to do this in a sec
so whenever i pick on these guys it's
not because wordpress is terrible
wordpress has a lot of problems and it's
weird but
this is the kind of stuff that's making
it weird right leaving your defaults on
we got rid of uh
flash on websites you guys remember
flash
why did we get rid of flash
anybody know
it was an awesome malware platform like
we could load malware because it's
deeply embedded into your machine right
but why did we have to get rid of it
couldn't we just stop that well it turns
out there were mechanisms to stop it
it's called a crossdomain.xml file and
that tells you where you're allowed to
pull the flash from and you know how
everybody configured it
splat
pull all flash right which had malware
in it
it's just
hygiene right these are simple hygiene
things
so here's a few questions that are
um obvious attacks that are going
against api endpoints
but
this is the kind of stuff that we see
all the time right
um
240 different 247 different ip addresses
in two minutes same user from all over
the world
right
um
the ml that we use picks this stuff up
pretty easily
um this is a the second one is a really
good one and i've been dealing with this
at a client
should you see the regular chrome user
agent
touching the mobile app endpoints
typically you name that as a user agent
right i call it my cool app or whatever
and that's what the user agent i see
that's the browser that i should see
hitting those endpoints
if i'm seeing chrome it's one of two
things
it's a developer testing to see if
something works
or attacker
right
there's only really two reasons you'd do
that
this last one is one that i've been
dealing with with a customer minus in
canada they only do business in canada
they're a canadian company they only
should have traffic from canada and you
go look at the traffic hitting their
site and it's from everywhere in the
world
right china russia ukraine
all places that you would not expect
them to be ordering you know food or
whatever
from them
so should everyone in the world be able
to get on your site this is the kind of
stuff that
if you're looking at the way that your
site manages itself
it's a good idea to ask
so in this automation example
if we look at that a little client
user agent that's up there
[Music]
this was hitting a regular web endpoint
right and i saw about 350 requests in
two weeks
so this is kind of a low and slow they
were just looking at php files trying to
find are there any vulnerabilities in
here and this is the kind of stuff that
we see constantly
another one of these is
um order numbers right this is somebody
just iterating through order numbers you
notice they're not sequential
and we saw this two ips generated
twice of this many requests
in about 20 minutes and then went away
right
what this is is somebody had ordered
shoes and they were checking to see if
they had shipped
right
so what ended up happening is
we realized that they got through and
bought a bunch of shoes and shut all
their orders down on the back side when
they started running their tracking
program on it
um and you know
then they do a restock and
the bach guys get mad
what are you going to do
i had a responsible disclosure right
before covet started
where
i bought this webcam
something was eating my cucumbers
and i know you all can relate to this um
right out in my greenhouse something ate
all my cucumbers it was aggravating they
were eating the plants they weren't
eating the fruit the plants right down
to the grounds annoying
so i put a i bought this camera and i
had a web app that's fun
um and
so i started playing around with the api
endpoints and i realized that if i gave
you a a bad account name
it gave me an error message and if i
gave you a bad password it gave me a
different error message
man talk about a system that makes it
easy to go figure out what the usernames
and passwords are i mean it just kept
generating all these error messages
so i did a responsible disclosure with
them and you know what they did they
made this error message the only error
message
so
people will be confused
it was a good idea
all right so now i'm going to do
something that's uh possibly a little
controversial but i haven't had a live
demo fail in years right because we
haven't been out walking around uh too
much so
i think i'm gonna you know tempt the
demo gods and see if i can't get some of
this to work
so what i'm gonna do
um is i'm going to set up burp
so i've got burp here
and
it's not displaying it on the screen
because
i need to do that
see i haven't had to do all this in a
long time either i'm sitting home with
two monitors usually
[Music]
yeah
so this is burp
anybody here use burp
yeah anybody here use burp
for machines that are not the machine
burps running on so proxying things
through your machine okay so the way
that you do that is up at the top i'm in
proxy options so if you aren't familiar
with burp there's kind of primary
secondary navigation that happens on the
page so i'm in the proxy settings under
options and what i've done is i've added
port 8100
to all interfaces
then what i can do is go into my mobile
phone and say i have a proxy it's port
8100 and it's the ip address of my
machine
that way my mobile phone will proxy
everything through there if i want to
start looking at api endpoints or
whatever i can do that
so
let's look at some stuff
this is uh fitbit
um like i said i pick on them quite a
bit because you know
i found this problem with lithium
once i get logged in here i'm
authenticated onto their platform
but i'm
not just authenticated on the fitbit's
platform i'm like i said i'm
authenticated to everything that lithium
has
and the reason that that's important to
sort of note is when you go look at
proxy http history
when i go look at this actual post that
logged me in
where you at
it made a request to go get my
information
really small
i tried to blow this up as big as i
could but still kind of small but inside
of this query it's just simply going and
getting my user profile information that
kind of stuff
so
what i can do is take a look at the
requests that go out and the responses
that come back and see can i make
changes
and so in this case i can see that i'm
making a request
to get information after i authenticate
and then
all right and then the request
here it is
sent to repeat
so here's the request after i
authenticate
and up there you can see that select id
if you got really good eyes you can see
select id avatar profile etc and so
forth and my profile id
doesn't that look like sql
remember that thing i showed you earlier
um
select id login avatar where users etc
right this looks a lot like sql to me
when i sent this in i said listen you
guys have our string concatenating
directly into sql you should never do
that they said it's not sql
that's
liql
it's lithium query language
not sql at all
and you can't do anything with it and i
went oh okay
if you
were to zoom in on this a little better
you'd notice up in the
in the query string there's this weird
alphanumeric character set
and i looked at this and i thought well
what is that what what on earth is this
weird alphanumeric
numeric character set that's up there
and if we look at it it's
x-m-n-u-z whatever
so i went and did a dns query
and i figured out that that's
fitbit's community
and what i can do
is just
change the string in the front and it'll
change the community that i'm looking at
because it's a multi-tenant platform
so what i've done now is i've changed it
to a different one i now need to change
probably the host that it's going to
because this is actually roku
and i send in the query and it sends me
back success
i was looking for myself if i go throw a
splat in there it's gonna go get
everything
um and so what i've done is i've
you know pre-set up this query so that
way it'll be a little faster up here but
just do
this
and now i've got the api sending me
everything what it's done now is sent me
a list of all users
so i'm authenticated onto fitbit's
platform and i just requested all users
by changing the sql query on roku's
platform
anybody think this is wrong
because lithium didn't
and
when i sent it to him they thought it
was completely normal and i was like
okay
so this is ciao now
i also sent them a bunch of stuff about
this this is a really wordy response
site they have a lot of things that come
out on their responses each one of these
numbers up here represents one of their
customers so you can literally get all
of their customers their gps coordinates
their addresses
who the administrator is for this stuff
it's a lot of things that shouldn't be
accessible to me
as somebody that's out there
yesterday i
i did a talk
on api specs
for api world uh which was a conference
that occurred as a virtual conference
and they use a system called hop in
uh as their
zoom if you will the conference
management software
and so
while i was waiting to to give the talk
i ran one of our new tools against hop
in and and i went and found their api
specs
right
their specs now tell me all of the
things that i need to know how they
authenticate
and interestingly like if you go digging
through all this stuff
it'll tell you like
here is how our authentication is
supposed to work it's supposed to be a
jwt in this header right so now i know
quite a bit about how the authentication
is going to function here
and i know a lot about all of the routes
that they have where their documents are
hidden and all that kind of stuff
what makes it nice um is that i've been
doing this with a tool that my company
is just now starting to put together
um so this is api fury
um and all this is is we are taking this
concept that kite runner has put
together
and adding a bunch of stuff to it based
on what our customers want so you can
see i put in hop in that's the the
organization the conference running
software
and it told me here are all your open
api swagger endpoints there's a bunch of
exposed files that come out of this all
the rest api services that we could find
um all the different pieces that i would
need to move to the next phase right
so
what i'm
now
trying to illustrate to folks is that
this information
these apis that are out there that are
making all of this noise
um
they're easier and easier to
find in addition to that more of us are
putting out specs or documents that tell
us how to interact with the api
and
not necessarily as a human as computer
to computer interaction
um so if you just google go out and
google and look for things like
app api docs
or slash swagger.json or any of those
kinds of things
you're gonna start to see spec sheets
and you're going to start to see
information that's going to lead you to
the what would be the next phase of the
attack
open api files
i recommend that you have them you
should have them for your security teams
definitely it should be a review process
that goes along with that but it
definitely shouldn't be something that's
open to the public
i believe that if you're going to be
publishing an open api spec or a swagger
spec for your apis
receiving that should require an mba
right
um just simply because
you don't want to have it out in the
public
because people can find them
so in addition to
simple dns queries simple searches
through your mobile applications
if i know your top level domain i can
start sweeping it for
specs
once you have a spec though being able
to do things like monitor for spec
conformance
is the app actually doing what you
expect it to do our users actually
making proper requests to the
application that kind of stuff
you're going to start to see
your api security is going to get a lot
more robust
and you're going to see the attackers
coming less
i always recommend to people that they
go out and they teach themselves about
these things
simply googling yourself and having a
good amount of google foo is a great
idea
test for errors in your applications
what are the things that you're telling
people
run your apps and your mobile apps
through proxy
and try to find any of the endpoints
that might still be stuck or that are
out there look at your logs
and if you don't have logs get logs
they're great
and they let you look for things like
do i have endpoints that are open that
people are using
right that makes it very easy to figure
that stuff out on your own
and finally if you're interested in api
security and you want to learn more
about this there's an application out
there if you've ever used web goat or
juice shop there's an api specific
vulnerable app called crappy
uh it's a
completely ridiculous api
but crappy's got some uh really neat
features in it and it's a very good
education tool if you have a group of
developers uh back at the office that
you'd like to teach about api security
have them install zap have them install
burp install crappy
and work through the challenges it's a
it's a pretty good system in my opinion
like i said be on the lookout for our
api fury if you're looking to do some
discovery on your apis that'll be coming
out here in the next month or so
you can find me on linkedin
uh or shoot me an email
jason.kent at sequence.ai
i think this is the fourth time i've
spoken at this conference and every year
it's just as fun as the last so i really
enjoyed being here
if you guys have any questions i'll be
sticking around for a little while and
then run into the airport so
i really appreciate the time you spent
with me today and i hope your apis are
safe and secure
[Applause]