all right good afternoon everyone let's
find receipts we'll get started
my name is jeff duhovnick
and today's presentation is
infrastructure as code
all right to kick things off we're gonna
do a mindful minute
and for those of you who don't know what
that is uh basically
we're gonna
take some deep breaths
just relax soften your gaze
for a minute we want to be aware of
where we are
and just try to clear our heads to get
ready
if you have any thoughts
flip through your head maybe stresses of
the day just try to label them
let them float away
about halfway through
a couple more deep breaths
10 more seconds
all right
all right continuing on
uh who am i the whom i slide
i said jeff the hovenic i work for rec
space government solutions
i'm a senior netsec product engineer
and don't let the term product
throw you off too much i still do netsec
so
firewalls ids ips that kind of thing
i kind of didn't know what product it
was before i took the job so in my
interview the boss pretty much
said hey you know this is product like
so i developed new things and i'm not on
call he said yeah i said great
sign me up so
i learned a lot about the product
development process and cycle
learned a lot about the business side of
things
in my new role so
really happy to be there
really happy for my security background
that i've gotten along the way
as you can see
i like python i've been deep into aws
and been doing devops
i'm not a security connoisseur
not so much of a practitioner
not doing the day-to-day operation stuff
i have a family
i'm an avid hockey fan
any other hockey fans in the room all
right
and
i'm in enemy territory so i won't say
um but i
yeah i do
i grew up in pittsburgh
so
i
i also do woodworking and i am an avid
reader as well
all right so real quickly uh this is not
a prescriptive presentation i just want
to get your wheels turning thinking
about things so as i present ideas uh
it's not meant to be a
a solution but more of a thought or
something you could take back and think
about
there's a lot of links in this
presentation so i encourage everyone to
download and follow the links
and get some ideas get some more
reference material to re-up on
also this is not a security focused
presentation
so
the question is
why am i here i'm at a security
conference well i think
a couple reasons number one i'm among
friends i've been to
rva sec
quite a few years now so i know a few
folks in the audience so that's great
but also my coding skills are not good
enough to be presenting at a developer
conference
but i know amongst hackers the idea is
you know get it to work and you're good
so
i got my code to work so i think i'm
good
any developers here
all right cool
you guys can
probably spot some inefficiencies pretty
quickly
all right so to kick things off this is
kind of the roadmap of what we're going
to do what we're going to talk about
terms and definitions so we're on the
same page
theory principles and concepts some
pseudo code some modeling patterns as
you can see we're going to go a little
bit into
some developer theory
some developer concepts
also i'm going to mention the cloud as i
said i've been working in aws so my
references are in aws but the theory and
concept should apply to
three major public clouds as well as
private cloud
all right so the first is you know
why would you do infrastructure as code
and
you know pretty much there's some
obvious things
um
you save time on deploying
you
you have a consistent deployment you
know all these things are obvious but
really when you look at leveling up
you look at your dry principles and
stuff it really becomes apparent and
we'll see that
with object-oriented programming how
that ties into infrastructure as code
making that bridge is
really crucial in getting to that next
level
all right so some terms and definitions
infrastructure
is probably obvious things router
switches your infrastructure that makes
iot run your database servers your app
servers your load balancers
but also infrastructure in this case
when you're coding
you want to think about things like your
iot
you want to think about things that
are connected but maybe not managed
so you can apply code
to those things so it's not just your
typical i.t infrastructure but
everything
infrastructure is code is management
code
then some programming concepts
object-oriented programming
i used to hate this concept because i
didn't understand it but once i started
understanding it and using it i really
started liking it because it made my
testing quicker and easier i mean my
development a lot faster
it just made my flow so much better and
it got rid of my
ugly scripts
that i was creating
all right so what's the big idea
we went through some obvious
advantages but
bringing that down to a business case
we've talked about saving time
increased and easier security so there's
our security mention
there's a talk tomorrow at one o'clock
on security with infrastructure as code
so good follow-up talk to
today's presentation
also compliance with uh your code repo
and version control any auditors in the
house
all right so what do you guys think
infrastructure is code if all your
infrastructure was in code
you'd be pretty happy you'd be able to
see everything right there what's
deployed how is it deployed what's the
configurations you don't have to go out
to every device
and look i can just check my code i can
see the version control in history
so who changed what and why is real big
with code versioning repos
that becomes readily apparent
some other not so obvious
benefits code is documentation
so if you've ever written documentation
you got to be a real special person to
write to really like doing that i know
there's tech writers that enjoy that but
me i'd rather code things and i think
most folks here in the audience are more
of that you know development type person
so instead of writing your code separate
why don't you just keep it all at once
so another not so obvious benefit
rolling back your version control
you make a change it's easier to roll
back we'll get into that a little bit
more with the ci cd stuff
it's reliable it's repeatable is manual
when you're just doing iac if you go
into devops it's not some manual anymore
it also enables business process
automation for you business types
there's your buzzword
tagging we'll talk about that as well
all right so
principles and concepts
let's follow some practices
um i didn't use as many memes as i did
last presentation so
here's a couple for you though
some days i feel like
the dos equis guys some days i feel like
the husky um
you know what is
these concepts it's one of those things
it's a rabbit hole you know where you
you start learning one thing and you
find that oh there's another way to do
this or there's a better way there's
more levels we'll talk about some of
those levels as well
but really
uh the big title what's wrong with your
2009 script anyone here just have a huge
script that they run i know
i currently do i'm working on moving
away from it but
uh there's nothing wrong with that cloud
formation templates if you use them
extensively they get very big and it get
out gets out of hand really quickly
so
there's nothing wrong with it though if
you're if you like doing that
if you are comfortable with your cloud
formation template
that is code it's infrastructure as code
just be aware that
it gets unmanageable pretty quickly
so if you like it you can keep it
otherwise
let's look at another way
one of the big things we talked about
don't repeat yourself try the
programming principle so code needs to
be reusable so if i write code i
shouldn't be writing the same code
again you know i should be able to reuse
the code i've written leverage what i've
already done otherwise i'm repeating
myself
and repetition and programming is bad
so why not just reuse our code that's
how objectorian principles come into
play here so as if i treat my code as
objects it doesn't matter when i use
those objects
they're available for reuse
also documentation on code libraries is
important you need to know how to
interface with your objects in your code
a single responsibility principle
and the the kiss method
i apply the kiss method to a lot of
things i do try to keep things simple
try to keep them understandable because
as soon as they start getting complex
you know within a company i used to work
at
if you started presenting something and
you got the response of
that sounds complicated let me think
about it the answer was no
so keeping things complex really keeps
people engaged
whereas you start going over people's
heads they just kind of space out
so what's the difference
between our object-oriented programming
scripting
so in procedural programming or writing
a script you just have stepwise one two
three with object-oriented programming
you have
whatever whenever wherever i need to
call it so i still have my logic i still
have my flow but i now
maybe i jump around a bit maybe i
break my code up into different files to
manage them easier
and then i call those objects in those
files so it's not one two three
but it's actually easier to read because
my main file is not so cluttered you
know because i have references to
objects and then knowing what those
objects do is also important
so
some concepts
at the high level
code should be reusable we've went over
that loose coupling
this is really important
concept to understand is well if i have
dependencies
those dependencies are going to hurt me
in the long run because when i go over
if your business is siloed or even if
it's not but if you try to take what
you've done and it's got dependencies
and move it to another business or
another part or even another
organization you need to have all those
parts move whereas if i'm loosely
coupled
i can move one part and not depend on
the other
so object-oriented programming really
hits home on that too it's a lot easier
to move classes versus
your script
so classes inheritance from parent
classes
passing objects
those are some of the principles that we
can apply
all right so here's that ugly code i
promised you
pretty quick we'll step through it
this is just an example of using
object oriented programming
the bottom part is actually the
execution you can imagine if that's in a
different file it's just put up here on
the same file as
for simplicity
but basically i'm creating my class
creating my objects
having instantiation so my
initialization of them
but
i have a method to get and set the
object
and in this case it's just a simple
vpc which is a network so vpc
ip subnet
pretty simple pretty uh quick
uh if you were to use cloud formation
this would probably be three times as
long
to set your vpc up
all right so we've gotten the basics now
but
now we're really going to get into
some programming concepts
we're going to look
at two patterns
this book kind of
just for historical context this book
brought to the forefront some
programming concepts and patterns
that are still in use today so
if you have interested in object
oriented programming and want to take it
to the next level
definitely
pick up a book or at least some of these
ideas and concepts
so to the first pattern we're going to
look at is the factory pattern
it's a creational design pattern with a
common interface so you create your
infrastructure and regardless of what
you're creating it's always going to hit
the same interface
for me this is the next logical step if
you already have a script and you want
to take that script to object-oriented
programming
factory pattern is a
quickest way to get there
next is the builder pattern so the
builder pattern
is nicer when you don't have that
succinct
environment if your environment has lots
of variables if you're deploying
different environments with different
pieces of infrastructure the builder
pattern is pretty much better way to go
the builder pattern focuses on using
pieces and parts versus the hole
and then you can take those pieces and
parts and build your environment
with those whereas the factory kind of
builds the whole environment
as is
with
you can change it up too but
it's easier to do piece by piece with
the builder pattern
okay so moving to modeling complex
information systems
all right so this is something that i've
presented actually at one of the rvsec
monthly meetings it's my automation
worksheet
and basically it's very simple but it
helps me get my thoughts down to move
this into an infrastructure as code
worksheet
mostly get my prerequisites so i think
think about things like
what are my dependencies what do i need
to be successful
if you work in a
compliant environment a very strict
environment do i need my build tickets
do i need reference tickets numbers
what modules might it need we saw the ip
address module in the earlier code
what other modules might i need
do i need to test those modules before
using them in my code
existing classes other people have
written
do i already have code i can leverage
additional resources i'll need do i need
other developers do i need network
configs
warnings known issues gotchas i might
hit
timeline is probably a good one to add
in here as well
so my pseudo code
this is a great programming concept that
i like to apply but basically i import
my modules this is what i'm going to do
i don't have to worry about my syntax i
don't have to worry about
if it's going to work this is just
getting my thoughts clear and getting my
steps defined and how i want to actually
build my infrastructure
and even this to me is a little bit more
detailed i like to personally go a
little bit more free form than what's on
this page
for my operations
this is actually i consider this more of
a database concept but we'll borrow it
for our playbook on infrastructure
basically anything i do with my
infrastructure boils down to i'm either
creating something
i'm going to read and retrieve it
i'm going to update something that's
already there
or i'm going to delete something that
exists
also we'll add upsert
upser is kind of doesn't fall into any
of the ones above so i just added it
basically it says make sure something
exists and if it already exists make
sure it's set to this specific
configuration
so you don't have to do your check you
know does it exist if it does exist
makes you know make sure it is this if
it doesn't exist create it the logic is
already built into an absurd operation
so now we need to map this to our
infrastructure it's called practice and
principle
how do we do this well everything is an
api call today
you know
everything literally everything is an
api call or
can be so mapping that to our crud
operations
is pretty important the most obvious and
common one is get git does a few things
get re
first off it's very easy to
to accomplish a get request you don't
have parameters generally but the get
request also
test my authentication and authorization
so if i can do a get request i know that
that's good to go i can move on to doing
more complicated things like doing
updates doing deletes
patch i don't really use very much but
it is their
post um probably more so
or i'm sorry put more so
all right anyone here use postman
all right good
postman is pretty awesome um i think
postman create very easy to create api
calls
very extensive libraries
they now have
modules available you just download the
module fill out your parameters and
create your api call so getting from
my pseudo code of what i want to do to
mapping out to those api operations now
i can actually syntactically create
those api operations with postman so
postman is a tool
pretty nice to leverage api calls with
here's an example
this one
using the aws library again just fill in
your parameters
pull your data
one thing i noticed right off the bat
with this
is
the amount of data that's returned is
kind of insane
so you have to account for that
be able to parse it there's ways
documenting ways to do that but we'll go
into what
maybe another way to do this
one of the cool features i like this is
a
stupid developer trick
we'll call it but basically
in postman you just go to code and you
can create your
python or whatever other code you want
for your api call so i get my api call
down in postman hit a button and now
i've got my my code i can use in my
language
which brings us to
our software development kits so now
we're going more on the developer side
so as i said i'm kind of python back
background
python sdks are readily available
they're cloud dependent though so you
need your sdk for what you're doing
so now you're getting more into am i
doing aws well now i need the bottom
three sdk am i doing vmware well i need
you know the nsx sdk so it depends on
your cloud it's cloud dependent but
a little bit more powerful a little bit
more streamlined
also your cloud vendors do document
these
fairly well
minus one of them which i won't mention
which one that is
uh here's a here's an example
so again this is doing the same thing
that we saw in postman
um
the return is
about the same but
the code for this is pretty elegant
what you don't see on here is the off
and off z portion but that you can write
as a class
make it an object and pass it into this
and you'll be good to go
so i used to think oh yeah this is all
great for all languages but then i
looked at the java example and um
that's why i don't do java no i just
um
i don't do java because i i stick with
python because i like it
but anyway
um the point being here is that there
are sdks for other languages that are
usable so if you are java or other like
if you're a go developer there's sdks
for your clouds
which would allow you to leverage
object-oriented programming
me
so api is a simple way
sdks now we're getting a little bit more
flexible really getting more to the
object-oriented approach
api calls generally be swapped out for
your sdk
objects classes methods
so if you want to create a vm in azure
versus creating a
instance in aws it's going to be
different
all right so now we get a little bit
more into
some different tooling this is uh
configuration management tools
so your puppet chef ansible
uh those type of tools
uh we're gonna leverage those for clouds
so we have cloud agnostic ones i
mentioned some of those salt is in there
uh
terraforms in there uh we mentioned
terraform a few earlier talks
and then you have your specific
cloud tools so
cloudformation the aws cdk which is kind
of a hybrid of a sdk
terraform its own language interacts
with python so the cdk is kind of the
dark horse and all this
azure resource manager templates
gcp has theirs and vmware viewrealize
orchestrator uh they do have a
sdk i believe definitely do have an api
and a gui
your templates basically define your
infrastructure i want this
defined go
object-oriented programming kind of has
an advantage of
well not unless you can do it this way
but you could also say well i already
have this but what do i want different
or based on this that i already have
maybe i want to do some more logic so
that's where your
um principles come into play templates
just kind of define
your set i think a template's a great
starting point i don't think it's kind
of the end goal for a lot of places but
i think templates are the way to
uh to start
all right so
now where are we as an industry
are we using object-oriented
oriented stuff or are we at least using
some sdk are we using cloud formation
are we just defining our infrastructure
and so really crude attempt at research
going through
the github
search
bottle 3 which is python sdk for aws
you got about 2500 repos 92 000 commits
that's pretty good
because that's only one language don't
forget there's like java go and other
sdks out there
cloud formation
we have 2000 repos
48 000 commits so
that tells me that the industry is
embracing
these sdks and is primed for
object-oriented programming principles
to be applied
so now that i have these
this infrastructures code then we'll go
to the ci cd world well how do i do that
well it's
really
infrastructure is code is the first step
to go to ci cd you need your pipeline
in your pipeline you're going to do your
builds you're going to do your
tests
and then you're either going to deliver
or deploy depending on compliance
requirements or how comfortable you are
with doing a full automation suite
for my industry i work in the federal
government it's mostly delivery because
you need at least one manual process in
there to be a gatekeeper to say go or no
go
there's lots of opportunity for
automation in your cic pipeline of
course
you know all all the cloud players have
various tools to
automate this
the big thing to take away here is
there's a lot of information coming in
for devops and ci cd but start small
just just pick one thing like maybe i
have a firewall that i want to
start automating on so i'll start
writing some code we'll put that code
into a cic pipeline just for that one
firewall and then start expanding well
maybe i want all these other firewalls
and let's start from there
definitely don't try to eat the whole
elephant at once
you do have the security benefit in your
cic pipelines so now don't forget our
audit logs for infrastructure as code
we know who implemented a change because
they wrote the code we know what changed
once we go to ci cd for auditors we know
when it changed because we have logs of
that pipeline run and we know where it
changed we know where the code was
applied and to what environments
if you're looking for some more
training on this sans sec 540 which i'm
currently taking
is a great resource for this as well
but csc to devops so there is a
difference frequently you kind of hear
the terms
interchanged
i say oh yeah we're devops well
are you devops or are you just using a
cic pipeline well what's the difference
so
here we have the agile manifesto who's
seen this before
yeah okay
yeah it's been around it's kind of the
start of
devops
it's really a great read if you get time
i encourage you to read it if you think
about devops but it explains
you know
what devops is it's not a tool it's not
a technology
it's something that the whole
organization needs to buy into
it's something that's more about
the processes it's something more
about people working together
how to respond to changes versus
having
post mortems
and stuff
also you need support throughout the
entire org because in devops you're not
going to be working in the silo you'll
be working with
everyone
so that said uh let's go over a quick
review i would
define some terms objection programming
classes methods all that stuff that's
something to be more read up on
and not so much something to be
memorized
we went over some theory principles
and then we got into how to kind of
apply those with pseudocode
i got into some patterns i really
encourage you to check out the different
patterns that are available i went over
two of them the builder and the factory
method
and some of the benefits of those
we went into modeling complex
information systems
and finished up with config management
tools going into ci cd and devops
so for that went really fast
so left a lot of time for questions
so
any questions
yes
ah that's a good question
so how do you drive
um
we've been migrating to infrastructure
as code with staff who are resistant to
change
well that one
is actually fairly easy
so you start small with the small quick
wins
so pretty soon
the rest of the staff is going to notice
that you're sitting there drinking your
coffee while your code is being deployed
or tested or done
and they're writing their code or
they're
they're managing their infrastructure or
they're building and configuring things
like the network team is a great example
as i said i have a security background
focused on netsec
so this is one thing that we're
currently going through which is
managing firewalls anyone who's managed
firewalls or touched firewalls or looked
at cisco ios
knows that it's a bear and so
if you have your network team focus on
like one firewall
and say okay here's our code to manage
this firewall
and then start applying that
well they'll start noticing
the benefits it's quicker it's easier
i'm not stressed out because i'm not
worried about mistyping a configuration
or an acl that takes down the network
you know i am i have my code it's been
vetted uh it's been peer reviewed that's
another big part of this uh which also
helps with audits and compliance
so i'm i'm less stressed out
okay
so that starts catching on so the pretty
soon your network team
starts catching on um
and then so your database team notices
those network guys they sure do drink a
lot of coffee i wonder wonder who's
managing their network oh it's code
oh they're code repos the code repo is a
big one too
you know any everyone likes to
contribute to code repos
you can see what's going on
so pretty soon your database team goes
you know what
the sql queries i don't really
like writing those every time let me put
them in this code
so
that's a good way start realizing the
efficiencies start small small quick
wins
is is a key to
school success
um
yeah yeah that's another nice thing to
point out is uh a lot of the
organizations a lot of the big
enterprises have recognized the value of
infrastructure code and devops and the
movement towards it so you are starting
to see a lot of vendors
and
and manufacturers integrate
with things like ansible puppet chef you
know they're starting to write their own
modules
putting them on github so you can see
what the code does exactly so if it fits
your needs or even if you want to
contribute to it it's there for you so
thanks great example
any other questions
yes
um
yeah so
uh
i'll admit uh i was i'm probably there
myself whereas that the patterns book is
the next step up for me
uh so how do i get to that step or
wherever you're at how do you get you
know to the next level
and first is recognizing where you're at
so
i'm assuming most folks in here can
write a script whatever language it is
doesn't matter it's bash python
powershell ruby
um you know anything right you write a
script next step would be going into
object-oriented programming concepts so
can you do object-oriented programming
in your language is the first question
if not then this can't apply
but in python which i found to be the
easiest yes go to go get some
object-oriented programming with python
education
linkedin learning has a really good
course if you have access to that
a cloud guru has a great course
if you have access to that
there's open source references on the
web
there's lots of python documentation out
there
again that's my background if you if you
like go or whatever i'm sure there's
resources out there so start going into
object oriented programming
and once you get comfortable with those
concepts like i showed decorators
there's like magic methods all you know
all that kind of stuff that's
maybe foreign to someone who just does
scripting once you get comfortable with
object-oriented programming concepts
then go into your patterns and it'll
make a lot more sense
because if you just jump into patterns
it can be very very overwhelming
good question
yes
right uh good question so the question
is if you have a smaller organization or
if you have an organization that's
focused on segregation of duties how do
you move that to devops
and
i think the response for a smaller
organization is pretty simple uh
you know we're not simple it's probably
easier to get folks on board because you
work with everybody so you can
evangelize hey we want to move devops we
want to be agile
you know and knowing everybody you can
work with everybody
the second part of that question the
segregation is a little bit harder
because you can't really have your
segregation and have your devops um
co-exist you have to say i might be a
netseq developer but i have to work with
the windows developer now you know and
we have to make make networking work
together or
uh for prime example
you have an organization who hires
sysadmins right sets that means to
manage your systems well if you notice
here infrastructure as code is more
about development than system management
yes i need my parameters to know
you know
maybe maybe what processes i need open
or system management type stuff doing
iem i need i still need
that expertise but now i put it in code
so i need that added developer code
so it's a little harder to do with
segregation of duties but keep in mind
you still need that segregation of
expertise maybe working together that's
that's what i would
probably say would work
so yeah definitely as you saw
in the manifesto
not so much segregated
more about working together
cross-collaboration and that's that's
how agile works so if you have a company
say oh we're moving to agile okay great
can't wait for everyone to start working
together and break down these silos
uh any other questions
okay great
i'll be around tomorrow if anyone has
any discussions
again encourage everyone to look at the
links on the slides in the slide deck
it'll be posted shortly
and
thanks again for attending my
presentation and hope you have enjoyed
the rest of the conference
[Applause]
you