all right everybody welcome to my talk
introduction to inner loop security
shifting left but better
so quick overview today we won't uh
spend much time on this slide tell you a
little bit about myself i'm first time
rva sex speaker so super excited to be
here i've been doing this work in some
way shape or form for about 17 years now
i started off as a what we would now
call a full stack developer what that
really meant was i knew delphi and
fortran and databases and everything in
between
ultimately moved into consulting where
i've had a very exciting career spent
some time with a little boutique firm by
the name of aspect security and i'm
super proud of working with the founders
of owasp and a whole bunch of other
people who are smarter than me i did
some time in big4 where i worked at ey
and led our defsec ops for financial
services so working with some of the
biggest and most mature applications
security programs in the world and
scaling them
passionate about really everything i do
around apsack and def secops as will
probably be obvious in this talk i think
we do it all wrong um you know this
whole talk is based around how i think
shift left itself is particularly flawed
then i'm a big believer in
developer enablement and just making
things easier for developers making
security the path of least resistance
and when we make security easy
it will just happen and people will do
it
i'm really fortunate married my high
school sweetheart i like video games
hiking guitar
next few weeks are particularly exciting
to me if anybody plays mmos we've got a
big expansion for final fantasy 14
coming out if you like fantasy books
we've got will of time coming out on
amazon i couldn't possibly be any more
stoked for that
so thesis for today's talk shift left is
an outdated sentiment and it's no longer
relevant in the world of agile and def
devsecops it's developed into a culture
where we punish developers for taking an
interest in security and ultimately
there's got to be a better way
so the end result of this talk is really
i want everybody in here to think about
developers your development teams and
the impact that we have on them as cyber
security practitioners
so i want this to be pretty interactive
so
show of hands
let's start off easy how many of you all
are in cyber security
all right pretty much everybody is
anybody a developer
half hand all right how many of you
write scripts even if you're not a
developer
so quite a few people right yeah i would
argue to be in security you have to be
able to do at least some level of coding
how many of you are on an appsec team or
do appsec
all right a handful
how many of you have an apsec team at
your company even if you're not in
appsec yourself
yes
all right so got a good good mix here
it'd be interesting normally i present
this talk to developers and appsec teams
and devsecops conferences so we'll see
how it goes with the cybersecurity group
so i guess you first of all again this
talk is really about devsecops so we
need to agree on what that means before
we start because probably everyone out
here thinks something different when i
say devsecops right so to just boil this
down make it really simple what i mean
is performing security inside of devops
devops or
doing application security
at speed and at scale
so regardless of your preconceptions
about def secops for the next hour this
is what def sec ops means
so before we talk about shift left right
we just kind of need to level set a
little bit further especially since a
lot of you aren't developers right we
need to understand the software
development life cycle and hopefully
everybody even in security has at least
heard of the software development life
cycle before it's kind of like the
scientific method
it's basically the process that
developers follow the life cycle as
they're writing code
and it goes from there's
tons of these right if you google
software development life cycle you're
going to find a hundred different models
they're all variations of the same thing
they're all correct right but it
basically goes from requirements to
design to implementation to testing to
deployment and then release and
maintenance
it's a very waterfall
concept from back in the day when we
used to write waterfall code um and if
you google it you're going to find this
written in all sorts of different ways
now right we've written it for agile and
it's the same damned thing it's just
inside of an infinity symbol we've
adapted it for devsec ops right where we
just took security and put it around the
infinity symbol
and just
have just messed it up
really badly along the way
but
explaining it in a waterfall way makes
it really easy to understand because
it's linear right and we can all take a
look and we can understand what these
six items on the screen mean
so what do we mean when we talk about
shift left right if any of you have ever
been to any apsec talk ever in your
careers you've probably heard about
shift left right and every appsec talk
starts with some scary numbers and a
graph and we talk about how we find
issues with pen testing
and they're really expensive to fix and
if we find and fix those issues earlier
in the software development life cycle
it's cheaper and we don't takes less
time for us to fix them it costs less
money and depending on whose paper
you're reading those numbers vary
anywhere from 30 to 150 times more
expensive to fix issues in the
requirements phase than in the
maintenance phase
and so this term shift left kind of came
about which referred to all right well
everybody in the world is basically pin
testing even if we're not doing appsec
we're probably pin testing our apps
sometimes
well
let's start doing things earlier right
let's look at static analysis tools
let's talk about
threat modeling hopefully some of you in
this room are as excited about threat
modeling as i am
with the obos top 10 2021 you know wasp
is now saying everybody has to threat
model nist just wrote a paper three
weeks ago that says if you're not threat
modeling today you need to be threat
modeling and not only do you need to be
doing it you should be doing it multiple
times per release for your applications
you know so look forward to that
impacting a lot of you in the very near
future
so to boil it down really simple right
shift left is just
doing things earlier right you'll hear
other people talk about you know shift
everywhere or devops will talk about
shift right it just means doing security
throughout all of this software
development lifecycle regardless of what
yours looks like
all right and so let's let's talk a
little bit about the history of shift
left because i this is one of those
things that you know i've been doing
this again for a long time
i've always heard shift left literally
every vendor talks about it every
conference presentation
so i kind of asked myself well where did
this come from right what started this
shift left thing and you know when did
it
start meaning let's give the developers
tools that are hard to use
analyzers that give them false positives
that print out 700 page pdf reports that
nobody ever reads right like when did
shift left come to mean this and so when
i actually traced it back
shift left actually wasn't even an abset
concept it was an article written in
2001 by larry smith
so that was the first surprise to me
right it wasn't a pen test article it
didn't even talk about
you know stopping pin testing or doing
testing earlier in the software
development life cycle it was a quality
assurance a qa testing article that was
talking about writing
testable code
and doing qa focused testing throughout
the software development life cycle and
this is a quote from larry smith here
you know bugs are cheap when caught
young you can catch bugs earlier by
making qa a part of your development not
just a part of the release process if
you go to any def sec ops talk today
that's probably almost verbatim what a
lot of these people are going to talk
about this was 20 years ago this guy
wrote this so
my question is
why isn't this our reality right like
why how did shift left change meaning
along the way and why did this focus on
qa testing
never happened
and we even got a big quote that i'm not
going to read you here from larry smith
that talks about how embracing qa
testing and doing it throughout the
software development life cycle it's
going to make your life so much easier
it's going to make management think
you're not working at all
because you're working so smart and not
hard and you even kind of cautions on
the very last line but don't let it look
too easy
all right josh so you obviously don't
like shift left
why not right so
security responsibilities are added to
developers without any thought regarding
the impact
who here has static analysis tools in
your organization
who here has said that's a shift left
activity and because it's pluggable into
the ide and has given it to the
developers and forced them to use it
okay there's there was there was a half
hand back there we have one honest
person
it's poorly implemented
it often results in punishing developers
right i'm also not a big fan of security
champions programs right because i've
been in consulting for a while now and i
have seen many security champions
programs
fail
right and the reason they fail or one of
the many reasons
is because they all start with this
nomination program right because we say
okay well we have like
one you know to your point over there of
these apsec unicorns in our organization
we've got like 12 000 apps how on earth
do we possibly scale this program
oh great we have these apps champions
right so we find some poor developers
who you know maybe mentioned owasp or
they found a bug in one of the apps and
we say they would make great champions
you know what we should do we should
give them more work
make them use tools that aren't designed
for developers we should not pay them
anymore we should not give them a cool
title
and then expect them to do all of these
things that our security team is well
trained to do
and then we wonder why our appsec pro
champions programs fail right that right
there is is why they fail
tools aren't designed for developers uh
i
off the top of my head i can't think of
a single application security tool out
there that is designed they may be
marketed towards but they're not
designed to be used by developers
almost all of them take significant work
to configure them to get good results to
tune them to go through
the results to do what we call a triage
to get rid of the false positives
almost all of them are prone to to false
negatives
they take up
time
right especially a lot of the old ide
plugins you give them to the developers
and they click scan and they're single
threaded even so their ides lock up for
hours at a time and then they can't do
their job which is writing code
our developer performance reviews
don't include security right so we want
our developers to be an arm of our
appsec program but then we don't grade
them on it
right at the end of the day developers
jobs are to
write code
and right to push out business features
and business functionality and then we
want them to do do it securely
but that doesn't reflect in their
performance reviews
so how on earth can we expect them to do
things securely if we're not going to
grade them on it
and then finally the value provided by
uh shift left in my opinion is
questionable
i should ask before we started does
anybody here work for a tool vendor
hopefully not last week i presented this
and one of the guys worked for now
secure and
a little uh
felt a little bit bad
all right
so
all right that's a lot of complaining
and talking about the problem right but
we need to come with solutions not
problems so how do i think we can do
this better so come up with what i call
the inner loop and i say i come up with
it but i really didn't
i actually originally discovered this
through a client of mine um and they had
found this really cool article from a
developer at microsoft by the name of
mitch denney and his link is is up here
on the screen if you try to go there it
won't work
the site is now down but if you use the
the internet wayback machine you can go
and you know view the uh blog article
that kind of drove this whole
presentation
um but it's it's nothing new right
interloop has been around for a long
time it's been used for automotive
manufacturing software development at
microsoft project planning a whole bunch
of other places you know the only thing
innovative i've done is adapt it for
appsec
so what is the inner loop
this will probably be kind of exciting
for the developers in the room maybe a
little bit boring for everyone else so
we'll see how this goes but the inner
loop you can kind of think about it
right if you think about the developer
software development life cycle
the inner loop is everything from the
time the developers put their fingers on
the keyboard
until they push a commit to a local get
or whatever repository nowadays it's
typically get
everything that occurs after the local
git commit is considered the outer loop
so really it's the developers
local development life cycle
anything we would think of a ci cd or
kind of traditional devops is going to
fit into what we call the outer loop
so to kind of put a really ugly graphic
behind this
we kind of have these pre-loop steps
over here to the left right because
there's some things that are going to be
out of scope for this conversation
secure design patterns threat modeling
architecture reviews
training you know all of those things
that are happening outside of
development right that we would
traditionally consider shift left
activities are kind of out of scope for
this model right because at this point
we've already started uh developing but
then the actual inner loop itself
consists typically of four activities
coding building testing and committing
you can see them there in the circle on
the left then here in the middle we've
got a pull request you know to take our
code and push it to a git repository
right at that point that's where we
transition from the inner loop to the
outer loop and then that right circle is
just going you know a little more
detailed right because modern day again
it's it's not waterfall
anymore we've got a lot of developers
writing code pushing out features making
commits right so within the outer loop
it's it's really a whole lot of
different
inner loops happening all at the same
time that are pushing to that same outer
loop right because it's again where you
don't have single developers working on
a single project anymore it's a whole
lot of people committing to that code
base
and so if we kind of think of a
kind of a devops reference architecture
here and you've probably seen similar
drawings before again there's nothing
super innovative here right this is just
kind of a typical you know security
implementation or appsec implementation
within within the devops world right if
we start up there at the top left we're
hopefully we're doing this right
creating user stories epic sprints
tasker and all of our planning and jira
which hopefully security is involved in
many of your organizations probably not
then we have threat modeling and
architecture reviews
then we go into coding
and we write all of our code we do our
sprints whatever we take our code and we
push it out to source control
right this is where we get into the
outer loop so at this point we're no
longer in the inner loop
and then the reason i stress that is
because
in a lot of these other talks or your
vendors and everything that you hear
about today
security is plugged in
further down the list here right so if
we keep kind of following the arrows you
know we go to the build system right
this is our our jenkins or azure devops
whatever we might be using right it
builds our code pulls in our libraries
all that good stuff well then at that
point we have these ci cd pipelines and
that's where we take and we plug in all
of our tools we plug in our static
analysis or dynamic analysis our i asked
if we're super cool um you know qa
testing code quality all of that stuff
right and we throw all of this into our
pipeline and then a whole bunch of other
stuff happens right so
point here is
all of that today is happening in the
outer loop not the inner loop right and
all of that is impactful to your
developers build process
all right so a couple other key concepts
that we need to understand that's
critical to this model
is really tax and waste right so let's
start with the key tenets of the inner
loop
loop execution should be as fast as
possible
so if we start thinking about
traditional appsec tooling we've
our tools aren't fast
right you know anybody who has run any
of these tools before you take a static
analysis tool you run it you wait
somewhere between five minutes to two
hours maybe longer you get results if
you run a dynamic analysis tool maybe
you've waited for days to get results
the tools are not fast and they're
typically not accurate
feedback time should be minimized but
quality should be optimized right so
again things should be fast and they
should have quality results
tax should be minimum minimized and
waste should be eliminated all right so
so what's tax and waste right some of
you are probably already reading the
slide and know what they are but if we
break down these activities in the inner
loop right the coding building testing
committee right only one of these
activities
provides business value
that's coding right we're taking
features we're taking customer demand
we're converting it into code and we're
putting it into our application that is
the only one of these at these
activities that actually benefits the
business
building and testing
are necessary activities that we have to
perform as developers right we can write
code all day long but if we never
compile it it never
does anything right you know in our
compiler throws us some errors tells us
our code is broken maybe there's just
some warnings or if we're really lucky
maybe it actually compiles and then we
can run our app and see what it does
but the point is building and testing
are necessary activities that we have to
do
and they provide us feedback right you
know they tell us if our code runs maybe
sometimes even tells us if we have
vulnerabilities right but it gives us
feedback about that code that we wrote
and then we have committing over there
which is really a an essential evil it's
an activity that we still have to
perform but it's not providing us
feedback
in any way right it's not looping back
into this coding process in any way it
just lets us get our code from point a
to point b so that kind of brings us to
these concepts of of tax and waste right
so tax
are the necessary activities that we
have to do that we're not going to get
around and they take time but they
provide feedback
right and waste is just like tax except
it's
unnecessary so you know kind of key to
this inner loop model
is
reducing tax
and eliminating waste
and then we've got this big blurb down
here right conventional appsec tooling
introduces
large
amounts of tax and waste
so just like the real world right we
don't want to pay taxes
we we have to do it
but
it's a necessary evil and again you know
a lot of us nowadays are you know fairly
conscious we want to do good for the
world right we know plastic is evil and
we don't want to use plastic bottles or
plastic straws right so we want to get
rid of all that waste
so this is where i'm going to need some
participation for from everybody because
i'm going to kind of walk through some
some thought exercises here and just
talk about some different types of
common application security tooling and
just kind of think about the tax and
waste and if we think these different
types of tools
we'll work in this inner loop model
based on everything we just introduced
so static analysis right so you know
static analysis tools this is referring
you know for those of you who might not
be in appsec um you know kind of a
category of tools that
scan our source code right and then they
they go through some of them require the
source code to compile some don't but
point is it scans the source code and
then it says hey we found these
vulnerabilities some of them were lying
to you and it's really not
vulnerabilities but we think it is
within the source code and so you need
to go out and fix these because it might
be sql injection or whatever it might be
you so check marks appscan source
fortify
shift left you know a handful of the
tools that kind of qualify as static
analysis so for those of you who may be
well-versed in these tools
what do you think about static analysis
do you think static analysis is a good
inner loop tool and
why
there could be some value
of something quick that is local or
something like 7 grams or something just
start off getting some sort of entrance
or know that something could be
dangerous
all right
any other thoughts in sanic analysis
okay
anyone else
um
analysis
okay
all right so
i'm going to kind of half agree have to
disagree with all of that um
you know i think part of my my
hesitation is you know kind of to your
point right about going back to the 56k
days
it's been about 20 years since we first
developed the initial static analysis
tools and we've seen very little
improvement right appscan source and
fortify were kind of the two initial
vendors in this space and if we look at
them today compared to where they were
20 years ago they're about the same they
really don't do much more
you know i'd argue that check marks is
probably one of the the biggest
innovators in this space and like
they just don't require your code to
compile um
you know but otherwise it's kind of the
same under the hood you know to your
point about sim grip you know i do see
you know some future in tools like sim
grep you know it needs to get a bloody
yui on it so that people can actually
use it but you know at its core you know
it does have some some some potential um
but you know if we kind of relate it
back to the to the inner loop model
there's no right or wrong answers to
these right again this is just thought
exercises this is just my opinion yours
may differ and that's that's part of the
idea here right but you know i think
static analysis tools in general they
have long scan times which all of the
scan time is a tax
they all have problems with false
positives right we have to go through
they require a triage we've got to get
rid of all those false positives
hopefully before we give it back to the
developers so then just maybe they don't
ignore us
you know and all those false positives
are a waste
it takes they take a lot of expertise to
use which is another tax and then we
require scan configuration as well which
is you know another tax on on top of
that
so dynamic analysis so you know again
for the uninitiated dynamic analysis
we're talking about tools
like web inspect appscan enterprise
zap and burp to an extent our dynamic
analysis tools but basically this is
where we're taking a scanner and we're
pointing it at a running web application
you know we've got a tool that's kind of
simulating a thousand monkey hackers
you know just crawling your website
getting a good baseline and then sending
a bunch of malformed http requests back
to your site and seeing what happens
right and the whole idea being if it has
a baseline if it has a good http get
request and a response right we get a
200 back everything looks good and then
it sends say a cross-site scripting
payload and it sees a 200 come back and
also that input inside of the response
it's going to say ding ding ding
vulnerability
um so i guess the same same question
right dynamic analysis you know what do
you all think for the interlude model
good
okay
simply because
your ability to know or hope that those
all right
anyone else
okay
i think i'd largely agree with that
right so
dynamic analysis again our app has to be
deployed before we can do dynamic
analysis so that's kind of a waste um
you know dast is
by nature much more accurate than static
analysis tends to be right if we get a
result back in a dash tool it largely
tends to be a real finding so that kind
of gets you know a good thumbs up
varying scan times can range from hours
to days you know that's that's kind of a
huge tax there
i helped out an organization once that
had dash scans that were taking over a
week for a single application right
you know that's that's that's not good
um and just by nature of how the tools
work the reports can be inconsistent
from one scan to to the next so for
those of you who have used das tools you
know this may be a frustration of yours
right where you'll
you know run a scan you'll have some i
don't know 10 sql injection findings and
you won't change anything and you'll run
the scan again and you'll have five sql
injection findings but at that point you
lose all your developer trust because
they say well i can't trust the tool
because the results are inconsistent
from run to run
um
but you know the really the big problem
here is that your app has to be running
so even if we forgot about this whole
tax and waste thing the app's got to be
deployed before we can run dynamic
analysis um you know i tend to have a
lot of issues with the vendor messaging
here too because you know every vendor
now talks about how dast will plug into
the ci cd pipeline and we can
automatically scan our apps and it
sounds really really great to all the
cyber security people but what we don't
realize is that
most of us aren't at a level of devops
maturity where our apps are
automatically being deployed
as a part of our ci cd pipeline right we
still have change management and idle
and all these other things that we have
to worry about and even if we can deploy
them it's probably going to a static
host and then we're just having a static
configuration around the das tool right
you know to really do this right you
know we've got to be deploying to
ephemeral host we've got to be able to
you know dynamically set up
authentication and authorization
you know before we can really do this in
a pipeline you have a question
absolutely or maybe for those of you who
have run it in production you've maybe
broken an app before so i know i have
all right
manual pen testing right and that one's
just there because it's it's funny
um right you know manual pen testing is
never going to be in the inner loop
right and it's a you know in a perfect
world you know i would kind of love to
get away from manual pen testing with
some other things we'll talk about here
here in a minute um i think it still
tends to be a crutch and there's a lot
of things we can do to really reduce the
amount of time that we spend on pin
testing
all right software composition analysis
or open source analysis or one of a
hundred other different acronyms that
all kind of mean the same thing um so
again for for the uninitiated right this
is getting more into you know our third
party libraries and dependencies and
particularly relevant today with supply
chain security
so these tools primarily are looking at
your dependencies your libraries your
third-party code that you're pulling
down into your applications and then it
takes a look at all of those libraries
and it goes out to the internet in some
magical way and it's looking for known
vulnerabilities inside of those
libraries right so for example if you
have jquery
1.9.x or whatever
and you know it's going to see that you
have that library right it's going to
look at your your pom file if you're a
java shop using maven maybe in your mpm
build you know nougat whatever you might
be using right and then it's going to go
out it's going to look up jquery 1.9 and
it's going to say hey do we have any
cves you know for this particular
library
if so the tool will report them and tell
you that you have some cves inside of
your application
and here you know we're talking tools
like black duck
son of type nexus
white source you know a handful of
others even some free tools retire js
technically does this a loss dependency
check
what do you all think about software
composition analysis
a lot of times
which is a huge waste
okay
all right so
software composition analysis i get i
think i kind of largely agree right it's
it's good and it's bad right it's kind
of got its pros and cons i saw a very
interesting talk from jeff williams um
you know co-founder of owasp last week
um you know and he was talking about
software composition analysis and open
source code and some of the work he's
been doing and you know i think at this
point we've all seen enough
presentations right you know we've seen
you know the icebergs and i think
everybody talks now about how you know
like back in my fortran days you know we
wrote 80 percent of the code and 20 of
it was open source or whatever and how
that model is flipped right and now
twenty percent of our code we write and
eighty percent of it um is open source
libraries and dependencies um and so on
what he's done with some of the
instrumentation work that he's done like
you know with contrast and other tools
is actually try to take a look you know
like you mentioned um you know at the
code that's actually executing
and i don't remember the exact number
but you know what he found was that
on average across all of the
applications they have tested well
it was actually something like 85
percent of the applic of the code that
actually executes
is code that you wrote
right so even though 80 percent of our
code is open source and third-party
dependencies we never actually execute
it
which means it's just sitting there
doing nothing really getting false
positives from software composition
analysis tools so most organizations are
using software composition analysis in
kind of a scanning mode right you know
we throw it out in our ci cd pipeline
and you know we just have it run
or maybe we even schedule it you know to
where it runs against our apps on on
build or more of an ad hoc or a
scheduled basis right so you know we all
find out
about something exciting like you know
heartbleed or struts or something like
that you know we still don't have a
software build of materials or anything
like that hopefully y'all are working on
that because that's coming
and so then we have to go out and we
have to scan all of our applications and
figure out where that impact is right
you know one of my clients had a 15 000
applications in their application
portfolio right you know if something
like another struts issue comes along
how can you scan 15 000 applications and
figure out which ones have the
vulnerable version of struts right and
you just absolutely can't and i think
that's that's a huge tax um do you know
to your point it's difficult to
determine the actual impact you know
which i would argue is a waste right
i've built a lot of my career on helping
financial service organizations that
have a mature appsec program right if
you if you don't have a mature appsec
program and you put in something like
software composition analysis your
developers might even love you right
depending um you know if you tell them
that they have an issue they might
actually go out and fix it and swap out
that library if you have an organization
that's really mature in appsec the
developers are going to push back on
that and they're going to say
well i'm not even calling that
vulnerable code or show of hands how
many of you have ever read a cve before
most of you
do those cves usually tell you
how to reproduce a vulnerability
did they tell you where in the code that
vulnerability is
it's usually something fluffy like
there's a cross-site scripting
vulnerability in
you know this particular library from
version x to version y it doesn't tell
you where the vulnerable code is you
know and unless some super cool hacker
has has written an exploit or something
you probably have no idea where that is
so
you know a developer is not going to go
out and re-architect their application
because you told them there might be a
vulnerability in a library
um i will say
these tools are getting a lot of
innovation they're coming a long way and
i think there is ways to deploy them
well in the inner loop um you know snick
is a good example of this you know black
duck even has some lightweight features
so you know now like black duck for
example you can configure it so that if
say you're writing a java application
you go into your pom file you add a new
library it'll pop up and it'll say hey
did you know that library you're trying
to add right now has a vulnerability you
know maybe you want to use this version
instead right and so basically zero
impact to the developers we can go ahead
and let them know and let them make the
decision of whether or not to proceed
snick is doing some really cool stuff
also right so if you can configure snick
in such a way as part of your pipeline
even so that if you're trying to deploy
an application it's going through your
ci cd process and it determined it finds
a vulnerable library
snick will actually break the build
and it will actually create a pull
request
to go out and take a newer version of
that library and incorporate it into the
code base for you um now you're all in
cyber security so that probably scares
the out of you um you know which is
which is fine right you know it's
you know understandable but you know
it's what your developers need to do
anyway right and what you're going to
tell them to do if you had been the ones
to find this vulnerability so as long as
you have a good you know pull request
approval process in place that can be
incredibly valuable
so i want to talk a little bit about
securities code this is almost a
separate actually really could be a
separate talk um in and of itself right
and i think it requires a little bit of
an introduction before we kind of talk
about it as a thought exercise
so kind of before we talk about security
as code because this is kind of a
prerequisite here i want to talk about
testing vulnerabilities
versus testing controls
right so today
most of us test
for vulnerabilities
right this is how all of our tools
work it's how our pen testers work right
and security right this tends to be what
we hunt for right we find
vulnerabilities
but you know from absec perspectives
this causes a lot of problems for one we
get really really good
at finding vulnerabilities or for some
of us that have used some of these tools
we've talked about right i've run static
analysis tools that after you're done
running them
you have 60 70 80 000
vulnerabilities from one scan of one
application
right you know for those of you uh
hopefully all of you with mature
vulnerability management programs right
how do you manage 80 000 vulnerabilities
you know across your network even where
we're really good at vulnerability
management right we
would probably fail with that many
vulnerabilities
and that's just in a single lap from a
single scan right and the more we do
this the better we get at tuning our
tools we get better at pen testing and
we really just find more and more
vulnerabilities
um some of those are false positives
false negatives we don't treat
vulnerabilities as defects right we're
still giving developers you know pdf
reports and things like that we expect
them to read them
we don't treat vulnerabilities as
defects and really what we've started is
a race that we can absolutely never win
um and so what we what i think we need
to do is change our focus from
vulnerabilities to controls right and
again this is something else we've
gotten fairly good at you know with our
networks our hosts right a lot of our
security teams nowadays you know we're
thinking about you know security
controls mitigating controls um etc but
we're not doing it from an appsec
perspective
um so you know it's just important to
know from an apsec perspective you know
thinking about controls
and testing for the presence of controls
as opposed to vulnerabilities right it
enables us to you know do some really
cool stuff like have security design
patterns right i think the very first
slide i talked about making security
easy
right we don't do that well today we run
a scanner or we get a pen test the pen
tester comes back and says
hey we found this cross site request
forgery vulnerability and and you need
to fix it and the developer says okay
cool what the hell is a cross-site
request forgery uh the security person
you know probably says uh
i don't know you know here's what the
pin tester said go read their report and
and fix
it right so you know but if we give them
a design pattern you know that tells
them how to prevent cross-site scripting
and the code to put into their
application that stops it from be to
begin with
most developers are going to write their
code
with that design library already in
there right and this enables us to
eliminate entire categories of
vulnerabilities right so again if we're
hunting vulnerabilities if we do a pen
test a static analysis scan whatever
say it finds 10 sql injection
vulnerabilities
well that's just what it found
right there there could be 20 or 30 or
maybe even more right so if we're
focused on the vulnerabilities we're
only going to find and fix
some of the vulnerabilities within our
code but there's always going to be more
right but by focusing on those controls
and implementing strong controls we
could eliminate those entire categories
getting back to this inner loop thing
that also lets us do this stuff fast and
accurate right have any of you ever run
a qa test before
right it's fast
right you run a qa test is what maybe
milliseconds
right so if we can write a qa test that
will test for a security control and
have a result in
milliseconds or seconds that's accurate
and tells us if that control is there
that's incredibly valuable right and so
now that's what we're talking about with
security as code right so we we we
have to agree on a control first
once we have the control we can write
the requirements which we can turn to qa
test
and i always use the example of having
just a conversation with a csun right
because you know this is something that
happened to me once right you know cso
came to me and said hey
can you promise me that my application
does not have any cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities in it
no
right if anybody in this room can can
say yes you're you're probably a liar
right we can never guarantee right that
we don't have a vulnerability in our app
we might be able to say oh wait we've
had 10 pen tests and we found two and we
fixed them or check mark said that we
don't have any but can we really say
with confidence that there's none there
we absolutely can't
however
if we all agree as a group that's
something like
owaspa sappy will prevent cross-site
scripting in our organ in our
applications
and here is the snippet on how to
incorporate that into our apps
well now we can write a qa test for that
it's going to run in milliseconds and
check our application and tell us if
that control is present and configured
properly and so now if the cso comes
back to me and says hey josh can you
guarantee me my app doesn't have
cross-site scripting in it i still can't
say yes but i can at least say hey we've
agreed on this control that prevents
this vulnerability and here is all of
the green lights and the test results
saying that this was done properly right
so at least according to the thing that
you agreed to
yes your application is protected from
cross-site scripting
so that was a long tangent but that's
what we mean by security as code and i'm
running a little low on time so we're
going to skip the thought exercise here
a little bit
you know short version is personally i
think securities code is going to save
the day right you know this is kind of
part of the key
to enabling developers and being able to
do appsec
at agile speeds right and we can do
security as code both in the inner loop
and the outer loop and actually we kind
of have to use it in both
because you know some things like unit
and functional qa testing you know we
can do within the inner loop but you
know things like integration testing and
end-to-end testing we've got to have all
the libraries we've maybe even have to
have the app running so you know just by
the nature of those types of tests the
application you know does have to be in
the outer loop
but when done properly security is code
my opinion has immeasurable amounts of
tax and waste um and it also reduces
what we have to do with all those other
technologies right if we agree on owasp
sapi if we agree that it prevents
cross-site scripting well i don't really
need to test for that anymore right i
can configure my static analysis tools
my dynamic analysis tools that if this
qa test passed
well i don't really need to run those on
every build anymore right so i can start
tuning those scanners so that they're
less impactful when they are running
that pipeline
all right security spell checkers um
sorry security your cyber security
people in the room this is one of those
things that i think to to cyber people
sounds fantastic on paper um
right and we get really excited about
this hey you know how great would it be
if this developer was writing a
vulnerability
and we stopped them in the middle of it
and told them they were doing it wrong
it probably sounds really really great
right but
it's really not and in 100 of cases i've
seen where these tools are used they've
been actively fought or disabled by the
developers right and this really gets
down to you know just lost time right
you know there's a lot of studies out
there that show that every time you're
focused on a task such as writing code
and you're taken out of the moment
you're distracted you read an email you
check your phone whatever you lose 23
minutes of concentration right it takes
you 23 minutes to focus back on that
task so every time you interrupt the
developer from
doing their job and writing code you're
taking 23 minutes of time
out of their day that they could be
writing those business future features
so again right to security it sounds
fantastic
but to developers it's an absolute
nightmare i will say
in my opinion this is an area where we
could see a lot of innovation in the
next couple of years right we've had
some cool new things come out like
github co-pilot um you know that kind of
writes code for us you know it's still a
little iffy and does some weird stuff
but it has potential to be able to do
this and write code for us not only
write code write secure code
right you know think of gmail i can open
up gmail now and hit type in hi and then
tab tab tab tab tab and gmail will write
my email for me with pretty much the
words that i would use right that's
awesome
if we get these security tools to the
level of maturity where they can do that
they could be incredibly valuable in the
inner loop
all right so wrapping up
model for the future
so this is my i was in big four for four
years so i've got to have a slide with
as many buzzwords in it as i can
performing security inside the inner
loop drives a shift left culture that
shortens developer feedback loops to
release code at high velocity by
leveraging secure by design principles
and then we've got again in typical big
four fashion um you know just a few
slides here with a whole lot of words
that i'll publish and you can read at
your leisure but you know really the key
message here is right i would encourage
all of you you know the inner loop and
the outer loop work together i'm not
saying stop doing things the way you're
doing them today i mean i kind of am but
you know the ci cd pipelines are still
great automation is great right don't
automate things for the sake of
automating them think about the impact
but the inner loop and the outer loop
they work together they're hand in hand
and they allow us to change how we're
doing things today so that we're
enabling our developers you know rather
than punishing them right our outer loop
is is not scalable right every time we
put another tool in our pipeline it
takes more time right and right now your
development teams are severely outpacing
you
right they're trying to release code
maybe you just take them eight nine 12
months to release an app now they're
releasing them in four weeks
two weeks if you're amazon netflix maybe
eight seconds
right and if we take a tool that takes
eight hours to run and we put it in our
pipeline well you just created an eight
hour bottleneck
so
i'm getting the
sign here to stfu so we're just going to
jump to the conclusion here
so
in conclusion right
i want you to use the inner loop again
as a thought exercise just like we did
to consider the impact that you're
having on development teams so instead
of making these decisions purchasing
tools giving them to developers and then
wondering why they hate you
just consider that impact that you're
having right there is no amount there's
no right amount of tax and waste it's
going to be different for every
organization right so figure out what
works for you have the thought exercises
and adjust accordingly right continuous
improvement now also changes right it
becomes more of continuously reducing
tax and waste you're going to have a lot
of tax and waste today and that's okay
you know think about how you can reduce
that and then don't shift left simply
for the sake of shifting left right
we're doing this a lot just like don't
automate for the sake of automate right
if you take a 24 hour process and you
automate it it's still a 24 hour process
you just don't have to push the button
anymore right we got to figure out how
to make that process more effective as
well same thing with shifting left
and then
we're out of time but if you have any
questions feel free to find me happy to
talk about this more
you