[Applause]
all right good evening everybody like it
says here my name is Renier van de Leeuw
I would like to talk about Laura a
network that we're building in our
community in Temecula supposed to here
you go
so this is a picture of me installing
sensors in a in an orchard I've been
living in this in Temecula since last
year I own a small vineyard it's kind of
between commercial vineyard and and a
hobby vineyard it's it's too large to
manage by myself and too small to make
to make it my job so it's kind of like
in the middle
I started Findlay know as as a project
and I submitted it to hackaday as
Jasmine was telling and it basically was
a project started for myself how do I
manage irrigation in my vineyard and
then it turned out into an open source
project and now I'm the CEO of my own
company running that and you know thanks
to hackaday and the heck of a price I
got the seed money to get started on
that and then you see some prizes if you
want to reach out to me after the
presentation and you can get a hold of
me here's my email address and also my
phone number feel free to reach out
anytime well not not not at night of
course but so what is Laura that's
basically what I wanted to discuss about
because we started with irrigation and
the needs arose to have a wireless
technology that can transport sensor
data over a long distance and as we are
using battery-operated sensors we want
to do that in a very power efficient way
and when I got started in 2015 looking
into this I started with a handheld
reader so I had to walk around and then
connect the wires of every sensor and
take reading and just go on and on then
I thought well that's not a very
efficient way of getting getting data
from my vineyard can I do it wirelessly
I
I made a prototype with Wi-Fi but the
range of Wi-Fi was just not enough to
get to get where I wanted I got to the
first row of the vineyard and that was
about all the range I could get and then
with Laura I can I can get even further
so we get in principal about five to ten
miles range of you know and then run
over battery for more than a year which
is kind of incredible if you you think
about it anyway so this technology
allows for low energy it's low speed is
not my fight you cannot do over-the-air
firmware updates yeah you can there's
talk about it but I I don't recommend it
and it's suitable for battery operated
devices so small data packets the the
typical fair use policy is that you use
30 seconds air time per day and if you
have a typical half a second
transmission time and you can calculate
how often you can you can go online with
this technology it's a star tech start
topology so it's not that the notes talk
to one another and pass on the message
every node talks directly to the Gateway
so that's basically also the topology
and the way it works is that the Gateway
has multiple channels in the US you have
64 channels in the in Europe you have 8
channels but the the nodes can switch
channels and that means that a lot of
stations can share the same airspace so
a typical gateway can support thousands
of nodes and that means that you can use
it in a dense populated area like a
metropolitan area like LA if you want to
build a smart city that that can one
Gateway if it's placed high enough and
it has enough range it can support like
thousands and thousands of nodes so in
temecula we don't have that kind of
nodes but we like the range and it also
means that nodes interfering with each
other is not happening with this
technology we use unlicensed frequency
bands it means that you don't need a
license or anything you
it's like Wi-Fi you can transmit in
these bands with FCC approved equipment
and I don't know if you if you're a ham
radio operator or you want to know about
the modulation that is being used but
the the chip manufacturer that invented
the lower standard is SEM tech they're
based in California of course that's
where all the smart people live and and
they invented the modulation technology
that basically is allowing a three times
more range than a frequency shift keying
frequency shift keying is that you just
move the frequency of your signal a
little bit and that's how you transfer
data and they they use a chirp a chirp
and I'm trying to explain it but you
know if I'm not doing a good job just
raise your hands and as we to repeat my
story again so a chirp is a a frequency
that goes up so if I do like that's a
chirp like you go from a low frequency
to a high frequency and then what what
you can choose with this technology is
the bandwidth and and the speeds where
you change that chirp so if you want to
change or if you want to Center data
fast then of course you need to do very
fast chirps something like this so you
see that this frequency goes up real
fast but if you want to go long range
then you can do a long chirp and that
means that you get better
signal-to-noise ratio and you can carry
that that signal further but it also
means that your your air time is longer
so you need to make a decision about you
know how do you want to model to set up
your your lower system do you want to do
maximum range or do you want to do
maximum data transfer yes question
you can do anything you want you're in
Europe it's mandatory in in the u.s. if
you lose the things network as your
network provider it's a fair use policy
but it's not it's not enforced so if you
want to do well like a typical example
is if you want to to measure how far
your your your range is then what I
typically do is I set up a station to to
send the state a signal every 15 seconds
and I put it on the roof of my car and I
Drive around and I take the signal
strength while I take the GPS location
and I plot that in the cart I'm gonna
show you the results later but that is
something that I can do for now
an hour and then I used up all my 30
seconds but you know nobody's gonna flag
it like oh this guy spent more than 30
seconds but you know there will be
situations where well you get you get
penalized so there are the things
Network has free to use of community
network but companies like Senate laurio
and and short recently also Comcast they
have network services that are paid for
and then you're basically you're paying
for your data so if you're going over
your allotment then suddenly you'll see
that you know the rates go up
yeah
yeah let me let me explain you in the
next slide I was expecting this question
yeah so maybe this explains a little bit
how how the laura1 system is set up so
oh here you see notes and these notes
all communicate to a gateway which is
here so in some cases the the the
stations the nodes only can communicate
to this gateway because it's within
range in some cases like this this node
here it can communicate to to so its
signal is being received by two gateways
at the same time and the software in the
network will decide so it's not that it
will double the network data but you
know it will basically take the first
station that comes in as the dominant
one from the Gateway you go to an online
network server and the network server
basically identifies the station so the
advantage of Laura or Laura when is that
the data is encrypted so although it's
small data and sometimes you can wonder
like is the temperature in my home is
that you know worthwhile the security
measures but Laura is a two-way
communication protocol so why I want I
want I wanted the encryption and the
security of encryption because I want to
be able to operate irrigation valves so
I don't want you guys to start hacking
in my system and start messing with it
probably you could if you can decrypt
the 16 bit encryption key but it's it's
basically a basic layer of security that
that is added to it so if you if you see
how this works you need to set up a
station to connect to the network so
there's this I said over-the-air
activation protocol that's the first
time when the system comes online and it
introduces itself to the network it has
an app
Kinki which basically tells the network
I want to talk with this application and
it also has a security key which is an
encryption key which is shared between
you know the network and the station so
there's a two-way communication one one
is that they're secure communication
between this this node and the network
server and from the network server
because you have an application key
which basically points the network
server to which application server you
want to talk is that is that clear this
that make sense yeah so what what has
been the the the development of Laura so
it started a few years ago so it's not
that old this is the result of three
years of work a company in Amsterdam
started with a wireless solution to
detect water leaks in boats in Amsterdam
they have canals as you probably know
and the Dutch people I'm one of them
they like to to you know use their boat
during the summer but during the winter
it's it's not fun
so we more them and then in spring we we
find that our boats have been floated or
you know half sunk or whatever so
somebody came up with a great idea say
why don't we put water detectors in
these boats and then we use a wireless
network to to connect that to the
Internet and if you know something is
leaking in your boat you get a warning
so that was how did the things network
was born three years ago and they they
basically built ten gateways and with
the ten gateways they covered the whole
city like okay that's pretty cool
and so that that's what they started
with
ten and three years ago now they have
4,000 gateways active all over the world
and you can see the numbers here and you
can also see that it's a at this moment
Europe is is way ahead of everybody else
in it with using this technology we got
like about half of the 4,000 gateways
are in Europe
most of the of course most of the
gateways are in in in the Netherlands
but also Switzerland has a very very
dense network infrastructure already
then you see it's spreading all over the
world so we can catch up there so what
is Los Angeles looking like just you
know to give you an idea so yeah we we
can do something here there's two
communities that are active there's a
community in Marina del Rey so that's
the left one somewhere here and then
there is a community in Los Angeles so
if you want to know more about it if you
want to become involved you know there's
if you go to the things Network there's
information about where the location of
all the communities and who the main
contact is for that and you can
basically contact them and sign up or or
if you're if you think that you can do
better built or start your own community
because you can do that too so this is
the status of Los Angeles so what do you
need to get started so I bought some
stuff show-and-tell stuff yeah so this
this is a gateway I I experimented with
five different brands and this is the
one that I like best so this one has
been stable and this this is a unit that
actually is for the European frequency
so if I want to test a unit for it for a
European customer and then you can see
here I I didn't put an antenna on by the
dummy load so just for the so it's not
radiating at eight six eight which is
illegal here yeah so this is a gateway
and then a soil sensor looks like this
and the good part is I I know I'm
running out of time sorry about yeah I
know but I'm gonna run out of time
so if you talk about the the power of
open source and the open source
community this is a good example so this
this soil moisture sensor has been in
the market for about 30 years and I
checked that that company and I asked
them if they would be willing to share
with me the the calibration data of this
this unit and they said no no that's
that's our IP we cannot share that we
build our own equipment I said yeah but
I'm making an open source system and I
would like to use your sensors so no way
and I I tried a couple of times and you
know didn't get anywhere yeah I could
sign an NDA but that would basically
defy the whole purpose of being open
source so last week they they finally
made the calibration data public domain
which is good so we as a community we
put a lot of pressure on these guys
saying hey we can we can do the the
technology better than you you're good
at at sensors and we we acknowledge that
because we are interested in the sensors
but you know your your technology your
wireless and your stuff yeah there's a
there's a whole community out there that
can do a better job than you
so yeah they caved in so that's good so
these sensors connect to a station like
this so this is a little solar panel
that we use to charge the battery and
you can probably see here that there's a
little battery here and you see a little
module with an antenna so this this is
it guys that that's all so with this you
can get like 10 miles
yeah I I'll be happy to pass it along if
people want to see it or if you can come
after after the presentation I'll be
happy to show you but this is a this is
the radio module that you see here and
and what I wanted to show is that when I
started with Laura I was initially
pretty much overwhelmed with all the
data that I got like I asked a supplier
of Laura module 4 for data and they sent
me like this Big C library and it was
like kilobytes and kilobytes and said
what do what the heck do I need that for
it's like too much for me I'm not a good
programmer so I I admit it I mean if you
send me 10 pages of C code I'm gonna be
overwhelmed that I just don't know where
to start yeah at the top of course but
so so with this actually this is the
whole setup for the things network and
so it's basically serial data that
you've sent to the module and you send
80 commands so it's basically a cup of
print print commands you send data to
that to that unit and you configure it
for the type of join modes the duty
cycle and then the frequencies you
wanted to work on remember I mentioned
that Europe has eight frequencies for
Laura
the US has 64 and a gateway can support
eight so if you use the sings network
you need to pick eight eight channels
from the 64 and ideally you need to
figure out which ones the things network
is using so you are on the same
frequency as the network I found that
out the hard way to be honest so you
know I couldn't get my system to connect
I could get connect to other suppliers
other network providers I could not
connect to the things network and I did
I tore my head my hairs out and then it
turned out to be like a very simple
basic thing like I was transmitting at
the wrong frequency so who can come up
with that what kind of standard is that
well I found it out and hopefully you
know by sharing this you you won't have
to go through
again any questions so far yes sir yeah
yes yeah is that is it yeah is it yes
yeah you can build a private network as
well if you want that yes yeah and when
you think about the way it's been set up
you can now also implement your own
network server so one of the cool things
of the things network is that the code
of their network servers is also public
domain so if you want to copy that and
build your own network server you can so
in that sense it's pretty cool but you
know there's only so many things you can
do yeah in terms of signal yeah well
it's it's kind of it's kind of hard to
say because it's various country back
country like Mexico for example uses the
same frequencies as the US Australia
uses 925 makers and the Europe uses 868
megahertz so you need to look at you
know that the things the things network
but also the Laura standard organization
has a country-by-country a frequency
list and I need to warn you that if you
buy a gateway you need to order it for a
specific frequency range so this Gateway
for example is operating at the European
frequencies only I cannot use it in the
US because it's just limited in
frequency is that answering your
question yeah
yeah and noise is so far I haven't had
problems with noise I have problems with
hills and if there's if there's a hill
in between then it of course the signal
so you need really line-of-sight a free
free free line-of-sight yeah
okay so I'll up if you don't mind I'll
finish unless you have an urgent
question no okay thanks yeah so this is
this is you know a reading I took from
in Temecula so what you what you see
here is to see if I can get the laser to
work yes so this is one gateway here's
another here's another so we got a
couple of them and there are some
gateways here but I'm I haven't met them
yet but what you can see is when I Drive
around in the Temecula area there's
there's Hills but there's also this
there's road over here which is the main
road in Temecula wine country all the
major wineries are there and you see
that we have near continuous coverage
there so anywhere I place a gateway or a
station in any of these areas it's all
connect to any of these these gateways
and and often it will connect to
multiple of them so if one gateway you
know loses loses power or anything you
know the others take over so overlapping
coverage is actually a good thing here
the the the gateways with the best range
the gateways with the best range
actually have an external antenna on the
roof so if you use the internal antenna
that comes with the little rubber
antenna that comes with that that
gateway and use it indoors you can get a
mile because you know just just the
house attenuates the signal if you
really want to get good range you need
to be on the roof with an external
antenna and keep the antenna cable short
because at 900 megahertz you know a
cable attenuates as well so you want to
keep it short so what I typically do is
put the Gateway in a water water tight
enclosure on the roof as well and then
with power over ethernet power it and
and get the signal in so use-case
agriculture of course in my case there's
other use cases that you can think of
but this is what what I use so we have a
sensor stations in a vineyard and they
measure temperature they measure soil
moisture using the sensors that I just
showed and they sent that data to a
gateway over here so from the Gateway
you need to go to an internet router I
use Wi-Fi or Internet and from the
internet router you get on the internet
and there's a cloud-based application so
we work with a partner in Europe that
made a specific applications for
vineyards but now also for orchards and
from that application you can you can
look at your data and you can decide
depending on the soil moisture status
and the weather data how long you want
to irrigate every day so the computer
basically uses Laura when also to
wirelessly activate irrigation valves
so this is an example of an orchard that
we where we installed systems in in
Bakersfield and it was we install it mid
mid April this year so it's a 13 acre
it's a 13 acre orchard the 23rd leaf is
farmer speak for telling you that the
for the trees are 22 years old so you
know don't get don't get impressed by
that and then the the spacing is such
that you get 308 trees per acre so
depending on the season and how hot the
weather is each tree takes about twenty
to sixty five gallons sometimes even
more water per day so you can imagine
that you know a vineyard like that or an
orchard like that takes a lot of water
and when we install this we noticed that
the moisture in the soil was actually
pretty high so you know to explain this
scale the zero is wet and the higher the
number the drier it is so typically you
don't want to be higher than sixty and
you cannot be wetter than wet
you cannot go negative on on this scale
yeah so what you see here is we
installed it and we said hey this looks
pretty wet and then the farmer said yeah
but I still need to do the the
fertigation which is applying fertilizer
to the trees using the irrigation system
so you see a little dip here and that
means that the soil is actually getting
wetter it was already wet but it was
even get made worse because the farmer
and you can see that same dip here the
farmer needed to apply fertilizer and
that's the pre bloom fertilizer as they
call it and it's a mix of all kind of
stuff and they never tell what it is
because it's their secret for growing
growing pistachios but after that we
which I was still wet what do we do now
so we we got in touch with
you see a n R which is the agricultural
natural resources group within the UC
system and they have irrigation experts
that help farmers so we asked them what
do we do with this and he said well you
know stop irrigating and then wait till
the the sensor at two feet hits 60 so
okay we waited we waited with so we
waited a month so that that that is the
equivalent of eight eight Olympic
swimming pools and water and just on the
13 acre yeah question sir okay that's a
good question so in the in vineyards
they typically used rippers like dripper
hoses that you punch in a drippers with
these these trees they use a little
sprayer so they spray like 3/4 of a
radius and they spray in the area where
the root system is so the roots are
pretty shallow and they use a two
drippers of six gallons per hour so per
hour they basically irrigate 12 12
gallons so you can imagine if you want
to irrigate 65 gallons that's you know
you need to irrigate a long time is it
answering your question okay
so with that this is this is basically
by now you know second nearly the last
slide so it's a free network it's free
to use and I encourage everybody to if
you are within range of such a network
use it because it's free and it's it's
fun to work with it if you if you don't
have a network you know please consider
if that's you know within what you want
to do consider you know putting up a
gateway and shared with with everybody
in your neighborhood start a community
start developing you know other
applications a lot of applications are
things that you know require long
distance so it's different than Wi-Fi is
different than Bluetooth of course it
has its own typical application but you
can imagine like there was there was an
application where they have mousetraps
so you know they use this technology to
see if you caught a mouse so you don't
and and for some companies that do like
a test control that's actually a time
saver because they don't need to run all
these traps or check these these traps
in the building they just you know look
on the on the internet whether they need
to check on them trap and then you know
I talked about the boats you know a
water detection irrigation of course but
there are so much more and that's the
part of you know an open open source
community you know together we can come
up with applications that you know
nobody thought of before so there are
two communities here in the area one in
Marina del Rey one in LA you're free to
start your own community the things
network will support you
there's also another thing there was a
big conference in Amsterdam for the
first time and it was a huge success
they held that conference in Amsterdam
in February and although I'm Dutch and I
like to visit my family February is not
a good time of year to visit and it's
cold it's nasty and I I I didn't like it
and by the way it was my birthday and I
had to celebrate in Amsterdam who could
think of something worse
but they they basically floated this
idea of having the conference on tour
but this is a major commitment so you
know unless unless a lot of people want
to chip in and join I think it's a good
idea to think about can we do with
things conference in LA or Southern
California just to get you know things
started here they will support it but it
takes a lot of commitment and a lot of
effort to make a professional conference
so I'll put a question mark here but you
know if you want to be personally
involved there's communities there's a
lot of open source software and I saw
this this on Amazon last week which was
kind of cool this is a device that has a
a micro controller it has bluetooth it
has Wi-Fi it has Laura and it has a
little display and it's 26 bucks and and
and there were people that already said
that yeah we you know they gave it five
stars like we could connect to the
things network how cool can that be so
you know it's easy to get started as
long as you have a gateway and you know
this is just to finish it off this is
just a picture that I took of one of the
gateways that we installed on the roof
so you see that the antenna is really
tiny and you know this is the box where
you put that gateway in so it's it's
protected from the weather in the Sun so
with that I I want to show you a one
last slide and this is just useful links
so if you want to know more look at the
links first you know read the manual and
then call me if you have more questions
all right we have time for questions
yeah yes sir
yes it's a very good question so Laura
is the modulation is the the lower layer
of the protocol if you use that then you
can get a point-to-point connection
where you make a wireless UART so you
put data in one module and you get data
out of the other module the same data so
it's like a cable but then without wires
so that's Laura when our Laura land and
then Laura when users like the the
encryption and you knew you need to use
the server's so it's more complicated so
if you want to start developing using a
wireless technology it's actually easier
to start with Laura land because you
don't have all the complexity of logging
into the network and applying for for an
account so it's easier but if you really
want to go to the next level and I've
gone through that process you know I
want to control I want to control valves
I want to be able to control have
multiple stations work at the same time
and with Laurel and I found that if two
stations are transmitting at the same
time they interfere with each other and
Laura when has taken care of it I was
thinking like should I find it should I
reinvent the wheel well there is a
standard that already takes care of it
so that's that's
oh yeah so that yes so the the reason
why I asked what would the difference
between Laura and Laura one yeah was
because I actually have a customer
that's interested in using the Laura
technology but I couldn't understand the
difference between using Laura which i
think is what they want because they
want point-to-point communication yeah
versus having the higher level protocol
for actually establishing a network
which is I think what makes it nice but
that's a different standard yes is more
of a to support multiple endpoints
correct okay thank you
there was a question oh yeah let me okay
a little easier so everybody came here
here in Southern California grass fires
are kind of like water and boats in
Amsterdam you know it happens all the
time I'd like to know about it when it
happens if anybody in the room is
interested in talking a little bit about
using this technology with horizon
scanners which I build such that if you
get one which has a saturated infrared
signal you know the direction and you
know the intensity and then you trip it
up come and see me thank you
yeah there was actually a lot of use for
that I yeah you know I noticed that this
year especially in Temecula and that
area you know we had a couple of
wildfires and I've seen the the planes
fly over my home and so yeah it's
getting closer to close to comfort to be
honest yeah so I I appreciate the
initiative thank you another question
okay yeah
I'm wondering about the liquid sensors
basically to use battery power for more
you figure out a way to power them with
some local power supply I only use
battery power at the moment okay and the
way the way I achieved it because if you
use a an Arduino out-of-the-box it takes
like 19 milliamps at 5 volt and then I
use the Arduino Pro Mini which is using
8 8 milliamps so I found a sketch call
from our library from a company called
rocket screen rocket screen so it allows
you to bring the whole system down to a
very minimum power state it doesn't
operate but you can wake it up with an
interrupt pin or on a timer and it
basically reduces the the currents
dramatically you need to remove the LED
though because the LED takes about 1
million but we got we got now without
any other modifications and the rocker
screen we got from 8 milliamps to point
5 point 6 milliamps and then if we
remove some LG O's and other stuff we
get to 60 microns so
I use two types of batteries so in this
case I use a rechargeable lithium ion
battery which is 900 milliamps hour and
then in the case of using a battery only
we use a nine thousand milliamp hour
lithium battery which is a a Type B form
factor there are about eight dollars and
they can run at 60 million a 60 my crams
you can run for ten years that's pretty
good yeah well the thing is like that's
the theory right like I hope that that
battery provides that bed that capacity
over ten years but that's you know what
it says according to the specs so yeah
well talk we'll come back in ten years
and not you any other questions
alright so for you feel free to welcome
a free thrill to see me after the
presentation or if you have questions or
send me an email call me whatever thank
you thank you so much
[Applause]