hey hello uh welcome to the can you
detect this inside the ransomware
operators toolkit
so my name is pete i'm part of the dfir
report team of analysts
so
we make up a team of about eight or nine
um we're global based and
we all do this in our own time so we're
volunteer analysts and we've all got
skills in doing intrusion analysis and
some of us are
specialist skills in
malware reverse engineering
memory forensic analysis and so on
but foundation level
we all have a core set of skills being
able to
work with intelligence do triage
investigations um work with the data and
exploit that
so i've been contributing to the dfir
report cases
so providing the endless insight for
quite a while now um most of our cases
are ransomware intrusions
and
and we report on methods of detection um
i specialize in brett hunting
detection engineering
so
this presentation uh the focus is on the
review of the common tools and
techniques of 2021 so we published a
report on our website earlier on this
year
where
from the analysis of a lot of the
cases
we've reported the common techniques
that the ransomware that groups use and
the types of uh tools um um procedures
that they follow
um so we've collated that into like a
trend analysis charts
so in the presentation we'll also be
covering the attack objectives and how
this fits in with the attack life cycle
and then we'll be mapping typical um
attack on how to
leverage the detection so where do we
need to detect in order to
prevent
the ransomware threat operator from
progression
and then
we're going to focus on more on the
human side because ultimately
they are
uh human operative ransomware
groups there is a human being behind
this uh it's not automatic it's not just
code that fires and then you just get
run somewhere there is a human operator
what is using tools uh deciding when not
to use tools
and then making decisions uh where they
go through the intrusion
and then finally
some useful resources
for defenders
there's a lot of material out there
so what can we do to prevent detect and
respond to ransomware intrusion
so
just a bit of a background on the dfir
report so our aim is to find cyber
intelligence
that is actionable and tells a story of
an intrusion
using mitre
tactic techniques and procedures
so
like i said before we deal with a lot of
different types of intrusion cases
so from nation state sponsored apts um
through to organize crime groups
for a bulk of our cases is predominantly
ransomware um for actors
so
as a reader uh looking at this
information uh in the report you should
be able to understand what the attacker
did
and how they accomplish their goals and
importantly how to defend i.t systems
so it's not all about just providing
iocs as the malware hashes etip address
that they use it's all about
the techniques that they leverage so
um forgetting the ips um the hashes
um for those familiar with the pyramid
of pain
the the easy stuff to report and uh
report on is
the atomic indicators uh such as i'd be
addressing what's really tough is the
top level which is the tradecraft that
the
actually uses so that's what we're
aiming for um so
uh
so all our reports are free they're
available on the website uh we've been
reckoned by the us cert um various other
organizations as well so the aim is to
provide concise uh detailed um
indicators and
uh
indicator
activities and so on that that's doing
so
before i do a deep dive into
uh the content um just a recap on opsec
so
so we just have to be a bit careful um
so we provide cyber intelligence so the
moment is out in the community
both good and bad guys can utilize that
so
so we we do know that our intelligence
has been used by
attackers um they have been used by
ransomware groups um so for example in
the conti leagues county is a ransomware
group
they were breached uh end of last year
early this year
where an insider effectively leaked all
their tradecraft or their internal chat
discussions and so on
and there were
references to our reports in there
they were using our report to track
rival
ransomware groups
and
yeah so that's quite interesting but it
just goes to show
um we knew that would happen um so
anything else pushed out of there
so we have to strike a balance between
providing natural intelligence to the
community
but at the same time
not to disclose our source i.e where the
intrusion happened and
the methods
and the
which methods in terms of like detection
instant response and so on
because they could have made that
and that could potentially jeopardize
future cases
so for all of this we follow the traffic
light protocol um to protect our data so
any
um identifiable data relating to the
case itself which is like the
environment such as the uh the ip
addresses host names
specific user accounts that kind of
detail we will secure that in the report
so you'll see in screenshots
where they are redacted blacked out
effectively
there is no impact in terms of the
threat intelligence because like i said
before it's all about the activities the
tools that they use to move around the
network to achieve their goals so
knowing the um
the compromise environment is irrelevant
to the third intelligence
so the the brief
um
this presentation brief is tlp white so
it can be released uh there's nothing
sensitive in there um
so anything watch tlp red
we treat internally within our team
so
in order to provide reports we have to
work with data so these are the four
principal types of data that we work
with
um so
so that all these are artifacts that we
collect from the endpoints on the
network
um we don't do any hackback or probe any
attacker infrastructure anything like
that
so
the four artifacts are memory files
networking logs
so these are the core ingredients so to
speak
our main source is blocks
because they are smaller inside
um they typically track uh the whole
intrusion from beginning to end and the
the log sources come vary from
everything from av logs to actual host
logs themselves such as like
authentication logs and it could include
a web blogs around even edr logs and so
on so it's quite a wide range
collecting processing and storing that
is cheap
so
so that's our principal data source that
we work with
and the the other useful data source
that we have is network base so
so we're looking at
data on the wire so packet capture
is fundamentally the raw data type
these are
larger in file size
but we can use this because this if you
capture the packet capture you can pull
out a lot of useful information such as
um
to see to activity uh user agent strings
obviously a
domain supports and even
data
uh binary data that has gone across the
wire so like downloaded files and um
even like certificates so there's quite
a lot of data that
we could never get in the logs um the
challenge we have with the network is
just making sure having the right
collector deployed on the right part of
the network
um the the other one is uh files so
we
usually focus our file collection on
drop files so we're not going to pull
all the files relating to
the windows directory uh so we're
looking for anything that's being
tampered anything else in the use of
folders things like that
and
again that that can vary and depending
on the hosts and so on so it's quite
important to your collections for doing
uh that collection
the lastly is memory so this is the
largest file size um so that is driven
by a host
um so if you've got a host eyes um that
has a large rum um
memory coupon um doing a minimum dump on
that could be quite um expensive
there are challenges around that um so
the memory itself can be like a snapshot
in time so you really do need to capture
um when you know that there's malware on
there
um
well if you get the right memory capture
you can't really exclude it by pulling
out the malware understanding or
configuring their processes and
correlating that back to the lock
sources
so it is quite rich well that is very
detailed really adept it's only on one
house so you don't forget you've got
multiple hosts on the network so
you need to really think about
how do i do this at scale and do a do i
really want to do and when we jump to
every single house or just focus on
particular ones of interest so they're
the kind of data that we work with
so
we structure the report in a way that
provides a timeline of the intrusion
so
that's the best way where it articulates
uh the beginning to end what the
attacker did on one day to the next day
if there are any gaps
then we document each stage of the
intrusion bar the technique so we tried
to use a mighty attack because it's a
very good way of
um
it's a common language everyone
is broadly familiar with might attack
techniques
so
so we tried to call it against her
and then we also provide screenshots as
well um where we come in the reports
and in the case of ransomware attacks
uh there's a lot of emphasis in other
cyberpunk intelligence providing ioc on
the the encrypted bit which is right at
the end
so we don't just focus on that we focus
on the whole chain so what tools do they
use quiet uh deploying the encrypter
and we also took cover about how they
established the sport how did they get
onto the network and so on
and
so we try to focus on indicator
activities but we do provide the iocs um
as well um but we do try and make a
strong point on activities
so
in most of our cases uh the
initial access
starts with official email and most not
all but in most
so here's some example screenshots that
we've got from
some cases
and
yeah and then ultimately it ends in a
ransomware notebook
dropped on a desktop or presented on the
screen
but it doesn't happen by magic it's not
like an email comes in an attachment
someone clicks on it and boom the whole
network's encrypted
there is a
chain of events um and there's it's
quite it can get quite complicated on
the depending on the scale of the
network
so
there's activities about
okay once the user's clicked on
somewhere uh how do they maintain the
footload and then from there how do they
discover other assets of interest and
then how do they move around the network
where do they find those critical files
and then at one point at what point did
they exploit and then how do they
encrypt it and so on so
the initial access to ransom
uh the shortage we've seen is about two
hours um more complex cases it's been
weeks so again it does vary um and i
think part of it it does depend on the
size of the network um and how easy it
is to get to those critical files to
encrypt them so
so let's start off with the initial
access so this is the um
the email
so
a lot of the the malware variants that
come through are
uh tend to be like ice id reserved trick
part
so they come through uh mousepam
campaigns
um so
that is fairly sophisticated malware
they've been operating for a number of
years
um
the the malware variants are actually
developed
it's designed to evade security tooling
and they've been successful
and they're continuing to do that they
do go through phases
where there'll be takedowns of networks
and then they're rebuild and
launch again
so the malware variants typically tend
to be um
an email with
embedded documents or macro based
documents that kind of thing
um
in the last few months
we've seen
characters using iso images
so effectively these are like containers
and then there there are
an initial payload embedded in there
and that's designed to avoid the mark of
the web
so that is designed um to bypass content
uh build to him and endpoint security to
them
so
in one case the iso image contained a
legitimate looking shortcut file link
and in there there is a
malicious dll
so
when the user clicks the uh the link
file the dll gets executed
for example by run dll32 and then the
bizarre load of infection chain is
initiated
so quite simple uh it can be quite
complex it just requires uh the user
clicking um following instructions an
email but a well-crafted email
targeted an unsuspecting user who's
either expecting a similar email or just
not educated
it does happen um and they've been very
effective at that
so after again in the initial put out um
we've seen tripod
serving as access brokers
for various ransomware groups
so the biggest one is county
so
last september um
like i say it wasn't just emails we saw
an intrusion what came via a proxy shell
on microsoft exchange
so this is the only case that we've
really seen where vulnerability was
exploited
so
at the time
proxy shell
um was quite easy to access quite high
severity
publication so it just had the right
ingredients to
uh exploit and there was proof of code
concept code released
so it's quite easy for the threat group
to pick that up weaponize them and
incorporate it as part of their
techniques
so
accessing vulnerabilities um
is quite hard
so they tried to go for vulnerabilities
that are quite um that could impact a
number of different types of
organizations so exchange is a popular
vector
so
so from a detection point of view from
documents
we can look for office applications that
are spawning unusual chair processes
such as living upper land binaries
such as red surface 32 run dll and even
direct calls to command.exe
so
the business email compromise is still a
call for the attacker it's still active
it's still happening now
so
it's designed to bypass
the endpoint security tool and it's a
kind of mouse game though uh constantly
evolve and you've seen recent
vulnerabilities in the last month or so
certainly new features being exploited
in uh microsoft office um it's just
never ending so in this example we can
see quite a complex precious execution
tree uh where document has multiple
different payloads and ways of execution
so it's multi-stage
so it's it's been in the process and
then reaching out uh downloading the
files spinning up another process
calling
an
html application and then i took it
something out so very complex
and then this one the dll is much graded
as a jpeg
so
so despite attempts to evade a lot of
the security tooling and so on
looking at that you can say that's not
normal um so if you've got that
telemetry being collected you should be
able to see that and it is unusual
um
so
looking for unexpected process
interactions files being dropped into
non-standard locations such as temp
coders especially dlls and so on they're
really obvious kind of indicators
so the next step is okay they've got
access
is maintaining a photo on that endpoint
so it's still fairly fragile the process
could crash terminate and they've lost
access again it would require the user
clicking on it again
so
so they the factors will employ several
techniques to maintain that photo so
common ones are what we saw in 50 of our
cases
is creation of scheduled tasks so this
is effectively like a back door
so
another popular technique that attackers
perform is the creation of new users on
the the endpoint and then adding users
to local admins or remote desktops users
as well so
it doesn't depend on that user account
so if the user logs out they've got
always a means of getting back into them
uh in another case we saw a pitch job
being created
um
and i was calling a malicious dll uh
every three hours
for the length of the intrusion so
various different ways of maintaining uh
persistence
um they
also
um what we have seen there is deploy the
likes of teamviewer any desk top
artillery agent so these are legitimate
remote access tools
and so if an organization is using that
that could appear legitimate
and again there's always a risk that if
they've used their initial access to
game and it is malware it could get
detected at some point by an av and
they're just bearing access so having a
legitimate meaning to stay on there
again that's another technique
so
if you understand your baseline
so if you know you don't use those tools
um and then you start seeing the network
traffic to splashtop servers again
that's definitely worth investigating if
it starts here and tools being dropped
and installed on those endpoint with
remote access capabilities that should
be a red flag and certainly something
where it should be locked down
and
the
then the obvious ones are one key
registry so very easy to do so if um add
a new one key so if you use it just log
out log back in there just stop again
and
in the likes of proxy show vulnerability
um
that was slightly different and they
ended up dropping a lot of web shelves
um to maintain access on there again
they were very conscious that they were
using a properly available
exploit that could be detected and
removed or if they change the
configuration add in a backdoor web
shell
um that's a good way to hide their
access
um
the
the next stage okay they got initial
access they've established photo so
they're in a good position um they know
they've got
remote access to that machine though so
but they're still uh
nowhere near to
uh run somewhere in the environment so
in order to
deliver their pets uh they need to
understand that environment so
they ideally what they're aiming for is
to escalate their privileges because the
chances are the user account they
compromise is probably just a general
enterprise user um probably didn't have
much access um apart from accessing a
few file shares
and other resources so they really need
to get higher level privileges so
in virtual cases that we've come across
they've always deployed a couple slide
beacon
um
that is very common
as part of their tradecraft
and they use the built-in function
the technical name namepipe
impersonation also known as getsystem
and
so they use our as a service to
effectively get system level privileges
there's a great article on red canary
titled hunting for get system in
offensive security tools so they go
through a lot of detail about how that
punching works
methods of detection
one of our fellow analysts um he's
created a series of uh blogs um
called strike defenders guide and it's
available on the website as well so
there's a lot of detection indicators to
work through from there
and we've also seen um
powershell
which bypasses usc um so again i mean to
getting into our integrity
so once they got that system level
they really want to be moving around the
network and they can start targeting the
lsas process so that is a privileged
process
that does a lot of the interactions and
authentication to a lot of the host
um resources and other resources on the
network
and
in a mo in the majority of the cases um
the primary mechanism for interacting
with that
is via cobblestrike beacons
so
other methods um quite simple but
effective uh dumping of the outside
process um so they're effectively take a
memory dump
and then
they'll use things like system terminals
produm again legitimate tool developed
by microsoft
um it's primarily used for debugging
applications and so on there's dumping
process memory
even using task manager if you've got
that level of privilege uh another
fairly infamous one is mimikat so
that should be fairly rare and it's
that should trigger a lot of antivirus
alerts so if you do see that morning on
the endpoints and when we cut two
yeah i always pay attention to that
it's primarily used by pentesters red
teamers
it could be used internally for testing
security tools
and controls but if you do see um and if
you're not seeing that then i'll be
really concerned about the av
so
not so common is dumping the the
registry hives
especially the same security and system
so
so while performing all of these because
they are
doing fairly dangerous
activities now
accessing credential resources and a lot
of the tool and should detect that
um but they're what they would do prior
to that so they will take certain
measures to avoid getting caught
and one of those is discovering the
installed antivirus
um disabling those so
some of the common techniques are making
registered keys and a gpo and disabling
defender for example
so we see that quite a lot
and there are some other tools out there
such as defender control which where you
can disable like uh cloud submission and
all that kind of thing
so again look for that if you've got
visibility the avs and all of a sudden
you've got endpoints that aren't
updating or communicating to you then
it's definitely worth investigating
um the the other technique is uh process
injection so where
they spawn the process but what they
need to do really is hype up beacon and
i'll migrate into another process
which is legitimate
so again it's all about evasion
so
just expanding a bit more on
discovery they spend a lot of time doing
discovery so they perform a number of
discovery commands
and they'll do that frequently so they
won't just do it once on the endpoint
they'll be doing it across multiple
endpoints and the discoveries can vary
from doing
uh looking at security tools
determining what users locked in
what files are installed and trying to
find credentials and so on so it's
continuous um some of the common tools
we see living off the land built in
windows features is net.exe and lts for
network discovery they want to see if
that endpoint is connected to any other
endpoints
so you see them running really quick
succession
it's pretty unusual um you may see
admin scripts doing that as part of a
configuration
testing but it's a normal environment
should if you start seeing
dozens and dozens of probing activity
that should be a red flag
and
the other on the graph
there's a lot of different windows
commands that they use across all the
intrusions
but
they also bring in a lot of other tools
onto the environment as well
and so
two of the common tools that we see
repeatedly across our cases
one is advined and another one is
bloodhound so both of those are used for
active directory enumeration
um again quite quite noisy um bloodhound
as a bar as a binary the collectable it
should get detected by avs and so on
tools like adfine may not get detected
by avs because it is a legitimate
system admin tool
other types of tools they use for
program are post gunning tools um a
common one is advanced ip scanner we see
that quite a lot
just being dropped and effectively
almost like end mapped across the uh the
network and other ones like kp uh port
scan
in the uh the proxy show and the the
exchange um
we saw
command that's been exploited um such as
get inbox rule get mailbox those kind of
things again very unusual
it's not someone you see all the time
and
so
once they get into the end point they
really need to stop pivoting to get to
domain controllers file shares things
like that so um backup service as well
so for lateral movement uh they spend a
lot of time deploying other beacons
across the network
um so and they will use that
the primary commons is um smb
so they spend a lot of time building
their infrastructure internally um
so and they're data tuning them all
together
and they're also deployed remote access
on certain endpoints as well such as any
desk and so on um so not everything is
just going to be done through that
initial access point they'll try to
um
like spread the load a little bit
other popular tool for lateral movement
is resistant turn off ps exec again
um system admin tool which is very
commonly used in an environment
system administrators use it for
troubleshooting
so just look for unusual use of that and
if it's coming from end points that you
don't normally see have been executed
from that's worth having to look at
uh
other types of remote execution um is
using wmi where they're interact
directly with the host and execute
commands
so once they've
done the initial access established
photos
done the lateral movement they've done
the discovery
um they'll start doing exfiltration and
they may do some exfiltration throughout
the intrusion
so some of the things they do
there's established station service
where they've dumped our data and the
data
might be a user's folder which is quite
hidden away and then
just like what we do when we're sending
emails they'll compress their data to
make it smaller so there are multiple
files and artifacts to work with um and
then they will
upload them
in terms of data artifacts they've also
tried to dump sql databases so it's not
all about just
files or process dumps and things like
that
um it can be any anything else on there
such as configuration database servers
um
in terms of exfiltration there was a
trend at one point
or using the uh the mega storage service
i know using
um our clone quite a lot um it's
effectively a file transfer utility and
they would just upload all the data
pretty easy spot in the um
in network logs um
the other types of utilities uh include
one scp
filezilla again
common utilities that you'd like expect
to see on the network
uh
in one of the intrusions um
a really interesting one when they
dumped the uh the osas process
um they actually just opened the web
browser and just uploaded it to u
file.io so
really simple um it worked
um so we can monitor network connections
um you can kind of see what they're
doing where data is going and so on what
processes are firing on
ips and so on so um so yeah if you've
got that capability look for those
because you shouldn't be seeing that
kind of exfiltration
and
lastly we've also seen coco strike being
used
so that's got an internal capability for
uh doing downloads and uploads so they
can just exfiltrate it out the way they
came
uh so the final objective for the tier
uh factor is the actual ransomware
deployment
um so
this involves several things
encrypting the data
uh wiping the file so that you can't
recover it and then deploying a ransom
note
in
one case that we saw
so a lot of them tend to be custom
malware and they would encrypt in one
case we saw a bit locker being used
so you can see it's a complex chain and
there's a chart here
and it's not just an email and once you
know
there are a lot of tools and techniques
being leveraged
um but one of the things it the big
challenge is where do you invest your
detections because ideally you want to
detect it earlier or prevented
but if you try to detect it at the end i
ran some notes or the ransomware it's
too late you're not gonna have a chance
to respond from now
so
trying to understand where we need to
invest what techniques do we see used
quite a lot um and what are some of the
quick wins so
understanding at the procedure level uh
we need to understand why the attacker
is doing that why are they using that
command why are they doing it that way
and when are they doing that as part of
the attack life cycle
so using the mundian
attack lifecycle we can start to map
the observed procedures that we see in
the intrusions and then start
classifying them
and then from this we can start to build
an understanding of how frequent those
procedures are
where they've been leveraged what kind
of telemetry data sources you can do and
then start building up
opportunities for detection
so it's
evident from doing that analysis that
most of the procedures
are associated with maintaining
persistence and internal weak on stages
so to maintain persistence are
creating scheduled tasks
establishing that photo to cross all the
end points and they spend a lot of time
building that infrastructure so and they
want to maintain that because that's
their means of delivering that effect
the other one is internal recon when
they're moving around discovering
credentials powers of interest and so on
they do a lot of discovery
the the actual exploitation document
coming in
it could be quite difficult to detect if
it's a vulnerability that they're
exploiting you're not going you might
not even know what you're looking for
you may be able to
identify unusual things like certain
processes being called and so on
um
so but what we do know
it's not linear it's not
email
do this do that read out and run some
there is a big recursive loop in the
middle
and
so
still like the internal stuff like i
said they're
continually reviewed all the time and
got the persistence as well so they need
to make sure that the beacons are in
place
so the attack life cycle so this is
based on a 19 day period so the biggest
challenge is detecting a malicious
activity early on and then
before it's too late
so you can see at the start of intrusion
we can see a cluster of activity where
they seem to do a lot of techniques so
they're
trying to maintain access doing a bit of
internal week on on that endpoint
finding out what it's connected to
making some configuration changes um
establishing the backdoors access and so
on and then it appears that there's a
quieter period um and then i do more
internal recon discovering more
endpoints um they'll move laterally and
they'll keep repeating now um it's all
building
back doors again on other endpoints
they will service more footballed
elsewhere on the network
um carry on with more internal recon so
they're very deeper and deeper in the
network and then on the very last day
they would deliver that effect
so
the question is why do we see a lot of
the internal recon again
so
the main reason for that is when they
deliver effect they need to make sure
that i was being delivered i had to run
somewhere actually worked so i've seen
where they delivered the payload and
it's not worked they've made changes and
they've done checks check and see if the
files have actually encrypted so that's
a discovery technique
and and it's also worth noting that um
for
ransomware
um for actually maintaining
presence
so if i install like any desk or
splashtop
you don't just get an indicator when
it's been installed in process running
there will be a continuous network
connection to splashtop services to
allow me
an indicator that there's a strong c2
activity
um
yeah and then when we start to put all
these procedures in the context of an
intrusion because we see in multiple
cases of these we start to see a pattern
and it's quite clear they're following a
playbook
so
the country leak confirmed the existence
of very detailed playbooks and training
material
so
playbooks have several advantages so
they provide a baseline of common
scripts and tools
and ensures ensures consistent ways of
working
so when they've got a team of operators
within the group they're all following
the same uh ways of working when they do
their intrusions uh they've got their
same tool kits
um
and it helps because not all of the
operators are trained at the same level
so it helps
but they're all sharing that knowledge
um
and they've got the right tools and
configurations in place
so for example they have customized
scripts for like ad fines and so on
so the procedures are battle tested
they work
um it doesn't mean that they're
sophisticated it just means that the
operator know when and where to use them
and
they know what commands to enter um
and what to do
and what they objected on using that
command
some of the procedures are automated um
with custom scripts so
um
survival happened to type commands all
the time they will evolve their
playbooks put scripts in place to
automate that discovery the collection
and then the the analyst uh the operator
can dictate that and upload them
the the other bit
um so we talked about new vulnerability
so
it's a kind of mouse game for them as
well so as analysts if we detect how
they're doing them and a security tool
can detect what they're doing they would
have booked their game they'll have to
develop new procedures leveraging new
tools and if there's a new vulnerability
coming out or which has been released um
then they'll exploit that incorporate
into our procedures
so
so while the playbooks are great um and
they work it provides an easy to follow
procedure
operator can still make
mistakes so we've seen mistakes by
operators so
they either tend to fall into console
errors where they've entered the wrong
command or they tool in issues when
things break
so in one case as part of the discovery
they were trying to do enumeration of
installed antivirus products on the
endpoint
and
what the operator did and i was done by
a cobble strike
they entered the of a specific command
on the
host command shell
which was the av query command
which is very specific to kobo strike is
a add-on script called aggressor
and so they entered it effectively in
the wrong window so in their cable
stripe console they would allow like an
interact with the beacon and they would
have had another window for
non-interactive so
yeah so that was
at a bad day well that kind of telemetry
just get locked um see if you can
capture that
um that's pretty good
um
the the other controllers
is copy and paste so it looks like they
copied and pasted um a command straight
from the playbook
so where the ip
should have been past your taskless it
should have been the actual ip just over
the end point
so again that would have thrown an error
so
very useful detection opportunity it
doesn't happen all the time but it can
happen
and we have seen them several times
so the tools um
a defined
very popular tool of all the tools that
we've seen
and
the country group and they actually
automated that using adf.bat and we've
seen this being dropped on endpoints and
a number of cases over the last two
years
and they still use the same file name
adf.bat
and
the same script is also favored by other
groups so we can see from a country chat
they were saying that agf talked about
was used by like
and then someone remarked it was
actually created by them um so
there you go tools are being leaked or
shared amongst other groups
whether
uh intentionally or unintentionally
so we've seen other scripts such as one
side piece gunner and power view as well
so all of them are home to public domain
um
card so you'll tend to get dropped
so
look for files that are dropped in
unusual files like temp folder music
folder downloads folder they're
easy to
in spot of vulnerabilities um so we
talked about the the exchange one
um one i saw in the case
where
i was seeing sam the admin as part of
ldap request
um doing the analysis yeah it was linked
to a uh probably available script uh you
could get from github so they've
obviously taken that incorporated into
that procedure and um uh used it against
this
particular host
so it does demonstrate that groups
they are actually
reviewing the vulnerabilities out there
working out which ones are definitely
worth exposing and also looking for any
code that's been released to exploit
that
so they are relying on system
administrators not doing their patching
holding him and so on and exploiting
those weakness
and the us sir they produced their
report as well where they
even acknowledged that after two weeks
where vulnerability is disclosed
and and if there's a tool available such
as the people concept script
attackers will explain
so that's a trend that i have seen and
it pretty much
aligns to what we've seen as well in
cases
um
we don't
see huge amounts of customizations of
scripts so they tend to take what
they've got
and deploy it
it probably means that they're
probably got
operators but probably a lack of
developers in their teams so they can't
do a lot of tool development maybe um or
whether they just interested in using a
tool just for short amount of time
before everything is patched so they're
probably not worth investing in building
that vulnerability
um
so
yeah again
a lot of scripts tend to fall into
non-standard locations as well
so
intrusions never always go to plum so
some of the more unusual ones are
when things go wrong so we've seen
beacons be deployed
never
uh call home properly
and it's just continuous dns requests um
and then they'll deploy another beacon
on the same house so they end up with
multiple beacons on the same house uh
making continuous requests and then one
of them will connect
um so it could there's so they have
issues as well with their infrastructure
so they might have developed a payload
that might work fine the day before and
all of a sudden the c2 infrastructure
has been burned um so
sort of create another one so this is
the problem with iocs it's quite easy to
build a new domain new ip and so on
um
in another case
because there's a lot of ransomware
groups um i actually saw two
different operators on the same house at
the same time
which is another following almost
identical um playbooks uh how they were
doing their enumeration discovery and
moving
one took a different approach to doing
lateral movement whereas another one
was successful in their lateral movement
and did the
encryption
made it a bit more difficult for the
analysts
because they were very similar
techniques they were following um so it
just made it a bit harder to unpack but
it does happen
and
some of the operators they are really
good understanding of an environment
that they
compromise um they probably know it
better than the system administrators in
some cases so they'll know the security
of the configuration how things hang and
network together
um but they don't look out for the
factors so they may focus on
a defender or not necessary other threat
groups
so
so the operators were have been focused
on initial access all the way up to run
somewhere but i mentioned about tripol
so you mustn't forget about those so
don't just focus on ransomware
techniques try to detect tripod because
and other types of access books because
if you can detect those then it's
unlikely the one somewhere that you can
get into the network
some of these smart activities we see
are
related to checks and blending so we've
seen safety checks so this is fairly
recent so in one case i saw the use of a
change um
code page
which i thought was quite unusual then
look doing a look on that
um
they're effectively looking for a
language uh that is configured on the
endpoint so they're either trying to
acknowledge yes that is a target they
should be engaging or based on the
language or if they're using a
particular language they need to avoid
so that's my i posted this on that
so
so they they spend a lot of time doing
those safety checks as well and
they also did a
battle damage assessment as well so i
mentioned like it's not all about
discovering stuff but also confirming
his prevention where actually did work
so again pretty clever just confirming
what they've done
actually delivered the payload
pattern of life
exfiltration
um in some cases we've seen blending of
activities where they've tried to
exfiltrate data
over several days with gaps and over
hours so again fairly small so it's not
a data upload coming out which will be
very unusual
uh in terms of c2 i've mentioned that
this is very hard for
the operators to maintain post
compromise and there's a lot of things
that can go wrong
so
it's frequently served by cobra slide
beacons um but there's also any desks
and other legitimate tools for long-term
access
so typically you see a beacon
on the edge so in http then internally
uh they'll be smb and they're uh linked
together
and um when
things do go wrong i've seen in cases
where they've
pulled out a ban payload uh
revealing a
staging tooling server um where they
must store their tools and pull that
down uh again they use like curl um
quite unique user agent string you not
normally see
so ideally they should be going for
short and long term haul beacons um it
all depends how long their intrusion is
going to be
but the key is for them to maintain
access by any means possible
um it's worth noting that a lot of the
cobblestop beacons are out of the box so
quite easy to spot in terms of default
configurations
so going back to the data still there
before we work with we work with a lot
of different tools
a lot of them in the public domain so as
an analyst you should be familiar with
all these tools or have some awareness
of them
so that's what we're working with
so in terms of network analysis um
looking at peak up
it's not possible to just get a peak up
and then the story into wireshark and
just going through it individually
there's just um just too big data to
work with so
converting it into like zeke locks
will help focus the tree out a little
bit better
um and even running them against the um
emergence that's um
rules snort rules and that could detect
some of the low-hanging fruit as well
especially with default out-of-the-box
configuration for beacons
and even just doing uh some basic uh
analysis of the p-caps
you can probably start to see trends
where there's a lot of unusual post
requests a lot of traffic to particular
host domains
user agent strings which are really odd
they don't fit in and there's no other
network traffic um
so you can start looking for that
and the us
analysis reports
and they share a lot of the common
indicators as well especially with
cobalt stroke
so memory analysis this is quite a
complex area
so um if you get the right data and you
can you're confident whether you can use
that to correlate with your blog sources
especially if you've got telemetry
around processes and then you can start
running your scans against that as well
and you can start to understand more of
a deeper dive how that process is
injecting into other processes
um and if you've got the memory uh and
you've got a couple slight beacon you
can use some of the open um
and the public domain script such as one
one seven six eight dot python uh which
is created by digit stevens and you can
extract the cover stack configuration
again you can use that to verify your
indicators and the looks um
so
with all these data sources try not to
treat everything in isolation try to
understand what your analysis workflow
is and tie them all together
so if you've got gaps in one knowledge
um use another data artifact to
try to plug that gap
try not to solve everything just from
one data source
uh log analysis like i said that's our
main one you usually get lots of
different types of log sources
um we primarily work with microsoft
windows and we get a lot of we can work
with uh
powershell logs security logs system
unlocks and we can use things like
chainsaw uh where we can load them with
sigma rules again we can start to
understand classify the data
again with a lot of these tools you need
to understand the limitations and stuff
like you are for example
if you've got a rule just understand the
rule that you're trying to detect
because your can be used for detecting
files as well as memory resistant um
artifacts so if you try to run a file
based url in memory you might not get
that detection if it's looking for like
file size and
header bytes and so on which just didn't
exist in a memory properly
so
yeah so don't just drive to the tools uh
still think create hypotheses understand
what the attack is done and where
they think they are
documents
um again tools around that
related tools again you can quickly run
through those and they'll come up with
some
indicators so typical webplugs are
unusual api calls directly to win32
um
anti debug scripts where there's a lot
of macros where human
it's not human readable
where there's a lot of procedures
calling procedures and things like that
any unusual iocs call in um files that
are on the the endpoint
um so if you get enough of those flags
you can probably confirm hypothesis what
you're seeing in the logs and then what
you're seeing in the memory dump as well
and
so another tool we work with is cyber
chef by the ncsc that is a brilliant
tool it is like a swiss army knife we
can take
a number of functions in there for
decoding base64 and so on we can do
artifact analysis
um
in some cases they put square words in
there and
again that can be an indicator so
and we can start to
put everything together and even during
the binary you can see like county
reference in the binary files
um
yeah so there's a lot of data we can
work with testing
the key thing okay we understand how to
detect it we understand how the attacker
works the lock file the data that they
work with
the important thing is to understand uh
what actually works in your environment
in terms of preventing them detecting
and how to respond
so the likes of checking your avs using
um sigma
um there's a lot of
atomic tests out there that you can do
very simple test on the endpoint so
again a lot of resources so like georgie
generating an atomic case based on the
change control page and i wrote a sigma
rule for it so again that's the
community working in action really to
developing all these um
techniques and then being able to test
them
with a whole lot of resources um
far too many to list here um ncsc
provide the logging made easy solution
out of the box with a lot of default uh
windows log configuration which is great
uh mongen provides hardware
windows hardening guides
technique testing
and the us
provide bulletins as well
so
final advice so rob joyce uh woodwind
nsa he was head of a chief of data
access organizations he did a brief
several years ago
so one of the key takeaway comments from
that was and over those logs um look at
those locks no point just collecting
them and doing nothing with them
so is fear from
the nation state hacker point of view
was someone actually paying attention to
the logs and the data
and actually understanding what's
happening on the environment what usual
accounts are being used or
abused and so on so
yeah quite often we see a lot of
configuration where the logs are
misconfigured
they haven't got
the level of granularity not the right
time zone and it just makes it really
hard and then you end up with gaps and
you just don't understand what the truth
is um
so that's the key thing logs collecting
logs is really cheap so
yeah understand what you can collect
where you can store it and how to
exploit them
so
thank you um
i hope you've enjoyed the presentation
um so keep an eye out on
twitter feed on our website uh we
publish um
blogs um
talking
c2 servers uh quite frequently so we've
tried to produce uh one or two reports
every month um a big final thanks to the
dfir report team so
we spend a lot of time in our effort in
our own time uh analyzing and reporting
on techniques um yeah is
it's a great good team and and it yeah
everyone's making use of the intelligent
report out there and a lot of the other
intelligence reports have also matured
over the last couple years following
very similar approaches moving away just
from ioc or indicator activities as well
i'm nicer that's three o'clock