right let's get this going so we can all
pack up and go off to the after
conference social thing that's not a
party
quiet so i'll put baby shark back on
did we all have fun
[Music]
yes
that is that is why we do this
the this all still started still kind of
stuff because
i've been to conferences nails with
confidence mike's been conferences and
some of them are good but they're a bit
boring and we just wanted something that
was fun so as long as you guys have fun
that's the main thing hopefully you've
learned stuff and networked and talked
to people and doing all the stuff but
fun is the main bit
as we just start going to thank the
sponsors they've all been really good
some of them have had booths the ones
that have had booths that i've spoken to
they're all seemed really happy with you
um a lot of recruitment going on a lot
of companies want new staff at the
moment
people obviously switching roam netitude
to sec two sec two pentax partners
people move around the industry people
bounce about but the sponsors so far
feedback has been pretty good so you
guys thank you for going to them thank
you for talking to them
again hallum thanks for giving us the
venue we will be back next year as long
as you let us have them i have the place
we do need more sponsors for next year
talk to your marketing teams
you've been you know how good it is you
know what you've got out of it so talk
to marketing
as of this year i sent an email and a
blog post out about it a couple of
months ago
tito the new package we've got for
tickets lets us collect questions so
we've got demographics so we can now say
to marketing teams
this is the percentage of senior
pentesters this is the percentage of
students
we've got this from the north these
people from the south we've got a decent
breakdown
of um
of sort of who's coming in so it's not
just give us money give us money because
these are the kind of people you'll be
reaching and
aiming for so we've got the demographics
if marketing needs it
i have to go on social again networks
from netitude doors open when i stop
talking at the end of this so we'll try
to get through as quick as we can
uh food's out from about seven robot was
about nine
slideshow roulette if we got slides
we've we've got some slides to give up
we'll pull up some more later in the
night when the kids are a bit quieter
sure we can find some random things
uh yeah you need your badges
it's upstairs so hopefully come on run
run run
uh hopefully all of you have been to
track
[Applause]
uh
yeah if everybody's been to track two
so you up at the top floor
you go carry on going out of the
building double back on yourselves up
the stairs and it's up there it's on
level six so that's where the party's at
if you get stuck just look or listen and
you'll you'll find people
um if you haven't got your beer tokens
yet
see crew see me or neil or
a few others have got tokens if your
crew and haven't been giving out tokens
see me and neil and we will get you your
tokens so crew get everybody gets tokens
as long as you've got a yellow vest or a
crew thing or something or you can just
at least say please
uh last order's 11 15 we kicked out by
12.
uh it's a cat it's a no it's not a cash
on the bar it's a card only bar
so once you've used your tokens we will
issue more tokens as the night goes on
we just want to see how many we get
through first and how the bar tabs go
before we start handing out more tokens
um so while you're waiting for moto
because you can buy your own drinks but
it's card only not cash
food's coming out from seven and it's
going to come out in batches so we're
expecting sort of fairly big queues
because the way they're doing it the
queue is big just sit down wait let the
queue go down let the next match come
out
they should looking at the amount of
food we had left over from lunch there
is more food coming out for dinner than
there was lunch so we should not be
short of food this time
um
the doors to the outside world at some
point i don't know what time it is but
at some point they get locked from the
outside so you can go out
but to get back in again you have to
bust security and ask nicely to come
back in so if you go out for a cigarette
or anything like that or just get fresh
air
just be mindful that
whether you can get back in or maybe
leave somebody inside or whatever
security might get upset if every couple
minutes let me in let me in let me in
um liz quest is uh fully booked now so
sorry if you're not on it if you are on
it
eleven o'clock at bank street turn up
for ten two quarter two to make sure
you're in and you've got the uh the
details
sticker stall tim
tim tim
he's still counting okay whenever tim
comes in we'll get a thing i know it was
at least 150 quid before about 11
o'clock so we should have made a decent
amount of money on that thank you to
everybody who's put money in it will be
split between the two charities and i'll
put a blog post up on the site to say
where it's gone and just give receipts
and stuff
yes
it is 11 o'clock what in the past few
years they've well in the last year or
so it changed management and before they
would open early for us so we could get
in at 10 and do it and that's what i
planned for this time on the tournament
nope we're open at 11. so we're the
first gaming at 11.
uh scavenger hunt
where yep do i call up and sort people
out
yeah so
we've had a lot of very very interesting
submissions lots of people eating not
just spoonfuls but entire globs of
marmite
[Music]
lots of portraits on chocolate bars
um what else we got the production of
freddo surprisingly accurate including a
fictional burst
um
yeah it's just absolutely mad like fair
play to everyone who's playing because
the submissions have just been through
the roof i've been honestly busy doing
this including with my talk so
thank you very much for playing
um our winners at the moment by 30
points skin of their teeth is grass
touchers
[Music]
[Applause]
in second place we've got scavenger hunt
team
[Music]
and uh
then the best submission is just pirate
flag
so
[Applause]
but we were supposed to be giving out
prizes now to one and two and then carry
on into the evening yeah but because
there's only three teams really playing
well four well there is a fourth team
but 130 points
might take a while to catch up
do we want to roll over into the evening
or do you want to just claim your prize
now
good answer
right i'll sort your prizes out
afterwards come and find me in a bit see
you soon social
role the other two scavenger hunt team
and pirate flag roll you over into the
party we'll
announce it at some point later on yep
okay
thank you very much thanks for running
that for us it's
i've i've had sneak previews of this
list for the last few weeks
and it scared me some of the things that
were on it has anybody shared their
eyebrow
no
oh
yeah it's real really good
he's got the raise if anybody wants to
shove an eyebrow he's got a razor
team team three if you want to leap top
leap frog team two he's got the razors
right the acrostic point it was a split
decision on this one
we've got two winners
okay
so pippa do you want to read out your
winner
gun carson i don't think he's here today
he's here are you here i think he went
home i think that's the person that went
one of the people who went home okay
he's gone home but
we'll get a prize to him
jordan read out his
um entry
seven
safety and socialization technology
electricity enjoyment learning
communication opportunity nerds
[Music]
[Applause]
and for my winner we have ether87
yes
it is
we will get priced for the jewelry hose
out just so she can come look at the
camera
steel con
the excellent efilo clever observation
knowledge
[Music]
somehow i will get hold of the pair of
you and um yeah we'll get prizes out to
you both
number 16 and number seven
lewis did you put it back on again where
is it
he's get down here
yeah any of you get drunk or larry this
henge man is going to be taking you
outside
so we've had
you're not getting back in either way
because the door's not going to work
um so yeah we've got a few entries uh
we've got we got a tie so the the
amazing prize of two beer tokens two
whole drinks
forgetting how many this crazy man is
wearing uh goes to we have uh infosec
globo
if you hey
two beer tokens to you
and
daniel drackett aka ninja chicken
yeah
a whole two tokens yeah and now you have
to wear that for the rest of the night
[Music]
oh yeah that's a good point
nepotism uh no uh 65 and the two entries
were 67 and 67. surprising
[Music]
if he does take it off try feeling the
weight of that thing because it is heavy
we got it off him for five minutes and
it weighs a ton
who is the other winner is he
gone
wait where are you going get back down
here sit sit
right
we're going to skip past the robot wars
because he's got home
um
right towards the end of it this has
gone quicker oh
did you want to do the
macarena thing
no
okay
[Music]
they actually managed to teach me at
break time i am not doing the macarena
but i do remember the first two moves of
this and this
the rest of it
i've completely forgotten
who wants to do the macarena come on
get him up any come on adults it's got
to be somebody
come on right
we have swag bags come on somebody wants
to swag back for it
[Applause]
come
don't worry they'll tell you the moves
come on down you want to do it
[Applause]
[Music]
okay we'll do it at the party then
go sit down
oh here comes lizzy with possibly an
update
how are you going home
okay so in cash for the sticker stall
for
yeah that's one thanks pip um we have
raised in cash 580 pounds and 72 p
and there's apparently a lot of money as
well that's also gone straight to just
giving we don't know the exact totals
for that just yet but i'm sure that'll
be announced at some point
yeah cool right there you go before i
sleep
brilliant
i said thank you very much for all the
charity money it's uh it does make a
difference
oh that one that one that one
right um we courage the end so it's time
for the thank you is there anything i've
missed because i said we're running very
early we won't start the party till
seven it's only ten to six
with two beer tokens
yes
are we
we were gonna save that till the uh
party but if he's here
social
brian where are you
brian because this has been recorded
he's gonna ride it in the party
it's not a spa
it's an after event thing
right um yeah thank you to people cooper
ran the av again absolutely amazingly
how many videos have you got out so
far two
not
[Applause]
how many are ready to go out
how many
four
fourteen thought so yeah it's not his
fault it's university internet
connectivity problems i think possibly
all of us have had problems with the
internet today so
two videos uploaded 14 ready to go it's
uh
they will be there very soon i'm sure
tanya massive thanks for the kids track
um yeah have done the whole thing
without you so kids have you enjoyed it
um we still have six of them left so
ideally if you could collect them at the
end they're all here um
i've been referring to them by number
all day so
your kid your kids are thing one and
thing two um
but yeah the kids have been really
brilliant they've done all sorts of
lovely stuff
um and and nobody has caused any
problems
and and they've all been wonderful and
obviously we've had loads of volunteers
bring all their stuff along to show or
to play with and let the kids run riot
on on very complicated machines and
they've been absolutely brilliant with
it so um yeah thanks for everybody who
helped and thanks to the people who
sponsor the kids track because the kids
have got much better goodie bags than
you
[Music]
yeah that is a big thanks to the bcs i
think they've been with us since the
first years we did the kids track
and without getting the kids involved
early
we should we can lose them so get them
in now get them interested even if they
don't go into security or computing jobs
it gives them a mindset of hacking and
playing with stuff that's valuable for
any job or anything
well thank you
shannon and his big van
with without without challenges big van
i don't know how many car trips it would
have taken me yesterday to get all the
goodies and stuff shifted around we got
two very full van loads
uh shifted all around sheffield
um the bike stuff was yesterday
stuffed well over fun well about 450 odd
bags and it was just a brilliant
production line bang bang in done
stacked we got him down to the goody bag
room
and
yeah it was just really good really
quick got it sorted
um yeah good
the day crew today
i've gotta admit i have done very little
today
uh i came this morning sort of said
right there's the goodie bags there's
reg table
a few people took over right we'll do
this we'll do that mark and tasha just
started doing it and things organized
and it all just happened so
yeah me and neil have done very little
it's the crew that have actually ran the
event today we've just sat back and sort
of talked to people and schmoozed and
stuff and thrown things at people so
so what
yeah i went i don't know in what seven
years we've been doing this eight years
whatever it is i have seen about three
talks live and actually managed to go to
one today i saw andy's it was dreadful
won't go back
right
yeah trip advisor wouldn't go again
and that's it unless anybody else has
got anything else to do it's we've got
another half hour 45 minutes
food is not coming out until seven so
either light oh that yeah we do have a
whole ton of goodie bags left
i don't want
i don't want to be taking them home so
please if you want swag it'll be down by
the register just come and get it
yeah just took a couple of quid or
whatever in the um
in a charity bucket
but please i want to get rid of it all
it's i don't be looking after all this
for another year
and if we don't get rid of it you will
be getting
henderson's out of date for a year and
some monkey jelly babies in your bags
next year what
i
just been told in the social there are
colored eggs hidden around the place
therefore the kids don't touch them it's
a treasure hunt of some kind
that they might not know about yet but
they do know about now so just leave the
hidden things alone
right
with that
go home go away see you at the party see
you tomorrow