uh my talk is going to be on pretesting
cordova applications
and
i'm nishant i've
been working in security for the last
seven
years consulting
and the last uh right now i'm working
with empty set as a upset consultant and
the previous uh
job of restoring obviously mobile
application security
uh presented in few other conferences
most of all all of them there
online and this would be the first
offering
and uh so the asynchronous for the talk
is uh we are gonna touch upon
basics of cordova what's the cordova
application and
some of the vulnerabilities which are
which were present in cordova earlier
than perhaps right now
and also some of the security features
provided by cordova and also some of the
security measures uh which you can take
to provide
common vulnerabilities in accordance
application
so uh why mobile interesting like the
use of mobile applications have
exponentially increased in the last
couple of years
and
also if you see the research which comes
out for mobile application security it's
usually uh
android or ios
and most of the research focus on
android and ios and not on hybrid
applications like cordova cordova being
just one of them there are multiple
other platforms like uh flutter and
there's xamarin reactions and so on
and also if you see a lot of companies
have started moving towards hybrid
applications
in terms of mobile because of the ease
of developing the application and you
also develop the application once uh you
can deploy for both ios and
ios and android as well
[Music]
and so before we uh start with uh
cordova like i just wanted to
highlight some of the developer
assumptions
in terms of mobile applications so when
most of the application developers
mobile application developers
like they usually have a lot of inbuilt
protections with supply side for example
mostly think that if
my application is written for uh like if
i have protections towards
jailbreak uh jailbreak the application
is not going to run out of jailbroken
phone or the user is not going to use a
rooted or a generic broken phone to you
know
install and use the application and also
with apart from jailbreak there are
various other protections like ssl
printing where you fit the certificate
towards the inside the application so
that uh
someone was testing the application they
won't be able to see the traffic
involved and also
the integrity checks which are there in
the mobile mobile site
so
no adversity would be able to reverse
insane by up and change the code so
these are all some of the assumptions
but
all these client set protections should
they really protect the application i
would say
yes and no
for a very mature organization it makes
sense for them to
build or incorporate all these uh
additional security measures but for any
application uh which is right this does
not have any protection
[Music]
and yeah so with cordova basically
cordova is a hybrid
development platform uh written on his
table and javascript using html and
javascript
and
one of the main features of
applications being written on cordova's
it's the whole environment of cordova is
sandboxed so
it should not be able to access the file
system or camera or zero location and so
on but most of the
all of the applications
which we use in
uh day to day needs access to
geolocation and what about clients
camera and so on so how does cordova
still manage to get access to the nato
operating system apis is that
even though the webview is sandboxed
cordura basically exports this component
called glass
this javascript bridge or an interface
and
that interface can talk to both cordova
and it can talk to the nato operating
system and it might be for the couple of
apis which are exported and
using the bridge a cordova application
can you know uh get access to photos or
zero location and so on and again uh the
permission should be declared in the
manifesto or inferno key list for for
the functionality to work properly and
the
config.xml which we'll be looking at is
one of the
uh one of the key uh
key fights in cordova which
in terms of audit
and yeah this is the first one is the
implementation of the bridge so you're
just enabling javascript using said
javascript enabled and you create an
interface and i just called it ambriz
and you can
load a url this can be using a file
protocol or this can be a direct html xs
external url
and with ios you can
initialize review and call evaluate
javascript and using this the
ios javascript engine will understand
that okay this is a javascript object or
a javascript file and it is given
and in terms of the plugins which we
talked about or plugins and
functionalities
so
basically you create a listener for
device ready
uh device ready is the apac on device
ready
on device ready make sure that the whole
corner environment is up and running and
all the apes are
ready to be accessible
and so you just wait for the uh listen
for the event and once that starts and
uh the navigator like if you see online
number four that is console.blog
navigated or contacts navigator is
nothing but a global object provided by
cordova and using navigator you can
uh you can basically access all the apis
provided with the operating system into
like contacts and so on
and this is how you uh
for example access the contact station
cordova that's in android
location
and these are some of the availabilities
which were already discussed
and discovered in cordova
uh earlier and all of these are passed
the two interesting uh vulnerabilities
along these electrode one which is which
was information disclosure basically the
cordova's official camera plug-in which
was
being used
uh
they were storing the data they're
showing all the photos which were taken
with the application in the external
storage so that any application of
android so any application who gets this
gets
installed in the phone gets access to sd
card so they can still focus that's one
and the second one is the universal xss
which was found in the webview and this
basically allowed crossovers to you know
execute javascript from the top domain
and
basically escape the sandbox
and this is the configuration file it's
uh basically presenting config.xml in
the xml folder and this is under a
application uh folder of ios so
config.xml you can configure all the
apis plugins you can configure some
security features and so on
so the first uh critical feature of
configure xml is basically access origin
access original access origin is pretty
similar to you know content security
policy so if we say uh set the access
origin to start that means that
the
mobile application can basically
talk to or send requests to any any app
server any domain basically but if you
set it to say that steelheart.com the
mobile application can just talk to
student.com and
any other domain it tries to talk to if
the recorder will just physically first
this is very helpful to improve uh
not preventing too it is an additional
feature which you can
you know use to prevent excesses so that
people cannot load scripts from
different website and you know send data
to a different part of party websites
and the next one is allow intents so
intents are nothing but uh
deep links or like
it's like sms
slash slash four slash or something like
that you can also consider what index
can be used what you use and so on and
the next one is the content security
policy which is basically the csp of
applications the last one is aps or app
transport security
which is a ios specific security feature
transport layer security protection it
just enhances the transport layer making
sure that the site is so secure it's not
using http and so on
and some other things which we need to
consider while
while using web views or while writing
applications for web views is that the
in-app browser there is this api called
in our browser which should always be
used for opening links which you don't
trust or for example third party links
or advertisement links
if you want to load that in your
corridor application it's always better
to use in our browser because it's
isolated from the cordova environment so
you cannot access the contacts or
and so on
location and so on the next thing is
that what one another security
law when you
see in particular applications very
commonly is that the domain which is
there is this random domain it's not
even
not even the servers
made
made domain it's declared in the
config.xml
and even though
the application developers may think
that okay it's loaded in an iframe the
iframe still gets access to the contours
apis and environment so that they can
excel create data so this is again
one thing that you
should be
looking for in cordoba applications when
it comes to web
and so when we talk about xss
uh it's usually with uh
css in drug applications but in mobile
applications excesses are very hard to
find because the uh mobile native ios
and android engines do not pass his
similar javascript just like how he
browses to but since quarter was like in
his table in javascript any excesses
which is there in the application
is going to have a very severe impact
due to the fact not not only that you
can uh
you know steal the cookies from a
specific user or from the specific app
due to the cordova's api being already
initialized you can load the cordova's
apis and you know get contacts or you
can exfiltrate the photos you can
exclude the location of the current
device and so on and the second one is a
cv which was found in webview itself not
not on the application but it was sort
of the review itself
when you invoke an intent to start a
cordova application
the
uh
whitelisting was not done securely so
that it could populate any
url to exploit directly or
to go further
so how do we uh
how do we access the native apis is that
say we have a nexus is all an attacker
has to do is host this specific
javascript very similar to this
as we saw earlier you
wait for the on device ready even
and
once that is done
so
you start without i mean you
talk to navigator object navigating or
connects or location and so on
and
and you can do exact sort of external
history if you request to you know send
back the server to send out the data to
your server
and this is pretty similar for this is
for ios the second example is for ios
it's it's very similar you visualize the
navigator object you call the apis and
you can send it back to this if chp and
access control
is one another interesting feature or
functionality which i discovered while
testing cordova was
the
way in which you can use
the inbuilt browser the main browser to
debug the applications but why i was
looking forward to debug the application
was
like
uh
if you if you see banking applications
most of them have a lot of predictions
and one of the predictions one of the
additional client set protection is that
the whole network request and response
which is sent to the server
is being encrypted apart like apart from
tls
or https the
request body and the response body are
encrypted with the static or dynamic key
so if it is a static say consider this
example it is written in java and say it
is a static key you can reverse instead
of the java application and you can
basically get the key and you can use
online tools to
get back to network uh body and
plaintext which is encrypted
so something it looks something like
this like it's basically a normal
request but the whole body is encrypted
like we do not know what's being sent
and what's being received so
if this is a
this is an application written in native
i use uh android
it's uh it's pretty straightforward
nowadays due to
a lot of tools being available and frida
being available and there are already a
lot of free desktops which hook into the
crypto live versions of both android and
ios and print out the key or iv
the whole data and so on
so if this was the case of a native
application you can basically use
freedom call the specific api secret key
specification and hook into the specific
argument to print out the print on the
key and id and so on but since our
application is written in cordova and
like i was while was testing this
application i was i saw that it was
written in cordova and it was using
additional layer of encryption for the
liquid body and response body
and while uh digging in further like i
saw that the javascript files had
code for encryption and description
routines but it was very heavily
obfuscated and
like
for you to reverse engineer that and
read it properly it's going to take
pages
just to get where's the ways will also
get the key and so on
and
so while i was looking into uh webview
like figured out that
there is there was an also basically
since android's webview is
chromium browser it uses chrome and ios
webview is basically safari which uses
lipkit so since the
since chrome has a developer option
since chrome has a way of remotely
debugging your applications
there should there should it should be
possible to
you know
make the application running in your
phone to talk to the browser writing on
your system and use the developer
options or console people whereas you
want to hit the key
so
like while looking into the webview like
i figured out this
was this set that contains debugging
enabled api and looking further into
this like figured out that like if we
see in like 246 it
starts that m devtool server so devtool
serves basically chrome's uh you know
developer options you can start the
developer options one if and only if
this set web content will be selected so
but this is not enabled in prediction by
default but on debug builds it's always
enabled so if you have if you're testing
a debugger application you can just
connect your phone go to chrome string
you will be able to see the review but
since this was not the case
uh like you can just create a writer
free desktop to hook into the
red view and we know that this is the
api or this is the
module which we need to hook center
contains keyboarding enabled you
overwrite the function to always set it
to true so the
operating system thinks that okay this
is a debug application and from now on
so on on the left is
a protection application where we cannot
see
no or no review
endpoints and after running the script
like we can see on the end
that uh set web content
is set to true and slowly every time the
view is getting called the
this will overwrite it to true
and now we can see that view for uh
that you can see multiple review uh
instances one is one the main one is the
condo application and the next one is
the uh google ads which is loaded and so
on from here on you can just click on
inspector and
you know set breakpoints from the
debugger to
in our case you can look at the
definition of efficiencies
ios is pretty similar uh all you have to
do is resign the application with the
developer certificate enable the options
in both safari and your phone so that
they both can talk to you on top
and you resend the application to the
developers certificate
[Music]
and
in ios there are like two main apis ui
review and wk review and
ui preview is replicated right now
because
by default it has a lot of insecure
uh insecure defaults the file protocol
handler is enabled by default the
javascript is enabled by default
and
uav does not support out of the process
rendering so basically
the web view and the update like issue
can compromise the web group because
application also gets affected
so this this was one such availability
where the attacker was able to you know
explore the ui reviews api and since
file protocol is always
enabled it was able to send the adc
password button so
that's this piece
while uh wk reviews
the new one now please enforcing
everyone to use this
uh this version of webview it's
it has options to you know disable
javascript disable file protocol
handlers and so on which the ui will do
this entire so
if
you're using wkm view and if you're not
using javascript or if you're not using
and i was really surprised to see uh
malwares which were written in cordova i
was just i just found out like one of
them
was the encrypted horse malware and
surprisingly it uses the same uh
it uses the encryption
technique to you know pack and unpack
uh but uh and also to encrypt the
request body and responsibility and so
on
and uh for future research uh these
these were the things which were in my
mind
but i'm sure there are more uh added to
these
first the review libraries and the
javascript interface
for passing issues
how how it passes different or malicious
confidence and
find more vulnerabilities in the
official cordova plugins try to create a
malicious cargo plug-in and so on and
also the whitelist model which we
discussed the access origin
it was earlier possible to
bypass it if you if the access origin
was set to say
steelcon.com any website that has a
domain name of steelcom
steelcoin.com dot email.com bypasses the
right software but this this is scratch
now so
i don't know maybe there are more issues
with the whole whitelisting model and
you can fuzz and find out malicious
behind this
so basically references and that's
that's that doesn't talk if anyone has
any questions you should know
so apple released that likes weird
paranoid mode which as i understand it
starts to lock down from the javascript
huh do you know how that affects cordova
so basically uh with wkw view you have
the option to disable javascript but
with ui you don't have the option to
disable all together so if you choose to
say for according to applications you
choose to disable it altogether you
won't be able to use javascript in your
application basically it should be a
static histogram
and
when we see a lot of
websites or google applications
they do not really need javascript
because it says display data so if you
can generate the histogram and then
disable dashboard that that should be
improved
so this
is used
now so basically cardona for android
uses v8 engine
supports
and if
okay
sure