okay thank you very much for coming
I'll start with a little bit about Who I
am so I'm Mike hi
I'm also known as absolute bloke on
Twitter quite active on Twitter thanks I
do tweet a lot and about all sorts of
things can be anything about current
topics current events in information
security are you engaging quite a lot of
debate around some sensitive topics like
why we should have a fully HTTP web I
firmly believe we should there are
others that don't agree with that and I
can get a bit grumpy about it from time
to time generally in a good nature can
away I I write blogs a little bit more
detail shortly my blog out upset bloke
and I'm also a helper so I recognize a
few people in the room I like that so
greatly on the pleasure from seeing
other people flourish and develop and I
like to get involved with that in a
selfless way I just think that there are
good things and good people and I like
to help you do all that now I'm also a
speaker he can probably tell it's a bit
of an interesting journey for me my
first ever information security
conference was besides Manchester last
year 2017 so I turned up completely out
the blue had never been to a conference
before in this industry just as a punter
and a bug it kind of caught me and I
felt really at home felt like I was part
of the community for the first time have
been involved in the information
security industry for a number of years
but I just felt like a guy who works in
a company that does the security thing
and I never really had the opportunity
to reach out to other people and this
conference was the first time I had that
opportunity and it made me feel great I
kind of influenced me in my decision to
get involved in blogging I came right
out of this conference set up a blog and
wrote a review of this conference and I
tell the world what what I thought the
conference and how it made me feel and I
felt it was a life-changing event it
then encouraged me to become a lot more
active on Twitter I befriended a lot of
the people that delivered talks here or
who I'd met here and we've now become
really good friends as a result of that
and then I thought actually I've now
been blogging for quite a while I'd like
to set the message out in a less static
way reading my words on my blog have one
thing but me being able to go out and
give actual verbal experiences or
testimonies about my experiences and
what I've done I think can be more
impactful sometimes so I made the
decision back in the last year that I
really wanted to get involved in talks
and I thought well I enjoyed oh wasps oh
man I enjoyed b-sides Manchester so much
that I was encouraged to apply for
b-sides Leeds
didn't go didn't get it a big one but
went along nonetheless really enjoyed
the conference one of my colleagues in
the in the audience came on with me
I think he'd echo the fact it was we
have a really good time but I wasn't put
off I did get invited to do a lightning
talk at the event on the night before
the conference
I then applied for b-side Scotland in
Glasgow I didn't get that but I was
offered a reserved speaker position
there which was great because I was
invited up there and I was treated as if
I was part of the crew delivering
content on the day again met some great
people and again had a really good time
at that conference again it didn't put
me off I continued and then I put
speculative application into b-sides of
London I actually got that gig and that
was in June this year that's the talk
I'm going to be giving for you today so
when doubt London gave the talk really
enjoyed it and that was it I've done it
broke my duck and now I'm really I
really feel like I'm part of the part
the thing I did a talk for OWASP in
Manchester last month and that was
really good this talk once again
meanwhile I had it application in to
speak here but hadn't heard anything and
on Twitter I started see seeing people
going yeah got my talk accepted it be
sighs Manchester I thought well haven't
heard anything yes or no delivered the
talk it happened that Mark one of the
organisers of b-sides was at that talk
at the end after questions were answered
he said this isn't a question it's more
a statement
to come and talk at bayside Manchester
that was pretty much it was the best
moment of the year as far as I was
concerned because what that meant was
I'd gone from attending as a as a punter
at a conference just happened to be this
one to being a speaker at the same
conference within a year and I feel
really really privileged to be here
giving this talk for you guys today so
I'm I'm an infra sec guy an ISP a local
ISP won't mention the name but tell you
about who they are afterwards and I'm
also a member of Oh wasp so quick show
of hands who's an O wasp member one two
two okay keep your hands up because
you'll know but a show of hands if you
know a wasp is okay quite a few more for
those that don't know it's the open web
application security project so it's a
global foundation of application
security professionals and academics and
that come together and share great
experiences do good things get good
projects off the ground and bring that
back out for the greater good
there's been a lot of debate on to it
which I've been actively Roldan around
its reach out to getting new members
that's quite indicative of the to show
two hands three including myself in this
room they're not doing a good enough job
of getting the message out and getting
people back in and I think that's been
acknowledging that the board of director
level and they're gonna do a lot to try
and make that make a difference that I'm
a paid member of OWASP so the two guys
let's put the handle P but they paid
members over wasp
so being a paid member will cost you $50
a year as a professional an individual
about 35 pounds if you're a student it's
$20 a year which is about 14 15 pounds
for that you get to contribute money
into projects and chapters then get
money back so they can put Knights on
the input talks on and then share a lot
of the the knowledge and experience
that's happening more local level but
what you get in return is pretty cool
too
so for your 35 pounds a year or 14 15
pounds a year you get an OAuth
lecounte now that's pretty cool you get
a Michael Thompson Oh waspey dog email
address and I kind of like that because
it adds a little bit a little level of
authenticity to you as an in person so
I've consolidated down a lot of email
addresses I would have used previously
to communicate with people and I'm just
now use my old wasp account kind of
handy but you get a G suite account as
well
now that's pretty good G suite account
is a cool thing it's a really expansive
group set of legal tools including mail
but you get unlimited storage with it
which not a lot of people realize wasp
is somehow managed to negotiate with
Google to get this huge blast endless
space of storage on their on their
network on my platform and so you can
use that to put anything there's no
restriction on what you use it for and
it's endless storage and endless cloud
storage and you also get the benefit of
filling the part that you're
contributing to something that's pretty
cool globally but again there's a lot of
work to do within the foundation to
attract new members and I think that's
something they recognize about I'm gonna
skip that one because it's a bit boring
okay why are we here so who knows what a
Web Application Firewall is okay pretty
much more or less everybody in the room
who's got one a few people skewed
figures here because some of the people
in this room work with me but not too
many people okay what is a Web
Application Firewall a what so it's a
layer of protection between your
software on the web your assets and on
the bad guys and I'm therefore really a
layer of protection against intrusion
into your data via web applications
so we're thinking a wasp top 10 now
every 3-4 years Oh what get together and
they take data in from the the world so
what kinds of attacks are people
experiencing and they put all that data
together and they'll produce a top 10
now it can be misleading the top 10
isn't the only 10 web application
vulnerabilities that are out there
these are the ones that are considered
to be a more common easy to execute
impactful and have really severe
consequences if if there is an exploit
so we have a top 10 typically you'll see
in the top ten at number one injection
so sequel injection command injection
and so on and so forth things that allow
an attacker to modify an underlying
database or an underlying operating
system that's at number one it's been at
number one as far as long as I've been
involved in information security and
then you get other things like broken
authentication sort of things like
having cookie theft and hijacking
session hijacking and all that kind of
thing then you have things like
cross-site scripting cross-site request
forgery has gone out of the top zone
recently it's been kind of merged away
because there's a lot better mitigation
but those are the examples of the kind
of threat that the OWASP top 10 talks
about they're the kind of things that a
wife will provide protection against in
the way we've implemented it it's also a
method of controlling access to your web
applications so we control the DNS of
everything that we have on the web and
by doing that we're able to spear
traffic to wherever we want it to go
come-on for that in more detail in a bit
we're able to monitor a lot more again
I'll talk about this in more detail but
we've gone from a position in the past
of being not being able to mine as much
so now being able to monitor practically
everything so and it's a legitimate
component of your web app arsenal so
you're here again on Twitter I get
grumpy where people say well a laugh is
purely a compliance tool okay it's there
to say our apps are secure
nothing of the sort it's not a
compliance tool it's there as a layer of
protection okay
it's there in the same way that server
hardening is important it's there in the
same way that secure coding is important
it's got a legitimate role so what life
isn't it's not at all the solution so
I've touched on that in a previous slide
it's not the be-all end-all it's not a
way of saying well we've got a watch in
front of everything so everything behind
it it's cool it certainly isn't a reason
for dance to say well whatever our
software can go and whatever condition
we choose because the RAF will protect
it and I'll give you a little anecdote
you don't know is that
we've got a fairly big dev team where I
work and quite a large architecture team
and not many of them really if any know
what the wife is doing okay they know
it's there because we've done this kind
of talk for them but we were not going
into explicit detail about what it's
protecting against but there's a reason
for it's quite deliberate and the reason
is that while ever they're not entirely
certain of what's happening in front of
their software they're not encouraged to
be relaxed about securely coding it it
keeps them on their toes and I work very
closely with developers around secure
coding so what kind of bringing that all
together into a a kind of a harmonized
approach to securing our stuff it's not
an excuse not to patch so we see a lot
of the breaches that have happened in
recent years in the last 12 months have
been around not keeping software
frameworks up to date so we know that
Equifax got got attacked via obsolete
version of Apache struts okay patch was
available several months ahead of the
attack the knew about it but they did
nothing about it and they were attacked
a wife might have prevented that because
it wouldn't have been able to access the
underlying framework it's not an excuse
not to patch the stuff though and keep
the components up today and it ain't an
opportunity to around your boss and go
yeah oh we've got a wife guys what's
they're doing stuff and a pay rise we've
made improvements to the laughs can we
have more money it's not that sort so
how did we arrive at this this
enlightenment okay well we'd we'd had a
bad number of days actually in autumn
2015 September 2015 we were taken off
the internet for about two and a half to
three days and that wasn't just a
website that was our entire platform
marketing web site customer portals
diagnostic systems contact systems
everything had gone we were suffering
the biggest denial of service attack
that we'd faced as an organisation in
the time that I've been there so that
was a mixture of TCP syn floods okay UDP
and HTTP attacks we were being attacked
by putting WordPress helps they were
pretty easy to mitigate against because
that was HTTP and we were the web guys
we could see that and do stuff with it
but the TCP and UDP that was networks
we were really vulnerable to her and we
dealt with it but we dealt with in what
didn't feel like a sophisticated or a
repeatable way and that didn't feel good
enough so we needed to do something
about it so we had a bunch of meetings
and this was even board level and the
message was we can't this happen again
we can't have a repeat of this we need
that critical webapps up we're an isp if
we're not on the internet that's not
very good is it
it's bloody rubbish so we need to keep
our critical Web Apps up we need to
block malicious requests pretty obvious
we need to stop access to our origin
servers at that point you could if you
didn't ask you've got the back end IP
anyway so if we block me if we do kind
of office cajon of the dns if we knew
the IP you could still kill the server
and that was going on it's part of the
reason that we have such a problem when
it's allies on everything and it's be
able to monitor everything that's going
on we couldn't see much can now see loss
and getting a better understanding of
our traffic so where is it coming from
how we getting a lot of traffic from the
UK where our main customer bases I was
seeing a lot of traffic from Europe
China Russia the USA we have no idea
really we didn't have any understanding
of GL IP so we were already using some
technologies in pockets of the business
but kind of all the improve of concept
so we had a project that we kicked off
that was get off the proof of concept
plan and get on a delivering as a
production solution so we decided that
we were all reading AWS summers and web
services to deliver certain solutions to
customers so why not do some of that
ourselves why not reverse proxy
connections to our websites via a
proxying system so you don't ever see
the origin Webster ok why don't we look
at IPS as they come in we're currently
Trust all the IPS that come in until
they do something bad and then we
retrospectively block them on on the
other web server or on a firewall didn't
seem elegant and didn't seem something
we can do repeatedly request routing so
what if we get an attack from a
particular country what can we do about
it okay come on that screen a request so
what do our requests look like what's in
the user agent well we kind of could see
it if we looked in our is log what's in
the URI what's of the body of what all
the things are coming in the body we
have no idea really we could only look
again
after the event we needed to handle a
request so what if a request contains
something we considered bad what can we
do about it proactively rather than go
all the IP try it's single injectors
right let's block the IP until they come
in with a different IP and we needed
better monitoring so our technological
approach was to use route 53 Amazon's
native DNS infrastructure very powerful
I'll show you why in a bit elastic load
balancing so we need something that's
not ours to take care of DDoS and large
load huge volumes of traffic not
strictly speaking anything to do with
what but because we're using Amazon we
can benefit from their certificate
technology so in the same way if you use
let's encrypt you can say open it alter
and use forever with us the same you set
up our certificate management in Amazon
and it auto reuse forever
we've got a lot of certificates we
talked about reverse proxying so we use
nginx and interestingly our predominant
technology stack company is Microsoft
and asp.net when you hit is here and
nginx proxy and so you're gonna get kind
of linux thing but a bit of the aspx
page coming back these guys actually
doing so we can't we like that because
it's it's not clear-cut what technology
is some between an attacker and us we're
using it IP block lists again let's give
the work somebody else so we call out to
published IP block lists what lists and
if we see your IPS we do stuff with it
other technology that's always left in
because we've got something new every
time and I don't want to be keeping up
with updating this we use our actual Web
Application Firewall is is this thing
here noxee and it stands for nginx aunty
cross-site scripting and sequel
injection ok it's not signature based
pretty adaptive and soap and sauce
another theme we'll get to that towards
the end Oh what top ten everything in it
and Beyond is in that module and it
works with nginx and failed to ban that
does things with you when you've been
doing things bad and we'll come on to
that again and help
so anybody know Elka's wrote show hands
quite a few people it's pretty cool
skewed again because these guys
but yet elasticsearch logstash and
Cabana so it's a really neat way of
taking logs from whatever generates a
log so it could be a web server it could
be an event log an era log route 53 DNS
etc you stick in a big log pile and then
it can be indexed really easily into a
uniform pattern and then Cabana allows
you to build some really neat analysis
tools so that's a stylized diagram of
what it looks like but I'm gonna skip
this because I'm pressed for time a real
rough diagram couldn't be bothered
drawing this and you'll probably
appreciate why so that's you on the
Internet so you make a request to one of
our websites and you are you good not
misbehaving
so you hit route 53 route 53 does a
health check on the site you requested
if the site is for instance dead then it
will take a look at your request process
it and send you down to the static stack
here which says sorry guys web site bust
we're on it
come back another time if you are a UK
person or Island alamak cetera come
through here we do the health check on
the site is up we say where are you
coming from and you send you down here
and ultimately you'll get served web
stuffs from here if you're from outside
UK we do the same thing bring you down
here and we send you this stack so you
mentioned remember me mentioning about
being able to control how we direct
traffic to places well this is it we do
it at route 53 up at the top here if you
are doing bad things and say you come
through here and we recognize down here
that you're on one of these lists that
includes tor exit nose and a bunch of
other things we drop your connection on
the server so you know get near the web
at the web servers here we've got your
connection here and it's it's basically
a you'll get a CRO out connection error
yeah if you are not one of these lists
and you make a request that concerns
sequel syntax then nginx nak see on here
you'll go a hat sequel syntax I'm going
to put you I'm going to block you with
an HTTP form hey anyone know what that
is it's a teapot okay there is an RFC
it's a genuine HTTP status code do
recognizes it and we put you on a list
in failed to ban that says I found you
but you gotta fall right
if you repeat that three times you get
your final four one eight and you get
put on a band west for four hours okay
we've made some changes since this last
talk because there might be a few people
in the room that remember we did it a
different way which was to ban you first
time we're asking for life
I will took away that that was a bit
strong so that's what we do okay
I know before I was like a hacker comes
back and he gets three more tense for my
attempts he's down again okay the honest
question yeah well the quick answer is
the originally there were too tight to
use a using top an attacker which case
we're not bothered or a security
researcher in which case the security
searcher we think and would understand
that we were taking this approach but
it's it's just a list where we think the
eighty twenty year old we think the
majority of people coming out or are
probably doing something that we're not
interested in so it might be security
search in which case we'd hope you'll be
sympathetic or the chances are you
probably going to be an attacker in
which case we don't care quite likely
but we would at this time at this moment
but it's it's it's a good point okay so
that's pretty much how it works okay now
what you see here is that there's a
perimeter a dotted line perimeter
everything inside there is in Amazon Web
Services everything and for every single
box of forgot to mention the honeypot
here yeah what we do is when we process
a bad request we send you to a honeypot
here so you do get a two or newton if
you're running a script based attack for
certain things then you can knock
yourself out because we're just going to
see traffic but it's gonna sink hole
into that server there but we monitor it
for every single entity in this diagram
it generates a log every single thing
including down here on premise and
they're all drops into ELQ so again
we've got a ton of stuff coming in and
we're able to keep an eye on it so
wrapping up what we're getting so we can
modify what we can ban modify the quest
we can handle them far better teapot and
honeypot ylim we've got an external bot
list that we manage your Ganon might
look perfect but 80/20 rule is we kill
the majority and about we drop dodgy IPS
we look at user agents and we get rid
you can't hit our origins anymore it's a
big win for us
countries considered a threat they're
easy i disallow and afterwards if any
wants to talk more about that come and
grab me because there is some deep there
is a better level in that detail we see
all the HTTP traffic we get free cert
management and we keep our websites up
so spoofing and reap yawns aren't easily
handle but we do look at other things we
look at your request itself so we can
see user agent we can see you actually
TP request and we can handle it we still
do a bit of manual work so white listing
and things like that bad rules can break
raps so we've got a remindful of that
we've no machine learning our AI and it
kind of comes on and off our agenda
currently it's not our agenda we need to
keep up because new threats need new
analysis it's always a game of catch-up
so in conclusion life isn't the sole
version I think I made that point clear
it's part of a broader deeper approach
to security it is as valid as hardening
a server it is as valid as good Network
design it's as well it is secure coding
practices or good secure coding
practices it's a first-class member of
the layer security family so thank you
very much
[Applause]
finally and I'm I'll take questions
afterwards I'm upset bloke on Twitter
you can come and see me I do a lot of
stuff on there I'm a member of a thing
called the beer farmers that might be
worth following me just to find out
about that there is a member of beer
farmers staff in the room head of
security and we're all about security
right and shitposting and my blog is
except bloke calm okay so again thank
you very much your time
[Applause]