thank you so for the last nine years
we've underestimated the impact of a
common class of wonder abilities in PHP
applications hundreds probably thousands
of instances of this issue have been
found we've overlooked a simple behavior
in PHP which exposes them to
exploitation through on serialization my
name salmon one way or another I spend a
lot of my time exploiting web
applications while attacking web
applications so what I tend to do is ask
myself what vonner abilities does this
app have and what's the impact of
exploiting those issues the research I'm
gonna talk about today doesn't have much
impact on the first part of that
question so I'll be talking about
vulnerabilities that you've probably
thought you already knew about but I'll
be giving you a different answer than
you might have expected for what the
impact of exploiting them is so before I
talk about my own research I think it's
really important to say that this is
really just a tiny addition to some
wonderful research done by a man called
Stephan Esther about ten years ago so he
discovered this issue in PHP with on
serialization and so our serialization
is for those of you who don't know
really basically it's basically a
process by which PHP converts internal
objects into a string representation
that can be stored in a database or
passed over the wire and then converted
back to an object in PHP the examples on
the slide are really simple so I've just
given like an integer and a string but
it can deal with much more complicated
objects and what Stefan SR realized was
that there's a technique quite closely
related to return orientated programming
called property orientated programming
whereby you can construct sort of a
malicious objects that if you get
everything right upon being unsterilized
will sort of cause a chain of methods to
be caught and cause something malicious
to happen so as the issue is
additionally understood there's a
function called uncie realized on PHP
and that's called on some data and as I
mentioned basically certain methods are
automatically invoked upon unsee
realization so there's a method called
wakeup which is called whenever an
object is unsee realized and there's
also a method called destruct which is
called whenever an object is destroyed
if we get things just right basically we
can sort of chain together certain
objects so that something nasty happens
if you're not familiar with that issue I
can't encourage you enough to sort of
read Stephanie's research I gave a talk
myself here three years ago I think sort
of covering a lot of the same material
but for the rest of this presentation
you'll just have to accept that
serialization is bad okay so what am I
going to go through today I'm going to
start by talking about something called
stream wrappers which is a functionality
in PHP which basically can be triggered
on any file operation and I'll go
through a bunch of those and we'll end
up focusing in on the what's called the
fast dream wrapper which deals with a
type of archive called a far archive
which is sort of supposed to be the PHP
equivalent of jar archives I'll talk
about something called file planting so
we're going to need to get one of these
archives on to our target system the
easiest way is just to upload one if
we've got that functionality in the app
but there's a couple of other things we
could look at if we can't do that
identifying the type of vulnerabilities
that are affected by this issue then I'm
going to talk about there's a really
nice tool called PHP GGC the GGC is for
generic gadget chains by a guy called
Charles Fong who works for handy onyx I
think and that's sort of why say serial
foe PHP if you're familiar with white so
serial in Java exploitation and he's
kindly given me permission to release a
branch sort of alongside this talk which
uses some of the techniques I'm talking
about to embed some of the payloads that
are already included with that tool in a
in a far archive then I'll go through a
number of case studies talk briefly
about how we could defend against this
issue and then a few things to take away
okay so the first part of this talk is
essentially adventures in going in
reading the PHP manual and I came across
this cartoon which might not make that
much sense at the moment but we'll go
back to it after I've shown you some
stuff from the manual and then it will
hopefully make more sense okay so this
is the page in the PHP manual which
describes Stream wrappers so essentially
it comes with lots of these built in
Stream wrappers and there's a list at
the bottom of the ones which are enabled
by default and they're triggered by all
sorts of different file operations so
opening a file or checking your for file
exists copying a file that kind of thing
these have been used to other stream
wrappers have been used in lots of
different sort of exploit techniques so
you'll hopefully be quite familiar with
the remote stream wrappers which I've
grouped here file HTTP FTP and data data
is not strictly remote but it does
require this setting allow you are LF
open to be true to use it so it sort of
falls neatly into that category so these
are these stream wrappers that
essentially you use to access external
files from PHP so it can turn a local
file include into a remote file included
if you can provide like a HTTP URL it
will go off and grab that file and
include it as code often these are the
things behind server side request
forgery issues so for instance if we've
got a call to file get contents and we
control the argument we can give it an
HTTP or an FTP argument and it will go
off and get that file and finally
they're activated by X X Z so X and our
external entity issues the next stream
wrapper I wanted to talk about is the
PHP stream wrapper so that's often used
for instance in local file included
exploits we can use PHP code on such
that input to grab standard i/o which
will be what we've posted to a page if
we're you know if PHP is running as a as
a web server there's a quite a neat
technique you can use to read the source
code of a file with a local file include
because this stream wrapper includes
some filtering functionality so if we
included a PHP file from another PHP
file it's going to try and run that but
if we want to read the source code we
can base 64 encode that then include it
and then on our end we can basics
defrauding code that and read the source
code Stephan essay used a really neat
sort of variation of this on one of his
early on serialization exploits so he
was able to put together a chain which
would write arbitrary data to a file but
there was a prefix on the file which was
PHP Die which would stop any code after
that from running well what he managed
to do was essentially
base 64 decode everything before it was
written to the file and that sort of
nullifies this header and then he could
prepare his other data to write anything
to the file the next stream wrapper is
glob whenever I come across this I think
it's going to be really useful but it
works differently from the others so you
can for instance call file get contents
glob and then a path and get a listing
of files this is the example from the
manual of how it's used so it's used
with the directory iterator there and
there's a page in the manual that lists
all the operations supported by any
stream wrapper and the glob stream
wrapper literally supports none of them
so there's two stream wrap has left as
they deliver and four which are both
related to archives so if we're looking
to exploit those what we could think
about is if there's issues in the native
code so maybe we could supply sort of a
malicious archive and try and trigger
some memory corruption or something like
that that's going to be quite difficult
to exploit sort of in the presence of
modern mitigations like a SLR and Det
now obviously there's something else
there otherwise I wouldn't be giving
this talk so we'll focus in on the far
wrapper
and within the manual it lists
everything that's in a far archive and
the first thing it lists is quite
interesting so there's something called
a stub and the stub contains PHP code so
immediately as an attacker we think what
can we get it to run that code through
the stream wrapper so I wrote a simple
test program to set the stub to just
echo something out and then to access
the file through the stream wrapper and
unsurprisingly it doesn't trigger that
code and just to sort of confirm that
everything was working as I expected we
can execute that archive and the stub
does get executed now as best as I can
tell essentially that's the only
circumstance in which that code gets run
if we access that file as an executor
not wanting to be desired we move on to
the next element of the file and there's
something called a manifest in all four
archives and if we look at the manual
page which lists what within a manifest
there's something very interesting in
there so we can have metadata in this
archive which is contained in the
manifest which is in the standard
serialized format so sort of again not
expecting it to work but we may as well
try I constructed a simple sort of test
program so we define a class called test
object and we set the metadata to an
instance of this class and then another
test program which again defines this
class but also has a destructor defined
this time so that if the object gets
unsterilized and destroyed it should
trigger this code and we're going to
access a file in the archive and
surprise surprise it actually does work
so if we can put serialized data within
an archive and then access it through
the stream wrapper that will be unsee
realized and if it hadn't been so
obvious you would have done something
like that okay so just to sort of
confirm that everything is working as I
expected I made a couple more test
programs so instead of getting the
contents of a file within that archive
we'll just check whether the file exists
and also we can check whether a file
that clearly doesn't exist exists and
both times the destructor still gets
called so hopefully now that makes a
little bit more sense so from this sort
of obvious attack methodology emerges
with sort of two parts so we had need to
get one of these archives onto the
target and then we need to reference it
through the stream wrapper to cause our
payload to be unsee realized and this is
quite similar to local file include
vulnerabilities so in that case we need
to get a file onto the target and then
include the source code so if you are
familiar with the sort of standard on
serialization issue there's a couple of
differences to be aware of so when a
normal uncie realization issue occurs
the application is very deliberately
uncie realized something and then does
something with it so it's often easy to
access a number of magic methods so not
just this destruct and wake up for
instance there's one called two string
so we could you know try and trigger a
chain that way in this case the
applications not really had any
intention to one serialize anything so
we only have destruct and wake up to
start our chain from and there's a sort
of a quirk that means it within a
destruct chain we've lost the current
paths or anything any file operations we
do within that chain we need to use
absolute birth okay are the I showed you
a lot of copies of this slide with the
different elements of a fire archive the
third element is the file contents which
I hope is obvious the fourth element is
a signature which it says is optional
but by default PHP will only access one
of these archives if it has a valid
signature so that's not optional to us
as an attacker
okay that you've probably seen enough of
the manual now so I'm going to take a
few things out of it and hopefully you
can trust me that this is what the
manual says there's three valid formats
for a fire file sort of the base file
format tar format and zip format for now
I'm going to ignore the zip format so
that might be useful if we were
attacking a system which had some
legitimate functionality which allowed
us to upload a zip file but fahren tar
both have some sort of interesting
flexibilities in their format that could
be exploitable to us so we'll start off
with the base file format I've done has
sort of a little hex dump with all the
different elements in it and if I can
from here the green is the serialized
metadata in the sort of standard format
so that's probably the most interesting
thing to us but what I wanted you to
actually notice is for the stub so that
stub never got run but we can set it to
essentially anything we want as long as
it includes this small segment of code
and that means we can prefix a valid
archive with anything we want we can put
it in the stub and that will be the
start of the file so we can fake a lot
of file formats by simply putting data
into the stub now sometimes that might
not be quite enough for us and there's
some interesting flexibilities in the
tar file format that allow us to do
something else I'm not going to go sort
of into the full details of that file
format but these are sort of the the
important points and these two in
particular so the first 100 bytes of a
tar archive is the file name of the
first file in the r-mo so that's quite
flexible to us we can change that and
we're simply changing the name of the
file and the end of the archive is
marked 1,024 zero bytes and anything
after that is ignored so this is quite
useful for us to sort of make files that
might pose as two different formats so
to just to go through it really simply
here's here's another hex dump this is
at the start of a tar archive what I can
do is change the name of that first file
to what looks like gibberish but if I go
through I said the first two bytes to a
JPEG header the next two bytes say
basically this is a comment within the
JPEG file and the next two bytes to the
length of that comment now we can set
that length to encompass the whole of
the archive and then just carry on a
JPEG file afterwards and because we've
got those 1,024 null bytes the PHP when
it's dealing with the archive will
ignore everything after that and
something dealing with the image will
see the archive essentially as a comment
and everything else is the image so
hopefully I've got one of these in the
distant so this is just a picture of my
cat you're missing some good pictures of
my cat prepared like a song-and-dance
routine
so make sure so HDMI so I meant to
strike finish a PC right back to the
important stuff a picture of my cat if I
change the file name of the picture
might go and open it with an archive
program we can see it's recognized as a
tower
right so it's got this unusually named
fun in it but it's also got all the
elements of a file file which I
mentioned earlier so it's got the stub
and the metadata which is in the
standard PHP serialized format and it's
got the signature which isn't really
sort of human readable but so we can see
that it's essentially a perfect polyglot
so the you know depending on which
application is using it it views it as a
perfectly legitimate sort of file of
that format so I mentioned earlier about
our sort of fall planting so is there
anything beyond just uploading a file to
the target application we can do to get
one on there so there's a couple of
tricks from local file inclusion that we
could use I've referenced them there
so Brett Moore came up with a really
cool technique with PHP Mpho whereby
basically if you upload a file to a PHP
page it gets saved to the temporary
folder and the dollar underscore files
array gets populated and if I'm PHP info
outputs this so it will tell us where
that temporary file is but as soon as
PHP info has finished outputting it will
delete that file but what we can do is
sort of store PHP info by refusing to
receive its output once we've got what
we need and that will cause the fire to
persist for some time Jimmy ran smart
demonstrated that there's basically
really low entropy in the names of these
files on windows so a bit of feedback
I've had after I gave this talk last
week if black cat has made me realise
that one of the things I put up here
isn't really feasible so the session
file stuff you can only trigger this on
a file which has an extension so in
Windows the temporary files will have
the TMP extension but in Linux they
won't and as far as I know in both
session files won't have an extent
you can't trigger this issue on a file
with no extension and then finally up
but sort of mentioned log files there
I've not managed to pull it off but in
theory it's possible it's quite
difficult too we need to know the entire
contents of the file to calculate a
valid signature for whatever we're going
to append on the end of that file or you
know in the middle of it okay so in
terms of identifying the vulnerabilities
that are affected by this it's
essentially all X X E and a number of SS
are F issues on PHP applications I
thought it was worth mentioning that
there's an option which is sometimes
used to protect against exit C which is
the no net option which says no network
because this is dealing only with local
files that doesn't protect against this
if we're looking to sort of detect the
fact that we can use Stream wrappers you
know in a black box way it's much more
preferable to use the FTP wrapper than
the HTTP wrapper because it supports a
lot more operations and I'll demonstrate
that shortly if we've got no way to sort
of connect our band with ourselves we
can try using the file stream wrapper
and observing the behavior of the
application so essentially if it behaves
a certain way with a valid path and we
can chuck file colon slash slash in
front of it then that probably means
that stream wrappers are working ok so
PHP GAC is basically why so serial for
PHP I've just taken all the good bits
and written a couple of lines of code to
basically put the the palos which are
already included with that into a fire
archive using the techniques are
discussed a quick note on the payload so
so to have them work with the demos I'm
doing today I'm doing most of them
against the latest version of PHP and
there's kind of a defense-in-depth
change that's been made so you used to
be able to dynamically call a function
called the sir
which would evaluate as PHP our
strengths but they've prevented you from
doing that now so I'm simply calling a
function called passed
which calls out to a system command and
spits the output out if we're sort of
attacking a hardened system and it has
functions that pass through our exit you
know banned most applications seem to
use this library manager called composer
and that includes a simple function
which wraps include so we could abuse
that to include PHP code from another
file so all the case studies I'm going
to go through today were found with
manual analysis two of them could have
been easily found with this sort of FTP
kernel such techniques I talked about
earlier and they all use just a simple
uploading a file onto the target to
place it there okay so the first one I'm
going to look at is a CMS called typo3
many things to a developer called Oliver
Haider who helped to fix the issue so
the the code path from user input to
where the vulnerability is is fairly
complicated but the the vulnerability is
hopefully fairly clear from here so
where we end up is with file exists
being called on a URL decoded value so
when it's trying to work out what type
of path were giving it it's issues when
it processes links but when it's trying
to work out how to process the but it
does things like check if it's got
colons or slashes in it and says I know
that's a remote file but it does that
before then URL decoding so as long as
we encode for instance the colon we can
trick it into thinking it's dealing with
a local file and it will call file
exists on a path completely under our
control
they say the first thing we need to do
is generate a payload like any sensible
person but lots of pictures of my cat
and my pictures further if at first if I
run PHP did you see - yeah that this
will list the payloads it's not
formatted very nice so I mentioned some
of these are so some of them were two
string payloads so we can't use them you
know with this exploit but what I'm
going to do is so I'm taking as the
input cat one dot jpg I'll output ip3
dot jpg I'm going to use a payload of
brother Loki one and I'm going to try
and run the command do you name - I ok
so that's written into my pictures
directory type it's reader jpg so I'm
running this demo just as admin this CMS
of implements of fine grained access
model and it doesn't come with any
standard roles or anything like that the
functionality I'm abusing would be
accessible to lots of non admin users
[Music]
so I'm going to upload the payload that
I generated earlier and actually what
I'm going to do I'm just going to listen
on port 443 on me so I'm listening on
port 443 on another server and I'm going
to try and trigger the FTP stream
wrapper to sort of demonstrate that
Stream wrappers are being activated so
if I go to any page and add some content
add an image is element that has a link
as long as I encode that colon so that's
connected back to us and we can see that
the FTP stream app has been activated
I can do my poor impression of an FTP
server and we can see that it's trying
to access xxx why why why
so if instead of using the FTP Stream
wrapper we access that payloads through
the faster a mapper
hopefully
[Music]
try again
I thought I was so clever when I fixed
the damage to work not online that's
that's what this turns me right that's
right this is the request
so somewhere down here this be saying
that the link to that far and if we
intercept the response at the top there
and see it's triggered the pilot and
yeah that's the end of that demo there's
not okay so the next step over is in
WordPress and when I first found this
issue so that you know they ultimately
the issue is in PHP but we need to find
vulnerabilities in applications to
exploit it so I found this issue in
WordPress and thought how that'd be a
you know a good one to demonstrate it
and thought they would fix it fairly
quickly you can see when I reported it
and it hasn't been fixed yet so you know
I've ended up feeling that the only
responsible thing is to disclose it as
it is so this is this is my favorite of
the vulnerabilities because it's
slightly more subtle and this is
ultimately where the vulnerability is so
it calculates this variable thumb file
and it ends up calling file exists on it
but the way it calculates this variable
is it takes this value file calculates
the base name of that and it replaces
every occurrence of that with this value
thumb and there's no guarantee that the
base name of the file only occurs once
so what we're going to do is try and get
it to replace the start of the file
rather than just the end so write this
value file comes from this function get
attached file and in most cases that
prepends the applications sort of upload
directory to to the file name but in
certain circumstances it doesn't so if
the file starts with a slash
then it's a Linux absolute path but if
it starts with a single character then a
codon then a forward slash then it's a
Windows absolute part so despite the
fact that we're attacking a Linux system
we're going to give it a file path that
looks like a Windows absolute path and
as you know abused this functionality to
end up replacing the start of the file
name and therefore activating the stream
wrapper in terms of the payload I'm
going to use today until fairly recently
so November 2017 there was a payload
that I presented here three years ago
which went from two string two code
execution they've made some changes
since then and that payload is no longer
valid so we have to try and find another
one WordPress is quite limited in what
classes you can use to construct these
kind of payloads so sort of looking
through the the classes that are there
there's a one that really stands out
which is this requests utility filtered
iterator which is an array iterator so
this essentially backs an array and when
you iterate through an array this is the
code that gets executed and this uses a
property defined for bet so if we
control the object we control this
callback and we can call any function we
want with any argument we want now this
is obviously only triggered by iterating
through the array so we need to find
something else to iterate through the
array I looked around you know both the
classes that are already loaded and
WordPress and a few system classes and
couldn't find anything to do this so the
natural sort of next step is to look if
there's any common plugins that have
anything like this and there's a very
common plug-in for the word commerce and
that includes a class which has a fairly
benign looking destructor because it's
just for closing files but the thing
that it does that's useful for us is it
iterates through one of its properties
so we can use that to trigger the other
part of the payload
let's have a look at this turn now
for this demo I sort of scripted it
because there's quite a lot of you know
grabbing various values from various
places WordPress seems to run horribly
slowly on my computer so apologies so I
was just this is the one case where
WordPress has sort of predefined roles
and stuff like that so it's quite clear
what user we can do this asked if I can
log in the server right so this is the
latest version of WordPress and has the
latest version of WooCommerce installed
on it one of these should be users users
and so I've set up a user called author
which is a member of the earth or Alf so
WordPress goes of anonymous subscribers
authors editors admins so you know this
issue is only exposed to authenticated
users but they're certainly not supposed
to be able to execute code
this should hopefully do everything for
me so the first thing it does is upload
the file is doing it through XML RPC so
the value is base 64 encoded but we can
have a look at that file in here it's
basically got sort of a JPEG header on
it but not much more and then it goes
straight into the stub and has are
serialized payload in the metadata
exception so it'll upload the file
slowly so it's uploaded to file and then
we need to just log in to the normal
user interface to grab a cookie
basically all right
so it's logged in and got his cookies
we're gonna use this one here is the
admin cookie or the you know the backend
cookie so using that cookie it's then
going to access the page to edit the
post that represents the file that we
just uploaded we need to access that
page to get something called the nonce
which we're going to need to do the next
stuff that we need to do so it's
grabbing the value of this non sear and
then it's using that and it's setting
the file name to Zed colon slash said so
when the code that we looked at earlier
replaces the base file it's going to
replace the said at the end but it's
also going to replace the Zed at the
start because the start of the file is
the same as the basepart
but eventually go through so now it's
going to set the thumb value to a fire
path to access the payload that we just
uploaded and now finally when it
triggers the it triggers the thumbnail
functionality through this XML RPC call
to work press get meteor item so
hopefully if I intercept the response to
that down on the bottom we've called you
name - a again we'll see how fast it
sphere
it's just to say you know we can call
any girl my bitch is closer I'll leave
that running in the background okay so
the final case study is in a library
called TC PDF I'm going to exploit it
through CMS could console but really the
important point is this is that this is
in quite a widespread library so as far
as I know this is the standard library
and PHP applications to convert HTML to
PDFs and in quite a simple way of sort
of exposes the issue so in this sort of
standard application scenario there's
some situations where we might be
deliberately given access to the HTML
that's being sent to a PDF but also we
often find we can sort of cross-site
script into some code that's then being
rendered into a PDF and the
vulnerability is like I said quite
straightforward essentially it's it you
know runs a tag handler through all the
tags at the HTML and if it encountered
an image tag it calls this function
image with the source attribute and that
does a few things but you know full
story to a file exists called with with
the value as we supplied it so let's
look at that
so we need to generate a payload again
and try cutting ezc faster this time
[Music]
again the same as the first demo it's a
you wouldn't need to be an admin to
access all this functionality but I
haven't set up a bunch of users with the
various different parameters so the CMS
includes this article functionality and
there's a setting you can have on
articles to allow them to be exported as
PDF which then uses the library so I've
got this article set up I've just got
the contents there's xxx yyy that should
generate PDF latex yyy if I edit the
content of that
so first I'm just going to put an image
tag that literally references the image
with no stream wrapper so I'm just using
a relative path to the image in the code
now if I save this the HTML view of the
article won't work properly because
that's the browser is looking for that
relative path and not finding it
but the PDF asked me did I upload the
image
we try that again
we got a PDF with the image and define
try that so you can see it's still
breaking you know in the browser but if
I put the father in front of this see
even more broken in the browser because
that doesn't understand the file you are
a little if we send it to the PDF
Janerio triggers the failure
okay so in terms of defending against
this issue obviously it would be ideal
to avoid those types of vulnerabilities
altogether but bearing in mind that they
were already nine types of
vulnerabilities and we're still finding
them in applications now that might not
be that realistic sort of IPS is IDS's
antivirus software should be able to
detect this quite easily you know with
signatures and things like that it
doesn't seem possible to disable that
the sort of behavior of that stream
wrapper from the command line or PHP dot
ini' but you could potentially you know
a disable it during compilation
I've spoken to PHP about the issue a
couple of months ago I haven't heard
back but hopefully in the long term as
they will address this issue so what do
I want you to take away from the
presentation more broadly than just PHP
we're seeing a lot of unsee realization
issues in multiple languages and they're
made a lot worse by you know I've said
complexity there but bloat is probably
the right words you know people are
adding libraries to applications and not
worrying about whether they're used
anymore or not not removing them we're
starting to see some libraries implement
sort of defensive codes they're trying
to you know remove behaviors that are
very useful for on serialization
exploits by abusing this streem wrapper
you know we can exploit a number of
different vulnerabilities so xxe yes srf
you know certainly if certain settings
are set so for instance allow URL F open
is set to false on PHP some of these
issues you probably wouldn't even pick
up and you would certainly report them
as very low impact on the pen test now
hopefully you realize they can be used
to trigger code execution and yeah
hopefully I've made it clear sort of
easy ways to identify the issues either
looking at source code or with black box
methods so I've added one slide from the
talk that I gave last week
because a couple of people have pointed
out to me that somebody else discovered
this behavior and used it in a CTF so a
guy called orange side sort of said it
as a CTF challenge I think towards the
end of 2017 you know I think as far as
we're both aware we both just discovered
the same thing independently and and
yeah you know you often find that in
security people have the same ideas
around the same time so that's me all
finished are there any questions anyone
got a question for Sam yep when you were
basically injecting your injection into
the JPEG there's no possibility to
actually insert a reverse shell so you
cannot get a shot back out of it yeah so
what you could do I mentioned about the
the assert stuff so previous to PHP 7.2
it was really easy to with these kind of
an serialization payloads to run
arbitrary PHP code which obviously you
could write a whole reverse shell and
and contain it within that JPEG I
mentioned the composers got a wrapper
for include file so if you were looking
to execute sort of more complicated code
than just running one command what you
could do is embed in that jpay your
whole PHP source file as part of the
archive and then include that with the
sort of composer wrapper function and
then you know you'd be running a whole
whatever you wanted but you reverse
shell would probably be the funny things
yes anyone else know don't give it up
first Sam
you