right okay so a couple of opening
remarks before we get into the main
action of some tracks so welcome to
Manchester those you live here will know
how awesome it is those who are visiting
hopefully we'll find out how awesome is
it it is those who went to beer sighs
last night poppy still shouldn't be here
so go to a quick show of hands who's at
beer sighs last night who was still
there after 12 who was still not after
one anyone they must all still be in bed
it was on there no okay here's a great
night and we'd like to thank all the
presenters who spoke there and
Manchester it's got a rich rich heritage
of IT quite possibly responsible for the
first computer first program um probable
start computer and it's the home of
honcho in who's obviously really great
things for us so if you're in mansions
for a bit longer get yourself to mozzie
you can see the replica of them of baby
and if you go to sack bill parking have
a selfie with her I'm cheering so we can
loosen cos out to the sponsors these are
the people who you need to thank for
financing this whole gig so we're gonna
start with our platinum sponsors
we've got e to e a new sponsor for as
this year strain of platinum so we will
thank them
NCC group spotted us for a whole five
years so we appreciate their dedication
to us and so karma who have previously
been pen testers spotted as them over
the years as well so thanks to you those
guys our girls sponsors at ports we get
10 ml of echo
Netta tude Acuras Trend Micro co-op Nova
coast some of them are supportive those
up over the years and some of the new we
appreciate all of you for helping put
this event on they all have stuns or
most impressed and out there and they've
pretty much all got competitions
challenges and prizes so go and visit
them all go and talk than they've all
got some interesting things to say
they've all
got some great challenges at the end
we'll have a prize-giving with with the
winners of these challenges also
mentioned to our silver sponsors
advanced research managers they that
they're around about so if you can find
them and have a chat with them and then
our after party sponsors MWR so if B
assigns wasn't enough for last night
MWR thrown another party tonight which
lead us on to this if you want to go you
need to go and talk to n WR you need to
get a wristband or you're not getting in
so I'm sure the next break the end of
our stands gonna be very popular so make
sure you go that is in the back of your
program so it tells you where you go and
what you need to do so please read it
one slight change to what's in the
program lunch it's in a different place
to what we expected and to where it's
been previously so wearing this top bit
wearing lecture theatre deep about 27
the other that is the rover the way
there's all the sponsors area lunch is
around the corner or if you're in here
through there we've got so many people
here this year that they can't fit it
into the one atrium so they're moving
into two which is which is great finally
on nearly file this is our fifth year
and we hope it's going to be bigger
better faster stronger more enjoyable
this is the eclectic group who dedicate
time to putting this on they don't get
paid myself Rick there's Matt who's dive
monkey who this pitch was taken last
year he's not dead
and that's not a tribute to him but he
somehow got stuck in Vegas as someone
couldn't make it to Manchester so but
he's here this year he's um doing
something similar in track to there's
dom gaff and lloyd and you'll find those
guys dotted around they're all in green
shirts like this
finally the health and safety bits
there's no fire drills or anything
expected ace if the alarm goes off it's
a real one so follow the signs get out
listen to the venue stuff and we want to
crowd source click keeping this place
clean we have to tie these up at the end
and the longer that takes the the longer
it means were away from the pub so we're
going to get some bags and put them at
the doors and if you've got cups or
rubbish and bringing
when you put it in the box and help us
keep this place tidy finally enjoy your
day learn get involved meet people visit
our sponsors have fun any questions find
somebody who's got a t-shirt like this
or like Dahmer or Gareth and we'll try
and help other than that thank you very
much
okay so onto our first talk hello
everybody
right okay so onto our first oh right
yeah you can take this moment if you'd
like to switch tracks so we'll just give
a moment for anybody to do that so we
have here in track 1
ahmud who's going to be giving us no
view of apt 15 live and kicking and then
we have Joe Gardner in track 2 tricking
binary trees so let's give you a minute
to swap over