good afternoon and welcome to web crack
school web cache poisoning have you ever
been working away and just noticed
something that wasn't quite right maybe
you thought that's weird but rather
complex
I think I'll deal with that later on but
when I have more free time for years web
cache poisoning has been a vulnerability
that people just didn't want to think
about it's existed mostly as a kind of
theoretical vonner ability are more
often used to scare people into patching
things or maybe paying out bounties that
it is actually proven to exist and for
years I lived in fear of web cache
poisoning and it's the tourist
complexity but recently I found myself
in a situation where I had no choice but
to try and discover that actually web
cache poisoning is wonderful so today in
this session I'm going to share with you
practical tools and techniques to detect
explore and exploit web cache poisoning
I don't know we start with the story of
how research came to be because it's
quite right generally but for this one
time I'm gonna make an exception so I
started out about a year ago with a
simple plan and a lot of optimism I
wrote a talk called around minor to find
hidden query parameters i'm idea was I
won this I'll find some cool parameters
and I'll find some cool exploits and
those and I'll give a talk about that
and this started out fairly well I found
some pretty insane parameters on some
websites but
in these parameters in each parameters
over and over again the most interesting
vaguely serious thing I could find was
born old reflected cross-site scripting
which is not very exciting I kind of a
talk on that so I thought well this
hasn't worked out maybe all the core
vulnerabilities are actually hiding in
cookies so I hacked up my code and I
made pram liner also guess cooking it
myself doing that and I found something
that looks incredibly promising spend
about eight hours on that and then grabs
Lily nowhere and had to admit that that
was actually a waste of time as well and
at this stage there was only really one
option left and that was to hack up my
code again and make for a minor also
guess HTTP headers so I set out doing
that I ran that on loads of sites I
found all the sites of all sorts of
crazy headers but once again all those
headers had was a boring old cross-site
scripting and cross-site scripting in
headers is generally regarded as an
exploitable because there's no way for
me to make someone else send some random
funny header across the maintenance to
exploit the only glimmer of hope that
remained at the stage was that maybe I
could trick a cache into saving these
responses and basically turning itself
into an exploit delivery mechanism from
my header based exercise and quite
unexpectedly that actually worked so
first I'm going to talk about what web
cache poisoning is and how you can find
it then I'll have a look at a bunch of
real websites that I was able to catch
poison and also do a live demo in a very
well-known piece of software and after
that I'll talk about how not to get your
cache poisoned and then wrap up and
hopefully take five minutes of questions
why first of all we need a bit of
context this talk practice web cache
poisoning is not about poisoning the
browser caches browsers have built-in
caches these
and from an exploit point of view from a
cache poisoning point of view they're
quite boring I'm not looking at those
also there was a really cool attack on
the old last year called web cache
deception which is about tricking caches
into saving sensitive information
belonging to legitimate users so that
the attacker can access it I'm not going
to talk about that that's a different
attack it should not be confused with
cache poisoning which is about storing
delicious payloads in caches to use the
cache as an exploit delivery mechanism
also in some circumstances you can
poison caches using using response
splitting by ahead of injection and with
malformed requests using request
smuggling these are both core techniques
but they don't work on very many systems
these days as far as I can tell and I'm
not talking about those either finally
and most importantly practical web cache
poisoning is not theoretical everything
every example this entire presentation
has is based on a real system where I've
proven the web cache poisoning works and
often is not even difficult first let's
take a quick look at how caching is
supposed to work here we've got three
users fetching the same resource one
after the other
this was more some might be an image
JavaScript or just some HTML and the
cache sees the first user fetching it
saves a local copy of it and just serves
it up to other users thereby speeding up
the users perception of how fast the
website is working so far so good and
the cache poisoning what we want to do
is send a request to the back-end
application that causes a harmful
response to come back to us and then we
want the cash to save that and serve
their harmful response up to other users
when they're just browsing the
application the first step to achieving
that is to ask the question with those
first three users how does the cash flow
then they're all fetching the same
course it can't be doing the bite by
bite comparison on the whole HTTP
requests that the users are sending
because HTTP requests are full of all
kinds of junk I like the use of agent if
those uses had a different browser the
user agent header would be different
than the caching wouldn't work to
resolve this issue caches have the
concept of cache piece where they say we
only care about certain parts of the
request and we're just going to ignore
the rest so generally they only care
about what makes up the euro so the host
header and the request line and if
anything else is the same
is different they just ignore that it
doesn't matter so this is fine but it
sets us up for the next question which
is what happens if something important
is not included in the cache key so here
we have two requests they're fetching
the same URL but using this language
cookie one of them is trying to fetch it
in English and one is trying to fetch it
in Spanish and that's great that works
absolutely fine until you per cache in
front of this system because the
language cookie probably won't be
included in the cache key and that means
when the English user fetches this white
paper they will end up accidentally
poisoning the cache with the English
version of the white paper and other
users trying to get in other languages
will guess end up with the English
version obviously that in there is just
a nuisance but that's the behavior that
we're going to try to turn to our
advantage in effect anything that's not
part of the cache key is part of the
cache poisoning attacks office
so this is the methodology that we're
going to use to find and exploit web -
poison first of all you have to find an
unpaid input or you probably a HTTP
header or a cookie now fortunately this
step do this manually is a lot of work
but I'm releasing parameter as an open
source tool the works in both the Pro
and free versions of burp suite so
everyone can use that and if you run
that until that to guess headers or
cookies it will do it and it should do a
pretty decent job so that will find you
hopefully some on key inputs once you
found them the next step is just to work
out if you can actually do anything
interesting with them before you can do
is change the language well that's a lot
of him exciting when you're doing these
two steps it's absolutely crucial to
specify a random hash Buster on all your
requests if you don't do this you risk
getting a response from the cache rather
than from the back-end server and if you
get a response from the cache many
unhealed inputs will effectively be
completely invisible to you I think this
behavior is the reason that web cache
poisoning has remained so low-profile
for so many years even though once you
understand it it's not actually very
difficult and it's definitely high
severity so once you've found your
unhidden put you found you can do
something fun with it
the next thing is just a training have
it saved in the cache and served up to
other users now you might find it's
already been saved how are you even
doing anything but if it hasn't it's
probably because the cache is using some
kind of low set saying things like I'm
only gonna cache URLs with a certain
file extension or content type or status
code or something like that
so you'll just need to reverse engineer
what the caching rules up and then find
a page on the site that you can
successfully poison when you're doing
this successful when you're doing that
actual poison injection thing you'll
want to stay static safety parameter
more on that later
so that is all the theory of gas
poisoning now let's take a look at what
happens when we actually apply that to
real websites part of the goal of this
section is just to show you that cache
poisoning actually works and isn't just
some random are but do you think I made
up but I've chosen these specific
examples to show you some of the
challenges that you may run into when
doing the cache poisoning and give you
some ideas as to how to address those
challenges as usual I've exclusively
targeted websites that have bug bounty
programs and all the demos here all the
example sites have fixed the specific
vulnerabilities I'm showing you but the
techniques still work on many many
websites and frameworks and in these
examples I'm exploiting targets using
all of the caching on all of the caches
you can see here and ultimately this
this technique works on all on all
caches out there I don't think there's
any caches that have any way of
preventing cache poisoning so please
don't think that just cuz you're using
some funny cache that's not here for
your safe okay the tip again with we're
gonna have a look at Cerreta com makers
of a popular Linux distribution so the
first thing you'll notice if you look at
their homepage is that it doesn't look
very promising from the cache poisoning
point of view we've got this header that
says please don't cache this response
and also there aren't any headers that
suggest that they are actually using
caching in the first place so it might
be tempting just to not even bother
trying but that would be a mistake
because headers will lighten so if
you've one parameter on this that will
spot if you specify the X for did host
header the value in that header is
reflected inside a URL in the HTML in
the response so that's our unhidden pub
weight what's the most of this attack to
try on this input
probably cross-site scripting right
since it's bloody everywhere so if we
talk about short enough it works we can
break out of this attribute we can break
out the tag and inject some malicious
JavaScript into the spots on the
homepage now by itself this is useless
because we're only exploiting ourselves
here we're fully reliant on the cache to
deliver this payload to our victims so
to see if that's going to happen we're
going to pretend to be a normal user so
we're going to send a request to the
same URL and without any funny headers
just like a normal user would how we're
gonna see if our exploit comes back and
sure enough it does so wait we just got
full control over the home page of
Reddit calm I think wasn't very
difficult right the only thing I need to
draw your attention to here is this safe
equals one parameter that a lighter than
blue this is not part of Viacom this is
a safety parameter that I've manually
specified that means that when we found
this for real lots of Red Hat users
didn't have boxes pop enough so that's
quite important if you're testing
something introduction please forget it
so we've seen headers will lie to you
but they will also tell you useful
things so let's pretend that you're a
malicious person and you want to poison
the real official canonical version of
the homepage and attack all the visitors
to a site you effectively in a race with
the genuine users of that site in order
to get your response cached rather than
having their benign the spots cached so
you need your first request you need
your the quest to be the first to
request to hit the cache after the cache
entry expires and obviously you can just
spam your request lots of times and
you'll probably get there but sometimes
headers will help you out this so here
are we looking at unity3d
they make a well-known comes to game
engine and the X host header is
reflected in site is reflected inside
our script source imports so we've got
cross-site scripting by that but the
interesting thing is these age and max
age head
taken together those tell us the exact
second that this response will expire in
the cash so that tells us the exact
second that we need to send to our
payload to successfully poison so HTTP
headers can give other clues too
so this target I can't name them
unfortunately but if I cover them who
they are I think they're pretty well
known anyway they're using fastly for
their caching and they're reflecting the
export is what I said in a way that has
exorcists just like what Ritter had the
interesting thing is the very user agent
header so that's telling the crash to
add the user agent into the cache key so
that means this request will poison the
cache but it will only poison it for
other people visiting the site with the
same web browser as me and this is both
a blessing and a curse it's a bit of a
headache because if I want to poison the
majority of the visitors to the site
then I'll need to resend resend this
attack with every possible user agent
that a visitor might have but on the
other hand it gives us the chance to be
a bit more creative about who we target
so for example imagine that I happen to
know that the developers of this website
all tend to use Microsoft edge well what
I can do is poison this website for
everyone who is not using edge and then
the developers are going to have a
really difficult time figuring out why
everyone visiting their site is getting
exploited all right so so far we've seen
three websites and they've all been
poisoned using basic reflected
cross-site scripting but life is not
always that easy I hear we're gonna look
at a US government website they actually
patched this at the day before by
presentation which was in the US which
was slightly worrying but it is badged
so here
exported host is being reflected inside
this data so we actually but we can't
just break out that actually and get XSS
because it's been encoded and what we
need to do is figure out what this
attribute is actually for so in order to
do that I set up matching replace for
burps week to add this exported host
header to all my traffic and then I just
browse the website and Y found was when
I loaded certain pages on the site my
browser would send a request to the
calibrator server trying to fetch some
kind of internationalization data from
it
so using this cache poisoning I can make
visitors to date or gov fetch
internationalization data from website
let's have a look at what the state is
supposed to be it's meant to be a
mapping of English phrases into the same
phrase in other languages and the
translated phrase is then just
concatenate it straight into the HTML so
what I can do is tell everyone use my
internationalization file and then in
that file on my server I'm going to
translate English phrases into
cross-site scripting exploits and then
whenever you load a page that has shown
more on it
my injected exploit or fight this
pattern of something where you trick
someone into loading JSON from your
website and then serve them up serve
back malicious JSON in order to get
Exorcist is one that I've seen over and
over when doing cache poisoning
now after that exploit I forgot to
delete the head of injection rule in
book so book just kept injecting this
header into all of my traffic and a few
days later when going when I was about
to close down book I noticed something
really weird this request had hit the
clout waiter server it due to this
header but it didn't seem to be coming
from data.gov in fact it was quite a
mystery where it was coming from because
I had this a lowercase origin null
header and after some investigation it
turned out to come from a core Firefox
feature
so Firefox has this system called
Mozilla shield which is for kind of
forcibly and silently installing
extensions in the background for
research and marketing purposes this is
turned on by default in Firefox you
might have actually heard of it because
it hit the news late last year when
Mozilla decided to install a mr. robot
extension on millions of computers
worldwide and some people got upset so
anyway so yeah if you're you if you're
running Firefox when you open up Firefox
and like periodically every 30 minutes
it sends a polling request that looks
like what you can see here and this is
fetching a list of URLs and one of these
URLs points to a list of recipes which
basically specifying what Firefox
shouldn't stop and what happened was
Burke had injected this exported host
header and that had overridden the URLs
being returned to me and then Firefox
had fetched the recipe list from my
website and sure enough this site was
using nginx with caching and didn't have
that in the cache key so the end was
always I can actually make every Firefox
installation on the planet connect him
what his site for this list of recipes
which was quite exciting so so Mozilla
to their credit was smart enough to sign
these recipes so what I couldn't do was
just make a malicious extension and
install that 150 million computers in
one go but there were various other
things that I could still do so I could
replay any old recipes that they'd ever
use any extension they'd ever installed
by this system I could just force that
on every Firefox world right and so if I
knew of an extension with a known
vulnerability in it I could just force
that non vulnerability on everybody also
I could force the Missis a robot
extension on everyone which would be
hilarious also there were unsigned
versions of all of these recipes which
were used by Firefox but were used by
Mozilla's back-end infrastructure
related to the system for developing
recipes so potentially using that I
could have got a foothold in the
infrastructure gained access to the
signing key and then got my 50 million
powers a botnet I imported this to them
and they patched it really quite quickly
so another reoccurring theme in cache
poisoning is that we'll see something
that the first clue looks completely
useless like this here on this redacted
site which is a well-known computer game
the exported host header the value
former is reflected inside the domain
attribute of the cookie by itself as far
as I know that's pretty much useless
also there's another unhidden book the
exported scheme header if we set it to
anything other than
HTTPS causes a redirect to that domain
over HTTPS
once again by itself uses but if we send
both of these headers at the same time
suddenly we've got a redirect to a
website of our choice so we can convert
because this is happening at the server
we can do this to any any response on
the entire application ISO on this
specific site I can veto back post
requests in order to steal CCF tokens
and I could also once again redirect a
JSON fetch to make them fetch some some
malicious that JSON from my site and get
Dom XSS now so far we've exploited loads
of sites fundamentally because they use
headers to create your votes some
systems go beyond that and they use
headers for internal routing so on good
fire calm their website is hosted with
HubSpot and HubSpot trusts the exported
server header to specify which client
you're connecting to now we can't
directly exploit this with cross-site
scripting because it's encoded what we
need to do is go to HubSpot comm
register our loading site on HubSpot put
a malicious HTML on that site because
they let us and then specify my domain
when I'm accessing go to Viacom which so
that gets our malicious HTML coming back
and then CloudFlare will help me save
that and serve that up so using this we
could take full control over go TOCOM
and any page on anyone else using
HubSpot now i reported this to go ty who
passed it on to HubSpot who responded to
the issue by a permanent in banning my
IP address which wasn't very polite but
I did check back later on by passing the
baton and they have patched it too so if
you're using card spot I think you'll
probably okay
okay this one's my second favorite
attack partly because I'm exploiting the
security company because they used their
own security product on their website so
here below CloudFlare comm is hosted
with ghost and ghost are doing something
with the exported post tenet if you
specify it we just get this meat
Oviraptor / Fable so it looks a little
like what we just saw on HubSpot but if
we try the technique the worked on
HubSpot and register ourselves with
ghost it doesn't work we get the correct
response after a mysterious ten seconds
wait but I never figured out the cause
off in order to successfully exploit
this we need to hit a different part in
ghost stuck so what we need to do is
register ghost and specify a custom
domain name white wife top party and
also and then in the exported host
header put our ghost subdomain so this
is a domain that they issue all of their
clients with and that will trigger a we
dive XY domain and that comes from a
different part of their HTTP stack and
as a result we can over write any
response with the redirect to our domain
so here we're kind of halfway to an
exploit this is great but we need this
response to get cached and on this site
it was configured to already cache
responses with a certain file extensions
so I could read over JPEGs and images
and suchlike and basically inject my
images into other people's blocks which
is pretty cool
it's not really that serious what we
want to do is hijack to JavaScript
import right and JavaScript responses
were getting cached but the redirect the
ghost was issuing used HTTP rather than
HTTP and that meant that browsers mixed
content protection or kick in and block
this video rect
completely preventing the exploit from
working and the same thing happen with
CSS
this proved out to be a really
challenging problem I spent ages trying
to find out a way to bypass it and ages
for trying to find a way to make this
protocol use HTTPS instead and I ended
up even considering contacting ghost and
just asking them to change this to hate
it fierce there was a minor ethical
issues with that plan so instead I
decided to try and crowdsource a
solution I have this hitting game called
hacksaw and I put a level and hacksaw
that replicated the problem that I'd run
into and then I said there's no known
solution to this level and if you find
it I'll split the bounty with you 50/50
and that led to have a great community
response followed by - or some solutions
the first one or someone found in Safari
if the website you'll be directing to is
in safaris strict Transport Security
cash in the video met will get upgraded
to HTTPS before the mixed content block
happens so that will work also latest
sound and presented here a couple of
hours ago found there on edge you can
issue a 302 redirect over HTTP and as
long as that's going into any HTTP URL
there just mix content protection or
just spectacularly fail that that's a
vulnerability niche
so Microsoft might want to fix that at
some point yes so the end result is if
you go to any good ghost posted blog
like blog cocktail for their calm in
Safari your edge I could execute
arbitrary JavaScript and if you go there
in any other browser I can hijack images
and track you that way a list okay if
things start to get more difficult
though so here we can only poison this
open this og URL meta property we can't
break out so we have to find out what
it's for Oh et stands for Open Graph so
the point of this property is to specify
what happens when someone shares this
page on Facebook by the by
clicking like a share page share button
on this page or just by pasting the URL
and Facebook or Twitter or other social
media whatever so we can kind of
partially hijack shares with this also
in order to get this response cached I
had to specify this cookie yeah the
session ID for some reason and I had to
fetch a specific page on the site but I
had the right caching headers in the
spots but even having done all of this
when I tried to share the page it wasn't
getting hijacked and this turned out to
me because they were using cloud flare
and cloud flare has a lot of caches and
I was poisoning Akash near the UK
somewhere and Facebook was hitting a
cache in Atlanta so I googled cheap VPS
servers in Atlanta and I got one and I
did the poisoning from there and sure
enough that worked so this is a video I
had to redact it quite a lot you say
you've been oh definitely use your
imagination but basically we've got a
website well-known computer game you
press the share button it ends up
sharing my site I've got full control
over what happens then amusingly a
facebook also caches this for spots so
when I report this vulnerability first
they've gotta fix the vulnerability and
then they've got to clear they've got
approach their CloudFlare cache but even
that even after doing that likes on that
page is still being hijacked because
they just have to wait for facebook's
cache to expire as well so it's quite a
persistent
kind of attack now that was great but
obviously hiring a VPS is a bit of a
headache if we want to do that every
time we want to poison a specific cache
so I decided to investigate whether we
really needed to do that but now cloud
flür have a fantastic feature where if
you access CDN cgi slash trace on any
cloud for Everest insight you get this
kind of trace page which has some
metadata including this Colo line which
tells you which cache you've hit
and so I did was I'm a little Bosch
one-liner
because I don't know how to our
multi-line scripts and it's since on the
quest it sends a request to my target
website like with their host header to
access this trace page and it routes
that request through every single public
type of ipv4 address the CloudFlare half
so it sends it like a few hundred
thousand times maybe and the end result
is there I list of which IP addresses I
should have ripped my payloads to to
poison which geographic regions and
basically you can you can use this kind
of two technique on any other caching
provider in general I you don't need a
VPS as long as you're willing to put in
the F of doing a bit recon first all
right at this point we've seen many
different attacks almost all using some
kind of host overwrite I found others
using other we live each one off headers
like bucket translate and path
underscore info but what I want to
introduce you to is my favorite header
which is the X original euro header this
header is designed to overwrite the URL
in the request line and the reason I
love it is because it's supported by so
many services now just by itself even
without caching being involved this
header is quite useful so for example on
unities website they were my favorite
targets in this presentation if we
access slash admin we get blocked by by
a reverse proxy like varnish having a
rule that says block slash admin but if
we put slash admin in the X original URL
header we can get access to it and I
initially found this header because some
of my targets were running Drupal and so
I reported this sir tuple and their
security guys like I can't find any
mention of this header in our code base
but I can't confirm it works and it
turned out that
Drupal 8 is using Symphony and Symphony
supports this header but Symphony
actually only sports its header because
they inherited it from Zent
so if you were using if you've got a PHP
application and it's built on anything
built on Zend or symphony or drupal then
you probably support the center and
there's a lot of service so what can we
do with this header but yeah what one
other thing I it works with with X
original URL there's also a header
called XV right URL it does exactly the
same thing so let's say our target has
an external cache like every target I've
shown you so far what we can do with
this header is effectively the place any
response with the response to any other
path so on triple and symphony and so on
the query string in the X original URL
header is ignored but their path is used
so we can't do anything fancy with the
query string but we can basically swap
the paths around so after saying this
request if you try and access the unity
for education page you get the unity for
gambling page which looks like this so
that's kind of entertaining and we kill
this needing more harmful things like we
can swap the change password page for
the logout page so you can't change a
password anymore
but it's really proved how dangerous
this header is I need a case study and
for that case study I'm gonna use
vanilla triple because there's a lot of
people out there so rupal also has an
internal cache this has turned on by
default and this cache is aware of the
ex original URL header so we can't do
anything with the parts but my colleague
Gareth Hays was helping me out on this
and he noticed something wasn't quite
right
and eventually figured out that Drupal
is eternal cache has a bug in how it
handles this header if
thinks that the query string in this
header is used when actually it's
ignored so this gives us something
there's kind of the opposite of the bug
that we just saw we can replace the
response to any query string with any
other query stream basically if you're
on a page I can't change what page
you're on by can over override the query
string you've got with anything else
so after sending this you just do a
search for kittens you get a search
results what's not and that by itself is
really quite powerful but for generic
mass exploitation of Drupal sites we
need one more ingredient
and luckily triple provides so tuple has
this a slightly crazy feature on any
response
that's a redirect tuple lets you specify
this destination parameter which
overrides the distillation of the
redirect and they try and do some
filtering on this to make sure that it's
not a cross origin it mean I met to stop
themselves from having an open meadow
makes but we can bypass it fairly easily
so by yourself this is rubbish white
assistant open me direct but this is the
last ingredient that we need to start
properly exploiting triple cites so I'm
gonna look at two Drupal sites first of
all business top interests calm here on
the sun pages on their site they import
JavaScript via of redirect so what we
can do is we can use the internal clash
poison to change the parameters on that
JavaScript import request and what we're
gonna do is inject this destination
parameter and the end result is anyone
who goes to that page ends up importing
JavaScript from my website so I get
control over their account so that's
cool but we have a line on the fact that
business doc Pinterest comm happens to
be exploiting happens to be importing
JavaScript via me right
and we can do better than that so in
every attack that we've seen so far
we've poisoned the cache in order to
exploit the end user like the victim has
been the end user that way but on almost
all the Drupal installations you've
actually got two caches because you've
got the internal cache that's turned off
by default and then you've got an
external cache like varnish or or
CloudFlare that basically everyone uses
because the triples really sluggish you
don't use it so what we can do is we can
make we can do two attacks and the
victim of the first attacked is going to
be the other cache so the first request
is gonna try and poison the internal
cache so we we just find any video
vector spots on the entire site and then
we poison the internal cache by adding
this parameter to change it to a
redirect to our website by yourself
that's not that much good but then we're
gonna shift that poison into the
external cache so we're gonna send a
request that has the same exit visional
URL value so I'll fetch that was
malicious poisoned response from the
internal cache and it will put it in the
external cash at a URL of our choice so
using this we can poison any of the
spawns from the application with a
redirects to our site so for example on
unit 1 stored or unity comm the main
thing you're gonna do is by unity or get
the free version and so if you I can
make it so that if you go on there and
you click download installer your your
browse has got your own unity calm but
the Installer is malware coming from my
website so let's have a quick live demo
which is hoping the work so here we have
stocked report I haven't changed
anything all I've done is put a cache in
front of this and the first thing I'll
show you is that if we just take a
request to the site I if you run the
latest version of burp it will hopefully
it's not working oh scanner spawns to
cut yeah
it's maybe gonna find it maybe not we're
also for a minor okay for my - no still
let's see if it works I swear I five
minutes ago okay right here we are
oh no no no it's still me twice now okay
I'm gonna go with the top minor okay
we're gonna sell it to guess headus wait
come on okay okay well Berbers work so
purpose yes they both like so Berbers
fouled
this is vulnerable to web cache
poisoning and also the Ramlila
has found the x and x me right no
available heather and it's showing you
the evidence for it and it's also found
x original URL and it's even parameter
has found that it can do cache poisoning
parameter will try a new cache poisoning
it's pretty fitting this i don't rely on
that but it does work sometimes okay so
now we're gonna try and basically redo
that attack manually on this site so
here this response is just OB direct
white nothing interesting there so now
I'm gonna send a request it's gonna hit
the same code path because of this X
original URL header but I've added this
destination parameter so the goal of
this request is the poison the internal
cache at that key with avi direct so if
I send this yeah great we've got this
video X to our server coming back and
then for the next step we want to shift
that to the external cash so we're going
to leave this header exactly the same so
that we get the same response back
thanks to the poisoned internal cash but
we've changed that so what you can see
here is the yellow that we want to
poison so if I send this we should get
the same response great so now the
external cash it's hopefully poisoned
finally I'm gonna just resend I'm gonna
send that request without any headers to
confirm that it's been poisoned and that
appears to be working great
so now if I go on Firefox and I so I'm
just on the normal home page if I press
login then wind up on course with the
labs on a fake malicious version of the
login page kill I'm glad about what
Thanks there was a coordinated security
release for that the week before last
so you want to install that probably
yeah yeah great defense
sorry good for the most effective
defense against cache poisoning isn't
not in use caching and then the way not
a sound like fax cool advice but I think
the thing is some people might end up
with caching kind of by accident for
example they might start using
CloudFlare because they want cloud
flares DDoS protection because it is
very cheap
and but caching is turned on by default
so why would say is if you're not using
caching just turn it off anyway
regardless of whether you're
intentionally using caching in his spare
mind some people may be accessing your
site for corporate proxies or airports
in such like even summarize peas and
those ISPs will be doing Kashi so in
general you're going to want to try and
mitigate cache poisoning
regardless of whether you have to the
intention here using cash now to do that
you need to avoid indeed input basically
don't intentionally take inputs from
HTTP headers and cookies wherever
possible also the where the many
frameworks will just add in random
headers unexpectedly so you'll probably
want to audit your application with
burps down and we'll program miner in
order to try and find out if any weird
headers have been snuck in there if you
find them ideally just completely
disable support for them that's the best
fix if you can't do that for some reason
you could potentially configure your
cache layer if it exists just to strip
these headers out or if you really need
these then you could add them into the
cache key which will effectively remove
them from the cache poisoning attack
service
there's a bunch of resources online
there's an online white paper there's
also I believe one or two printed copies
of this on the Manchester stand at the
moment also power and wine is open
source you can grab the source code for
that online and install it via the BAP
Store and I've also built a cache
poisoning challenge into my hacking game
so you can have a shot at that to see if
he's really got to grips with this stuff
I hopefully have some fun okay three key
things to take away are the header based
input is inherently dangerous frameworks
can hide lethal functionality and just
because they're open-source and have
millions of users doesn't mean they're
secure and cache poisoning is not
theoretical I'm going to take five
minutes of questions now if you have any
more after that just chuck me an email
we'll come and talk to me out the back
don't forget to follow me on Twitter
thank you for listening
thanks James has anyone got any
questions yep do most cutting prop C's
honor the very response header to to set
their cash I would say no I've only seen
I've only noticed the one that does it
how's that definitely doesn't have you
seen this irony of the WordPress plugins
because there's a lot of question
plug-ins for WordPress for WordPress
look at work Billy I'm sure so I found
this via this research showed up like
hundreds and hundreds of sites and I
only had time to actually look at half
there's there's a lot there's loved
stuff out there that's still vulnerable
another interesting Avenue Avenue would
be to look at so I exploited Firefox's
update functionality basically right and
there's a lot of software out there that
has update functionality if you could do
cache poisoning on WordPress is update
that would think these funny yeah no
more for James will give them one more
round of applause please