[Music]
hi everyone I'm Nathan welcome
so I actually working on me called gusto
so it's funny that no total raise at all
there's a company based in the UK called
gusto and we often get confused like
there are different tweets the cooking
subscription companies so oftentimes we
get tweets talking about how we didn't
deliver their food and we have to like
say no actually we do payroll software
I've been doing something very very
different it's fascinating to watch our
tweets come in and it was yeah so our
company called gusto
we do payroll benefits for small and
medium-sized businesses I was the first
application security engineer there and
for a moment of time I was also the only
member of the security team someone
start out with a little story initially
a lot of my co-workers and friends
thought that it was super cool that I
was the only one on the security team
they thought that I had a ton of power
and I could do whatever I want again as
the only member of the team but spoiler
alert I had no power then when they knew
that I was only member they wanted to
know more about it they were curious to
see what it actually entailed what my
day they would look like again as the
only team member on the team then as I
started to go over some of the
responsibilities and what my did they
looked like they realize oh wow this is
not fun this is a lot of work and maybe
some of you have been in the same place
where you feel overwhelmed understaffed
and honestly you just don't know what to
do so to sum it up that actually
represented a lot of my day today and
what I thought like in that I had a lot
of things stacked against me so I want
to take a step back
kind of go over what things I had to
face and what challenges had against me
so first off I was outnumbered by the
engineers from one to I think it was a
hundred ish at that time so as you can
imagine a lot of them and only one of me
and next gussto is a startup so there
are ever-changing priorities what is
important one quarter is probably not
important the next quarter a lot of
things going on trying to iterate and
move fast and then finally I was also in
individual contributor so I had no one
reporting to me didn't have any fancy
c-level title and I was just someone
pretty small and far down on the whole
Shane come in so the fixed input was my
time I only had a certain number of
hours in a day and for those who know me
I like to sleep like a lot I think like
eight nine ten hours so probably
unhealthy amount but again I wasn't
willing to give up my sleep so how could
I balance my work at gusto getting sleep
and everything else that I wanted to do
just as a millennial living in San
Francisco and I wanted to maximize my
output so how could I do that and let's
go ahead and dive into this so first off
I had several technical strategies that
I use and I want to go over with you I
think a lot of you are quite familiar
with the idea of shifting left correct
nothing new here but then there's one
term that Tania who was the keynote
speaker has been advocating for is the
idea of pushing left and this is the
concept of moving security as far left
as possible so even before
features are developed during the
ideation phase we're going to get
security involved at the very very
beginning so why was pushing or shifting
left so important for me and this is
because once the features the code has
been written some features have been
shipped then effectively there's nothing
I can do I'm not gonna be the one to
block the release and say no you can't
do this and all the code review it's
humanly impossible so I need to find a
way to insert myself at the very very
beginning to get at the very forefront
and see what the engineers and the rest
of the company wanted to ship and
produce so it's honest easy as ABC
always be coding so if you haven't seen
Dino daizo V's blackhat keynote this
past year he had an amazing talk where
he advocated that modern-day security
teams are most effective when they write
code and in fact they should be writing
code so I'm coming from a software
engineering background and I can confirm
that writing code is really really
powerful and during my time like in the
very beginning I often wrote code to
build security features for our teams so
whether it was trying to strengthen our
2fa flow or trying to improve some reset
password flow that in itself was
powerful because I had control over that
I was able to see what was going on with
the code in regards to the security and
then when reports would come in through
our bug bounty or append test reports
oftentimes I would go myself in the
codebase and create the poor class
themselves so one thing that may be a
bit controversial but is that I gained
instant respect from a lot of engineers
instead of being able to just like hand
it off and say hey go and fix this for
me by me showing them that I can hang
with you that I can write code that in
itself gained instant credibility and I
will say that even when I went over the
code reviews or the different design doc
reviews or flows by being able to point
out maybe some tiny flaw in the os/2
implementation then they were able to
trust me
that much more so by gaining that much
respect then I was able to create that
rapport with the engineering team so the
next thing I want over is the gap still
talking about software is that we should
be automating anything that's repeatable
and deterministic so think about it it
doesn't make sense
try and do something that machine
software can do faster more reliably and
that will always be correct so one
sample of this at gusto is a tool that
we use called danger it's a fantastic
open-source tool where I'm able to write
custom rules to look for basically
whatever I want and one example is if
someone touches a configuration file in
this case brakeman that it'll
automatically alert me so if they try to
be sneaky and add in an exception to
bypass one of the things that I've built
in I have like eyes on them so or if
they try to use a vulnerable function or
things that maybe seem kind of
suspicious then I'll be alerted as well
and this means that I won't have to go
through every single pull request I
won't have to go through every single
config file that I've set up
I have eyes basically on the entire code
base of the entire system so I can just
keep up on my email and then I have eyes
in nearly every place
it's actually leads well to my next
point is static code analysis so it's
useful because again this is not me
going through every single pull requests
this is a tool that I had implemented
and put into our CICU pipeline so
continuous integration can use
development as soon as a developer
pushes a pull request it'll run a whole
suite of tests and then one of them is
break man and and that's the tool of
choice that we use at ISO so by a show
of hands how many of you have used
Brickman or familiar with it so one and
a half haha cool so for those you who
are familiar Justin Collins over there
audience he is the author of brick man
and he's actually joining gusto which is
super super cool and this is cool but
also terrifying so super cool because I
got to learn from him and pick his brain
on just a whole bunch of static code
analysis things security things also
terrifying because now he can see how I
built up the thing the toilet he built
and how it integrated it so hopefully he
won't judge me too much depending on how
I did it but overall yet thrilled that
he's joining us though
and then also one thing I wanted to know
on this as well is that this provided
instant feedback for the engineers so as
soon as the pull request was created
they were not blocked on me to go over
their code to review to give it a thumbs
up so if this pass and then assuming the
other criteria were met as well they had
the full liberty to merge the code and
we get without me blocking them I was
able to empower them through this
mechanism which i think is pretty cool
and the next thing I want to go over
is vulnerable dependency management so
very much along the same lines of the
previous few slides about software and
code this is the idea just repeating
myself is that I don't need to have eyes
on every single package every single
config this is the perfect way for the
engineers themselves to get instant
feedback if a package is outdated
they're going to receive a ping that
their team needs to update their their
gem their package or whatever else
they're using in this thing and then
github has a tool built-in called
dependable they bought it about a year
ago or so and that has been fantastic
because it creates pull requests
automatically it gets assigned to them
to the respective engineering teams and
then it's been a lifesaver saving a lot
of time on my end trying to coordinate
different things so now I want to move a
little bit further right down the whole
chain of development so pen testing I
think we have some mixed feelings on
this some people love it some people
don't love it
but whatever your stance is I think we
can probably all agree that it's not
available in in certain situations so at
a minimum I would say that you should be
running pen tests at least once ear
maybe even more if your budget allows
for it and so there are quite a few wins
that you get from this so from the first
one is that it's an easy compliance win
so when let's say your company wants to
create a partnership with a different
company a different partner and then
they want to send you a massive 28 page
rapport talking about your security
posture time on personal experience
those things are no fun to fill out and
if you have had to fill out some of
those things they suck so by being able
to pass along a pen test and
demonstrating your security posture to
these potential partners it saves you a
ton of time and then also give you some
baseline of how secure your product or
your application actually is and then
another thing which may not be super
obvious is that you can gather a lot of
data points around your security posture
so from year to year as you want to see
how much more secure getting we can see
how many critical high medium bones you
get and start to graph and benchmark
them and as we all know the execs upper
management love data and here are hard
data points where it's often difficult
at times to get our data for security
this is an easy one here's a few vendors
that we've had good good success with at
gusto and next again similar Japan
testing but I would argue different and
important as well is to run a bug bounty
program so this is something that I took
a lot of pride in trying to set up
trying to get their interests from the
different research community to have
them proactively hack on our gusto
platform so one of the benefits of this
is that I have hundreds of different
eyes perspectives methodologies active
hacking their platform 24/7 so I myself
also love to get down and dirty
fire up burp suite and start to poke
around hack stuff but again that's
probably not the best use of my time
again as the single engineer on a team
when there are a lot of other higher
as much as I would love to poke around
and try to find the next big fun
vulnerability I'm gonna leave it to
others who have it as their sole
dedicated mission to find
vulnerabilities on our platform again so
this is a continuously monitored thing
so I don't have to worry button goes
even night and the wake up inbox if I
see some things I just great that's work
that I didn't have to do was able to
empower and pay others to do for me so
those were some of the technical ones
now I want to move into the cultural
side I think this is often overlooked in
our industry and something that I'm
practically trying to change again with
this talk right here and even as a talk
with different friends colleagues and
different people in this industry I want
to advocate that sure it's great you can
be as technical as smart as you want to
be but if you don't have people on your
side then you're powerless so with that
being said these were some of the
departments that I partner with closely
at custom so this is just a snapshot of
what or who I partner with but again
this may look very different your
company I just want to go over some of
the reasons why I chose these six teams
to closely partner with so the first one
is IT and I like to think of them as
frontline security so when something
goes wrong on the employees computer
they oftentimes go to the IT Help Desk
or the IT team or engineer asking why
can i login what's this do a push what's
this random thing showing up they get a
ton of the requests from the everyday
employee so by working with them and
having ITP actually past law anything
that may be suspicious
up to security that was a huge win so
the IT team was quite a bit larger than
just myself so that again was skilling
myself procced that compliance this was
an interesting team because we are in an
industry with a lot of regulations with
what data we hold with PII and pH I then
we're constantly running into different
situations where we need to ensure that
we're fully compliant with the different
rules to effectively yeah not be in
trouble so I had to work closely with
compliance to ensure everything that we
were doing from a security engineering
standpoint was approved and was given
the thumbs up by them and the next group
of individuals which may not be a media
at first obvious efforts is are the
product managers so these are the group
of individuals that are coming up with
the features at the very very beginning
at the ideation phase so when they want
to create this brand new feature for
this may be fancy new login it's not the
engineering team that's coming up with
it it's the PM's that are coming up with
it so by me having a close partnership
with them by me having my name in their
whole document where they fill it out
and they know that if anything touches
securely remotely so anything with
authorization such as management
authentication and great new API
anything that may touch or jeopardize
our security then they are already aware
and are happy to loop me in which was a
huge win you're not having to go through
and comb through every single part of
sheet that they create
I get pinged on only the relevant ones
and then legal I think there is a super
common goal for both of us is to
mitigate and reduce risk for the company
so by me partnering with legal by me
chatting with them and
them having that tight-knit partnership
then I have eyes on a whole bunch of
other things that I wouldn't get access
to normally the next one hope is pretty
obvious are the developers or the
engineering team and then these are the
folks who are writing the code who are
building all the features that are and
customers use so by having them trust me
and to build that rapport that's been
invaluable having them know that hey I'm
here for you my goal is to not block you
it's not slowed you down but I want to
empower you so one thing that awesome I
could tell the engineers is actually how
many of you are familiar with Rainbow
Road and Mario Kart there we go okay I
got a few more hands this time so I like
to say that you all like the engineers
are the drivers on the Rainbow Road that
they're going as fast as possible it's a
really tricky situation they want to
just go fast fast fast but then I'm the
ones putting guardrails on the track so
that if they bump into it they can't
fall off that they're going to still
ship features as fast as possible but
I'm going to place these girls for them
do it as fast and securely as possible
and that's honestly my job so the
guardrails dome down
they just keep them in their own lane
and keep them safe and finally
infrastructure if your ec2 instance
already is not configured properly then
you have much bigger problems than some
tiny XSS vulnerability so having a close
partnership with infrastructure knowing
that they have your back from what
you're trying to secure in the web app
that like the whole platform and the
base is already secured upon that should
give you a great peace of mind knowing
that the base image is up-to-date and
all the bones have been patched and you
can slowly focus on the layer seven and
six and down is you can leave to them
so how many of you have seen this image
okay got some more hands there too so
oftentimes I feel like when people ask
us how are we doing a very common
response is fine good okay and I'm gonna
advocate that this is absolutely not the
right response that we should be saying
as security professionals that we should
not be saying that yes life is okay life
is going life is great and in fact I
don't think we're being truthful when we
say that because as all of you probably
have seen that again we have a lot of
work to do a lot of changing priorities
and trying to balance a thousand
different things so I'm trying to
advocate that we be more authentic with
the different engineers the different
teams people that we interact with so be
open and showed them the pen test
reports show them the bug money reports
show them things that that might be
broken
I know it's may be a little bit scary to
be vulnerable to be transparent but from
what I've seen from my experience is
that once you have them on your team
once they're pro security that is so
powerful is that they actively want to
help because I don't think there's
anyone who actively wants to not do
security maybe it's not a top of their
mind but once they realize that what
they're working towards is for the
greater good company I think they're
just all and they want to do it once you
get them to buy into your mission and
vision of holistic security
the next thing I'll talk about is to be
accessible so be open and be willing to
help others and there are a few reasons
for this so the first one is just the
right thing to do oftentimes security
might be seen as this scary amorphous
random team off in the corner but
honestly there's no reason why security
shouldn't be like a friendly presence
and the company people should know who
security is and what the team does and
secondly it's because whether you like
to admit or not you're most likely as in
you will need to ask a favor from
different teams so through this again as
the only engineer I oftentimes would eat
lunch with nearly every team so it
bounced from table a table trying to
make friends to chat with them to see
how their day was how the weekend was
and sure it was a lot of effort to get
around every single team every single
person but yeah and now they knew my
face they knew who I was in office so
that in itself was pretty powerful I
want to share another story with you so
there was one member of our legal team
who had an issue with their 2fa on their
personal account I think it was for some
banking app and they were having some
issues trying to set up to scan the QR
code to set up the token and then this
person asked me for help again so very
outside of my job responsibilities so
this is their personal 2fa on a banking
app but they just didn't know how to do
it and they want some help so I sat down
things spend 10 minutes figured out some
of the things and they were super
grateful and as it turned out I think
supposed six months later I need a huge
huge favor I had to push a contract
through for one of our vendors and then
I
like past the deadline a little bit from
like that's the way that they give I was
like walking to them like can I ask you
a big favor and they were actually super
open to it because I built the initial
rapport with them so they had no issue
with kind of fast tracking me which yeah
I was eternally grateful for so odd to
think of what we do in a sense are
different transactions as kind of like
working like a bank so when we are
accessible when we tried to help others
maybe not at responsibility we are
effectively making a lot of deposits in
the goodwill bank and then more often
times than not we're gonna need to take
a chunk out and to withdraw some
goodwill and to ask for a big favor so
by putting in the work at the beginning
then you have a whole bunch of favors
ready to go and that itself helped me a
time
so next thing I want to go over is
security education for this portion it
was important again to get my face out
to the rest of the company as a single
person with a company that's
ever-growing hiring a ton of people how
could I maximize my single time or my
single person and my time to a whole
audience so the answer to that question
was to do several types of training so
when and when employees were on boarded
to join us so they go through a about 30
to 45 minute security onboarding
training where we go over some basic
basic things like fishing - if a
password managers or just like simple
things that we might be for in ta'dibi
able to spend some time advocating for
security at the very forefront like when
they join the company
that in itself they already knew what to
do and more importantly they knew who to
contact so it was a ping you know slack
or - email security act and then to add
on top of that we also had a specific
engineering training that I built for
the engineers joining us so so then this
was a super security 101 high level
overview of what we do or what I do for
the engineering teams in terms of going
over different tools we use in our
pipelines different vulnerabilities that
we've seen in the past how we develop
software security through our SDLC and
just like really basic things so my goal
through this was not to teach them how
to mitigate every single type of XSS
vulnerability under the Sun or how to
build some crazy to a faith flow but
rather it was for me to put a name to a
face so again when I
had to work with them on a polar class
or to build a feature that that was not
the first time that I was interacting
with them so I think as a lot of you
have a ton of meetings on your calendars
every single day I myself also have
booked basically every day with meetings
and I can honestly say that doing the
security 101 training was one of my
probably the only meeting every two
weeks that I really did enjoy so getting
a chance to work with the engineers to
meet them even more importantly
especially we have a few different
offices across the country to know that
hey I'm here for you let me know what I
can do to work with and support you in
any way possible
and then one more thing wanted to add on
to this is that we occasionally ran and
do run phishing campaigns and the
purpose of this is to in no way shame
anyone who does click on a link or
submit some information rather it's to
show them that hey security is the most
importance and that people are actually
out there trying to attack and vicious
it's the idea of creating awareness and
showing that even though you may be some
new grad who just started on a sales
team you may seem unimportant but in
fact that you have a ton of power
yourself with what systems you have
access to and that we have to be
collectively conscious of security as an
entire company so that has had a few
different wins that worked out really
well
so what happens when all these things go
right what happens when you
exponentially skill yourself through
technical and cultural strategies and
what does success look like so now I
want to share a few screenshots of
different interactions I've had with
various colleagues at work so what this
first one right here is one of my
favorite engineers as you can see he
found access to a system that people
definitely should not have had access to
and indeed this was quite concerning so
somehow his engineer's stumbled upon it
found it I sent it over to me this was a
fantastic we find something that would
not have poked into because this was a
system that this engineer uses every
single day and had a lot of film the
familiarity with and he indeed has found
numerous other fun little things like
that
the next screenshot shows someone in our
in a non engineering function so this
person also has sent quite a few emails
over to myself and has shown that they
indeed do care a lot about security and
phishing emails and even though they are
no way a technical security person
they're very much aware of implications
of phishing given all the trainings
given the different interactions I've
had so by knowing that I have eyes on
emails that I don't even receive makes
it a lot easier to sleep at night
knowing that the company does indeed
care about security and what things they
do receive the inbox and to be cautious
of what actions
they can and can't take and this might
be one of my favorite interactions had
with one of the engineers here so I come
in to work I'm 24 and I'm not sure how
it isn't here in Austin but a lot of the
culture in San Francisco said people
rolling like 10:00 10:30 11:00 so I
think this made like a 10:30 ish day for
me and seeing this message was both sad
and that we did have some reports come
in but also made me really really happy
because this engineer took the time to
proactively go through the port's that
came in I gave them access to the hacker
1 platform to look through the different
reports and the best part of this story
is that I had to pull requests ready to
go in the afternoon with fixes for this
so even though I didn't get a chance to
actually go through the reports to get
them through it didn't go through all
details this engineer took security to
Hart and proactively reached out about
this and pushed out to fixes so if I
don't know like what more I could ask
for after partnering with the
engineering team getting them to love
and truly care about security I mean
that's what I have been trying to do for
the past couple of years and this was a
culmination of a lot of efforts paying
off and I felt really really good
so we went over a lot of things and as
you can see it's not easy to get a team
get the entire company to care about
security and what it actually looks like
in an everyday
changing environment but I think by
using a mix of technical and cultural
strategies that it's honestly doable to
evoke a security engine company to get
engineers and non engineers like to
rally together and build something
special so just to summarize some of the
things the first one is to always be
coding ABC to have static code analysis
to work through vulnerability dependency
management to have pen testing going on
to have also run a bug bunny program and
then from a cultural side is to build
key relationships with different teams
that you want to partner with it's
important to be accessible to be open to
be transparent and then to have security
education for all the different
engineers and and non engineers alike at
your company so now I want to go back to
one of my first slides so despite being
outnumbered
despite have ever-changing priorities
and despite just being an Icee without a
fancy title
I was pretty powerful and I did a lot of
things and like not to brag but this is
to show you that if you're in a similar
role that it very much is doable and
obviously these changes don't happen
overnight it took a lot of work trying
to partner it with the different
cross-functional teams to get them to
bind this whole idea a mission of
working
for working together to create a more
secure environment definitely not easy
but when you see all this work as I
showed you in some of the screen shots
from slack it's a fantastic feeling
again so if any of you like are in a
similar position don't give it hope like
it definitely is possible through a lot
of work to get your team members the
other company to truly care about
security so as I started to wrap up I
like to thank flea and Ricky for helping
me with this presentation they were
fantastic in editing and supporting me
with the whole process and both are
honestly amazing individuals I've had a
chance to work with and learn from them
and they've working a company that cares
a lot security seems interesting to work
with people like Justin then guusto is
hiring for all security roles so if
interested you should definitely hit me
up and we'll chat afterwards and I like
to leave you with one last quote to
summarize this entire thing is that
relying solely on a title to influence
is a problem that positional power does
not solve but rather true power comes
from a desire to solve to understand and
solve challenges with software and
people so I assume in your startup so
you must have lots of remote employees
right so what's right do you have lots
of remote employees we do have a few of
them but I'd say 95% are based in our
own office I wasn't gonna ask you
mentioned about building key
relationship with different Garmin yeah
if four more employees how was it going
how we wanted to do it you know
absolutely a great question so I think
fortunately for us the people who were
remote often came into the office about
once a quarter or so so then I would
actively reach out to them if I knew
that they were coming into office just
to catch up and
say hi to keep some eyes that have a new
remote engineers or whoever was coming
in and I know that's not always the case
for different companies that they are
sometimes fully remote but I was yet in
great position where they did come and
once a quarter and I would take the time
just to go for a walk or grab a coffee
with them and that's how I build
relationship by keeping eyes on who was
coming into the office who was remote
what keeps you up at night a lot of
things what do you think about at night
back then or now those are probably two
different answers yeah yeah so early on
was I would say some of the human
components of security so the phishing
emails by them installing super sketchy
random packages on the computer
different extensions that gave them full
access to the entire Dom to do whatever
they wanted with whatever data and I
don't know if I fully realize again at
the very beginning how important was to
communicate and evangelize security so
the very very beginning I was like heads
down on the technical portion trying to
build all the software that I could but
taking a step back and realizing that
the biggest risks were coming with the
human side and not that I wanted to get
ashame them in any way but just show
them that hey I'm here for you and let
me see how I can actually put up those
guardrails for you
so if they were to install some sketchy
package that I would put up the
guardrails but again to know in the best
case to not install in the first place
yeah so it's kind of working with the
human side which can the other night in
the beginning there we go
hi-hi earlier you mentioned that you use
cultural tools to address you know
security concerns and am I am interested
in in these cultural tools that I don't
know you can provide me example provide
us examples as a human human factor it's
in my opinion quite relevant in security
yeah yeah yes I think if I said cultural
tool I apologize I meant more of the
cultural strategies I don't know if
there are tools per se that can make
force someone to do something again even
if I did have power like as a CSO or
director of security I can't force you
to really do anything other than like I
guess firing you so it's more about
trying to build these soft skills and
working with the different individuals
to show that security is not maybe like
has been seen in the past as a blocker
as attempting to slow people down that
was I would say is the biggest tool in a
sense is to remove that barrier by
showing that there's an open clear
channel of communication between whoever
wants to chat with me or the security
team okay on behalf of last con Nathan
we'd like to present you with a token of
appreciation awesome so thank you you're
welcome
thanks so much
[Applause]
you