[Music]
so yeah welcome to the talk thanks for
joining in the session it's been great
for the last two days lots of talks on
Deficit carbs you know purple teams I I
really love all of the sessions I'm a
brick I mean I am a big fan of you know
dev cyclop culture so I really loved all
of the sessions before we start this I
want to kick off with an analogy right
so imagine you are tasked with saving
titanically so I'm sure all of you would
agree you will not be writing a strong
email to not to the iceberg or the
captain to you know the list of
recommendations to stop it right you
would probably want to create a secure
path for the ship to sail through and
and you know stop bad things from
happening that's really kind of lessons
of this talk to create a secure you know
security paved pathway then you have the
publication's accepting file uploads so
that a little bit about myself I know he
has said eight years that was written a
couple of years back but I have been
doing software development mostly
developing security products and over
the past few years focused on product
security I really like building things I
know a lot of people like breaking
things but I like building stuff and I
really like to invent and you could see
a lot of inventions there I believe in
once inventions are core to kind of help
cyber take take it to the next level
I've heard earlier career attempts I
tried playing soccer didn't go well
but I'm not complaining I really like
this carrier I'm very passionate about
InfoSec and that's one of the reasons I
kind of go around the globe
talking conferences and contributing
awaken to the community for the agenda
today we are going to talk about the
current trends in you know fight based
attacks and then just to set the stage
I'm gonna talk about different malware
processing techniques what they are and
then we will take a look at some of the
recent attacks to kind of give an idea
of made the threat vector shard and then
I'll go and to talk about the
architecture of file upload how you can
design a secure pathway and just a bit
of the introduction on the topic right
I just want to convey that this is an
independent research and this is this
talk will not be you know targeted at
any vendor it's a vendor neutral talk
and the mileage can vary in your
organization so I'm going to talk about
different techniques different
architecture and about scalability but
you should take it with a pinch of salt
this is just descriptive approach I'm
going to propose it's not a prescriptive
approach so I'd like you to take it of
that on a disclaimer before I go on just
so I keep my legal team happy this is
nothing related to whatever I do it
Ouiser the current version or the future
so please take it that way all right so
let's jump into a file based attack
trans right so if you look at this chart
this is from the virus on data breach
report so in 2016 if you look at the web
based attacks it was about like think
about 15% and it has jumped or maybe 17
and has jumped 6% from 2018 so what it
means is attackers are trying to send
malware through where earlier the most
popular
you know delivery method was email but
it's shifting rapidly and also if you
see on the right office doc is becoming
a very popular way to deliver a tomorrow
man
so let's kind of zoom in on that and
talk about what it means right so when
you think about malware typically you
think of an executable that comes into
your environment it gets downloaded in
your system and then it runs a set of
programs maybe talks to the
command-and-control server sends your
data out what nothing but the new trend
is file a Smallville so you have a file
like a word dot which carries a set of
binary instructions and it executes as
part of your known application let's say
PowerShell right so you trust that
program there is no executable or binary
but then it gets executed as a file s
attack so let's talk about different
Marvell processing techniques that are
available to us right before we deep
dive into the tags I will talk about
what the techniques we know of so far so
first surface analysis this is really
kind of taking a piece of file and
understanding what it is right it
doesn't go into the details on what it
does or you know other details on how it
gets executed it doesn't really involve
a lot of CPU cycle per se so you just
take in a fight look at it to say hey
this is Fred for example it doesn't tell
you anything other than that but it's
quite useful because you detect the file
type and if somebody is poofing right
for example if Fred if it's not release
Fred and if it's shut coming in as Fred
you cannot detect and reject that so you
don't want to take a dot exe file
masqueraded as dot doc spawn so that's
what this really does
and then the traditional antivirus scan
I'm sure you're all aware of this
technique there are quite a few
you know drawbacks with the way AV
engines work there are a lot of you know
pasta fall obviously that's that's the
reason we use it but if you think about
the completeness of detection meaning
how many files an AV engine would detect
it kind of varies across different AV
engines and it's always an opinion of
what the product things and it's also a
correlation to the kind of signatures
the product has and a lot of time the AV
engines are not good at classifying the
malware so they can detect and say hey
it looks to be malicious I don't know
which family this belongs to right so so
that is kind of the drawback but there
is a lot of you know good features that
come with it especially if you run
multiple AV engines together it's going
to increase the completeness ratio and
the correctness ratio because now you
instead of having opinion from one
expert you're going to have opinions
from you know different experts on the
same issue or the same file for example
and then we go into dynamic or runtime
analysis so this is where a lot of CPU
cycles goes into right so to run a file
and then see how it behaves and then
kind of extract all the indicators of
compromise and then conclude on whether
the file is malicious or not so it is
typically run in a sandbox so you give a
file to a sandbox of VM and it executes
the file looks at a bunch of indicators
to decide if it's looking to be
malicious or not it's fairly accurate
but then it takes a lot of time to set
up imagine if you have the above
accepting you know PDF
etc you need to have a VM that is set up
with Adobe Microsoft Word for example
and then run the file and also there are
certain nuances to it right if you have
a PDF reader version 19.2 that may not
give you an idea of how it will execute
in a different version and also if you
run it in a PDF Reader versus a writer
the results are going to be different
and sometimes the system doesn't just
work it'll probably be a you know a
pop-up that comes up and you have a
screenshot of the pop-up but there is no
analysis that runs so due to all these
factors it's very time-consuming to set
up and it's also very time consuming to
run a file and get a result and and when
you get a result that comes with a
caveat because you now run a file and
then you are generating result based on
the run of that file and that result can
in turn have a model where if somebody
is writing a sophisticated malware the
results can in turn have infected inputs
so the next technique is a packer
so attackers usually like to obfuscate
the payload so one common way is to pack
the file so that the analysis doesn't
detect it so malware think of it as a
software program like zip or gzip so
somebody can package it and send it and
if you don't answer the file you're
going to lose a lot of analysis metrics
so a good way to kind of analyze packed
files would be the first unpack it and
to unpack it you need a different I mean
define several factors right how many
recursions if you're taking in a zip
file how many recursions do you want to
allow for example what are the file
sizes of the files that could be inside
the packed file so you would always want
and
right if you're taking any fact software
and the next technique is static
analysis I'm talking about this after
unpacking because that's kind of the
primary factor before you could do this
analysis what it does is it looks at the
PE sections or the file sections to see
which sections can attribute to
indicator of compromise so if you take a
PDF file it's going to have a header
it's going to have a section name so
based on these factors you'll be able to
generate a value that could you know
contribute to your IOC factors reverse
engineering this is a complicated topic
and it's very hard to automate write
reverse engineering is very specialized
somebody has to manually look at the run
reverse engineer and look at the code so
I'm not going to go into a lot of
details there are tools available like
ID Pro which you can use to you know do
a first run
you know D compiler but a lot of the
sophisticated malware's are going to
just you know bypass it because they
know ID Pro and it's very easy to
associate something that is not detected
by you know your D compiler
okay so the last technique this is kind
of very recent and modern there are a
lot of engines available that classified
based on a machine learning based
algorithm there are primarily two
different types of classifiers one
before executing a file before the
execution you can do a static analysis
of the file and figure out whether the
file falls into a ml classifier that
that is designed for a malware and the
second is on the execution right you let
the file run detonate it in a V
and then see how the file behaves and
then get the label sort of the behavior
and then classify it with AML classifier
for a detection again this is very
premature right so there are lots of
false positive and there is going to be
a lead time in training the classifiers
to be effective okay I know that's a lot
of content so I'm gonna pause and ask a
question right so we've looked at
different analysis techniques how reason
do you think the analysis have to be if
it has to be useful any any quick
comments thoughts it's 30 minutes
fair enough or if it's coming after two
days 24 hours yeah yeah I'll let we'll
come back to that I'm gonna talk about a
few attacks and then we'll see whether
24 hours really makes sense so yeah
let's talk about the tax rate I want to
talk about three different attacks so
this you probably recognize Carla
Johnson right from Avengers yeah so this
is an image file so in this attack
somebody uploaded image of Scarlett
Johnson and it got stored in the
database Postgres sequel and that
database had a Metasploit module enabled
so you cannot see it in the image but
there is a binary code somewhere near
the left half right so basically what
happened is when the payload came in and
when it got stored the Metasploit module
and behind that there is Linux and there
is a software called data duplicator in
the next that actually extracted some of
the binary components and made a call to
a command-and-control server to download
another image which then led to data
exfiltration so the data from the
readable
is gone so what happened in this case
was it actually evaded all of the AV
scans that would typically run on end
points or the server's right so that's
one example now let's take this image
file and run it through widest total see
what what it gives us
so if you see at the top so this is
virustotal result from you know 67
different engines that look for
malicious URL right only one engine out
of 67 detected it's malicious and and
it's at that time stamp right it it
would have changed over time there are
better signatures available in each of
these engines so it will marry and if
you look at every engine detection for
that image file only three engines had a
signature that detected a variant or a
mutex of that file so order 58 only
three Avery engines are affected so what
it really tells us is av engines are
effective as long as you have the
signatures for it right so even though
we threw a lot of av engines at it it's
probably going to fail depending on the
vector we are looking at
okay so the next one I don't know how
many of you know there is a library
called imagemagick this is a open source
library that you can include in your web
app and it allows someone to edit and
create form
you know files on the fly within the web
app so this had a vulnerability in 2016
there was a very popular attack called
image tragic and what they did was there
a bunch of CVS but if you look at it
they have image files like PNG file that
they run through image magic and that
those files had an exploit which will
then impact the underlying server so
they executed a PowerShell script did a
remote command injection into the server
etc so this is again to highlight a
vulnerability through a file upload that
happens at the library right it's at
application level where something is
exploited so the third example this is
kind of very you know popular in the
sense that Java scripts right they they
could be embedded in PDF and that's one
of the popular mechanisms or vehicles by
which attackers like to deliver the
payload so if you have a web app you do
the baseline and you make sure you're
clearing the OWASP top 10 attacks but
there are cases where web apps can have
exercise for example right maybe some
someone did a good change and they do
not check something this type of attack
can leverage that vulnerability in the
application layer so if you have a web
app that is vulnerable to exercise if
you deliver a PDF or the JavaScript with
that can basically reflect and you know
you execute that JavaScript and attack
that web application
I think that that's pretty much it so
and this is the main point I want to
convey today right you know if you look
at all the attacks we have looked at
endpoint protection or AV scanning at
the server level is not really very
helpful and if you look at the
traditional protection mechanisms we
have all of them made a focus on you
know server based AV detection or laptop
based endpoint detection if a file comes
through right so what do we do about it
so I think having a submission based
automated analysis system it's a good
way to take the files in when I say
submission based analysis system it is
pre execution so when the file is in the
flight and it's coming through the web
application you have this automated
analysis system that does a check on the
file and then accepts only you know
benign files and we'll talk about
different set of controls that that come
into play right in this sort of a
submission based system so before we
architect I think the first step would
be to define the goals so what do we
want this submission based analysis
system to do and at the core we have to
define how much it needs to tell us
right so if someone is coming in but
there are B okay to kind of say hey this
file or this person is checked and we
know Chuck is either bad or good it
starts efficient or do we want to know
what is this wait what is is height and
what is DNA result for example right so
that is the first step you would want to
design or this I mean define based on
the environment that you have and the
other controls you have in the
environment and also when we start
designing solution as
important to look at the customer we
cannot just block PDFs because they have
malicious URLs or embedded scripts so
it's really important to ask questions
to the web applications on who the users
are who upload the file what are the
formats what are the valid business file
formats the application will need and
also talk about the file size and the
traffic that the application really
wants and depending on that you would
then decide what enforcement can be done
on the application side can you enforce
you know a particular file type
whitelist or can you enforce a
synchronous versus synchronous calls
what will the user do if a file is being
scanned for example right and then you
can also think about risky file types
and see whether the application really
needs them or is there a way to you know
kind of blacklist those type of files
okay so putting it together right so
these are kind of the eight steps in a
sequence that I think would help secure
a file upload so one the first thing
before something's accepted we would
want to authenticate and authorize the
user right we thought without
authorizing we don't want some anyone in
the internet to all our files to be
uploaded and then number two there
should be a set of validation or
enforcement based on the surface
analysis of the file that ties back into
the business case of the application to
say you know this application can accept
XY and z but not other type of files and
the third always and you know every time
unpack the file for analysis and analyze
after unpacking it and number four
utilize the AV engines though they have
drawbacks it helps you know get that
first opinion on whether that file is
bad or not
and it's good to have a mixture of Av
engines a mixture of technology that
does it based on signature versus
machine learning based algorithms number
five sanitize the file meaning if there
is a Java Script in a PDF
there is no reason an application needs
javascript in opinions right so sanitize
those malicious you know embedded
objects in the file number six randomize
the file name anything that the user
sends in is untrusted it's not going to
be easy always but you could start with
something like a hash of the file name
for example and then return a generic
error we don't want to say it without
attacker here you uploaded a PDF and
three of my engines detected it's bad
when you keep it straight and say you
know this file is not accepted by the
system and the number eight is very
important whatever the submission based
analysis system does is a primary check
you would want a secondary check where
you try add you have your reverse
engineering and malware analysis team
look at the file D compile it and do the
second level of analysis and
investigation now to the scaling part so
if you tie tie this back to the question
I had initially write how recent should
the analysis results be for us to a
lower file so if you look at the web
applications today a lot of time access
files through api's there are web
services where somebody could write a
bot to upload a file and typically there
are no restrictions right somebody could
upload you know 30 files in a second for
example so there is high frequency of
file uploads and the submission based on
ours needs to churn out and result in a
defined time right again that could
depend on what your application flow is
if you want to have a synchronous flow
allow your user or client to do some
thing else while this is working there
are popular email systems that do that
right Gmail for example allows the user
to do something else while the file is
being uploaded so that's something it
could think about so to her point 24
hours could probably mean or make sense
to you depending on your use case but
what's harder is handling this high
frequency right I mean you have 86,400
seconds in a day and let's say you're
getting 100k files that's what one file
that you'll have to churn out from the
analysis every second right and if you
have 10 minutes for the scan time it's
going to mean 10 minutes is 600 seconds
so it means that you would probably want
to have 600 VMs working in parallel to
churn out 100k files in one second which
is which is huge right so we have to
think about whether it makes sense to
scale horizontally or be scale
vertically have more CPU cores for
example have processing in different
servers so that it doesn't fail and also
we have to think about queue management
how do you place the files in the queue
when it comes through whether it will be
based on the file size the priority and
whatnot so these are just the
considerations that you want to take
there is no one-size-fits-all like I
said but this would be the top
considerations as you try to scale this
automated analysis system and make it
work for your business use case so
streaming is very hard to analyze why do
you need the entire file so you would
have to stream it to a central location
Club it together as a file and then send
that file for analysis otherwise we are
looking at bits and pieces of
information and the submission on our
system or molar processing technique is
probably going to miss a different
factor
yeah I think irrespective of whether
this HTTP or other protocols like SFTP
right we need to look at what are the
different delivery methods and then try
to see the file as a whole and then
analyze the file as a whole before
accepting it so it would apply for SFTP
so it depends on the user base right so
if it's an internet facing application
and if it's allowing a user to sign up
based on email basically anyone in the
world can do that right if you have your
gmail account he can sign in create
account
he still authenticated an authorized
user but the risk level is higher so
you'd want to define who the user base
is and then put in a set of controls
based on that and and that could vary
depending on okay I'm allowing only one
file to be uploaded by this user for the
entire lifecycle rain or if he is based
out of a very risky region of the world
I would want to scan a file so it
actually varies right right yeah that's
that's perfect example right in the
container world you can spin up on
demand run a file and then throw it away
if you don't want that's that's going to
be very useful I think that'll be very
useful but you want to keep in mind that
spinning up that VM and running that
analysis will probably take you say 10
minutes you want to see how the users
would react or what the users would do
in that meantime all right I'm going to
be here if you want to talk to or you
know a chat about anything otherwise
thanks for taking the time it was good
talking to
you