[Music]
all right good morning
they said I wear a lot of hats and most
of these hats will actually work weave
themselves into this talk and hopefully
to a coherent narrative I'm vice
president of security research and
intelligence at a small security company
called threat stop I am working on my
PhD in machine learning or informatics
specifically but machine learning at the
University of Illinois as well as
lecturing and teaching which I've done
for the last seven years and I produce
open sourced threat feeds so I have an
agenda things that are covered to
hopefully go from the abstract to
hopefully some general and specific
takeaways that I think will hopefully be
useful for you as we talk about ethics
technology and data in some aspects of
security of really of data that we are
creating through web apps and mobile
apps and some of the technologies that
we may all be involved in of which the
implications of that data creation I
don't think are entirely well understood
or well thought through and how we
secure it is also important but the
start is you know I often you know get
asked I'm sure you know by others right
why haven't you fixed security yet like
why is hacking still a thing Oh wasp has
been around for about 15 years 10 years
right and sequel injections still happen
right why haven't these problems been
fixed and a lot of these problems have
real implications not just in terms of
data theft but in real world physical
risks a different part of my research
involves surveillance malware used by
the Chinese government on ethnic
minorities and Tibet's and all the
various groups inside PRC that you can
name that are targeted by the Chinese
government who are using mobile phones
and vulnerabilities and mobile phones to
track and ultimately put people in
concentration camps you know we haven't
really fixed those problems in terms to
how to figure out how to use securely a
technology securely but as a way to kind
of hopefully wake you up a little bit
what is the earliest documented case
that anybody in this room of can
think of a social engineering attack yes
Genesis chapter 3 right and no matter
what you happen to believe about that
book right not to make a religious point
but that pen was put to paper for that
book thirty four hundred years ago and
they were talking about social
engineering back then the point is all
of this stuff has been around in essence
as part of the human culture since the
beginning right after Adam and Eve what
did the next generation did you know
Cain and Abel right you know we went to
straight fratricide right in generation
two all of these problems that we face
in cybersecurity are really human
problems that we're trying to use
technology to solve why do people commit
crime the only thing that technology has
allowed them to do criminals is to
commit crime on an unprecedented scale
in over larger distances people have
been doing credit card and cheque fraud
ever since there were credit cards and
checks until the internet you just had
to physically expose yourself now you
can do it from Russia so we can't fix it
because we can't fix you know we can't
fix human beings I don't know how to if
I did I you know I don't know what it
would be do you know what I do with that
I do a lot of teaching right of
in University and community college
environments and and higher ed right we
do okay teaching people concepts but we
don't do a well very well job of
teaching curiosity which is really what
is important for security and fixing
things and finding vulnerabilities so
here is a thought exercise what is the
neatest IOT embedded whatever gadget
that somebody in this room owns surely
somebody has some kind of you know smart
meter or something sir and Alexa all
right everybody knows what an Alexa is
now can I have a volunteer somebody who
has an idea of how to kill somebody with
an Alexa
that's a good point right if Alexis tied
into a smart home right disrupting
people's emergency communications right
that's a great example right
we had awkward silence but all of us in
this room are not normal right we're
dealing with misuses of Technology right
so we have biases but when I walk into a
college classroom and go through this
exercise with my students right and most
of my students are Chinese because of my
university they don't know how to parse
the question I'm asking all right if
you've ever seen like what it looks like
for a human mind to blue screen that's
usually the response that I get it's
actually and I couple years ago I
interviewed students for just a you know
a student job wore a nice suit whatever
and just put on a Burger King crown
didn't say anything about it the Asian
students could not parse what was
happening right I just had to take it
off because they were just completely
lost but this is not how normal people
think of technology right we do because
this is the world where and this is the
problem we're here to solve but when
people make these technologies they're
thinking oh with an Alexa right now I
can order stuff you know and just use my
voice I have an act on Alexa in my
office because I'll never have it in my
home and all it does is play Pandora I
really don't know what people get out of
this device because we're making
technology to do things to solve
problems people really don't have to
make money but nobody's as these
technologies are created saying hey what
are the consequences of that what data
is being collected how can that data be
accessed and misused the misuse of data
is particularly important to me
right informatics is a science of
information right specifically I do
machine learning a couple of weeks ago I
did my PhD call exam you know where I've
got my committee they're asking me a
bunch of questions and one of the
questions was this one right rough I
don't know if it's an accurate quote but
the essence of the question is right in
the context of the Hong Kong protests
how would you address adversarial
machine learning and facial recognition
so I don't know if people know if those
terms are but adversarial machine learn
is basically subset of machine learning
of how you do machine learning safely
off of untrusted inputs it's an academic
gussied up way of saying input
validation but we use just various image
transforms to make a3 be processed as a4
or whatever so how do you solve that
problem and in Hong Kong we have a live
world way of doing it in academic
literature we've never there's never
been an attack in the real world until
Hong Kong on image recognition systems
their facial recognition systems we've
used Gaussian transforms and all this
nice pretty little math but ultimately
right if you think about it we're still
solving the same problem that was
written about 23 years ago and smashing
the stack with for fun and profit which
is basically buffer overflows is how do
you do computing safely on untrusted
inputs and we're really not anywhere
farther on solving that problem we have
lots of complexity some things we put on
top of it but that's also the problem of
web security right sequel injection XSS
you know all the web vulnerabilities you
can think ultimately come down to input
validation problems or untrusted inputs
so how bad is facial recognition or
litter image recognition what number is
on the slide no it's it's it actually is
3 we're not there yet
soon decaf slow down
there's what's called an M NIST data set
right which is just a pretty acronym
which it doesn't really matter what the
acronym stands for
it's just handwritten numerals of zero
through nine and getting a system a
computer to recognize what number it is
three four seven right the number of
classes is fairly simple so simple right
zero through nine nothing overly
complicated how accurate do you think
machine learning is on untrusted inputs
to recognize that correctly
percentage-wise wow you're all dark and
cynical it's not that bad for this data
set right there's this exercise right of
white box and black box testing of
machine learning algorithms and we get
up to two ninety six percent off of
artificially generated adversarial
examples right think about that one in
twenty five chance that a three gets
recognized as a seven and everybody is
throwing machine learning and AI into
everything and we can't figure out
Decimus just one decimal what could go
wrong right oh I don't know the biggest
use case I can think of of image
recognition is self-driving cars right a
car has to figure out what's around it
well you've only got a one a twenty five
chance of hey that pedestrian is really
a crosswalk oops
right we're creating technology that
that really the biggest loss is an
information it's life and safety
we're the best we can do is maybe
ninety-six percent to go back to our
example right image recognition or
facial recognition Hong Kong protests
I'm sure some of you seen the news there
use of laser pointers pointed at the
cameras people are putting faces they
got this little hologram stuff they put
on in front of their face all sorts of
real-world examples to mess with image
recognition systems right but assuming
you know that's done in in ways that the
system can handle it's a one or twenty
five chance that you throw the wrong
person in a concentration camp
that's the stakes of some of the systems
that we're creating today right and some
of those I mean Facebook is doing image
recognition
I don't think Facebook is feeding into
what's going on in Hong Kong yet but
that's the world we live in right and
we're adopting this technology anyway my
entire career in information security is
consisted of me saying hey you know what
this is a bad idea and you ought not to
do that
and people doing it anyway so hey the
great news is it's good training for
Parenthood right I'm about to have
teenagers who are gonna ignore me so I
spend most of my time as a father and
I'm gonna say this to my ten-year-old
son what you know when daddy says what
happens when you play stupid games you
win stupid prizes right that's about 12
years of fatherhood from you know to be
fair you know the toddler years I don't
say that too much they're just toddlers
but you get the point people are doing
things they ought not to be doing and
it's just not how we deal with data
that's changing right how we're dealing
with media and lots of other problems
right you know here's something I just
saw yesterday is that Newsweek uh you
know Newsweek was an established and
reputable media company back in the day
and this was a reporter saying you know
what our compensation was tied directly
to clicks which radically skews how we
do news I don't know what the political
balance of this room is and what you
feel about the media but the way
everything is reported now is basically
an influence operation I had the
influences clicks and whatever to make
you outraged or angry so you keep
clicking and keep reading but we are
radically changing all sorts of things
downstream because of social media and
lights right because now the number of
likes you have and the number of
retweets you have is a leaderboard that
now people are getting compensated on
which radically skews things but as you
know as people who've done security for
a while anything that is algorithmically
generated can and will be of algorithmic
ly manipulated that's life right what's
SEO or blackhat SEO
it's just manipulating search engines
because if you're not on the first page
of a Google search you just don't matter
so this is an entire industry we've
created to manipulate algorithms just in
search engines but to go back to my
point right what would you do in the
context of the Hong Kong protests to fix
the machine learning and facial
recognition I don't know if it was a
response my thesis committee was looking
for but my answer is I wouldn't I'm not
going to create technology that's going
to enable people to be thrown in prison
because they don't like what their
government is doing period full stop
kicked me out of my ph.d program if you
don't like right now the benefit is no
you clap right as if this is a
courageous stand it's really not right I
don't need the PhD kick me out whatever
right I'm getting the PhD to troll my
university it's being powered by
contempt and rage right you know yeah
I'm a lecturer they pay me 12,500 I
think we all know the median salary of
what we do in this room twelve five is
like my beer money it's money I can
spend that I don't have to tell my wife
about on stuff that I like right I mean
it affects me but really I'm going to
eat at the end of the day but when you
start your career you don't have that
luxury right but I think our primary
duty right I mean it's a rhetorical
question because you already know what
my answer is right is our primary duty
to our employers or to the world around
us we are not normal right is that we
have skills to help defend against
problems that we don't even really know
exist yet or at least the world around
us don't know exist yet and we all make
good money right getting into this
industry is you know a meal ticket to an
upper middle class life forever right
there's more problems than there are
people to solve them we're going to be
employed forever I'm not gonna retire I
don't have to retire right I can work
until I'm 80 having six kids by the time
the six kid is out of college I'm gonna
retire because I don't want to do crap
for nobody after that but I don't have
to retire I can keep working there'll
always be work but we have skills that
can help the world around us because if
we're just looking at our employers or
the web apps that they create we're
really talking about a small sliver of
the problem right of just enterprise
security basically but most of society
is not protected by security teams or
security tools or the things that we
create their whole genres of threats
that are directly b2c only as an example
of this I don't know if anybody in the
expo room has this swag it's my favorite
piece of swag because it shows how much
we suck how many people have that little
slider in front of their webcam
it's more than that you can rape you can
all raise your embrace your shame people
right we're professionals our job is to
secure stuff and what do we tell people
about creeping on other people's webcams
put this little slider in front of your
webcam James Comey at one point the
director of the FBI got on TV and said
well you know what I put this little
slider in front of my webcam you're the
director of the damn FBI and we can't
protect your webcam we're nowhere on
solving this problem right here's a
little piece of plastic to just pretend
that the problem doesn't exist does this
have to do with web apps right you know
machine learning is just a subset of
data science as many of you know data
science is huge I think data science is
huge because we've created Web Apps we
created mobile apps or just another form
of web apps that generate tons of
information about us most of the people
who design these systems just want all
the information they don't know what
they're gonna do with it they don't know
what their use of it is just give me all
the information we'll figure it out
later now we've got this stock pile of
data on humanity that would have been
impossible to figure out even a small
scale 20 years ago let's figure out ways
to make money so we're gonna hire data
scientists to do data mining we're gonna
do machine learning to say oh people who
tweet about this you know we probably
ought to give them web advertisements of
these products and these services but
there's all sorts of risks just having
you know that data sitting around right
we talked about OAuth in terms of on the
front end right preventing malicious
access to that but on the back end
there's plenty of ways to access the
data what do you think Facebook's going
to do when they get in a National
Security Letter they're going to give up
the data as one example it's a cloud
service not a web app but I come from a
family of lawyers and judges and petty
criminals which is what makes me great
in security I can find a loophole in
anything but you know there's some
voice-over-ip company that goes to my
family's law firm says hey we can do all
your voice over IP or
voicemails will be in the cloud all this
study it'll be great it'll be cheap they
call me it says what do you what do you
think about this I think this is a
profoundly stupid idea because at the
end of the day every call that you get
as a lawyer is attorney-client
privileged it is the most privileged in
the Western world anyway it's the
highest class it's enviable except in
very narrow circumstances you just
cannot break that so cloud company what
happens when you get a National Security
Letter wanting to know my my uncle's
voicemails who's a lawyer his
communication between his clients
well we comply with legal process wrong
answer and that is why we're not going
to put it in the cloud but we're
adopting these services and I got an
example on you know the slide here right
what happens if you email your doctor
your therapist talking about anxiety and
depression right that happens we should
take care of our mental health you're
going to have that kind of communication
well now all the algorithms they may not
mine your therapist but they're minding
you and now you get has anxiety disorder
label on your gmail account even though
it's HIPAA protected information
congratulations we found a loophole in
HIPAA the data can be stolen it can
categorize us people have been talking
about China's social credit score if you
behave in ways that the Chinese
government doesn't like well all the
sudden you don't get to ride on trains
and fly on planes anymore okay well that
wouldn't ever happen here except well it
does because hey do you want a 20%
discount on your auto insurance install
this app on your phone that pays
attention to where you drive and how
fast you drive and all that information
is now available right insurance
companies like the social credit score
concept because it allows their
actuaries to give discounts to good
people and not discounts to people that
they don't like but it also allows for
some interesting you know avenues of
trolling one of my favorite hobbies in
the world is harassing politicians
not I don't harass any of them right you
know in order for this to happen they
have to deserve it in some way right
they're just bad people and eight years
ago had a conversation with a state
rapper right
it was redistricting you know he
promised to move into his new district
his wife didn't want to move so he
didn't so he decided to transfer his
voter registration to a hotel room I
don't know why that made sense to him
because the way they do it in Chicago I
also grew up in the Chicago suburbs from
a political family
I know Chicago politics because I lived
it for 20 years right how they do it in
Chicago is you just rent some apartment
somewhere you're getting 270 thousand a
year salary you get a $300 a month
flophouse in order to figure out if
you're actually there you got to put a
guy on the room watch it well this clown
with a functional IQ of 40 does a hotel
room which has patent BS to begin with
then the conversation goes something
like this
representative did you think about what
you did before you did it were you
talking about
that hotel room when you got it does it
have a little remote keycard well yeah
so you put it to the door to open it up
yeah well that means instead of having
to monitor the door I just send a legal
request to the hotel operator
how many times did your key open that
door representative is that number zero
yeah congratulations there's your first
felony that hotel operator also runs
nursing homes that get state funding
yeah that means you got a free hotel
room from a state vendor that's your
second and third felony would you like
to go to prison or would you like door
number two to just rage quit your office
he chose door number two I particularly
like the ragequit that's my favorite we
can't secure information right we can
try we can mitigate the risks right but
even if your web app is secure right you
can't deal with the malicious insider
problem very easily we haven't found a
good way to it about a month ago there
was a yahoo employee who was trolling
all the images people upload to Yahoo
looking for less than closed pictures of
women he went to prison
but I assure you there's more people at
Yahoo they were doing that he just got
caught right people with otherwise legal
access that are not behaving in
appropriate ways let's call them
intelligence agencies for short they get
information all the time right in China
they're all state-owned companies they
just ask in the United States well we
have due process that due process has
send a national security letter and they
get the information right so we create
all of these tools that have risks right
we may look at the risks on the front
end with web vulnerabilities but what
are the implications of that right now
of course when you start telling your
employer's no they tend to not like that
right I'm sure some of you have run into
this this is a bad idea right or better
yet I'm sure many of you do penetration
testing or vulnerability assessment in
this room how many of you do that now
how many of you having done that have
run to a client or your company who said
I'm not going to fix that vulnerability
because that would never happen in the
real world I'm pretty sure that's almost
every hand that was up for both right
now if you've done this you know
commercially right you know or or
internally right the most important
document you have right the tool that
says okay I mean you can make that
choice I think it's a bad choice you
just signed this risk acceptance
document because that means when it all
blows up that I'm not the one holding
the bag you accepted the risk that also
comes with consequences but that's okay
you just can't sit on top of the server
room yelling stop or whatever the
there's an old poem that has something
about that yelling on top of the hill
yelling stop we can't do that but how do
you secure the unsecure right
because the reality is it's all
defective duct tape and bubble gum right
you think web app security failure to
handle this character breaks all sorts
of things right the single quote just
one character out of 255 right there
there's your sequel injection problem of
course it's all web security is more
complicated than that
but the compromises are relatively
simple and we're just skipping past that
you'd compromise people trivially we'll
just skip past that problem because I
can't fix humanity right I can barely
fix technology right but these simple
vulnerabilities also allow us some
simple tools from time to time to do bad
things to bad people
or at least keep tabs on them help them
get put in prison every now and then as
an example in 2016 right the russians
hacked the dnc the russians hacked the
Democratic Congressional Campaign
Committee they didn't know what to do
with the data they had so hey I got an
idea let's get on Twitter and created
this account booster for 2.0 the reason
that we know the three individuals who
are associated with that account with
the Russian GRU is because one time they
were obviously not doing this from the
home office they went to a coffee shop
or wherever off site and one time the
VPN wasn't down I'm sure many of you
have personal VPNs these things fail
silently and now all of a sudden your IP
address is exposed oops there's Russian
intelligence you think they know better
but they're using tools that happen to
fail quietly and now we know who they
are
and they're under indictment but it's
not like they're ever gonna come to the
US anyway right they made a relatively
simple mistake that allowed us to
enumerate them there's lots of
interesting other use cases right I love
Bitcoin right one of my hobby projects
is tracking neo-nazi fundraising the
reason I love Bitcoin is because it
allows me to follow financial
transactions without bribing bankers
right intelligence isn't my job title it
is what I do because bitcoin is
anonymous right you gather you know the
alphanumeric strings this is your wallet
right but all the transactions are
public because how do you know that
money has changed hands when there isn't
a central authority well all the nodes
have to see it and if they have
consensus then the transaction happened
it has to be public by design okay there
is so-called perfect use of Bitcoin but
you
the perfect use of Bitcoin is unusable
people want to transact money which
means they've got to let people know who
their wallet is which means anonymity
breaks right privacy is not even part of
the use case if you openly ask for
donations then it's obvious who you are
right daily stormer is not exactly a
wholesome individual right you know when
I say neo-nazis this guy has swastikas
on his website right this is not hey
he's conservative I mean straight-up
hates the Jews all all the way down no
ambiguity there's Bitcoin wallets on his
website all I got to do is go to an API
and now it's every time that he raised
his money he only got four dollars since
the last transaction but he's raised
depending on the value of Bitcoin about
a half million maybe a little bit more
and by the way as just a random aside
most of the mass shootings in the United
States and the unfortunate one in the
Christchurch Moscone nutri in in
Christchurch in New Zealand are tied to
his organization right so fairly
interesting individual but he operates
openly enough to where I can track his
money and he has real well real wealth
you can also do things like surveil
miscreants almost everything uses DNS
I'm gonna say DNS is life but as far as
the Internet is concerned it is right
without DNS there is no internet and
almost everything uses it so if
attackers want to reach victims or vice
versa they can't really play games with
DNS right there are host names need to
resolve which means I can go figure out
where they're resolving to and track all
of their infrastructure at least their
proxies than the first the first layer
of their network which means I can also
put those IP addresses into firewalls
nobody really thinks about firewalls
right this device oh I got a firewall i
plug it into the network I allow port 80
in port 443 you can also use that to
just block known bad stuff right and you
don't have to worry about that we'll
come to that point in a little bit Dhar
some caveats about deception an
attackers lie that you can handle you
know it also this kind of surveillance
says enable the predatory business model
where they register malicious domain
names and then see an IP address from a
company connect to it and then they get
a call from a sales associate it hey you
got breached I got the evidence right
here here's my invoice to help you clean
it up you know so we're also enabling
that vendor tactics but such as humanity
but it's easy to do is the point is that
often in security we create the
complicated solutions first and skip
past the simple ones which means we're
awfully inefficient in what we do right
limit amount of time budget and people
right start with a simple block as much
as you can and go from there because big
enterprises have big budgets I'm going
to guess most of the people in this room
are associated with small and medium
business and you're not going to be able
to I mean you'll get Splunk you might
get a security tool but you're not gonna
put a bunch of fireEye boxes in and a
bunch of Palo Alto this and a bunch of
this because you just don't have the
budget for it we create our security
tools for enterprises and we hope that
the people in smaller medium business do
what they can right there aren't that
many companies out there for that market
so I took that method right using this
one little line which is the guts of a
bunch of shell scripts to say I've got a
bunch of malicious domains about 900,000
whitelisting clean it up I'm writing
this little little shell script to just
turn those in IP addresses and turn it
into a business right not that I'm
trying to sell it but the point is is
sometimes some of our security problems
can be solved greatly not completely by
simple things right like using parallel
and asynchronous DNS queries right it's
not hard if somebody just has to do it
and sometimes I said me over complicate
things there's a notion of imposter
syndrome right which I'm sure some
people in this room know you know but
basically it's the notion of you know
what I'm not smart enough I'm not good
enough I can't I can't get on a stage
and give a talk I'm sure many of you
have not given a talk at a conference
are perfectly qualified to give a
we think of the problems as way too
complicated sometimes the solution is
relatively easy right DNS queries are
not hard right I've solved lots of
problems simply by just saying you know
what I can figure this out simply by
just doing advanced counting and math
all of us can do this but we're
pre-wired for whatever reason to think
of the problems more complicated than
they really are so start with a simple
and then leave the complex for last
because there's only so much so much
time so many people and so many
resources right especially if you're a
smaller company right and you should
always start with people if you have
employees that are resistant to clicking
on phishing links you have a lot less to
worry about that problem going back to
the human element you're never going to
solve social engineering but you can
make people a little bit more resistant
to it so let's take the example of
business email compromise right not a
web vulnerability primarily it's I'm
basically social engineering the CEO or
CFO or the accountant or whoever to wire
money my boss might see I report to a
CEO he gets us about once a month while
he doesn't people in the company get it
they get an email spoof from him the
email doesn't look like it's anything
close to him but it says his name hey I
need you to wire this money I need to
get back in contact with me ASAP people
are afraid of the CEO so they do
whatever he says instead of picking up a
phone how many people have bought or
sold a house about everybody how many of
you did that transaction exclusively
over email fine I said we're not normal
I had this conversation because I bought
a new house two years ago the bank's
like yeah I'd like your tax returns can
you email them to me no you're a bank
and this is a $300,000 transaction right
this is your a business email compromise
that are just compromising that low-rent
compromises of real estate lawyers and
title companies just doing low-rent
tricks no malware involved it's all
social engineering
it's a billion-dollar business and by
the way if your money gets wired
someplace else for a down payment on a
house you can't just say hey that wasn't
me and and it all goes away
you know somebody is going to eat that
loss it's not like credit card fraud
there are people that I've worked with
who have lost their life savings over
this because we can't secure information
email is insecure and it's insecure
there is nothing I can give you for an
email we have PGP how many people have
installed or GPG now how many people
have used a few people of the people
keep your hands up who have GPG
installed
how many sent just one email a day
that's encrypted right here's the best
part I didn't notice this until I was I
was teaching the CISSP class where
somebody sit there and shows screenshots
of what gbg looks like or actually what
PGP looked like in the 90s the interface
is still the same it literally hasn't
changed in 20 years everything else
about technology has changed email
encryption is here's this complicated
unusable thing that us normal people and
there were abnormal people in the room
don't want to use because it sucks well
just send your tax returns over email
it's all good it's not all good patching
the password security go a long way but
the third data points the most important
every time I do an audit of a small to
medium business you know I ask a
question right do you really need to
keep that information is that really
essential that you have health records
for ten years can you just shred that
you know do you really need to keep that
class of information and store it in the
first place
you know because you can't steal what's
not there people over collect
information and they keep it forever
right how many people had prune their
email folders how many people you know
or I said the flipside how many people
keep email forever
almost everybody right nobody goes back
and deletes it here's a fun anecdote
because I teach digital forensics also
how old does email have to be until I
can get it without a warrant 180 days
because then it's considered discarded
content unless it's on my server right
if you store it on a third-party
provider and it's over 180 days and
there's no under indication that you're
trying to keep it or preserve it you can
get it with just an administrator an
administrative warrant which means just
signed by some special agent in charge
of the FBI right you lose all your
protection of that right so why would
you keep data that long right for
folders for email servers that I don't
have to preserve I just have things
automatically delete after 150 days
unless I start how many people have gone
back to an email two years ago or three
years ago
occasionally how often do you do it once
a month once a quarter every now and
then it happens every now and then I
mean convene so I wish I had that email
from two years ago but it's really not
that big of a problem right use things
you already have
we like layering more product on top of
security right oh here here's another
appliance and another appliance and
another appliance hey that 24-port
switch can you make 22 of them span
ports so all these things can inspect
traffic but you have lots of things that
can already protect things and will the
firewalls are one right we'll talk about
another in a minute start with the
simple stuff and stuff that you already
have and then see what's left right see
what the gaps are how many people think
antivirus is still effective raise your
hands one person all right - a lot of a
room of a couple hundred give or take
right how many people would say don't
install antivirus as a security control
just say skip it don't ever install it
nobody would do that why is this product
still the thing we professionals don't
have much love for it right
dart nurse says AV is dead why is it
still here any idea
and up you know I asked a roomful of
cynics this question and you just
reinforce my low faith in humanity you
glorious glorious people all of that is
true but it's not the point I'm trying
to make we still have it because it
still blocks 70% of nonsense
80 percent on what the percentage is
it's it's going down surely there's ways
around it yes but it just blocks things
and it just makes it go away
right hopefully it's blocking dark comet
which is still a thing
12 years later or whatever it's made but
things are just blocked and you don't
have to worry about it
right and focusing on things like that
it's simple it's easy it's cheap it
blocks some percentage of the threat
landscape all right because it's often I
said it's not sometimes simple things
get you
so I ran for office in 2012 I actually
I'm starting to run for Congress now but
that's another story altogether
this happened a couple what day is today
hey this happened Tuesday Monday I know
the days blend together whatever
happened recently right we ran for
office in 2012 at one point I set up a
test WordPress site we're doing a
redesign whatever forgot about it
it's not linked anywhere this test dot
whatever right the main website was
converted to static HTML because I lost
the race so I just down the website
little H static HTML Thanks whatever I
saw him going back to work cool
completely forgot about it right I just
assumed it was online unlinked so was no
longer live somebody found it two three
days ago right a scanner popped it and
tried to run an IRC BOTS on it some
other defenses that I had on the server
caught it which is how is like you know
let's go take a look at that that says
oh somebody's turning on IRC BOTS on my
server that's bad right but I'm a
professional right I shouldn't make
these mistakes well it's pretty easy to
make these mistakes this stuff I don't
have an IT department it's a test site I
forgot about because the main site was
already down but these things happen
right and that happens an awful lot
because of DevOps and cloud deployment
you've got a developer saying I need to
make something so I'm going to spin up a
bunch of
in AWS with test data ha we don't know
how to generate test data so we use live
data maybe it's you know we'll we'll
just swap first names and last names of
people but all the other data is still
there so it's test date it's not valid
and here we are right and I figure out
which bank it was where they found some
tens of millions of credit card
applications on an unsecured s3 bucket
it say oh you're a big bank you
shouldn't have unsecured s3 buckets well
when you give your developers access to
AWS and there's no control around it you
really can't stop that problem right oh
but there's data loss prevention ha okay
how many people actually believe in DLP
that DLP works you're professionals a
couple of people you have way too much
hope sir give me time I will break you
yeah it's a band-aid on a bullet wound I
think I said it makes you feel better no
not really
does Brown look or help you feel better
just brown liquor help you feel better
let me play you the song of my people
so as an anecdote of simple things that
could work right how does DNS work all
of you are familiar with DNS right you
know you've got your root servers you've
got your top-level domains you've got
the authoritative nameservers and you've
got your resolver that's mitigating all
of that and trying to figure out how do
I get to WWE Google calm because
computers don't understand names they
only understand ones and zeroes well if
you control the resolver you control
everything right and everybody has a
resolver how many of your workplaces do
not how many of you work in play
workplaces that do not have your own DNS
resolver right essentially nobody unless
you work in a company of five people and
then use your ISPs resolver and you
shouldn't do that because your ISP
probably wants your data and you might
be tempted to go to qua dates you should
because Google wants your date
but you can block lots of stuff in DNS
right
there's response policy zones it's built
into DNS you don't have to install
anything it's already there all you have
to do is tell it what to block right so
instead of going to bad site comm they
get something else either it doesn't
resolve it goes to a security awareness
page whatever you want because
everything that's bad on the internet
often starts with DNS how do you secure
these IOT devices does anyone work in a
medical environment here nobody all
right that's fair right
there are tons of devices we're putting
on networks that we cannot modify
regulatorily speaking you cannot modify
an MRI machine that includes putting a V
on it endpoint CrowdStrike whatever you
want to put you can't do it when you a
patch comes out that's all sorts of
problems with the FDA and
recertification right we've got devices
that we can't modify IOT devices it's
basically a computer without an
interface full built out operating
system you could do anything you want on
you know an IOT teddy bear because you
know what humanity really needs is a
teddy bear connected to the Internet but
you know it's there it's communicating
and as full operating system and you
can't protect it but that teddy bear
uses DNS which provides you something
right you can detect on hostnames IP
addresses the authoritative name server
hostname and IP address right your turn
in X domain you could log the query and
let it happen many of you work in large
organizations that are allergic to
blocking things because oh there could
be a false positive okay well then you
could log at at least the sake knows
somebody queried something bad and do a
response to it you can move things to a
walled garden it says hey you clicked on
a link an email that was fishing and
this is why you shouldn't do that the
reason that that is important is that
everything we know about security
awareness training and the indicators
that we give people of the padlocks and
the warning messages of this sites not
secure the academic literature says all
of that crap don't work effectiveness
near zero the only thing that does work
is real-time feedback that they did
something and
immediately they got feedback you
shouldn't have done this and that's why
you can do that in DNS right in fact
there's a couple of companies that exist
their entire business model is to send
phishing attacks to their clients and
when people click on links they get
awareness training this was your
security vendor fish labs or whoever we
tried to fish you and we succeeded this
is what you should look for don't do
that again that is very effective not
not very effective more than zero
statistically significant effectiveness
right
you knew similar with firewalls you've
got these devices in your environments
how many of you work for companies that
don't have a firewall
everybody's got a firewall and these
things have access control lists let's
say you're a financial institution right
there's an O fact list of sanctioned
countries thou shalt not do business
with they have entire net blocks you'll
put in your firewalls go block Eastern
Europe right you not that Geographic
blocking is great but you know banking
fraud is pretty heavily correlated to
Eastern Europe if you block that that
space you block an awful lot you can
also do this for web apps usually and
going back to the campaign website the
IP address that initially found the
vulnerability and put a little PHP
script on on the server was a different
IP than was actually uploading the IRC
BOTS whatever the automated tools the
adversary uses and most of the
exploitation of web apps start with
automated scanning come from
infrastructure that's well-known right
they scan everything they hit honey pots
right there's companies that will sell
you honeypot data great woohoo tell you
what set up your own honey pots you get
all sorts of intelligence you to block
those IP addresses because nothing
should ever talk to a honeypot
that's not terribly exciting but if they
don't know you're vulnerable in the
first place then they don't come back
it's not a hundred percent right 80
percent whatever it goes away because
the automated tools won't catch you so
that people won't come back to do the
interactive stuff
now if you're specifically targeted
they're gonna go to your website and
figure it out but the scale of the
vulnerable space of society is too large
even for the attackers right they have
just as much of a scale problem as we do
right so we can use that to our
advantage right it's not a hundred
percent nothing's 100% got an unlimited
budget I could probably get you to five
nines all right anybody who says they
offer you a hundred percent Security's
full of crap don't buy their stuff
because they're probably just running a
Perl one-liner and you know and and
selling you snake oil but you know that
but if you get ninety percent for cheap
right that's why a V is relevant you
spend fifty dollars a year at block
stuff it blocks stupid stuff that you
don't have to deal with because you use
this every now and then are gonna click
on stupid stuff right you're gonna find
minor mistakes everybody in here has
probably developed a web app and there
was a stupid mistake that got missed
and so you hopefully your automated
scanner found it or your red team found
it or maybe the attacker found it
this is all too complicated and way too
easy to make a mistake
but if you can at least limit the the
threat landscape by 90% hey that's
something yeah my might be the one that
saves you how many people have heard
that in 2016 election authorities got
compromised right I live in the state
where that happened
state of Illinois we had an online voter
registration system right so people
could say oh I want to register to vote
normally you could do that for the DMV
or whatever they created an online
system because it made sense now we have
universal voter registration so I it's
all kind of deprecated but online
website right they found a sequel
injection vulnerability because
something was scanning the entire
internet and found it the way the
Illinois State Board of Elections
noticed that I had a problem is that
their web servers were being knocked
down under high load and they took a
look and found that somebody was
basically brute-forcing the tables to
find information it was not nearly as
targeted as an attack as people think I
actually disagree with the FBI I think
it was a conventional cyber criminal
that was doing it not Russian
intelligence that person may have been
flipping information to Russian
intelligence because you know that they
do like their tribute every now and then
either you're gonna cut him in on your
on your profits or you cut him in on
information and you get your 6 months
harassment free card right but that
would have been prevented just by the 7
IP addresses they publish 6 we knew
about would just scan the internet
machines for years those who have done
blocked the that compromise never would
have happened so you can focus your
spend on things that matter where your
gaps really are or the security vacation
club right you go to conferences DEFCON
blackhat don't go to don't go to
blackhat don't go to RSA go to well I
guess Derby is not a thing anymore go to
smooth shumou in DC is good right and
and and less products but I mentioned
earlier right what about the unprotected
the amount of the internet landscape
that's actually in an enterprise
environment is relatively small most of
the Internet is just people at this
point most Internet traffic is mobile
devices often on 4G right which means
there's no protection whatsoever as just
the endpoint on the wild wild west you
know there is no AV for iPhones right
here's you know here's what you have
right we work for companies we have
budget we have training we have tools
the unprotected doesn't they don't have
tools training they're just folk right
and I said a majority of mobile devices
are out there and if I compromise an
employee at home well I've compromised
the organization how many of you heard
of the shadow brokers release right lots
of data stolen from the CIA right and
and and there's a different one from the
NSA and and all sorts of interesting
leaks that have happened in the past
couple years which would lead to the you
know the question in your minds is how
is it that one of the most well-funded
intelligence agencies in the world can't
keep a damn secret anymore but that
happened because somebody brought
hacking tools home because they're a
contractor wanted to get ahead I'm sure
many of you have brought your work home
too he turned off his AV because he
wanted to for whatever reason get a
cracked version of Microsoft Office
because he didn't
I imagine what a salary was I don't know
why hundred dollars would make or break
him but he installed a crack version of
office and he had to turn off his AV
because AV was deleting his crack
version of office could have put in a
directory exception whatever didn't do
that realized he got all the malware
because he didn't have a V anymore so
bought Kaspersky Kaspersky is good
antivirus kind of by russian company but
it's good AV sol attack Kaspersky found
all the malware and coincidentally the
hacking tools that he was working on
because well guess what those are
hacking tools that AV shouldn't detect
that and all these things ship it all
back congratulations
the Russians now have the CIA and NSA
stools which created a great
geopolitical shitshow between the United
States and Russia over Kaspersky and
leaking these tools all sorts of fun but
the matter is even intelligence agencies
you had a contractor bring stuff he
really should have brought home because
it was highly classified but did anyway
and got compromised at home because it
was outside of the Enclave right if I
can compromise intelligence agencies the
most well-funded Intelligence Agency in
the world over this problem right this
is where the problem that the problem
really needs to be solved you're not
normal right all the other normal people
they don't know how to protect
themselves right
you know what normal people do is I
don't know if anybody has a VCR anymore
but I'm sure you have friends or family
who couldn't figure out how to set the
time on a VCR or a DVD player if it's
still blinking 12:00 o'clock right we've
got to solve the problem for that
because we may be able to solve the
problem in terms of the front end of our
web interfaces but a duty to broader
society has helped protect the ones
around us right we have all sorts of
physical threats that are being emerged
ten years ago the information security
threat was information you'd lose credit
cards you'd lose state secrets you lose
whatever now we were inventing actual
physical crimes or things that with a
physical Nexus right romance scams
cyber bullying all this stuff which
leads to body counts I don't know how
many people have killed themselves over
cyber bullying but that
number is not zero right and that is
enabled by technology that we are in
part helping to create if I steal user
credentials for an online bank and
transfer money you know are we gonna
make the victim eat that loss you know
in some cases we do in business email
compromised in real estate fraud so with
great leap this comes great
responsibility we have all sorts of
ability right we are trained
professionals if we're we're not really
protecting our employers one but society
and generally until we start doing
something about those unprotected there
are resources for that there stop think
connect you know you can have a session
to protect consumers go meet with your
Chamber of Commerce or a church group or
a PTA or whatever and say hey you're
having a problem with this here's
something you can do for cheaper free
because we have that knowledge and
there's nobody out there doing it we
could say why isn't the government doing
X or one example why isn't the FBI
prosecuting more cyber criminals because
we would have to grow the FBI to an
insane proportion to deal with the
amount of crime what and that's skipping
past how hard it is to get international
cooperation in law enforcement because
crime can transit can travel across
borders and law enforcement jurisdiction
doesn't right you could look at the
global cyber cyber alliance they have a
toolkit to protect elections and SMBs
how many of you concerned about election
security everybody is but the problem
landscape for them is much the same as
what you dealing you or your own
organizations the Illinois State Board
of Elections had a sequel vulnerability
I'm less worried about the state
election authorities because elections
are governed and the votes are counted
locally I have counties in my state that
have sub 10,000 population they're never
going to have resources to stand up to
the Russians or the Iranians or the
Chinese or anybody else that was
inspired I'm up around in our election
since 2016 it means the only thing that
they can do is rely on somebody like me
driving down to help them and say hey
let's go look at your website
let's go run a quick pen test let's go
put you behind cloud Slayer so at least
you have in effect some kind of a laugh
at home so I protect myself right
you got people to do it at home I've got
two raspberry pies one running a piehole
run running threat stop which you know
that would cost them the money for
normal people but just give people pie
holes and just start blocking things in
DNS which oh by the way starts blocking
things from kids who like visiting where
games and places on the internet they
ought not to because kids click
everything right it's two raspberry pies
you know it's about $100 $120 and I
could block millions of domain names
with it right it works is relatively
simple I had to tweak it a little bit
but by and large I travel a lot if
there's any problem with the internet
I'll hear about it and I've got to fix
it for whatever so yeah I could I could
create a whitelist and github
doraleous I get to have fun with my kids
every now and that yes Gabe I dunno what
websites you're going to not sorry at
all
InfoSec will never be solved we can't it
is it is I don't want to say it's an
unsolvable problem but we can't solve
humanity right
I can't sanctify mankind I'm not sure
mankind would like it if it were my
brand of Santa fication we are making
society less secure by adopting
technology that we ought not to adopt
but we can't say no we overcomplicate
protection start simple go from there
but also you know we've got to work and
protect the unprotected right spend some
measure of time sometimes pro bono
protecting things around us that matter
we all have skillsets that could solve
some problem somebody in society is
having right so I said I'm gonna make a
good salary providing for our families
it's all fine and good we need to expand
the sphere of beneficence and obviously
the actual risks are no longer just
information right there are physical and
real-world risks any questions
I know it's not 10:00 a.m. quite yet but
you don't have to let me off easy it is
I am bang on best speaker ever
[Applause]
[Music]
you