[Music]
yeah I live in epic fantasy land
actually I live in Utah I also work in
you too I work at my house so my house
is a really abstract fantasy land but I
work at github which which many we'll
get to why we the the the background of
the joke kind of the running joke that
github is app sec Fantasyland in fact
Justin Justin just walking in if you
turn and look at his shirt we'll be
previewing the absolute app SEC some
stuff from that podcast that is where
the running joke about it started so
perfect timing Justin thank you and I
chatted briefly with James wicked
anybody know wicked here you know we
talked a little bit he said you know he
said you know a lot of these talks we
give we're all given like variations on
the same talk you know so as I sat
through Dan's and Tonya's and now Justin
Sacher thought yeah we're gonna a lot of
these same things we're starting to say
here so so if you guys don't enjoy my
talk you probably heard it somewhere
else so you fall asleep because you just
had lunch that's alright you probably
heard no I I think there's some unique
things and and my purpose here is is not
to promote github not to tell you to use
this although it's great if you do but
genuinely I got to get hub and I was
like this is amazing like I'm amazed at
what they're doing here app SEC wise as
a longtime developer so so let's just go
ahead and transition to that Who am I
did development for 15 ish years all the
way back to the days of slinging Perl
anyone ever write a CGI script can you
claim that yes did that have always been
interested in security in the year 2000
around 2000 I was a grad student they
brought me to work on a data warehouse
and they got me a log and I'm like how
does this authentication stuff work I'm
really curious about this there was this
new thing called cookies by the way
they weren't using cookies they were
passing a hidden input from page to page
to page to page valid username in the
input hidden input you're logged in that
works so I put my exploit on a floppy
disk
the the three-and-a-half inch walked it
down to the project leads opposite said
you know you have a problem here and and
he was for to my good fortune he didn't
expel me from the school didn't call the
FBI for hacking he said thank you he
said you've just made a theoretical
debate we've had real you demonstrated a
real problem now go go work you young
grad student go work with the 50 year
old IT guy to fix this problem whose
thing you just broke and then I learned
I said I'm not qualified for that and he
said well the land of the man with one
eye is king and land of the blind so go
help him anyway so that that was my that
was kind of the start of my interest in
web application security I saw how
brittle it was not until 2016 did I
start working full-time I'll get to the
last con connection in just a moment and
everyone's me with imposter syndrome
right feeling like you don't belong
everyone knows more than you I'm
postured my way into work in an abstract
fantasy land ie
github so there's hope for you if you if
you're if you feel you're struggling
also I don't have this on here but I've
worked on web goat from an old purse
pecked above yours I don't put it on
here because I haven't done squat in
like two-plus years so I've done squat
but very little so for the last gun
connection there were some good things
you may have seen this image circulating
around the bottom image here from Pete
chest lock this was part of the keynote
when I came to Alaska in 2015 that image
has gotten a lot of mileage and it's in
some ways true about our life at github
some ways not so I thought it was worth
including Jack Daniel also gave a talk I
think it's a good reminder something
just good to remember it's not germane
to my talk today but he talked about
saying on the shoulders of giants and I
think it's always important to
you do you remember that there's someone
came before you laid some groundwork and
to be grateful for that
as far as the last gun connection anyone
seen the job board ie the white board
out here so I took a picture of that
took home and the one booth that I
didn't stop at Aztec consulting I they
had written up on that board I sent them
an email and that was my and my entree
into app application security full-time
work working with Aztec good company
they're now part of Moss Adams which is
a larger consulting firm like a like a
smaller grade like a smaller version of
Ernst & Young sort of thing so anyway
that's my last kind of connection so I
appreciate last con I think it's a great
conference and I have an extra special
connection there so let's talk about why
this app sec fantasy land here is
anybody recognized I know Justin
recognizes these people anybody else
recognize the people in the picture here
I got on the Left five more people know
Jim Manukau mana code security or mana
code I think just and incest law over
here runs a podcast of that of that a
friend of mine coworker co-host within
Kohn absolute app second both of these
clips are from it
so let's just listen to what they have
to say the first one was Seth here is I
haven't done this with keynote is it
nope gotta go over there so then this
one he's actually talking with my boss
great oh so on this absolute aspect
podcast
[Music]
so that that's the that's the one
example of the apps tech Wonderland and
it's cue up Jim as well Jim's a little
more animated if you've ever seen Jim
present or speak or train Jim's kind of
on the animated
[Music]
you have magic duster there okay
so there you go I know Jim's a lot more
fun to watch than me by the way github
magic does for sale after the present it
no no so
so no so yeah we have magic dust where
Letus were jaded we live in the promised
land Promised Land was actually a
comment from the hacker one rep we
worked with them they like yeah you guys
are like the Promised Land and I'll talk
about bug bounties later so kind anyone
go to Justin's sock over here by the way
yeah sorry we still have an app sec team
we haven't gotten rid of it yet we have
an app sec team we also have a project
team but credit where credit's due
you know I I struggle with putting this
presentation together I don't want to
sound elitist I don't want to sound
jaded I just really want to share
something I hope will benefit someone
else I think it's really cool to see
what what's happened at github from an
application security perspective and so
top left is Greg OSA I'm not going to go
through everybody he's my boss you saw
him briefed briefly in that clip and he
runs the app SEC team he along with let
me see if my pointer works Neal that's
Neal that was mentioned Patrick to me
and Bente is here they're kind of the
original app sect team at github and
have done a lot of work along with other
people that have come along over time
and now we've split off so we have an
app SEC app sick team and we have a
project team differences app SEC I'll
say assesses and educates and project
builds security features so to FA
web off in credit credential scanning a
one heard that we scan public repos for
like AWS tokens left hanging out things
like that they build those sorts of
features so that's more or less the
layout but but these are the people that
really deserve credit over time and
continuing to to build great things at
github for a knapsack perspective so if
you really want to go get lunch this is
the this is it this is this is the list
of things I think that makes a github
app SEC Fantasyland except for the one
weird trick that I'm gonna wait until
the end to tell you about but it's
actually kinda been mentioned in some
other presentations just not the exact
same way I'm going to mention it I feel
like I'm cutting in and out on this is
that do I need to hold it differently or
it's something might turn my head yeah
it's gonna be great for people listening
on YouTube is that better yeah there we
go alright
oh the messing up Monalisa here miss
Mona Lisa the octi cat by the way that's
her name our our mascot so that's a
that's an overlay but we're gonna talk
about here's another way to look at
things I'm gonna talk about the things
that make us that makes github app sick
Wonderland but there's things that we
still struggle with and some of these
things are you might look here and say
yeah we struggle with that too and I'll
tell you right now I don't have specific
slides on asset or domain inventory I'm
just gonna tell you that's a struggle
everywhere oh we have we're running
something on that domain oh that's still
hanging out there you know that that
custom app somebody built for this
specific event three years ago oh that's
still hanging out there and it's
connected to what yeah we struggle with
that too so here's here's some other
things we're gonna we're gonna talk
about and yes that is not a copy-paste
error
anyone running bug bound near been
involved in a bug bounty program so you
understand maybe understand this okay so
number one reason the well not the
number one reason but the first thing
I'm going to talk about is top-down
support
and Neil mannitol was supposed to give a
presentation and we talked about this he
wasn't able to give it but one of the
things we talked about was my threat
model is not your threat model of the
things I have to do don't necessary
apply to you if you work in retail you
probably have to run ads you have to
worry about performance if our page
loads if github loads a second slower
are you running over to get lab to use
it probably not right and we don't have
to regret our bitbucket
so we finally got we finally got Dave
off get bit buck no is he still a bit
bucket Justin I can't remember anyway
anyway the point is is is we're not
running ads remember sceneline a
headland github.com if you have then
something happened please let us know
because you shouldn't see that and so
that affects our threat model we don't
have to worry about that and the fact
that we have a Content security policy
in place that would eventually kill what
essentially killed most ads helps us so
that that gives that at bay we don't
know how long that'll last but we'll
take it for now
top-down support another point in town
top-down support this was posted when we
had an application security position
opening earlier in the year sorry it's
filled in case you're job hunting but
feel free to talk to me if you want to
network some for the future but you know
the recognition that that security and
trust is paramount and we need to do
that but whose company says that secure
anyone no companies that publicly say
security is important but internally a
little different
anyone ever experienced that yeah yeah
probably most of us from an internal
meeting NAT said I'm proud of the app
SEC reviews we're doing a CEO of a
company mentioned an app's tech review
where does that happen AB SEC
fantasyland right it happens a knapsack
fantasy line and so we have a repo and
more about this everything on github is
done in github we dog food to the nth
degree so you can come and create an
issue for a knapsack review and we will
review your feature your your new app
your new service whatever and so so we
do that we work right in in github and
we do app set reviews and that's
recognized from the top down prod SEC
their ships are celebrated at universe
and satellite in case you don't know
universal satellite or events that
happened about every six months universe
is coming up in November satellite will
be in spring satellites usually in
Europe universe is in San Francisco it's
the big event github announces great big
features it's like a conference but our
security features get get celebrated
right along with hey we're doing actions
hey we're doing these other things that
github and so credential scanning to FA
you have often pwned passwords
integration they might know about the
panic pwned passwords integration what
that is anybody know about pwned
passwords
Troy hunt have I been poned look it up
you can download the list of compromised
passwords see if you can see if you can
use one of those compromised passwords
on github and it told you yeah and so
initially right yeah we think they
finally started enforcing originally it
was just we're gonna put this banner up
and annoy you until you change it now I
think they actually enforce it and force
you to change it we got a lot we a
little bit of backlash about some of
that B were like no stop telling me I
don't it won't for one funny story was
someone was like you're telling my
co-workers that I have a weak password
like there's an easy problems an easy
solution for this so that was literally
their complaint on Twitter okay and then
if you didn't know if you didn't see
this actually Mike's presenting later
today
we acquired simul which is a secure a
code analysis for security company and
we'll be integrating that as
github offering we haven't from an
internal perspective we haven't been
able to dog food it I wish I could talk
more about it I wish I had been able to
get my hands on it so far but
essentially we are we are bringing
bringing the tools to do code analysis
for security into as a github of
offering so pretty cool when you get
that level of top-down support this is
all about top-down support so what's the
downside of that most of us all of us in
github
you know apps X like what did I miss
who's gonna get a bounty on this right
what did I miss it's gonna show up in
the bounty bounty program anyway I do
pen testing here No so anyone know who
ed SCOTUS is so somewhat the sand shirt
you should know who it's go this is
let's go this has a great at least as I
heard this attributed to him he talked
about you get a pen test penetration
test and there's no findings are you
secure to your pen tester suck maybe
right but that's how we feel right I
didn't find anything
do I just suck right I'm no good I
didn't find any problems in the code and
so we struggle with that right impostor
syndrome I don't belong here
just a side note public service
announcement you know this is people who
get imposter syndrome other people who
get it and yeah all of us get it so so
you know it happens it github - we
struggle with that and it has happened
where we've done reviews and I'll talk
about it in a little bit where we will
remit something or we don't get to it
and it does show up in the bounty
program and and it's not easy it's a lot
of stress because well this is important
we're supported to do this right so I
didn't understand the 10x engineer
thread that ran around on Twitter while
ago name one see that anyway we're two X
engineers at github meaning if you do it
two times it's time to automate it and
so one of the things that makes OPSEC
github apps like Fantasyland is mature
engineering I gave as I spoke in
a separate webinar about this in my
advice if I come into a place to consult
and say what do you want to do to make
your secure your development lifecycle
secure first answer is mature your
development lifecycle get away from
works on my box doesn't work on your box
right get your automation down get your
unit testing down get your integration
testing down get your functional testing
down authorization tests right ozzie
automated tests right this was this was
just another software engineer at github
we didn't do this we didn't work with
this it just showed up on an internal we
call it team there's a like an internal
blog to get hub and this showed up one
day someone's like I improved writing
authorization tests you're welcome
and we're like this is amazing it's ABS
act Fantasyland right so but the
struggle then is you get mature
engineering things happen faster right
so we get mature Imagineering we can
reproduce problems we have automated
tests we have confidence in our deploys
things really start to move fast and so
we struggled to keep up with it right
and we don't always get apps or services
or future reviewed and hit I want to
chat more about that Justin the whole
concept you had in your presentation
about reviews and peer reviewing but I
would say this the example I want to
give is a peer review because prod sec
wrote a security feature anyone anyone
see that we shipped organizations can be
ssh certain authorities and you can
require that for commits in your
organization okay so if you have an
Oregon github you can require you can
become an SSH Sirte thority for your
organization and you can sign
certificates and issue certificates for
people in your organization they have to
have
that that see it your CA issued cert to
commit code I can issue them for one day
and then I show you another one for one
day so I can kind of like a let's
encrypt model so Project Engineer wrote
that up ssh is pretty solid the
components on that are pretty solid
right so that went to the bottom of my
review pile because i had other things
to get done and it stayed at the bottom
of my review pile and then they shipped
it and then a bounty submitter found an
issue with the management interface
pretty simple problem but i didn't get
to it because there was a lot to do and
i thought yeah project guy wrote that
we're good
that's solid right and so you know we
struggle with that just the the the
shipping security at scale and speed and
keeping up with that and we're not
officially a blocker in many cases like
i said this didn't get us an app sec
review before it shipped and so
sometimes that means we miss things
other times it's perceived that we are a
blocker and we're pressured into it
because we do want to review things
before they go out and so that's a
struggle like like many places like seth
talked about in the clip you know you've
got three people four hundred apps
they're all high priority right so same
buddies company hire rockstars anybody
work with a company and says we hire
rockstars you've seen that right we hire
rockstar developers or whatever well
this is a great thing a github is we we
prefer janitors over rock stars janitors
get their hands dirty they clean up
messes they take on difficult tasks they
do the jobs people don't want to do
anyone ever dealt with OAuth code from a
review or a writing perspective you're
lucky okay
Omaha is a nasty complex thing to code
to implement to get right and so you
know Liz feminists Diaz her her handle I
think pretty much everywhere she said
and that's her it's also her Abbott
are everywhere the sloth in a and a cup
you know and she took that on she just
came in and said you know this needs
doing I'm gonna do it and so this makes
you know these issues get hung out and
what happens anyone done consulting like
a security consulting you do the review
right and there's a finding and you come
back for the next annual review and the
finding is so they're right so this
wasn't a finding but it was an issue
that was hanging out that needed
addressing and it got done right because
janitors are better than rock stars
because rock stars trash your room right
and throw a fit the janitor comes in and
cleans it up wait we want janitors not
rock stars and your wall was much better
than mine Justin we don't lob things
over the wall github and I think this
was very high on the list of why it's AB
sec fantasy land
there's no lobbying hand over the wall I
see got on a call yesterday with a
developer they want to do an integration
with a partner on something and we sat
and worked out the problem together
right we sat we got on the call and he
showed me what he was working on and he
showed me this error message and content
security policy was blocking him right
and I'm like okay well this is why and
let's let's talk about other options of
how we can do this or if there's a way
to get when you call it an exception in
place for this and I said you know bars
are bars pretty high for a set of
exceptions but you know let's let's look
at all the options and so we don't lob
things we work in issues we work in pull
requests we work in repos all together
dogfooding
within github and so that makes it a
great place to work with developers
sounds fantastic right dreamy right
anybody want to guess what the downside
is
notification bankruptcy right so high
when you work with all the deaths you
work with all the Deb's right we anyone
used mentions I mean we use mentions in
github so we can at github slash app SEC
internally that is us as a team or you
individually I might get an app misfire
and hey can you look at this hey can you
review this or I've got a question about
this and you know email and then we get
all the email about that from github and
yeah anyway so yeah notification
bankruptcy yeah it can be overwhelming
[Music]
so you again this was something that was
mentioned in at least two talks possibly
three today I've I've come across tuned
and automated sassed security static
analysis security testing so if you've
done application security for any time
or you've use sassed you've probably
seen the run run the stock SAS product
on some large code base generate one
thousand pages of mostly false positives
right lots of noise little use okay
so must be tuned it must be automated we
run we run this and these are automated
actually Sentinel that's the user that
does it and Sentinel will drop a comment
in the issue and will say hey looks like
you're it's like Clippy right but
tougher all right if I remember Clippy
so Clippy but much tougher right so say
hey it looks like you're changing you
want to change the content security
policy looks like you're trying to do
this and then we'll link them off to a
guide if we have it about like what they
might want to consider or how to do that
securely etc one of the things we look
for for example is in in concerns about
server side request forgery SS RF we
look for HTTP client connections
outbound
and so we get a notification and it
drops a comment about that do we get
false positives yes are they easy for us
to triage yes do we also get some true
positives yes and that's where the bang
for buck really comes in until we run
break man on Ruby on Rails opinionated
framework break man works well for that
we have customized components of break
man and then we do a lot of reg Xing
quite simply right we just say if we see
this in the code we want to look at that
for two seconds and we can usually
triage it right so automated and tuned
this happens basically on every PR on
every pull request that comes in to the
you saw the reference the monolith
anybody want to guess what the monolith
is it's github.com it's the main product
right so it's the large code base that
is the monolith so this runs regularly
on github.com code but our struggle is
oh there's much shinier things than Ruby
on Rails right so there's golang if you
hadn't heard we were acquired by
Microsoft so we might be using Azure
some may be AWS we have github actions
now which is hey run your own code over
here in the sandbox and hopefully we're
safe right so there's all kinds of stuff
we have to worry about that that we
still have to learn how to tune and
automate and look at to alert us on
you'll notice no c-sharp though so all
right so this is this is another thing I
think that's great about github and I
think Greg OSA my boss is a really does
a great job with this security
absolutism right I remember sitting in
as a software engineer my 15 ish years
as a software engineer anyone sat in a
meeting and like we have these eight
tasks and this guy literally was like h
h h h for what high priority
everything was in h by the time he was
everything was an age high priority if
everything's high priority
nothing's high priority so we have to do
that in security right you have to care
about certain things you know and dan
Cornell I think earlier today talked
about this he got a great perspective on
it the business is risk right we often
worry about information security risk
but what about the businesses risk right
you have to think about the business
risk if we stop to fix absolutely every
little security potential security bug
we're gonna slow down until we're out of
existence right so what do we care about
we care about authorization issues we we
care about cross-site scripting we don't
think it's just solved we've just put a
lot of work into it and so we have a
pretty good handle on it now we really
do care right we watch for it
so and I and I've told my son this a few
times recently anyone have children
teenage children especially you end up
in these all-or-nothing grudge matches
right or it's I want this at no
compromise and I told my son I tell them
I told him a number of times recently if
you go about all or nothing you're gonna
end up with a lot of nothing right and
so can't be security absolutist bounties
all right
so who is my who's one who's that who
has improved my bounty people in here
what's your favorite part of the bounty
yeah it's kind of nice like say hey you
found something good here somebody
what's your what's your least favorite
part about the bounty this why do I
outsource my presentations yeah yeah so
and so the great thing about bounty you
notice I had you know wonderland
bounties struggle bounties right and so
bounties are great my first week at
github 10,000 bounty 20,000 bounty I
watched them happen because problems got
solved not publicly right we handled it
early that problem came up early we
dealt with it we rewarded the bounty
submitter and we moved on right I
awarded about a month or two ago I
warded $42,000 in bounties Fred came in
from over the weekend again I'm not
gonna tell you what it was I can't but
those problems were solved and that's
the great thing I don't have to tell you
about it it's not one Krebbs on security
on the front page so that's the wonder
of bounties and you get talent that you
get and I don't have to pay anyone until
they find that right once they find it
it's good we pay them I don't have to
pay for the extra forty hours they spent
not finding something but we pay them
for what they found and then we get to
triage and so that's great so let me
walk you quickly through just just the
anatomy of how a bounty works at github
because I think it's I think this is
useful we chat off a lot anybody else do
chat ups know what anybody know what
they might want to know what chat Ops is
I'll pause for a second okay great I
please stop I should have said this
earlier if I throw out some term and
it's there like what please stop me is
you see I have no problem interacting
too much often so I'm watching my clock
here because yeah I got lunch still so
chat up is the concept of like any when
you slack do you use slack okay so you
can wire up slack essentially to listen
for something and then send off a
request elsewhere and then it would does
work that's the short way to put it
right so essentially we we give slack a
command in this case it would be dot
bounty and then I tell it triage it or
give it an info response which means
yeah that's helpful but no we're not
gonna pay you and then it closed it so
if I do bounty info the the submission
ID and then we have like canned messages
we can optionally send a canned message
to them and so what happens is we chat
up so a bounty comes in let's say and I
look at and I take whatever time it
takes me sometimes short sometimes long
there's the downside of some of the
bounties and I say yes this is real this
is valid right so we need to we need to
look into this we need to create an
issue so I would dot bounty triage the
bounty ID and then I'd pick the repo
it's gonna go into and github and it
will create an issue in that repo and
github I'll go in I'll go in will click
the link into that issue from slack and
then I will comment a little more
usually like I tested this I think this
is where the code is that's causing it I
might have already found the code I
might have tested another scenario on
top of the one the bounty submitter gave
me and I'll add a little more commentary
to the India issue of what's going on
and then I will typically mention
whatever team has responsibility I'll
find what team has responsibility for
that area I'll at them and then that is
my issue to work with them right so I
work that issue to the end till it's
fixed and sometimes before it's fixed
but oftentimes after we then will pay
the bounty submitter and again the
bounty that's dot bounty payout bounty
bounty issue ID and the amount I'm gonna
send them all right and yes we whitelist
the amounts we send them so if you had
an extra zero because because that is
it's an issue right so so we chat off
all of that meaning basically we
automate it so I can just do it right
from slack I don't have to go into 20
different systems to do it
and that's one of the that goes back to
the mature engineering aspect right we
all chat up it at github like every team
does and so it's a culture of doing that
it's an automation it helps vastly
because those tanya talked about toil
right if you were in there she talked
about toil something else that makes
github app sec Fantasyland is we don't
have we do have some of the toil but a
lot of it has has been been handled that
way so we run that we're comment the the
the absolute Fantasyland story in this
was I got a submission it was cross-site
scripting but it was low risk because it
was not it wouldn't have it wouldn't
affect github.com it didn't have your
github session it wouldn't have been
related to your github session and he in
any way I created the issue I added the
I mentioned the the responsible team and
I think I mentioned a specific developer
who had worked on a similar issue she
came in she fixed it we verified it we
deployed it in three hours so that's the
absolute you know Wonderland story for
that and that yeah and that and that was
an amazing experience
um the downside though we have someone
who's written blogs complaining because
we didn't accept their submission they
also deleted their blog in like two
hours after they posted it but kind of
weird but yeah we have that back and
forth because inherently there is
competing interests in your bounty
program the submitter wants that
security absolutism they want the
low-risk issues to be seen as high risk
so they can get paid out and so they can
get their reputation because reputation
is also a currency on bounty programs
and understand that if you're looking
into one they want their signal there's
there's two things reputation and signal
and some people are very particular
about the reputation and signal in those
programs so that's the the downside of
the bounties right and I and I should
have clicked forward to this at that
point right so bow me please right
I went seeing that the clip which like
money please so anyway so that is the
that's the upside and downside of bounty
programs in terms of abstract Wonderland
so what are we doing to make it more
wonderful I'm going to hit on a couple
things that still at the end that that I
think make it wonderful that one weird
trick included but the automation and
the chat hopping that I that I've talked
about right so walk over here so when
when I create a bounty issue it puts a
label on that issue that it was bounty
it also puts an issue on it those
security I can run a separate command
that says dot vuln or dot bounty I think
we Elias at both ways and it says I put
in the github issue and then I put in
the severity high on this one so it puts
in our security high label right and on
top of that and I think this this is one
of so much here since we started doing
this just in the last several months we
say high severity target time to fix
this is not contractual no one from the
top down said hey when security tells
you it's high this is how you have to
fix it we're just saying this is one we
think it should be fixed and we find
that developers go you're right we
should get to that we should fix that
and then there's a little note about why
what are examples of high severity
issues so sentinel sea sentinel drops
this issue in for its and comments on it
and that helps a lot so just for the
record our issues are or our our
severity czar since the low medium high
critical times are ours one day one week
and then negotiable but we don't want to
let it go past two months and we'll set
a reminder to follow up on it so for low
issues we don't really bother with
informational issues we might I think
it's officially a level but we rarely
they're hardly worth an issue bounties
again we are cultivating relationships
with top security researchers
this is from the hacker 1-7 h1 702 event
it's co-located to Def Con hacker one
puts on a life hacking event Verizon
github other companies participate in it
where they actually bring the hackers in
live and they bring them in live and and
we get to work with them hands on
I haven't participated in one yet but
it's a lot of work it's a lot of work
it's like a long long day cuz you know
the stereotypical hacker works until
like 2:00 or 3:00 in the morning right
yeah that actually happens here I don't
think it's just because of stereotypes
it's just because it's a compressed time
scheduled to do this but the other
aspect to bounties and if you if you
decide to go on a bounty program and you
don't learn from your bounty submitters
you're missing out that example of the
SSH Sirte thority review where I didn't
get to it in time and someone submitted
a bounty even though I hadn't got to it
I said well we reverse engineered and
said how did this person find this so
fast and we thought they probably have
these three this thing on their
checklist so we added that thing to our
checklist and said when you're reviewing
make sure you double-check that simple
check it was sam'l related I'll tell you
that much and so we said hey you know if
something sam'l protected make sure you
do this check all right so if you run a
bounty program and you're not learning
from your from your top submitters
you're missing out on something take the
opportunity whether or not you missed it
or however they got the submission got
there take the opportunity to think how
did the bounty submitter find that how
can I add that into my own repertoire of
of checks to do ok so I think we're
getting pretty close um
paved paths and I think Justin mentioned
this in a better way in his presentation
that is api's that are secure by default
example code that's secure by default we
had a conversation we had a series a few
weeks where we did chats with other app
sect teams for
from a number of companies but one of
those was Netflix and Netflix very
interesting when they look at the app
security of an application to measure it
they look at the percentage of paved
paths Ness that's their primary thing
that they look at are you using the pay
of paths that have been put out there
and I'm like that's a great that's
that's wonderful you know so so that's
something we're working on when I say
we're working on it it means literally
we're not there yet it's something we're
working on and this is a continual thing
right obligatory all the things right
automate and chat ops all the things
right all the things that are repeatable
mundane that you don't want to do
manually multiple times and so one of
those things is the over notification
that I mentioned earlier that's one of
the things that I'm eventually going to
get to is a better job of automating
awareness essentially what we should be
looking at and what we can kind of
ignore what's been sitting for a long
time what just happened
so we can be involved in those things
all right you know only two slides I
think I'm doing pretty good there might
be hope for lunch yet is there any
questions up to this point by the way I
meant to stop earlier any questions or
comments this is the best part no I'm
not done I'm just pausing quickly before
I get through my last two slides are
there any questions or comments thus far
okay I do actually have if you at the
end after the next two slides you have a
good question I think I have some get to
github wireless chargers phone chargers
I just I just ended up with two extras
so from a company thing so if you'd like
one asked me a good question or make a
comment at the end just flatter me
really that's all I ask no don't please
so
yep he's just lost so thank you but you
did that does not gonna qualify so it
all comes back to good people if you
ever hire if you ever interview to come
place and you ask what why should I work
here or what makes this company great
and it'll say something about the team
or the people they really should write
and so that's one of the things that
made github apps like Phoenix and I
mentioned this earlier these are great
people that I work with talented smart
humble you know like I said I don't want
to say that you know we're not ëletís
right there's been some hard work that's
gone in there's some good good outcomes
but good people make all the difference
so the one weird trick the one thing I
think that number one thing I think that
makes github app sec Fantasyland you
probably weren't guessing it maybe you
were empathy this is a written down
formally written down part of your
orientation core value at github so when
they talk about core values that github
empathy is one of those others include
things like product improvement quality
shipping collaboration right things yeah
we want to do good work we want quality
those sorts of things but I this is the
first company I worked at where they
said empathy is a core value and why
does that make a difference in half sec
right because it helps us build trust
with the developers no-one's ever worked
in a place where the developers avoid
security right developers avoid security
right and it does so empathy helps us
build trust with developers we're not
scared they're not scared of us when I
sat down when I had the video chat
yesterday with developer he said no my
he said my my my interactions with
security have been generally positive so
he had no reason to avoid me I had
another one where when we came one there
kind of like what I didn't know what I
don't oh that wasn't bad like that
wasn't as bad as I thought it would be
right so obviously this person has had
bad experiences with security and you
know and but we were able and so if we
can build that trust internally and
he is a key way for us to do that we
build that trust internally the
developers won't avoid us and in the end
we all want really to build trust able
software right and so this enables that
if we have empathy and we work with the
developers some have some have seen the
mean you know developers or friend not
food with the Finding Nemo shark right
and that's it
developers are your friend I was a
developer so I have I have a great deal
of empathy I know what they do to day to
day and so I think this is the number
one thing and this actually was this
morning
this was the developer I spoke with
yesterday because his problem was
content security policy and we could
have just told him what no no you can't
make an exception to content security
policy but Oreo shake neo mannitol has
done work such that we have a way to do
it safely and scope it properly and so
we've supported them doing that and so
because we have empathy we're able to
make that win and so if we do that I
believe that is the number one thing
that makes github apps that Fantasyland
and thank you
[Applause]
you