[Music]
foreign
second b-sides and this time despite
having a tool that I'll be doing the
moderation part I also at some moment uh
participated in call for papers and
despite me having the most bizarre
speaker's bio to check it from the
website later
uh I got selected
so the talk is about something I'm doing
uh at work and that I I have been doing
touring also past five years when I was
working at Zone
so a lot of these things are kind of
contribution of my current and previous
uh work thanks to whom I understand
these things and and I have learned
these things
uh logs don't lie even if part of them
is lost we are in the theater basically
if it's a theater place so of course we
need to start with a plot twist
rocks namely extremely good at lying to
you and especially not showing up when
you need them it has happened to me a
lot of times in my life
but I've also during that learned how to
kind of like massage the Rocks into
being
and turns out that while I actually like
dealing with reading the logs and
finding the bad guys and everything then
actually most important part of my work
for example when we were on lock Shields
cyber exercise was actually making sure
that all logs are in Pro performance and
they reach elastic
uh so some scene setting
[Music]
what I'm going to talk is because I've
been dealing with the side of security
which could be web application security
so I'll be looking on at the logs not
from the side of Marlborough happening
on your Windows computers but exactly
things that are happening earlier in
relation to web servers
and somehow uh starting from the 24th of
February there has been a more DDOS
attacks than I've ever seen before so
I'm using that as a case to case for
that
and then we are going into the logs
themselves
but to kind of like specify the
territory
there is this very famous Google
interview question about what happens if
you are typing the URL into the browser
so I went out and tried to find this is
there some kind of explanation and turns
out some Alex
Gonzalez whatever
has done 300 comments and come up with a
very detailed thing in as much detail as
possible when you go in and you're
actually going to see that the part I'm
going to talk is just this one line in
this thing
and even more
I'm going to talk about the part that
request ER is received by a web server
then probably it is passed on to some
application I really don't care how how
the application works for me currently
it is just something that takes time I
don't go deep into that
uh and then the responses can send back
again these parts as I said I don't care
uh I'm just talking about basically this
part and perhaps a bit about how it is
going to get sent back but what people
are doing with the response who cares
it's DDOS they're probably not even
reading what they are getting there so
anyway
uh
what kind of uh
denial of services I'm going to keep in
mind uh when uh while describing the
things I have been looking for in the
logs uh
three different examples
the first one is
something called a concerned customer
who informs a website that they are
giving error 500s or something like that
this picture is actually when I
check the logs later and actually
painted the number of requests and turns
out that the user arrived at 4 33
started doing different kinds of
loads looking for things and by 446
which is like 12 minutes later the user
had the concerned visitor had found
endpoint that very effectively took the
site down and actually with very few
requests so there wasn't a question I
think the original one I've apparently
cut away part of the numbers but I think
it was thousands of requests and then as
you see it's basically a TENS of
her ecos was taking Tower
again interesting to understand how it's
happening because if some random dude
can find out how to take your site with
10 requests then probably this is an
important issue
the next case is actually this picture
by the way the first picture was like
something like
tens of minutes so this is basically the
Escape down there 5 10 cilities a
seconds
so this is one minute of a massive
Adidas attack
level seven so because
these sites are behind cloudflare so we
don't care about lower levels just what
could come through
interesting to see is actually the red
line there is indication of error 500s
and when you see the brown line is the
cloud fairs defense kicking in so we can
say that by the number perhaps a bit
after 10th second of the attack it
starts kind of like doing something and
it actually gears up at a 30 second mark
so until that we are kind of naked we
are not being protected and we need to
deal with these things ourselves so the
question is for me uh why did it start
giving these error 500s and what do I
need to make my ingresses and apps more
resilient to these kinds of events
third one
is some person or person's
trying out how the cloudflare works or
how the site Works behind the cloudflare
so the first hit was something like I
think four million requests in one
minute the second one was I think three
or four minutes
and uh and uh third one was also again
one minute ten something like four
million requests in this graph
okay and the time was like one hour in
the night and uh 30 million requests
total
so
Let's uh think now about this thing what
is happening uh Behind these attacks and
actually on the side of our server
and let's look a bit more detail into
what's actually happening
and for me always the question is that
okay I know what happened site went down
but what actually caused that what was
the bottleneck where I need to deal with
things so we can imagine that the same
HTTP request after somebody typed it in
in the browser or launched in a DDOS
tool
either it's cloudflare from cloudflare
it comes to some kind of our whatever
kubernetes Ingress
uh or whatever is kind of like there uh
sometimes it's just going to maybe
some kind of load Challenger there is
probably a varnish doing caching there's
probably nginx serving Pages then there
is something doing the PHP or whatever
language
processes uh
distribution and then there is a process
which again is going to talk to a lot of
different things so what is exactly the
thing that goes wrong
unfortunately there are things that are
repeating and there is always a lot of
specific
questions that can be with each of these
uh we can see it is the cloud for
trigger
these English connections run out was
the page actually cached somewhere
because you I especially picked the
picture with uh blue and yellow
lines because one of them was like
and the page is served by cloudflare and
another one was Pages search by origin
and it was a static page so why the heck
went half of the pages to our origin why
we are not caching it where we could
that
uh there are questions with uh web
server all of these proposable processes
in fbm and actually CPU Cycles
which
is a thing which I working in a hosting
company I
was testing a lot and I found that one
of the very easy explanations usually
works very well so if serving one
request takes like half a second 500
milliseconds and this is not database
time but mostly something happening in
the whatever PHP our JavaScript wherever
then if we have 10 cores then 10 cores
can serve in one second 20 requests
if we have one
request a response taking two and a half
seconds then well we can probably
respond with uh for for respond to four
requests per second
uh
when we are now thinking about the kind
of the first
data set deck then I accidentally did a
similar thing a couple of days ago
when there was a question
from
from one of teams that uh why some
servers
giving error 500s and I took the logs
and uh going over I found that there was
a SEO tool doing site scan SEO tools are
very bad for your sites because they are
often visiting pages that are not cached
because people don't go to all of the
million Pages you have
but it
it shows very nicely what are the slow
requests and I found that for some
reason
some specific and these are actually
category Pages were taking uh very long
I picked a specific category pages
and started running just a curl to see
how long it takes quarter time is just
my my Alias that runs curl and outputs
not what it received but just how long
it took to do which is kind of nicer to
do than in a browser and well I have
also another command which is time Loop
so it's doing the same thing over and
over and again so currently I think I
opened five browser tabs started running
this 30 second codes a 30 second
requests with changing cache poster
at the end just changing number to make
sure it's not cached
and I think in 10 minutes the developer
was in slack asking that why are you
interested in this product
because all of the New Relic alerts had
been went off that there is a lot of
very slow requests reaching the site so
basically and I think uh here is the
picture
so the blue blue area is one minute so I
did I think it's uh 10 requests per
minute
and I was able to basically crash the
site with 10 requests per per minute I
could probably variate more or the
categories what I'm looking and
everything because there is site map
where I can get these but here it's uh
very simple basically boom and the site
is gone
uh
now the good part of this log is
actually that
it had at the end of the line also
similar seconds the seconds don't match
exactly because I'm taking them from
kind of a slightly different part of the
test
but I can very easily understand what's
going on there
unfortunately
when we are looking at your average wave
access log then it turns out that it
doesn't have that kind of data
and it is very difficult to understand
what is the application actually doing
while it's under stress
because uh for me the indicator that
it's just running long long time is uh
um is indicator which helps me find
but there are other mistakes in this
particular line
first the IP address
because often the web requests comes
through different parts parts for
example it starts with a Cloud Player
golfer comes to your loot balancer
whatever Ingress there it goes to
Varnish and so and so on
and uh
the web server usually or actually the
one which is currently processing gets
there gets the request from the previous
guy
so by default everything tends to be uh
the
previous guy's IP
next question is the time
when you're looking at the time in nginx
logs
then what time you're actually seeing
any idea
it's a time of end of request
so if you are trying to kind of like
find a race condition
which request came first and crashed the
site
then you are going to find my 30 second
requests way after things happen well
there is no milliseconds because and
when we are talking about
4 million requests per minute then you
need to couple of have a couple of
decimals to think about that
the duration
and also what served that was it
actually this uh application maybe it
was a statical file and I should kind of
like completely get rid of that uh from
the logs to make it more easily readable
uh fortunately the the version I was
using there
was kubernetes
Ingress nginx which has a default
logging format I think unlike Engineers
Ingress there is a completely different
configurations engineering Ingress and
Ingress nginx and I especially shout out
to my colleagues who have named the
Ingress engineics as nginx Ingress so
when you are whenever I'm going to look
for a configuration settings I'm kind of
like just going crazy
uh anyway it has cool things it actually
tells it has correct IP address
uh time okay
it does have the time it took to serve
time actually how it how long it took to
talk to Upstream there is also a
specific IP of this Upstream service and
then I know aha okay this one went to
these guys and now I can start looking
what they did there so providing more
information is log files is something
that
when you are setting up the system uh
which is better than the first time
first thing because afterwards everybody
forgets that uh
uh there is a need to kind of like
configure the server because server
usually gets together like configured
the first thing and nobody looks at that
later
this is now a bit uh
wider View and uh while it is actually
copied from Excel because I needed to
get this data somewhere on one page this
is actually from Google Cloud's
uh what's the
stackdriver or whatever is there the
logging logging system so the same
requests I showed have actually three
different types
so we have the end of request processing
time which uh thankfully is very
informative I know when nothing when
nothing stopped happening where
everything stopped happening there is a
time of receiving the log line
and usually the first one is the time
the lock was received in some kind of
logging system it is very common when
you're loading the logs into pushing
them into elastic or wherever you are
running them that they tend to have the
time you are seeing is the time it was
received and this is kind of like uh it
usually takes a bit of configuration or
making sure the field is named timestamp
or actually looks like a timestamp or
something like that
but uh
yeah probably this time doesn't look
automatically like that
so
we actually do need
did we get three quests in which order
they actually came in and then we can
start off trying to see that what is the
relation what why did things go the way
they went because I think one of the
very common problems when things start
to snowball is
that there is some kind of database lock
something in the back end is happening
or maybe the server is making some
external request to somewhere and this
kind of like uh request stall and uh
server eventually is dead
this is actually how I like my locks
this is my own lock configuration my
default
configuration for nginx if anybody ever
wants that like you are welcome to I
don't know find me on whatever Media or
here ask me later I can I can show you
that I have also on next next slide but
I do have the request start time I have
the request end time I have a request
duration okay I could calculate having
one time and duration I can calculate
all that time but it's kind of like very
convenient to have them so I can sort
the request by start or end and if I see
like for example that all of the
requests started ending at the same
moment it means this moment is when the
lock was released wherever and I I can
confirm this was a lock related problem
her remote address user if it's logged
on remote Port the remote Port is also
cool because when you're looking at
all of the traffic coming from mobile
operators who are doing that ip4
then probably the only way if they are
locking how you can go to the police and
find out the person who is behind that
is if you are knowing the remote Port if
they are logging it
request length how much data was sent
during the request this is a post
request I'm showing here so I know ah
okay it's five kilobytes looking at the
same application at some time I started
seeing very long post requests so I knew
there was a problem at the site which
was sending data to this particular API
for some reason the requests to grow
growing so I needed to fix the front end
two interesting things request URI and
URI what's the difference
one is the one which web server got and
the other one is actually what script
was executed as a result of that
which again kind of often helps me
understand what's going on arguments
that are not there is a hosts oh and I
have a couple of host names the host is
actually the host header of the request
yeah you're saying it can be forged cool
if I see it forged then this is
interesting information for me so I need
to probably look at these requests more
and also actual hostname which is the
server from the web server configuration
so I know exactly which part of web
server was serving that status points
different content type again very cool
to know what the server actually thinks
it's sent back it's Json okay but if
let's say if we are I don't know getting
maybe accessing CSS and it outputs I
don't know HTML it's a bit suspicious
fbm1 did it use actual application so I
can very easily sort out from the logs
the lines that are running the code
because if it was not running the code
probably it's not causing me DDOS
problems it's not something that uh
hackers are trying to I don't know abuse
so very information Upstream response
time which might be different from the
request time because it takes time and
also the difference between these two
times uh shows me that uh okay if if
they have closed it's not a problem but
if they are very separate there is a
question why does the
response from the Upstream
take so much but the full request is
longer again when you're looking at the
servers doing bad stuff during attacks
there are moments when the two things
get kind of like uh much separated
and they're also very cool and fakeable
uh header x414
we have been coming back to that but I
recall uh Ethan once uh mentioned that
when you were looking at spectixes kind
of access logs it was interesting to see
that people snooping around were using
some kind of vpns or proxies and this
proxy is very nicely added the X forward
in four headers so it was also actually
visible but it what it was
So currently it's actually interesting
the main address is a z-scaler and then
the four or the four addresses some from
from South Africa
that scalar is basically what it says
zero trust provider they are describing
themselves as a leading zero trust
whatever stuck in the world
so basically as somebody is using their
Network and accessing this site
the configuration
uh actually I'd like to see same thing
also in the health charts of uh English
engineers and the other one as well is
calculating some specific values
uh like uh I'm setting because it can be
only set on the server level so it's
like below
I'm setting the start time you can
actually in nginx record the start time
of request if you are configuring a
variable yourself
so this will be the start and the final
request time will be just the end of the
request which is usually locked
why I'm doing this safe numeric values
well this is because I like to put the
numbers
in Json as numbers not strings makes it
easier for later to interpret
turns out that it is very important
whenever your
configuring your log ingest to make sure
everything gets proper data type
for example we found out during lock
Shields we wanted to make some filters
for IP addresses and use consider
notation not adding iprs is one by one
to see what the red team is doing of
course
or maybe real users and turns out that
if it's string it doesn't work it needs
to be IP address so you need to make
sure all of the formats are always
correct and it's always again better to
do these things at the very beginning of
your logging process
and then get the real IP
again my examples are from from my life
where I'm behind Cloud fair so here is
two things first I'm using Cloud for
specific header I can be sure that it's
a cloud fair is not letting to letting
it be letting it be faked I've tried at
least I couldn't maybe some some people
can and only if it's coming from their
IP addresses
um to be sure that it's not spoofed and
I can always uh trust that
interestingly the IPR set of clover has
changed over past years
I think not not very often but there was
a change there was a part of I think it
was this 104 16 or something like that
where they took one's part which is
currently used for Apple has for iCloud
Pro users some private browsing solution
which is using cloudflare Akamai and
fastly networks to root the traffic
so it's going there also Cloud first own
zero trust I think is using the eyepiece
from that range so it turns out that
when you don't know that you can
actually start thinking that okay how
are the users coming from cloudflare or
what's happening
I told her doesn't provide their users
of Ip of course in X4 or before
uh funny part with that is whenever you
are setting up web applications
there is this chain of all of these
participating points that all need to
get the first and correct IP address
so
my my configuration on that part is that
when I get it in the Ingress I make sure
it's Cloud for IP I make sure nobody
else but go upload for a gun access this
uh our Ingress and then I
uh
Uber ride the X forwarded four with this
information that I know to be correct so
there is no question because X forward
E4 can contain multiply purchases and
it's always the question did the
programmer actually read the manual
correctly and decide if they need to
take the first or last one or maybe the
middle one or I don't know put them all
together
so all of this path and uh
it's just uh I'm just kind of like
starting from the in inside most thing
let's say PHP setting my X4 or the four
header and seeing if it comes the stupid
number comes through if it comes it's
bad if it's some internal IP it's bad so
I kind of like go to set up to the end
because there is always some smarter
somewhere who has decided to implement
whatever they found on stack Exchange
so when you're looking from getting uh
for instruction to creating client Type
e in PHP you are probably arriving on
this page
which has actually for some reason this
one isn't the topmost transfer there is
a lot more wrong on answers before you
come to that for unknown reasons maybe
it's so down because it's a security
problem so say they are having those
comments which uh so those answers which
don't explicitly say they are security
problems up there
editors note and comment this is bad
thing
but yeah somebody always does that so
you have kind of like passed everything
through they are going to find from
somewhere from some rare header the
wrong information and using it because
it's so cool
client type views also
uh let's now look at the things uh once
more from the uh
so what was actually behind this picture
that I was able to understand thanks to
just looking at the count of requests
uh
this was a nice MP4 video
sent to customer our cover customer by a
concerned citizen
who demonstrated that they found a login
page and
opening process inspector there is a
request and then they are going with
that to copying the things and going
with these into something called open
bullet which probably is a good tool for
you to test your own servers in the same
manner
and I said okay I understand okay you're
doing a login for end times uh the
hashing of the password probably takes
time it's okay it's it's easy to crush
the server
and then I watched uh
why does it say error 400
not something like uh bad password or or
whatever no not matching
and then I found that
huh script kid he didn't notice that the
original uh question had a content type
of application Json
this one had uh
form encoded so there's some kind of a
middleware API decided that okay I'm not
going to do anything
and despite being the API doing some
decision on the most Elementary part of
just making sure that okay this doesn't
look like a Json request that's not
serve that
he was able to take that down
uh
there was a
wrong content type I think it was
related to the question that just
somehow the node.js backend died again
because
I've seen a lot of cases where people
don't understand that they know no
chairs application when you launch it
it's basically a single thread or let's
say thing single worker you need to kind
of like make sure there is more of them
doing the work
so probably that's what uh died there
uh alternative font scenario which I've
seen for multiple times is
more from requests so forward it to
whatever is behind the API elastic
which gets an error which is not caught
promises are not fulfilled and system
dies very cool
that's now the second DDOS mitigation
it started with a request set like that
it quickly went up into trying to
provide changing URL and bypassing
caching
interestingly this is wrong query
parameter they didn't check what's the
correct query in this system so it
didn't actually try to run unique
queries for everything
it still crashed because there was just
so much of them
and
the interesting part is that the kind of
starting of the cloudflare cloudflare
has very good level 70 dos rules
there is basically signature number 15
which I think is that it has a strange
looking
user agents but the most probable one is
that the origin is we're going to give
errors
so basically Cloud first level seven
DDOS protection very much depends on
your server dying
so basically if you feel it's too much
start giving error 500 Cloud for takes
over just make sure you kind of like
stop giving 500 later
uh so this one was
again four million requests I think the
one minute and four million requests
kind of like seems to be a repeating
pattern here something like 4000 IP
addresses doing somewhat more than
thousand requests but it's uh not that
much and unfortunately most of the rate
limiting is very stupid you can rate
limit requests per IP
and if they are doing thousand requests
to basically the same uh URL then it's
uh
just uh for them it's just a thousand
requests which is completely different
than actual user traffic which is
usually requesting different files
different AP endpoints and so on
and we also learned that recovery took a
way uh longer why did it take longer
because uh
all of these paths
somewhere it was stuck
there was probably some problems with
Ingress
there was probably some PHP adapter
application back there which was
struggling it probably had overloaded
the SQL database and whatever so until
all of these queues kind of like empty
themselves the site was down so one
minute tdos
even if the protections click kick in at
uh
second 30.
then recovery from that might be
actually maybe five minutes maybe eight
minutes or something like that depending
how well you have looked what actually
is happening back there so that's the
point where I went away from looking at
the
at the access logs and I started
actually correlating the times
to the logs I have about the different
server components performance again
that's why it's very important to have
correct times because otherwise I can't
correlate these things if it's kind of
like lock has lines which are telling
that when everything ended then how can
I find the start of the attack
uh
which comes brings us me to the last
example
which is
the detection has left the house
uh it happened uh some time ago the
official answer came later to me was
that oops Yeah we had some kind of uh
problem with false positives or false
negatives in rule number whatever 15. uh
I don't know how they didn't notice that
the server is giving error 500 also but
anyway somehow it happened and for me it
also happened to be a very inconvenient
case because it wasn't our Enterprise
Cloud for it was client's own uh
cloudflare Pro which is a very cool
service
but I can't get the gold Cloud for rocks
and I'm actually
kind of like I totally like that even if
they let the Adidas protect Adidas is
through and whatever mistakes that
happen we are still friends because I
can get super quality Json formatted
logs that have start time with
milliseconds and time with milliseconds
what happened everything and I can just
sit and take all of the four million
requests and then start uh painfully
going through them and seeing what
actually happened
uh this time I didn't have so what I had
to do was I had to resolve to whatever
the actual web servers had provided to
me and it turned out that the yellow is
the normal traffic and the peak is then
uh what they were able to take until
they went down so I think there is
currently capacity I don't know by I
maybe 15 20 times so I think kind of
like for normal use everything is okay
but of the 4 million requests I think I
saw in uh in my side logs I think it was
58 000 or something like that it was 1.6
percent of the logs that I actually was
able to get
and uh started to work and uh draw the
duration of that Tech and uh whatever
happened
and then I noticed
that actually
leave my locks were with error 499
uh
which means that the client has left the
house
uh basically the Adidas serves very
nicely made the requests and didn't
bother to wait until the end
for my side all of this long chain or
whole of the requests was booted up the
application started working and the guy
said okay I'm going to do something next
so I had full of the request log of
these things
I also found that okay there was a fake
IP addresses which turned out uh
multi-car statuses and something like
that uh I found out that the default
Ingress configuration is trying to reach
the back end three times
so basically our own Ingress was
increasing the load on application which
was already down and instead of just
saying error by 500 no guys go home no
nothing to see here it just kept can I
get something can I get something
so uh and I also found that the log is
very cool because the log at some point
has one IP address and at some some
point has at the same time the three IP
address is separated by commas uh it's
very difficult to parse that
uh I also found the numbers went went
back and because I didn't have any any
real IP addresses I started looking what
what fun I can do with uh fake IP
addresses and I found that this
particular botnet is just generating
addresses with all four uh parts of ip4
address starting from 100 to 255.
so again interesting piece of
information uh to uh to use
that is also interesting that some of
the IP ranges are not spoofed I'm not
sure why
and then I went actually to look how
things are happening in the in the uh
container land and I found that yes in
50 seconds after start of the attack we
detected that the hell aliveness has
gone it's basically at the end of the
attack
it wanted to ask the server to go down
nicely
the server was busy dying it didn't
listen so it took like totally five
minutes to get to the point when uh it
finally said okay container go out start
new one so uh
yeah that was uh the story and oh and I
actually tried because of the worker
connections uh uh got full uh on the
second 23 of the attack when it was just
ramping up
so
when you are whenever you are seeing uh
anything happening do you try to get all
of the data and which is available from
that side and then go back to all of the
steps and see what kind of information
you can get from there for me I
currently have these things in a memos
so next time this happens to me I can
easily copy the strings of the messages
from here and just see the same things
in the uh
logs very easily
thank you
we have like one minute for questions
considering there is also
a price for that then it's possible that
you're going to get the price if you ask
now
oh question
this ah there's a question there maybe
you can run the mic
wait for a mic thanks
dito dito's are usually result of uh
asynchronous effort you need to provide
more effort than an attacker does
looking at that and looking at what
you've learned in the in the last couple
of years how would you design a new
environment to be as resilient as
possible
oh it's uh
I have been always thinking that I need
to build smart protections on my side
so I one thing I want to do which Cloud
for currently doesn't let me do is to be
able to detect if there will be the
number a number of requests with exactly
the same path
is rising uh faster than expected so you
can
do the rate limiting by default It Is by
IP but with nginx you can actually
specify what you are using for a string
and being able to modify that and decide
when exactly you are going to just throw
error 500s is something I've been trying
to do for uh for a long time and and
also using more security to to do that
if that's available or then just
Engineers own rate limiting so I can
just throw my hands up and say oh header
500 Cloud Fair please save me and
hopefully in 30 seconds the ignite
Plover and the White Horse or whatever
arrives
thanks
we need some competition for the best
question maybe one more
anything
well then
yeah then the the only question is also
the winning question and you can later
pick a correctly sized uh uh hoodie or
the voucher for twenty dollars in starch
press Bookshop from the back of the
stage thank you thank you to Peters