- Hey everybody.
I'm Alyssa Miller, a hacker,
a security researcher,
cybersecurity professional.
I'm the Business
Information Security Officer
for S&P Global Ratings.
And it is absolutely my
pleasure to be here with you
at RSA today, we're talking about talent
and workforce management in
the cybersecurity industry
and those things that we need to do
from an industry perspective in order
to make our workforce more sustainable
Over the course of the pandemic,
if you live in the UK
or you paid attention
to some of the headlines
that came out of that area,
you know what the British Government went
through this program,
they called a rethink, retool, reboot.
And I was kinda broken
hardy when I saw this
because the whole idea of this was
they were encouraging
people who are working
in one industry to pursue
a career in cybersecurity.
And they had different examples,
but it was one example,
that is the reason why
it kinda bothered me
was they brought up a barista
and they said that this
barista, Justin, you know,
his next job could be in cybersecurity,
he just didn't know it yet.
And they did others with
ballerinas and some other things.
And these did not go over well,
which is part of why
it concerns me because
I have been talking for the
last year using this idea
of a barista and how a barista
can make that transition
from their role making
coffee into cyber security.
So I wanna reset on this
metaphor a little bit
and I wanna share with you a story.
So, I was working in a consultancy
and I was trying to hire
cyber security professionals.
And one of the resumes
that came across my desk,
was for this person who
had worked as a barista
but never worked in a technical field.
And it was one when, when it came to me,
the HR person said right away like,
I realized this is
probably not one you want.
And I said, well, wait,
let me take a look.
And so I read through
it and you know what?
What if I told you that as I considered
the skills that a barista has,
I could see the way that those skills
would translate to a cybersecurity career.
What if I told you I hired that person?
And they were an amazing
security consultant.
Sure, they needed some technical knowledge
but I could see they had
the technical aptitude.
Would you believe me if I told you that?
Well, as you might've noticed
from the title of this session,
that's exactly where we're going.
How can we leverage the idea
of a barista in a coffee shop
or other non-traditional roles
that people may come from,
when they join cybersecurity?
I'm willing to bet that most of you,
maybe at least half have some
pretty interesting stories
about how you got into cybersecurity
that have nothing to do
with technology whatsoever.
I'm the co-host of a podcast
called "The Uncommon Journey".
And you know what, that's what
we focus on with every guest,
we bring in guests who have
all sorts of unique stories
because we wanna highlight
all the unique stories
of how people ended up in
this particular industry.
So we're gonna use this barista metaphor,
we're gonna keep coming back to Justin.
And we're gonna talk about,
how skills that Justin might
have, from being a barista,
would make him a great
fit and cyber security.
Just wait, you're gonna see.
Now, let's talk about the other headlines,
the headlines that are all over the news
when you look at cybersecurity,
you've seen these right?
Four million unfilled
jobs at the end of 2019,
cybersecurity suffers
from this talent shortage,
Oh, the great cyber security
talent shortage continues,
all of these alarmist
headlines talking about how
we just don't have enough
people in cybersecurity.
We don't have enough people
to hire for all the jobs
we have.
You've heard things like
talent gap, skills shortage,
all of these different terms
to describe the story that,
there's no enough people
to fill all these jobs.
What I'm gonna tell you that,
the problem might be just
a little bit different,
we don't have a talent shortage,
we have a talent gap.
We in cybersecurity do a terrible job,
of maintaining a workforce
that is sustainable
and manageable and can
take us into the future.
It's not because of a lack of interest.
Think about it.
How many of those aspiring professionals,
people who wanna get
a job in cybersecurity
do you hear from on a daily basis?
But they can't find jobs.
We have 4 million open jobs,
countless people looking for
jobs that can't find them.
It doesn't sound to me
like a talent shortage.
That sounds to me like
we're doing something wrong.
So last year I dove in,
I had been hearing these stories,
these different narratives
about this talent shortage
and just, you know, how
nobody could find the talent
they needed for these roles.
And I was hearing those other stories
from the aspiring security professionals,
people coming out of college,
who couldn't find jobs last year, at RSA
I went to a dinner that was hosted
for a number of cybersecurity graduates.
And they expressed to me the
trouble they were having,
finding jobs in cybersecurity.
So I started to do research,
I surveyed thousands
of aspiring and experienced
cybersecurity professionals.
I interviewed hundreds of recruiters
and hiring managers to find
out what they were seeing.
I even did research
into online job postings
to understand what was going on there.
And I'm gonna share all
of this research with you
because what I found supports
that same conclusion that,
it's not really a problem
of having enough talent,
it's how we search for that talent
and how we go about
maintaining this workforce.
That is really what's causing
our troubles when it comes
to hiring for cybersecurity jobs.
Now there's a lot of stories to tell
and I would love to share
with you the countless
reams of data that I've got
but we're gonna highlight
a few things here
and we're gonna work from that.
And I'm gonna share with you some tactics
that your organizations
can employ tomorrow
in order to start making strides
in improving this situation
and building a more
sustainable workforce model.
So, one of the first questions I asked,
I'm gonna be honest, when
I started this research
I too thought maybe it was
a matter of the job seekers
that were doing it wrong.
I thought they, if I could
just look into this information
I could figure out what it
is that they're doing wrong
and I could give them tools to correct.
Now the reality is I
did find some strategies
that I've shared
in other sessions with
aspiring professionals
on how they can be better adept
at finding that first job.
But the reality is, there
are issues in our industry
in how we handle this.
So, because I was focused on job seekers,
well, first things I did was
I asked those job seekers,
what their job search was like.
I asked them, how long have
you been looking for a job?
Let's just understand how
long do these people sit
and look for jobs when
they already have maybe
graduated high school,
graduated college,
they've got degrees, some
of them have certifications.
Let's look at these
aspiring professionals.
How long does it take?
And by the way, this data set
comes from all over the world.
I had people in many different countries,
it was very dispersed.
Some of them, as I said,
had college degrees,
some high school diploma,
some had cyber security certifications.
We're gonna talk more about
that in a few minutes,
but what you can see here,
is that in an industry that
has 4 million open jobs
these aspiring professionals,
who've gone to school
in some cases for this,
will spend three months or
longer looking for a job.
Look at that, way more than half,
more than a quarter of them
takes seven months or longer.
And you know what I said, that, you know,
some have degrees, some don't,
there is no correlation between
degrees and other things,
and how long these jobs searches took.
I even asked them, you
know, do you have a mentor?
Do you have degrees?
What did you do prior?
There was no correlation.
What I saw was this, these times
these jobs search lengths
were evenly distributed
across all those other demographics.
So that's concerning, but,
you might look at this
and you say, well, all right, Alyssa
these are people who've never
worked in the industry before,
I mean it's hard to find
some entry level jobs
and that's fair.
But I didn't just ask the,
the aspiring professionals
how long it took them to find a job,
I asked the experienced professionals
how long did it take them to
find a job, and you know what?
It didn't change a whole lot.
Now you do see one thing that changed,
is okay 46% of them do find a
job in less than two months.
That's good.
Okay, little less than half
but that means the other
more than half, almost 54%.
It takes them three months or longer.
What's more concerning is that 23%,
very close to a quarter
of them who will search
for seven months or longer
to find their next job.
So these are people with
demonstrated experience
in cybersecurity, who
also can't find jobs.
So suddenly this narrative,
about there not being enough talent,
this narrative about
well they're entry level,
so of course, it's hard to
find, that starts to fall apart
because we see the problem
as much bigger than that.
And this is where things
really started to unravel.
And I started to,
really dig in and try to figure out, okay,
there's more to this
story than meets the eye.
I need to find more.
So what up, I asked other
questions on the survey.
This one was really
particularly interesting,
because this comes up a lot,
if you follow me on Twitter, by the way,
you'll see me tweeting
this stuff all the time.
The idea of bad job descriptions.
When I asked,
both aspiring and experienced
cybersecurity professionals
what the biggest challenge
was that they ran into,
you can see overwhelmingly,
they said it was bad job descriptions.
More so than salary, more so
than company culture, more so
than finding the right level
of role or finding remote work
simply what the job
description stand in the way.
So again, this is an indication
that we as hiring organizations
and hiring managers
and recruiters are not
doing this the right way.
That there's something wrong
in how we are searching for talent.
If we can't find these
individuals who wants so
desperately to be a part of our industry
or who are already here and
just wanna find a new gig.
So these are some very telling tales,
and I started to dig in more.
I really wanted to start to
develop some ideas of what it is
that we're doing wrong.
So I told you, I investigated hundreds
of job descriptions online.
I talked to hiring managers
and recruiters, as well.
And what I found,
was that our job description suck
and our hiring expectations
are completely out of whack.
They make it impossible for us to maintain
a sustainable workforce, and
that's what we need to fix.
So let's talk about what
we can do as cybersecurity
professionals in this
industry to make this better.
Let's start with job descriptions.
Let's talk about these for a minute.
Let me share a few examples with you.
So let's start with this job description
for a cyber security intern or
Information Security Intern.
As an intern,
think about your definition of an intern.
It's usually someone coming out of school
or someone may be still in school,
who's gonna work for a reduced rate,
they're gonna come in and kinda learn
some of the skills of the trade.
They do, maybe some lower level
tasks for your organization
things that you otherwise
wouldn't be able to get to.
Right, that's what we do with interns?
But look at this job
description, for an intern,
a bachelor's degree, a
CISSPA, CISA, CISM or CEH.
So we want them to have such too
before they get an internship.
And that's, what's pretty funny,
a memo seven years working
in Information Technology
Security, excuse me, what?
Seven years of experience
insecurity for an intern!
I don't know about you
but when I hire somebody with
seven years of experience
they're probably going into a senior role.
So this is problematic.
So the only one I found,
check this one out.
This one goes on for an
Information Security Architect,
for three pages,
we're gonna just this intricate detail
of all the responsibilities
for an Information Security Architect.
Now understand,
an architect is a very senior role,
we expect them to have a wide
breadth of skills, no doubt.
But look at the laundry list here,
look at the list of requirements,
all these various technologies and things
that this organization who I have,
for their right have obfuscated here.
Just look at what they're asking for,
what magical unicorn out there
is gonna fit a job like this?
There just isn't one.
This isn't realistic, but
this is what job descriptions
in cybersecurity look like.
Now, you, I can hear you
thinking at home at your desk,
and you're like, well, Alyssa,
I mean these are a couple examples
and I know you tweet some more.
No, the fact of the matter is,
this is the predominant
pattern that we see.
The majority of cybersecurity
job descriptions have issues,
just like these.
You see them asking for
CISSP from, you know,
for entry-level roles,
while you have to have,
five years of experience to get us CISSP.
We see them, some of the
worst ones I've seen,
where they ask for, you know,
10 years of Kubernetes experience.
Anybody know how long
Kubernetes has been around?
Not 10 years.
So things like this that are
just absolutely impossible,
and what does it do?
It turns away those job applicants,
who might be a perfect fit
for what you actually need,
if you could just write
a decent job description.
So I've mentioned a couple
of times now, certifications.
Let's talk about what I
found when I started looking
at job descriptions in
relation to certifications.
How many of you list an
industry certification
when you post a job?
Well, the fact of the matter
is I know for it's most of you
and that's not necessarily a bad thing,
but it really depends
on what certifications
you're looking for,
and what your expectations
are, and whether or not
you're providing other ways
to fill that requirement.
Or is that the only one?
So in looking at job descriptions,
what I found first and
foremost was that 71%
of entry level jobs
Was the CISSP as a requirement.
In most cases, they specifically
said the reason I take them
as entry level, if they
didn't specifically
call it out themselves,
was that they were asking
for less than three years of experience.
Well, that right there
is pretty problematic
when you're asking for a
five-year certification,
that doesn't work.
91%, now this is really interesting.
91% of job descriptions list
of requirement for a degree
and a CISSP or an equivalent,
interesting.
What about all those people
who don't have degrees?
We hear from them all the time,
I have many colleagues in
this industry who never
graduated college and do a terrific job.
They're amazingly skilled and talented.
What are those people who don't have a CS
or a computers, a cybersecurity degree?
They didn't go for engineering,
they went for communications
or other things,
don't they have skills to bear?
But we say that we want
a degree in cybersecurity
or in computer science or a related field.
That's kind of problematic too, isn't it?
So thinking about the CISSP and
the way it comes up so often
and I don't mean to pick
on ISC squared, right?
I like the CISSP don't get me wrong.
It's how hiring managers and
hiring organizations treat it,
that becomes problematic.
Here's the story,
so you see 91% of job descriptions, right?
So CISSP record 71% of entry
level say they want it.
Well, ISC squared tells
us as of October of 2020,
there are 2.8 million
cybersecurity professionals
in the world.
Okay, so those are actively
working cybersecurity professionals.
This is from their 2020 workforce study.
But as of that same time, October 2020,
only 142,000
of those professionals
have a CISSP certification.
That's about 5%, do
the math, 71% versus 5%
91% versus 5% something doesn't work here.
Certifications are not the answer.
And in fact, when I look at
the information from my survey,
only 49% thinking back to these degrees,
holds an IT or a
cybersecurity related degree.
So I've got 91% of my job
description say, you must have,
but only 49% of the
people coming in actually
have a degree that is
in one of those fields.
So I think you're starting
to see the problems here,
you're starting to see what it is,
that is causing this
disconnect, this talent gap.
It's not a shortage, it's the gap.
Because we just can't bridge a connection
between our hiring and those professionals
and talented individuals
that are out there just
waiting to be a part of our organizations.
So the whole point of this is,
this isn't a sustainable model.
We need to look at how do
we make it sustainable.
Because we're doing this to ourselves,
if we can't find
cybersecurity professionals,
it's all self-inflicted wounds.
So how do we get better at this?
How do we highly progress?
How do we make sure,
that we're able to adjust?
Not only are our job descriptions
in our hiring practices
but literally our
expectations and how we handle
our employees to make a
more sustainable model.
Here's where the problems begin,
when we look at the core issue,
when we build job descriptions,
when we build a job role
and we're gonna, we're
gonna talk about everything
that's involved in that job.
We are so hyper focused on all
the various technology tools
and techniques that these people
must come in the door with.
And we think that's how we
measure a successful candidate.
Now, wait a minute,
I've heard some of you,
I've heard you say it,
and I've said it myself.
Why could teach anybody the skills?
I want them to have something else, right?
And we'll talk about what
some of those things are,
that what people say they want.
So if that's the case,
why are we so hyper-focused
on technologies?
Why do we expect people to come in
and be able to immediately sit down
and expertly configure
our Sims or our wafts
or our cloud security
environments, our CASB Solutions.
Why do we think that that's
what we need to hire?
I'll tell you why.
And it came from those
interviews that I did
with hiring managers.
For some reason,
we have this prevalent
belief in cybersecurity
that we're gonna be perfect.
And that the only way to achieve
perfection in our security,
is to bring in people who've
already worked in the industry
and already know things and
have them fill our roles.
That's what we do.
We do it over and over again.
The job descriptions prove it.
Hiring managers attitudes, prove it over
and over and over again,
but that's not realistic.
The fact of the matter
is looking at candidates,
based on what technological
skills they have,
what they've worked with in the past,
which tools they've used, which, you know,
Olsen challenges they've done.
This is great information, but it is not.
What is the primary
measure of whether or not
they're gonna be successful?
Think about it.
What other industry do we do this in?
What other industry out
there on this planet,
do we sit there and say the only people
we're gonna hire, are people
who already have the job skills
necessary to sit down
and do the job tomorrow?
Where do we do it?
Doctors, you know, people are
responsible for human lives.
We don't do it there, do we?
No, they have a very structured
progression of, on the job
learning through residencies
and all the things that
they do, think about that.
Doctors, learn on the job,
but we can't do it with a
cybersecurity professionals.
What about skilled trades,
plumbers, electricians,
what do they do?
They just show up and they've
got a master certificate
and they can go work anywhere they want?
No, they go through apprenticeships,
they learn on the job, and by the way,
when they're learning on the job,
they get paid to learn on the job.
We don't tell plumbers and
electricians and doctors,
oh go learn on your own,
go figure it all out,
and then come to us with that information.
We don't tell them that,
we give them a very structured career path
that they need to follow,
but we don't do that in cyber security.
We need to move out of this approach,
as hiring organizations we need to start
investing in our people again.
I know this is a wildly unpopular idea,
the thought of spending money
to train our individuals,
because we're also worried.
And I think of the
cartoon I've seen on this
and you probably have too,
well what happens if we train them,
and then they go in and get
another job somewhere else?
Because we know
cybersecurity is a hot field.
So I don't, I don't wanna pay
for them to go get an OCP.
I don't wanna pay for them
to go to this vendor trainee.
So I'll split the cost with 'em
or I'll reimburse them after
they successfully pass it,
and they've worked here
for six months afterwards.
We do all these crazy things,
we probably use restrictions
because we don't wanna
invest in our people.
We don't wanna bring in people
who we have to invest in from the start.
We think we're just
gonna keep hiring people
who already have all the skills.
It doesn't work that way,
that's not sustainable.
For obvious reasons, if every
organization in the world
only hired people with experience,
what would we do?
Suddenly, we wouldn't have
people with experience anymore
'cause they had all retired
and we'd have nothing.
That's a pretty obvious issue.
And it's something that
we need to correct,
but it's not the only issue.
Here's another one that
you're probably gonna
moan and groan when I say it,
the idea of diversity,
and I told you before,
that a candidate success isn't based
on their technology
skills alone, and in fact,
I would tell you it's not
even the primary contributor.
If you think about it,
whether it's an individual
or at the industry level,
think about it at a macro level,
how do we be successful inside?
How are we successful in cybersecurity?
It's our problem solving
skills that make us successful
in cyber security is it not?
That's what we do every day,
we're here to solve problems.
Maybe we go looking for some of them,
and then we solve them.
How do we find those problems?
How do we solve them?
How do we get better at problem solving?
The key is diversity.
Now I'm gonna give you
some real talk here.
There's some dog whistles out there,
when I start talking
diversity, people say,
oh yeah, well, I hire
for diversity of thought.
And that's a way of saying,
I don't wanna look at
demographics of people,
I just I'm gonna hire and,
or you hear the other one is
I want the best candidate.
Well, what is your definition
of the best candidate?
Does the diversity of their
background play into that?
Because it should, consider this example,
what happens if you hire
say 20 white male engineers
and another 10 white female engineers
and you're gonna build
new scanners for the TSA?
What happens?
Well, if you know the story,
it should sound familiar
because it did happen.
We ended up with a bunch of scanners,
that were unfairly indicating
issues with women of color
because of their hairstyles.
Why didn't that get identified?
Because the people working
on it, weren't diverse.
You didn't have black
women there who would have
said right away, hey, you know what?
This is something that we
deal with in other spaces,
that might be a problem here too.
So when you say diversity of thought,
diversity of thought comes
from diversity of backgrounds,
experiences and other things.
And that diversity comes from
their demographics as
much as anything else.
So the reality is no,
I'm not saying go out
and say this job is only
open for one particular race
or whatever demographic you wanna choose.
That's not what I'm telling you.
What I am telling you is understanding
and being deliberate about
hiring for diversity,
needs to be a part of
your success criteria
for that candidate.
If you're gonna say, I'm
gonna hire the best candidate
or you're hiring for diversity of thought
you need to recognize that
diversity is a part of that.
And you have to challenge your own biases.
You have to challenge
your organization's biases
looking for people who
came up in the ranks
just the same way you did.
You're not getting diversity
of thought that way.
And then, let's talk about this idea
of core transferable skills.
And we're gonna bring Justin
and some other examples back in here now.
When I talk about core
transferable skills,
I am talking about those skills
that transcend any industry.
Things that would apply,
no matter if you were
working in hospitality,
in cybersecurity or in the arts,
what are those skills?
They're core transferable skills.
Now don't make the mistake
of talking about soft skills,
this idea of soft skills,
first of all, I hate the term
in the first place, because
it's used more as a pejorative
and it implies that they're soft,
so they're not really
the rugged foundation
on which we wanna build
things, and that's not true,
core transferable skills
are the best indicator
of how someone's gonna be
successful on a particular role.
So what do I mean
when I talk about core
transferable skills?
I'm talking about those skillsets,
that somebody learns in one job,
as I said before, and it
transcends any industry.
So while I might describe
that job in a certain way,
based on that industry,
if I bring that back and
identify what's at the core
of those skills that I
was using in that job,
now, I find what's
transferable to other roles.
So let's talk about a couple of examples.
We're not talking soft skills.
So let's talk about retail employee,
and why do I tell you
about retail employee?
Because I also hired somebody
directly out of retail,
who had no experience in cybersecurity
and has also been a wildly successful
cyber security consultant ever since.
Why did I hire this person?
Well, their resume told me two things.
One, they had customer service skills,
and I'm sorry to all my colleagues
out there in cyber
security, but we lack that,
that empathy, that ability
to understand the people
we're talking to and communicate with them
in a way that's meaningful to them,
so they'll understand and be
motivated to wanna help us.
We don't do a good job of
that in cyber security.
This is an ongoing struggle
that we need to get better at.
And so when I saw customer service,
dealing with customers day in and day out
and having to learn that that
was pretty attractive to me.
The other thing that
he listed on his resume
and it was really impressive
to me, was that he talked
about his ability to problem
solve when he was faced
with issues that affected the delivery
of their products and services.
Specifically, he
highlighted an example where
he found a problem in
their inventory system
that was affecting their
returns processing.
Now think about this for a minute.
So let's dial this back to
core transferable skills again,
that ability to be able to
see the interrelationships
between two disparate systems
that seemingly aren't related
in any way, to see how
the impact each other
and to be able to problem solve for that.
Isn't that exactly what we
wanna see in cybersecurity?
That's a core transferable skill.
That's what we need to be looking for.
That's what tells us if our candidates
are gonna be successful.
So now let's go back to our barista,
let's talk about Justin for a minute.
What skills does Justin have as a barista
that would make him a great
cybersecurity candidate?
I'm gonna tell you right
now, a barista like Justin,
given that they have all
their technical aptitude
and desire.
They're great as a SOC analyst,
they have core transferable
skills that fit right
into a SOC analyst role.
What are they?
Think about what they do every day,
a barista processes, multiple
inputs from disparate sources.
They then have to translate
those inputs into tasks
that then they're going to prioritize
and organize to make sure
that they can execute them
in the most efficient manner possible.
And then they have to focus
on efficiently delivering
that product to the customer.
All the while they also have to plan
and execute maintenance activities.
So think about this from the
SOC perspective, isn't that
exactly what you want a SOC
analyst to be able to do?
To be able to process
those multiple inputs,
use a method to prioritize
and execute them and do them
in the most efficient way possible
and delivering to the
customer with quality
and still also being able
to plan regular maintenance
and other things.
That's exactly what we want in
cyber security professionals.
Those are core transferable skills
that we need to be focused on.
Not have they worked 10 years with Splunk.
So, how do we improve this?
Let's go back to our job descriptions
and our attitudes to our hiring.
We need to be more precise
in how we build our job descriptions.
This is how we eliminate bias,
this is how we make them more
open to our professionals.
We need to be precise,
and when I say precise,
one of the things we
need to understand is,
how do we address the
skills, the experience
and the knowledge we want
them to come in with?
Each of those words has
a very different meaning.
And so when we write them
in a job description,
we need to be sure that we're
asking for the right one.
So we're not talking about
knowledge I'm talking about,
I just simply have knowledge of it.
I've read about it.
I've studied it.
Maybe I've gone to conference talks
or I've researched it myself.
That's knowledge.
So you might have some things
in your list of preferences,
that, hey, you know what?
We want you to have knowledge
in this particular thing.
Now, if you say, I want
you to have knowledge
in Splunk because you use Splunk.
And I feel like I'm picking on them.
I'm really not.
Please don't take it that way.
I could just be just as easily talking
about Security Audience or anyone else.
Is that really what I want them to have?
Maybe it is, maybe it isn't
but is that going to be effective
or do I want them to have
knowledge of maybe SIM strategies
thread Intel, thread hunting, maybe that's
the core of what I actually
need them to understand.
I can teach them the technology,
send them to training for the technology,
but maybe that's where I need it.
Now, when I say skills,
I'm talking about taking
that knowledge and putting
it into action right?
Skills are those things where they have
some demonstrated way
of
applying what they know
and using it in a real world environment.
And then finally experience,
for experience is obvious,
that's when we all talk about it,
hey I've worked on the job
and I've done this somewhere before.
So we need to be precise about these,
when we write these in job descriptions.
But let's talk about those
hiring attitudes now, too.
Now I asked the hiring
managers for what they
would tell aspiring
cybersecurity professionals
trying to get into the industry
and the word that came
up more often than not,
and I hear it every day
and it drives me insane,
Is people saying, have passion,
have passion, have passion,
have passion, have passion
all this stuff about passion,
be passionate, make sure
you're passionate about it
and have an aptitude for it.
Genuine passion for the field
trump's dry experience really?
Does it?
Look at your job descriptions?
How do you demonstrate
passion when you're passing
in a resume and it's going into an ATS,
automatic applicant tracking system
an applicant tracking system,
can't measure passion,
get this stuff out of your head.
If you wanna see them demonstrate passion,
tell them in your job description how,
is there a place where
they can submit to you,
videos that they've created,
tutorials that they've generated,
all their online content,
that they've authored,
things that would demonstrate
their mastery of the topic,
even though they don't have experience.
This involves getting
outside of just the ATS,
and the problem is that
ATS is the limiting factor
on too many of our job searches.
I told you about what happened
with that barista resume
I got it scored very low on ATS,
I only, I'm not even sure why
the HR person handed it to me
because they were so convinced
I wasn't going to want it,
but I'm so glad they did because
I hired an amazing person.
And that's what we need to do.
We need to invite more that's
what we've gotta get out
of this mode of all the
applicant tracking system
being the gate, because it breaks things.
How do we encourage applicants
to demonstrate passion?
How can we think about hiring differently?
This is where we need to go.
So, to wrap things up, how
do we bridge this divide
this talent gap from a hiring
organization perspective
the owners is on us,
we gotta do better, we've gotta do more.
First of all, we need to realign our goals
for on-the-job training.
We have to understand
that learning and training
on the job is to, what's
gonna make people successful.
We need to challenge our biases
in deliberately seek out
diversity in our candidate pool.
We need to focus on core
transferable skills,
those are so crucial
in measuring the success of any candidate.
And finally, we need to be precise
in how we word our requirements
and our preferences
and our qualifications.
And then we need to invite our candidates
to be able to share those
non-traditional ways
that they can demonstrate their expertise.
So thank you so much,
I really appreciate you
all being a part of this,
coming and attending RSA today
and being here for this talk.
I hope that you can take to
heart many of the lessons
that I learnt through this research
and work with me and the
rest of our colleagues
to truly see that hidden link that exists
between a great cup of coffee
and a great cybersecurity professional.
Thank you so much.