- Hi everyone.
I'm Lorrayne Auld.
And thank you for attending.
In this session I'll be talking about
Higher Assurance Identity Proofing
in accordance with NIST
digital identity guidelines.
Through the use of these guidelines,
I will provide you with the tools
to give you greater confidence
if the applicant truly
is who they claim to be.
Now, I know we're in a
virtual environment today,
but I will be there through chat.
So if you have any questions
throughout the presentation,
feel free to shoot a question
and I'll be there to answer.
So this is the agenda for today.
I'll be speaking to you
for about 35 minutes or so,
regarding what's driving the need
for Higher Assurance Identity Proofing.
What exactly do I mean
by identity proofing,
for in accordance with
this special pub 80063?
And then I'll go over
some of the techniques
and technologies to identify fraud.
And then wrap up with some guidance.
So remote work has exploded
during the pandemic
up to 18 times more remote work now
than what has been done in the past.
This pandemic has truly changed
how we do business today.
What was once done in
person is now done remotely.
Technology and executives
aren't driving these changes.
It's really COVID-19 that
has transformed telework,
with everyone working from home
and no longer come into the office
or going in person to their local bank.
What confidence do I have that
you are who you claim to be?
So, fraudsters are also working from home.
They are no longer working from 9-5.
With more people working remotely,
fraudsters will have
many more points of entry
to attack your organization
or your service.
But it's not just in the workplace
where fraud is taking place.
This chart, shows that
fraudsters are targeting
those facing heartstrings or hardships,
especially those out of work
who need that unemployment,
or that stimulus check or tax refund.
As an example,
corona virus unemployment insurance fraud,
was first identified in Washington
state in may of last year
and has since spread to all 50 States.
So now that we've laid out the drivers,
so let's shift and talk about,
what exactly do I mean by Higher
Assurance Identity Proofing
and why it's so important
in a COVID-19 world
to help combat identity fraud?
So, why is identity proofing needed?
So traditional identity proofing
was performed using static
knowledge face authentications.
That means to establish
trust in a digital identity.
Questions such as, what is
your mother's maiden name?
Who's deemed satisfactory
in establishing that trust?
However, with the rise in data breaches,
what's once was a secret,
has now been stolen.
So new approaches are needed
in establishing that trust,
in a digital identity to
ascertain that you truly are you.
This trust is key in
providing a foundation
for all future interactions,
where I have confidence
that the digital identity
as being presented,
truly belongs to your real life subject.
So there are new risk situations
where you can not be
a dog on the internet,
and it reliably establishes association
of the digital identity
with a real life subject.
There are also situations
where the association
is required to establish accountability
for high risk actions
such as changing the release
rate of water from a dam
or transferring $50
million to a bank account.
Identity proofing establishes
that a person is who they say they are
based on the validity
of one or more pieces
of identity evidence.
The more due diligence incorporated
into the identity proofing process,
the higher the confidence
that the applicant
is who they claim to be.
For example,
one would place little confidence
on self asserted identity.
I say I'm Sally Jones.
Therefore I am Sally Jones.
However, if I claim to be Cindy Joe,
and can provide written and
corroborated identity evidence
proving I truly am Cindy Joe,
there is much higher confidence
placed in that identity.
Now, if I provide all that documentation
to a credential service provider,
you could be pretty sure
I am who I claim to be.
So identity proofing is
thought to be done once,
at the time of enrollment or registration.
But that may not be the only case
you may be required at various stages
of the digital identity life cycle
where life events worked it.
So thinking in the physical realm,
I get identity proof periodically
for renewal my driver's license
or renewal of TSA's
Global Entry Pre-check.
same thing applies in the digital realm.
For example,
I may initially have
been identity proofing
lower assurance level,
but based on required access
to higher risk transactions,
I may be asked to be identity proofed
at a much higher level of assurance,
or in times of emergency
or transactions between strangers.
One may need to be identity proofed
to ensure that that digital identity
still belongs to that real life person,
who was initially identity
proofed at enrollment.
Or in the context of progressive proofing.
My account was initially created
based on minimal proofing
and as new privileges
or roles assigned to me,
I may be subjected to
additional identity proofing.
So in 2017, NIST released
an update to SP 80063.
The Digital Identity Guidelines.
This four volume set provides an overview
of general identity frameworks
that use digital identities,
authenticators,
and assertions together
any digital system.
One of these volumes 63A,
is solely dedicated to
enrollment and identity proofing.
And I want to mention
that these guidelines
are not solely meant
for government agencies,
but can also benefit commercial industry
where higher assurance needs are required.
So, let's talk a bit more about 80063A.
The identity proof in enrollment document.
So NIST describes the process regarding
how applicants could
prove their identities
and then become enrolled
as a valid subscriber
with an identity system.
The document also provides requirements
for applicants going through
the identity proofing
for both in-person and remote scenarios
at three different
identity assurance levels,
ranging from the lowest
level of assurance,
to the highest level of assurance.
Identity assurance level
one is the lowest level.
And essentially is self asserted
that these attributes are
neither a validated nor verified.
I am Sally Jones.
Therefore I am Sally Jones.
Identity assurance level two
essentially states that
some sort of a remote
or in-person identity
proofing is required.
For this level,
the applicant typically
uses their own equipment
to perform the remote proofing.
At the highest level,
IAL3, require some sort
of physical presence,
either in-person or via supervised remote.
Supervised remote means that
there is a person physically present
during the entire
identity proofing process.
Typically a kiosk in controlled spaces,
oversee the entire proofing process.
At the other end is a trained operator
utilizing a web cam for example,
who can remotely supervise
the entire identity proofing process
from the time that you arrive
to the time that you
complete the entire process.
If you have any questions,
feel free to put them in chat.
So, how does determine exactly
what identity assurance level to pick?
Well, NIST developed a decision tree
to help organization
select the appropriate
identity assurance level.
This decision tree uses the results
of a credential service
provider's risk assessment
of the digital services offered
to provide the assurance level
provided by the identity proofing process.
The risk assessment determines the extent
to which risks must be mitigated
by the identity proofing process.
So I'm going to walk
through this decision tree
real quickly.
So for step one,
the organization will first need to ask
if whether they have any
personal information collected.
If no, you are at IAL1,
and it could stop the process.
Otherwise you proceed to step two.
Step two determines if any
of the personal information
needs to be validated and verified,
or if self asserted
attributes are acceptable.
If any of the personal information
needs to be validated and verified,
you proceed to step three.
Otherwise you are IAL1
If an organization actually
makes it to step three,
it means that some sort of
higher assurance identity
proofing is required.
Step three is intended to
look at the potential impacts
of an identity proofing failure,
to determine if IAL2 or IAL3,
is the most appropriate selection.
If any of the questions are
in step three is at high risk,
then you are at IAL3.
If not, you proceed to step four.
So step four asks the
question regarding whether
the personal information
required by an organization,
will ultimately resolve
to a unique identity.
If yes, the process gets
stopped here at IAL2.
But the organization should consider
steps five and six are a value to them,
where the acceptance of claims
will reduce exposure to
the risk of over collecting
and storing more personal
information is necessary.
A federated environment is a great example
of receiving claims as
the service provider
is not in control of the
attribute information.
If the organization deems that
a federated attribute
approach is acceptable,
a similar decision tree
is available in 80063-3
to determine which Federation
assurance level to use.
So once an identity assurance
level is determined,
the credential service provider,
can follow a general process flow
to implement the required
identity proofing
identity assurance level.
So NIST defines three
steps for the enrollment
and identity proofing process.
Resolution, validation and verification.
So resolution uniquely
distinguishes an individual
from all other people
using a minimal set of
core attributes or PII.
This is the only step
that the credential service provider,
may use knowledge based verification.
Note that is extremely important
to use dynamic out of wallet.
Now let's say face verification
sets a question such as
what was your last mortgage payment?
Or what is the amount of your auto loan?
So step two is validation of
your physical identity evidence
that is collected or captured.
Examples of identity evidence
are a driver's license,
a passport or a bank statement.
For example,
when one goes to the
department of motor vehicles
for their driver's license,
the applicant must provide
an unexpired picture ID,
proof of residence,
and perhaps additional support
documentation to the clerk.
The clerk looks to see if
there's any evidence at tampering
as well as look at the
information contained
on the identity documents.
In the digital world,
this is essentially what is performed
during the validation stage.
The identity information is
presented in digital form,
is validated against authoritative sources
to ensure that the identity
evidence is genuine, authentic.
It contains information that's correct.
And then it contains
information that pertains
to a real life subject.
Once the identity evidence
has been validated,
the last step is verification.
This step verifies the applicant
to the claimed identity.
Going back to the DMV example.
After the clerk reviews the
presented identity evidence,
the clerk will determine whether
the individual standing in front of them
is indeed the individual
on the picture ID.
In remote proofing,
this is accomplished by
matching the identity evidence
via a biometric check,
such as by the applicant taking
and uploading a selfie
picture of themselves
to the credential service provider.
Liveness detection and
other fraud detection checks
are performed to ensure that
the image is of a real person.
Lastly,
the credential service provider
issues an enrollment code,
either via mobile phone
or through the postal service,
to confirm address of record
through verification the address contained
on the supplied valid
piece of identity evidence.
Once all of these steps
are successfully completed,
a digital identity is created.
So let's walk through an example
of what the identity proofing
process would look like.
So for this example,
we'll assume that we're
using IAL2 remote proofing.
For resolution to unique identity,
the credential service provider
would need to collect minimal
PII from the applicant,
such as their full name,
date of birth,
full mailing address and phone number.
In addition,
the credential service provider
needs to collect identity evidence.
NIST offers specific requirements
for strength of identity evidence required
for each of the identity assurance levels.
In this example,
the credential service provider,
provides one form of
strong identity evidence
such as a driver's license,
and two fair pieces of identity evidence
such as a utility bill and bank statement.
NIST released implementation
guidance last July
where examples of identity
evidence are provided.
And I'll revisit the
implementation guidance
later in this presentation.
Once the identity evidence is collected,
the credential service provider
validates the core attributes that gets
authorities sources such as credit bureaus
or EMVO for driver's license information
to ensure the information is both accurate
and belongs to a real life subject.
For instance,
forensics checks are performed
against the identity evidence
to ensure that the documents are genuine.
These checks include,
checking the font,
the color,
and watermarks.
Once the identity evidence is validated,
the Prudential service provider
needs to establish a linkage
between the claims identity
and the applicant providing the evidence.
verification typically is done
by matching the strongest
piece of identity evidence
via a selfie.
Once the credential service provider
is satisfied with the selfie match
to the identity evidence,
the credential service provider
sends an enrollment code to
the validate phone number.
So, now that we've walked through
a high level overview of review
in this Higher Assurance
Identity Proofing Guidelines,
let's now focus on answering the question.
Why is it so hard to do?
And by doing that,
we'll provide a use case
of a NIST conformance
credential service provider
detecting fraud,
and then walk through
some of the techniques
and technologies that are used
to help detect fraud.
So, remember that slide back
earlier in the presentation
where we talked about identity theft
and the vast amounts of data
stolen about an individual?
This data is readily available to purchase
on the dark web by fraudsters
to then obtain access
to your bank account,
receive your stimulus check,
or your tax returns.
It's due to this high
increase in stolen identities
where organizations are finding
that they no longer trust
that digital identity.
For example,
these fraudsters are targeting
unemployment insurance
benefits and stimulus checks
using stolen credentials
to apply for unemployment
benefits through state websites.
This is a key reason why higher
assurance identity proofing
can help provide confidence
that you are who he claimed to be.
So how can identity proofing
help identify, defeat fraud?
The following slides will first introduce
credential service providers
who offer this Higher
Assurance Identity Proofing
and then provide an example
of how the Higher
Assurance Identity Proofing
can detect and prevent fraud.
So there are currently
two full service credential
service providers,
who have either completed
or are currently going
through IAL2 certification
by the Kantara initiative.
Kantara is a nonprofit
who provides third-party assessment
for special pub 80063 revision 3,
based on their conformance criteria.
The first credential
service provider ID.me,
has been certified by Kantara at IAL2,
and offers both remote
and virtual in-person
identity proofing via web cam,
to assist those applicants
who need additional help
through the identity proofing process.
The second is US Government
Services Administrations
since then seen login.gov.
login.gov is currently
being certified for IAL2
and offer us remote
identity proofing services
for citizens who are seen to
do business with some agencies.
These two credential service providers,
offer higher assurance
remote identity proofing
and strong authentication
in accordance with NIST
special pub 80063-3 guidelines.
Since the start pandemic,
requests for this remote
proofing services have increased.
So, the need for unemployment
insurance benefits
is one area that has certainly
increased since COVID.
Given that the unemployment
insurance program
allows claims to be filed online.
This certainly presents an opportunity
for fraudulent filings.
The cares act presented an
opportunity for fraudsters
as well as scam rings
as noted on the slide.
In fact, the U S labor
department reported fraudsters
were able to still billions of dollars
in filing unemployment payments
since from the US last November.
One of the reasons is that
the state unemployment insurance offices
are working with decades old technology
that cannot keep up with the fraudsters
who have bypass identity safeguards
by using stolen and fake identities.
So instead of battling with
the decades old technology,
20 States have selected ID.me,
to provide identity verification services
in accordance with the NIST guidelines
for those individuals requesting
those unemployment benefits.
The numbers you see here on the slide
are how those individuals were verified.
90% pass through
a completely unlined
remote proofing experience,
and 10% required additional
assistance via a video call
with a trained ID.me representative.
Since the end of January of this year,
ID.me has blocked over
800,000 fraudulent claims.
So, these are the types of fraud
that were detected during
the identity verification
for the unemployment benefit payment.
While these percentages listed
are based on the numbers
of fraudulent claims
for this particular use case,
the types of fraud listed here
can be applied to many use cases.
So how do credential service
providers following NIST 80063
detect and prevent these types of fraud?
How can I be confident
that the individual at the
other end of the device,
is who they claim to be?
The following slides will
cover the types of fraud
seen in the identity proofing process,
as well as best practices to help detect
and prevent fraud following
the NIST guidelines.
So now face verification
has historically been used
and continues to be used
to verify claimed identity,
by testing and knowledge of the applicant
against information obtained
from public databases.
However, RPII has been
stolen from data breaches
which truly defeats the
purpose of using KBV
to verify an applicant.
We therefore must limit the use of
static knowledge based
verification as much as possible.
Answers to static
questions are easy to find.
For example, all one has to do is
look at social media to fine
ones mother's maiden name,
date of birth,
and most likely names of family
members and names of pets.
In addition,
many are now posting pictures
of their COVID vaccine
cards on social media.
Please do not do that.
It lists important PII beyond
just your name and date of birth,
including the vaccine
type and the lot number.
If one must use KBV,
limit its use and make those questions
as dynamic as possible,
as well as basing the questions
from multiple authoritative sources,
and not just from financial
or credit bureaus.
So synthetic identity fraud,
combines real information
such as once social security number
with false information like a fake name
to create a new identity.
This type of fraud is
typically financially driven.
And those who create these
synthetic identities,
will spend months
cultivating their identities
and building up lines of credit.
These fraudsters frequently
target individuals
who are less likely to check
their credit information often
such as children,
the elderly or even homeless people.
So how does one combat synthetic identity?
The number one thing to do
is query authoritative sources
such as the credit bureaus
AMPA for the DMV,
as well as see if the social
security number being presented
is on the master death file.
Some examples that may be
that one may be dealing with
a synthetic identity include,
is there an ability or inability to match
and or verify an identity
across all PII attributes
provided by the applicant.
Or are there multiple
identities associated
with the same social security number?
Or check for multiple
candidates originating
from the same IP address.
User behavior can also help
detect patterns and anomalies
that indicate potentially
fraudulent behavior.
For example,
user behavior could be used to determine
if the identity is stolen or synthetic,
based on how familiar the applicant is
with filling out the data on the form.
For example,
does the individual pass entering PII
that the true person should know about?
Or are they using control
keys to fill out the form?
So let's talk briefly
about identity evidence.
For this step,
the applicant will take pictures
of the front and the back
of their identity evidence
such as their a driver's
license and passport
and submit that information
to the credential service provider.
The type of identity evidence required
depends on the strength of evidence
required by the credential
service provider.
So I like to use the example
of going to the department
of motor vehicles
to receive your driver's license.
The type of documentation required,
varies with the type of
driver's license received.
If you get a real ID,
you're required to provide additional
forms of identity evidence
then you wait for a
traditional driver's license.
That clerk at the DMV,
is also trained to detect
altered identity evidence.
The same applies in the
context of remote proofing.
The higher the identity
assurance required,
the stronger forms of
documentation are required
to resolve that identity.
Forensics checks are
also performed to detect
the authenticity of the
identity evidence provided.
Some checks performed include,
are the holograms in the correct location?
Is the font the right size?
Is the blue the, excuse me.
Is the color the right shade of blue?
So take a look at the picture on the right
while I speak to this slide.
I'll be coming back to the photos shortly.
So during the higher assurance
identity proofing process,
one is required to capture a biometric,
usually in the form of a selfie.
The selfie is then compared to the picture
in the identity evidence
such as your driver's license or passport.
Liveness detection,
helps determine that there is a live human
instead of a fraudster
circumventing this
channel by using a mask,
an altered photo,
or recording a doctored video.
So deepfake, takes key characteristics
of a person's appearance or voice,
and overlays these
characteristics onto another's.
These deepfakes are now
starting to make an appearance
to attempt to bypass
the liveness detection
and selfie checks.
So how are they doing this?
Liveness checks are performed by
possibly asking the applicant to blink,
smile, nod or speak a phrase.
This pattern does not vary,
which makes it fairly easy to spoof
by a deepfake or an animated GIF.
So currently they are
rudimentary deepfakes
that are being discovered.
But those will improve in time.
So some things to consider
when combating deepfakes
is the selfie check.
Is to never use the same directions
for each identity proofing events.
So what do I mean by that?
So if I as a credential service provider
always ask the applicant to blink,
it's fairly easy for a fraudster to use
the blinking animated GIF or a deepfake.
However, if I asked the applicant
to turn their head to your
left and then to the right,
and ask another applicant
to smile or frown,
and then another applicant
to read some words,
it makes it much harder
for a fraudster to use these techniques
to defeat the liveness detection check.
Use of artificial intelligence
in the liveness detection
will help as well.
The artificial intelligence,
used in the liveness detection,
could help determine that
something is not quite right,
such as is the background
embedded a static image,
or is a lighting off
where shadows in the room
doesn't affect the face.
So speaking of shadows and static images,
let's get back to the
pictures on the right.
So imagine them animated.
Can you tell which one is real
in which three are fake?
See anything blurred or
missing in any of the images?
Are the reflections of
the Iris's different?
Feel free to put your answer in chat.
So if you picked image number three,
that's the real person
and you are correct.
The others were computer generated.
And I did not get that right.
So think of a Fraud Consortium Network
as a watch list in digital realm.
For example, in the real world,
your identity is already checked
on the do not fly list
prior to checking to the airport.
This do not fly list is only applicable
to those who fly on commercial aircraft
within, into or out of the United States.
Other countries, such
as Canada and Pakistan,
have their own form of a do not fly list.
So in the digital world,
organizations within
industries affected by fraud,
often rely on consortium data
as assistant defense against
new fraud strategies.
Consortium data for fraud prevention,
is a system that shares information
with a group of customers.
In other words,
if a fraudulent actor
is known to commit fraud
at one customer website,
and then that individual
attempts to commit the same type of fraud
in a second customer website,
then that attempt will be flagged
as fraudulent and blocked.
These Fraud Consortium Networks,
pool information of
known fraudulent events,
sources, or IP addresses
and could be leveraged during
the identity proofing process.
For example,
when presented with a
new customer identity
an organization can ask the
Fraud Consortium Network,
whether they name, email
address and device to identify
this new customer belongs
to an identity other members
of the network trust.
Other more member organizations
could then respond based on their
own identity proofing efforts,
and their own transaction histories
with that customer identity.
So my personal opinion is,
that it would be beneficial
for the government and industry
to partner together to create
a wider fraud collaboration network.
This will capture and share
a known fraudulent identities and devices
on a much broader scale.
So now that we have learned
about Higher Assurance Identity Proofing,
where do I go for guidance
or best practices?
So NIST released implementation resources
early July of 2020.
The implementation resources
offered guidance to
facilitate understanding implementation
a special pub 80063-3.
And they are broken down
by topic area for each
of these three volumes.
One of those areas in the 63A piece
includes a list of
example identity evidence,
such as, as driver's license and passport
and social security number
and other items.
So definitely take a look for
their examples in that piece.
Furthermore for volume 63A,
one of the areas NIST mentions,
it's a requirement that
the identity proofing
enrollment processes performed
is based on applicable written policy
or practices statements,
that document all the
steps taken to verify
an applicant's identity.
Within this section,
NIST points the reader to
MITRE's guidance for this area.
So last year MITRE
internally funded an effort
to document in the form of
practice statement templates,
the requirements and processes
to achieve compliance with
either remote identity
assurance levels two and three.
So I want to quickly step through
what the template looks like,
that we created and published.
Again, that these are our interpretation
of documenting all the processes
used in enrollment and identity proofing
as well as capturing any proofing errors
as required in 80063A
section 42 requirements 6.
On the left are the steps of
the identity proofing process
that we've walked through earlier.
For this example,
I will step through what
the template looks like
for collection of identity evidence.
In the center is an
overview of what is required
in the collection of identity evidence
as well as the bottom center
showing examples of the
types of documents required
for the strength of identity evidence.
On the upper right hand
corner of this slide
provides a blank table
to allow the credential service provider
to fill in the collected
identity evidence.
Each column along the top of that table
is defined below to guide the
credential service provider
in filling out the required information.
Lastly,
there is a table to capture any errors
that may occur as well as what technology
or process be used to resolve the error.
For example,
the number of retries allowed,
proofing alternatives
such as going in person
if remote fails
or fraud counter measures
when anomalies are detected.
So NIST plans to update
this special pub 80063.
Last year, NIST sought public
comment to revision three,
to be taken into consideration
when they work on revision four.
What you see on the
slide is the timeline for
all the milestone activities
associated with this revision.
The plan is to publish revision four
by third quarter of fiscal year 2022.
So, here are some items you can apply
based on what you have learned today.
So next week you should
download and start to
review this special pub
80063 revision three.
NIST implementation resources
in MITRE's templates.
These documents will help you
with the development of the
required identity proofing
and enrollment practices
statement documentation
starting with 80063 revision three,
start following the decision tree
to help determine the
assurance level you are based
on the amount of risks
that must be mitigated
by the identity proofing process.
Start gathering your organization's
identity proofing requirements
and document them using MITRE"S templates.
All the links provided on this slide
are for the documents I just mentioned.
So, the first three months,
you should be doing your market research.
While doing that market research,
please keep in mind the types of fraud,
such as forced documents
or the risk of deepfakes
and synthetic identities.
Ask the credential service providers
how they mitigate these
and other types of threats and fraud.
Once you have made your selection
of credential service provider,
work with them to complete the templates,
to ensure that they
satisfy the requirements
to mitigate the identity theft and fraud,
you have identified
So Higher Assurance Identity Proofing
can help detect and prevent fraud.
Use as many channels
and sources as possible
to help render decision regarding,
is that applicant who
they really claim to be,
or is in fact a fraudster?
Fraud mitigation measures
include inspecting the identity
evidence for any forgeries,
examine the device characteristics
used by the applicant,
and evaluate behavioral
characteristics of the applicant.
Is the applicant using shortcuts
while filling out the form,
or pausing to fill out the street address?
Check multiple authoritative sources
as well as vital statistic repositories
such as the death master file.
Lastly,
include liveness detection
for the selfie check
and ensure that randomness is used
to avoid animated GIFs and deepfakes.
All of these techs.
All these tools and technologies
will help answer the question.
Are you really you?
Thank you.