- Hey, hi everyone.
My name is Paul Rosler
and the paper that I
present today has the title
of systematization of knowledge
for game-based security
models of group key exchange.
And this is joint work together
with Bertram Poettering,
Jorg Schwenk and Douglas Stebila
and we directly start
with the core of our paper
which is the idea of group key change.
And we can motivate
group key exchange easily
by the most recent and
most prominent use case
which is a group messaging.
So we can think
of group messaging being
split in modern applications
into a first group key exchange
phase where the members
of a group exchange a key,
and then this key is used
to encrypt every group
message exactly only once
instead of encrypting
every message multiple times individually
to all the receivers in the group,
which is for example, done in signal.
Now we look only at the key
exchange component here.
So multiple users exchange a key,
possibly in dynamic groups.
So maybe users are added to the group
and these users can then exchange new keys
with the new members say,
maybe users are added simultaneously.
And eventually all the users compute
in a group, the same shared
group key, but we are looking
at the security of group
key exchange, which means,
that we also have to consider adversaries
that can maybe reveal key
material or that can introduce
and add malicious users
and control the traffic
between all the members
while exchanging the keys.
And the ultimate goal
against such an adversary is
of course that the keys are secure
meaning that they look
random to the advisory
even though they are
exchanged between these users.
And now I will look at the
literature of group key change.
We see that there are many
even hundreds of papers
on this topic, specifically if we look
at a DBLP paper repository,
we see that there are
more than 150 papers with
a title group key exchange
or group key agreement.
And we can split this literature
into three different phases.
The first one started in the early 80s
where researchers proposed new protocols
for group key change
but they only provided heuristic
security arguments instead
of rigorous security proofs.
And these rigorous security
proves were only introduced
in the second phase
which roughly started in the early 2000s,
leading to the final current phase
on group key exchange research.
Well, researchers try to
understand which properties
are relevant and important
for the specific use case
that I mentioned earlier
which is group messaging.
For example, synchronicity is one
of the properties relevant right now.
And since our main core
consideration is the modeling
and the definition of security
for group key exchange,
we ignore the rather vague
and not really rigorous security analysis
from our consideration, but still we see
that there are more than
30 different definitions
of security for group key exchange
in the literature phases of research.
And this brings us
to the core question and
problem that we investigate
in our paper here, which is
systematization and unifying
the ideas and security definitions
for group key exchange.
Now with this goal in mind
we have to understand what
is group key exchange,
what are the generic definitions of it
and how can we define security for it?
And for this in the literature
of key exchange or in the
literature of any cryptography,
we, first of all, start with syntax,
which describes the abstract interfaces
that capture the inputs
and outputs of group key
exchange algorithms in general.
And for this, we look at one user here
in this picture and this user,
as well as all other users
run on their local devices
the group key exchange algorithms
and these algorithms have
of course, interfaces
to their environments.
For example, to the
upper layer application,
we have to keep in mind
that group key exchange is
never a standalone application
but always serves with
the exchange group keys
to an application that uses these keys.
But this application, in addition
to obtaining these keys
also wants to control
the group key exchange
algorithms by for example
changing the members site,
and many other things.
There are also other interfaces
like the network interfaces
that helps these algorithms
to communicate the information
necessary to exchange keys
between all the members of a group.
Also the storage interface
for saving key material
for these algorithms
on the local devices are important.
Now there are different properties
that these abstract
interfaces have to fulfill.
The first one being, that
is that these interfaces
have to have the algorithms
to become useful, such that,
the environment can use these algorithms
for their different purposes.
For example, sending the cipher text
or exchanging keys for the
upper layer application.
The second property being
that these interfaces
should be defined as generic as possible
such that different
constructions can be captured
by this framework.
This helps us on the one hand
to compare different types
of constructions in the same framework.
It helps us on the other hand in practice
if a group key exchange is deployed
along an application
that this group key exchange construction
can be replaced by another construction
if the former turns out to be insecure.
And lastly, a property is that we want
that these interfaces as
little restrictive as possible
such the construction that
implement these interfaces
can be very efficient and can also
be as functional as possible.
Now, turning to the security
perspective, we have to look
at which security goals
do we want to be fulfilled
and which types of advisories
do we want to capture?
So in the presence of these adversaries,
a good idea for defining security is
that the security goal
is defined intuitive.
And one type of security
definition could be
that the keys look
random to everyone except
for designated members
specifically for the adversary.
On the other hand,
we have to capture those adversaries
as realistically as possible, for example,
an advisory should be able
to control the interface,
specifically the public inputs
controlling the members side,
controlling also the communication
of the algorithms by other network
and also probably corrupt
the secrets that are stored
on the local devices at least temporarily.
Okay. So these are the overall ideas
that we think have to be
considered when defining
and modeling the security
of group key exchange.
And now what we did was looking
at the literature that I
introduced at the very beginning,
but we saw that there is
a very large literature.
So we reduced the considered papers based
on the properties that on the one hand,
we only considered papers that
appeared at Tier conferences.
And on the other hand,
we considered papers that did not appear
on Tier one conferences,
but contributed new insights
to the modeling of group key exchange
which resulted in a set
of 12 different papers.
Now for these 12 different papers,
we defined a framework with which
we characterized the different types
of definitions that we see when modeling
group key exchange.
You see here, the
characteristics that we think
are relevant when defining the
syntax for a group key change
and with this framework,
we then analyzed how
the different papers implemented
these characteristics
or features of the syntax.
And we also try to
understand what we think
are desirable implementations
of all these features.
We continued to do this for
the security definition,
for the partnering or matching definitions
and also for the correctness definitions.
And the result of our analysis was
that none of the papers that we looked at
provided a generic standard
model for group key exchange.
And we can also say this
for the papers that we did not look at
in the many details that we looked at
for the 12 papers that we
considered in our systematization.
The reasons for this are
on the one hand that many
of the definitions are too informal
or unresponsive because the definitions
are not clear enough to
understand what exactly
the requirements are that
are captured in those.
Secondly, we saw that many
of the models are over fitted
meaning that many of
these models were designed
for the analysis of one
specific construction,
and thereby, these
models are not applicable
to other constructions
and cannot be generalized appropriately.
Lastly, the shortcomings are that
many of the external environment
properties or requirement
were ignored in the literature before.
For example, many of these models
required that a public key
infrastructure is deployed along
these group key exchange constructions
or many of the models did not allow us
to generically compose
group key exchange according
to these models with other
upper layer applications.
So our result was that we
came up with a new model
and you may now ask that this
is just yet another model.
And we think, no,
it is a good model because
we learned from the past,
we concentrated on what
modeling should fulfill.
And we thought what group key exchange
in general is, so we came up
with a new syntax definition,
the insecurity definition
that is both precise
and compact because we are independent
of previous constructions
and we give a compact
pseudo-code game definitions
both for correctness and security.
Along other properties,
our model is indifference
to membership operations.
So we fulfill
or we can capture many different
types of constructions.
The ultimate results of our model is
that we can handle different
real-world settings
within one model framework.
On the one hand, we can capture
asynchronous communication.
We can consider different means
of authentication for the group
key exchange constructions
and our model is easily extendable
and as I mentioned, compact and precise.
So you see here are my overall agenda
or the overall contributions
that we provided
on the one hand, developing
a new and fresh understanding
of what group key exchange is,
then deriving from this understanding
a systematization framework
with which we then compared
and analyzed the literature
basically the models that were
proposed in the literature.
And we came up at the end with
a new generic, compact model
with which we think we can
help the future research
on group key to change to understand
what the basic properties
for a group key exchange model should be.
All the details are in
our print publication
and you can contact me via Twitter.
I thank you very much for your intention.
Yeah. Thank you very much.
- [Jacques] I'm Jacques Poway
and I will present the results
of our paper entitled EPID
with malicious revocation.
In this paper, we revisit
the security model
of an animal signature
schemes called EPID,
which has been introduced
by Brickle and Lee in 2007.
This is a joint work with Olivia Sanders.
Enhanced Privacy ID, EPID for short
is a digital signature
scheme supporting anonymity,
just like a group signature,
an EPID signature attests a
legitimate signer belonging
(crackling drowns out speaker)
we mean here, for example,
a group of eligible voters
who are allowed to participate
to a given elections
or a group of customers
who subscribed to the services
of a given service provider.
Anyone can check the validity
of an EPID signature using a
so-called group public key.
EPID signatures are anonymous.
We don't know who among
the group of signers
generated with a signature and
contrary to group signatures,
they are entrustable that no
one can open an EPID signature
and identify a signer.
EPID private signing keys
can, however, be revoked
given the signatures created
by that EPID is standardized.
It is included in the ISO standard
2008 dash two anonymous
digital signatures.
EPID is widely deployed.
It is embedded in billion of devices
as is closed by Intel in
the RSA conference in 2016.
Three types of entities are
involved in an EPID scheme,
an issuer is a member of the group
of the signers and verifiers.
The role of the issuer is to
manage the group of signers
and to ensure to legitimate
member is private
with this private sign-in key,
a member can sign a message
on behalf of the group and any verifiers
can verify the validity
of his signature using a
group public key published
by the issuer.
How does it work in practice?
So in the joint protocol,
the member will have
to choose a secret S which
will be his private key
and then execute with
the issuer a blank thing
at your protocol in order to
obtain a blind certificate
on his secret S.
To sign your message in,
it just has to compute
a non interactive zero-knowledge proof
proving that he knows a secret
S that has been certified
by is an issuer.
The verifier can verify the validity
of this non interactive
zero-knowledge proofs
by using the group public key.
The private signing key
can be reworked
using a signature that has
been generated with that key.
So to this end, the member just has to add
to his signatures
or revocation tag, that
can be computed as follows.
So we just have to
choose a random value H,
and compute the relocation tag
which is a core to H to the power,
S is private signing key.
Before signing a message,
you just have to retrieve the
signatures revocation needs,
which contains revocation tags
of old revoked signatures.
To sign a message,
you then have to compute
(crackling drowns out speaker)
proving that you know S
and the blind certificate on S,
a proof that the revocation tag
has been correctly computing,
that is key is equal
to H to the power S is private sign-in key
and that it did not produce
any of the revocation tag RTI
including in the signatures revocation.
It has to add a proof of
knowledge that PI is different
to the power S.
From a security point of view,
if it's in your choose should
be unforgivable, which means
that an adversary should not
be able to forge a signature
either by framing and an
end user that is signing
on behalf of this honest
user, or by using forge key,
that is key that has not been obtained
during the joint session.
(crackling drowns out speaker)
I may corrupt users and
then own their private keys.
So how to detect in this case,
that the forgery is non-trivial,
the signature has not been generated
using a corrupt key.
The solution to this issue
would be to recover all
the corrupt keys owned
by user adversary.
In current EPID constructions,
this is done by requiring
a zero knowledge proof
of the secret S during joint session.
This has two main drawbacks.
The first one,
if we use classical rewinding
techniques to extract
as corrupt keys, this
really limits the number
of concurrent joint session
that can be done virtually.
On the other hand, if
we use online extractor
is we get heavily impacts the performance
of the joint protocol.
(crackling drowns out speaker)
that there are private signing keys
are not revoked.
A natural question that comes
to mind is we should manage
the signature for revocation.
(crackling drowns out speaker)
it is assumed that this revocation
So this would lead
to a centralized and not
very practical solutions.
So it would be more
convenient for the verifier
if they could manage
themselves this revocation key.
We should also emphasize
that in the ISO standards,
it is only recommended
to have a trusted entity
for updating the signature revocations.
It is not a requirement.
So another natural questions that comes
to mind is what can be
achieved in terms of security
if this revocation needs are
generated by a malicious.
We observed that if such
revocation is managed
by a malicious entity,
this entity could easily win
the current anonymity
gains by simply adding
to the revocation needs
randomized versions
of the revocation tags
instead of the original revocation tags.
So we revisit the security model
of EPID by removing some
limitations of previous work.
We propose a new unforgeability
where this time, we task
the adversary to produce
N plus one one valid signatures
if it owns N corrupt keys
that have been opened
during successful joint sessions.
We however put in the revocation
needs each new signatures
that it produces in order to ensure
that the N plus one output
signatures were generated
with N plus one distinct keys,
which means that at least one
of these output signatures
is a non-trivial forger.
So we do not require to
recover all the corrupt keys.
We also proposed a new
anonymity game where we stand
where this time we give to the
re-address rate total control
on the revocation.
We also proposed two new EPID schemes
that satisfies our new security
and functional requirements.
In both constructions,
we modified the structure
of the relocation packs
in our constructions,
they are non-millennial goals
in order to prevent their re optimizations
and to prevent the attacks
that I just mentioned in
one of my previous slides.
So to summarize,
EPIDs are standardized,
anonymous signature schemes,
which is widely deployed, it is embedded
in billion of chips.
We have proposed a new
security model for EPID,
which addresses several limitations
of previous models.
Our new unforgeability property
remove the need to extract
corrupt signing keys
which will make our enrollment
of new members simpler
and which will alert concurrent joins.
Our new anonymity property
allows a decentralized management
of revocation list
which we believe better
captures the spirit of EPID.
Finally, we have introduced
two new efficient EPID schemes
that satisfies this new security
and functionality requirements.
Thank you.
- Hi, my name is Magnus Ringerud.
I'm a PhD student at
the Norwegian University
of Science and Technology,
and I'll be talking
about our paper signed
Diffie-Hellman key exchange
with tight security.
This is joint work with
Josh and Pam and Jen
also here at the university.
So a brief outline of this
talk, I'll give an introduction
and try to establish some
context for our work.
Then I'll move into some
technical aspects and finally
some real-world relevance,
as in why is this important for you.
So to start off, we
have to mention the TLS,
the Transport Layer Security.
TLS is used everywhere
and it is dependent on
a key exchange algorithm
for establishing shared key material.
And when I say everywhere in particular
it's used as the security layer in HTTPs
which is used on the
RSA conference webpage.
Now, signed Diffie-Hellman is a core part
of TLS and is one of the algorithms used
in this handshake where you
have two players, Alice and Bob
which is just trying to
create shared key material.
And there are many other versions
of signed Diffie-Hellman.
The point is you have
a Diffie-Hellman share
and you sign it to get
authentication and integrity.
So this is our version
of the protocol where we at the end,
have this is context where
you have the public keys
and you have the, both
the messages, and then,
you hash this together with
the shared key material
which is this Y to the
X term, X to the Y term.
You hash all this to get the final key
and this is important and
we'll get into it later.
So previously, the previous security bound
for signed Diffie-Hellman was made
(crackling drowns out speaker)
As you can see from the
equation it's dependent
on breaking the decisional
Diffie-Hellman problem
and the multi-use security off
a digital signature scheme.
The important part here
is this S squared term.
Now S is the number of sessions.
And hence we say
that this is a security
loss that is quadratic
in the number of sessions.
So S squared, and I would
mention security loss.
And that brings us to tightness.
Why is tightness important?
Well, security loss reduces
the guaranteed security level
that security proof gives you anaive proof
or easy proofs for signed Diffie-Hellman
and many authenticated key exchanges
have this S square security loss.
What this means in practice
you can consider a case
where S is two to the 30
then according to such a
naive proof, if you implement
for 128 bit security, then in reality,
we obtained 68 bits of security.
This is not a safe margin
for large scale applications.
So our contribution is
that nice tight reduction
to the strong computational
Diffie-Hellman assumption.
So we get rid of the security
loss and we abstract ideas
from reasons tight proofs
for the TLS protocol.
So to mention
(crackling drowns out speaker)
there are a variance
of scientific element,
which has been proposed
but most Lewis, this factor of S squared.
(crackling drowns out speaker)
proposed by us
But this is since it's a
three message it's not back
and forth, but it's that way,
that way and that way again.
So it's an additional message
which of course increases
the communication complexity.
It is also proven in the multi bit model
which does not automatically
give you a tight composition
with symmetric primitives like AEs
which is what you will want for TLS.
There was also a recent, tight, secure AKE
(crackling drowns out speaker)
which use some more
sophisticated techniques
to obtain tightness
which ours is very simple
and straightforward.
And the protocol is very well known.
So some technical details,
this is a sketch of the model
and it's going to be a very simplified
but it'll suit our purpose.
So the idea is
that you have an initiator
which generates a message
and internal state, it sends
the message over and then
you have a responder who
generates his response message.
And now, since he has
all the necessary details
he can also compute the S key
and sends the response message
back and initiated computes.
Hopefully the same key.
Now, the idea here is
that the adversary can
learn these messages
and transcripts as we call them.
And in our very simplified
model, we can say
that Denver's really wants
to be able to compute a key
and the real model, it's
a bit more sophisticated
but the ISM model will
suffice for our purposes.
So why is tightness for AKE here?
Well, we have this thing
called the commitment problem
and a reduction or security
proof is just a way
to relate mathematical problems
or a scheme to another scheme.
And then you have challenges
or you have a reduction and
you have your adversity.
And the reduction wants
to use the adversary
to solve the challenge.
That means that you need
to embed your challenge
in some way, if you
don't, then you could just
attack the scheme without
using the adversary at all
then you have a more of a
direct proof than a reduction
some sense, but this
brings about a problem
because if you am bad,
the challenge everywhere
you're not able to compute
everything anymore.
And in particular, for AKE,
you have to be able to respond
to what's called a key reveal query,
which is a model of what happens
if a session key is leaked,
somebody gets hacked.
You need to be able to model this
and then make sure that the
protocol doesn't break down
but you can't answer this unless you
or if you can't compute the relevant key.
So this is a problem.
If you want to just use the naive,
so I'm betting it everywhere.
It doesn't work
but simply guessing which
sessions are important
than trying to embed them
means that you have to
guess correctly twice
out of S times, which gives
you this at square loss.
So the naive solution leads
to highly non tight groups.
So our approach is then this random Oracle
because instead of actually
computing this Y to X
X to Y term is simply
assimilate the random Oracle.
And then you patch them later on.
This means that you can
now and a consistent way
answer these key reveal queries.
So everything seems good
but that's then still
one challenge remaining.
And that is since we are
in the random Oracle model,
the anniversary can also query
the random Oracle itself.
And if it happens to query
on this particular context
and then wit some element
upended at the end,
we need to be able to
distinguish this element,
the key that you would
compute from this context
or is it just random?
And the answer to that should determine
if he gets what the response
from the random Oracle is the actual key
or just something random.
So in short, we need to
be able to distinguish
is this element a key
that you would compute from a
context or something random?
And then our solution is then what we call
verifiable key exchange.
So you have a key exchange protocol
but you also have a verification
Oracle that can verify
with a given transcript and a key
if this key matches this transcript.
And for signed Diffie-Hellman,
we use the Oracle provided
by the strong computational
Diffie-Hellman assumption.
So how does this affect you and good news,
(crackling drowns out speaker)
supports the current implementations based
on this strong CDX assumption.
So most implementations today
simply ignore security loss
and implement everything as it fit tight.
And our analysis supports
that these implementations
should still be secure
which is good news
if you're able to have a
slightly stronger assumption
and then you have the model
and performance table.
So we compare with some of these others,
other AKE's I've mentioned,
this table is obtained
with a tightly secure moldier
succinct, just scheme.
So all the schemes get the same amount
of extra group elements, et cetera.
So we are communication
efficient, and we are
in the correct single bit model
and one drawback to our work is
that we do not allow state
reveals like this JKRs work does.
However, TLS itself does not
allow state reveals either.
One of the reasons is that
(crackling drowns out speaker)
they are in general not resistant
to state reveals like snore,
for instance, if the secret state leaks,
then your sign in key,
it's open for grabs, which is bad.
So to conclude, we have a tight production
for signed Diffie-Hellman key exchange
where we have improved the security loss
from this S squared to a constant.
(crackling drowns out speaker)
because signed Diffie-Hellman
is one of the core components of TLS.
We have a new key technique
which is verifiable key
exchange, which is an abstraction
of many tight security proofs
who use different kinds
of Oracles to respond exactly as we would
especially this last one
here, Mark for the star.
This protocol is not entirely tight,
but it is exactly, they use exactly
the same Oracle simulation as us.
So it seems fitting to include it.
And finally, the extension of this
or our ongoing work is to extend
this to group key exchange.
So we want to have group key exchange
with tight security through
this verifiable key exchange.
And that is my talk.
Thank you for listening.