- Did you know that 60% of cloud storage
has logging disabled?
You heard me right,
60% of cloud storage has logging disabled.
It's these types of blind spots
that we're gonna talk about
over the next couple of minutes
as we go through this presentation.
My name is Matt Chiodi,
and I'm the chief security
officer of public cloud
at Palo Alto Networks.
So when you think about a blind spot,
what is it that comes to your mind?
I know for me that this picture
that you're looking at
here on your screen,
this is exactly what I think about, right?
Usually it says objects in this mirror
are closer than they may appear.
But a blind spot is usually something
that you think you know
what the reality is,
but in actuality, it's quite different.
That is how at least
I define a blind spot.
And when it comes to cyber
security and cloud security,
it's when you think you understand
what the cloud threat is
but in actuality, it's
something quite different.
So that's what we're
gonna talk about today
over the next 30 or so minutes.
Now let's talk about some areas
that I'm not gonna go into
detail on in this report.
These are the areas of
what I call cloud clarity.
These are areas we've
talked about so many times,
I'm not gonna spend any time
going into these, right?
Shared responsibility.
I think most organizations at this point,
cloud's been out for well over a decade,
most organizations understand
that there is a shared responsibility
between them as the cloud consumer
and then as the cloud provider.
They understand there's
a difference there.
The next area has to do
with storage buckets,
or should I say leaky storage buckets.
This is an area that if you go
back probably 18 to 24 months
this was something that was in the news
probably on a weekly or a
bi-weekly basis if you remember.
Somebody uploaded data to a storage bucket
and then inadvertently,
it got set to public
and now someone had a massive breach
that they were gonna need to deal with.
So leaky storage buckets,
that's an area of cloud clarity.
The last area that I
think most organizations
probably understand
pretty well at this point
is that when they move
from their traditional
on-premises data center to the cloud,
they have reduced the visibility, right?
You can't get in there
and wrap your arms around that server
like you used to do in the past,
you just don't have that option anymore.
And therefore, when you move to the cloud,
there is at least by default,
a reduced level of visibility.
So let's talk about the two blind spots
that I think are most
prevalent in the industry.
And one of the advantages,
one of the blessings
that I have in my role
is I get to speak with
literally thousands of customers
across the globe,
and I rarely get asked
about these two areas
that I'm gonna show you.
So let's dive into identity
and access management.
Now to just illustrate
why cloud identity and access management
is so very complex,
I've created probably an
overly simplified diagram,
but I want you to get
the point here, right?
And that is here, we're just looking
at a generic cloud account,
the cloud provider doesn't
matter, cloud provider X, right?
And it's a single cloud
instance or subscription,
depends upon which provider
you're more familiar with.
In this case here, I've created two roles,
dev ops admin, staging builder,
and I've also created a number of policies
that can be assigned to
each one of those roles.
Now, typically roles are
then assigned to a user.
It could be a user that's
right in your cloud account,
or it could be a single sign on user
from a third party IDP.
Any case, this is what
we're looking at here.
Now, in this case,
we're only looking at two
roles and six policies.
Those policies they're typically defined
in JSON or something like that.
What they do is they allow
or deny access to a service
or something like that.
And you can get extremely granular.
There's only three here for each role.
In most production
accounts that I've seen,
there's not two roles
and just six policies
it's usually hundreds of roles,
and maybe even thousands of policies.
It becomes really difficult
to understand what we call
net effective permissions,
net effective permissions.
And all that is is if you've given Jane,
maybe Jane's your user,
and you've given her access
to both of these roles
and we're just looking at a
single cloud subscription,
it's really difficult to know
what she can and can't do.
And then that problem is further magnified
when you add in the fact
that most organizations,
they don't have just one cloud account,
they usually have multiple.
Right now, we're looking at three accounts
and now let's say Jane has
access to all six of these roles.
And now we're not looking at six policies,
but we're looking at 18 policies.
Again, this is a very
over-simplified scenario
and what I wanna point out
is how would you actually know
what her net effective permissions are?
This is one of the challenges,
and a reason that I believe
cloud IAM is a blind spot
for most organizations.
Let's look at a red team exercise
that my team at Palo Alto
Networks under unit 42
carried out earlier in 2020.
And what they did was
is we were approached
by a large SaaS provider, and
they were a customer of us.
And they basically said,
"Would you red team our
cloud infrastructure?"
Now I will tell you
that we normally do not
do penetration tests,
we don't normally do those,
but in this case here,
we were just enamored by the sheer scope
and scale of their cloud environment.
We're talking massively
scaled, thousands of instances,
hundreds of thousands of users,
and the bottom line
was that we were able to
quickly own their environment.
Now let me tell you
exactly how we did this
and maybe you can then go ahead
and try to carry this out
in your own environment.
Number one, what we did was we brought up
a completely separate cloud account.
Just as if you would go out
and you would get a credit card
and bring up your own
cloud account, we did that.
And then we started to do some recon.
Now this customer, they provided
us very limited information
on their cloud account.
We knew just a few things,
we didn't have remote access,
we didn't have a login,
username, and password.
And so what we did was we
acted just like an attacker.
We went out and we started
to do reconnaissance.
We searched on Google,
we went to amazing places like GitHub
where developers
unfortunately, like to give out
some times more information
than they should.
And so we were able to
mine through all of that
through our reconnaissance operation.
And again, all publicly
available information,
we were able to concatenate that
and then to start an enumeration exercise
where we're basically testing
different configurations,
different role names.
And after doing this
process for several days,
we were able to procure
a temporary access token
into the customer's environment.
I wanted you to note here,
this is one thing that I think
most organizations don't realize
is that when you're carrying
out that enumeration exercise,
you typically have zero
visibility into that.
Now, if I was carrying out
an enumeration exercise
against your on-prem environment
or your on-prem, that's
maybe you're using something
like Active Directory,
you would see all of those failures
in your audit logs, most likely.
But in the cloud, when I carry out
a similar enumeration exercise,
you have usually zero visibility into that
because I'm not actually
attacking your cloud account,
I'm attacking the cloud
service providers, IAM service.
So as in the case of this customer here,
they had zero visibility
that we were doing this
until we procured that
temporary access token
in their environment.
And the way we were able to get that
was they had a misconfigured IAM role
via a role trust policy.
So this was a complete misconfiguration
on behalf of the cloud customer,
not the cloud service provider.
Now, once we had that
temporary access token,
we were able to see their
entire fleet of EC2 instances,
we could read from the metadata
that was attached to those instances.
And if you're familiar with metadata,
there's a lot of juicy
information that's in there.
One thing that we noticed
was that there were some S3 buckets
that were meant to be readable internally
by these EC2 instances only.
But because of this
misconfigured IAM role,
we were able to read from
those internal buckets only
from an external account.
And we noticed there was
all types of information
that was stored in those files.
And one thing that caught our attention
was a set of encrypted credentials.
Now, typically when you find
an encrypted set of credentials
it's game over, right?
If the encryption is done correctly,
if the private key is maintained properly,
it's usually game over
unless you wanna spend
a massive amount of GPUs
and processing time to attack
and brute force that file.
Well, it turns out we
didn't have to do that.
We didn't have to do it because
this misconfigured IAM role,
it gave us access to call
the key management service,
which then allowed us to decrypt
and get a set of plain text credentials.
Now, once we had those plain
text set of credentials,
we were able to log in interactively
and access all types
of additional services.
And as you can imagine, this
would have been a great way
to do a supply chain style of attack
because I mentioned that we
had access to their S3 buckets
well, you can store all types
of things in S3 buckets.
And one of those things that we found
was a source code repository,
and we could have
infected that potentially
which would have then impacted
not only the customer,
but then also all of
their other customers.
Now I wanna call out.
In this case here, and here's
a kind of an extracted view
of what we started with originally
around talking about just
the complexity of cloud IAM.
In this one case here, I've
got dev, test, and prod
and while this is genericized
as to protect the customer,
we were able to penetrate
through not just their dev environment
or just the test environment,
but rather through all
of their environments
because they actually
followed a best practice.
Now you're thinking, wait a second,
a best practice got the
customer in trouble?
And the answer is yes.
They used infrastructure
as code templates.
And because they had a misconfiguration
in those infrastructure as code templates,
it replicated across all
of their environments
which mean that we were able
to get across all of the
environments and own all of those.
So this is something
that you need to be extremely mindful of
as you build and as you
mature in the cloud.
Now you might just be thinking,
"Well, hmm, that sounds
like you just found
kind of like an ace in the hole,
and maybe this is something
that was just extremely
unique to this customer."
Well, we thought the same thing,
maybe they're just having a bad day,
maybe someone just made a
mistake, right, mistakes happen.
So what we wanted to do
is just to see how prevalent
these types of misconfigurations
are out in the wild.
And so we started with a massive dataset,
and we really wanted to look globally
to just to understand how difficult
and how widespread this problem is.
And so what we did is we went out
and we got a massive, massive data set.
As you can see here, we love,
and you'll see this over and over again
if you look at unit 42
cloud threat research
you will see that we love GitHub
and we go back to the
source over and over again.
And so we essentially scraped, again,
all publicly available information,
we scraped almost 300,000 files
and nearly 150,000
source code repositories.
And then from those,
this is essentially a huge
data science operation,
we were able to extract
nearly 70,000 role names,
and nearly 33,000
potential cloud accounts.
You can see we kind of windowed this down.
And then we had to do a
little bit more refinement,
you can't always believe
just because you found 33,000 accounts
that those are all valid.
So we had to do a process,
call the cloud server
first provider via an API,
test that those counts are still valid,
and then of course we couldn't
do this iteration process
through with 70,000 roll names,
it would've just taken probably months
and we didn't have that time.
So what we did was we went through
and we found the 500
most common role names.
And those are the ones we started with.
So we basically took,
here's 500 of the most common role names
along with those validated
cloud account lists.
And then we just tried
different combinations
enumerating through them,
looking for what are, again,
some of those combinations
that might cause misconfigurations.
And well, let me just
show you real quickly
what our research revealed.
Again, this is all from
publicly available information,
essentially a very large
dataset science's operation.
What we found again with
these misconfigurations
is that we could have had access
to literally thousands of EC2 snapshots,
hundreds of S3 buckets,
and a whole lot of KMS
keys, and RDS snapshots.
Now the level of that access
that we could have had
to these different types
of information, it varied
in fact, it varied greatly,
in certain cases, it was
just read only access.
And then perhaps at the worst,
we could have executed lambda functions
on behalf of various
different accounts worldwide.
And so you can imagine in
the hands of an attacker,
what they might do with
this type of access
that is so widespread and so
prevalent in the industry.
Here's what I want you to take away
from this first blind spot.
It's that when you have a
compromised cloud account
due to one of these types
of misconfigurations,
it is almost always much worse
than a compromised cloud host.
Now think about it.
If I am able to compromise a single host
in your cloud account, maybe
you're running a window server
and it's missing a patch.
I execute a vulnerability
or an exploit on that,
I get a shell, I can get to
the data that's on that host,
maybe the data that's on that segment
if I find other hosts that
have that vulnerability
but I'm generally limited
if you've done your network
segmentation correctly.
Now in the case of what we found,
it didn't matter if you
had every single host,
every app patched, MFA turned
on, it wouldn't have mattered
because I can weave
around all of those things
when you have an
identity-based misconfiguration
at the cloud service provider level.
So this is an area that I
believe is the first blind spot
that most organizations struggle with
when they move to the cloud.
Now a few minutes ago
we touched a little bit
on infrastructure as code.
And I think that this is really an area
that is really blossoming
for most organizations.
And for maybe some of
you who are uninformed,
or maybe just haven't used it a whole lot,
infrastructure as code
is certainly the norm
for most dev ops and most
developer led organizations.
Now, when it comes to security teams,
that is different story
and they're all over the map
in terms of if they're using it
and how much they're using it,
but the bottom line is
that infrastructure as code
is a way that you no longer have to go
and manually provision
your cloud infrastructure.
You don't have to go to
the cloud service provider
and log into the console,
click here, click there,
you can instantiate
your entire cloud infrastructure in code.
There aren't many, many benefits,
but as a security team or
as a security practitioner,
this should be something
that you are championing
because it aids in
standardization of the system.
And as we all know, the more
that you can follow a standard,
the easier it is to
keep that system secure.
And there's many ways to do that.
Now let me share with you
perhaps the negative side of it,
about how doing a best practice
can lead to misconfigurations.
What I'm sharing with you here,
this is from a previous
cloud threat report.
If you wanna see this specific report,
you can just go to
cloudthreat.report/spring2020
and it will take you
directly to this report
where you can go into all the details.
But I wanted to just share
with you a couple areas
that really stood out to me.
The first is that, you
know, the methodology
behind this specific research,
we literally surveyed
almost a million infrastructure
as code templates.
And again, you probably can
guess where we found these,
that's right, GitHub.
GitHub through the GitHub searching API
we were able to download
and essentially scrape from their site
all of the templates
that were available publicly at the time.
And what we found was that about 42%
of cloud formation templates
had at least one or more
insecure configuration to them, 42%.
Now cloud formation templates,
they tend to be the most prevalent
simply because, and
they're specific to AWS,
AWS was the leader in
infrastructure as code
so they tend to be what is the
most out there in the wild,
but 42% of the ones that we surveyed
had at least one insecure configuration,
perhaps it was identity,
perhaps it was something else,
I'll share with you in
just a couple of minutes
what exactly those issues were.
But 42%, that's a high number.
The next comes to permissive access.
We found that when organizations
rely upon infrastructure as code
to create their external
and even internal security boundaries,
76% of the time, they're
exposing sensitive ports like SSH
directly to the internet.
That is a very poor practice
unless of course it's intentional,
maybe it's a bastion host
or something like that.
But we've seen this behavior
over, over and again.
So 76% allow that very sensitive access.
Now this next one is somewhat
befuddling and questionable,
but 60% of cloud storage,
again, this is all surveyed
through these infrastructure
as code templates,
60% have their logging disabled.
Now this is where we started
out in the presentation.
But can you imagine if you're
configuring your cloud account
through one of these templates,
that means that if you
had some type of issue
where you had exposed some
sensitive files to the internet,
if your logging's disabled
and an auditor asks you for it
or someone in law enforcement
asks you for those logs,
you're gonna have no way to provide those.
Now, one of the reasons that we suspect
this number might be so high
is that a lot of times,
these infrastructure as code templates
are actually created in
development environments.
And then they get migrated
to those higher level
environments UAT, prod,
a lot of times they're not upgraded
for those higher level environments.
So that's one way we suspect
that this number might be so
high around cloud logging.
Now, the last area here
that I wanna call out
has to do with encryption,
which is very closely related
to privacy and compliance.
We found that 43% of the time,
when organizations are configuring
their cloud native databases
via infrastructure as code,
they actually have encryption
at the database layer completely disabled.
Now, if you're like most organizations,
you fall under multiple
different compliance mandates
from GDPR, to CCPA, to HIPAA, to PCI
all of those have some type
of encryption requirement.
So these are just some of
the high level findings.
Let's zoom in a little bit,
and look at specifically what we found
around cloud formation.
Now cloud formation templates
again, they're specific to AWS
and I mentioned that we found 42% of them
had at least one insecure configuration.
In this case here, you're
looking at the top 10
but I wanna call out
just a few specific areas
that I think are interesting.
Number one, we talked a little
bit about encryption already
but you can see here that
when it comes to S3 buckets
which are extremely useful
and extremely prevalent,
that almost half of the
time, 48% of the time,
organizations have server-side encryption
completely disabled.
And this is literally a
flip of a configuration
where you can turn this on.
This is not bring your own key,
this is where AWS manages the
encryption key on your behalf.
So this is a very easy setting to turn on
but unfortunately, almost half of the time
we found it to be disabled.
The other one, and maybe
even perhaps more troubling,
we found that AWS-RDS instances,
that's the relational database service,
almost 42% at the time, those
instances are not encrypted.
So that's a challenge.
Number two has to do with eventing.
So when an event happens
in your cloud environment,
that could be a start
and stop of a service
maybe a delete of a
service, things like that,
well, we're seeing that
almost 100% of the time
specific to the relational
database service,
that the event subscription is disabled.
That means that if you
had a security issue
in your environment and
related to an RDS instance,
which is an extremely popular service,
that you would not be
able to tell forensically
what actually happened leading
up to a security event.
So these should be on.
There's very few good reasons
to have these services disabled.
Now, the next area has to do with logging.
Logging is generally what we think about
when it comes to security,
but there's a separate area with eventing.
So as you can see here, we
found that about 55% of the time
that organizations are
configuring access logging
via infrastructure as code templates,
specifically for S3 buckets,
35% of the time they have
the logging disabled.
This gives you a little bit more
of a lower level view
into what we're seeing.
Now, I can almost read your minds here.
Some of you are thinking,
"Well, I don't use cloud
formation templates,
I use something that's
more multi-cloud friendly."
Well, you're probably
then using Terraform.
Terraform is extremely popular
because it allows you
to do these multi-cloud
infrastructure as code templates
across all of the major
cloud service providers.
But those that are using Terraform
while the numbers are a little bit lower,
they still had some fairly serious issues.
So we found that 22%
of all Terraform configuration
files that we surveyed
had at least one insecure configuration.
Now here's the top 10, right?
You can see the numbers
are a little bit different
but I think you'll see
that there are some
consistent inconsistencies
when it comes to security
misconfigurations.
Number one, and I lumped
all these together here
in logging, eventing, and versioning
you'll see again that while
the number's a little bit lower
when it comes to Terraform,
we found that about 67% of the time
access logging on S3 buckets is disabled.
The other one, I call, and this
is a little bit differently,
I don't think this came
up on the other one,
but we found that about 52% of the time
when it comes to objects
versioning, that it was disabled.
Now you're thinking, "Object versioning,
like, why is that important?"
Well, it's really important
in the case of ransomware.
So if you have a ransomware attack
and it's able to encrypt
your cloud storage,
if you have versioning disabled,
you have no way to roll
back to previous versions.
You might have a backup of that file,
but that backup is likely
going to be encrypted itself.
That's why the versioning is so important.
Now the next one, this
one I kinda chalk up
what I call to public exposure.
And this one's a little bit scary.
We're talking now about AWS-RDS instances
that are completely accessible
to the public, right?
RDS snapshot, so a snapshot,
it's not a full backup
but it is a aversioned backup
of a smaller section of the database.
In this case here, we found that, again,
this is all all through
infrastructure as code
delivered environments,
we found that those
snapshots, 79% of the time
are available to the public.
There's all types of sensitive data
that is usually kept in
a relational database.
This is scary.
The last area is what I would
call allowed ingress traffic.
In this case here, you
can see there's a number
of overly permissive access
that is being allowed in the environments
from SSH to just security groups
which are sort of AWS's
cloud native firewalls
that they're allowing all
types of permissive access
into the environments.
So these are really two different areas
that I think are really important.
I think from cloud identity,
all the way to infrastructure
as code templates,
I'd say that many security teams
especially when it comes
to infrastructure as code,
they don't realize the threats
that they might be allowing
in their environment.
So you're probably thinking,
"Okay, you got my attention.
I'm a little bit scared.
What can I actually do, to
make the situation better?
How do I better manage these risks?"
Well, there's a couple ways
that I think you should look at it.
And number one, that's by making sure
that you have a holistic view
of your cloud infrastructure,
and also the entire software
development lifecycle.
Now we've talked about
Shift Left, secure CICB
for many years in the industry
but many organizations have
not yet gotten to the part
where they actually are integrated
when it comes from people,
process, and technology
into all three of these high level areas
that you're looking at here.
So the build phase for most organizations
what this it looks like is if
you have your own developers,
they might be writing a new application,
maybe they're creating a new container,
maybe they're creating
a new infrastructure as code template.
This is where you can really
enable your development teams
to create secure code from the beginning
by enabling them with
plugins, security plugins
right in their integrated
development environments
so they can create secure templates
and secure containers to start.
You're trying to do this,
and trying to push security
to the earliest possible point
in the software development lifecycle.
Now, if we move to the next
phase, the deploy phase,
this is really where you're looking
at repositories and registries.
So in the case of containers,
if you're using things
like Docker and Kubernetes,
you might have a centralized
or maybe you have a handful of registries.
This is where you can begin
to scan those registries
for those common misconfigurations.
Again, maybe you have a developer
who just created a new
infrastructure as code template
and they've uploaded it to a build server,
maybe using something like
Jenkins or circle CEI,
you should have the ability
to be able to scan those
infrastructure as code templates
at the time they are checked in
to make sure that there are
none of those misconfigurations
like we talked about previously.
And then the last phase,
this is the run phase.
This is where most organizations
typically focus their security.
In fact, if I had to break it
down into rough percentages,
probably 80% of most
security teams resources
are focused on runtime,
and a scant 20% on the other,
and maybe it's even less.
But the runtime is equally important.
This is where you are leveraging
cloud service provider APIs
to get that visibility into
your cloud infrastructure,
but at the same time
when it comes to securing
the actual workloads,
be it a VM, or a container,
or a serverless function,
this is where you need
that runtime security
to make sure that a container
is behaving as it's expected to behave.
And then if it works outside of that,
you should be able to immediately
put a corrective control in place.
You only get that with runtime security.
So it's gonna usually be a
combination of some kind of agent
that's running at the workload level,
as well as API-based
security leveraging those.
That's really the only way
that you can really try to address
all of these and other blind
spots in your environments.
So in terms of maturity,
this is a question that I often get asked
is where should I be aiming
to go the next few years?
Well, number one, I always recommend
that organizations start
with deep cloud visibility.
And this again, goes to making sure
that you are using people,
process, and technology
that know how to leverage the
cloud services providers APIs.
You should be able to
understand all of your assets
across all of your cloud accounts
and all of your cloud service
providers in a single place.
You shouldn't have to go
to multiple different tools
to be able to get that
multi-cloud visibility.
So let's start with
that, that's number one.
After you have some
semblance of visibility
and situational awareness,
you then wanna move to looking at,
how can I put automated
guardrails in place?
And that may sound fancy
but automated guardrail basically means
I want you to think in
terms of anti-patterns.
What are the as configurations
that should likely never
exist in your cloud accounts,
and then I want you to go out
and look for those proactively,
and then if you find them,
to automatically take a corrective action.
Don't wait for a ticket
to be filed in the SOC
'cause sometimes that can take weeks.
Look for how when you see condition X,
you can take action Y immediately.
The third part of this
in terms of maturities
is what I call code movement transparency.
And this is really about mapping out
your entire software
development lifecycle.
It could be understanding
who, what, when, where,
who does what, what teams,
really mapping this out.
I've seen many teams do this successfully
and oftentimes it takes months,
but they've created videos
that really show this is the workflow
of starting all the way
back at the developer's IDE,
and this is how it moves
through in a workflow.
Once you've done that,
that's when you can really
start to understand,
okay, how do I take my security tools
and my security processes,
and how do I embed them into that?
That then leads us to the fourth step
which is about setting quality standards.
And quality standards is just another way
of saying that security becomes
another component of quality.
And so this is where you
set your security standards,
and security standards
are really important,
they're always important
but especially in the cloud,
because you cannot automate
what you haven't standardized upon.
This is where you should be looking
to heavily leverage
infrastructure as code templates.
Now the fifth step,
this is what I call you at
cloud optimized security.
This is where you've got
security people, process,
and technology fully embedded
into your CICD pipeline,
you're looking at all things
in terms of cost controls,
compliance, security,
you're leveraging things like cloud DLP,
you have strong IAM governance,
and you're doing that across
all workload form factors.
Don't just focus on traditional VMs
because you're using those today,
because I can tell you
that in your future,
no matter the industry,
containers will be in your future
even if they're not there today.
And then even further they're out,
and again, this is still
a little bit further out
organizations, many of them I've work with
are starting to experiment
and leverage serverless functions.
So make sure that you've
got that full visibility
across all of those workloads.
Now, how do you apply
some of these things?
Well, I tried to stay
away from the 30, 60, 90
simply because depending upon
the size of your organization,
if you're in a 500 person organization
or a 300,000 person organization,
the timing is going to
be wildly divergent.
So these are the kind
of the three next steps
I would encourage you to take.
Number one is make sure
that you are gaining
and maintaining that
multi-cloud visibility
with threat detection.
This is important.
If you remember the pyramid
on the previous slide,
this is that first step.
You always wanna start there
because it becomes really critical
and almost impossible to do
the rest without visibility.
So that's number one,
and you can typically get that capability
from a cloud native security platform.
I encourage you to start
there and then move up.
The second piece, and this goes directly
to the IAM security pieces
that we talked about
earlier in the presentation,
I want you to go out and look
at how you can auto remediate
some of those really common,
excessive IAM privileges
and misconfigurations.
As part one of our previous report,
we actually developed a open source tool
free to use called IAMFinder.
You can either go to the link
or you can just go to GitHub
and search all one word, IAMFinder,
and you can run that against
your AWS environments.
The next piece, and this is
easy to say but difficult to do
but to make sure that you
have a program in place
that will allow you to
shift security left.
And there's really kinda two
high-level pieces to this
that I wanna call out,
the first is I wanna make
sure that you are scanning
all of your infrastructure
as code templates,
containers, et cetera,
functions, whatever it might be
prior to deployment.
I wanna make sure you're doing that,
and then I want you to also be willing
to not just report on issues,
and they might end up Jira,
some kind of bug tracking
but if you find something that's
critical or high severity,
be willing and have a process in place
where you will actually break the build,
don't push misconfigurations
to production or UAT environments.
Well, I hope you enjoyed a lot
of what talked about today,
and I would encourage you
to download our latest cloud threat report
where we spent a lot of
time looking at security
pre and post-COVID-19 discovery.
You can see that report by going
to cloudthreat.report/1h21.
Thank you so much, I hope
you enjoyed the talk today.