- Hello everyone, and welcome
to Building Privacy-Resilient Identity.
My name is Ankur Patel.
I'm a Program Manager on the
identity team at Microsoft.
And with me is Daniel.
Daniel is with our standards team
and he leads the standards work
around verifiable credentials
and decentralized identity.
- Hey there Ankur, great to be here.
- Thanks man.
So, I wanna open the conversation with
why this topic is so important to us.
At Microsoft we believe that every person
and business deserves an
opportunity to achieve their best.
We believe that starts
with establishing trust.
As Satya said previously,
"all of us will have
to rethink about digital experiences.
We create experiences
that are rooted in privacy
as a fundamental human right
will be a bedrock for
experiences going forward."
Today, more than 128 countries
have some form of legislation underway
whether it's drafted or
in practice like GDPR
as in the case of European Union
or in California it's CCPA.
In each of these cases, organizations
are facing increasing responsibility
across a wide variety of topics when
it comes to handling data.
Whether it's how we capture information
what's the minimum set of information
that we can request of users,
of employees, of partners.
How do we use it?
How do we present it to
regulators and auditors?
As well as data subjects
to prove suitable use
of such important information.
This is not easy to do.
So what if we could verify
such information at scale
while protecting privacy?
This was one of the key questions
we found ourselves answering for Microsoft
but then for our customers as well.
What we discovered,
is that conventional
privacy management focuses
on finding personal information
that has been collected.
But often this information
is trapped across many silos
whether it's for employee purposes
or partner management
or consumer management.
And they have different
regulatory requirements
depending on the use
rights associated with it,
with the geography in which such scenarios
are being experienced.
And ultimately that results in
a lack of actionable insights
for what information does
a business need to retain
and manage on an ongoing basis,
or needed it at some point in time.
The net result of it is
a cumbersome, complicated
and high level of assurance
and risk processes around
keeping track of information
and proving compliant use
rights associated with it.
So we challenged ourselves to imagine
a different form of identity system.
So this slide used to have a title
called Incubation Hypothesis
for us four years ago.
Now it's the North Star
of identity at Microsoft.
We believe each of us
needs a digital identity
that we own and control,
one with securely and privately stores
all elements of our digital identity.
Now us here could represent
a person, a business
maybe a device, maybe
you want an application
or a service that represents
such persons and organizations.
But ultimately we also
believe that it needs
to fit seamlessly into our existing lives
or internet or business processes.
It would be a failure if we have
to reinvent a whole new technology stack
in order for such a solution to be useful.
So let's take a look at a demo
of what this new
experience could look like.
So here on my screen, we have a flow
where we are trying to
remotely onboard and employee.
This is a very common scenario
that just about every business faces.
Onboarding new employees,
partners, customers
or anyone else for that matter.
So let's imagine we received an email
to welcome us to the company.
In this case, we are Matthew Michael
and you're asked to as
is often the case
perform background check.
In our case number of
ID verification partners
around the world are leaning in with us
to explore identity verification
based on open standards.
So here's what Michael's
experience could look like.
In this case they're now clicking through
and going through a partner website
in this case it's TrueID
a fictitious ID verification
company for this demo.
And Woodgrove as a customer
has agreed on a policy
to verify their selfie and
their government issued ID.
Now, of course, this experience
could be as complicated
as the customer would like to make it.
It could even include
come see me in person.
But given COVID and remote verification
and remote onboarding
being a common place now.
Imagine you're asked to upload a selfie
and a government issued document.
ID verification partners
today are capable of
not only matching the
selfie of this person
to the state issued document.
In this case it's a driver's license
but they can do so across 192 countries,
6,000 different document types.
Now, of course, this is a
commonplace when it comes
to financial industries like banks.
They have been doing document verification
such as this for a long time.
But what's different now, is every user
can just as easily now scan such a QR code
that is issued at the end of
this verification process.
Type in
this pin which establishes
trust for remote signing.
And
upon doing so I can accept this card
just like I would have
accepted a card from
any digital wallet today on the internet.
If we tap on this credential,
it shows not only the name was verified.
And then this was a genuine document.
The selfie was verified
but also the address that goes with it.
Now such a credential can be
presented back to the employer
and you can say, I've
completed my background check.
What used to take days,
time and money and personal information
being peanut buttered
all over the internet.
Is now under the user's control.
They can present such a credential
by just scanning a QR code
and upon verifying the employer
can give me access to the Employee Portal.
The employee now can
continue the journey instead
of getting usernames and
passwords being issued again.
They can get a digitally signed credential
from their employer, which
I can take possession of
by giving my employee ID number.
And now I have these two credentials.
One of the first things
that most people do
when they get their new job
is order some sort of computer.
So we've all gone through
retail websites like these
and signed up for corporate discount.
So in this case, I'm going to sign up
for proving that I work at a given company
by using usernames and passwords.
But how many such websites
would a retailer federate with?
So instead in this new world,
they're able to scan this QR code
and prove that they work at Woodgrove
with the tap of a button
And I get my corporate discount.
Furthermore, if I click on this credential
recent activity shows when
was this credential issue
to whom did I present?
And the user has far greater insight into
what information they're sharing,
with whom, for what purpose?
So this is a quick overview
of what's possible today.
So in this demo, we just looked
at how based on open standards
issuers can issue
credentials that can be used
at a wide variety of places
and not require the user to create
different usernames and passwords
with every website they interact with
and further give control to the user
for such information.
So we believe by extending the familiar
multi-factor authentication.
So in our case, what you noticed
was Microsoft Authenticator app
being used to not only prove
that you had possession of some credential
but presented to a wide
variety of websites
just like you were used to presenting it
for your own company.
So on the left side is your
Microsoft Authenticator
that you are used to doing
multi-factor authentication.
On the right side what you're
seeing is the evolution
which includes now this open
standards base authentication
and presentation flows.
Which enables a user to
have a more verifiable way
of presenting their information.
A more transparent way to understand
what was shared with whom
and for what purpose.
And ultimately have a convenient way
to track such information
and how it's been used.
In the coming weeks and months we'll
be building some features
which allow the user
to further restrict use rights
directly from their phone
instead of having to figure out
all the other websites I have visited.
So this work is based on open standards.
A lot of this work started
in Decentralized Identity Foundation.
And the standards have
been ratified in W3C.
The bedrock of this technology
is based on Decentralized Identifier
and Verifiable Credentials.
Now, in a traditional identity system
a user has a User Agent
which is provided by the identity system
such as a Microsoft account or
your favorite social network.
But the user doesn't have
the actual keys under their control.
They're sitting in a directory system
in a centralized identity provider role.
In a Decentralized System,
the users have a User Agent
like Microsoft Authenticator
being an implementation of it.
Where their biometrics or pin
are used to protect such keys.
And we use Blockchain to publish the state
of the latest set of keys.
Using a client implementation
of Universal Resolver
and open source library.
All participating
parties have equal access
to resolving these identifiers
and the state of keys.
As a result, any application
can request a credential of the user,
verify independently who issued it
and if this is the user who
should be presenting it.
This is very different than
a traditional identity system
where anybody possessing
a username and password
can pretend to be that person.
In such a decentralized world now,
we can decentralize verification
and establishing trustworthiness.
What I just demonstrated to you
was our platform implementation
of such open standards.
You can use Azure Active Directory
to configure an issue such a credential...
Such as a Verified Employee Credential.
You can use our developer APIs and SDKs
to request and verify such information.
And the end user wallet
is Microsoft Authenticator
to request and verify such information.
We believe such a tech
approach can help transform
our everyday scenarios
to be more trustworthy,
faster and easier for users to use
and ultimately result in reducing cost
and complexity for everyone involved
while improving control across
each of the stakeholders
whether it's issuers,
verifiers or end users.
But much more work remains on going beyond
just enabling this basic control.
We believe we can do better
in terms of limiting
disclosure and correlation.
So I wanna invite Daniel
Buchner from our team
who leads our standards work
on inventing some new ways
with the community and
collaborating with them
for imagining new ways
that we can restrict
such correlation and improve privacy.
Daniel.
- Thanks, Ankur.
Yeah, like Ankur was saying
we have more to do in the privacy front.
So, I'm gonna walk you
through a few of the things
that we have planned
to enhance the privacy
of the systems that we're building.
Now, one of the first things we wanna do
is reduce the correlation points
in some of these identity systems.
When you're transferring credentials
getting them issued by issuers
users presenting them to verifiers
and verifiers doing revocation
checks, for instance.
There are many points at
which there's communication
between these parties where
you can essentially disclose
what and when is occurring
and when you may not have to.
So, all of those little disclosures
can leak little bits
of privacy information
and working with the community.
We have ways that we're going about trying
to remove some of those.
Some of the ways we're doing this is
by implementing Zero-K
Proof, Credential schemes
like BBS+ and some SNARKs based schemes
to really move some of
those communication channels
away altogether.
And so to illustrate this right now,
as a user common flow
in some of the basic credential schemes
is going back to the issuer
for sort of this just in time generation
of a credential that they'd been issued
to present it to the verifier.
Now this presents a side-channel
in the sense that the
issuer then can learn.
You know, obviously just about
when you're going to present
a certain credential.
So remove this, we wanna be able
to generate derived credentials
on the user's device
without having to go
and speak to the issuer.
So in this example, here you can see
what occurs is now, the user
can cryptographically derive a credential
instead of going back
and having one issued
and present it directly to the verifier.
What that does is remove that channel
where the issuer is then
able to see what's happening.
Great for the user, same information
the verifier can verify
the business process
can still go on.
Another thing that we're doing
is implementing the W3C Status List 2021
which is a privacy preserving mechanism
by which a verifier can
check with an issuer
to learn whether it
credentials, for instance,
has bee revoked.
Might be like a driver's
license or something like that.
Today currently, some systems
disclose the exact credential
or user that the verifiers inquiring about
but with this Status List 2021,
standard we're able to remove that
so that we're obscuring from the issuer
who exactly is being inquired about
what credential they're inquiring about.
So the next thing we're doing for privacy
is limiting disclosure.
And this just means like not disclosing
to verifying parties or
any other external parties
any information we don't have to, right?
We certainly wanna
facilitate the disclosure
of information that makes
business processes possible
and smooth interactions
between users and verifiers
but let's eliminate what
we don't have to disclose.
How we're gonna do this again
is by implementing certain
Zero-Knowledge Proof schemes
like BBS+ and SNARKs
that allow us to as you
can see here on the right
simply identify information
in this particular exchange
the street and city
that don't need to be disclosed
to a potential verifier.
And only present the
information that does need
to be disclosed like the birthdate
with schemes that enable
selective disclosure
and exchanged transport schemes,
like Presentation Exchange.
We're able to remove
those fields altogether
and present to the verifier,
just the information they need
for the business process
that engaged them.
So, last thing we're gonna do.
So additionally, we're going
to provide advanced capability
to mask data altogether.
We talked in the previous slides about
how we were going to reduce
communication side-channels.
We were going to eliminate
unnecessary disclosure.
And then the last...
The advanced capability we wanna offer
is the ability to obscure certain data
even though you're presenting it.
And let's talk a little
bit about what I mean.
Over here in this example,
carrying on from the last slide
you see that we're disclosing
the user's birthdate
maybe that's required
by the business flow,
but it's for the purpose of understanding
whether the user's over 21.
Now, in this exchange
were given the exact date.
But we don't have...
If we implement certain
SNARK-based ZKP predicates schemes
and DIF Presentation Exchange features
as well as offer some
good libraries out there
for developers and companies
that are implementing these schemes.
What we can actually do is
provide people a mechanism
to transition from disclosing raw values
to disclosing simple predicates.
And the predicates are,
is basically computation
over data that allows you
to give people a true or false
a cryptographic true
or false as to whether
it meets the criteria
for a business process.
These are some of the more
complex schemes out there.
They certainly require being
honed and developed further.
We are really excited to work
with the community on that.
To advance some of these
more privacy preserving capabilities.
We wanna partner with
you out in the community
to collaborate and
contribute to these efforts.
Now that could look
like partnering with us
to identify privacy issues,
accelerating open standards work
that happens in the
Decentralized Identity Foundation
and the W3C, as well as partnering with us
on integrating these systems
into your own products
to help kickstart the issue
and verifier ecosystem.
You can learn more about this
at aka.ms/ownyouridentity.
Ankur
- Thank you, Daniel.
As you can see, while
we've taken as a community,
a good set of first steps to enable users
to have greater control
over how credentials
are issued,
presented and verified.
There's much more we need
to do to limit correlation,
enable user to have greater control how
and when that information is disclosed
and have some say in it.
And ultimately even
prevent needless disclosure
such as what Zero-Knowledge
Proofs can enable.
However, a lot more work
remains of taking these ideas.
Some of them like Zero-Knowledge Proof
are many decades old,
bringing these ideas to work
with the modern internet,
with current applications
that run on OpenID Connect, for example.
So getting these protocols standards
and implementations all to work together
is going to require a partnership
from all of us working together.
So we really look forward
to partnering with you
on building these new class
of issuers and verifiers
for a more trusted internet.
I would love to share with you
some of these resources
to help you get started.
As Daniel mentioned,
Decentralized Identity Foundation
is a key working group...
Industry working group
where a lot of these ideas are discussed.
We've published our own
white paper on this work
and it describes work that needs to occur
over many more years to come.
Some of it we've done
much more work remains
is a quick overview video.
There's a developer walk
through documentation
and an ongoing blog series that describes
all the details from how
might such a system scale,
how might recovery work
as a cellphone key recovery scheme.
And there are many more topics
that the community is discussing,
but these might be a few
set of good resources
to help you get started.
Thank you very much for this
opportunity to share our work
and requesting your help
to help us go build a more
privacy resilient workplace
and ultimately a more trusted internet.
Thank you.