- Hi everyone, my name's Heather Adkins
and I'm a senior director of
security engineering at Google.
And I'm here today to talk a little bit
about building secure
and reliable systems.
Thank you to RSA for having me.
Thank you for all of you for joining in.
I'm here to answer questions throughout
so you can drop questions
into the chat box
and I'll try to answer
your questions as we go.
So I'd like to start today by pondering
some of the following questions:
Can a system ever be fundamentally secure
if it's not reliable and similarly
can it be reliable if it's not secure?
Now, if you think about the way
complex systems are designed
whether they're airplanes or automobiles,
a fundamental principle is to make sure
that they run and execute under duress,
reliably over long periods of time.
Similarly, we expect them to be safe.
Not only do we run to run safely every day
but to protect us in the
event of an accident.
And this is not unlike
modern computing systems
and large scale services
that we use online
like YouTube and Gmail,
perhaps Netflix and Zoom.
These are services we've
come to really rely on
especially during the pandemic.
They have allowed us to connect
with people all over the world
and get stuff done while
we're working remotely.
So imagine if these services
weren't reliable or secure,
for example if zoom was reliably running
during a classroom session
but a lurker constantly zoom bombed it.
Or if your access to Gmail is
really fast and stores lots
of data reliably, but your
email is constantly being read
by hackers because they
guessed your password.
And in reality, we as
developers have long relied
on principles of
reliability as cornerstones
in any of our designs.
If a system doesn't run
it, then it's not a system
but increasingly we're seeing
the rise in this principle
of security and its
close counterpart privacy
as being similarly mandatory.
So what I'd like to discuss
today are some new ways
we should be thinking about
resiliency in our systems based
in how they're architected and designed.
And these are the ways we thought
about how to make Google
really resilient over time.
And this is an increasingly
important topic.
Every day, we see new headlines
about companies that we
rely on being compromised.
Let's just take the example
of supply chain attacks
which is very front and center right now.
Supply chain attacks very
simply put, are attacks
on technology companies
that build the software
and hardware we rely on
and that we integrate
into our environments.
These are tools we use to design software
and hardware to compile
test, deploy software.
Even the tools we use
to verify that software
and hardware is in and of
itself reliable and secure.
And these technologies and
the companies that build them
we're all at risk and attackers
know how important they are
to us and how they can be
leveraged to attack others.
Now, if you're new to the
field, you may not realize
that these have been
going on for some time.
I put a quick timeline together.
How does you can see it's not complete
by any means those of you
in the know who will probably
spot some things missing
but it does demonstrate that
we've had some challenges
in this space for a very, very long time.
You might even wonder if we've known this
as a risk for a long time.
Why does it keep happening?
I would pause it it's
because as an industry
we haven't really gotten
down to earth serious
about how our systems need to be built
how our networks need to be constructed
and how all of these ecosystems
fit tightly together.
And we haven't made that
hard choice to change
how we teach practitioners
better ways to do things.
So the method I would
propose is that we start to
view these systems as
having interconnected
interlinked properties of
reliability and security
and that everyone who builds, maintains
and deploys them thinks of
these things as existing
not only by default, but
as inherently necessary.
And one reason I like
this framing so much is
that reliability concepts are
so familiar to developers.
And these concepts are
often more approachable
than some of our complex
security topics have been
over the many years we've
been talking about this.
At a high level, what
does this really mean?
What am I talking about?
It means we need to
rethink entirely the way
we build systems and the way
we approach designing things
in effect, we need to
reshape our ecosystems.
Now I'm fond of saying
that modern computing systems are a bit
like fish without scales,
scales help keep the saltwater
out or gills, gills, help fish
consume oxygen in the water.
Well, modern computing
systems are a bit like fish
that have not adapted
to living in the ocean.
Modern computing systems have
no resiliency on the internet.
That is the ecosystem that
they live in by default.
We need to start building
the systems differently
and reshape the ecosystem they live in
in order to avoid the kinds
of problems we are seeing
with the software supply
chain every single day
but practically, what does
this mean practically?
Let's walk through three
examples I pulled out.
There are so many others,
but I picked these
because we've walked this
journey at Google and
because they're hot topics
that I hear practitioners
discussing all the time.
The first example I'd like to use is
around enterprise architectures.
That is the kinds of
networks that we build
for the companies we all work for.
Now, when most practitioners are learning
about enterprise network
architectures, they're doing so
using curriculum that
that we've been teaching
in the same way for many, many years.
For example, right now,
if you're going through
a certification, let's take
the CompTIA Network+ cert,
you'll learn about the TCP/IP Stack
and what ethernet is.
And they teach network
segmentation as a security feature
which is great.
I also did a quick survey
through the academic courses
online at the moment
during the pandemic, all
of their syllabuses are
online, which is really great.
So let's take computer
networking class at Stanford
that they're teaching right
now, they're teaching all
of the same basics and
even some advanced topics
like software, defined networking,
but at a high level for us was 30 years.
Most of us are taught
and network architecture principle
that results in networks.
Like the one you see on this slide.
Here, we have the internet, which stands
to reason is relatively untrusted.
And then there's usually a connection,
an internet connection
into your private network
such as your company's enterprise network.
And then there are people who are mobile.
Maybe they usually travel for business
or occasionally work from home.
And very recently we've
also been seeing the rise
of software as a service and
corporate infrastructure moving
into cloud computing environments.
But surprisingly, one
thing that hasn't become
very common is the way
people work remotely.
In fact, I've met many
enterprises who moved to the cloud
but still require their
employees to connect
into the cloud-based services
through corporate VPN,
through the trusted corporate network.
And I often call this the castle model
where we assume everything
inside that trusted network
is safe and everything
outside the castle is not.
This castle model presents
us with a number of problems.
Let's talk first about reliability.
And again, I'll use the
remote worker as the core
of my argument here.
I think it's familiar to many people
because COVID-19 has really
brought us front and center.
First off VPNs don't scale very well.
And if you're in a company that's made
this transition to work
from home during COVID-19
you've probably seen this
firsthand systems designed
for people to occasionally work from home
began to fall over with the sudden traffic
when everyone was required to be remote.
And if you've also ever
tried to work on an airplane
using a VPN you've probably
experienced frequent drops,
or actually just the complete inability
for the VPN negotiation to happen.
And this is because VPN connections
are typically full tunnel.
The technologies behind them
like IP sec are really high cost.
And from a network traffic perspective,
they're not very efficient.
And finally, you know, all
this service aggregation
around VPN disconnects and
reliability issues leads
to productivity loss
and productivity loss means revenue loss.
On the other hand with security
unless you're very, very diligent and very
careful these kind of remote
work VPN architectures
start to introduce more
security issues than they solve.
First, you end up with roaming devices
that you don't necessarily control.
A lot of companies don't restrict access
to strongly managed, verified
devices, even Google,
and before it's tickets
journey to rethink this
over 10 years ago, lots of
people connected over VPN
with their personal
systems and many companies
even still today have a BYO program
where you can use any system to do it.
And goodness knows what's
going on on the systems.
VPNs are also often used to
grant broadly privileged access.
They are designed to be
tunnels for all traffic
between two highly trusted places.
And this means that if
any threat is introduced
into that roaming device,
children using them
for remote school, or unfortunately,
as we are increasingly
seeing spousal abuse at home,
you know, attackers can get
onto these machines
and then laterally move
from the VPN connection
into more sensitive spaces
of your network.
And this is not ideal.
And finally, when things don't go well,
if you start throwing up
roadblocks or start reducing access
users get creative.
I've known many users who have worked
around our security controls tried
to just in order to get stuff done.
So you can see here that
we have both reliability
and security problems
with this very traditional
enterprise network architecture
that we teach practitioners
in their training
and we want to do differently.
We would all be right to ask,
what could this look like to be better?
How can we reshape this ecosystem?
Well, Google started doing this back
in 2011 with the goal of doing just that.
And you often hear this
called zero trust networking
in some circles at Google we
pioneered this architecture
and called this BeyondCorp.
Beyond Corp being beyond the old Corp
or beyond the enterprise
that we used to know.
The premise here is that the
once trusted corporate network
is no longer trusted.
In fact, working inside a
Google building is the same
as if you were working
inside the Starbucks.
First, every device has
to prove itself is safe
Whether it's in that building
or whether it's here at home
where I am right now, a
series of checks happen using
what we call the trust decision pipeline
that allowed the device to
assert its trustworthiness.
This could be because the
machine has the certificate
that we've given it but
we'll also use other factors.
Like, is it the right patch level?
Has the user authenticated
using a strong authenticator
like a security key, or
are they even working
at the right time of day
that we would expect them to be?
Second, we leverage the fact
that most enterprise services
at this point are web
based productivity apps
like Gmail or Google docs
filing expense reports,
accessing HR systems.
This is all facilitated
today by the web browser
which is increasingly the
most important software
in the ecosystem.
And all of this means that
we can begin to narrow down
what traffic needs to be trusted
and to come from these trusted devices.
Now I'm simplifying here a bit for time
but effectively what we're saying is
that we do strong verification and machine
and the user before
allowing any SSL connection
to our enterprise cloud services.
There's no VPN, everything is done
over the internet using SSL.
The effect here is clear for
both reliability and security.
Instead of the heavyweight VPN
for connections into corporate services,
we rely on the strength of
the more performance SSL.
And by designing the network in this way
at any time we can make
the workforce mobile.
The solution even works on airplanes
without disruptive VPN
software, configuration problems
protocol issues with
routers and firewalls.
It just works as soon
as you open the machine.
And it also has a lot
of benefits for security
because we have confidence in the devices
that are accessing the cloud services.
We know who the employees are.
We know that their devices
are trustworthy also.
And one of the best benefits we've gotten
that wasn't immediate in
our design 10 years ago
but we have seen be very
successful throughout is
that if the attacker does
happen to get control
that roaming device they're
trapped, that's all they get.
They can't use this
connection to make remote
Windows RPC calls into the
active directory environment.
They can't access into the
company's financial server.
There's no trusted tunnel back
to a highly privileged network
or a set of highly privileged systems.
Now this isn't foolproof
but our studies have shown that
it does slow attackers down.
It slows our red teams
down and importantly
it gives us a leg up during
incident response to get
to the attacker sooner while
they're trying to figure
out what ecosystem they're operating in.
So you can see that
by rethinking the way the
enterprise architecture works
we've actually solved a lot
of problems about reliability
and security together.
And we can solve these challenges
together at the same time
in a way that the practitioners
in the field who are
implementing the systems can also
appreciate using the domain
that they're most familiar with.
Let's shift topics to my second example,
around application development.
And this is a really vast to topic.
So to give us some
focus, we might actually
consider web application
development for our conversation.
I did a quick survey,
you'll see a theme here.
I did a quick survey of
professional trainings,
certificates, academic studies
and there are a wide variety
of approaches that are taken
to teaching developers,
how to build, not just code
but systems that that code runs on.
And there are two pretty popular models.
There are others, but
I'll talk about these two.
The first is the three tier architecture.
And when I first entered
the industry 20 years ago
the three tier model was the
one talked about the most.
In fact, before I joined
Google many, many years ago
I used to run the large scale
mail system for excite.com
which was when web mail
was still very very new.
And our architecture,
mostly fit into this model.
And the second model that
we've seen become very
very popular because it's open source
and very flexible is the LAMP stack.
Now LAMP stands for Linux
Apache, MySQL and PHP.
We also use the P two mean Perl and Python
whatever scripting language you're using
to create the applications.
Again, there are other stacks
but let's just talk about
these two for a moment.
Now, these models provide a basic engine
for someone who wants to design,
implement and maintain a web application
such as an e-commerce website
and LAMP has particularly attractive
because it's all open source
there's reasonably good documentation.
A very strong community and
training that you can get.
It's also very quickly quick to deploy
on all the bins cloud providers.
You can quickly develop
and deploy a LAMP stack in
in any of the big cloud
environments at this point.
And you can even do it on
your home Linux system.
You can do it on a laptop
so that you can run an
e-commerce application
while you're on an airplane.
Nobody else will be able
to use it, but you will.
You can see there's a lot of
convenience and having quick
easy access to technology that just works.
And this is the promise of open source.
And it's, it's great for many reasons
but it does come with some
downsides, any developer
that has launched a
single LAMP stack instance
for example, for an online service begins
to notice the issues
immediately first reliability.
By default there's no load balancing
between multiple servers
which means that if you
have too much traffic
you can't distribute the load.
You find yourself having
to add another server
and another one
and then find a solution
for load balancing.
And you can kind of see
where this is going.
Similarly if you have an
errant process or a bug
in your code that leads to
an expensive database query
maybe it overloads the database,
your application queries
the database too often.
The web app has lots of
hanging up and connections.
It starts to become overloaded.
This is all expanded if you're
running the whole LAMP stack
on just one single machine.
And when all of this complexity is going
on and your app is crashing
you don't really know
which module is broken.
You don't really know where
to start your debugging.
Everything's broken all at the same time.
And keep in mind that there are solutions
in the space to help solve this.
And I don't want to
downplay the importance
of those common modules
networking hardware that
provides load balancing
and allows you to distribute
your apps and do replication.
There are certainly solutions for this
but they're strangely
not as straightforward
in default as we'd like.
On the security front this architecture
has no boundaries built in by default.
If you're running a LAMP stack
on a single machine, or even
if you've distributed across
several machines and sites
for say Apache for the
web server and MySQL
for the database, actually,
the way that these
are administered is that
people just set up SSH
between the hosts and your
MySQL connection allows you
to query any data over it and any time,
as long as you have the credentials.
So an attacker working
in this environment,
perhaps after exploiting a vulnerability
in your web application
suddenly not just has access
to that, but suddenly
has access to everything
because everything so
closely tied together
and the privileges are broadly shared,
and this is the way most
systems administrators
get introduced to security.
Is they find that they've
suddenly been hacked
by vulnerability in their infrastructure.
And suddenly the attacker
has access to everything.
And that's how I became
a security engineer.
I was assisted men who got hacked.
I think we'd like to think
about this differently.
I would hope in 10 years
we're no longer talking
about this problem I'm discussing.
And one of the solutions to
this, it's not the only one
but one of the solutions
is to this is to begin
thinking differently
and no longer teaching
the basic architecture I've described,
but instead encouraging people
to use these technologies,
Linux Apache, MySQL,
Python, hopefully over PHP,
is to use modern architecture
design from the very beginning
to put these pieces
together in a different way
that becomes the best practice.
And a prevalent example of this
is using Microservices as a concept.
Microservices segment elements
of an application into smaller components
create boundaries around them
and allows the components
operate in a container environment
or sandbox that provides
that boundary for you.
And then in order to work together,
the different components have to speak
over predefined data flows
APIs RPCs that can be
authenticated in strong ways
and in predictable ways.
And by doing this container
isolation plus data flow model
we're able to control the reliability
and security properties of the system.
Just a bit more carefully.
I grabbed an example here
from the Google cloud
migration documentation.
This is not a Google talk.
I am gonna use some examples from there
but you can find similar examples
in a cloud of your choice
but here we have a relatively
basic monolithic application.
You can see here in the diagram
that you have some app servers
perhaps these are web servers
for a commerce website and
built into the application there
you might do everything from
accepting the HTTPS connection
or allowing the user
to do a product search,
maintain a web cart, maybe even
go through the whole process
of purchasing what's in their web cart.
So these single app servers
tend to do many things.
You also have a cache server
and a search database, a
primary database, and replica's
this is actually a fairly complex web app
but you can see here,
the monolithic nature
of that application server
layer in particular.
But the commonality here is
that there are very few boundaries.
And because of this,
these systems often have
highly privileged access to one another.
Typically the admins can SSH between them.
You can connect from the front end
to the database with a highly
privileged SQL connection.
And they're also highly
dependent on the performance
of one another, any issue with
one becomes an issue with all
but what might this look like
if we consider a more modern
approach to the architecture.
And again, here, this example comes
to us from the cloud
migration documentation.
This is what your architecture might look
like if you decided to be redesign it.
And it takes the most important
thing that we're doing here
is that we're taking that
monolithic application layer
and breaking it down
into different functions.
And each function then
goes into a container.
In this case, it's a Kubernetes container
which allows you to take,
say the product search
or the web cart or the purchase
process, break them down
into a smaller app, and then
put them inside a container
all on their own, which we
then call a microservice.
Each of them would then
connect to other resources.
So instead of MySQL
perhaps you'd use cloud SQL
and access the data through
an API or an RPC interface
instead of the very broad SQL connection.
This allows us to better
control what kinds
of data can be accessed.
And we can put really granular
permissions on that access
so that it's more heavily restricted.
Separately, one of your microservices
might need to store metadata.
Let's say that your product search feature
needs to quickly retrieve data for search.
You always want that to be quite fast
we've learned that over time.
So perhaps instead of a
really heavy SQL database
you put this in a quick retrieval system
like Cloud Firestorm.
And so you can see in doing this
that we've broken the application down
into smaller components, and
as they speak to each other
they're speaking over APIs, and RPCs
this makes the application
a bit more complex.
So microservices are
somewhat controversial
and they need to be balanced
for too much complexity.
We know that too much complexity leads
to worse security outcomes actually.
But what we've gained here are
some very powerful boundaries
and failure domains, and
this benefits, security
and reliability in multiple ways.
For one, if one of your
microservices go down
let's say that you have
a catastrophic failure
of your product search feature.
If that microservice goes down
it won't necessarily bring the others
down because you've broken it out.
Yes, your website will be
a little buggy for a bit
but people could still check out
and they could still
click around your website.
It's also easier to diagnose
if that component is family.
Debugging becomes more straightforward
because you can see within that container
in that failure domain, that's
the domain that's failing
and it's quite easy to see.
This also benefits security.
An attacker overtaking any one
of your microservices means
that they're contained
within that environment.
They won't necessarily be able
to compromise everything else.
Secondly, the inherent
reliability properties
of configuring and running microservices
and modern cloud environments means
that breach recovery is
much more straightforward.
And typically you have to set
up the configuration ahead of time.
It gets stored in the
cloud as a configuration
your data storage solutions
are pre-configured and all
of this is highly reliable
in and of itself by design.
So should an attacker gain
control of this environment.
And you have to rebuild
a lot of that setup work
is saved, and I've seen
customers who get compromised
be able to redeploy new
environments in a matter of minutes
instead of the heavy work
that we typically have to do
in these more traditional environments.
Now I've prepared a really
simplistic picture here.
And for those of you who have
actually done this migration
you know, it's very, very difficult.
But I've simplified it for a reason.
It's because when we are taught
application design as developers
we are taught using very
simplistic examples.
I would advocate that when
we need simplistic examples
these are the examples we use instead.
And in fact that we began to advocate
as we build more complex applications
in our work that that looked
like these simple examples.
It's a way of changing the conversation
within our own ecosystem
and our community.
There's a bonus
because I do imagine
this sounds really hard.
And sometimes the light at the end
of the tunnel is very difficult to see.
So let's just talk about
mobile phone operating systems
for the slightest moment.
Every day, new developers
are being trained
to use the software development kits
for mobile phone apps,
and they're doing so
using frameworks that capture
the inherent properties
of what I've just discussed.
This idea of app isolation,
where the components
of the systems don't have default access.
Each app runs in a container,
and you have to apply
for permission to access data
outside of the container.
Now, you, as a user on
your phone, see this
in the form of allow and deny
permission prompts, right?
As a developer, the
developer doesn't really
have to do anything to
get all of these benefits.
The framework that is inherent
in operating system does it for you.
So we've been able to abstract a lot
of that complexity away from
the developer and the user.
Now getting to this
point with mobile phone
operating systems has
been a decade long journey
whether you're talking
about the Android ecosystem
or the Applebee's ecosystem,
or even the Chrome ecosystem
we have not, it's not been
an easy journey for us
but it's been a really beneficial one
because we are really getting the benefits
of having rethought the
way operating systems work
and apps work.
So just a quick example here
on how we can really make
change over the longterm.
And finally, my third example
I wanna talk a little bit
about managing infrastructure.
And again, I did a quick look
through all the training materials
and the certification programs for setting
up and managing infrastructure
and strikingly despite the fact
that we've been doing
this for many decades
it's still super common
for new administrators
site reliability engineers,
network administrators
and so on to be taught
that to manage a system
you have to log into them
with really high levels
of privilege, a root account,
an administrator account
or having enable access on a router.
And these broad privileges
make you feel really cool
about yourself, but
they have immense power.
I remember being rude at
Google and it felt really good
but I look back on it now
and I cringe with how much
power that those accounts had.
You can upgrade software
and change configurations do debugging.
That's all great.
You can also accidentally
delete the file system
or corrupt data, or even
bring the system down.
Any Unix administrator
who's been in their field
long enough has accidentally
deleted the root file system.
At least once I am guilty of that as well.
And it's not just about you,
anything that you can do
an attacker who's hijacked
your account can do as well.
And so if you've been
fished if you have malware
on your machine or you've come
to any other catastrophic outcome
this can be really dangerous
for the whole ecosystem
that you're administering.
And in a study that Google performed
on its own SRE's we spoke
publicly about this in 2019.
We estimate that there's a
0.01% chance that any SRE
at Google could make a
mistake and with a team
of about 1400 SMEs, that
means there's a 75% chance
of a major outage every year.
And that a major outage might
take search down or Gmail down.
And nobody wants that.
Now, mind you, this isn't
a massive infrastructure
the size of ours, but
you can extrapolate this
into your own environment that
it will happen eventually.
And again, I mentioned that, you know
anything that you have
an attacker can get too.
And so we realized at
Google quite a while ago
that really what we
wanted was to stop people
from having route administrator
broadly privileged access
and that we wanted to
reshape the way we thought
about this and the way that developers
and SREs interact with
our key production systems
and what I'm gonna describe here
doesn't apply to every system at Google
but we've been able to apply
it to the most important ones
that are fundamental
to our infrastructure.
And this is now the default
such that every change made
in our production system is
validated either by automation
or pre-validated by software,
or we have two party systems.
And as a final result,
break glass mechanisms.
And I'll talk about what that means
but it effectively means that humans
are no longer directly
logging into the systems.
If they do it's a rare event.
And this is a concept
we call Zero Touch Prod
and it has massive implications
for security and reliability.
Here's one approach for
how we've solved this.
And this example comes
from a book we wrote
which I'll reference at the end
if you're interested in reading.
Instead of the SREs and
developers logging directly
into systems we've built a
set of command line tools
that send RPC calls to a proxy.
And this proxy only
permits certain actions
against the system to be made.
This is common actions like
starting and stopping a service,
deploying a new version of the service.
In the example you see here,
the tool will allow you
to kill a borg which is our nickname
for our cluster management infrastructure,
the equivalent of logging
into a unit system
and killing an Apache process effectively.
The proxy serves several purposes.
Its job is to authenticate
every request made,
and we do this with a highly
secure two-factor solution
called security keys.
And this means you can
no longer log in directly
as route and do a hundred
actions with one authentication.
You have to successfully
validly authenticate
for every sensitive action
that you want to take.
We also leverage the proxy to
enforce two party approvals.
That means if you want to do something
extraordinarily sensitive we
can require a peer to review
what you're going to do to see
if you're making a mistake.
The proxy also lets us
document any bug numbers
change management, IDs,
anything else associated
with the action, meaning that we have
a really good documentation
and attribution
on every change made in
our production environment.
The proxy can also do validation checks
to see if you've made any errors.
Maybe you've put an invalid path in
or you've got over-broad scoping
and you're gonna touch too many machines
that you didn't mean to
common issues such as this
that we've often seen lead to mistakes.
And we can program these over time
as we learn about new kinds
of mistakes that we make.
And you do still have a full log in option
if you are in the right kind
of role, but it's really meant
as a last resort in rare circumstances.
And they're small enough
and number that every time it happens
we can carefully audit that manually.
And the benefits I would
think are fairly evident.
Mistakes are captured
before they're executed
and we have great records
on how it happened and who approved it.
And on the security front
if you're an attacker
operating in this environment
it's actually really tough to do anything
with these accounts.
If you can imagine you've
gotten onto an SRE's workstation
your only interface into
production really is this proxy.
And it's not perfect because we know
from our red teams that it can be bypassed
but we usually see that it
usually takes the attacker longer
to figure out how to work around.
You can slow them down
before they get to anything.
And in some cases they're
fully prevented things
like security, keys to party authorization
really create strong
barriers for security.
Finally, coming all the way back
to our topic of supply chain.
Imagine if we had these
three examples deployed
at a company that developed software
if we were using zero trust networks
for us or using the
developers who are working
we would trust their devices.
We would know who they are at any time
and that they are safe to use.
Imagine your build repository
your build process,
your delivery pipelines.
They could all be
architected as microservices
in and of themselves with
strong boundary protections.
And all of this could be managed by SRE's
who practice Zero Touch Prod
techniques, and an attacker
in this environment would
have to work significantly
different than those that attacked
SolarWinds Microsoft and others recently.
And in fact, many of
the techniques they used
for lateral movement
and privilege escalation
just simply wouldn't work here.
And this would be
architecture we use at Google.
And we have witnessed the difficulties
that our red teams face
on a regular basis.
And it really does give
the blue team quite ahead
a leg up on things.
So in summary, by reshaping the ecosystem
and working very differently, we can begin
to move the conversation forward on
how we solve some of
these systematic issues
that we've been observing for so long.
So how might you get started?
This is always the big question
because it sounds really hard.
I would recommend starting small, you know
maybe next week you do a quick study.
How many outages have you
had in your environment
sort of how many attackers have
gotten into your environment
and maybe try to identify
where Zero Prod Touch
or Zero Touch Prod would have
worked if you'd had a proxy
in your environment mitigating
or rather remediating
some of your actions
would that have actually
prevented on the situation?
I think a lot of leadership
teams really value data.
And so having data is an
important thing to gather.
Secondly, maybe you'll have a workshop
with your colleagues to discuss maybe one
of your monolithic services
that isn't really working
very well and maybe play
around with the idea of a redesign.
What would that look like?
Don't get too bogged down
in and is it feasible?
I think it's important
to have the conversation,
even if your outcomes are failures,
if you fail enough times
you'll succeed one day.
And maybe try thinking a little bit
about training for the longterm.
You don't have to necessarily go out
and change everything right away
but you can start helping
the teams you work
with rethink some of these ideas
about how you can reshape your ecosystem.
And maybe you're stuck with
the systems you have today,
but maybe the next one, your
teams build will look different
than the ones you have today.
Re-architecting is always
hard, but when you can get
into the ground zero
and and start reshaping
from the beginning, that's really great.
And then I'll give you a
bonus, maybe host a book club.
I can recommend a great book.
This is a book that myself
and about a hundred Googlers
put together that describes
all of our experiences
and recommendations for
thinking about building secure
and reliable systems and
how you can move forward.
We use this internally
and read a chapter about every two weeks.
It's great to get together
and just talk through some
of the concepts in there.
And I know a lot of teams have
been very successful at that.
And then if you have any questions or any
of these three examples I
gave you or interesting at all
here's some additional
resources you can take a photo
of this or a screenshot
and these might provide
a little bit more insight
into how to do some of these things.
I think microservices,
especially as a concept
there's some great resources
going back several decades
but also some really great books
that have been written
recently that came out in 2020
during the pandemic particularly
on container security
the fundamentals of software architecture.
And I find these to be really,
really great resources.
So with that, I wanna
thank the RSA teams so much
and to thank all of you for
joining me here for chat.
And I wish you all of the best.
Thank you.