- Hi,
and thank you for joining
us for our session,
"Compliance Made Easy-
"Simplifying Your Approach to Privacy."
My name is Kelly Hood.
I'm a Cybersecurity Engineer
with Optics Cyber Solutions.
- And I'm Mike Green,
I'm also a Cybersecurity
Engineer with Optics Solutions.
Pleased be with you today.
Talk about privacy compliance.
- Great.
So today for our agenda,
we're going to be, yeah,
really talking about the approach
to simplifying your approach to privacy.
So to do that, we're going to be looking
how to bring requirements
together into one place,
to be able to streamline our approach.
And to do this,
we're going to use the privacy
framework that NIST put out.
So we'll provide an overview of that.
And then we'll create
a profile to document,
you know, what you're doing today,
and think it will help you figure out
what you can do tomorrow.
All in all coming together
to streamline improvement
activities moving forward,
to help simplify your approach.
So there are many similar
privacy requirements and controls
that we're seeing coming out from...
Many of the states across the US
are putting out different requirements,
such as CCPA that came
out a few years ago.
ISO also has requirements
covering cybersecurity
and privacy.
NIST has, you know, control frameworks,
and cybersecurity and privacy frameworks.
But one thing we see across
all of these different
standards and best practices
is there are a lot of commonalities.
Obviously there are
nuances between all of them
having slightly different focuses,
but here, for example,
we pulled out a few examples of,
specifically related to data inventory,
or understanding what you have.
So we can see from CCPA
that we're looking at the
sensitive, personal information,
understanding what we have,
what the sensitivity of it is.
ISO 27001 has requirements
for inventorying
your systems and data.
A153 has, you know,
requirements around inventorying,
and so does the cybersecurity framework.
But when we can look across
all of these different places
and see that there are
those commonalities,
it allows us to be able to bring
that together in one place.
And what we're going to
talk about doing today,
is bringing it together in one place,
in the privacy framework.
So here we can see one
of the subcategories
from the privacy framework
is focused on that systems, products,
and services being inventoried.
And so we'll talk about all
of these different things
and how to bring them together.
And as we do that,
we wanted to provide a quick overview
of the privacy framework itself.
So the privacy framework was published
or put out last year in January of 2020.
It does have three components,
the core, the profiles and the tiers.
And if you are familiar
with the cybersecurity framework,
this may look familiar, 'cause
it is set up in the same way.
So the core really,
is where we get those key pieces of
what should a privacy program include.
What are those things we need to be doing?
What are those outcomes
that we need to meet?
And that's what we'll be able to use
to look across industry,
and look at the different
standards and frameworks,
and say, "Where do these
things align and map?"
So the privacy framework, the core itself,
has five functions that we
can see here on the screen,
identify, govern, control,
communicate, and protect.
And these are all creating a hierarchy.
And this is the highest
level of the hierarchy
that helps us to understand,
what are those things we need to be doing?
To it, within our privacy programs.
And as we break that down
and the hierarchy, it goes from
the functions at the highest level,
to the categories, and then ultimately
to sub categories at the lowest level.
And so here,
we'll be able to look across and see,
what do we need to be identifying?
And here's back to that
example we were looking at
with inventorying and mapping,
and understanding, you know,
what are the systems that we have?
What are the data that we're processing?
What is that sensitivity,
and what do we need to be doing with that?
As we walk through these different areas.
The second component of
the privacy framework
is the implementation tiers.
And the implementation
tiers are really here
to help us understand how
sufficient we need to,
or how sufficient these
capabilities need to be,
and how kind of mature we need to be
in these different areas.
So they vary from level, or the tier one,
from adding a partial program,
to two, being risk informed,
three, being repeatable,
and four, being adaptive.
So it's often thought
of as a maturity model,
but it is a little bit different,
in that the tiers are not discreet.
And you don't also need to
get to be that highest level.
Where in a maturity model,
oftentimes you are trying to
be the most mature you can be.
But here it's okay to not
be a level or a tier four,
if you want to only be a, you know,
a tier two or a three,
where you know that you have
a risk informed and repeatable process.
That might be enough
for your organization.
But having this conversation
around the tiers
can really help us understand
and communicate well
across your organization and others,
to make sure that
everybody's on the same page
with where you're striving to be.
The tiers also have characteristics
within each of them,
broken down across risk
management processes,
the integration of your
risk management program,
ecosystem relationships,
and workforce as well.
To help you really,
as you're looking at what
tier you want to be to be,
to figure out how you would
actually implement that,
and what that means in your context.
Okay?
And then the third component here
is the privacy framework profiles.
And this is where we're
going to be spending
a lot of time today.
In our example scenario,
as we look at, how do we
actually build a profile,
and a profile is really
a place to just document,
what are we doing today?
Where do we want to go?
Basically bringing together the core
and the tiers, and defining
that in a central place.
So we can look at bringing
together our requirements
from you know, maybe our
regulatory requirements,
our business requirements,
and having all of this
information in one place.
And then using the tiers to say, you know,
how mature do we want to be?
How sufficient,
or do we want these capabilities to be,
for each of these, for
each of the sub categories,
from the core of the privacy framework.
Additionally, I just
wanted to point out that
the the core has, you
know, all of the, you know,
about a hundred sub categories,
but you you don't necessarily
have to do them all.
There's no requirement.
I mean, this is a framework
that was created to help create the bounds
and kind of the structure
for what a privacy program should be.
And it really creates that nice structure
as we start bringing together
those legal and regulatory
compliance requirements into one place.
But if you wanted to just
focus on a subset of them,
there's no requirement to use them all.
Here on this screen,
we can see an example where, you know,
you can see the core
has all five functions listed out.
Our current profile,
if we're looking at what
we're only doing today,
this example has, we only have things
across identify, govern, and protect,
but we haven't started
implementing anything in
control and communicate.
But knowing that we want
to get there eventually,
that's our target.
And that we're going to be covering topics
from all five areas,
but still maybe not all
of the sub categories.
But that's a conversation you can have
internally within your organization,
based on your risks and your needs.
So finally, before we
get into our scenario,
we want to talk a little bit about
cybersecurity risk and privacy risk.
Knowing that there is an overlap,
and oftentimes it can cause
a bit of confusion between,
you know, what is the difference,
how much of an overlap is there?
So we wanted to pause for just a moment
to talk about it for, talk
about it a little bit.
But cybersecurity risk
is typically focused on,
or associated with the
loss of confidentiality,
integrity or availability.
Where privacy risk
is really focused on the unintended
consequences of data processing.
So that could reach in, or
result in a privacy breach,
you know, or a lack of confidentiality,
some sort of disclosure.
But it's not often related
to the availability concerns
that would be more closely
related to cybersecurity.
So we wanted to just kind of highlight
as we're moving into this scenario,
and talking about the privacy framework,
and the privacy risks
that we're considering,
whether they're business related,
or coming as a result of
a regulatory requirement.
That's what we really want to focus on,
is those unintended
consequences of data processing.
And some of the key
terms that we'll be using
that show up in the framework
in a lot of these requirements,
are included over here on the right side.
With data being a
representation of information
that we're all familiar with.
But a data action
is a term that's used a
little bit less common,
or less frequently.
Where a data action is really,
all those things we're doing with data.
So that could be,
collection retention,
logging, disclosure, sharing.
It's what are we doing with that data?
And then data processing,
is really a collection of data actions.
So it covers the whole life cycle of data.
That could be all of those same things,
but looking at, you know,
what's being done with
that data over time.
And then privacy risk is really what
we're going to be looking
to mitigate, or reduce,
as we are looking at
the privacy capabilities
to put in place.
Then we want to make sure
that we're reducing the likelihood
that individuals will
experience any problems
with, due to, you know, data processing.
So now as we jump into
the example scenario,
I'll hand it over to Mike,
and he'll walk us through how
we're going to get started.
- Sure. Thanks, Kelly.
Yeah, I think that last
slide there with the,
the Venn diagram between
the privacy and security, (clears throat)
is really salient here.
We'll kind of walk through,
but it kind of forms the basis
for sort of the discussion here.
We kind of leverage those
cybersecurity frameworks,
regulate you know,
regulations, control, catalogs,
et cetera to kind of walk through
the examples scenario that
we have laid out here.
And just as a reminder, as
we kind of pointed to you,
upfront, with the, you know,
we have different regulations,
so here we actually pulled in CCPA,
you'll notice from ISO and NIST as well.
For this scenario we're
going to walk through more
from a inventory perspective.
So from a data inventory,
system inventory,
and you'll notice the
CCPA, as an example here,
just talks about sensitive,
personal information.
It doesn't explicitly mention systems,
but obviously you'll
kind of need the systems
to understand how the
processing kind of goes through.
So that's really,
we're going to go through
here for this example,
to kind of walk through
how you can use different
frameworks, different alignments,
to kind of interpret and understand
some of these more higher
level legal requirements
that different acts and laws
kind of brings from a privacy realm,
kind of align that to
the privacy framework.
And again, here, so you see the ID.IM-P,
so really,
we're focused on the identify function
for the cybersecurity,
for the privacy framework.
And so here you see an example crosswalk,
really across the different regulations.
You'll notice most of them here
from a cybersecurity
perspective, control catalogs,
different frameworks, and
we have CCPA there as well.
So on the left, the really,
as Kelly mentioned earlier,
the subcategories of
the identify function.
And you'll see here,
they're broken down into
specific statements or practices,
for really what you're trying to achieve
for this specific sub category.
Next here, as I mentioned,
you have the different regulations
sort of aligned in a crosswalk fashion.
And really here,
you know, there may be overlap there.
There's not usually a one for one mapping,
but you can kind of understand the intent
of a privacy regulation.
And kinda use this as
a basis going forward,
to kind of understand where to start,
when you're starting to document
your privacy program.
And then the last two columns here,
(clears throat)
are really the notes and gaps.
So really what you're doing here is
you're understanding from
inventory perspective,
really, what you're doing today,
document any notes, any gaps.
(clears throat)
It's essentially your
current understanding
of where you are from
a privacy perspective.
So you kinda understand
where you want to go,
how, I guess, as far as the tier,
where you want to be as far as the tier,
kind of meeting some
of these requirements.
So like I mentioned here,
we want to do is kind of walk through
each of these.
To kind of give a high
level, high level overview
and sort of some examples
of what this kind of looks like
in practice as you walk through.
- Right.
And so this will be an example
of a profile that we had mentioned before
on one of those core
components of the framework.
That a profile can take
a lot of different forms.
We've seen people use it,
spreadsheets is what we
typically like to use.
We find it's an easy way
to track the information.
And it's like Mike had mentioned,
being able to map the the subcategories
to the other regulations or frameworks,
and then include notes and gaps.
But we've also seen people use profiles
or create profiles that
are pictures and graphics,
and, or, pie charts,
or all kinds of different things.
So there's not any one way,
that is the, you know, a
right way to create a profile.
But we just, this is an
example that we like,
and we wanted to walk
through that with you,
and hope that it helps
to see how you can really
pull everything together and
capture it all in one place.
- So with respect to the overall,
so the process we're going
to walk through here,
so you kind of see on this sheet here,
we kind of have the gaps, notes
and gaps kind of filled in.
We'll walk through each
one of these in depth.
But again, just sort of
an overall perspective,
this is what we've seen kind
of work well for organizations.
You have a one place where you
can kind of map everything.
And specifically,
if you're an organization that's using
a cybersecurity framework or ISO,
you may have some of
this information already.
Typically the privacy may
be driven from compliance,
maybe, or the privacy organization within
a specific organization or a group.
But you may have inputs
from other parts of the business,
that's IT, or compliance,
or the cybersecurity
within the organization.
So really here,
I think this alignment kind of helps,
kind of form that
baseline, as I mentioned,
for organizations that sort of
have that framework in place.
And it's really it's here,
it's just a translation into,
it wasn't made from a privacy perspective.
(mumbles) most of the way there,
and they really what those
gaps kind of look like.
(clears throat)
For the first example here,
the ID.IM-P1,
it's really talking about
systems, products, services,
that process data, you know,
that process data are inventoried.
And really, when we're looking at here,
is really kind of understanding
what the inventory of data is.
And you'll see here in the notes
for this specific organization,
it looks like they have a subset
of critical business systems are included
in their configuration
management database.
But it looks like the
inventory doesn't account
for all of those critical systems.
And that's really what
we see in organizations.
You kind of want to start somewhere.
So if you understand
that you have a subset
of your critical businesses,
business processes,
or business systems sort of inventory,
that's a good place to start.
And kinda in understanding that gap.
And even as a first step,
that may be aligning to
what the critical business processes are
from you know, the business perspective.
So at this point you may not want
to get a full inventory
of all your systems.
Maybe it is just focusing on
the critical business systems.
And again, here you're
really just documenting
what the current state is
so you can understand where
you need to go from there.
If it is talking to other
parts of the business,
other parts of the
organization, but really here,
you're just kind of
understanding where you are.
So you kinda know where you need to go
with respect to building out
this profile that we have here.
- Right.
And like Mike was saying that this is,
obviously this is not a full list
of all of those critical business systems,
what's being done,
what type of database this is,
what's all being tracked there.
But one thing we like about this approach
for capturing it and kind of this form,
this type of profile, is
that I always think of it
like as an elevator speech.
If somebody came to you and said,
"So what are you doing to, you
know, with your inventories?"
And you can say, "Well,
we've got our critical,
"our critical systems are
included in the CMDB."
And you know, it's,
and you can kind of characterize it,
what it is that you're doing,
without having to stop and figure out,
where is the database, who controls it,
what all is included.
'Cause sometimes it's so easy
to get kind of bogged down in the details.
And knowing the details
are obviously important
especially when there's
regulatory concerns.
But as a step one for
somebody just getting started,
sometimes it's easier to just kind of
sit down with a sheet of paper,
write down what you know,
and get something there.
Because it's obvious or so commonly,
it's that starting with
a blank sheet of paper
that's the hardest part.
And once you've got
something written down,
like Mike had said, you can go talk
to the other people in
your organization and say,
you know, what on here is right,
what on here is wrong,
what don't I know?
And kind of get their input as well.
Okay.
So as we walk through
these, so the next one here,
we wanted to talk through ID.IM-P2.
So this is kind of building on ID.IM-P1.
Where owners and operators
and their roles with
respect to the systems,
product service and components,
are also included in the inventory.
So like Mike had said, we had,
in that first subcategory,
we know that we have a subset
of the critical systems
that are included in the CMDB.
But here we're asking, okay,
so now we know what we have,
or some of what we have,
but who are the people responsible
for those systems, for that data?
So looking at who are
the people responsible,
for our example scenario,
and for a lot of businesses that we see.
Oftentimes we know who the
business system owner is,
or the technical system owner is.
But honestly are a lot of times
the roles and responsibilities
of those people
are not often defined.
And so that's what we wanted to,
we captured here, in this example is that
we know at a really high level
who's responsible for
this business system.
But whether or not,
we haven't actually
documented what their roles
and responsibilities are.
So there's a lot of things you can assume
as being the person responsible.
You're the business system owner,
but a lot of times
having that written down
can go a long way to just making sure
everybody has the right communication
to know what expectations are,
so that we're not missing anything.
Also the BSO and the TSO,
they may have different
levels of responsibilities,
or authorities, and then it
does vary across organizations.
So having that captured
for your organization,
and what is necessary for you
can be really helpful with making sure
that everybody's on the same
page with those expectations.
And can also be a really great opportunity
to go back and talk to the
different business owners
and system owners
to say, "What do you think
your responsibilities are?"
'Cause here, just looking at like I said,
with this is, you know,
knowing this is the elevator speech of
maybe I'm the, you know,
privacy is, the person,
if I've been tagged with
figuring out what we're
doing with privacy,
with respect to my organization,
or a Chief Privacy Officer.
A lot of people are getting
new privacy requirement
or responsibilities added
to their roles right now,
that may not have previously
had those responsibilities.
But being able to step back and say,
what do I know, what don't I know?
And being able to document that,
and just get, like I said,
just get something on the paper for now,
and then be able to find
out those details as you go.
- That's really a key point here.
Is as you mentioned,
with the responsibilities,
and really who's responsible for what
from a business perspective.
A business owner may own the data,
but they may not understand the technical
interconnections with
different systems and things.
So in a lot of cases,
you may need to speak
to multiple individuals,
kind of understand the
roles, responsibilities,
to get a full picture of really
which systems or process,
and which data within the connections are.
And sort of what the
impact of that might be
as you kind of build out
your privacy program.
- Right.
And actually, in leveraging,
even looking back at those,
the columns in the middle,
where we're mapping back to CCPA
and cybersecurity framework
and all these things,
for anybody that maybe, yeah,
you know, might be
documenting this for the first time,
if you have already gone
through an exercise,
I think, yeah, Mike had mentioned earlier,
you can go take that information from,
if you've done a cybersecurity
framework profile,
for example, and see
what did you write for
ID.AM, you know, one and two,
or what did we say we
were doing for CPA, CCPA,
and be able to leverage that
information here as well.
- And so for the next one here, ID.IM-P3,
this is really looking at
categories of individuals.
Having examples here,
as you know, customers,
employees, consumers,
whose data's being processed or inventory.
So in this scenario,
this specific organization
doesn't have any specific inputs
or knowledge around, you
know, if that's being done.
And you see the gap here is really,
you need to evaluate categories
of data being processed
for the relevant subject types.
And, you know, that's, like I said,
what we're doing here is really just
documenting what the
individual, organization,
who was actually completing
this exercise knows at the time.
So it may be that the
organization does have it,
it's just not known by the specific group
who's kind of going through this exercise.
And that's totally fine,
but you're trying to understand what
the baseline of your privacy program
(clears throat) sorta looks like.
For some of these, for
this one in particular,
you may be able to infer the types of data
that a system process processes.
So if it's a human resources
system, for example,
I mean you can be pretty sure that
there will be employees' data
within that type of system.
So you could infer that,
but it may not be a full picture.
You could have contractors
or non-employees' data
that's also part of
that specific inventory
of data for that system.
Like I mentioned, I think the gap here
is really just to do that analysis,
what you understand.
Or when you say that there, you know,
you don't understand what the full scope
of documentation around
categories of individuals
where you do that analysis on,
system that you can reasonably infer,
and then kind of broaden
it out from there.
Again, probably focusing
on all the critical business systems
to really understand the
impact from that perspective.
- Right. That's a great point.
Sometimes I know it hurts to write none,
or that you're not doing anything,
but sometimes it could be
an impactful statement.
I mean, maybe it's something you've been,
you know you need to do,
or maybe you haven't realized
was something that needed to happen.
And it always, you know, it's,
sometimes it's always the,
you try to write something
up that you're doing
related to a subcategory or requirement,
which obviously gives you a great start,
if you are doing those things.
But by walking through the exercise
line by line like this, and kind of seeing
where those gaps are, it can
also be really informative.
To be able to say here are the real,
the things we need to start with,
or the things we don't
have anything we're doing.
And so it can be, as much as it
sometimes hurts to see the none,
or the, a blank cell,
sometimes that can be really impactful,
and really you can get
a lot of information
that way, or communicates a lot.
So the fourth sub category here,
data actions of the
systems product services
are inventoried,
it is focusing on what
are those data actions?
So when we were talking
about what are we logging,
what are we generating,
disclosing, sharing,
all the things we're doing with the data,
we want to document that as well.
In addition to the, you know,
the systems and the
data that we have, yeah.
What are we doing with the data?
So here and for this scenario,
our organization has the system functions,
and data processes are
documented for critical systems
in the systems requirements documents.
So this may have been done initially
for more of a functional purpose,
just wanting to know what
is it that our systems do?
What are we doing with
the data on our systems?
But it is just our critical systems.
And so we've got a note
over in the gap section,
that says the data
actions are not documented
for our legacy systems.
Which may be okay,
if we don't have a regulatory
requirement, or a real driver.
But in some heavily regulated industries,
or if we really know that we're processing
sensitive data or personal information
that we want to make sure
we are heavily controlling,
we may want to be able to go back
and look at those legacy systems.
Or look not only at our critical systems,
but any new system moving forward.
There can be a lot of opportunities there
by identifying what is
it that we know today,
and maybe a stepping stone to
getting everything documented
in all of those data actions inventory.
It's just that as we're
creating new systems,
or doing new things,
where we're documenting
and defining that as well,
and then we can address
the legacy systems in time.
But this is back to that.
You can take it back to
the tiers conversation,
as well as you don't
have to be a, you know,
an adaptive tier four
organization in every subcategory.
It may not be necessary always.
It really depends on your risk tolerance,
the risks to your business,
and those compliance drivers,
to know what is appropriate
for your organization.
So here is where you can start
to have that conversation
with yourself and say,
this is what I know I'm doing.
This is what I know I'm not doing.
And then we can look
at those gaps and say,
how do we prioritize?
Where do we need to start?
What do we want to do moving forward?
And at a later time.
But just knowing here, that for example,
that I know I've got my
critical systems documented,
because they were critical,
and I knew I needed to
have this information,
but the legacy systems we may
need to come back and revisit.
So just having that documented
can be really helpful.
- Yeah. I think that's true.
And in this case, it may even be,
as part of the action of,
we just use that same process that we use
to document critical systems,
and just apply that to all systems.
Or it may just be, you know,
for net new systems, we'll apply
the standard going forward.
And then there's a different process
to kind of handle those
legacy systems as well.
So again, as we kind of walk through this,
you can kind of see where there may be
things that aren't in place,
but you can leverage current
practices, current processes.
And at least be able to kind of, you know,
as you look at things,
prioritize what the focus may be.
If the legacy systems are legacy,
and they're being replaced by new systems,
it may not be as critical
to kind of walk through that exercise.
But kind of having things on paper
like Kelly mentioned that, you know,
having something on paper
where you can kind of evaluate,
take a look at, and baseline,
is really a good first step to kind of,
as you build out your
program and understanding,
or even augment and mature
your privacy program going forward.
Okay. So for this one, ID.IM-P5.
So the purposes of data
actions are inventory.
It looks like here for
our example organization,
their system requirements
mapped to the business process,
for the purpose of being, you know,
data being processed, where again,
it looks like here for the in,
the legacy system, that's not the case.
And it could just be a,
it could be like for several organizations
where you've gotten mature
processes over time,
and they just apply to new systems
as you kind of built out,
developed new systems going forward,
but you didn't do, you know,
go back and retroactively
apply that to legacy systems.
So like we mentioned, for
our previous subcategory,
it may just be that based on the process,
or the sort of the position
of the legacy systems,
where it may not make sense
to really document those actions.
If they're going to be
replaced in the near term,
certainly, from a compliance perspective,
it should be something that you focus on.
But if you have a roadmap of,
sort of how you're going to
handle this going forward
with the, you know, the
inventory or the data actions,
it's really something.
This document will be informative,
to kind of make those
decisions and understand.
We say legacy systems like
it's just one system or two systems,
where we talking about, you know,
a thousand systems,
will really be, you know
really drive that conversation.
You know, what the priorities will be
kind of going forward
to really meet these,
the intent of this specific practice.
And again, like we mentioned before,
if you went through this exercise,
and you kind of map to, you know,
say the cybersecurity framework or A153
or any of the ISO controls
you may have a lot of this information,
that doesn't necessarily
need to be redeveloped, or,
you know reanalyzed,
that decision may have been made already.
It may just be the fact
just kind of have to
input that here until you're just informed
across your privacy program as well.
- Yeah. ID.IM-P6, here is, yeah,
another example, but we're
not doing anything yet,
but data elements within the
data actions are inventoried.
And as much as it hurts, yeah,
sometimes the rate that
we're not doing anything,
soon as it's really impactful,
but here for this practice or
this subcategory specifically,
we know that we probably should be
recording those data elements.
You know, categories of
customer information,
so that we can handle things
like data subject access requests.
We need to know what are
those different categories
of data that we have,
with where's our employee data,
our you know, maybe our contractor data,
and if somebody sent a
request to say, "Hey,
"I want you to delete all my data."
Or "I want a copy of my data."
We need to have a way to be able
to provide those answers
and address those requests.
And so that's where this one is.
I think a lot of people will be finding
that this is a new thing that
will need to be addressed.
'Cause we're seeing
this as a little bit less commonly done
through other requirements previously.
- So for the next one here ID.IM-P7.
This was around the
processing environment,
as identified, and see examples here,
geographic location,
whether it's internal
cloud or third parties.
And for our example here,
we have data processing curves
both on premises and in the cloud.
And then it looks like the gap is,
it's unknown where the data is stored
in the cloud, where it
geographically located.
And also we have a note here
that the inventory process doesn't require
the environment to be recorded.
So I think that last
piece there is really key.
So it's not necessarily the efficiency,
it's just the business process of how
the specific organization sort of
inventories their system or their data.
There hasn't been a
requirement to kind of document
where resided both
physically and logically.
And it could just be,
this is an organization that
primarily had on premises systems.
There was no need,
because it was always in
one specific data center
or on premises locally.
But as businesses and
organizations mature,
you may move to different
environments, include cloud here.
So it's just something again,
where we document what
the current processes are.
And so you can kind of
understand where to build
from there as far as
where the data resides.
No specific regulations do require
that certain types of data reside
in certain localities or
countries, geographic locations.
So depending on the types
of information processed,
it will be
something that the organization
needs to understand.
And again,
focusing on those
critical business systems
should be a first good start to understand
these are the critical systems
that our business relies on.
There'll be a likely to
have the types of data
that may have that type of restriction
around data locality
requirements, things like that.
So again, where we
documented what we know,
and we kind of understanding,
so we can sort of build a roadmap
and go forward.
To really understand,
are there anything that,
any additional practices,
or controls, that we either
need to put in place,
or that we may have in place,
and just move into the
appropriate processes
to apply to a specific practice.
- And please feel free to
add any questions you have
into the chat.
We'll be happy to address those as well.
As we're getting into
the last example that we
have here for ID.IM-P8.
Data processing as mapped,
illustrating the data actions
and associated data elements
for the systems products, services,
and really just looking
at those interactions with
individuals and third parties.
So what we have, is we do have the data,
data maps have been created
for a subset of the critical systems.
So we're pretty consistent
that we've got a good handle
on our critical systems
across all of these
different subcategories.
But knowing that the data maps
currently only outline the systems,
and the expected data flow,
but we're not handling or not defining
those data actions or elements,
knowing that that's a gap
that we'll have to address moving forward.
So we just, yeah, in this example,
we pulled out, focused on one category
from the privacy framework here
that has the eight sub categories.
But really by, you could see,
we quickly walked through all of these
to capture, what do we know?
What do we not know?
Where are the gaps that we think we see?
But by just walking through this,
and defining this in one place,
and maybe pulling from some
of these other standards
and frameworks, and other
exercises we've done,
and having this together,
it now creates that centralized place
to help us streamline that process.
And we can then, if we
capture it in this way,
we can hand it off to
those different groups.
Like Mike had mentioned,
whether it's an IT team, or
maybe the cybersecurity team,
or my leadership, or other stakeholders
that are from the business,
that want to know,
how are we processing data?
What kind of privacy concerns do we have?
And being able to clearly show here,
where we know that we are doing things,
where we know there are gaps.
And then we can use this as a place,
it's kind of that jumping off point
for diving in a little bit deeper,
and figuring out where do we want to,
where do we want to learn more?
Where do we think those largest gaps are,
by looking in that gaps
column on the right.
And seeing where do we have
a paragraph of text instead of a bullet?
Or where have we put, you know,
none in on the notes column,
that we know we're not doing anything.
- And I think, yeah, like Kelly mentioned,
it's really, yeah, we started
with this example here is,
it's just one sub category,
so there are several within
the privacy framework.
But really understanding your inventory,
both the systems and data,
is really a key or core component
to kind of build it out the
rest of the privacy frameworks.
That's what we wanted to
start with this example here.
I think that's the exercise
that most organizations
will go through first
to kind of understand what, you know,
what do we have?
What systems do we have?
What data do we currently process?
And then from there, you can get into
the more mature, I guess,
different sub categories
to kind of understand, the processes
beyond understanding just
your inventory and systems.
And here I want to talk a
little bit about resources from,
specifically for the privacy framework.
So these are cross walks that the
community actually provides.
So you can see the link there
for the NIST Privacy Framework,
where they actually have these.
So these are, like I said,
provided by the privacy community.
And we've listed the ones here
against laws, regulations,
some against the standards.
And then other frameworks you'll see there
like cybersecurity framework
and even the A153 controls.
We did pull some of these into the example
we went through today,
but they're really there
for the community to kind
of use as that baseline
like we did with this walk
through of the scenarios.
So if you've mapped to some of
these other frameworks here,
you're not starting from zero,
you kind of understand
where you are currently.
I mean, you kind of build them in,
and certainly, you kind of
build them in, tailor 'em,
ensure that you're mapping
to the right pieces
within your organization.
But these are really here just as
informative, I guess, references,
and just help to kind of get started.
As you sorta build out your,
and augment your privacy program.
We also have some resources as well.
Our resources from Optic,
specifically the one there
at the privacy framework crosswalk,
which was the template.
It's essentially a blank template
that we have of the scenario
that we just walked through.
Therefore, for you all
to use as appropriate,
if you need to tailor and
bring in additional controls,
certainly use that.
But like I said, we've
used it with organizations.
We find it helpful to kind
of document that process.
They kind of have that crosswalk there,
but they're certainly there
and we have other templates as well
for both privacy and cybersecurity.
And then again, here we
have the NIST resources,
the privacy framework crosswalks
that we just went through.
And then also two use cases
that NIST provides that
provides additional detail.
More in a text format,
sort of what we did, how
organizations sort of
approach privacy from a
baseline to kind of apply
the privacy framework as
they're just starting out.
Okay.
- So, yeah, to wrap up here,
and apply what you've learned today, yeah.
We've got a few things
to do over the next,
over the coming weeks
and months next week,
so you can identify the
relevant regulations,
what actually, what are you worried about?
What applies to you that you need to meet?
And start aligning that
to the privacy framework,
using those crosswalks
that Mike mentioned,
or the template that you could get
from the Optic website.
The first three months,
you know, you, after
you've got that mapped out,
you can start documenting
what you're doing today.
Inventorying your data maps, and systems,
getting that started, identifying
your privacy stakeholders.
And then moving on past
that in the next six months,
documenting your current state
across the whole framework.
Really rolling out across
all the sub categories,
and then begin prioritizing your gaps,
and implementing capabilities
in your privacy program, to
figure out how to improve.
- Yes, so to wrap it up,
it's really take action (laughs) early
what we're saying here.
Like Kelly mentioned, I mean,
there are a lot of things that
can be done in kind of moving forward.
Hopefully this will be
helpful to kind of use
to kind of build out as
you kind of walk through
building out and maturing
your privacy framework.
But yeah, it's really just
to take that first step.
It may seem daunting at
first, but yeah, really,
kind of start with what you know,
and you kind of move
forward as you build out.
And with that, we thank you for
watching our presentation today.
And hopefully, keep the questions coming.
We really enjoy answering your questions
throughout the presentation.
- Thank you very much.