- Welcome everybody,
my name is Jinan Budge,
and I am the principal analyst
leading security and risk
research in Asia Pacific.
And globally our research
on people and culture and security.
I've been a practitioner
as well as an analyst
as well as a consultant
for the last 20 years.
And I feel like I've seen all
sides of our amazing industry.
But today I'm going to be talking to you
about my number one priority
and number one passion insecurity,
and that is people and culture.
And I'm hoping that by
the end of this session,
that you're going to be as
motivated and excited as I am
to always prioritize people and culture.
Which I know may sound like
a strange idea in a field
as technical and analytical as ours.
But I believe it is so important
because it's that cultural journey
that's going to make you shine
and achieve your full potential.
But first of all,
lemme start with my own cultural journey.
And it begins back in 1988,
when my parents took the bold
decision to move themselves
and their three daughters
from Syria to Australia
for the Australian dream.
And for those of you non Australians
in the audience who are
wondering what that is,
it's very similar to the American dream
or the Canadian dream or
any other of those dreams
that newly immigrants have in their minds.
And this is what transpired.
This is me by the way.
I equally accepted the challenge,
I was 13 years old,
I spoke fluent Arabic, some
French, excellent maths,
and three words of English,
which were egg, orange and water.
And I also had piggy tails and a mano brow
and did not understand any of
the 1980s cultural nuances.
I had four years to
make it a to university.
We moved to the Arabic hub of Australia
to safety familiarity and to comfort.
Why am I telling you a story
about myself in the
middle of RSA conference?
I am suggesting to you that my challenges
as a teenager trying to decipher
my new Australian culture
a very similar to yours
actually as a security leader,
as a security professional
when you step into the
organization and you try
and achieve your security aspirations.
I spoke three words of English.
At a very practical level, this meant,
I couldn't understand what my
teachers and peers were saying
and nearly burnt out of science lab.
I was painfully shy,
making it very difficult
for me to make friends.
Life on the playground
certainly wasn't pleasant
in those early days
for all of the reasons described above.
And I had one view of the Australian dream
and that was my parents be good at math,
science and computing,
technical, analytical.
And the temptation to stay
in the multicultural hub
in Sydney with an abundance
of Arabic groceries
and familiar sense was overwhelming.
I know from hundreds of
conversations with many of you
that you security professionals,
security leaders actually
face very similar challenges.
We insecurity do not naturally come out
speaking the language of the
business as our first language.
I know when I interviewed board members,
one board member told me
as directors realized this
is a complicated topic,
we need security leaders
to use terminology
that makes sense to
experts in the business.
We are also shy,
we shy away from politics.
And I'm going to talk about
politics a little bit later
and I'm going to want your
comments and perspectives
in the chat.
This reluctance to engage in politics
has actually put us in a position
where we can not influence
key business decisions.
We are not always well
received or perceived
as a chief operating officer
of a large tech company told me
the perception is still that
security is an impediment
and the bane of convenience.
And something I'm going to
raise with you all today.
Toxicity, security teams
are actually played
with a hidden problem
that we don't yet know how
to talk about toxicity.
And we try to hold on
firmly to what we know,
security technology and tools.
If any or all of these sound familiar,
that's great news.
I'm here to help and to
overcome these challenges.
What I'm suggesting in this presentation
is that your focus needs to shift
to prioritize human
interaction and culture.
And I know one CISO in a
research interview told me
you as a security leader,
you're not going to be
doing security anymore.
So get that off the table.
Your job is now all about
people, business and strategy.
And as though we have the
data to magically prove this,
this is from our survey at forest stuff.
And you can see that
actually security leaders
specifically spend so little time
on the analytical and technical.
The rest of the time is
spent managing stakeholders,
building awareness,
developing business cases
and setting the strategy.
All of these things require a significant
amount of human interaction
and hence this conversation.
And something that a CISO
reminded me of during
a research interview,
security is actually a
very emotional subject.
I know we forget that.
I know we forget this as
security professionals,
this is what we live and breathe.
But people have very specific feelings
about security actually.
So, it's really important to
understand those stakeholders,
understand those feelings
and learn how to manage them.
Because the thing with failings is,
I mean you can ignore them if you like
but actually you won't be successful.
So you need to tackle them head on.
And all of this human interaction
that I'm talking about,
Absolutely we can,
and we do, I've seen it.
I've seen us leaving it to chance,
But whether you are aware of this or not,
actually every single
interaction that we have,
we are creating some sort of a culture.
And what you don't want to do
is you don't want to be
sleepwalking into this culture.
You actually want to be
intentional for how you create it.
So what I'm going to show you today
is the four or four components of culture
that I think you need to prioritize.
And I'm going to start with
feeding supporters and detractors.
Insecurity, as we all know,
we have a lot of
initiatives to push through.
We have got zero trust
inside threat programs,
privacy, phishing simulation exercises,
with all of these initiatives,
you're introducing change.
And guess what?
People generally don't like change.
They're not comfortable with that.
And it's only natural with those scenarios
that you're going to have people
who love what you're doing and
people who hate the change.
So your job is actually
to bring all of these different
people on the journey.
So to do that, build your stakeholder map,
work out who's who,
who needs to be on board with
your strategy or initiatives.
What role are they going to
assume in your transformation?
Take the time to develop
a deep understanding
of each one of those players perspectives.
I've got several personas
he for you to consider.
They're going to be different
for every initiative,
every organization but typically
in a large cybersecurity program,
your CEO is going to be the
ultimate decision point.
You're going to have visionary,
visionaries in the organization.
You will need to align to their vision.
Otherwise, you're not going to succeed.
You're going to have champions,
you're going to have budget holders
and you'll have to have
different conversations
with all of these people.
One thing that I've learned in my career
is to never ever surprise
those stakeholders
with a strategy.
Successful professionals,
successful leaders plant the seed
for the need of change and its benefit.
And really a cultural change happens
one conversation at a time.
And you're having these
conversations actually
because you want to understand the remit
of the stakeholders.
What is their level of
awareness of security?
What's their level of
support for security?
And all of this involve a
lot of talking on your part
but actually also it needs to
involve a lot of listening.
Because once you've
listened and understood
how people are likely to
react to your strategy,
then and only then can you steer them
towards the correct outcome.
And I know when I've presented
some of this in the past,
people like half of this is political.
Yes, you're right.
This is politic.
And this is where I'd love
you to jump into the chat
and give me some feedback.
Because when I say politics,
I want to know what do you think of.
Do you think of politics as a dirty word?
Does it make you squirm?
Does it make you block your ears?
Or do you welcome and tackle it?
I know that when I was doing interviews
for this particular piece of
research on change management,
I interviewed a whole bunch of leaders
from more long standing professions,
such as CRO, CIO, CEOs.
And they all told me about
that moment in their career
when they changed their
mind about politics.
When they went from thinking
of politics as this dirty word
to something that they embraced.
And they will often tell me
that this coincided with the moment
when they made the internal
decision to become a leader.
People play politics every
time they send an email
or chat at the water cooler.
So, my suggestion on that
one is get with a program.
You can absolutely be
political with ethics,
transparency and integrity.
Now I'm gonna give you a couple of tools
for your toolkit.
Once you've done all your listening,
you've adjusted your course,
you're in a good place.
So you need to work
out your next maneuver.
You need to actually persuade.
And the theme with persuasion is,
again, don't mistake it
for a situation of begging
on your knees, type of influence.
Persuasion is actually a
process of professional
political maneuvering and its very finest.
It is ethical, it is acceptable.
There's some tools for you for
example, collective momentum,
you are doing a whole bunch of socializing
and building the momentum
so that when you finally present your idea
or you finally present your
strategy or your initiative,
you can list all those engaged
sponsors that you have spoken to.
Authority, one to be used
carefully but super-important.
Influence comes from the top down.
If your CEO believes that
something is important,
most of the other staff, most
likely to fall into line.
You've got things such as
of course relationships,
building positive
relationships ahead of time,
highlighting commonalities
that you have with people.
Then, you can use this relationship
to influence the program.
And vice vasa you can with
things like mutual exchange
you can provide some service,
resource, assistance,
in the hope that at
some point in the future
you will receive some of them back.
Now, everything that I
have just talked about
is super important.
You are creating change,
you're creating culture
that isn't your vision.
But take care because sometimes
you can get so caught up
in managing upwards
and engaging with stakeholders
whilst internally,
a toxic security team culture festers,
and you end up with infighting,
unhappiness and aggression
between the security team members
and inevitably what I've
seen over and over again,
a brilliant jerk comes out of the woodwork
and causes dissent.
Welcome to security's dirty
secret workplace toxicity.
This is a hidden and
often undiscussed problem
for us within cybersecurity.
Although I have to tell you,
I have been talking about it extensively
in the last 12 months.
Because nothing prepared
me for what happened
when I asked the question on
LinkedIn, very innocently,
what do you think causes
toxicity with insecurity?
I received it analyzed 200
contributions from the community.
And builds a research and
a word all around that,
which will hopefully help you.
The number one cause of toxicity
is actually lack of
organizational support.
As somebody said,
it's really hard for the
security team to be happy
if security is viewed
as a negative or tax,
this culture for security team members
will always be difficult.
Eager was something that
was repeated multiple times.
And something else, the hero
complex or the brilliant jerk.
The Messiahs, the rock stars,
the broilers, the invisible.
This came to me as so many
different names and words.
Some of which I'd never heard of before.
But what it describes is those people
in security teams who are not team players
and we all know at least one
and they feel that they and only they
can solve the problem
and they beat their own
chest about it.
Now, in doing all of this research
and talking publicly about it for a while,
one of the questions that
kept on coming back to me was,
what happens if the security leader
is actually the one
who's the brilliant jerk?
What happens if it is the size though?
And we had to take that very seriously.
And some if I ever get
a chance to go deeper
in some of these calls is actually eight
out of the top 10 causes,
relate to a lack of
leadership at some level.
Based on that and a
number of other factors,
we made the prediction.
We make it for us to five
cybersecurity predictions every year.
And one of those is that a
CISO from a global 500 firm
is going to be fired for instilling
a toxic security culture.
And why do we think
that this could happen?
There's actually a few factors.
Number one is social media.
I know I've been insecurity as
I mentioned for 20 plus years
and sharing lists of serial toxic Pes,
used to be the domain of private networks.
My friends and I are like,
should we hire this person,
she like accepted job with this person.
And we'd all exchange this ideas.
But what's happening now with
the prevails of social media.
Employees understand that
they can take to social media
if their concerns are discarded.
So that was number one reason
why we made the prediction.
The second reason is,
we are seeing a huge move
towards values paced decisions
for consumers, shareholders and employees.
A couple of examples there for you.
78% of millennials are strongly
attracted to innovative
and purpose driven companies.
In 2019, we saw employees at Amazon,
Facebook, Google, Microsoft Twitter,
go on strike to protest
their employers inaction
on climate change.
Again, values-based employees specifically
are collectively bargaining
on ethics and morals.
In Australia a couple of examples,
AMP shareholders pressured the firing
of a trio of executives
for harassment claims.
This is, again, this is not something
that happened only by the employees,
but the shareholders are driving this.
The Ellen DeGeneres show,
definitely not something
you're expecting to hear about
in a security presentation,
but that show snag the
spotlight for bullying issues
with three producers being
ousted as a result of bullying.
Many of us it seems are
voting with our feet
as either consumers,
employees or shareholders.
So some of those behaviors
that have been tolerated in the past
and not going to any more.
And it's really interesting for me
when I dig into and try and understand
what are organizations doing about it,
yeah, not much it seems.
We actually found this data
that showed that 53% of employees
say their firm does not
address toxicity issues.
So whilst people are telling us,
this is a really big deal,
no one is doing much about it.
48% say that their firms
don't allocate funding
to promote a healthy workspace.
And one of the things I wanted
to explore in my research is,
so are we speaking out about it,
is the prediction likely to come true?
Is there enough of a speak up culture?
And again, I asked the
question of my LinkedIn network
and the responses were overwhelming.
Hundreds of comments with people having
very strong views about,
yes, you absolutely must
speak out about this.
And no, it's a really terrible idea.
So it's the percentage is effectively
from the data we analyzed 35% to 65%.
On the yes side,
people have moistly noted
that it's really important
so that we can change the culture,
so that we can make this
better for future generations.
The ones who said no,
have said the repercussions
is not worth it.
There are mental health challenges,
career implications, personal impacts,
so it's a no.
So what do we do about this?
I think from your perspective
if you are not a leader,
then it's really important
for you to decide
whether or not you want to speak out.
If you decide to speak
out, how do you speak out?
That's actually going to
be part of my research
for this coming year.
And I can't wait to share it
with people moving forward.
I think it's really
important for all of us
and for leaders especially to acknowledge
and deal with toxicity.
That means, correcting culture problems
before they met us to size,
I find that with toxicity,
if you bury your head in
the sand and let it fester,
it just becomes quite the situation.
So it's really important
to call it actually
putting labels and things,
calling things out is really important.
Understanding all perspectives.
Is that person's behavior toxic
because they are exhibiting
symptoms of the brilliant jerk
or have they actually had
a really tough time at home
and they potentially need some counseling
and some help.
Fix the hero complex.
And you do that by coaching empathy,
encouraging and modeling
positive behavior.
And what I've learned through my research
and my own personal experience,
is sometimes as a leader in particular,
you've got to make the tough calls,
you do have to let people go
if you cannot find a space
where they stop being toxic.
And going back to the theme
of international women's day
this year which I absolutely love,
choose to challenge,
we all whether we are
leaders or not leaders,
we all have the responsibility,
we all have opportunity to challenge.
And again, I think in this day and age,
it is absolutely the right thing to do.
I'm now going to change tact
and go outside of security teams again
and engaging with organizations.
In 2018, only 19% of sizes
said the lack of visibility
and influence within the organization
is one of their top challenges.
This is done, I'm mentioning
this figure, sorry, 2019,
because back in 2010, that
figure used to be 51%.
51% of us used to struggle
with visibility and influence of security.
We've come a really long way.
But while this apparent increase
in visibility of security
and influence is a great sign,
I'm not convinced that
we've actually increased
people's understanding
of what security is.
And I think you still have
a huge task ahead of you
particularly in managing the human risk.
Now, sadly traditional approaches
to managing the human breasts
have been limited to perfunctory
one-off security awareness
and training session.
And quite often,
some of those security
awareness and training
completely disengaged the
employees from the topic actually,
because they're so long,
they're so disengaging.
And it ends up resulting
in little long-term behavioral change.
So I want to share with
you a couple of pieces
from our research on
managing the human brisk.
And suggesting that to
manage the human risk
actually you need to build a
human centric security program.
You will have the slides,
so you can look at this in
a little bit more detailed,
but effectively you have
got four simple steps,
simple but not really so simple
because most people don't do it.
Step number one is identifying
your key stakeholders.
Step number two, determining
what are some of the behaviors
that you'd like to change.
Step number three, it then becomes
about creating the security awareness
and training initiative
or initiatives and building your plan.
Step number four,
measuring and continuously
improving the plan.
So I wanna go to the stakeholders a bit.
The trick with the stakeholders
is getting in a lot of
depth and a lot of detail
about understanding who
your stakeholders are.
Because what you want to do,
is you want to focus your
culture efforts up, down,
across and even outside
of the organization.
So if you imagine this being a triangle
and you're starting at the top,
you've got your executives,
you've got your boards,
you've got your group
management committees.
So what do you need from them?
Yes, you need them to change
some security behaviors.
But I think moisty potently
what you need from them
actually is advocacy
because we that the executive support,
security initiatives are going to fail.
Security budgets will get cut
and therefore critical risks
are going to be elevated.
Those executives more than ever
need education and need engagement.
Number two, moving down the triangle.
Business and technology leaders,
again, some behaviors to change.
But also you need their buy-in,
you need their support,
and you need them to be
engaged at project levels.
For that to occur, security
has to act as a team player,
as a facilitator and an advisor,
and to work with the business
to deliver those projects that they need
without compromising security.
And really that can only happen
through that process of
buying and listening.
And then of course,
you've got the end users.
And that is where you need
to raise that awareness
and change their behaviors.
We know that organizations are as strong
as their weakest link and those end users
need to be an essential
part of your strategy.
They are your human firewall.
The thing with the end-users is that,
the messages to them,
we've got to change the way
that we're doing it guys,
we need to be a lot more relevant,
engaging and consistent.
And one more trend that
I'd like to share with you
up down across the organization,
yes, but we also need to step outside
and we need to build trust
with external stakeholders
security has to engage
their customer community and
exceed their expectations.
I know in many parts of the
world and some industries
such as financial services in particular,
they are using their security and privacy
and trust programs actually
as a competitive advantage.
So it's really important to engage
with those customers also
externally and regulators
and all sorts of external stakeholders.
Now, I've got a very long story short,
I'm really conscious of this.
But I wanted to share
something else with you.
Because this is usually,
this is a step that people start with.
People start with a step off
less push out security
awareness and training program.
But you really needed
to have done that
stakeholder analysis first,
understand the behavior,
understand what you need from them.
But even when you get to
the security awareness
and training initiatives,
what you could either choose to do
a tick in the box exercise
and push something out
or you can do something
really transformational,
something that's going to win
people's hearts and minds.
And to do that, our
research showed there's 10,
what I'm going to call
for you design principles
that you need to consider
that are going to take your
security awareness training
from that very boring perfunctory
to something that wins
people's hearts and minds.
So these such as having the
cars to use humor and fun
on a very serious topic,
don't be scared of that.
Using experiential
learning and gamification,
I've got a couple of examples
of that for you coming up.
Using micro and nano learning,
nobody has the attention span right now
to spend more than
a couple of minutes consuming information,
repeating the information frequently
to make sure that people understand it.
So, just be aware that
there's some design principles
that you need to incorporate.
And here's some examples actually,
board members executives
using them as an example.
One of the questions that
I get asked by inquiry,
one of my most frequently
asked questions is,
what are the best board
presentations to give,
or what are some of the best metrics
we need to give our boards?
And whilst these are
super important topics,
I just want to note metrics
and presentations and not enough,
we can and should go above and beyond
and engage those executives.
So a couple of examples there for you.
I've seen some of my
clients use gamification
to simulate a company breach.
The executives end up playing
the role of the attacker
or the executives,
and they have to make
on the spot decisions
in every stage of that tech.
So cool, so much energy.
It just gives them a completely
different perspective of security.
Another client of mine placed
their senior executive group
in the spotlight and
they conducted research
into their personal cyber digital profile.
What that ended up doing
is it showed those executives,
their personal, how the risks
of their personal behavior,
and how information
found about them online
can be used against them.
Some other examples back in the days
when I used to be able to travel,
I was traveling in India,
and I stumbled across
this beautiful Rangoli,
and Rangoli, I'm sorry.
And for those of you
who like me did not know
what Rangoli is,
it's this beautiful art using rice.
And it was to celebrate
computer security day
outside of the State Bank of India.
What a beautiful way to attract customers
and employees to that conversation.
Back when I used to leave in the UK
a very long time ago,
one of my clients were having issues
with identity and access
management behaviors.
So instead of lecturing
their employees about it,
they invited a famous comedian
to talk about identity theft
in a comedian kind of a way.
Again, building the hearts
and minds engagements.
And I know I've shared a lot with you,
there's obviously a lot more
depth we could have gone into
and please just don't
let this be overwhelming.
This is all a journey,
it's not a miracle,
you don't have to do it by yourself,
you can share the load.
And one of the ways by which
I've seen my clients share the load
is creating security champions networks
to help create that engagement.
So I've got a couple of steps for you here
on the slides that you can take away
for how specifically to build
that network of influences.
I'm getting towards the end now.
And I want to talk about possibly
the most important part of
this presentation for me.
All of the above,
everything that we've just talked
and spoken about need skills.
They are skills that we were
not necessarily born web
and nor should we have.
We've all had different trainings,
different backgrounds,
different experiences.
That's what makes our industry
so special and so unique.
But there are skills
that we need to develop.
And at some point,
all of us in our careers
need to make a decision
to build on those skills.
So I'm gonna give you a
few leadership skills,
people skills, so important,
particularly if you're a leader obviously,
but even if you're not,
it's really important that
you develop unfamiliar skills
and you can do so by
engaging with members,
executive coaches, sponsors,
acquire communications and
public speaking skills.
I've had too, a lot of people have too,
you don't want your
first board presentation
to be your first ever
public speaking engagement.
So start building on that.
And if you are a leader specifically,
it is unlikely that you're
going to develop and perfect
all of the skills that you need
fill this leadership positions.
So, recruit those skills
and those resources that you don't have.
And it's really important
for me almost at every talk track
and presentation that I do,
that I raise this issue of mental health,
particularly as we are still
in the middle of this global pandemic,
you need to have the mental
space and the clarity.
Burnout is life in our security industry.
And managing this burnout
needs to be a priority.
A couple of tips for you,
make sure at all times that you
put on your own oxygen mask,
lead with purpose.
When things get really overwhelming,
go back to the purpose
of why you're doing what you're doing.
I find that industry in particular
is extremely purpose driven.
We do this for the good of society.
Communicate with each
other, with your boss,
with your teams, at the
appropriate frequency
with empathy and clarity
and be vulnerable.
And I'm not talking about walking
around the office so
virtual meetings crying.
No, I'm talking about being
able to share parts of yourself
to make sure that others
understand that you're human,
that you're going through challenges,
which will in turn help them to open up.
And as the old adage says,
people don't care how much you know
until they know how much you care.
You empathy on funding
is something that's coming
up in so many leadership
and organizational
conversations at the moment.
Now I want to close with this.
I talked about my own cultural Jen,
and I want to introduce
you to the new generation.
This is my daughter.
Her name is Mia, and
she's now 12 years old,
her challenges and mine
as a young immigrant,
they're not even comparable.
Mia as born and raised in Australia.
She never owned a mano brow.
And as you can see from this picture,
she's always on trend.
She's a very easy person
to receive and to be liked.
One of the things that I admire about Mia
is that she has been raised
with the importance of
the skills of empathy,
influence and politics.
So for example, when Mia wants an iPhone
or an app to make receiving
her pocket money easier,
she goes through a process.
She goes through a political process
and that political process
happens to be exactly
the same takeaways that I
want you to take with you.
She will start by planting a seed
well ahead of once she wants that iPhone.
She will document her
requirements quite often,
she's written me business cases,
I've seen more business
cases come out of that child
than I have from some of my team members.
She will explain in her business case,
not how the iPhone is going to help her,
but how it's going to be easy,
you're for me to track and
monitor what she's doing
for her safety.
And in parallel to all of these,
she's going to enlist
my sister, my father,
she'll message my best friends,
she'll message my mother,
she builds a coalition.
She understands the concept
of collective momentum.
She has a growth mindset,
always willing to listen and change course
based on the feedback.
Feel us, full of empathy,
vulnerability, and possibilities.
I wish for all of us to be
like that next generation.
Thank you very much for your time,
I'm really looking
forward to engaging more
with you on the chat.
If you've got any questions,
also welcome, hit me up
on LinkedIn, on Twitter,
and thank you very much.
(silence)