- Hi, my name is Kim Peretti.
I'm a partner with the law firm
of Alston and Bird and
co-chair of our privacy cyber
and data strategy practice.
We're here today to
discuss the panel entitled
"Defend forward, moving toward coordinated
"Active Cyber response" with
three esteemed panelists.
Randy Sabett, Special Counsel
with the law firm of Cooley,
as well as his associate Andrew Epstein.
And we also have Shane McGee,
General Counsel and Chief Privacy Officer
of the company Cofense.
So thank you for joining today.
I'm gonna spend a couple
minutes introducing the topic
and then we're going to
do a round robin panel
discussing the topic in more
detail with our panelists.
So the Department of Defense
described defend forward
in it's 2018 cyber strategy, stating that,
"We will conduct cyberspace operations
"to collect intelligence
"and prepare military cyber
capabilities to be used
"in the event of crisis or conflict.
"We will defend forward to disrupt
"or halt malicious cyber
activity at its source
"including activity that
falls below the level
"of armed conflict."
In light of recent cyber events,
including supply chain
attacks such as SolarWinds
and Microsoft and Codecov,
along with the ransomware
attack on colonial pipeline,
increased intention is being given
to what the private sector
can do and cannot do,
and how to improve information sharing
between the government
and the private sector.
To help provide some guidance,
here is the Cyber Solarium
definition of defend forward.
Proactive, observing,
pursuing, encountering
of adversary operations
and imposing of costs
in day to day competition to disrupt
and defeat ongoing malicious
adversary cyber campaigns.
Deter future campaigns
and reinforce favorable
international norms
of behavior using all
instruments of national power.
Now, there are some people
who mistakenly viewed
defend forward as purely
authentic activity
but that isn't what it actually means.
While active defense,
Active Cyber response,
and hack back can be a
component of defend forward
they are not necessarily part of it.
So, defend forward
involves cyber activities
that couple of things are intended
to affect resources
outside of us networks,
don't rise to the level of armed conflict,
comprise appropriate actions
that are proportional
to the threat and are
intended to disrupt deter
and defeat the threat.
So with that as a brief
introduction, Randy,
could you please introduce
yourself and talk to us
in a little more detail
about defense forward?
- Thank you, Kimberly.
And thanks everyone for
joining our session.
As Kimberly mentioned, Randy Sabett,
I'm a Special Counsel at
Cooley based in Washington, DC.
I'm part of our cyber
data privacy practice
and spend my time sort of
split between a combination
of different things, both
on the proactive side,
counseling clients on
cyber and privacy issues,
transactional issues around M
and A, IPOs, things like that.
And then the more reactive side
of things with cyber attacks
and breaches and those sorts of things.
In a previous life, I was a
Crypto engineer for the DOD,
and it's really interesting
today to be talking
about these topics and sort
of where they originated,
compared to when I was doing this stuff
many many years ago as an engineer.
So I guess to start out when
we talk about defend forward
in the context of not just the government,
which obviously has different authorities
and can do different things
related to these concepts.
What we wanna sort of focus on today
is not just the government piece
but also the private sector piece
and sort of the intersection of the two.
We'll talk about information
sharing a little while
a couple of other things,
but I think to start out
when you talk about defend
forward in the context
of the private sector, to me, it really,
it can be broken up
broadly into two things.
First of all, proactively
imposing costs on the adversary.
And as a result of that,
degrading their cyber operations
or their ability to
take action against you,
your network, the networks of others.
And it's also effective
public-private cooperation
that allows gathering of
information, sharing of information
about threats and effectively cooperating
in a collective defense type of posture.
It's comprised of a number of
other discreet considerations
that we'll be talking
about in a few minutes,
but I think at the end of the day
those two things are the
things to keep in mind.
Proactively imposing costs,
and the public-private cooperation.
On the issue of imposing costs,
I like to go back to believe
it or not a quote from 1964,
from a RAND paper, by a
person named Paul Baran,
who was one of the true
inventors of the internet,
some of the very early pieces of it
and in this report, he
said, the following, 1964,
"We should fully anticipate the existence
"of spies within our
extensively secure communication
"secrecy protection structure.
"Hence our primary interest
should be in raising
"the price of the aspired information
"to a level which becomes excessive."
So back in 64, there's the
concept of, first of all
assume the attackers
are inside your network,
and second of all, your
job is to impose costs
on the attacker so that
they actually decide not
to attack you and go somewhere else.
Now, back in the, I'll
do the finger quote,
back in the old days,
I used to use the bear
analogy here, which was,
I don't need it to be faster than the bear
just faster than my buddy
who's also being chased by the bear.
In the context of defend forward
and a public-private
cooperative environment,
that's not quite the
analogy you wanna use.
It's really more of a me
and my buddy and a bunch
of our friends and different
folks in the ecosystem,
all cooperating and sharing information
on what that bear is doing
so that the bear doesn't attack us.
I think that's the analogy to take away,
but I wanted to emphasize the fact that
this is not something new
and neither for that matter is the notion
of active defense and
Active Cyber response
which we'll talk about
in a couple of minutes.
So these are not new concepts,
What they really are are new formulations
and new approaches to these concepts.
And to sort of put that in context,
if you think about the
notion of cooperation
and public-private partnerships,
it's helpful to look at
what types of policies
and strategies the government has proposed
over the years that talk about this.
So going all the way back to 2003,
the national strategy
to secure cyberspace.
The strategy talked about,
and it was an early attempt
at articulating a national cyber strategy,
and it was clear that information sharing
was a core component of that.
Then in 2008, we had the
commission on cyber security
for the 44th presidency.
I was a part of that commission
and the commission was a
little bit more critical
at that time of
public-private partnerships
because as the report said,
the so-called public-private
partnership is marked
by serious shortcomings.
And the real sort of problem,
was the notion that you
wind up in a status quo,
if it's not done right.
If you don't have workable
and effective public-private partnerships,
it results in sort of a status quo
where nobody's really doing anything
and neither the government
nor the private sector
needs are being met.
That was 2008 followed in 2009
by the cyberspace policy review,
Melissa Hathaway's review.
And the re review team found
that addressing network
security issues requires a
public-private partnership
as well as international
cooperation and norms.
In 2015, we had executive order 13691,
that focused on information sharing,
cyber security information sharing,
and it was focused on the private sector
and the use of ISAOs
which are Information Sharing
and Analysis Organizations,
and for those of you who know ISACs,
they're very similar to an ISAC,
which is an Information
Sharing and Analysis Center,
but whereas the ISACs are focused
on critical infrastructure,
the ISAOs are more flexible
and can be broader than just
the critical infrastructure.
So we've had ISAOs popup across a number
of different industries,
and a couple of different
organizational manners
that really become those effective things
that allow information
sharing, effective mechanisms.
I worked on one with a group
that was a real grassroots effort.
They literally met at Black
Hat in a very informal manner,
a bunch of CSOs, and two years later,
we had a formal meeting,
we had membership,
we had bylaws, and they have
in place this organization
that does a great job of
sharing threat information.
Even though the members are competitors,
they know that defense of the whole,
is made better by all of them cooperating.
And so it's that kind of the ISAO concept
that I think we wanna
talk about in the context
of defend forward.
The commission in 2016 said
that joint collaboration
between the public and
private sectors is necessary
before, during and after a cyber event.
So we start to see the focus,
not just on the reactive
but also on the proactive and the during,
while there's an attack going on.
Kimberly mentioned the DOD
cyber strategy from 2018
and the notion of collecting intelligence
and the defend forward concept.
It went on to say that the
government is gonna strengthen
the security and resilience
of networks and systems
that contribute to current and
future military advantages.
And here's the important part.
"We will collaborate
with our inter agency,
"industry and international partners
"to advance our mutual interests."
So you've got this concept,
flowing through all of
these different policies
and getting refined and
getting more focused.
The cyber commission that also
was mentioned by Kimberly,
they looked at and focused on
the need for imposing costs
to change the adversary behavior,
and the fact that defend
forward is proactive.
And it really was, it looked at the fact
that the US has prevented cyber attacks,
I'm sorry, has not created
credible insufficient costs
against malicious adversary
behavior in the context
of trying to prevent cyber attacks
of significant consequences.
As a result, defend forward
posits that the US has to shift
from responding, being in
a responsive reactive mode,
to being in a proactive mode.
And then even as recent
as the executive order
on improving the nation's
cyber security from 2021,
the executive order said the
private sector must adapt
to the continuously changing
threat environment and partner.
Now we're talking about partnering
with the federal government
to foster a more secure cyberspace.
So building on what Kimberly
said at the beginning,
defend forward is not, a single
point or a narrow concept,
rather it's a combination
of different aspects
of overall cyber policy
and it includes the notion
of Active Cyber response
and active defense
which we'll talk about
in a couple of minutes.
And also the fact that the dialogue needs
to address liability protections
beyond what we have in SISA
and Shane we'll be talking
about that in a little bit,
and ultimately defend forward
involves a balanced
approach that has a number
of interacting dynamics
which Andrew will discuss toward the end.
So that's a little bit
more on defend forward.
- And Randy, can I just ask another,
a little bit more detail on this concept
of imposing cost, is that financial costs
that the government imposes by proactively
taking certain measures?
Is it the, imposing costs
making it harder for them
to hack into systems 'cause
we're banding together,
as you mentioned the bear analogy
and discussing together
how challenging it is,
but what exactly does
it imposing costs mean?
- I would respond by saying
all of the above and then some,
in the sense that it's not financial
from the private sector's perspective,
at least financial in terms of money,
it's financial in terms
of creating situations
where the attacker has to spend more,
where more might be
money, they might need to,
have better computers, they
might need more computers.
It might be spending time.
So it takes greater time
to get into your network
'cause you have these defenses in place,
or you've taken mechanisms, I'm sorry,
you've utilized mechanisms
or have taken steps
that are an impediment to the attacker
getting into the network.
And even going so far as to
talk about active defense
and Active Cyber response.
Those are all things that
are going to impose costs
on the attacker that aren't just sort
of financial in nature.
- That's very helpful.
I was always sort of,
wondered how it breaks down
in that way.
So thank you for that.
So before we get into
some of the hack-back
and active defense in public-private
sector sharing, right,
we've talked about this for
years and years and years
what is holding the private sector back?
And I would also be interested
in maybe we'll cover it later
about the new executive
order which much of that is,
relates to sharing more threat
Intel with the government,
the IT service providers, as
well as mandated reporting.
So, what is holding the
private sector back?
And is that resulting in the
government taking the position?
Well, maybe we need to, require
more information sharing.
- Well, I guess let's start out with the,
maybe perception is the best word,
because I do think having
worked with a number of clients,
having worked with law enforcement,
both federal and non-federal,
I think the sort of the
historical response is that,
I'm a company, I've had something happen,
or maybe I might not have
had something happen,
but I'm worried, and so
I'll go to the government
and I spill my guts.
Here's my OCs, here's
the concern that I have.
Here's what I think is
happening in my network,
et cetera, et cetera, and
again, I think it's more
of a perception than a reality,
at least in my experience.
But I do think there is
some nugget of truth in it.
Companies don't feel they get
as much actionable information
in a timely fashion from the government.
Now, I think, and this could go off
in a whole separate direction
but we won't go there.
I think there are a number of
dynamics that play into that,
does the government have an
active investigation going on?
Could there be, could that
investigation be compromised
if they shared certain
information that might be helpful
to the company?
So there's a whole bunch of
things that come into play.
But I think at the end of the day,
the perception is not
necessarily the full reality.
I've had a number of
clients who have worked
with law enforcement.
I had two very distinct
situations with clients
where their network would have been owned
much much worse than it ended up being,
were it not for the cooperation
and in one case, an
agent from, I'll just say
a federal agency who
spent an entire weekend
on his own time, tearing
apart a hard drive,
and finding out sort of
what was gonna happen
to that client next and
as a result, it didn't.
So it's a one time, one specific example,
but I think there are others
where the government
does provide information.
It is actionable, hopefully it's timely.
And I think really what
we need to work toward
is an ability for that dialogue to happen.
And as I always tell my clients,
you should have somebody from the FBI
or some other federal agency on speed dial
and a first name basis
so you can just call them
and bounce things off of them
because they will do that for you.
- I think beyond reporting
to law enforcement
is just DHS and SISAs,
attempts to get more and
more information over time.
And we have SISA, we have
a process for doing that,
we got rid of, don't have privilege issues
with respect to it and otherwise,
and now perhaps the new executive order
with requiring notifications
to SISA may elevate their role
and be another way that they are able
to get additional information
that they're looking for.
So it'll be interesting
to see how that plays out.
- Agreed
- But let's talk about the
favorite topic of everyone,
hacking back, active defense,
Active Cyber response.
Where does this fit in
the whole discussion?
- Well, let me first start
out and give a tip of the hat
to Anand Shah, one of our
co-authors of our paper,
who couldn't be here today,
he's done a bunch of work as we all have,
done a bunch of work in this area
and talked about this topic
for quite a long time.
And I think if you look at, I said kind
of in my earlier remarks,
we've talked about the concept
of defend forward and some
of the imposing of costs
and things like that.
Active defense, at least for 20 years,
at least in my experience
in an unclassified setting
we've been talking about the topic,
the conversations don't change too much.
I think there's been at
least some subtle changes
over the past few years.
A group of us have been
writing and talking about
various concepts within this
and some of the boundaries of it,
but it fits in, in a way of,
as we talked about earlier
with your earlier question,
with respect to imposing
costs and moving earlier
in the attack process to
confront the attacker.
So you mentioned
Kimberly, the notion that,
this is potentially outside
of your own network,
that some of these
activities are occurring.
And so that's imposing
costs because the attacker
hasn't even gotten to your network yet.
And it's a set of techniques
at the end of the day.
If you think about it as a continuum,
I used to talk about port scanning,
and we had this whole diagram
of a number of different things.
And even port scanning is controversial
but all the way up to
destroying the attackers
facilities physically.
Well certainly the private sector
is not gonna be doing that.
But there are several things
that people have proposed
that that could be used to actually
from a defend forward standpoint,
put in place those additional
costs on the attacker.
- And are you talking mostly
about the government doing this
or in this context right
now, the private sector?
- Well, that's, again, going back
to the historical
discussions, I think people,
used to think of active defense
as the wild wild west,
then I'm just gonna,
find the best attack tools that I can,
or maybe come up with them myself
and go after the cyber attackers.
I think the more realistic
view that's being
taken these days is that
it is a cooperative effort
between government and private sector.
Private sector is not doing things
outside of their swim lane.
Collectively we are saying that if,
an action that is illegal
under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act
is not something that we would advocate.
And we would in fact discourage,
that's again going back
to the authorities,
the government has certain authorities
that the public I'm sorry,
the private sector does not.
And so from, however, from a
defend forward perspective,
there can be things one,
I think one very well
used example is the notion
of a honeypot.
I've developed a honeypot.
I've collected some
interesting information.
Should I take action on it?
Probably not.
If it's, truly is for
example a nation state kind
of attack or situation.
But turning that over to the government
having that dialogue with
the government that we talked
about a minute ago, I
think would be a good way
of taking the information
that I've developed,
and providing it to someone
who could then take it further
in this defend forward fashion.
So, again I think it's that acquisition
of actionable intelligence.
I can do things that, collect information.
I can work with the government
in a public-private partnership
or dialogue kind of way,
and then have those real time responses
that perhaps do come from me,
If it's nothing else, maybe
it's some diversionary response
or response from the government
if it's something that is,
if it's something that the
actions that we've discovered
if they weren't action by the government
then the government can go forward.
The example I like to talk about is,
imagine if various companies
who might be affected
by some of these supply
chain attacks very early on,
had the intelligence and
provided it to the government
and the government could triangulate on,
"Hey, there's something about to happen."
And then share that with the community.
That's the kind of thing
we're talking about.
- And again, active defense
and Active Cyber Defense are,
Active Cyber response are
synonymous in this context
with those two factors
you're talking about
or is there a meaningful difference?
- Ask a dozen people you'll
get 25 different answers.
(laughs)
We've never, we the Royal,
we have never come up
with a solid, we, it's
not for lack of trying,
but I would say we've never
come up with a solid definition
or maybe let's put it differently,
a unanimous or nearly
unanimously accepted definition.
I prefer, I'll have my colleagues
weigh in at some point
during their discussion
but I prefer Active Cyber response,
because you're actively
doing something potentially
from a defend forward
perspective, outside your network.
It's a cyber action and it's in response
to something not necessarily reactive,
not necessarily an attack,
but it's a response to
something that you're seeing
or you're concerned about or
something you've detected.
I think active defense is sort of the next
least objectionable, in the
sense that it has the notion
of active and defense of your network.
I think one of the problems with it is,
it was one of the earliest
phrases to be adopted
and so therefore got
viewed in a negative way
or a negative connotation.
And that hacked back, I
just, I absolutely don't like
'cause that's really only
talking about the stuff
that we're saying the
private sector can't do.
If it's gonna be a violation
of the Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act, i.e, hacking,
then it's not something
that we condone or advocate.
But I think the notion of
hack-back people hear that term
and they think of it
covering whole continuum
that I've been talking
about when it's really only,
I view it as only the
things that are true hacking
which we're saying you
shouldn't be doing anyway.
So that helps?
- You might have covered this,
but how does private sector
Active Cyber Defense play
into the Department of Defense's
defend forward strategy?
- Well, I think it's kind of
what I talked about earlier
in terms of being able
to provide information
to the government perhaps
about things outside
of your network, perhaps about,
there was a company for awhile,
I don't think they do this
anymore, but one of the vendors,
one of the first vendors
actually that I saw that talked
about active defense, but
what they were really talking
about was active defense
inside of your own network
which sort of confused
things even further.
But I think it's that combination
of activities that will
allow this overall effort
of defend forward, both the combination
of both private sector and
the government to take action
that will defend our overall
network for the country.
If you think about it
from a, what a lot of,
I shouldn't say a lot.
Some of the policies that we talked about
a little while ago,
talk about a whole of government approach
and a whole of society approach.
And it's really
integrating those offensive
and defensive measures
where appropriate into a,
and now we're getting sort of theoretical,
but if you view it as
taking these measures
that the private sector has,
or can take legally collect
information from it,
share it with the
government who can obviously
observe other things
that the private sector
may not have access to,
and also take action,
it's that whole of government
and whole of society approach,
that will allow you to, or
will allow the government
to leverage information
collected from all those sources
and essentially do the things
we were talking about earlier
progressively disrupt, deny,
degrade, or in the case
of the government potentially
destroy the attacker
or the attacker's cyber
weapons and other resources
within their computers and their networks.
- Randy, one last question in this area
before we move on to our other speakers.
What are the key considerations involved
in actually implementing
Active Cyber response measures?
- Well, I think there's,
there have been a number
of efforts and a lot of
things written in terms
of the considerations that
will allow it to work.
Anand Shah, the gentlemen
I mentioned earlier,
participated in the Talon. One effort,
which produced a guidance
that really went into a lot
of detail about both the public sector
and the authorities that
the public sector has
and also some of the
international law issues
and a bunch of other things.
They're now on their their
third set of activities,
the Talon group.
And so there's a lot of
folks who have put together
a bunch of different work.
But I think if for this
conversation and for purposes
of thinking about what
the private sector can do,
one thing, the first
thing to think about is,
who should be able to use Active
Cyber response techniques.
There was a proposal,
I actually don't remember
who came up with it,
but there was a proposal to essentially,
based on testing and
certification, deputize for lack
of a better word, private
sector organizations
that have the skills to do the things
that would be needed by the government.
I'm not saying that's
a good or a bad thing
but I think it's something
that, it's a creative way
of looking at the issue of
who can use these techniques
and when can they use them
and how can they use them.
I think at the end of the day,
like we talked about earlier,
anyone who is going to
take action like this,
on that spectrum that we talked about,
really needs to think about,
is this something that could
be viewed as a computer fraud
and abuse act violation, or a
violation of some other law?
And if so, move further
down on that continuum.
Is it any personal organization,
or should we have a certification process
or we should, we have some mechanism.
I think all of these are open questions.
In a paper that a separate group
of us wrote a few years ago,
one of the things, in fact,
I think it was in the title,
was the notion of needing a dialogue
on this particular issue
and getting all of these,
getting a collective approach that,
again a majority of
people would agree with.
And so that would be one way
of answering who should be able to use it.
What actions are allowable?
I've already talked about that spectrum,
certainly not all of
them would be available
to the private sector.
Are there temporal limits or other sorts
of guidelines that bound when
the activities can take place?
Is it only after you've collected,
a certain amount of information?
One of the things we talked
about a little while back
in a different paper was attribution.
And, this assumes you've gotten
past the attribution issue
because we don't quite
know who the person is,
or the entity is, how are you gonna even
carry something out?
But at what level of
certainty do you need to know?
So are there those limits that bound
when something can be done?
Who's responsible if
there's collateral damage?
If you attack or if an
attack is carried out
on a resource that looks
like it's an attacker
but it's only because the
attacker has taken it over,
and it actually causes
a problem, then what?
Who's responsible for that?
Is there any kind of liability
which we'll talk about
in a few minutes, are there
any kind of liability limits
or safe harbors in a sense?
And then when you look at
this in the broader sense
of the global norms being pursued
by the US and other like-minded nations,
I talked about the Talon
manual a little while ago,
now in it's third installment,
you've got UN groups
that are working on this
(clears throat)
in the context of information
and telecom environments.
And so, you've got all of that,
but then you look at some
of these espionage campaigns
that you mentioned earlier,
SolarWinds and others
and what does that do to
calibrate what can be done here?
Do we need to allow things
to be more aggressive
because we're sitting here
in total defensive mode?
A lot of people are pointing to that.
So, I think at the end of the day,
if these recent attacks that
we've seen prove anything,
we need agreement from not just an active
cyber response perspective,
but this whole notion of defend forward.
How do we share information
with the government?
How do we do things in a
way that create this better
than the separate entities,
when they're all together
they're a better group.
How do we create that in the context
of cyber and defend forward?
So I think we need to look at
that and as is talked about
in the Cyber Solarium report,
and it's talked about
elsewhere, essentially leaning
into all of the strengths
that we have, political,
economic, social, cultural,
and in that way, these kinds of attacks,
they're gonna, of course they'll occur,
going back to the Paul Baran quote,
the attackers are going to
get it inside our networks.
But if we actually
operationalize of these concepts,
we will be in a better place
and the attacks won't be as catastrophic.
- That's great.
And it's so topical, right?
If you think about the Russian sanctions
by the Biden administration,
key aspect they identified
was the international coordination,
and groups to discuss the
attribution and other things.
So there's so much of what you've touched
upon in the whole of
government approach we've seen
just in the past couple of
months and announcements
in various ways from the
Biden administration.
So very interesting.
Let's shift over to Shane, talk
about liability protections.
And Shane maybe you can start with
a brief introduction of yourself.
And then when we talk
about defend forward,
it would seem that there are
a number of things that could
be done to incentivize the private sector.
Love to hear you talk
about some of those things.
- Sure, okay.
I'm Shane McGee, I'm General Counsel
and Chief Privacy Officer
for a company called Cofense.
I started as an attorney
in the large law firms
ending up at what is now Dentons.
Running the cyber security
and privacy practice there
with my friend and colleague Randy Sabett,
who you just heard from.
Later went in-house to
become general counsel
of Mandiant.
Mandiant was acquired by FireEye,
stayed at FireEye for a little while
and then ended up here at Cofense.
Cofense is and email security company.
We're known mostly for our
phishing defense solutions.
I wasn't an NSA Crypto genius like Randy
but I am a hobbyist technologist
which certainly helps me in my work
on these issues as they get
very complex technologically.
So the question to me is,
what can be done to
incentivize private sector,
to take a defend forward posture?
And you've kinda hinted
at the solution there,
what I think is the solution
which is providing liability protections.
I've been both as a private,
as an attorney in the
law firms and in-house,
I've seen kind of the
fears, the trepidation,
and rightfully so that
companies feel when it comes
to how far forward they're
gonna lean on cyber defense.
We'll get in a little while
I'll talk about the
Computer Fraud Abuse Act
and some other things
that Randy touched on,
but certainly liability
is and removing liability
or getting some shield is the
best thing that you can do
to get the private sector
a little more involved.
But before we talk about
the liability limitations themselves,
because there's liability
limitations throughout the law,
those never come for free.
There's always some price on the companies
that are receiving that protection.
They have to meet some standard,
they have to do something.
They have to keep from doing
something to be eligible.
And I think here given the likelihood
that if this ever comes
about, that there would be
a likelihood that there's
gonna be a similar requirement,
I'll kinda start out talking
about what I think the costs
of limitation of liability should be.
I would start with something
like a requiring the use
of trust mechanisms for
vetting any products, services,
threat intelligence used
in Active Cyber response.
Certainly when you're
talking about something
that's important the
companies should not rely
on any unproven technology or intelligence
and doing so can result
in some dire consequences.
To do that though, these
trust mechanisms require,
going back to some, the things
that Randy was talking about,
a strong public-private partnership,
to vet that intelligence
that you're using,
or the products with
not just other companies
in the private sector but
with your government partners
that have the best access to
information and technology.
The threat information sharing
in that public-private
partnership also needs
to be reliable and timely.
And I think there are historical problems,
again that Randy touched on with
with government information sharing.
I won't get too far into that, but that's,
but yeah, just generally
I think trust mechanisms
and that partnership is
probably the first requirement
a company would need to
meet before it qualifies
for any type of liability limitations.
Another is, comply with some type
of clear rules of the
road for attribution.
And, Randy also mentioned attribution
and the difficulties of it,
it's incredibly difficult both
from a technical perspective
but also from a political perspective.
There are political ramifications
if you have a state
sponsored actor attacking.
So even if you do find out
that it's China or Russia,
saying that in a public forum
has certain repercussions.
So again, you lean on your
public-private partnerships
and try to coordinate
the attribution as well.
That's more on the political,
and the technology side of
attribution, also very difficult.
You can have serious collateral damage
if you attribute an
attack to the wrong party
and collateral damage from
your response to that.
None of this works,
what I'm talking about
works without this real-time
information sharing and that
public-private partnership
that results in that
but you also need more
than just the sharing with the government,
you need some level of coordination.
And when I say coordination
I'm talking about with law enforcement
and sometimes the intelligence community.
There are, if you think about
a situation where you're gonna
have private companies kind of
leaning forward a little bit
in terms of their Active Cyber response,
I think one of the main
goals of coordinating
with the government is
going to be deconfliction.
You wanna avoid impacting
ongoing government operations.
And you also, if there's gonna be a lot
of other private sector entities involved,
you wanna avoid stepping
on other people's toes
if they're involved in
some type of active defense
or Active Cyber response.
There's also just the
coordination in the sense
that there needs to be
some type of standard
or oversight on
proportionality and escalation.
If the government is, or a partnership
between private sector and
the government is there,
then companies can
coordinate their responses
so that they are not, they
don't lack proportionality
and they can all be
somewhat similar in terms
of defining a practice and
in how people are responding.
So, in addition to the
coordination aspects
we also need some type
of ongoing assessment and certification.
I'm gonna talk about a little bit,
some of the current
statutes that I believe
we could build a template
like this on, but the,
whether this is a government
body or an industry group,
it's up for a whole lot of discussion
but the idea that is that
there needs to be some type of,
if not oversight, then larger cooperation.
And the idea, so I started with,
what you kinda need to
do to get to the point
where you deserve any type
of liability limitation.
If you do all these things,
the idea at that point
is that you should receive some type
of liability protection.
And there are, at that
point, you ask yourself
what are you defending against?
Or what are you trying to protect
against in terms of those protections?
There are two different types
of liability that generally
that you would be looking at.
You'd be looking at government action,
and there are civil action,
and criminal action from the government.
So there are two types just in that,
but also third-party lawsuits.
So that's the type of
life liability protection
we're looking for.
Randy mentioned kind of
the big 800 pound gorilla
in the room when it comes to liability,
and that is the Computer
Fraud and Abuse Act.
I'm not gonna get too far into that.
I think everybody really kinda understands
what it is generally but it suffice
to say it's very broadly interpreted.
It covers a large percentage
of conduct that people think
about when we're talking
about Active Cyber Defense
and kind of a defend forward concept.
So if that is the first
and the largest hurdle
you need to get over
before you engage in any
of this type of behavior.
So whatever happens, you have to make sure
that the Computer Fraud
and Abuse Act is amended
or there's some type of exception made
for this type of conduct.
But that doesn't mean that
that's all you need to do.
It doesn't necessarily
protect organizations
from third-party liability and lawsuits.
To protect organizations
from third-party liability,
you need to do something else.
And there, I think you
probably look at something
like the Safety Act.
Safety Act was to support anti-terrorism
by fostering effective technologies act,
that was passed after 911.
It offers a liability protections
and liability management program
for providers of
anti-terrorism technologies.
Now, this is something where
you take your technology,
you vet it with the government, you say,
"Hey, this is what I wanna
qualify under the Safety Act."
And then if you are able
to get through that process
and the government gives
you a stamp of approval,
then you get certain
liability protections.
And that comes in the form
of half on litigation damages
or sometimes just a complete dismissal
of any third party lawsuit
lodged against you.
So you have both going back
to the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act,
you have to do something
about that type of liability,
the governmental liability
and then you might want to
take some type of Safety Act
sort of use that template
to create some sort
of liability protection
against third party lawsuits.
- And Shane, could I just ask
- Yap.
- What is the type of activity
that we're talking about
that we would be providing
liability protection against?
Is it broad ranging Active Cyber response?
Or is it a narrower component
of that type of activity?
- Can I recycle Randy's answer
and just say all of the above?
- It's a, I mean, there, I actually think
that there is a range
of different behaviors
and clearly we're gonna
need to define that
before we start going into
the liability protections
and the exceptions and everything else.
I wanna echo what Randy said in that
I do not believe that the, and
if you wanna characterize it
as active defense or hack- back,
is smart under virtually any circumstances
for a private company.
It is both dangerous in the
sense that usually companies
are fighting out of their league,
I guess is the saying,
they are in serious trouble
if they are trying to
put themselves up against
a hacker that was able to
get in their environment
if that hacker is state-sponsored
or otherwise sophisticated,
because you don't wanna,
you don't wanna be hacked
back for the hack-back.
So that that's one reason not to do it.
The other reason is just the possibility
for collateral damage is huge.
And we've seen, I've seen
several times where clients,
back when I was in the
firms, have not gone after
but done some reconnaissance
to see who was responsible
for their hacks,
it is led back to a particular process
on a particular box
somewhere and then they later
find out that that's
just a shell running out
of a web server, a multi-tenant web server
that's serving hundreds
of thousands of sites.
So if you would have gone after that,
you would have shut down hundreds
or thousands of sites that
were perfectly legitimate.
You could get into infrastructure,
they could shut down utilities,
you could do any number of things
and private companies
are just generally not
sophisticated enough to be
able to go after a hacker
in such a way that they could mitigate
the collateral damage that's
gonna come out of that.
So that's a long way of
answering your question
to say that there is this very broad range
of behavior that we're talking about
but I would say that
hopefully we're talking about
just the type of things,
the more passive Active Cyber Defense,
things like the honeypots,
maybe beacons, things like that,
but not the act of trying to hack-back
and take down your opponent,
not that type of thing.
- Okay, that's helpful.
So turning it over to Andrew,
based on what we've heard so far,
it seems that developing
a balanced approach
to defend forward makes sense.
Can you both introduce yourself
and also elaborate on this
in our remaining time.
- Yeah, thank you Kimberly.
Andrew Epstein, associate at Cooley
and our cyber data privacy practice group.
My process mainly involves
advice and counseling clients
for each response, transactional support,
both mergers and acquisitions IPO level
and then also on a
commercial level as well.
In terms of the balance approach
I think that to Shane's point,
of the things that we're looking for here
is establishing a framework
in which organizations can operate.
And so here we are talking about
clearly following delineated roles,
understanding what are the
limitations on the actions
that you can take while
also trying to assess
how you could best go about
defending your own network
and also, as Randy said, imposing
costs on the perpetrators.
And to do this, one of the
solutions that we had proposed
in our paper is creation of
a public-private partnership
along the lines an ISAC or
ISAO that allows for sharing
of information both between
private organizations,
public-private organizations,
and then the public
organizations themselves.
And this would facilitate
sharing of information
and real time that allows
for organizations to respond
to threats seamlessly while
also not the inhibited
by the perceived delay in any sort
of information sharing regime.
I think that there have been
efforts to do so previously
but I think with the knowledge
that the organizations
are better when they are working together
as opposed to working in silos,
I think that you're going
to see an increased push
toward information sharing
between public and private.
I think that is one of the main messages,
that the Biden administration's
new executive order
is that these organizations
really need to step forward
and in a timely fashion share information
so that our networks
are not caught off guard
or further perpetrated.
- Great, thank you for summarizing
that balanced approach.
And I think you're absolutely
right when you look
at the new executive order
and the emphasis on public-private
sector sharing again,
but also increased reporting
and increased reporting
to multiple agencies that certainly
is indicative of the importance
the government believes
of receiving that information timely.
- Kimberly, let me jump in
- Yeah.
- On that last point that I
think there's a nuance there
and I wanna make sure
everyone understands it.
So for some number of years now,
cyber incident reporting has been an issue
not here in the US, it's
been predominantly in the EU,
and it's the idea that if
you have a cyber incident
and depending on the country
and depending on some definitional issues,
you may or may not have to,
but at the end of the day,
there are certain entities that have
to report cyber incidents, oftentimes,
there are critical infrastructure
or they're telecom based
or they're in some other sector,
but this type of reporting
that we're talking about now,
is not the same as the laws that you have
in the 50 states for data breaches.
So data breaches as
everyone knows are focused
on personal information and
some other, in certain states,
different types of
information about people.
This notion that we're talking about now,
cyber incident reporting,
is focused on exactly that,
reporting of cyber incidents
from a cyber perspective
as opposed to a personal
information perspective
which is a pretty big policy change,
but I do think given all
that we've talked about
and given this notion
of a collective defense,
it's that kind of information
sharing amongst entities
and with the government,
that is going to lead
to some of the effects
that we talked about.
So I just wanted to clarify
so everyone understands
what we're talking
about when we're talking
about cyber incident report,
mandatory cyber incident reporting.
- Yeah, no, it's important.
Of course we have a little bit of that,
right in the insurance industry with
the NAIC model law and DFS,
and pre-licensed entities
the material standard though,
for cyber security incidents.
And we saw that right with the
banking agencies a proposal,
to include a requirement for
reporting cyber incidents,
but you're absolutely right.
Very, very different
than the data breaches
that we mandate reporting here in the US
in contrast to other countries
that do have the NIS
directive and others so,
very important distinction.
- I think that this is
an area that is right
for additional support, both
at an organizational level
and at an individual entity level.
I think that as private organizations
are becoming increasing
targets of cyber events,
there is going to be a
greater concern among them
and that they're all no
way that that could kind
of leverage their ability to respond
is through collective action.
And so I think you're going
to see a greater sharing
of information hopefully.
- Be optimist, right, so.
And Shane, you wanna give
us your thoughts next.
- We being the cyber security community,
the legal community, the
policy community have for,
it seems like forever,
been trying to convince the government
and different components of the government
to share information with,
to bolster the partnerships
with private industry
because this can't be done
without that happening.
With virtually every executive order
I see every cyber security
bill I see introduced
that is acknowledged.
It's acknowledged also executive branch,
legislative branch, we've acknowledged it
that we need to have this partnership.
That there needs to be more cooperation
and that the country will be better off
if we do that and it
seems to never happen.
It's been a very frustrating
process for those
of us that have been
very involved with it.
I think it, I'm glad that
all sides definitely seem
to see the benefits of
it of that cooperation,
but I am not terribly optimistic
that it's gonna happen in the short term.
- There is a question of
whether we have metrics
to help evaluate whether
we are making progress
towards better coordination,
coordinating activities between the public
and private sectors on
Active Cyber response.
- Great question.
I am not aware of anything.
I mean, we've got the STIX TAXII approach.
Andrew kind of alluded to the fact
that there are, there have
been attempts at this.
They haven't necessarily been successful.
I don't know if we got much
information out of those efforts
but I do think it's
something that is needed,
and it is something we
had, some of us had done
some work with the US Chamber of Commerce
on cyber incident reporting
and one of the issues was metrics.
And how do we measure
what's good, what's bad,
what's improving, what's
helping, et cetera.
So I'll use that to sort of segue
into my response to the earlier question.
I was gonna say, either glass half full,
I'm hopeful, it seems like
there's enough momentum.
I share Shane's concern.
So I'm kinda between on my screen,
Andrew's over here and Shane's over here,
I'm kind of in between them in terms
of where I think this will go.
I think there's enough
people talking about it.
I think, I believe the
message has gotten through
to the government that we
need more timely information
we're operating at
network speed essentially,
but I'll also approach it with
two words, colonial pipeline.
I saw a really interesting
piece just a couple of days ago
about how, it wasn't specifically talking
about defense forward, but
it was talking essentially
about this whole of nation
approach to cyber defense
and up until the colonial pipeline,
the majority of people, unless
you're in certain industries,
or focused on certain technologies,
people just don't get it.
- I just, I wanna thank all three of you.
Great lively discussion today.