- Hi, and thank you for joining us today.
This is Digital
Identities, 21 PKI Pitfalls
and How Best to Avoid Them.
I am Tim, the Chief
Compliance Officer at Sectigo,
and I'll let Jason introduce himself.
- Yes, my name is Jason.
I'm the CTO of PKI at Sectigo
- And Jay, and I do this
sort of thing together a lot
because we do have a PKI podcast,
a rather long running at
this point, PKI podcasts.
So we'll talk about that
a little more in the end,
but if we feel like we have
had these conversations before
it's because we've had many,
many conversations before.
So we do look at a lot of PKI,
so Sectigo is a leader in the PKI space.
We have a variety of tools,
we offer certificates,
and we also offer
certificate management tools.
And as a consequence, we deal
with a lot of enterprises
that are either creating or using PKI,
and we get a lot of visibility
on the various ways that
things can go right,
and the various ways that
things can go not so right.
So what we hope to do today
is just talk you through
the PKI errors as we see,
the common pitfalls, explain what they are
and maybe how to be on
the lookout for them
and what to do about them,
does that sound good, Jay?
- That's good, Tim, thank you.
- So we divided this into five
different kinds of problems,
you can see them right
here; certificate problems,
deployment problems, security problems,
governance problems and
visibility problems.
And we are going to drill down on each
of these types of PKI pitfalls to avoid.
So first off certificate, op.
There we go, here we go,
so those are the five.
So first off certificate problems.
Jay, problem number one, weak keys.
- Yes, you know Tim,
you and I talk a lot about
on our root causes podcast.
The whole idea that there
there are specific key links
that are chosen in the industry.
And unless you have a
sufficient amount of entropy,
the sufficient amount of bit length within
that is chosen with your keys,
it might make it a
little bit easy to hack.
And therefore you should really go
with industry standards,
industry best practices.
a weak keys or something
you should look for,
have visibility to and
try to avoid at all costs.
- And numbers do move,
they don't move very often,
but if you have, you know?
If you're a gray hair like
Jay and I are, you know?
The key length that you believe that
was acceptable 20 years ago
when you started in your job
may not be acceptable anymore.
So it's a good idea to make sure that
you're with the current practices on that.
And then of course, the problem
if they do have weak keys,
the trouble with that, Jay is?
- The trouble is it kind of depends.
If it's publicly trusted certificates,
hopefully you're getting it
from a certificate authority
that is obviously using
the correct key links,
RSA 2048, ECC 256, et cetera,
typically where you're gonna see problems
with weak keys though Tim,
is in privately trusted environments.
IOT perhaps even DevOps.
So that's a situation where somebody
who might not be a PKI professional
might have chosen incorrect default.
And that's where you're gonna see
more of a problems more commonly.
- Yeah, the public CA's
are gonna take care
of a lot of these for you,
and maybe we can clarify
which ones they do and don't,
but this page is gonna be pretty much okay
for the public CA's because
they can't give you the certs,
(chuckles) it would be against the rules,
but when you control your PKI,
you get to do whatever you want, right?
So that's where a lot of
the certificate problems
are gonna come from.
The second one on the
list, the term is too long.
So in the public certificate space,
depending on the certificate type,
if it's an SSL or TLS certificate,
you're limited to one year,
essentially 13 months.
If it's an S/MIME or
code signing certificate,
it's limited to three years.
But once again, if you're
issuing certificates on your CA,
you get to do whatever you like.
And one of the things we see
sometimes is someone says,
"Oh, this is great, I'll issue a cert.
I'll make it 20 years long,
and I'll never need any
worry about it ever again".
- You know, Tim, for terms,
especially again in the
private trust world,
which is mostly where I live,
it's quite common now
to see you much shorter
and shorter terms being
chosen for two reasons.
One is because it just flat out,
it makes the difficulty
level of the bad guy easier.
If you don't have a very
long live certificate.
If a long live certificate
is captured by a bad guy,
that bad guy has a long time
then to go doing bad things.
So therefore shorter
and shorter term lengths
are becoming more common.
That requires certificate
management, of course,
but that's part of what modern
PKI is gonna be promising us.
- And we'll be getting
to that I'm sure, right?
So just by reducing certificate term,
you reduce the potential
attack time, right?
Pure and simple, there's only so long
that you can work on a cert
before that So it doesn't matter.
Outdated cryptographic algorithms.
So once again, as with key lengths,
these are things that do evolve over time.
You know, once upon a time SHA-1
was considered to be state-of-the-art.
Now, SHA-1 is deprecated and
is considered to be unsafe.
And we'll come up on the
fact where RSA and ECC
will be considered to be unsafe,
that's not that many years away.
So cryptographic algorithms do change
and you need to stay current,
and we still see people using SHA-1 still.
- Yeah, So we're mixing a few things there
where the primitives, right?
The hashing algorithms are the ones where
deprecated cryptographic algorithms
are things that we've seen
quite commonly in the past,
and we've to deal with them.
Again, visibility of the certificates
that you're issuing and using
is incredibly important,
because just like you
don't wanna use a weak key,
you do not wanna be using
an outdated cryptographic algorithm
whether it's for hashing or anything else.
Once again, though, in the public world,
the CA's are typically
doing this thinking for you
but it's when in the private world
where you're having to do
this thinking yourself,
where it's quite easy to make mistakes.
- Yeah, for sure, and then
certificates stapling.
Oops, talk to us about
certificate stapling, Jay.
- Sure Tim, you know this was a big topic.
I think mobile devices are where this
really came up quite a lot,
where certificates were
used in mobile apps.
And it was quite common for applications
to hard-code public key information.
And unfortunately,
applications don't get updated
as often sometimes as need be
to be able to keep up with
perhaps a revoked certificate.
And so therefore something
happens in the background
all of a sudden that application
unless it can be updated to
the whole world very quickly,
you're gonna have a major problem.
And so therefore certificate stapling,
there's other ways that this has been put,
but essentially the
risk here is hard-coded
public keys within applications.
- Yeah, and it may not be
quote unquote stapling per se.
But I mean, I was just
this morning talking
to a major enterprise who
had hard-coded applications
look for specific details
inside their certs
and those details were changing
and they had to create a roadmap
item to deal with that, so-
- You should consider all
certificates ephemeral, period.
- Yeah, absolutely, that's a big one.
And you lose your agility, right?
We're gonna talk about agility,
the ability to change out your certs
and swap out your certs
when unknown events occur
or an unexpected problems occur
is a major part of the robust high uptime
high security contemporary enterprise.
All right, deployment problems.
So those are certificate
problems, deployment problems.
First of all, reuse of
certificates, we see this a bunch.
- Yeah, Tim, so I think
in the public trust world,
there are examples of, if
you have multiple servers
that are handling a specific domain,
you might be doing a
reuse of a certificate.
I'm not sure if that's the
worst thing in the world
but I will tell you that
one of the big problems
with a reuse of certificate
in the private trust world,
again, is all the automotive industry
had a problem with this
with their key fobs
where there a practice of
using the same certificate
just copies of certificates
in all the different key fobs,
they were not issuing
different certificates.
And so therefore if that
certificate were to be stolen,
or by some sort of process
especially because the risk there
is the fact that every single certificate
was just within a physical
device that was so easy to steal.
Unfortunately it caused a
situation where that key fob
could then be used against
a number of targets at once.
Reuse of certificates, not a good idea.
Issue a certificate per destination.
- Yeah, and in an IOT
scenario in particular, right?
One of the problems of
course is oftentimes
there is no replacing that
certificate on the device, right?
If you revoke the cert,
you break the device.
And so under those circumstances,
you want granular control, right?
If there were a reason
why I had to get rid of
one cert to break one device,
it'd be a shame if I had to take
10,000 of its closest
friends with it, right?
But that's a real scenario that really
people run into in the real world.
Now on the public trust side, you know?
Certificate reuse this is a tough one
because on the one hand I get your point
and this comes up where people say,
"Look, I have a cluster
and I have to manage this.
And you know, it's
putting an individual cert
on every individual machine or VM
is very difficult for
the following reasons".
Yeah, but what you're doing again
is you're extending your risk.
In the hypothetical scenario
where there is a search
that needs to be got rid of right now,
or in the hypothetical scenario where
somebody steals a private
key and you don't know it.
If you have it on one machine,
your risk is more limited.
If you have it on 50 machines,
your risk is much broader.
And so that's a problem.
- They call them leaf
certificates for a reason.
Every leaf should have
a unique identifier.
- Yeah, so it's tough.
I understand the temptation
and probably right now,
some of you in the audience are going,
"Well, but you know I
really gotta", I get it.
But you also have to understand that
you are extending your
risk of outage or worse
as the more you raise certificates
the more you're extending that risk.
And so I guess what
we're probably saying is
keep that to a minimum
do it when you must,
don't do it when it's more convenient.
And that's actually kind of a
theme for the next two, right?
Overextension and six and
seven sort of go together.
They're are two flavors of the same thing.
It's overextended use of
a specific certificate.
So just like when I copy a certificate
and put it on multiple machines,
I also can say life is
easier if I use wild cards
cause they work with more domains.
Or life is easier if I use MDCs
cause I can take the same certificate
and can work with more
domains, and that's important.
They're important tools in the chest,
that's why they're there.
But on the other hand, you
can be too enthusiastic,
in your use of these things
and you can overextend.
- So Tim, a perfect
example that I can think of
from a bad guy's perspective,
wildcards are great if
you're attacking that site
because the ability to create sub-domains
at will is quite easy and-
- Right. (laughing)
- Right, so therefore
convenience to the person...
The convenience factor
to the victim was great.
All of a sudden, it's not very convenient
once you find out that your sites
are being used for phishing.
- Yeah, and also once again,
this extension of risk argument
it's just like reuse is the same.
In the event that there is a problem
instead of you losing a more limited
part of my service infrastructure,
while I deal with the problem I'm losing
a bigger part of my service
infrastructure, right?
More problems, more cascading effects,
more outages, more
customers can't be served,
more employees can't do
what they need to do.
So again, it's like reuse of certificates.
I know the reasons why people do it.
Those reasons are valid.
Our environments are technically complex,
and at the same time,
just be careful about being lazy about it
and make sure you're doing it
because you must and
not just cause you can.
- Yeah, well said.
- All right, we're already
hinted at this one.
So automation, a big one was see.
Failure to automate certificate renewal.
So in the public trust world,
all of your certificates will expire,
the will expire by a certain timeframe
that's not that far away.
Normally the certificates lasts longer
than the services that they serve do
and that means certificates
need to be renewed.
And when they aren't renewed,
there are outages, bad things happen.
A couple of years ago the
O2 data service went down,
O2 SoftBank and other providers went down,
maybe 40 million people were without
phone service for most of the day.
The root cause was an expired certificates
that didn't get renewed.
The Equifax breach that
affected 45% of Americans,
myself included was enabled
by an expired certificate
that didn't get renewed.
Every year we see high profile outages
from major technology providers,
and major online services that go down.
And the root cause is a certificate
that didn't get renewed.
- The list goes on and on, and
these are not minor players.
We're talking about Microsoft Teams,
- (chuckles) Yes.
- Sony had an outage.
It just, the list goes on and on it.
And it was interesting
Tim as we were waiting
for the first big example of this in 2021,
and we've now seen it as well.
- Yeah, exactly.
so automation of
certificate renewal is key.
And again, a lot of us
especially the old timers,
remember once upon a
time where I had a room
with the drop floor and there
were exactly 23 servers in it
and they had to be swapped
out once every two years.
And it was easy to put
things in your calendar,
but that just isn't our world anymore.
And if you're still
trying to do these things
manually with spreadsheets
and are getting more and more complicated,
this is how people get in trouble.
Automation of renewal is so valuable.
- Yes, sir, I'm thinking,
think of the proliferation of web servers,
the proliferation of load balancers
the proliferation of
all the different places
where your certificates are renewing.
That's just in the public trust world,
nevermind the private trust world
where they can be in
hundreds and hundreds,
if not thousands of locations.
This has to be automated now.
It's 2021, it's gonna be 2022 soon enough.
We've got, dealing with it by spreadsheet,
we just have to get rid of that.
- And then this ties
into your earlier point
about shorter terms, right?
If you wanna shorten your terms,
then automation becomes all
that much more important, right?
If I take my average, if I take my stats
and I say instead of one year
I'm going down to 90 days,
I just quadrupled the
number of renewables,
right?
- Right Tim.
- And (chuckles) so I
better make sure that
I'm able to deal with that.
The next two also in a
way kind of go together.
So multiple private CA's
so here's the scenario,
somewhere along the line I need a CA,
and so I go and I put something together
and I put it in place I
sat up and I run that.
And then somewhere on the line,
someone else in my organization,
they need some in-house certs.
And so they make their own CA
and et cetera and et cetera.
And suddenly I have all
these CA's out there
and I've all these roots,
and I have all this stuff to be managed.
If I don't get all the right routes
in the right machines
then systems don't work
and it can become an
administration nightmare.
- Tim, here's a pro tip for you,
and for anybody who's watching this.
Every Kubernetes cluster has a CA, right?
Anybody who's doing DevOps,
raise your hands virtually,
(laughing softly)
you have CAs
that are proliferating
within your environment
that you may not know about.
You might say to yourself,
"This doesn't apply to me.
I've got a great governance program.
I've got a risk officer
who's obsessed over this".
Yeah, but you probably have a DevOps team
that's creating CA's and
you don't even know it.
- Yeah, absolutely.
And again, the disadvantages
of having multiple CAs
run around, it's less efficient.
it is much harder to maintain,
consistent compliance with
your own government rules.
There's more things you need to look at,
and there are potential,
there's the potential for
systems not to work correctly,
not to connect to each other correctly
because I was expecting one CA
and I was getting a different CA.
- Tim, I would say, this is an where
we don't often in the PKI industry
talk much more about trust models,
we used to back in the old days.
- Oh yeah, (indistinct)
- But I think
it's gotta come back as a conversation
and that's where going to
the experts really helps,
because we've seen it
all, been there done that.
And there's a sweet
spot for every use case
in every scenario and there's a sweet spot
for the growth that you're gonna have
within your enterprise as well,
especially out to the cloud.
There's dealing now with
extending trust to partners,
multi-vendor ecosystems,
There's ways to determine how
you should structure your CAs.
- Okay, fair enough.
And probably we can't get into that now
but that might make a good
podcast or a future webinar.
And then connected to
that is maintaining an...
Excuse me, an unnecessary Microsoft CA.
So again, what happens here?
What happens here is
I have a Microsoft CA,
I've had it for a long time,
cause I've had windows
servers and windows machines.
And by my operating system,
makeup has outgrown that, right?
It's more heterogeneous
than it was at the time
but we still got this old
Microsoft CA sitting around.
That's only good for part
of what it needs to service,
and then we have to
service everything else
with a different CA but we
don't rip out the Microsoft CA
just cause it's kind of always been there.
- Well, Tim, my hair is quickly graying,
and that's just proof that Microsoft CA
has been in my life for a long time,
I've seen a lot of implementations of it.
What used to be a very Microsoft-centric
siloed enterprise environment
has now quickly grown to
be extended to the cloud.
You now have multiple operating systems,
not the least of which is
Android, iOS, et cetera,
on and on and on to
various flavors of Linux.
Mobile device use cases all
these things did not exist
in the heyday of Microsoft
CA and it has not kept up.
And Microsoft has basically left it
to the industry to deal with that.
And so therefore you really
have to question, you know?
Should you be, at the very least,
you probably have to be
augmenting your Microsoft CA.
But on the other hand, are you keeping it
just because it makes
you feel warm and fuzzy.
It's one of these things
where that free CA
has cost you a lot of money over the years
with the difficulty of maintenance.
PKI has moved on.
It's good to look at what's out there
to be able to replace it
or to augment it very well.
- Fair enough, all right.
So the next one security problems.
Good old fashioned things are
security and vulnerabilities
with your certificates and your keys.
So first of all, inadequate
protection of your private keys.
Private keys are what it's all about.
If anybody gets the private
keys, the certs are no good.
So talk to me about this, Jay.
- Sure, Tim, I'll use an example
that's probably very easy to
relate to for most people.
But how many of you know for a fact that
within your organization, your SSH keys,
not necessarily your PKI managed keys,
but just your SSH key
pairs are sitting around?
They're just on somebody's file system,
and when you need them you use them.
- In a folder called "Keys".
- In a folder called "Hack Me Now, Here".
- (chuckles) Right.
- Unfortunately that's incredibly common.
So if you enter then the
PKI version of that story,
it's exactly the same
scenario which is obviously
for your CA root keys
a private CA scenario.
She'd put in those in an HSM.
But for leaf certificates, for example,
we now have all sorts of
secure elements available,
all Windows 10 laptops come with a TPM.
There are various other form
factors to protect your keys.
So regardless of whether
they're root keys,
or whether they're leaf certificates,
these are things that
in the modern age now,
we can protect these things properly,
and that even includes IOT.
I still see a lot of IOT devices
where the certificates
are stored in software.
There are very cost-effective
secure elements now
for IOT devices where the
certificate can be stored
in a very, very secure location,
isolated from the main kernel,
isolated from user LAN memory.
You gotta check into these things.
- All right, and then patches
and vulnerabilities, right?
Patch management, so, you know?
If you're using a third-party service,
a SaaS service like for
your PKI, for instance,
that vendor is going to take care of this.
They're gonna make sure
everything is patched and current.
They're going to make sure that, you know?
They know about the zero days on day zero,
and that they respond for them.
But if you take it and you
kind of set up your own PKI,
and somebody puts it up and it's running
and everybody forgets it,
and it's sitting in the background,
who's keeping an eye on that?
Who's making sure that you're current?
Who's making sure that
you don't have holes
that have been discovered
that you could have patched
but you didn't cause
nobody thought about it
or nobody thought it was their job?
- I think it's very common.
And Tim, I remember that during
the last set of overwhelming
difficulties in the industry
for everybody in IT,
there happened to be
also be a patch Tuesday
to patch other things at the time.
And all these things,
unfortunately have to be tested
in a lot of organizations
before the patch is allowed.
And so these dependencies of patching,
leading to long lengths of
vulnerabilities being wide open,
it's a golden age to
be a bad guy right now.
- It is, it is so that's another, again
that's a common one we see a lot.
Governance problems.
So first of all, just good old fashioned,
"Oh, we don't have rules. (chuckles)
We don't have rules for our certificates.
We don't have rules for
PKI, was that a thing?
Now, again, not so much
an issue for public certs.
Although even then you might wanna say,
"Look, we're we're in ECC shop",
or things along those lines,
but in the private PKI world
where you can turn the
levers any way you like,
it can we've seen it where
it's just absolute chaos
- Chaos to the point where
if you go back to some
earlier slides, Tim,
SHA-1 certificates aren't
even part of the policy.
So in other words
issuing anything you like
is kind of a possibility
and nobody's got the visibility to it.
So I think we'll be
talking a little bit more
about visibility later but
governance plus visibility
together are incredibly important.
- Yeah, and also remember
that a lot of the people
involved in your organization
are not the PKI experts,
they are expert in something else.
They are great developers perhaps
but they don't know
really anything about PKI.
And so if there aren't
policies for them to follow,
if there isn't a recipe
book that you give them,
then they're forced to try to figure
these things out for themselves.
And they may not be the
best qualified people
in your organization to do that.
- It's hard enough for
a full-time risk officer
in a normal size organization to do it.
Nevermind, leave it to people who are-
- Yeah.
- That's not their full-time job.
- Someone who's overworked and busy
and on deadline and supposed
to be doing something else,
and they have an internal customer
who's screaming at them, yes, exactly.
CPS problems, so once again,
is there a CPS, do you know what it says?
Where did it come from?
Was any consideration built into it?
These are all legitimate questions.
- The big question to me Tim, is
did it lock you into something
that doesn't grow with you?
And that, again, something I said earlier,
which is talk to the
experts because CPS papers
can be written in such a way that
it won't lock you in or
paint you into a corner
for future considerations, I
think that's very important.
This is an area where even I don't claim
to be an expert, Tim.
And I've been around this
industry over 20 years,
there are specialists in this that
you really need to talk
to to make sure that
you don't have CPS problems.
- Right, and we do have certainly
our share of them here at Sectigo.
It's just not you and I Jay,
because we focus on different things.
Revocation checking.
We've already talked about revocation.
Revocation, checking doesn't help
or revocation doesn't help
if you don't know if
a CERT's been revoked.
- Yeah, I would say there are some
use cases in IOT, for example,
where revocation isn't even possible.
Therefore you have to make the decision
of having very low term
links for your certificates,
we talked about that earlier.
But certainly verification checking in,
especially in private trust,
if you're not checking those certificates,
they're essentially
long lived certificates.
And therefore that term
problem we talked about earlier
it becomes the equivalent problem.
- Yeah, I don't have
anything to add to that.
And then the public private certificate,
these two, again, 16 and
17 kind of go together.
Public certs and private certs,
they have their own
individual advantages, right?
Public certs are essential for certain
interoperability scenarios
where there's just
no other way or for services that
reach outside of your own walled garden.
Private certs though,
can be much better assets
when you're confident that you
can stay in the walled garden
cause they give you more
freedom and more control.
And people don't always think about
which one is preferable,
rather they just do what they're used to.
Do what they did last time.
Do what's more convenient,
do what's more available.
That that's one of the
things we definitely see.
- Yeah, Tim, I would say,
I think the real quick
rule of thumb here is
if your use case utilizes
a web browser of any kind,
public certs might be a good idea
in order to be able to
avoid error messages,
warning messages within the browser.
For every other use case,
the public trust is kind of a misnomer
because a lot of times
when you might think
you might need a public trusts,
what you really need is a trust model
that effectively allows
a multi-vendor ecosystem.
And so you think of it
more like a walled garden
for multiple vendors and that
could be hundreds of vendors.
Hundreds of organizations,
hundreds of partners,
but not necessarily public.
- Yeah, we just, on our podcasts,
we just had a guest the Chairman
of the SunSpec Alliance,
which is a clean energy consortium.
And he talked about how there are hundreds
of technology providers inside
of that single ecosystem,
and they all have to be interoperable.
And so that's where, you know?
If you have to use private certs,
that's where you need to make sure that
you give this stuff some
very careful thought.
And that's again, where
you should ask yourself
if public certs is perhaps
the way you have to go.
- It's pretty black and white,
but Tom gave a really good podcast.
That's one worth listening to, for sure.
- Yeah, for sure,
All right, problems with visibility.
And by the way, you'll
see 21 is the last number.
So this is the last of our five sections.
Okay, and again, this two kind of,
first who kind of go together.
Rogue certificates.
What we mean by rogue certificates is
somewhere in the organization,
someone is working on a
project that is being financed
by some kind of internal customer.
Let's say it's a marketing department.
The marketing department says,
"I have an idea for a great new service.
We're gonna do really well with this,
we're gonna sell lots and lots of stuff".
And they go out and they
hire a development firm,
and the development firm
puts things together,
and they look at it and saw great,
and they standard up.
And one of the things those
guys do is they go buy certs.
So they buy some on your
certs and they slam it in,
and you stand up to your
service and you're a genius
and it's hugely successful.
And so 365 days later
this is an essential part
of our revenue stream, and
one day it's not working,
and people are panicked and
people are in trouble, why?
Because there were some
certificates that nobody knew about
that never were on the roadmap
or never visible to the
office of the CIO or the CISO,
and suddenly bang, things are down,
and people don't know why
and this happens a lot.
- I would say, Tim, you know?
A lot of customers will
initiate certificate discovery,
which is a modern
capability of a good PKI.
- Right.
- And they'll run it at the beginning
and then they think, well, I've got it.
That's it, we're good.
I think what you've just argued is that
it might be a good idea
to do it periodically
- Yeah.
- To see whether or not
some rogue certificates have shown up
within your organization
cause it is a possibility.
- Rogue certificates
creep in all the time,
and when they do go, you have outages.
And by the way, there are other scenarios
like an MNA scenario, right?
I acquire a company, how do I know that
I know about all the certificates
in the company I acquired, right?
And I just spent a bunch
of my hard-earned money
for their revenue stream.
I don't want that revenue stream breaking
because certificates expired.
So yeah, rogue certificates.
I think we understand that
scenario a little more,
but there's also a rogue CA scenario
where the exact same thing happens
but it happens with an entire CA
and all of its leaf certificates.
- Tim, I think I mentioned earlier,
the visibility problem of
Kubernetes clusters having CAs,
if unless those are part
of your governance program,
unless you know what
CA's are being issued,
what's their key links
if they're being revoked,
what are the policies?
Then I would consider
those to be rogue CAs.
And I guarantee, this is
number 19 on the list,
but this may be number one
(laughing)
on your homework list today.
- Right, we'll get to your homework list.
Yeah, so exactly.
And once again, you know?
This could happen through
internal Skunkworks projects.
This could happen through, you know?
A diversified set of internal customers
off using their own development teams,
or their outside development firms.
This could happen through MNA,
these are all scenarios
where this can occur.
And I'm growing and I'm
standing up new machines
and they're not working,
and I don't know why they're not working.
And it turns out at the end of the day,
they're looking for a route that
I didn't know existed, right?
So that's a real thing, we see it.
Future use case planning.
Yeah, there's a lot of here and now
in people thinking about
digital certificates
and CA's and PKI rather than asking
what do I need to look like
in a year or five years?
- Hey, I'm setting up a Microsoft CA,
because 100% of my employees
at this very moment
log into things that are
connected to active directory.
Hallelujah, I'm good to go.
Fast forward to today,
you now have the cloud.
You now have operating systems
that have nothing to do
with Microsoft Stack.
You now have burgeoning technologies
that are all over the place, distributed,
not Microsoft operating system
and you didn't plan for any of it.
And that's the story of the
near past but I guarantee
the same kind of mistakes
are happening today
because the future is only
gonna blossom that much more.
The proliferation of
technologies in the near future
will be more than we've ever seen.
Are you planning for those unknowns?
- Right, your environments
are gonna get more complex.
Repatriation is gonna become more common,
the total number of systems
involved is going to go up.
The amount of DevOps is gonna go up,
the role played by mobile
devices is going to go up.
All of this is just going to
make things more complicated.
- Are you gonna extend trust
to partners in the future?
Are you gonna be dealing with
the multi-vendor ecosystem?
Are you gonna have trust models
that did not exist today?
Are you going to split product lines?
Are you gonna do MNA's in the future?
All of these things
are extremely important
when thinking about trust models
that you're building today
and technologies and trust models
that you're gonna wanna
be using in the future.
Don't paint yourself into a corner.
- Yeah, absolutely.
I mean, it's funny you just
brought up the MNA one,
that's such an interesting thing.
Like sometimes when somebody
has to spin off a business,
all right, we're gonna...
We're keeping this but
we're gonna take this part
and we're gonna carve it off
and we're (chuckles) gonna
sell it to someone else.
And disentanglement there
becomes really, really hard
especially if it turns out things like,
well they're all part
of the same (chuckles)
CA infrastructure and
suddenly they can't be, right?
So for sure, failure to stay
current on cryptography.
We kind of referenced this one early on
but crypto is changing.
For example, I mentioned
earlier, you know?
Quantum computers are
probably going to render,
are soon to render RSA and ECC obsolete.
We're gonna have to go
to completely different
crypto, right?
And completely different cipher suites.
And so if you are running your own PKI,
you're taking on an obligation to know
what is cryptographically sound
and what is not and staying current.
- Again, for the homework list,
it is time to get your
hands dirty in 2021, 2022,
on to quantum safe certificates
and on hybrid certificates
which will help the agility
of moving forward into that world.
It is time to get your
hands dirty with that now.
And that's something we can help you with.
- Absolutely.,we're happy
to help you with it.
So the final point, so
that's it, that's the 21.
So what are you gonna do?
So what are you gonna do now?
You have this presentation
it's also available recorded,
so you can go back and look at it again.
This is what we recommend you do.
First of all is review this list.
Go back and look down the list of 21.
That's why we gave you a specific
list, why we organized it.
And think about which one of these
potentially applies to your organization.
And then we suggest
that you make a project
where you go to your internal SMEs,
and have them evaluate your practices
in light of these common pitfalls.
So you can identify things
the easy way and fix them,
before you identify them the hard way
when stuff stops working.
And this is something you can go do,
you can go work on right now.
- Well said to Tim.
- So we did mention,
allude a couple of times,
Jay and I do run a popular podcast,
focused on the PKI and security space.
It is called "Root Causes".
You can find it on SoundCloud, Spotify,
iTunes, and a bunch of other places
where you may listen to podcasts.
Just search for Root Causes
PKI, and it'll come up.
You can also just find episodes
directly on the Sectigo website.
We have recorded more than 150 episodes,
and we cover all kinds of matters;
digital certificates,
PKI and related topics.
And we would love to have you join us.
So with that, I think I will
thank you for your time.
We've been answering questions
and chat throughout the session.
And if there are more questions,
we will continue to
answer them, thank you.
- Thank you.