- Welcome everybody to today's session.
End The Battle Between
Security And Productivity.
I am joined today with my
colleague, David Holmes,
talking about a super important
topic and the future of work
and in cybersecurity today,
which is how to balance the need for
securing enterprise data
and your organization
as a whole with end-user productivity.
And so this has been a major challenge
for many organizations today.
We're gonna tackle some topics
around employee experience,
engagement productivity
and also how to balance that
with a modern security strategy.
So David and I both work for
a company called Forrester.
If you don't know Forrester,
we are a market research firm,
based out of Boston, Massachusetts
and we work with business
and technology leaders
to drive customer obsessed
strategies for growth.
And so I sit on our Infrastructure
and Operations team.
I've been at Forrester
now for seven years.
So I think I'm the lone IT Ops person
that doesn't work at
insecurity at this conference
but I cover all end-user
computing at Forrester.
I'm one of our lead
researchers for remote working.
And I also do a lot of work
on technology experience
for employees which is why
I was the representative
on the technology EX
component of this research
with my colleague David Holmes.
So David, you wanna introduce yourself
and bring the audience
through our agenda today?
- Yeah, hey everybody,
it's David at Forester.
So I am an analyst on Forester
Security and Risk team
coming up on my second year at Forrester
but it feels like 14 years.
So I think it's like dog years,
like your time as an analyst at Forrester,
but I cover things like security,
Zero Trust, Zero Trust network access
what Forrester calls the Zero Trust edge
or what you'll see in
the market and sassy.
And I cover DDoS and
network security controls
and crypto and DNS, and
a whole bunch of stuff.
And I'm really, really
excited to be here with Andrew
to talk about ending that battle between
productivity and security, right?
This is something that has been
a challenge my entire life,
is when security gets in
the way of productivity
and what we're positing in
the report that goes along
with this talk is that not
only can you end that battle,
you can actually,
when you do Zero Trust or
do cybersecurity correctly,
you can actually improve productivity
and improve the employee experience
while you improve your security posture.
So we're gonna lay this out really simply.
We're gonna talk about what we think
of as measuring productivity,
the EX part, right?
And then we'll talk about
and define Zero Trust
in the cybersecurity part.
And then we'll try to tie those together.
We'll give real world examples
and then we'll leave you
with, what can you do in
like in the next 60 to
90 days to get started?
But one of the things I wanted to mention
before we move on is Andrew And I actually
started this research prior
to the pandemic, right.
I think it was at the
company Christmas party 2019
- It was, our last in-person interaction.
I think it was with you dude.
- Oh my goodness.
My goodness seems like
forever ago, but we actually
started this report prior,
this research, prior
to the pandemic, but
everything that happened
during the pandemic has,
I think, proven us out
and given us real good concrete
examples to, to show you.
So I'm going to turn it back to you
for a little bit, Andrew, to
explain what we mean by EX
- So EX is the really
important research area
at Forrester and also a
really important area to focus
on as an organization,
as you go into 2021.
We define employee experience as the sum
of all the perceptions that an employee
has working at the company.
It could be perceptions
around a manager relationship.
around collaboration
with their coworkers, with technology.
It's really, basically
everything that they experience
on a daily basis.
The sum of all those things.
And does that make them happier
or does that make them
want to leave your company
and go somewhere else?
And so one of the things that you'll see
throughout our presentation is
the importance of technology
in that overall employee
experience in terms
of how it either contributes
to better engagement
of your workforce or
contributes to the opposite
which is burnout and
attrition and your workforce.
And specifically, we're
gonna talk about how security
really can play a role
in driving an employee
towards more engagement
or to more burnout.
And so I'll make that
connection here and then
we will apply some of the best
practices around Zero Trust
technology and strategy as a whole
as far as how do you overcome
some of this tension between
security and productivity?
So let's dive in a little bit first
I'll say that the stakes are
incredibly high when it comes
to these two topics.
So the thing that really launched
this whole research stream
for me, and it was really
illuminating with clients
is I had a conversation
with an IT director
and a large financial services firm.
I believe it was in the US and he said,
"I'm worried that if we don't
give employees more choice,
there's going to be a full-on
revolt in our organization."
People are going to leave and
they were starting to hear this
in the exit interviews that the technology
that they were given on
a daily basis was not
allowing them to do
their jobs effectively.
It was a very standard,
PC to employee type
of environment, lock
down, corporate image,
very little self service,
very little autonomy overall.
And so the employees
wanted more flexibility,
something that was being driven a lot
by consumerization of IT that
we've heard about for so long.
And so for this organization
trying to solve this tension
between what do we need to do
from a compliance risk
and security perspective
on our environment
versus what our employees
actually want was a major
challenge for them to overcome.
And we posit three things
in our research that are
major business outcomes
from not solving this issue.
So number one is engagement
is going to increase
and decrease, not increase
across your workforce.
And what we found
statistically is that the most
engaged employees also are much
more likely to be satisfied
with our company's security policies.
We'll show some of the data
that proves that point.
We also found that employees will dodge
the security blanket if it gets in the way
of them being productive.
There is some pretty horrifying
and eye-opening data about the frequency
and willingness to
circumvent security policies
in the name of productivity,
which we'll also show you.
And thirdly, which is really
important as you start to come
out of this pandemic is
innovation will suffer
and why will that occur?
It will occur
because organizations will spend months,
if not years,
going through RFPs to make sure that
they can handle the newest
and greatest technology
that employees want to bring
into the workforce, that they
can adopt it in a secure way.
If you don't have a modern
security architecture
that allows you to take on things quickly
and do it in a secure manner,
what you're going to find
is that your competition
is going to start to
take on new technologies
and start to out-compete you in markets
because their employees are
going to be way more effective
at getting their work done
and contributing to the company overall.
So just to wrap things up,
this stakes are really high.
We need to start thinking about
how do we end this war here.
So diving a little bit into the
employee experience overall,
we have at Forester what's called
our Employee Experience Index
and this was developed by an ambulance
by the name of Dave Johnson
on our future of work team.
And essentially the Employee
Experience Index measures
employee engagement on
a scale of zero to 100,
100 meaning I'm most
engaged, very productive,
I'm likely to stay at my company.
Zero being I'm not engaged at
all, probably gonna be gone
in the next couple of
months, that sort of thing.
And so what we found
that there were a variety
of different psychological
factors that impact
whether someone is engaged
towards that 100 or disengaged.
And they roughly break down into these
three buckets of empowerment,
which is all about
how does the organization,
give you clarity
of your role, gives you
the right manager resources
etcetera, to be successful.
That's the most influential
on the overall employee experience.
Inspiration which is all about alignment
of my personal values with the mission
and values of the company,
feeling like my work matters,
that sort of thing, and enablement,
which is all technology.
So this is one of the biggest
findings of this research
is that 30% of what drives
the employee experience
are actually technology
related factors here.
So you can see six of
the most statistically
relevant factors for
improving employee experience
or impacting employee experience
from a technology perspective
on the screen here
- Can I put you on the spot if we didn't
- Yeah.
- That these data points here
where they collected prior
to the pandemic
- They were, yep.
- So you think these numbers
are probably even more skewed
toward technology in
the remote work worlds?
- I would say absolutely. We
haven't done the analysis yet
but technology is literally the lifeline
between the employee and the organization.
Now, there's broad shifts
towards remote working
and you'll see some data later
on that we're going to share
around that we expected this
to continue to increase.
So absolutely, I think
if we were to look back
at this data now and rerun
the engagement survey
we probably see it's potentially
even higher than 30% now.
But the end goal here is to really
to drive a purpose worker.
That's what we call a
fully engaged worker.
Someone who is bringing
their selves to work
in the fullest way
possible every single day.
And so technology plays
a major role in that.
And one of the really
interesting things that we found
in the research is that security directly
impacts engagement as well.
So if you look here,
the light blue bars are
your most engaged employees.
And so 89% of your highly
engaged employees are satisfied
with company technology,
security policies,
just 25% of the lowest engaged
employees are satisfied
with that overall policy.
So there's a huge gap.
If you are a non-engaged
you're likely not to be satisfied
with those security policies overall.
And the same thing occurs
for things like information access.
There's a 63% gap there,
satisfaction with
collaboration technology 66%.
And so there are a variety
of different technologies
that we've looked at as far
as their impact on overall
engagement, security policies
and satisfaction with
those policies are one
of the most decisive for
someone's satisfaction
with technology and engagement
in the workplace overall.
So it's actually
- This correlation - born out.
There's a correlation. Yep.
That's born out in a lot of the data here.
And the reason the following
question to that is,
why does this matter so much?
When you think about overall engagement
one of the most illuminative
pieces of research
that I've read is from the
work of Teresa Amabile,
who's a PhD at Harvard who says that,
"Employees are most happy
when they're making progress every day
and work that they feel is meaningful."
So it is about productivity overall
that's driving higher levels
of satisfaction and engagement.
Think about it in your own life.
How good do you feel at the end of the day
if you go home and you've just
been procrastinating all day
and you've gotten nothing done
versus a day where you were super focused
and you got a lot of stuff off your plate,
you feel a lot more engaged on the ladder,
I guarantee you.
And so this is one of the
reasons why, when we ask folks
why do you sometimes ignore
or go around your company's
security policies?
34% said they had to
collaborate with peers
outside of the company that's
related to productivity.
And 33% said, it's the most efficient way
of doing what I need to get done.
31% saying that their policies are strict
or unreasonable in nature.
So if an employee feels
like their productivity is being impacted
by security policies,
they will circumvent that.
And interestingly, we didn't
include this data point here
but 10% of employees
admit that they would go
around a security policy
if they knew how to.
So it doesn't sound like a
huge number, but if you think
if 10% of your workforce is
saying, if I knew how to get
around this policy, I
would absolutely do it.
That's why this conversation
is so important because lack
of productivity leads to
lack of security as well.
And it also leads to burnout.
Here are your 10 predictors
of burnout as statistically proven
through the employee experience index.
You can see at the bottom here
these are the top 10 security
policies, hinder productivity.
So security policies are
basically the number 10 driver
of employee burnout in the workplace,
which is high considering
all the other factors
that can contribute to overall burnout,
not the most, correlated
with burnout overall,
but definitely playing a role.
And so as you start to
think about productivity
in your organization,
you really going to have to start thinking
about how does security get
in the way of people
getting their work done.
And so one of the major
posits that we made
with this research, and I'm
going to hand it over to David
in just a moment is that a
new, modern security strategy
what we call a Zero Trust
at Forester, is a way to help
overcome a lot of these issues
and resolve some of that
fundamental tension.
So over the next couple of minutes
I'm going to hand it over to David.
I'll probably chime in as well.
Just to talk a little bit
about how ZT specifically can help you
with your employee experience strategy.
Over to you, David.
- Andrew, Fantastic.
Thanks for setting that up.
I'm going to back up one slide real quick
because I wanted to look
at the two numbers where security policies
hindering productivity,
and too many meetings
on my calendar who
doesn't hate that, right?
Those are like, that's the same
almost the same number four.
That's going to drive on employee burnout.
And that's, I just
wanted to highlight that.
- I bet that that would be
higher this year as well.
- I think so too. I think
they're both (indistinct)
Okay so, in two slides, I just wanted to,
if you weren't familiar
with Forrester's Zero Trust, right.
This was a paper that came
out of Forrester in 2009.
And I remember I was a younger man,
almost maybe Angela's age.
When I first read the paper
and I was reading a
bootleg copy of this paper
and I was like, "This, these
are what should people get."
This is what we have
everything we have done wrong.
It's security, and this
is the way for it, right?
So the paper lays out
three core principles
for a Zero Trust model
of information security.
And the first one was consider
all networks on trust.
There shouldn't be part of
your network where you say,
"Oh, well it's coming from
that part of the network
so I'm just going to trust it"
Right? And that's less common today
that you see networks like that,
partly because of the
advocacy of Zero Trust.
And another way to think
about this principle is
trust the identity, right?
Establishing, trusting identity.
Don't just trust a network connection
because it's coming from a
place that you consider trusted.
A second core principle
is least privilege access
must be enforced, but
only give the privileges
to somebody that they need in
order to do their job, right?
And if you need to
elevate them temporarily
or to do a certain task and we do so then
but then revoke it later, right?
And then the third one
is, well, the paper didn't
use the phrase assume
breach that came later.
That's what it was really talking about
is assume that attackers
will eventually get in.
If they're not in already
and have the machinery
in place that you can detect them
and then hopefully block
the lateral movement, right.
Or contain the blast radius.
And then if you wanted
to make a bumper sticker
out of Zero Trust, you would say
"Never trust, always verify."
As a matter of fact if you
ever want to sound smarter
at a party, right?
You can just say "Never
trust, always verify people."
People in the know will
know what you mean.
Now, we haven't sat still
at Forrester for over the
since 2009, we have somewhat
evolved Zero Trust to
make it a little bit more
less about the network
which is what the initial papers
were really talking about.
And more to talk about the
different elements, right?
And so this is how we
visualize Zero Trust today,
and what we think of as
an extended ecosystem
with seven domains, right?
And the reason we do this
is we put data at the center
because we think Zero Trust is
all about protecting the data
and not protecting, about
protecting a network.
However, you need more
than just data security,
you need to have security controls
around the things that
interact with the data
which can broadly be categorized
into four domains,
people, devices, networks, and workloads.
And so when you think of people
you might think of technology groups
like identity and access
management, right,
or workloads can be applications.
And you could think of application
security or for networks
you might think of technologies
like micro-segmentation.
And for devices, you may
think of device security.
And throughout all that,
we think you need to
have this some kind of visibility system
or what we call network analytics ability
so that you can see events
and correlate them through
the different domain.
So for example, if David was put
on a personal action notice
and may leave the company, so,
but also started downloading a whole bunch
of data on his laptop.
Maybe those two things are related
and we need to have some kind
of visibility between those.
And then lastly, we think you
need to be able to orchestrate
and automate everything
because the number of threats
coming at you are too high.
So, anyway, just in
those two slides, right,
that was Zero Trust, the
three core principles.
And then here's how we
can operationalize it
and think about it today.
All right.
So we have set up EX and
we have set up ZT, right.
And now let's talk
about how ZT can improve
the EX part.
So, there are, so the
pandemic happened, right.
And nobody was prepared
except for, I guess,
the home, the people who
are already remote workers
were prepared.
But, but Andrew, I don't know
if you wanted to speak to
some of these stats here.
- Yeah. So I think, if you
weren't thinking about Zero Trust and
how to implement that to
improve user experience in 2019,
you were definitely thinking
about it by the end of 2020, right?
Because this data that has
left the data center that is
now traveling to home network
to personally own devices.
It's never coming back, our personal,
or your Forrester's take
on the overall increases
that 300% expected increase
and permanent full-time remote workers.
So in the US that means one in five
typically it's on a yearly basis.
7% of US workers are full-time.
We anticipate it's going to be 21%.
And so you're going to have
to deal with this challenge
like it or not.
That's the way that the world is moving.
And most organizations are
going to be hybrid in nature.
We've said 60% of
organizations will be hybrid
but that means that
you're still gonna have to
protect that data wherever it goes,
whether it's on your corporate
network or whether it's in,
a coffee shop, or in a
library, or at someone's home,
it's never coming back.
And so we knew that people
weren't really prepared
for this 47% responded to our survey.
And the early part of COVID saying,
our infrastructure, wasn't
ready to handle this.
And so we've had so many
different conversations,
both David and myself on
what are those technology investments
that you can make to one,
improve your security
and make it more flexible
for remote work environment.
But two, also enable someone to be very
productive in basically any circumstance
- Perfect segue into this first thing.
So here's the first example we have
of how Zero Trust can improve EX.
And as Andrew was hinting
that less than half
of the organizations that
we surveyed said that
they were equipped to handle
so much remote, remote work.
And guess who all of
those people who are not
equipped to handle calls,
they called Andrew and myself.
And I basically sat on
the phone for months
at a time talking to people that said,
"Look our VP can't
just, can't handle this,
all this remote work."
And they want, can I
split tunnel my traffic?
Right. Can I just send all
of my internet bound traffic
out to the internet, but still
keep me keep my VPN going?
And that was a conversation
I had all the time
when they still have
that with clients today.
But I tried to tell them, you know what
that's suboptimal from
a security perspective
because while you may be improving
your employee's experience
with their internet browsing
you're actually providing a
tunnel for them to get infected.
And then for the malware to
go right into your perimeter.
So don't do that, right?
And so they would say, well,
what am I supposed to do?
The answer fortunately
was a technology called
Zero Trust network access.
So you may have seen this
prior to the pandemic,
it's called a Secure Remote Access
but it is applying Zero Trust principles
to be able to create some kind of access
that allows a remote worker to connect
to the on-prem applications
that they need, right?
So for many organizations
that I talked to,
the applications that
people use day to day
are ones that are, they're
up in the cloud, right?
They're the workdays of the
world, Salesforce, etcetera.
But they still have a
few on-prem applications.
And having a Zero Trust
network access was one
of the things that they were able to say,
"Okay, we're going to use this."
And maybe in combination
with cloud deliver
and secure web gateway, we'll
combine those two things.
And then our, all of
our remote workers are
will be unhindered by our VPN capacity.
And they'll have a mostly straight path
out to the internet while
still being protected.
But then when they want to come
into our on-prem to access,
whatever resources we still have on prem
that they can do so.
And so this is a
conversation they still have
with people every day.
And remember that we
started this research prior
to the pandemic, and then this was one
of the signature technologies
that happened, right?
And so very likely at your organization
you may already be doing this right.
If you signed up with one of the many
there's probably 30 vendors
that offer a solution like this,
or Microsoft itself offers
a solution like this.
You may already be doing this.
And ideally it works so well
that you don't even notice, right?
And that's what we're trying to get up.
Now, one of the things I wanted
to make clear here is that
if you are a security
professional and attending this
conference, very likely you are, right,
you might've been familiar with Zero Trust
for the last 10 years.
And you might've seen
that, it's been creeping
up in adoption, was popular
while it's become the sort
of defacto Mindshare
cybersecurity strategy.
You may have to look pretty far and wide
before you find somebody who's
actually implemented it, right?
And one of the things that was missing,
the Zero Trust was missing
was a clear business driver
for why to do it, right.
Many security professionals to say,
"I clearly recognize this,
this is a security strategy,
that's built around the theme
of reducing the threat surface."
And I totally get that.
That's great.
But how do I sell that?
How do I get the budget to do that, right?
What you actually need
was a business driver.
And here comes the biggest externality
of my entire career, the pandemic.
where everybody goes to work from home
and then nobody can get any work done.
And then somebody headboard is gone.
What, we're losing
millions of dollars a day
because none of our employees can work.
Why don't we adopt their trust?
Boom.
That's like, there's the business
driver that took this off.
So many companies today are sort of
they're dating Zero Trust by
using a Zero Trust
network access solution.
And before I, before
I move on here, Andrew
did you have any comments about this one?
- I would just say, thank you so much
for taking all the VPN
inquiries last year.
(both laughs)
- I was the new guy time.
I felt like
- You were missed their VPN last year.
- It was VPN, hail the VPN.
All right.
I think you might have some things,
we'll both have some things
to say about this one
but I'll let you start.
- Alright.
Okay. So, if we look back at some
of the drivers of engagement
for employee experience
one of the top ones is access to tasks,
critical information to do my job,
ability to get stuff that helps
me learn about my customers,
learn about my colleagues,
really just contribute to my company.
And the biggest thing that gets
in the way of this is the
traditional password and the,
especially with some of the
more difficult requirements
around password length and complexity
and how often you have to
shift out that password,
that can be a huge mess.
And especially when you start thinking
about a multi OS or
multi-device environment
where every time I
update a domain password
on my primary laptop, I have
to do it on my smartphone.
And every other thing
that I'm, that I'm using.
And so passwords are one
of the key areas that
you can start thinking
about as part of your Zero Trust strategy.
One, eliminate them
because they're less secure
than a passwordless
form of authentication.
And two, think about
reducing the cognitive load
for that employee, as they're thinking
about what is my password, I
know I changed it last week
but I don't remember what it is.
All of a sudden I'm super distracted
and can't focus on my most important work.
So when we think about sort
of modern Zero Trust security
with regards to the password,
obviously there's things
like multi-factor authentication,
which continued to be
highly asked about amongst
our clients, biometrics,
and device factors are also
a form that can help to
decrease that overall
need, facial recognition,
I think will be something important
once we get rid of the masks
- That was going great
till the mask thing.
- Yeah, it was going great.
- Lot more touch ID.
So the touch ID was a
perfect example of security,
helping, your finger was about
to touch that button anyway.
And so instead of having to enter a pin
like we used to have to
which just authenticate you based
on the button you are
about to touch and same
with the, face ID was
supposed to be was instead
of putting in an eight digit pin,
you were going to lift this
up toward your eyes anyway,
so that that's the example,
but I wanted to rewind people.
So some of the older
people might remember this
remember back in the late 90's,
when we had different passwords
for everything, right?
And the average person who worked
at a corporation might have to
remember like 17 or 22
different passwords.
And these things would
expire every 90 days.
And so people would just be,
"Well, I can't remember 19 passwords."
I'm just gonna use the
same password, right?
Think of how far we have
come since those days.
Right. I never, I worked
in the whole SSO business
for a long time and it's such a pain.
It was awful.
But now, because of the standards, like,
OWWA, and Federation SAML
and all that stuff, Andrew was saying,
"Oh, I have to change my
password because we all have,
many of us only really have one password."
That's like a corporate password.
And here we are right on
the verge of talking about
could we get rid of
this last one password?
And sometimes I think we
forget how far we have come.
How far we have come, like,
when you go sit down
to your computers today
you might be faced with, here's my 15 apps
and you don't have to log
into each one of them, right.
If you have to log in to
a single one separately,
you might be like,
"God, that's so old timey
who does that anymore."
Right? At least that's what
you should be thinking.
So we've actually come a huge way.
Now we're talking about
could we get rid of this last password?
Right. And so if you
remember back in those days
people couldn't remember 19 passwords.
They forget them.
They have to call somebody.
And that person would be like,
"Oh, I'm on call for
two weeks, after hours
just so I can reset passwords."
And it was the number
one, it was the number one
IT tickets for like over a decade.
And now we have gotten to the point
where we almost reduced it.
And, I would like to celebrate the fact
that we've come so far and we're right
on the verge of being able to say
no more passwords, right?
Okay, okay. I know we can talk
about this snowballed name
and I'm going to move to the next one
just so we don't run out of time.
- Alrighty.
- Alright.
- So I start off with this one
since it's very end-user
computing focus here.
So trends in endpoint management
and endpoint security specifically,
David showed the graph of
different elements that interact
with data in a Zero Trust model.
One of them is devices.
And I think we haven't
paid as much attention
to devices in the Zero Trust model,
as David mentioned it's
very network focused,
but I think we need ought to
be paying more attention
to a modern security
and endpoint management
strategy when it comes
to those devices overall.
And so there's two major trends that
I want to highlight here
that are Zero Trust oriented
that also have an impact
on the user experience.
And the first one is this
endpoint management strategy.
So if you're not familiar with this
certainly go reach out
to your EUC, a leader
across the aisle over the next week or so,
just to learn a little bit about
modern management of endpoints.
And so the traditional way of doing this,
if you're not familiar is
domain joining the endpoint,
pushing out patches, updates,
all of that stuff via the VPN,
and using an on-prem endpoint
management tool in order to
do policy configuration,
all of that stuff.
And that is completely changing.
And it's moving very
much towards the cloud,
utilizing mobile device
management, APIs, instead
of kind of your traditional
group policies to do management.
And so this overall shift
actually has a pretty big impact
on the overall user experience.
First of all,
it doesn't require you to domain join
and receive all your patches
via a VPN, which is by the way
as we already mentioned
already completely full
as a result of the pandemic.
And so if you're pushing
out patches that way
it's going to have a
really terrible impact
on the user experience.
If I can push that out over the air
it gives me more flexibility to ensure
that I can patch those end points.
Remotely, people can work
effectively in a mobile setting.
And then the second area is
that it gives me an
opportunity to bring in
different types of devices.
The APIs from the major
OEM operating systems,
are consistently getting
more and more granular
and our ability to go out and just hook
into those APIs and manage those devices
over the internet is just getting better.
And so we have an opportunity
to provide more autonomy
and choice for the user
by making the shift
towards modern management.
And then the second area that I would call
out here is a major
shift that we're seeing
with endpoint security
point products, and a lot
of that starting to shift into
the native operating system
and leveraging less bolt-on technologies
third party tools, and more
of the native operating
system security capabilities
and forced through say an MTM
or unified endpoint management tool.
And so, a lot of that has
to do with performance
of the device.
I talked with one of our
US, government clients.
And they came to me and said,
on average it takes employees
20 to 30 minutes to boot
up a workstation every single morning
because the amount of security
agents that we have loaded
onto the device, right.
That's just too much,
that is too much to enable productivity
at the beginning of the day, right.
And so the more that we
start to embrace the sort
of native security functionality,
the less of an impact those
third-party tools have.
And so all of this is in
the name of reducing some
of this complexity you see down here,
some of the biggest
information, security challenges
in organizations are complexity
of the IT environment.
So if you can expand
and modernize your endpoint
management security strategy
you're also going to have an
impact on the user experience.
So David, anything to add there?
- Yeah. Just, I'm going
to echo what you said.
And I recognize that some
of what we just talked
about there was like, well
this will definitely make the IT people
their jobs easier and better,
but especially that move to native,
where we're seeing that on
the security side as well.
And that's not be recommending that.
I'm just saying a lot of our clients
that we talk to seem to be opting
for the native device security,
which appears to be getting better
to the point where they're happy with it.
And it enables higher productivity.
And at the end of the day,
that's what it's all about.
Okay, so we have provided
in the very last slide,
I think it's like two from now
some links to a lot of the reports
especially the report
that we mentioned here,
enhance the employee
experience with Zero Trust.
And we recommend that people can,
if you are an IT ops,
you might want to reach
out to your security people
even more so than you have been already
because if they're not,
they may or may not be
on board with this concept of
right security done, right.
Can actually improve productivity, right.
They may look at you like, that's crazy
but you just tell them
to watch this video,
like these two guys at
Forrester figure this all out
and they have the numbers to prove it.
So what do you think people
should do this month, Andrew?
- So I think some of the
major things you can do
are one, figure out all the
device agents that you have
for endpoint management and security.
See if there's overlap between them.
Do you have duplicates?
What does that look like?
What is the impact on
the overall performance?
That can be a quick way
to get some performance
improvements overall,
especially if you feel like you're covered
from a security perspective.
The other thing that we hear a lot about,
especially during the
pandemic is employee listening
and really giving a chance
for the employee to,
give feedback around the experience.
And so this is something that you could do
with employees directly,
or you could do with,
IT ops to really discover,
how are these security policies
actually impacting productivity?
How, what sorts of things are you running
into on a daily basis?
What's super frustrating to
the point where you need to
get up and leave your
desk, because you're so mad
about not being able to
access something, right?
So get that user feedback upfront
and that'll help prioritize some areas
over the next three months.
David, you want to take this one?
- Sure.
So we're working with a lot of clients
who are either doing the
digital transformation, right.
Or selling already in the
movement into the cloud.
But they're also looking strategically
and how, because remember what Andrew said
about remote work increasing by 300%,
there's you cannot treat remote workers
as second class citizens anymore
whatever you do for them,
you actually have to do,
whatever you do for the non-work at home,
new on-prem people you have
to do for everybody, right?
So treat, I guess the theme
of that is treat everyone
the same and give them the best security
and employee experience that we can
in order to keep up
their, their productivity.
All right. So I hope you can read this,
but if you can't hear,
here's our email addresses
ahewitt@forrester.com and
dholmes@forrester.com.
And then the last slide here
you'll see is the links,
to a lot of the research
that we referenced.
And I just wanted to
thank everybody for coming
to this talk, and I hope you
enjoy the rest of the show.
- Thank you everybody.
And thank you, David.