- Hi, I'm Chris Cronin
from HALOCK Security Labs.
Today I'm gonna be talking
to you about forecasting threats.
It's way easier than you think.
This is a topic that has
some controversy behind it,
some organizations and some
people say that we really need
to evaluate the likelihood of threats
using classic probability modeling
and some say there's no
use in doing it at all.
I'm gonna show you
today that it's actually
fairly easy to think about likelihood
once we have access to some public data.
So let's jump right into it.
What we're using as a premise here
is that we're predicting not
so we can know the future
but so that we can change it.
That's the idea of what we're going for.
So let's forecast your threats
so that you can change your
future to the one you want.
Knowing your future threats
means securing your
likeliest threat factors.
It means prioritizing
the likeliest threats
that create the most harm
and then spending no more
than you need to secure your organization
which is exactly the
definition for risk management.
So let's come to a common
agreement on what we mean by risk.
So however you evaluate risk
and there are many
different ways to do that.
There are at least two components,
there's some aspect of likelihood
and some aspect of impact.
Risk management means we're reducing risk
by reducing either likelihood or impact.
Today we're focusing
primarily on likelihood.
Now I'm most known for focusing on impact.
I invented the Duty of
Care Risk Analysis method,
DoCRA standard and wrote CIS RAMs,
CIS risk assessment method,
which both use this way
of looking at impacts not just to you
but to others who might be harmed,
to be sure that any security
controls you're having
in place create a burden that's
in balance with the risk.
That's what regulators
and litigators look for.
So we focus a lot on impact but people ask
what do you do for likelihood?
So that's what we're focusing on today.
Keep in mind too, that the
CIS risk assessment method
it's got version 2.0 coming
out in a couple of months,
we're estimating June, keep your eye on,
the work we're doing
here in this presentation
putting data together
and using it to automate
the way we calculate
likelihood will be packaged
in this CIS RAM tool for free.
Now CIS RAM tool that I was starting
with an implementation
group one usage so it's
organizations that don't
have a lot of resources.
It's a very simplified risk analysis
but you'll be able to see exactly
how what we're doing here, the
mechanics of it and the data
behind it actually works
inside a risk analysis.
So keep your eye out for
CIS RAM 2.0 June 2021
is when it looks like that's coming out.
So how do we use likelihood
and risk analysis?
Well, whenever we consider the potential
of harm of an incident,
we think both of impact
and likelihood of foreseeable threats.
How do we estimate likelihood
of foreseeable threats though?
Well, what if we think about a likelihood
as an aspect of tendency not probability,
I know that 2.7% chance
of having this much
of an impact is what I'm
facing for this risk.
But what if you look at
things like tendencies
like what kinds of breaches tend to happen
in organizations like mine?
If you can do that you need the data.
So where do you get the data
about tendencies of impacts?
Well, today we're gonna talk
about the various community database.
There are other sources of
public data for threat analysis
but what the various
community database is,
it's a publicly available data set.
It's provided by Verizon,
the same team who created
the data breach investigation report
but they create a subset of that data,
a representative set that
allows us to use that data
as we want, it's updated
periodically around twice a year.
And it's very, very rich in data.
I don't know if you've seen
this thing, it's a monster.
If you look in the CSV version of it
you're gonna see almost 9,000 records.
And you're gonna see
more than 2000 columns.
Each record is an incident
and of those columns
is a whole lot of data about
the things that are featured
about each of the reported breaches.
Now you can be intimidated looking
at more than 2000 columns of data
but what Verizon has
done is they created sort
of a language that allows
us to look at clusters
of these columns that
have certain meanings,
interesting things about
the attack vectors.
How did the bad guys get in?
Attack methods, what
did they do to get in?
Assets, what assets did they hit?
The victims, characteristics
about the victims,
what kind of industry were they in?
Where were they?
Attackers, who were they?
Where were they from?
Lots of information about this.
So once you think about
the data in these clusters
the columns become easier
and easier to understand.
So how do you find tendency
in a database that is huge?
Well, you start by asking questions.
The questions I find really good answers
for it in the various
community database are,
how common are certain threat vectors,
the way that bad guys get it?
What is the commonality
of certain attack methods?
The things that they do to get in.
And what is the commonality
of certain compromised assets?
If we can find patterns and
we're going to find patterns
and we can start to
filter out by industry.
We start to see that
threats happen differently
depending on the industry
that's being attacked.
And we can find even patterns over time
because the various
data also has the years
that breach has happened.
So we can start to look at
trends, very interesting
but it allows us to have a new
kind of likelihood question.
We don't have to be locked
into this question of asking
when will we be breached and how?
And then move towards formalized
and sometimes for some
organizations is difficult
to use probability analysis,
but we can ask questions like
what is the likeliest
way I will be breached?
Assuming that we will
have a security incident,
how do organizations like
mine tend to be breached?
That helps me prioritize the
things that are most likely
to happen because we find probabilities
very difficult for people to implement.
And it's fairly controversial,
stolen information security
and because formatting
or forecasting based
on these tendencies is fairly
easy once you see the data
I'm gonna show you.
There are those who say
you can't predict cybersecurity threats.
But we don't wanna predict,
we're not going for accuracy.
What we want is to forecast,
we want to estimate
based on tendency so we can
prepare for those common events.
When you look at regulations and laws
and information security standards,
they want us to think
about foreseeable threats.
You're not saying you must be accurate.
And frankly we don't expect
that we will be accurate
but let's think about forecasting.
And besides cybersecurity does innovate
but not very much year over year.
There's a lot of
commonality year over year
and we'll discuss why.
In fact, if we were going
for accurate prediction
here's what our outcome would be.
Tell me if you like being
accurate with your risk analysis.
We were breached this year
and lost a million records
just as we predicted, that's accurate.
I don't know if I want accurate.
I want results from
risk managed forecasts.
Here's how that reads, we
saw that personnel tend
to breach data by
accident in our industry.
So we remove their access
to the Crown Jewels.
Their eventual error
released much less data
than we originally estimated,
that's thinking in terms of forecasting,
in terms of a risk management idea.
I want to think about how
to reduce the likelihood
of the bad impact by looking
at how common in organizations
that are shaped like mine
have the kinds of problems
they should be addressing.
I'm gonna show you how we
pull this data together
and how we found it.
But before I show you the how
I'm gonna show you the result
this beautiful picture is all of the data
inside the various community database
of all industries and
all threatened vectors
and methods, attack
factors and attack methods.
What you see here is up to the top-left
personnel error and personnel misuse.
These are what HALOCK Security Labs,
My company calls a
cluster, a threat cluster.
When we see hit index
that's just HALOCK use of the
various community database.
We blend the data and
melded in certain ways
but personnel error as a cluster
and personnel misuse
have component threats.
Carelessness is a personnel error,
misdelivery is a personnel error,
device immediate loss
is a personnel error.
Personnel misuses, privilege abuse,
that's someone breaking a rule on purpose,
LAN misuse, data misuse,
misuse of the facility.
When you see this you're
gonna see undetermined vector
and undetermined method
but we see this a lot
in the various community database.
Don't let that disappoint you.
When people are doing forensic analysis
and sending their data to
the Verizon team for Veris.
If they don't have data it's very likely
because the organization that was hit
didn't have good log management.
Didn't have good log correlation.
Didn't have good alerting.
So organizations never
knew what the cause was.
So the forensics folks
send records up saying,
we don't know because
we don't have the data.
So that stands in as a very good proxy
for organizations that don't
have good log management,
good log correlation,
good situational awareness
or good forensics, so keep that
in mind as you look at that.
But again, this is all
industry is all time.
That's kind of interesting, but let's look
at what happens when they
look at a specific industry.
Now, retail looks different
from everybody else.
Again, this is retail over all times.
Physical facility is the leading
issue as a threat cluster
and then hacking systems and
then physical asset loss.
And then we get the personnel misuse,
people breaking rules on purpose
and in personnel error,
making mistakes accidentally.
Why is physical facilities
such a big deal in retail?
Well, let's take a look at
what the component threats are,
tampering, disabled controls,
victim at facility, public facility.
These are all aspects of
point of sale scammers
which happened quite a lot at retail.
You're gonna say, well, wait a minute
isn't that double-counting
I got schema here
and I've got schema here.
Yes, it is double counting.
And it's very important to
double count when you're looking
for tendencies because
you're looking at causes
and methods and we can get rid of a cause
but the methods might still exist.
We're gonna have a
conversation after this,
it will be Q and A after this session
if you wanna have a conversation
about the appropriateness
of double counting, let's
have that conversation.
But now we start to see
that physical facility
matters a lot and then hacking
system matters a lot too
because retail has quite
a bit going on online.
What does it look like when we look
at public institutions over time?
Personnel error is really big.
Why is that?
Well, because public institutions,
government organizations are
an intensely person-to-person
one-on-one people handling
information about people business
People are handling a lot
of business information
about tax collection,
about property values,
about actions, about research.
Public institutions
have a lot of this data
but it's a lot of people
handling a lot of this data.
There's a lot of opportunity
for people to make mistakes.
Look how big misdelivery, what is that?
Those are things like tax bills.
Those are billing for VA,
it's a lot of people just making mistakes.
But when you have a lot of
person-to-person business
you have a lot of opportunity
to personnel error,
that's where the common
attacks are gonna be.
And malware, but that tells you something
about the systems that are
being operated in number one
or number two, the methods
that are being used
by state actors who are trying to get
into our government systems, right?
So we have a couple of glimpses
of what we mean by looking
at that data to see trends
and to see tendencies and threats.
So how do we actually
put that data together?
Well, we start by knowing
how our business operates.
What do we mean by how
our business operates?
And that turns into this
concept of a threat landscape
because the way we do
business, where we do business
is where we get attacked.
Then we get threat data
we'll show you how to do that
from the various community database.
We aligned threat data
to our threat landscape
and then we organize the data to see where
the threats have recently been.
So we get a sense of where
to look at next, all right?
So we're gonna walk you
through all those steps
starting with knowing how
your business operates.
So we're gonna look at a
couple of examples here.
What we're looking at here
is in terms of hospitals
where do we expect the
sensitive data to be?
Well, quite a bit of physical
because in healthcare
you go to a place, you go to a
hospital, you go to a dentist
you go to a pharmacy, you go
to places for your healthcare
and you physically need to
be there for the most part.
Well, how about systems?
There are definite systems
and we're not talking about the
number of records somewhere.
We're talking about the interfaces
that the business has with the world.
The opportunities to be a breached based
on the opportunities
are based on the amount
of work you do at a kind of asset.
Personnel, lots of personnel
at hospitals, the doctors,
the nurses, the clinicians,
the pharmacists, the lab techs
the people who are doing
billing and collection.
A lot of people handling a
lot of individual records.
This is tremendous opportunity
for personnel error in healthcare.
How about for banking?
Well, physical is pretty big.
We tend to think about
banks a lot more and more
being finance tech, a lot of systems
but think about what your
interfaces are with banks.
ATM's are everywhere, the ubiquitous,
bank branches everywhere.
Personnel, this is still a very big
person-to-person kind of business.
Yes, systems have the most records
but we interface with
the systems in banking
much less than we do with the
physical and the personnel
just because of where those interfaces
are with the public and their customers.
Information services is
very different from those.
I have never been to an
AWS office in my life
but I've been in AWS systems
a lot without even knowing.
Systems are tremendously predominant.
And the personnel who manage those systems
are tremendous and predominant.
So information services
has a very different business profile
than the other businesses we looked at.
What does the data teach
us when we look at.
Well, as you're about to
see your threat landscape
is where you conduct your business.
So let's understand what
our threat landscape
is now that we've looked at our business.
Hospitals personnel took the lead
and then physical facility and systems
because that's where the business is done.
Let's look at clinical
healthcare of all time
from the various community database.
Personnel misuse is in the lead, right?
And then personnel error.
There's a lot of opportunity
for people to have sensitive information
and now physical asset
loss, data, immediate theft
and then undetermined factor
because the hospitals were not aware
of how people lost those assets
because they were not
connected to anything.
There was no RSA connection
to a device, the USB device
on the system to track it, they're just
there's just an inability to
track a lot of this stuff.
And then only in social engineering
which is tremendously personnel
and only after that, did we
get the physical facility
where we have a patient files?
So what's the issue that
we're getting to here
that we see with clinical healthcare.
The incidents happened
with the business, right?
How about banking?
Physical took the leave
here with personnel
is a lot of predominance
of ATM's and bank branches
and certainly physical facility.
And the reason for physical
facility being predominant
is similar to retail, take a look,
again, tampering, disabled controls
victim of facility surveillance.
This is just like card skimming at retail.
Retail banks look much
more like retail stores
than retail banks look like
other financial services firms
even though they got a lot of money, why?
Because the interfaces with
the public are so similar.
It's the conduits by which
we interface with the public.
It's the presence of the asset
that becomes the threat vector.
This is something that
statisticians jokingly call
interocular, meaning you
don't need complex analysis
it hits you between the
eyes when you see it.
This is the commonality of a banking
because the banking assets
are this much common
to the public, information services,
you can guess what's gonna happen next.
Hacking system, hacking
web are taking the lead
because that's where the opportunity is.
That's where the largest
presence of that business is.
And then after that personnel error
by things like misconfiguration
and carelessness.
The people who are configuring the systems
that end up getting attacked.
So if you're an information
systems organization
and you're trying to think
about where are we gonna
get hit most, I'm gonna pay less attention
to my physical presence,
which is barely an issue
and a whole lot of attention to my system.
And I better come to a
determination very quickly
that I've got to get good
log management in place
because most people in my
position do not know the causes
of the breaches that happened
in their organization,
because they're log management,
log correlation alerting,
forensics were not up to snuff.
So this is what we mean by interocular.
It just hits you between the eyes.
The threats are happening
with the businesses.
If you look at the various
community database,
you'll see a lot of interesting things
but you're gonna see a lot of industries.
You'll very likely find
yourself in there somewhere.
This is just a sample of them,
but if you think of an industry
they had a breach there in the
various community database.
So let's test this hypothesis.
I've been leading you down a path
I've been telling you,
well, here's the kind of business it is.
And here are the kinds of threats,
but let's try this out yourself.
I'm not telling you what business this is.
I'm just telling you what kinds of threats
are most common and least
common in this business.
And then we'll quiz you tell me.
You tell me what you think this is?
So personnel error is a big deal.
They don't know what causes most of them
but there's a lot of
misdelivery which means
there are people handling
a lot of sensitive data
that they're supposed to
be sending to other people
and they're doing it
wrong, personal misuse.
People have a lot of
access to a lot of data.
What kind of business is that?
Let's take a look at something
that's very, very uncommon, skimming.
So there isn't a lot of on-site purchasing
going on in that business.
So what kind of business is that?
Is that a fast food chain?
Is it a financial advisor
or is it a hotel chain?
think about where the risks are?
Well, it's a financial advisor
because there's lots of
one-on-one contact with customers.
So there's lots of opportunity
for misuse and error.
Most employees are handling
personal information.
There's lots of delivery and distribution
of personal information
that's just being misdelivered
and there's very rare
on-site transactions.
So you can actually look
at a trend landscape
and guess what kind of organization it is.
Even if you don't know
the name of the company,
you can say this looks like
an X kind of organization
because the information is
that well tied to the industry
which brings me to this idea.
One of my favorite quotes,
history doesn't repeat
itself but it rhymes
what's happening is that organizations
because they have certain business methods
they have certain business processes
their assets pretty much
your stable year after year,
retail took a long time to go
from brick and mortar to online
They eventually got
there, but it was slow.
Hospitals took a long time
to go from paper to systems.
It took a long time, but they got there.
It just takes a long time for an industry
to change the way it's shaped.
So your risks from a
previous year look a lot like
your risks from the following year
but there are some things
that actually give you
a reason to watch trends.
Let's get the threat data,
where do we get it from?
Well, I'm talking to the
various community database
but there are other ways to get data
that's sourced from the public.
I've got some listed here that are good
for tactical prep and response.
What I mean by that is looking
at things going on wire.
So you're gonna have a lot of variation
day over day, sometimes hour over hour.
What threats are happening a
lot in environments right now,
and how do they correlate
to our operations?
There's some good public data sources
and some good commercial tools
that allow this to happen.
I'm using Veris because
it's good for planning.
It's good for sketching out
what your budget should be this year
or next year or next year.
What are you focused on most?
Privacy rights clearing
house has a very skinny
set of data, very good
data, but much skinnier
than what you've seen in the
various community database.
And if you belong to an ISAC
you really should be involved
in threat information exchange.
But these are just some other places
where you can get public
data about these threats.
Now let's align threat data
to our threat landscape.
How do we do that?
Well, remember this is the
Veris Community Database
and the CSV format 2000
or more columns wide, 9,000 rows deep.
What we're gonna do is ask
them the questions, right?
Now the questions that I find most helpful
are the ones that I have here in red.
Industries and sub-industries,
threat actions,
threat vectors and assets.
I can ask questions about size of breach
and financial impact but
you're gonna see very little
to correlate in, it is
very little information,
very little consistency.
There's a lot of very useful information
about what happens to whom.
And again, we're gonna questions.
We're not gonna dive into the data
before asking good questions.
We're gonna ask, how common
are certain threat vectors,
the way people get in, the commonality
of certain attack methods,
what they're doing to get in?
The commonality of certain
compromised assets,
what's being hit, what should I protect?
And then we're gonna
ask, how does this apply
to certain industries and
pluck mine out with a filter.
And then I'm gonna look
for patterns over time
and I'll show you how to do that.
I recommend if you're not
agile in probability analysis,
statistical analysis,
you're not using programs
like R to do this kind of analysis.
You're gonna want to pull
in the CSV file from Veris
and not the raw JSON files
but you're also gonna have
to get used to pivot tables in Excel
if you're not already proficient.
Pivot tables are ways to aggregate data.
So you can ask a question
like we have here
toward the middle denial of service.
You can look at a whole lot of
data, 9,000 records and say,
"how many times does the denial of service
come up from my industry?"
You get an answer 48,
pivot tables help you
do that kind of aggregation when you ask
certain questions about data types.
So get proficient with
those in pulling the CSV
if you're not capable and
good with statistics in R.
Now let's see where threats have been.
This gets very interesting.
Remember we looked at
clinical health over all time.
We sought a personnel misuse of a leader
and personnel error was next.
There are those of you in the audience
who would have said, I heard news
that ransomware is big in healthcare.
So why is malware and ransomware so small?
Well, this is overall
time and what we wanna do
and we're analyzing this data
because there's so much
data in that database.
We can do this kind of thing,
let's look at what happens year over year.
So we're gonna look at a five-year trend
of threat vectors in
healthcare environments.
2016 what we see is personnel
error taking the lead
just like we saw with that mass group
but then personnel misuses next
and then malware very common, right?
Now in 2017 keep an eye on personnel error
it went to second spot
and personnel misuse
to sort of switch rows 'cause
there are a lot of people
there is a lot of opportunity for people
to do the wrong thing on
purpose or by accident.
Malware stays in this third position.
In 2018, something interesting happens
while personnel error remains
up top malware drops down.
We don't know exactly why,
it's worth saying people
figured out that when you put
certain ransomware software in
you lay low, you take a
look at what's going on.
We think what we're seeing here
when we look at the data is the shift
of the very efficient ransomware
business, which it is now.
It's a whole industry that functions
in the business started to figure out
what to do in hospitals because watch
what happens in 2019, it rises to the top.
Ransomware takes over as the
leading cause of breaches
but personnel error stays in second place
because the people are
still handling this data
and they're still making mistakes with it.
Now we see that the
ransomware business maintains
its position because it works
as an efficient industry.
It maintains its tie, at
least in lead position
and personnel error remains upfront.
What are we seeing?
Yes, we did see a very quick innovation
but what we're also seeing
is a real clear message.
If we're in healthcare, we have
to realize we're targeting.
We have to see that this
is now the new pattern.
Malware is going to be
the continuing issue.
Personnel error is not to be neglected
because that's a constant
issue to be faced with.
Packing hacking web is starting
to become a bigger deal.
And we're starting to see that correlated
with a lot of other malware attacks.
And again, personnel misuse is almost high
with these other things.
It's very significant still
because people have access
to this personal information.
So now that we've taken a look at this,
we've got to ask a question,
how do I use this data
in a risk assessment?
I can't just say my risk is great
because the commonality is great
because I have to take care
of take into consideration
two other things how
capable are my controls
to fight those common attacks
and what is the impact
if something goes wrong?
Let's take a look at this.
When we see the data in the
various community database
and this beautiful tree
chart, it looks very nice.
that means there are
numbers behind it, right?
So this data at these threat clusters
there's one threat cluster per row.
It's associated with a great title boxes.
And we actually see the number of records
and we see the percentage
of representation.
How common are they in breaches?
You'll notice that these
percentages add up to more
than a 100% that's because
when you look at the data
in aggregate, you're
gonna see that an attack
has multiple threats occurring.
So someone made a mistake and
they misconfigured a system.
And the system was attacked.
There are multiple threats
and multiple threat vectors engaged.
So you're gonna get a higher than a 100%.
That's perfectly fine
because you wanna see where the noise is.
Now let's consider this.
If I'm looking at likelihood,
I should be looking the forecast
and I should be considering
control strength,
the stronger my control
the more it should mitigate the forecasts.
So if I have a way to say, look
at the maturity of controls
and I think about maturity of controls
in terms of how reliable that control is,
how much can I expect
that control the function
when they need it most?
And that's how we define
this maturity model.
Then that should mitigate controls.
If I were analyzing just
off the top of my head
and I'd say there's a very
common issue of personnel error,
and my ability to protect
that as inconsistent.
That's not good.
I clearly know I had to address that.
It might be overkill for me to innovate
and do root cause analysis
and continual improvement
over something that is rarely
present in reporting breaches
that might be overkill.
And it's important to
know where overkill is.
We don't wanna over-invest.
And in fact, when you look
at regulations and laws,
and I'll guide you into that
in a little bit in a moment,
you're not supposed to over-invest,
that's actually bad for you
in the public if you do,
it seems right to have
tested and corrected controls
for things that are as common as you know,
they happen say one in
every five breaches,
but now how do we correlate that?
So this is just a suggestion.
Now this is just conceptual,
there's no math behind it.
We'll call it a likelihood slide rule,
this is for the sake of this presentation.
What we're doing here is
looking at the percentages
on the top row, the
percentages of the commonality
of any one threat.
And then we're comparing those percentages
in groups of 20% chunks quintiles,
and we're associating each quintiles
with the maturity of the control.
So quintiles went through five associated
with maturity control one
Quintiles of one through five
with material control two,
and on for three, four, and five.
And what we're trying to say is,
if I can look at the
commonality of a certain attack
in my preparation for that,
I should be able to
prioritize a likelihood.
Now I'm not saying
I think this is probability
three out of five.
I'm saying in terms of my likelihood,
it's the third most likely
thing considering things
that might happen more commonly.
So this is a conceptual model.
There isn't a likelihood or
a probabilistic, I'm sorry,
there isn't a probabilistic
risk statistical model here.
It can be implemented.
You can use a log normal distribution
or a bell-curve distribution
depends on a few things.
And you can ask me when you would use each
in our discussion after this.
But if you're in an organization
where you have a control
against the threat that
happens in the fifth quintile,
it's the most common kind of attack.
And you only have a level
two maturity of the control.
You can expect that to
be a very common thing.
You're not saying this
risk is this likely occur,
you're saying this risk
when we have an incident,
it's most likely to happen this way.
And that's what we mean by tendencies.
If I'm well-prepared for something
that doesn't happen often
I've got a low tendency,
I've got a high tendency for it to occur
if I've got a very immature control
against a very common threat, right?
So now how do we bring it all together?
Well, I've talked earlier about
duty of care risk analysis
where you're looking at both
impacts and likelihoods,
but you're looking at the
impacts and likelihoods
that you could suffer and the impacts
and likelihoods of risks
that others might suffer.
There's a new definition
now for reasonable security.
It's something that
people have been clamoring
for it for years because regulations
and information security standards say
get to a reasonable control,
but lawyers and regulators and judges
have not come to agreement
on what this word means.
There's a paper released in
February that lays all this out.
And it asks us to look at the likelihood
of perceivable threats,
and the potential harm
that might come to ourselves and others.
And what we're doing in that case
is we're comparing one
state versus another to say
is the burden of a control
worth it given the difference
of the benefit so do
you wanna see something
whether there's a talk tomorrow called
your breach controls
may have been reasonable
where we talk about this
paper, it's very important.
If you're familiar with CIS RAM
you'll recognize that's you're gonna apply
duty of care risk analysis
to evaluate a risk by saying
what are the impacts to me and others?
And how likely would this be?
If you were reading CIS Ram and saying
but I'm frustrated and knowing
how to estimate likelihood
you now have the guidance for doing that.
And again, in CIS RAM 2.0,
you're gonna be able to use
an automated way to do like we had
from the various community data,
using the methods that I showed you,
and to compare a current
risk with a different risk
after a safe card to determine
whether it's a reasonable control.
So what are you gonna do next week
now that you know how to do this?
I recommend that you get into the data,
go to veriscommunity.net,
and download the CSV
again if you're not
doing statistical work.
And if you're very
comfortable with statistics
and you're using R,
then download the JSON
files and work back.
You're gonna want to be
proficient with pivots,
if you're using Excel,
it doesn't take a whole
lot of time to do that,
but it's really a good idea to use that.
You gonna start to see
where you can do aggregations and filters
Three months from now,
what should you be doing?
Well again, I highly
recommend that you use
this likelihood data
for your risk analysis.
We talked about a way to do
that with that slide rule.
If you look at CIS RAM
2.0 when it comes out
for implementation group
one in about June of 2021,
so a couple of months from now.
What you're gonna see is how
all of this stuff is automated,
and you should be able to use
it in your whole environment
to see if that works for you.
You can extrapolate a lot
once you see that information
it's for all, all breaches of all time,
but it'll give you a
sense of how you can use
that slide rule method
in your environment.
Don't worry about being exactly correct.
You're estimating using
a consistent method
and that's really important not just
for getting good management,
but showing that you applying to care.
You may want to work with a statistician
if you wanna get that slide
rule to be based on evidence,
there are ways to do that.
Again, I'm happy to talk to you
about that after this session.
What should you be doing in six months?
Well, you need to make risk analysis
a regular part of what you're doing
because those regulations
that you're operating under
are telling you to do exactly that.
You need risk-based
risk-based ways to look
at for the foreseeable threats
to be sure that what you're
paying attention to matters.
And also to be sure that whatever controls
you're putting in place are reasonable,
the burden is reasonable given the rest
of that you're facing.
And check the various
community database periodically
because it changes a
couple of times per year.
And it'll help you keep up to date.
I wanna thank you for taking part in this,
and watching the presentation.
I would really enjoy it,
if you come talk to me about
this immediately after,
we've got about 40 minutes in the chat,
then I welcome you, look
forward to seeing you there.