- My name is Steve Winterfeld,
I'm the Advisory CISO at Akamai.
And today, I wanted to take some time
and just share some of my experience
talking about some of the things
I see going on in industry
and across our customer bases,
and really, it's around you
know how to protect the edge.
Traditionally, when I
was building a program,
and as we're gonna to talk
about today is building programs
is I used to think about, you know,
the edge facing out my
network, and then the endpoint.
And today's you know, multi
infrastructure options,
that's actually becoming dated.
I have some customers that
everything is almost on the edge.
And so I wanna talk through
how to secure that edge.
I love this quote by
Michael Jordan, you know,
first of all, it is
absolutely a team sport,
everything we do in infosec.
Second of all, you know, we
used to think about going out
and getting the best
athlete, the best product,
for each individual capability.
And now I've got some customers
I've talked to an insurance
company the other day was 63,
talked to major Bank of
England they had 500,
which just blows my mind.
And so it's about, you know,
getting rid of some of that
complexity, and moving forward.
So let's jump in.
I wanna start talking about, you know,
the concept of really a
strategy versus a framework.
And I think they are different.
Some people will say, you know,
the framework is my strategy,
and I'll push back on that.
So let's say, you know, you go out there
and now you're in banking now
resiliency is becoming something
the federal auditors looking at.
So let's say I wanted to
have a resiliency strategy.
Why, you know, that
that can mean, you know,
a simple definition of
ensuring my customers
have access to their wealth
in a contested environment.
And what are the resources?
I could, you know, move to a CDM.
So they had, you know, good capacity,
I could move to something
that prevented a threat
like denial of service.
I could move to, you know,
a cloud infrastructure
that could scale and give me more capacity
by building more servers, you know.
So I think, as we think
through that though,
then the framework has
to come with something
that's a little bit different,
and that's more around,
you know, NIST 800-160
talks about resiliency,
or ISO 22301 talks about
business continuity,
and resiliency and security
or components within that.
So I think those are the frameworks.
And I think those are tools
we use to get to the strategy.
And in fact, one of the things
I'll talk about today is
we're gonna recommend an analyst strategy.
And I would be careful, analyst framework,
I would be careful calling it a strategy
because then you can be
held to by an auditor
to doing everything within that framework.
If you call it an analytical
tool, which is appropriate,
since it's from an
analytical organization,
then you can just implement
things that are in accordance
with your strategy.
And so you know, let's look
at some other frameworks
real quick here.
We've got a number of them.
The first is, you know,
government base NIST.
The one second the bottom,
mitre is semi government,
it's government sponsored.
I'm a huge advocate of the mitre framework
is a way to measure the
maturity of your SOC.
We've got some over here to the right
HITRUST similar to PCIs
and external paid for auditing capability,
COBIT is an audit capability
framework you can use.
So there are a number of these,
we're gonna to focus today on
a two (indistinct) edge based.
Forrester, Zero Trust Edge,
SASE, the Secure Access Service Edge.
And that actually came out
in 2019, in a paper called
the Future Network
Security is in the Cloud.
And if you wanna access that paper,
you can get it on Akamai
or a number of other sites.
And of course, with Zero Trust Edge
has a great blog that anybody can get to
that kind of outlines
their thought process.
But these are a couple
tools I wanna focus on it.
And we're really focused
on the Gartners today.
I think it's gaining a lot of (indistinct)
similar to Forrester's
Zero Trust 10 years ago,
we're still talking about that,
because it's something the
industry was already doing.
And I think the SASE framework
is just hitting us at a
time where it makes sense,
'cause we're already
moving in that direction.
And then the last one on here
is something a little
bit outside security,
but I think with insecurity
should look at those, you know,
what is the cost of doing business?
What are some of these
other other frameworks
we should be paying attention to?
So as we work across the
stakeholders and partners,
we're talking in the same language.
So let's talk about the SASE framework.
And I love the saying that,
name SASE all day as much as you will.
And so, you know, it
is about the benefits.
And so the first thing we
wanna do is reduce complexity,
while actually gaining
more situational awareness
by being on one platform,
you're getting that integration up front.
Simple vendor management equation.
You know, if I think about one customer
managing 500 vendors,
they're spending a lot of their
time in vendor management.
And so if I can cut that number in half,
regardless of it is.
And if I'm a small company
with two employees,
and 15 vendors is a lot of vendors.
And so if I can cut that down,
it just makes life easier for everybody.
You know, staffing.
I can't keep increasing my staff
and finding the skills quite honestly
is making it hard in the first place.
And so I wanna look at
something that, you know,
instead of having four security tools
with one engineer managing four
and barely being able to keep
them patched and optimized,
now I have one engineer
managing one platform,
able to do a much better job.
So I think there's some benefits there.
And then finally, you know,
reducing latency and
improving enforcement,
by collaborating with the network side.
And we're gonna take a look at that here.
So we have is, we have the
ability for the framework
to include both the network
side and the security side.
And so we're looking at,
I'll give you an example
from my past, it's one
of my favorite stories is
(indistinct) done,
I had my program in place.
And then I found out
some of the applications
I'm protecting, were being
moved to public cloud.
And so now I'm scrambling to say,
how do I get the controls
into this particular cloud?
How do I make sure that
I'm able to meet my audit requirements,
you know, it just sent me into
a scramble to protect those.
Because we weren't really
tightly integrated with IT.
We've all had this experience
of being pulled in too late.
But this is an effort to
kind of get in front of that.
And so as you look to the
left hand of the screen,
you have all those network capabilities,
Software-Defined WAN and
Content Delivery Network.
On the other side, you have all
those security capabilities,
you know, Cloud Security
Brokers, Secure Web Gateways,
Zero Trust Network Access,
web and application firewalls,
you know, cloud based firewalls,
secure DNS, remote browser isolation.
If you look at the broader list,
there's probably between
10 and 15 capabilities listed there,
that you should think about integrating
all both sides of this into one platform
to get that complete integration.
So now, let's take a step back.
And you know, we said okay,
we've got a framework,
it talks about the edge,
how do we define that edge?
How are we gonna come to
consensus on what that looks like?
And so what I wanna look at here
is just the ability for
us to say, you know,
you can have the edge and
still be in the data center.
There are some infrastructure,
some industries,
that just makes sense to
stay in the data center.
There are others that
are gonna go into Cloud,
they may go into multi cloud,
they may go into private cloud, a mix.
And so you know, what does that look like?
And there are others that are moving
straight out to the edge.
You know, you've heard
the term edge compute.
If you're thinking about, you know,
even if we go back to
cloud, you have you know,
infrastructure as a cloud,
you have data storage,
you have functions, or
running code snippets,
what we call serverless.
Some of the serverless are
going straight to the edge,
and they're doing more
and more distributed.
And so as you think of
these different concepts,
you have to say, what
does edge mean to us?
Am I gonna, you know, protect the edge,
protect the network, protect the endpoint?
How am I gonna protect the edge?
What does that consist of?
And so as you get your arms around that,
I think that really helps
you then, be able to say,
what are the requirements to secure it?
What is the strategy I'm
gonna go about to do that?
And so next, let's kind of say
what are some of those architectures
that might be involved.
And so the first architecture
is kind of a content delivery.
Now that was one of those more
than (indistinct) concepts.
And so if you're building into
this, what are the threats?
How do we deal with that?
And how do we build towards this?
And so if you have a lot
of web facing capabilities,
be the APIs or web pages,
this may be a good concept to think about.
Now, again, it's not gonna the
only thing you think about,
there's just one architecture.
But as you talk to the networking side,
this will be part of it, you know,
are they gonna use something
like content delivery?
Are you really worried about
denial of service attacks?
You know, again, going back to the example
of wealth management,
people need help access
to their bank account.
And so are you gonna focus on, you know,
availability being extremely high?
And so are you gonna do some
kind of scrubbing center
or something to mitigate DDoS?
'Cause that's a high threat.
And then, you know, ultimately DNS,
so people can find things,
where people can find you,
how are you gonna protect that?
How are you gonna optimize that?
So these are some samples of
things for us to think about,
as we say, you know,
we've defined the edge,
now we need to talk about
the different architectures
involved in the edge and others, you know,
going back to Software Defined WAN,
there are other opportunities
to have a discussion here.
But this is just a sample
of the kind of things
we should think about.
As we think about those, you know,
it's always good to crosswalk
those to the threats
we're most worried about.
And so, you know, first of
all what are you protecting,
kind of mapping to the
architecture before (indistinct).
And then, you know,
what is the requirement,
you know, as a performance
as a just access?
You know, what are we concerned about?
Or where are we willing to take risk?
And then, you know, which
infrastructure should we use?
So, as it everything,
I think this is an excellent opportunity
to make sure your red teams involved,
or your penetration test
team or your SOC team.
Whoever's in charge of
bringing that threat
to the conversation
to make sure you're building
something that is secure
and meeting the needs up front.
And so, you know, the next
thing we wanna talk about
is kind of these different models,
as we tie back to the
(indistinct) architecture
and all that is,
we now need to go look at
what our business model is.
'Cause ultimately, you know,
when I talk about the security strategy,
the security strategy should be a subset
of the business strategy,
the security architecture
should be a subset
of the business model
we're gonna be using.
And so you know,
different industries are
doing this differently,
we're coming out,
some will continue to
lean into remote work,
but even remote work is different.
I mean, we're back to the challenge
of somebody being in a hotel,
or a coffee shop, or an airport.
And as that starts to
happen more and more,
I think the traditional challenges
of people (indistinct) will expand,
'cause now you're on more and
more potentially untrusted
or compromised networks.
And so as we're looking
forward to this, you know,
are we gonna go to what I call more of a
location agnostic architecture,
are we gonna stick with our heavy branch?
You know, you get the main office,
and then you got bank branches,
or you know, you've got you
know, these sub components
that are physical places,
that you're mirroring your infrastructure.
Are we gonna stay in this more, you know,
distributed remote workers
and have each worker,
or each city, you know,
somehow be a thinner branch
and smaller requirements,
'cause we're not protecting quite as much
depending on how we have them coming in.
And then finally, you know,
we've got something that
is leaning away from this
more in the cloud architecture.
And so you see different
security components
based on managing risk and
your business processes.
And so you know, if you have
somebody that is simply doing
administrative work, they may
need fewer security tools,
than somebody that's working, you know,
a developer on your crown jewel
with all your intellectual property.
Some of this will be
very compliance based.
It may be regionally compliance based,
it may be compliance from
industry or privacy here,
all sorts of things.
So part of this goes back to you know,
how are we matching up
to the business model.
And it's something we need
to start leaning into is
one of those internet of
things we're trying to protect,
where are they coming up?
Just the other day, I took my car in
and they were like, have
you been here before?
Yes, they connected to the car,
pulled up everything from diagnostic,
my name, all my information,
never even asked me who I was,
but just focused on interacting with me
through the data they pulled off the car.
And that data included any
alerts that I wasn't aware of
that they may wanna have to
have called me before later.
And so you know,
what of my information is
on that little pad there,
the tablet they're using.
Is my credit card information is there
in my personal life information on there.
You know, protecting the customer
is certainly tied to a device
that may not have gone
through the security review.
So what are those internet of things
that we have to protect.
And so just something to think through
as we continue to do this crosswalk.
So now I wanna jump into a group of slides
that are really going to be text heavy.
The temptation is to read
through all the slides,
ignore me while I'm talking.
But I wanna say that, you know,
I built these and I built this whole thing
for you to be able to
go back and look later
to use as a tool, scribe this information,
and then build a program
or use it to take a review
of where your program is today.
And so there's a lot of text
here that you can go back,
pull up the slides,
and then scribe this
information and use it.
So we'll dive straight into here
to the first one (indistinct) backups.
If you look (indistinct)
you know, analyst paper
and another number of factors
as much longer than this,
I wanted to talk to the ones
that I think are the most critical.
And obviously, the holy
grail of security is,
you know, finding that
situational awareness,
knowing what's happened real time.
The minimize the dwell time of
any threats on your network.
And so what we have here is, you know,
how does this tie into
the rest of your system?
Is this, you know, a way
for you to get visualization
and situational awareness rapidly,
defense in depth obviously,
you know, classic.
I wanna jump into two
of these upfront though,
and that is really
resiliency and segmentation.
So everything we've been
talking about is consolidation,
and getting rid of complexity.
And here I'm talking about two concepts
that let's say, let's
make things more expensive
by having multiple capabilities,
some kind of a resiliency,
and let's do segmentation and
to make things more complex.
And so these are kind of,
I call them the yin and
the yang here to explore,
how are we gonna do this.
You know, redundancy and resiliency
are two different things.
So it doesn't mean you have
to have two of something,
it doesn't mean you have to double down,
it means it has to be able to again,
work in a contested environment.
You have to have
components of your network
and security capabilities
that are gonna respond real time,
ideally in an automated safe
way to ensure that access,
or productivity, or whatever
your business model is.
And so just need to
think about that upfront.
So you don't take away
some of what we're
trying to build towards.
And then segmentation.
You know, the classic
is VPN speed, you know,
segmenting VPN is great
'cause you reduce your risk.
You know, we talked about upfront
that your trust network access,
typically, there are two ways to approach
that micro segmentation
or network layer access,
you know, going straight
into the application,
benefits to both of those.
But as you talk through
this, having done this,
you know, when you have
an auditor come in,
and you say, well, I have that segmented,
and then they want
evidence of segmentation,
and then somebody does segmentation wrong
and you have data spillage.
And can so, worth considering
how to minimize this,
how to take things out
of scope where you can,
as a technique to minimize
what you have to segment,
and just think through
how to not lose some of
the benefits you gained.
And then the last one, I'll
emphasize on this is staffing.
I like to work with a vendor
that can give me (indistinct)
expertise on demand,
or maybe help me search for a project
that I need extra help with,
and then they can fade off
after I've accomplished that goal.
So, you know, when you
think you're staffing both,
how are you gonna minimize your staffing
and as you work with vendors,
how are you gonna be able to
leverage on demand staffing.
Next, I wanna give you
a kind of a checklist
of what I think are some of
the critical capabilities.
Up front, we just had a talked about
what the corporation needs to do
(indistinct) from the vendor,
and then a couple at the
end talking about you know,
the future and other
considerations to have.
So upfront, you know,
what are my requirements?
What's my edge look like,
we talked about that.
Then here in the middle, it is, you know,
what are the services do they offer,
you know, geographically?
And this is a huge component for me.
What are the compliance requirements?
I just need to understand, you know,
if you're in the United
States for privacy,
it's different by state,
if you're International,
it's different by country.
You've got somewhere
they're talking about,
you know, where data can reside,
inside or outside the country.
You have different definition of
what is included in privacy.
You know, and so, as you
work through all this,
you want a vendor that
is going to pay attention
to that for you, or you're
gonna take care of that.
And this is an example
of where we talked about
it being a team sport.
You may need to pull in
the privacy or the legal
and get those reviews on a
one of those requirements
actually look like.
You know, how mature are they?
How are they gonna be around?
Do they deliver on the roadmap?
Is this a company I'm gonna
be wanting to work with
long term?
You know, the smaller companies,
are they gonna be bought
by another company
and then they fade out?
And there's just so many
things to think about here
in the big picture.
And then as we look forward, you know,
what are the emerging threats
that aren't in the SASE framework?
An example I'll use is kind
of that JavaScript threat.
You know, we have a lot
of JavaScript on the edge,
the SASE framework as it comes to you
doesn't really talk about protecting that.
And with major current threat
out there, another concept.
So one of those emerging threats,
how do I add that in, again,
pulling in your threat team
to try to talk through that?
And then ultimately, it
comes down to efficiencies.
You know, what is the cost,
and what is a benefit
to my risk portfolio?
And so then the next capability,
I think is for me really important,
which is you know, I always think of,
as it is and to be, when
I'm building up a program.
And so we need to take
(indistinct), as is look,
you know, and say, what
is our current risk radar?
What are our audit findings?
What do we need to fix?
And by moving to this new
architecture to this new paradigm
what can I fix that I already know,
are challenges that I have?
And then where are we going?
Where's the business going?
Where is IT going?
What are our transformation goals?
A classic one would be, you know,
we're trying to be cloud first,
or we want to go from web page
to application base,
you know, and move more
into the mobile app market.
You know, where are things going?
Where is our cyber strategy headed?
And so as we think through
you know, this program,
we wanna understand all of those things.
'Cause it's easy to build
security not tied to the business,
it is vital that we go back to understand,
are we building out for the
business model we're headed to?
And then ultimately,
you got to look at your
technical depth, you know.
I've done that where I bought a capability
that solved one narrow problem,
I'm using 10% of the capability
of whatever I purchased,
you know, and I never
optimize it to use 90%.
And if I had use 90%
of three of the capabilities
that I did that with,
are there redundancies,
or I could get rid of
with other capabilities?
And so you know, really think you know,
and the worst thing you
could do is have a capability
wasn't up to date that would
have prevented a breach.
'Cause now in the class action lawsuit,
your due diligence isn't there.
And so these are just kind of concepts
that I think are
important to think through
and make sure that, you know,
our current risk, our technical
debt, and our strategy,
are all tied together,
so that the program we built
is ultimately gonna move us forward.
And so, you know, the next
thing I wanna cover is
really just kind of how
you're gonna do this.
How you're gonna accomplish this?
You know, we talked about all
those network capabilities
on the one side,
we talked about all the securities
tools on the other side,
it's not like you don't have any of those,
it's not like you're not doing anything.
And so, to move into this,
you're not gonna walk
away from that investment.
And so you're not gonna do this in a year.
And even if you're moving into new like
let's say you're gonna move into cloud,
and you wanna do this,
you know perhaps you could do it then.
But even then,
you're not gonna find one
vendor that does all of this.
And so you're gonna have to
say what's most important?
What do I wanna start with?
Maybe I start with a vendor
that has some of these
and is gonna move into
future capabilities.
But ultimately, you need to
pick a priority to do this.
And so without knowing what your you know,
your gaps and your challenges are,
or your business model
is, generally speaking,
this is kind of where you wanna start.
So the first thing would obviously be
you kind of wanna start
with this Zero Trust Model.
And you wanna go in
here and you wanna say,
okay, access is number one.
And so how are you gonna provision access
in a way that, you know,
if you're moving to location agnostic,
how are you gonna do it,
if people moving back into the office,
and they're still gonna
have more flexibility,
how are you gonna do that to
give them that flexibility
to be out of the office when they want?
But really, I think so many
of the compromises we've seen
are from, you know,
compromised credentials,
or people, you know, getting
in through some identity path.
And so, number one, Zero Trust.
Whatever model you're
going to, most important.
And the next thing I would
think through is, you know,
protecting that infrastructure.
Last year, we saw a huge
spike in both the volume
and complexity of DDoS attacks,
as well, as you know, attacks
against infrastructure,
extortion DDoS campaign,
one of the largest we've
had in the last five years.
So how are you gonna stop
that denial of service attacks
against your infrastructure,
or against your DNS?
And then this also, you know,
talking about your infrastructure DNS
is where you go back and tie
in with your network folks?
How are you gonna optimize?
How are you gonna have a joyful experience
for your customers and
your employees on this?
Next talk about CASB, you know.
And this depends on how much
you're using that would require, you know,
a SaaS, CASB solution.
If you're not heavily into this,
this would be deprioritize.
If this is where everything is,
then this might move
up higher on the list.
Secure Web Gateway
just becoming more and
more and more important.
And this is, you know, preventing
those phishing attacks,
interrupting certain types
of ransomware attacks,
just so many areas
because of how your
employees are interacting.
And then firewall and web
application, or API protection.
And this is on the bottom of the list,
'cause you probably have this.
If you didn't have this,
it'll be number one.
And so over time, some of these you know,
we're just going to
replace it with an actual,
the natural contract expires.
Others we may, you
know, have a new concept
that we wanna move into just
things to think through.
But I would really take a look
at your overall prioritization
as you go through this.
And again, I'm talking
about the security side,
you absolutely need to tie
back to the network team
and get their buy-in,
so that we can build together
and prioritize together.
So finally, I wanna spend
some time talking about
how to kind of tie all this together.
And so you need to sync with IT team,
if I haven't said that before.
you wanna figure out what the
mandated requirements are,
what models you wanna go through,
I've given you, you know, a
couple analyst frameworks,
SASE tends the way it's written
to be a little bit more
focused on protecting
the company and your employees.
But you can absolutely
expand those requirements
to protect your customers,
the web application firewall,
DDoS, a lot of the things you need to do
that are already in there.
You just need to expand the
scope and the requirements
to do that a little bit better.
You know, tie in those
key stakeholders the risk,
you know, is the board gonna be involved
depending on how important this is.
Get those stakeholders buy-in,
understand what their requirements are,
privacy, legal, fraud,
all those different stakeholders.
Look at your (indistinct) you know,
what do you wanna get out of this
and what do you wanna solve with this?
Get that all done.
You may wanna do an external
assessment of your plan,
or afterwards, ideally both.
And publish this, go out
and make this happen.
And so with that, I wanna
thank you guys for being here,
give me some of your times.
Please continue your questions in chat.
I'll continue to answer those.
Reach out to me on LinkedIn
just say hey, you know,
I saw you on RSA talk
wanted to ask a question.
If you have something
you want in the future,
reach out to me however you can.
But again, thanks for
giving me some of your time.
Thanks for sharing this journey with me,
and look forward to
meeting you in the future.