- Alrighty, well, hey, welcome
to the ''2021 Gula Tech
Foundation award ceremony''
and we are going to be
awarding a variety of awards
that we call Data Care
Awards for organizations
and nonprofits that increase
cybersecurity awareness.
- Yeah, data care has been a term
that we've been gravitating to because
when we're looking at the
workforce development shortage
how do we get more people
engaged in cybersecurity?
We're trying to use and change
the terminology to data care
to try to make it more personal,
to get people's attention
and understand that they have
a personal responsibility
to help with national
security and national defense
but their own defense.
And then turnaround companies
also have the responsibility
to protect the data that
they have been provided
with by the public.
- So today we're going to
talk a little bit about
why we need public
cybersecurity awareness,
even though we just had
the Colonial Pipeline
and we're doing this
at the largest cybersecurity
conference in the world.
We're gonna announce our winners,
we have four runners up and
we also have a first place,
second place, and a third place winner.
We're gonna hear from
each of those winners.
And then as Cindy said, we're
gonna go in a little bit
if we have time to talk a little bit more
about our data care initiative.
- And keeping in mind these
were competitive grants,
so people, organizations
put their programs forward
and we had the ability to vet
and look at a wide variety
of submissions to come
up with these winners.
- So for those of you attending
who don't know who we
are, this is Cyndi Gula.
- Hi, I'm Cyndi.
- I'm, Ron Gula, we run
Gula Tech Adventures.
And we named it adventures
because we were actually involved
in a number of different things
in the cybersecurity industry.
We have a foundation called
the Gula Tech Foundation,
which is focused on
philanthropy and cybersecurity.
Gula Tech Adventures is
our venture capital arm,
we invest in a lot of great companies.
You'll see a lot of
these companies at RSA.
People probably saw
Bryson Bort from SCYTHE,
for example, on a number of conferences
or one of our portfolio companies there.
And then we also have our own show called,
Gula Tech Cyber Fiction
because we're both science fiction nerds.
And we really actually
think science fiction,
has actually dealt with a
lot of the different social
and technological struggles
that we're dealing with today
in cyber security.
- So in January, we had a grant
like another competitive
grant, a million dollars,
looking to find nonprofits
that were engaged
in increasing African-American
engagement in cybersecurity.
Diversity is a very big effort
of pretty much the industry
and there's very specific
terminology backgrounds
and things that we recognize
and we wanna be a lot more
inclusive and inviting.
And so we really wanted to support
the top three organizations which each,
where the first place was 500,000,
the second was 300,000 and
the third place was 200,000.
And you can go to our website, gula.tech
to look more into those organizations.
If you wanna get involved,
that would be great,
education is very local and personal.
So again, the more that we can do
the more we can amplify
and get great people
in cyber engaged with the
public will be better.
- And doing that grant,
and it's more than just giving money,
I mean, we're happy to give
but it was about highlighting
what they were doing
and bringing them to the media,
introducing to the sort
of our network of funds
and companies we're working with.
And one of the things that happened
is we got the attention
of the RSA Conference.
So I think Cyndi and I
just wanna thank everybody
at the RSA Conference for being able
to run this Gula Tech
Foundation award ceremony
during the conference and
getting that kind of exposure.
So we couldn't do this,
it's not just the Ron and Cyndi show,
we actually have a board
of foundation advisors.
We have an advisory board,
a wide variety of names
I'm not gonna go through them all here
but it's a diverse group
of folks from academia,
folks from government,
folks from industries,
and folks from nonprofit land.
And we have an internal process
where we select maybe 10%,
20% of all of our submissions
and then our foundation board
they actually pick the winners.
So we try to make a way that's
non conflicted and whatnot,
but we couldn't do this without them.
I just wanted to acknowledge
who these people are,
and again, thank them for their help
'cause it makes our job a lot easier
because everybody's a winner.
I mean, everybody's doing good work,
trying to pick the foundation,
trying to pick the nonprofits
that make the most impact
it was hard work and we
couldn't do it without them.
- So this grant,
was increasing public
cybersecurity awareness,
again, wrap it around data
care, whatever we could do
and it wasn't limited to
a geographic location.
It wasn't limited to K-12
education or other demographics.
It was open to everybody
because this is going to be
one of the driving factors that we see
is the more public engagement we can have,
the more successful cybersecurity
companies are going to be,
the national security,
that the government's
doing is going to be.
So we just really need all hands on deck
and we were really happy
to see the wide variety
of applications that we did get.
- So today we're gonna be announcing
a million dollars in grants
across seven winners.
We have four runners up, nobody
wants to be fourth place,
fifth place or seven place
but we have four runners up
they're each gonna get a $100,000 each.
And we also have third
place, second place,
and first place getting a 150, 200, 250K
we're all in cybersecurity,
if the add all this stuff
it comes to a million dollars.
But it's more than just the
money, it's the exposure.
If anybody out there is
watching and wants to learn
about these people who
featured for their contacts
go right to their website,
but without further ado,
we're gonna start talking
about how we went through this
and how we just picked the winners
and what were some of
the different dynamics
in separating these organizations apart.
- Oh no, this is all you.
- All me, okay
- This is all you.
- We've rehearsed this, this is great.
So when you think about
how do you measure impact,
if you've ever seen somebody
like Sounil Yu slice and
dice the Cyber Defense Matrix
in all the different ways you could,
he practices this in
almost everything he does.
And what we wanted to
do is really find a way
to kinda separate organizations
and talk about how they did.
So one way was demographics.
So demographics is a fancy
word for your population.
Is it kids?
Is it senior citizens?
Is it veterans?
Is it minorities?
So some cybersecurity non-profits
is focused on a certain demographic.
Others have a different medium.
Do they speak in classrooms?
Do they speak on the internet?
Are they doing PDS, public
awareness news shows?
Are they doing coloring books?
So the medium is a different
thing to consider as well.
Then finally, what are the numbers?
If somebody is gonna make a coloring book
and give it to one K-12 classroom,
that's not as impactful as maybe somebody
who's doing it across a thousand.
So we looked at all three
of those different things.
And this was a lot of the ways
that our board was able to kinda separate
and pick some of those winners.
And we were just excited that
we actually got different,
if you look at the distribution
of everybody who came in here,
we've got somebody in
almost every demographic.
We've got a lot of different mediums
it's not just all people
doing online YouTube videos
and things like that
so they're some pretty innovative things.
So let's get right to it.
- Very excited to announce.
- Alright, so introducing
the four runner ups,
I think I have the first one here.
So the first runner up that
we're going to be announcing
is the National Cybersecurity Center.
So the National Cybersecurity Center
is dedicated to raising
cybersecurity awareness
through education and
public policy innovation.
Their education programs are K-12 students
and adult learners with education
and certification opportunities
to address the cybersecurity
workforce and knowledge gaps.
Cyber for state leaders
raises cybersecurity awareness
and hygiene practices of state leaders
across the contract country.
With respect to policy,
NCC focuses on innovative
technologies in elections,
and emerging cyber
resource center for state
and local governments
to include a cyber range
and the first space ISACA
with leading space industry partners.
So you can see that's a
great example of a nonprofit
that touches a wide number of things.
In particular we were really impressed
with how they worked with state
and local government leaders.
- That's quite the need.
One In Tech is an ISACA
Foundation organization.
They work to build diversity,
inclusion, and equity
within the cybersecurity space
to ensure underrepresented
and underserved populations
can stay safe online
and enable strong pathways
to a data caring career.
I like how they incorporated
data care in there.
Our key focus is providing
educators support,
leadership experiences, events in advocacy
about both cyber safety and cyber careers
to children and adults.
Specifically women, girls
and people of color.
OIT utilizes a collaborative model
for maximum impact partnering
with communicating,
and communicating with organizations
such as the Chicago Public School system,
American Black Librarian
Association, Erie 1 BOCES,
Women4Cyber, AnitaB.org
and various companies
in nearly 200 ISACA
chapters around the world.
Again, very broad capability
pulling in partners
that are all interested and needing
to drive forward the awareness.
- So this next third runner up
is not a traditional
cybersecurity nonprofit.
- Partners In Care from Maryland
is dedicated to helping older adults live
and thrive independently.
The culture of their
staff, sponsors, donors,
and volunteers of all
generations provide a network
to help keep senior
adults independent, safe,
healthy, and active community members.
They will launch a data
care for seniors, members,
volunteers, family members, and staff
on their new website designed
to provide information
and provide access to relevant
and free partners in care services.
Again, there's several of us
that know the senior population really
that the way you address
these different populations
is different, it's not one thing fits all.
So we're really happy
that there was a submission
specifically for seniors.
- And our last runner up is Theorem Media.
Theorem Media has a mission
to harness digital entertainment
to create a more educated, inclusive
and involved citizenry.
We work with world-class
directors, writers and producers
to create popular digital
short films, podcasts,
graphic novels with massive distribution
including K-12 and companion materials.
Theorem Media has established partnerships
with iconic culturally influential
international film festivals
and will establish further partnerships
with cybersecurity forms worldwide
to coordinate both festival
and command performance screenings.
This is a really cool non-profit.
They've also got, normally I don't call
out other people's advisory boards,
but two of our foundation folks
are on their advisory board,
both Dmitri Alperovitch and Tony Sager.
Now we have a process they
have to recuse themselves
but it's still kinda
cool that they're there.
Eli Sugarman, who helped us
kinda get our foundation he's there.
And also Jen Easterly,
she's probably a little busy right now
'cause she took over CISA
so that's quite a well-connected group.
So congratulations to all
of our four runners up right there.
- Right, and we've been crying
or collaborating trying to figure out
how do we do a PSA, a
public service announcement,
kinda like ''Smokey the
Bear'' or anything else
to help draw in.
And this to me is a really unique way
to draw in a more public
engagement in this industry.
- Excellent, well now
on to our third place,
second place, and first place grants.
Cindy is going to introduce
our third place grant.
- So the third place winner,
has for 25 years
significantly raised awareness
of the cryptologic communities.
This organization provides free
cyber's education resources
for K-20 cohorts and
stimulates conversations
regarding data care.
This organization will utilize the funding
to conduct focus groups aimed at reaching
beyond its current
relationships and to determine
and collect a storybook
content that resonates
and effectively communicates
this message to the masses,
especially those in
underrepresented groups.
It is crucial that credence
be given to the youth voices
to inspire the next generation
of cyber professionals.
And based on this, this organization
will exponentially increase
outreach and impact.
And the third place winner
is the National Cryptologic Foundation.
And today we have two representatives,
Laura Nelson, who is
the CEO and Mark Loepker
who is the Education Program
Director, so welcome.
- Thank you, well, good morning.
I'm Laura Nelson, the President and CEO
of the National Cryptologic Foundation.
And we would like to
thank the Gula Foundation
for this generous grant and opportunity
to explore and educate all individuals
about the importance of data care.
The recent hacking of
the Colonial Pipeline,
demonstrated the importance of data care,
not only from a corporate standpoint,
but from a national and
economic standpoint.
We recognize the U.S. is
being targeted more often now
than in the last 50 years.
50 years ago, we protected
the defense of our nation with
or through cryptology.
Now the lessons of cryptology
are being incorporated into cybersecurity,
the defense of our nation
and the defense of our own personal data.
For those of you not familiar
with the National Cryptologic Foundation,
we were incorporated 25 years ago
as a National Cryptologic
Museum Foundation.
We were originally incorporated
to support activities,
displays and artifact acquisition
for the National Cryptologic Museum,
but over the years our
mission has broadened
to include a robust education program
and a capital campaign to build
the Cyber Center for
Education and Innovation.
Our mission is to educate,
stimulate, commemorate.
To educate the public and
inspire our nation students
to explore cryptology, cyber
and stem fields of study.
To stimulate robust
dialogue and engagement
with the American public on cyber policy,
technology, privacy and data care.
And to commemorate all
those who serve in silence
in the cryptologic mission
with valor and distinction.
Our support of the National
Cryptologic Museum,
remains a vital part of our mission,
especially as we expand our partnership
with the National Security Agency.
The reason why we're
here and being recognized
by the Gula Foundation is due
to the steadfast leadership
of our Education Director, Mark Loepker.
Our education program includes,
one, the development and piloting
of High School Cybersecurity
Curriculum Guidelines
and use of the guidelines in
state departments of education
and school districts across the country.
The curriculum is available, at no charge,
to every U.S. high school
through our partner, Teach Cyber.
Second, hosting cybersecurity,
professional development
workshop for teachers.
Third, virtually bringing
cybersecurity education
into the classroom, even
before the pandemic started.
And finally, developing a
Data Care Concept booklet
for middle school students
and teachers that describes
how cyber touches every
aspect of our lives.
We've come to recognize
that introducing concepts of
data care and cybersecurity,
should and can be similar to
a team learning how to drive.
From a very young age
we teach our children
to stop at a stop sign or stoplight
and to drive at the speed limit.
It may be a concept that we
can duplicate for data care,
create the highway for
current and future students
to become a cybersecurity
literate generation.
And now Mark Loepker we'll explain
how we're gonna use this grant opportunity
to educate K-12 students.
- Thank you very much, Laura.
Developing that middle school booklet
with the data care theme led us to seek
this additional opportunity
from the Gula Foundation.
We discovered that we
needed a new language
to describe the personal
sense of responsibility
for how cyber touches
every aspect of our lives.
The cybersecurity message is very complex
and we need to change that language.
The middle school booklet
begins to shift that message
to the data care message.
In our partner start engineering,
this grant will allow us to
establish effective means
and channels to communicate
the data care message
to the masses.
Now, especially those in
underrepresented groups.
Now there's many ways to
tell the story, right,
and different communities hear and learn
by unique methods.
Using various techniques,
including focus groups,
we'll discover those
modalities and channels
that resonate with these groups.
From this research,
we will develop the messages leveraging
the work we've done already
with media vehicles calibrated
to those populations
identified so they can benefit
from this amplified awareness and interest
regarding data care
principles and behaviors.
Now our overarching
vision for this portfolio
of audience specific messages,
will portray data care
as a holistic enterprise
encompassing individual
and institutional responsibilities,
technology and behavioral approaches
to prevention and protection.
And most importantly,
the career opportunities
for the diverse populations
across the wide range
of roles and functions.
And we are extremely excited
about getting started on this project
and spreading the message of data care.
Thank you very much, Ron and Cindy,
we really appreciate it.
- Thank you.
- Thank you and congratulations.
Go back to sharing my
screen, awesome, awesome.
- Thanks guys, great job.
Very excited to see what you come up with,
and oops, oh, the cat's
out of the bag on this one.
- The cat's out of the
bag, sorry about that.
- Second winner.
- Technical glitch, so, all right
now I don't have to
pretend that it's a secret.
As the leading U.S. voice
in cyber crime victims,
Cybercrime Support Network
serves those affected
by cyber crime support during and after.
They connect victims to resources,
increase cyber crime reporting
and empower digital citizens
to defend against cyber crime.
CSN launched three new programs in 2021,
SecureTogether, senior
romance scam peer support.
That's kind of an interesting one
I wanna hear about that.
- No you don't.
- Al right, and partnership
to fight cyber crime
for the military and veteran community.
So with that, I'd like
to welcome Kristin Judge,
the CEO and President of
Cybercrime Support Network.
And again, apologies for
the lack of reveal there.
(Cyndi and Ron laughs)
- That's okay, we don't need a drum roll.
This is just so exciting,
thank you so much, Cindy, Ron
and to the Gula Tech Foundation Board
for recognizing the value of our work,
it means so much to us.
It's such an honor to
have your and support.
And I may be the CEO and founder of CSN,
but our success has everything
to do with our mission,
our partners, and a mission driven team
that we have working
every day to serve others.
I'm so honored to work
with the people at CSN,
we really are an incredible team.
Our mission is very simple,
we want to serve individuals
and small businesses
that are impacted by cyber crime.
When we started CSN,
it was actually a group of
volunteers coming together
with the understanding that
no one was really giving
the victims one place to go to get help.
And there's places to report
and there's also organizations
that do great education and awareness,
but we were missing this one piece
and that's what we wanted to fill.
Where is the one place I could
go after my small business
or myself have been a
victim of cyber crime.
And our board of directors,
our advisory board
are made up of some of the
industry's finest leaders.
And we partner with government agencies
along with NGO's leading in
securing the cyber ecosystem.
When I told people I
wanted to take on the issue
of serving cyber crime victims,
most people thought I was a little crazy,
but I said, I'm not gonna do it alone,
and we're not doing it alone,
we have so many great partners.
Multiple countries around the
world have federal programs
with one national call center to go to
for reporting response and recovery,
so that's what we've been
working towards in the U.S.
for over five years.
And the Cyberspace Solarium Commission
is now recommending a national center
to the Biden, Harris administration.
So we feel like we've been
giving a voice to the victims
in congress and around the country.
But until we have one
national call center,
we've created FightCybercrime.org
as a one-stop shop for
people to get resources.
We also partnered with Google
to create ScamSpotter.org
to go in and see, am I
in the middle of a scam?
Is this true or not?
And people can help get information there
on three golden rules to spot a scam.
So at CSN we envision a society
where everyone has the
knowledge, the skills
and the resources needed to recognize
and then defend against cyber crime.
Because cyber crime is
going to continue to grow
and devastate people and
businesses and our economies
as long as it's profitable
for the criminals.
So that's why the idea
of data care resonates
so much with our team.
'Cause we find sometimes
that victims of cyber crime
don't even recognize that
a cyber crime occurred,
it's a technical thing to them,
it's an IT thing for them.
But data care can really
help people understand
what this is about and it's about me,
and I have data and I
should take care of it.
So to me, it was really a no brainer
to wanna connect with this great idea
of helping people
understand what's happening.
And it's gonna take us a long way
to getting the buy-in from
whole communities now.
So I'd like to change the conversation to,
when we're talking about cyber
crime on a national level,
and talk about the impact of cyber crime
as an economic crisis.
Very few people talk about it that way,
but if we estimate that over $200 billion
is stolen from small
businesses and individuals,
just like you and I every year,
that's money not being
spent on health care,
food to feed our families, our rent,
going shopping on main street, retirement.
So when you put it that way, lawmakers
and decision makers really
understand this issue better.
Again, it's not an it issue,
it's an economic issue,
it's a personal issue,
it's a mental health issue.
So CSN has launched and is in the process
of launching three impactful
national programs this year.
We're so excited and the partnership
with the Gula Foundation and this gift
is really gonna help us
amplify these programs.
So the first one is our
partnership to fight cyber crime
for the military and veteran community.
We're creating a national program
in partnership with Craig
Newmark Philanthropies,
and the Bob Woodruff Foundation
to ensure our service
members, and their families,
and caregivers have consistent
messaging about the threats.
And then they have the
resources to recognize,
respond, and recover from an incident.
We know that they're
disproportionately targeted,
and we wanna make sure they
have consistent messaging.
So we've got some beautiful
PSA's and we're partnering
with military service organizations
and veterans service organizations
to help amplify the
messaging, and so hopefully
it'll be something that
people recognize right away.
We're thankful to Craig
Newmark and Comcast
that gave us the seed
funding for that program,
and Comcast actually just
gave us airtime worth
about a half a million dollars
so our PSA's can run all
around the country in the fall.
So it really is a public
private partnership,
everyone's coming together.
Second, we just launched this last Monday,
our first facilitated Peer Support Program
for survivors of romance fraud.
We work in partnership with prosecutors
and other impactful organizations,
like the Department of
Justice, Elder Fraud Hotline
to identify participants who
could benefit from the group.
And the FINRA Foundation
has graciously provided us
the seed funding for this program,
and it brings people together.
We are providing ourselves education
during this hour long session on fraud
and best practices and then give an hour,
which is an incredible nonprofit,
provides licensed mental
health professionals
to help support the healing.
So that program, we hope to grow and grow
and have hundreds of groups
and help people through that very dramatic
and impactful issue of
trust and losing money,
but then also wondering who
can I trust on the internet.
And when your love life is attached to it,
it's really raw sometimes.
So our third program is SecureTogether
and Trend Micro gave us
the seed funding for this.
It includes a webinar series,
and we've already gotten
that up and running,
and then we're gonna actually
change the security posture,
and this is the part that
gets me really excited,
of people in the U.S.
We are going to work with
partners to create a website
where someone that's a
little more tech savvy,
can sit down with someone in their life
and help them actually add
two factor authentication
to their email and social media,
and actually add automatic
updates to their browser
and their apps and change their posture.
Not just tell them about it,
not just show them a video,
but sit down and do it and then check off
that, yes, I did this for them
and with them they're more secure
and then put in their zip code.
We're gonna do some competitions,
maybe between fraternities
or between even state governments,
private sector companies can volunteer
to have this be their day of volunteer.
Where they all go out and work
with three small businesses,
maybe in their community and just put in
some basic cybersecurity that we all know
is gonna make a difference.
And then we're gonna measure
it with a thermometer
on our website and show
the millions of people
that are now more secure
because of this program.
So we've had so many
people come to us and say,
''How can I volunteer?''
And so we've created this great program
that will launch in October
and people will be able to volunteer
and actually change the
security posture of people
that they work with and
that they care about.
So more to come on that in October.
So the gift we received
today will help us,
help millions more through these programs
and our team could not be more proud
to be included among these
incredible organizations
doing so much for the community
that we all are trying to serve.
So thank you again for
the opportunity to apply,
and partner with you, Cindy and Ron,
we're just so honored on behalf
of the entire team at CSN.
- Well, that's great.
Again, we're very excited
about the work that you're doing directly
to the people and the victims.
And sometimes this
industry blames the victim
whereas any of us can get attacked,
and so we really appreciate
the work you're doing there.
- Thank you.
- All right, and so now
for the first place winner.
So this organization is at a
very significant university.
It's committed to creating
a culture of cybersecurity
through a comprehensive
K-12 cybersecurity program.
At this organization,
the program provides physical card games
and digital education games
and classroom material at
no cost to K-12 classrooms.
These stem resources are
designed to compliment each other
or function independently.
They are easy to access at home
to engage the entire family,
creating a culture of cybersecurity
throughout the community.
And the winner of this grant is,
the Center for Infrastructure
Assurance and Security
at the University of Texas in San Antonio.
And here we have with us Larry-
- Sjelin.
- Sjelin, we did practice, but you know.
- Okay, thank you very much Ron and Cyndi,
we're static of winning first place.
And the competition, obviously,
as you've heard was stiff
so to win first place it's just
a great honor for the CIAS.
The CIAS has been around
for about 20 years
and the culture of cybersecurity program
is just one part of our efforts.
We've been out in the
community, as I said,
for the last 20 years trying
to improve cyber security today,
what can we do to help folks
become better cyber citizens,
secure their organizations.
And it's different for many
centers in the academic area,
many come and go with a
grant, we've been around for,
like I said the 20 years and
we've been pretty successful.
We also, I can I say I guess,
have a competitions group
that is the technology behind
the CyberPatriot program
from AFA, the Air Force Association,
which is very successful.
And we also do
the National Collegiate
Cyber Defense Competition,
which is in its 16th year now.
We do training, we work a lot with FEMA
and CISA and DHS.
I am the director of the game program
and I think I have the
funnest part of the job
that's here at CIS.
We then started in 2016 this program
to reach students in K-12.
And we first targeted
the six through 12 grades
with our collectible card game called,
Cyber Threat Defender.
We wanted to develop something
that was truly a game
and it was fun for students to play.
And through this repetition
of playing the game
'cause they enjoyed it,
they would learn about cyber security.
We just didn't want something
that they would play once
and move on and never touch again,
we wanted something that
they would play in school,
maybe play it at home, play
with friends and family,
and really get them thinking
about cybersecurity is
part of everyone's life.
And so we have started that,
and we have over 50,000
decks distributed globally,
this was something that
we are very proud of,
where CTD is in 17
countries that we know of.
At least 500 schools for school districts
are using this tool daily
in their classrooms.
And one of the proudest
things is the Air Force,
the U.S. Air Force, that has adopted CTD
as part of their curriculum
at their technical schools
at the Shaw Air Force Base.
So it's proven itself time and again,
with a wide audience,
again, from sixth grade
on up to 12 and beyond.
This was only accomplished
through sponsorships
and gifts from the private
industry, individuals,
we know there is no dedicated
funding from the state
or the academic university
here for this program.
So it's really through folks out there
that are involved in
cybersecurity that wanna impact
and want that workforce coming
up to know cybersecurity
and what they need to do.
The demand was extremely great
from the elementary school teachers
for something similar to CTD,
but more on that the grade
levels, K through five,
so we developed two more games.
One was called Cyber Threat Protector,
which focuses on grades three through five
and then our Cyber Threat Guardian Game
which is K through two.
And obviously, you're not
gonna teach a kindergarten
about in-depth cybersecurity,
but it we need to start
as early as possible creating great
and good cyber citizens out there.
So this trilogy of games
builds upon each other,
they can go from grade to grade
with the same concept, the same tools
to help them understand cybersecurity.
We estimate that probably
we are reaching 250,000
students every school year,
so these cards that are in the schools,
it's just not one student that use them,
every year students are
being exposed to this tool.
So that number is growing rapidly.
And this gift literally
is going to help us double that number
and that outreach.
This is the single largest
gift that we've received
for this program and we
just couldn't be happier
that we can put this money
to use, like get these cards
into the hands of students and teachers.
The best praise for this
program comes from the teacher
and it's changed the way
they teach cybersecurity
in the classroom.
Like you can't get a better
recommendation from them,
from a teacher coming
to promote the program.
So again, we wanna thank
the foundation very much
for this gift and we'll
definitely put it to good use.
- Awesome, thank you very much.
Thank you very much, Larry,
that's really, really inspirational.
Everybody did a great job
talking about their non-profits,
I really appreciate everybody
kinda coming out today.
So just to wrap up, I wanna
thank again all the winners.
We just heard from the University
of Texas at San Antonio
with their CIAS program.
We heard from the
Cybercrime Support Network,
which came in second.
We heard our third place winner,
which was the National
Cryptologic Foundation.
And of course our four
runners up were One In Tech,
an ISACA Foundation, the
Partners In Care from Maryland,
the National Cybersecurity Center,
and of course, Theorem Media.
Now we're not announcing
another grant competition today,
I would say stay tuned, Cindy and I
we really wanna work
with the seven winners.
We wanna have them on our show.
We wanna make sure that if
there's anything we can do
as far as introductions
and follow through,
there's a good bit of work.
We're actually still working a lot
with the winners from the
first foundation grant award.
- And we've also realized
that the grant winners work together
to even amplify their own
messages and their own activities.
And that's just great to see
the organizations continue
to help each other through and navigate
and get more messaging out there.
And we just hope people
out there that have time,
have the ability will come
to our website, gula.tech,
and either look at the
previous grant winners
or the existing grant
winners and do what you can
to volunteer, to help, to get involved.
Because again, it's going
to make everybody more safe
and better in the future if we
get more people involved now.
- And also at the website, gula.tech,
we've got a section on data care.
It's not ours, it's not copy written,
take it, steal it we're
all in this industry
we live in a bubble.
As much as we're participating
in the largest and best
cybersecurity conference,
we are in a mere bubble of what the rest
of the world perceives
about cybersecurity.
They don't speak our language,
they don't know how to join our workforce,
they don't know how to protect themselves
and we really need to be better
as cyber citizens educating them.
And I think everybody here embodies that
and we hope to really to
continue to see through in that.
- And again, we can't
thank RSA Conference enough
to allow us to highlight these winners
and really highlight all the companies
out there doing great work
and working towards
being more cyber secure
into the future, so thank you.
- Thank you, and enjoy the
rest of the conference.
Congratulations to our winners,
keep up the great work.