- Hi, welcome to my presentation.
Hacker's Paradise: Top 10 Biggest Threats
When Working From Home.
My name is Paula Januszkiewicz,
and I'm the CEO of CQURE
also a Regional Director of Microsoft
and also a person who has access
actually to the source code of Windows
for the past 10 years.
And I'm absolutely happy to share insights
that are covering the current situation
when we are all working from home
in order to cover the biggest threats
that we have encountered
within the last projects,
and also interesting observations
from what to do in order
to become more secure
while technically sitting at home.
So regarding the agenda for today,
there are a couple of
things here to cover.
First of all, we're gonna discuss
the security awareness idea.
So what's happening
right now in this world,
then we're gonna dig into
top 10 biggest threats
and then of course, we're
gonna get into the summary.
So as we already know,
we are in the state where
we are working from home.
We are working from locations
that are not necessarily
being in our offices,
and there are different recommendations
and different organizations
that are creating
those recommendations
regarding the remote work.
For example, one of the
agencies, which is called CISA,
they have actually issued a recommendation
that organizations should
adopt to the conditions
that we got currently in the world
in order to enforce and
reach our security solutions
to avoid known vulnerabilities
and known threats that are
out there, for example,
when we take into consideration phishing
being the number one threat
currently in the world
that is the generic recommendation
that they are making.
CISA being one of the
organizations out there,
is technically the Department
of Homeland Security
Cyber and Agency, but they are of course
not the only ones here so
we've got, for example,
checkpoints that share research
that shows that cyber criminals
are actually using Coronavirus
pandemic to spread,
for example, spam activity
through both email campaigns
and malicious domains.
So whenever we take into consideration
some other aspects that are
related with the remote work,
we're also observing that
we've got employees, of course,
sometimes using their
personal device for work
or eventually sharing
that particular device
with some other people, for
example, members of the family,
we've got employees
connecting, for example,
to the company's network,
from their home wifi
or some public unknown wifi,
which technically creates
different situations
that are very comfortable
for hackers to be eventually misused,
and at the same time allowing us
to access the employee's computer.
So that could be work
device, personal device,
and eventually, maybe hopped
through the corporate network.
And here we are discussing of course
many types of attacks that
could be through phishing,
that could be, for example,
through being in the same sub-net
and then eventually,
affecting the traffic,
affecting the communication that employee
is using over here in
order to, for example,
to browse, simply websites or in general,
these kinds of problems
are also usually starting
when we are mixing two worlds.
So our private world with our corporate
or in general work
world, when, for example
we are using applications
or in general websites
with the social media so
things like Facebook and so on,
which could, for example,
lead to an attack
to a code execution on our computers.
Of course, if that's allowed,
if the company allows it
and then spread across the
organization's network.
So whenever we are thinking, of course,
about these top 10 biggest
threats when working from home,
some of them are simple and some of them
are a little bit more advanced.
So let me start with something
simple for us to warm up,
and that is actually
related with the situation
where we disable firewall
or in general different security solutions
that are working on our,
for example, personal device
that could be used for
work-related purposes
or either if we got a possibility
to affect security solutions
on the work device,
that could be also the case.
Or it could be also
misconfiguration of the firewall
that allows the different processes
that are technically
suspicious, not allowed
within our organization's policy
to be communicating out of the network.
Which brings me actually,
to a technical explanation
where we've got, for
example, certain macro
that we are receiving
within the phishing email.
And then macro opens up a child protest,
that child protest could be, for example,
PowerShell, which technically
is an allowed process
within the Windows platform.
And then eventually,
that particular process
is communicating out to the network,
to the internet in general,
in order for example,
to fetch some other items
that could be used within the attack.
Yes, on and the second part
it's something else there
but what is important is
that there is a child process
like PowerShell that from macro opens up
and then tries to establish communication,
which is clearly an anomaly.
So what I would like to show
you in the demonstration
is the perfect example of that.
Let's have a look how
through a malicious macro
we are able to take over
a certain workstation.
So the demo it's called
Initial Access Privilege Escalation.
What you see on the screen right now,
it's just Netcat.
So we're gonna be listening
for the incoming connections.
And in here there's a
microsoftonline.com.co
You probably guys recognize
that it's not a Microsoft domain, right?
That's the domain that we
use for phishing activities
but it's so similar to the Microsoft one.
So over here, there's other trend.
And as you can see over here
we've got similar looking document.
So technically the whole thing
over here, it is an image.
So we enable content for the macros.
User clicks somewhere inside of document.
There is a reverse show
and that reverse show
is in the form of executable design.
And this creates a
connection to the hacker.
When we check out the macro over here
you can see that there's
just one big button.
And over here is a URL
download to the file.
And we are downloading certain executable
in the text file see.
So then we are renaming that
to that executable so .exe.
and over here we are
running .rev-kali.exe.
And being on the hacker
side, if we run whoami/o
you can see that we are
this user right now.
So we managed to become a
user, as you can see Paula.
And eventually this user is just a user
because of the privileges that are listed.
So this is how, of course,
we are able to recognize who we are.
But it doesn't really matter.
So we can here get into
curl and technically
our machine payloads privesc
and then eventually we're
gonna be running the ps1.
So that's the PowerShell.
And that is the script that eventually
we are able to use for
the privs escalation
So they put the privilege
escalation in this computer.
So we can set up a
set-executionpolicy bypass scope
and then process and then for that moment,
we will be able to run scripts
that are not digitally signed.
You can always do it to by the way.
And right now, when we run
our privescalation script
that's actually a DLL hijacking.
Then here you are able to see
that we are using some DLL
and that's particular DLL,
we're gonna be loading
by the task scheduler
upon the service startup
and here we are using also the
internal windows mechanisms.
So everything is, of course,
something particular,
it's something specific over here,
but at the end we are able to
recognize also what's running
on this user's computer to
effectively run the attack.
And in here we're gonna
decurl, reverse DLL
and we specify the output,
We've got that part in 27
DLL, and we're gonna be
leveraging this particular
DLL within the attack.
So this is a DLL that
we have named over here.
This is how, by the way, we can hide.
He has to put it in some kind of a DLL,
into some kind of a folder,
And eventually a DLL that's
not digitally signed,
maybe amongst other DLLs
that are also not signed
out if for this solution.
So when we gonna shut down the computer,
we still set up a listener.
And on the client's
side, we have set up also
the persistency, and this particular DLL
when it's gonna be loaded
by one of their mechanisms
one of the solutions, even
in Windows Operating System
then you can see that that
persistency allowed us to connect
back to that Netcat to
the listening hacker
and at that stage, we are
actually escalating to a system
because from the moment when
we were starting the service
and so on, that was
actually running as system.
So because we were able to drop a DLL
into the certain location
we could at the end
also run it with that escalated
or elevated privileges.
So as you can see guys we were able to
take over a certain machine
just because we were able to
run the code through the macro.
Now it was not the simplest
possible macro that we got
because underneath we were
using the system mechanisms
in order to gain persistency.
So these kinds of situations might lead
to a further execution.
And of course there are many problems here
that we could cover yeah.
So one thing will be user awareness
another part would be why in general,
this email made our mailbox.
Another part might be related
why that code even executed
why there were no attack
surface reduction rules.
So there are plenty of situations
that might not be covered
on the personal workstation
that might be used
for example, for the work purposes.
Another part that I would
like to touch base on
is overly simple password
and security questions.
And that in general covers
situation where companies
do not have yet implemented
multifactor authentication,
that's one thing, and
using the simplest example
that I've got within that,
one of the latest projects is
when I was doing that password
spraying for the organization
cause that's technically my job
and I'm not leaving technology even though
I got a business role within the company.
I did the simplest possible attack
for the approximately 6,000 users
and they did not have
multifactor authentication.
And then it appeared at
2129 actually, of users,
in this example, they had the password
which consisted of the
company name and also a year.
So again, not very surprising, right?
But that is just enough
to use, for example,
one user in order to be able spread fodder
and then send phishing,
which is no longer phishing
because this is an email
that is actually sent
by our friend.
So let's have a look how
that kind of situation
could be escalated further.
What I would like to show
you, it's a situation how
for example, we are able to
sometimes give away our password
because multifactor
authentication is one thing.
But the second thing is simply phishing
that is encouraging us
to give away credentials
that could be later potentially used
within the fodder components
of the infrastructure.
In this illustration, we got a machine
that's connected to a certain network.
And if we open up the browser
and query demo.cqureacademy.com/admin
like you see, then here we can enter
a username CQDemo and certain password.
And then you've got a happy raccoon there,
we are able to successfully login.
Now another part it's
gonna be cqureacadeNy.com
and over here, we're gonna
be also launching the website
that is as well, or
could be as well HTTPS.
And over here we could do
CQDemo and enter the password
and then there was a bad raccoon.
So these are the two
similarly looking websites
but these are really
two different websites
where we are able to extract passwords
at that stage from the login form.
Yeah so this is the setup.
Now we can just close the cards over here.
And what will be our goal
is to verify the IP address
of cqureacademy.com and compare
it with cqureacadeny.com.
So here we are not really
acting on the DNS yet.
It's just, these are two different sites.
So we've got an IP
address given ending name
and then we've got the
also the cqureacadeny
which you can see it's different.
Now the next stage over here,
is that I'm gonna pretend
that I'm connecting to the network
through the malicious access point.
So I'm somewhere at the airport.
I'm connecting to the free
wifi, somewhere in a cafe.
It doesn't really matter.
I do not control my access point.
So here I entered it the
demo.cqureacademy.com/admin.
And that's the cqureacadeny,
yes but we do see CQDemo
and then we run the password.
And then as you can see,
it's just something wrong
because we entered a current address.
How could it be that our credentials
are actually leaking here?
And it's the same in this case, user name
and password that I typed.
An answer this question is
actually very straightforward.
We went over here demo.cqureacadeny.com
That's certain IP address
and also cqureacadeny.com,
that's this certain address.
Why this is possible?
Because we at that stage
control the access point
that the user is connecting to.
So as you can see, we've got a situation
where not only we were
able to get the password
of the user that was phished, but also,
through the possibility to
control the access point.
We were able to spoof the website
and replace the website
eventually either on the fly
or just play with the DNS records
in order to redirect the
user to the incorrect website
to give away credentials
and not a problem over here,
it's no network segmentation.
And what I mean by this, is
that if there is a certain code
running on the user's
computer, then for example,
a user is connected using the VPN.
We've got a problem with the situation,
what the user sees.
So things like VPN pivoting attack
it's perfectly working here.
So just to mention, but
that attack is based
on the situation where attacker manages
to be in the same network as the user,
manages to get access
to the user workstation,
maybe through phishing, maybe
through that kind of activity
that you just guys could see in a demo.
And eventually the next
step would be to treat
users workstation as a proxy,
that's what's called VPN pivoting.
Because user is connected
using VPN connection
to their organization.
And then the hacker is able
by using the workstation
as a proxy to see exactly
the same stuff the user see
in the infrastructure.
And if, for example, user sees servers
some other services that are critical
from the perspective of the organization
that eventually we call a Shadow IT
at the end, because
there might be something
that's misconfigured not
checked within pentest
or maybe checked, but not
corrected, but being still there.
Then this is something
that could be possibly used
within the attack.
So whenever we think about that
there's one thing that actually
comes to my mind as well.
And that's the lack of SMB signing.
So if the hacker is able
to see the same stuff
that the user could see
being connected through VPN
for example, by using VPN pivoting,
we are able at the same time,
to try to launch the attacks
like ARP poisoning and then
eventually, listen to the SMB
a related to communication
in between house.
And when you combine that altogether
with NTLM version three
authentication protocol
which is used in (indistinct) let's say
or instead of Kerberos, for example
across local accounts, for
example across service accounts
or also when you use the short name,
for example \\files
or when you use \\IP address
then you trigger by
default NTLM version two
and then this being
challenged response mechanisms
is actually be able to be spoofed.
And then you can relay the
response to that target.
And that is something that
I would love to show you
within the SMB relay attack.
Let's have a look at the simple attack
where are we gonna deliver SMB relay.
SMB relay in general, it's
relying on the situation
where we have no SMB signing
in the infrastructure
and at the same time we're
using NTLM version two protocol
for authentication.
Now this attack works in vast
majority of organizations
and the problem is that, well, it's easy
but at the same time
there is a certain code
that needs to execute and
it will be great, of course,
to know what are the ways to figure out
that that particular code
has actually executed.
So for the SMB relay, I'm
going to use smbrelayx.py
script, as you see.
And my target is gonna be 10.10.10.250.
And on execution I'm
gonna run CQShell104A.exe
which is actually a reverse shell
that is customized by our team.
Now, the customization
that is happening here
is actually related with the discovery
or nondiscovery by the antivirus solution.
But at the end, it's just
a simple reverse shell.
So that's gonna be the first step.
Second step that we got over here,
is related with the listener or handler
for the incoming connections.
And I have over here, made exploit
which I have simply set up
as you see that's everything.
So that's why it's like it's so simple
to perform the handling of connections
that are about to come if
they run the reverse shell.
So this is basically
what's happening here.
Now that reverse shell in general
it's gonna be running connects
because SMB relayed itself
in order to establish
a connection to assure
and so on has to run its own executable
which we would like to trace afterwards.
And that's gonna be a
very interesting situation
to have a look.
So let's see, first of all,
here we would just need to go exploit.
And second thing here, we
just need to run the script.
Now what I'm gonna do on my side
it's gonna be basically the query
from a certain type of machine.
So from one host to another,
in order to query or trigger
NTLM version two authentication.
Now that situation is
actually quite straightforward
because querying by IP address,
different types of hosts
in the infrastructure it's
quite a typical thing, right?
So basically we do backstage backslash
and then we specify IP address.
Now I'm gonna hear, listen
to incoming connections.
So please have a look.
Now I have queried a certain IP address
in the infrastructure.
Here we can do ps to list processes.
And over here, I'm able
to see that, for example
there an svchost running
as NT authority system
which has process ID 3136,
so let's do that migrate 3136
and the immigration process over here
I was asked to move our bad
piece of code to that process
and this is a typical
exploitation technique,
not in the form of DLL and
so on, but by modification
of the memory address
space of that process.
Now we are right now in
that system so I press shell
here if we do whoami
you are able to see that
we are actually a system
in that target system.
So this is all good, but
the question is, of course
how are we able to investigate that, okay?
And this is something that
I would like to show you.
So we were migrating the 3136
and we are able to see over
here that it's from 2909.
And once we did shell, then basically
here there has been process created.
So let's have a look how this activity
reflects basically on our target machine.
And it's extremely interesting
because this particular attack,
can happen pretty much anytime.
But the thing is, that if
it happened, for example,
six months ago, now the question is
how do we know that
that actually happened?
And there are a couple of
things that could indicate
even after that time that there
is something bad going on.
So first of all, what we gonna do,
We gonna look at the machine.
Yes so let's do it.
So here's the machine, we
can sort by the process IDs.
For the simplification of
this research, this by the way
it's not because there is some
vulnerability or anything.
No, no, no, this is how it works
because of the NTLM version
two and SMB not being signed.
Which is a default actually.
So here we go, we've got a 3136,
3136 we don't have, we actually do.
Do you see that process?
So we got 3136.
Yeah, so this is basically the one
that we are migrating to.
So I'm gonna move down a little bit.
So this is this one 3136.
But we don't have 2904.
If we look for 2904, that
process does not exist anymore.
Now why?
Because when we migrate to
3136, that 2904 just vanished.
Yes, now at 2864, that
is this one basically.
It is here.
We've got this one.
That's the cmd.exe.
Yes indeed, because that's the shell.
But of course, if the hacker closes it
you won't see it anymore, and now what?
So a long story short, first of all,
we can have a look netstat
and with your options ano
maybe let's do more.
And here we've got process IDs
that are related with the communication.
Now, funny fact is that
if you have a look at the
established connection
because it clearly stands out,
we're able to see that the process ID
assigned to that connection it's 2904.
But hey, did we just say that
that process just vanished?
Exactly, because unfortunately netstat
wont to tell you the truth.
Netstat unfortunately will
show you only the connections
or the process that was used
when we were establishing
your connection and that's it.
So simply we cannot trust it.
So is there someone to trust
in the operating system
assuming that that attack
happened long time ago?
Well, yes.
We've got something that
basically we call Prefetch.
And within Windows
Prefetch which is out there
running all the time.
We've got a possibility to verify
what were the processes running
since you have set up your Windows.
So let's do start .
And here I have sorted these
things by date modified.
So you're able to see that eventually
we've got more netstat
process hacker whoami?
And then we've got this strange guy.
That's this IYJR and so on.
So this is quite interesting
because it looks dodgy
but of course it might
have a really nice name.
So let's in general for the
sake of our research here
verify if this could be this bad process.
So what I'm going to do is I'm right now
on the hacker's machine.
And this is this attack
that we were delivering.
And over here, you can see
that authentication was made.
And then we've got uploading file.
IYJRD and so on.
So that's this one.
And that was also the one
that we could confirm.
That was on the client side.
Yeah, so this is basically the situation.
Now, if it was called, whoami, for example
or a notepad or something, then
it won't look that strange.
So how can we look inside?
Of course, Shift + right-click,
Copy as path.
And over here, I'm
going to go to our tools
where I'm going to use CQ and
in this case, PrefetchParser.
So in our team we've got
lots of tools like that
but this particular one we're gonna use
with the parameter F for file.
We're gonna paste above.
And then we're gonna do
minus A for analysis.
And long story short, and
we make a full screen,
We are able to analyze a bit of details
about what's going on
inside a Prefetch file.
For example, here,
we've got run count one.
And the run count one indicates
that this particular executable
has been running only once.
And that is already quite suspicious.
We can see when but we can
also see what kind of DLLs
are loaded over here.
So if this file has a named notepad
and it is actually
malware, then we are always
able to compare, for example,
the list of loaded DLLs
whether it's the same as
original notepad or not.
So prefetch in general allows
us to indicate what kind
of executables were running
in the operating system.
Even though process tracking, for example,
as one of the logging
methods wasn't turned on.
So prefetch it's not that detailed,
but in a worst case it
helps you to understand
if there was something suspicious
actually running on your machine.
How long do we maintain prefetch?
Well, since you installed windows.
So over here you were
able to find a history
of everything that has been ever running
in this operating system that's one thing.
Second, who can delete it or approve it
it can be deleted by administrators.
So long story short, if hacker knows
what he or she is doing, then this person
can go to the prefetch folder
and then eventually delete the trace.
So it really depends on the situation,
but actually during this analysis,
we really see that
prefetch is being deleted.
What if it is deleted actually?
Is it possible to recover
for example, deleted files?
The answer is, of course
we can always do that.
So as you can see, guys
we've got a possibility
to play with the network traffic.
And then at that point,
we are able to affect
the way how people can authenticate
to take over server or workstation.
Let me show you couple of things here.
So there was a code that was executed
and that is something that is
technically a bit of a mistake
because nowadays especially
dealing with ransomware,
we are allowing in some organizations
that ransonware to execute.
We know that, for example, from the news.
So having this in mind, we've got
the possibilities to
implement whitelisting
or something that's called
allowlisting eventually.
And this is something
that would prevent us
that code like that from running.
And we're not only talking
here about SMB relay
which could be fixed in
many ways, for example,
by implementing SMB signing,
but also it could be supported
by implementation of whitelisting.
And that is also
something that we consider
as a configurational mistake
and the problem of the current
times that, for example,
on the personal workstations,
we've got that one
that's not configured yet.
So whenever we think
about some other stuff,
we've got over here, old
protocols or DOD for settings.
So it really depends on
the business applications
that people are, for example, using.
Like we might have applications
that are using connection to SQL server.
And that is actually one
of my favorite things
that I'm checking within the pentest.
So when you are sniffing to the traffic,
then you can sniff for example, traffic of
or like a tabular data stream.
So that sends as a TDS and for
example, within the Wireshark
you are able to use TDS as a filter.
TDS it's a communication to a SQL server.
So for example, query to
database that will be running
within the clear text in
vast majority of obligations
especially the older ones
that is actually clear text
which is best for the
pentest or for the attacker
because that's something
that you can spoof.
And that's something
that could for example,
create an additional count in SQL server.
If, of course you're gonna
have a privilege query.
So that's one thing.
And another one it's trusting solutions
without really knowing how to break them.
So for example if we are using
the multifactor authentication,
is that something
that could be bypassed in a
sense so that when we take over,
for example, the cookies
for the certain application
that user is using, could that be a way
to bypass multifactor authentication?
Or another part is, if we've
got the antivirus solution
are we able to stop it
by modifying the SDDL
and approximately 40%
of antivirus solutions
they're actually allowing that.
So that is something that
we will need to check
how we were able to stop
our security solutions.
What in general are the
ways to bypass stuff
that we are using?
So that is a bit of a
thinking pattern here
and another part it's
misusing service accounts
and in general privilege accounts.
And for this one, I
got a super quick demo.
Where are you guys gonna
read how we are able to
extract passwords from
the service accounts?
Let me show you one of our favorite tools
which is CQSecretsDumper.
So over here, you guys
can see Paula's service
and it's running on the
account CQUREFreddykrueger.
So this is clearly not a built-in account
and there was a risk that this account
or under this account,
we are storing passwords
in the registry of this particular system.
So how you're able to extract it.
Well, that is actually
data prediction API system.
And we've got a tool for that.
And that is actually a problem
for many organizations.
So have a look, here
within the log on area
you can see CQUREFreddy Krueger.
And then eventually there
is this particular password,
and that is something that
we're gonna be extracting
from the registry.
Normally it's not stored in
a clear text in the registry
of this operating system, so
we will have to decrypt it.
And then eventually we gonna
be able to use it later
maybe within the attack who knows?
So long story short that particular secret
it is actually stored in the registry.
And it is used because eventually,
service credential manager has to use it.
So let's see, while we use CQSecretsDamper
and we specify service pjservice.
And in the moment you
guys are gonna see that
because we are running
this particular tool
within the administrative privileges,
then eventually, you can
see that requested registry
access is not allowed.
Well clearly because
that is a system secret
and it is technically stored
within the security hive.
So we have to run psexec -s -i -d cmd.exe,
to elevate ourselves
in the separate window
the local systems so with
the option, do not wait.
And eventually here, you
can see that we are whoami
and the authority system.
And when we moved to our
toolkit we can run again,
CQSecretsDumper or /service
and we're gonna name pjservice
and you can see that password this time
is actually to be extracted
in the clear text.
So I've never seen
organization by the way,
that did not eventually have this problem.
So it's good in the state of
security to verify what kind
of services you've got that
are potentially running
on the regular accounts because
100% password it's stored
in the registry over
there, because this is how,
by the way log on as a service works
that you guys are actually
able to extract passwords
like this, who can do it?
As you could see it could
be actually extracted
only by local system but
you could also use that
to perform volume maintenance
task privilege, for example
to copy that system and
security hive, and as well,
extract the password offline like this.
So these are the possibilities
while extracting passwords
from the service accounts
from the registry.
Okay, guys so you are able
to see how easy it is.
So it could be that
potentially misconfiguration
of the workstation could
be used as one of the steps
that the hacker technically could use
in order to do one step further.
And the extracting passwords
from the service accounts
is just one of that 20 places.
So it depends, of course,
what kind of solutions you got
but we are able to, just
like that, extract password
from the configured service.
So here we go, the last one
we've got falling for evil tools
and what we mean by this,
is that we already
deciding to use a solution.
And at the same time that
solution might appear
not to be safe.
So that is a generic
concept of the solutions
that we decide to use especially
within the pandemic times
when we, for example, switch
immediately to the remote work
and we are forced to do something
or get used to something
that users are simply not used to.
And that is something that
I would love to show you
in terms of multifactor authentication,
and also the ways of how
we are able to take over
user workstation or in
general users mailbox access.
So call it as you won't
because we can escalate
this attack further, but at the same time,
it is relying on the team's communication
or something that looks
like teams communication.
Okay, guys so I'm
leaving you with these 11
key cyber security questions
which is an important thing to note
because every organization
security differs
but having this, for example, 10
but there's definitely
more mistakes, situation
that we are dealing with
when working from home
maybe we are able to improve the security
of the current user
workstation, or in general
our security posture.
Here we've got information and questions
like does our business culture support
a secure cyber environment?
Or within the second set of questions here
are we adequately resourced and insured?
So by having answered this
11 key security questions
that I'm always sharing
with CSOS particularly
we are able to rethink
our remote work strategy
in order to prepare for the, I would say,
not to be missed and the
definitely undoubtfully happening
shift to remote work.
And then within the
summary best practices,
understanding it's definitely
the key to security
which means that the more we look
at our infrastructure from
the hacker's perspective
the more of the issues
we are able to spot,
especially within the users remote work.
Whenever we are thinking about
the remediation and tracking,
so the monitoring solutions
that's another perspective
that gives us basically the view
on what kind of things are executing
on the user workstations or on the server.
So in general, well-designed monitoring
and smart analysis about
what's happening right now.
Filtering and segmentation of the network.
The allowlistings/whitelistings
to prevent things
that are unknown on workstations.
Things like attack
surface reduction rules.
So these are the things that
are very easy to implement
but at the same time being a good answer
for the current remote work problems.
Thank you so much for
listening to my presentation.
I'm Paula Januszkiewicz,
and enjoy your day.