- Hi, everyone.
Welcome to our
How Risky Is Cybersecurity
Insurance? briefing.
We're gonna do here today.
I'm John Pescatore with
the SANS Institute.
- And I'm Ben Wright,
I'm a lawyer in Texas
and I teach LEG523 law of data security
and investigations course at SANS.
- So cybersecurity
insurance has certainly been
in the news recently.
A lot of ransomware attacks you see
on your screen have tended to drag it in,
but cybersecurity
insurance has been an issue
for a long time.
I've been at SANS eight years
before that, at Gartner,
I think it was as far back as 2005,
when I was working in things related
to cyber insurance in the major carriers.
So our goal here, Ben and
my goal for this session,
like all of SANS training is
to give you some information
and some background and
some things you can do.
So when you get back to work,
you can be an informed player.
You can work with your
company, making the decisions
on when cybersecurity does
or does not make sense
and how it relates to
the cybersecurity program
and what you can do to
sort of minimize the risk
to your company, overall, both the risk
of attackers causing
impact to your business,
but also the risk
of cyber insurance being
prohibitively expensive, based
on the status of your security program.
So with that, let's get started.
- So one of the key stakeholders,
who is interested
in cyber insurance at an enterprise
like a business is the
financial community.
When I say financial community
with respect to a business,
I mean investors like
shareholders, I mean lenders
like banks, and I mean, board
of directors and the ease
of stakeholders are not very
capable of evaluating security.
However, they understand insurance.
With insurance and institution
do some kind of a review,
which equals underwriting, it
evaluates the cyber hygiene
at the business and it makes a decision.
Okay, I'm going to take this risk.
I'm going to put money on
the table to take that risk.
From the point of view of
the financial community
as impactful that the
insurance company would say
that it will put its own money
on the table to take the risk
with respect to some
kind of a cyber event.
And so, cyber insurance can
cover many different kinds
of losses or expenses.
Cyber insurance often covers losses
like business interruption.
Oftentimes, cyber insurance
comes with services.
So those services can include forensics,
it can include incident response.
And today, increasingly,
cyber insurance covers
ransomware explicitly
and provides for the negotiation
of ransomware as well
as payment of the rants.
The kinds of coverages known
in insurance include what's
called first party coverage
and third party coverage.
The first party coverage
means the kinds of expenses
or losses that the insured
enterprise incurs directly
such as business interruption.
Third party losses
means covering some kind
of an expense that comes
from a third party.
An example would be a
regulator imposing a fine
on a business who has suffered
some kind of cyber crisis.
An important kind of
insurance in this field
as we think about ransomware
is traditional property
and casualty insurance
that's sold to businesses and enterprises.
So property and casualty
insurance traditionally
covers a lot of different property losses
as well as extortion.
And up until recently,
a lot of the insurance
companies were interpreting
their traditional property
and casualty policies to cover ransomware.
However, NotPetya was so damaging
to the insurance industry
that the insurance industry
has changed its mind.
So the insurance industry says
that it lost globally, $2.7 billion
because of NotPetya.
And they decided that NotPetya
has demonstrated to us
that ransomware is a whole new ball game
and it's not traditional
damaged property and extortion.
So increasingly, insurance companies are
changing their policies and
they're changing the policy
as they renew an existing policy
to explicitly part out ransomware
and say ransomware is not covered
by traditional property and casualty.
If you want ransomware coverage,
they have to buy it
specifically as a special rider
or a special bond policy
and pay for it special.
- So Ben just talked a lot
about the sort of benefits
that come with cyber insurance.
We want you also to be aware of the cost
and there's two types of cost.
One is what you pay for the policy.
So if you ever gone to a restaurant
and felt like having
a nice lobster dinner,
you probably saw the
menu saying market priced
because who knows how many
lobsters they caught that day
or that time of month or that year,
you can see the pricing is really variable
in what lobsters cost and
on a day-to-day basis,
it can fluctuate wildly
that's market pricing.
When there's not stable
dynamics in a market,
we have market pricing and
the prices change everyday.
That's sort of what the
case is for cyber insurance.
It's essentially market price.
I tried to pull together some data points
in late 2020 and the
first quarter of 2021.
And the 5 you see on there,
the documented public ones I could find,
I've got to walk through a
couple of case studies later,
we'll do a little drill down
in sort of similar space.
But you see here, this
has two smaller companies,
sort of the lower left of this
curve that had a $1 million
and $2 million policies that were only
in the fifteen to thirty
thousand dollar range
for that amount of coverage.
And then, you see to the
far right, larger companies
that had bigger policy
coverages of 10 million
and you see the dots are spaced out.
You see the one dot in the middle,
which was sort of a medium-sized company
and using my advanced
machine learning skills
and doing curve fitting.
I drew that red line,
which if you take that red
line is one of two things.
If you take that red line where it is,
we end up with on the
range of 12.5K per million.
But if you see that arrow,
that's where the prices have gone
at the high-end here more recently.
And you'll see in one of
the examples I use later,
much higher for large companies is,
as Ben mentioned, NotPetya hit
some really large companies
with $300 million plus
exposures of several,
at least two of them that were made public
and larger companies
generally have more computers
that get hit, it's more
expensive to remediate.
They have larger customer counts,
so the costs are astronomical
for these incidents that really
sweep across a big company
either disrupting its
revenue or impacting tens
of millions of customers or in real cases,
hundreds of millions of customers.
So the out-of-pocket cost
in two things is kind
of unpredictable stabilizing
a little bit here
over the past couple of years,
but it's not insignificant
for large companies.
For small companies, it
may be sort of simple.
Let's do it.
Let's hope it's like
backing up our hard drive.
If we back up the hard drive,
the computer never crashes.
If we're getting insurance,
we'll never need it,
that's small companies.
With large companies, it's
a significant expense.
And it's a decision to
divert company resources
towards paying the bill for insurance.
And you're going to see
Ben and I harp on a couple
of things here
throughout this one key thing
I always bring up is spending
on cyber insurance
doesn't reduce anything the
security program has to do.
We still have to do all
the same security things
to protect the company.
The spending
on cybersecurity insurance
does not replace any of that.
So that's sort of the out-of-pocket cost.
Let Ben drill down.
And so sort of the impacts and
costs of the security team.
- So one of the really important things
for a security team to bear in mind
as it's working with
insurance is tell the truth.
Now that's kind of odd.
The lawyer says, "Tell the truth."
That's so obvious, but telling the truth
to an insurance company with respect
to a very complex technical topic
like cybersecurity can be a challenge.
And so, during the review process,
before issuing the policy,
the insurance company goes
through what it calls underwriting
and it may give you a questionnaire,
it may send someone to come
and talk to you and audit you and so on.
And if the insurance
company believes later,
after you have a crisis like ransomware
that you didn't tell the truth,
during the underwriting process,
then the insurance
company may deny coverage,
or it may reduce coverage.
Another place where this need
for telling the truth happens is
during the incident itself.
As you're interacting, you're interfacing
with the insurance company
with its people and its investigators.
You want to be making sure,
I really am telling the full details here
rather than just a cursory overview
or something that we didn't
review very carefully.
And then, so it can be easy
in the heat of the moment not
to be really careful
about what you say to the
cyber insurance company
about what we were doing
or what was breached
or how the breach
happened to work or so on.
And therefore, the security team needs
to be thinking carefully about
how do we choose our words
when we answer questions
from the insurance company?
So for example, the insurance company
may say something like,
"Do you install patches
normally in 30 days?"
And it might be easy 'cause
you're busy, you just say yes,
but the truth is
maybe it's a really a
lot more complex process
in your organization.
And maybe a more accurate statement is
that you have a professional
team that reviews patches
and then, goes through a risk assessment
and then, makes decisions based
on a responsible review
of a risk assessment.
Maybe something like that
is a more accurate statement
than just quickly say, "Guess what?
We normally install
patches within 30 days."
Another practical aspect of
involving a cyber insurer
in a ransomware event is
that the insurance
company cones with people.
People start getting
involved with your incident.
And particularly in ransomware event,
the insurer's staff gets directly involved
in answering a technical problem.
The technical problem is,
are we gonna pay ransom
or are we not gonna pay ransom?
And so there's a hinge point there,
a pivot point for the
enterprise and therefore,
the security game and
executive management has
to be working with these different people,
who are helping the insurance
company make decisions.
And so other people that might be involved
from the insurance company's team
could include the insurance company
to own investigators,
as well as a payment compliance expert.
We'll talk in a couple of minutes
about why this payment
compliance expert needs
to be involved,
but the rich wider number of people,
who might be new and extra
that you have to deal with
in an incident response.
And actually the fact
that so many new people
have to participate
in incident response
could actually detract
from the value of having that insurance
because it's just incident
response just becomes more
of a bureaucratic process that it would be
without the insurance company
there in a ransomware event.
- I think Ben brought out
an important point here.
Many mature security
programs have playbooks
for incident response
to be able to do things
in a repeatable way and keep them updated.
And many security programs learn
to have a communications playbook,
how to deal with the press?
how to deal with corporate
marketing and communications
and who needs to make decisions
along the way about
communicating an incident?
I think it's almost
like you need to have a playbook like this
for dealing with the
insurance companies each year,
when they're doing these type
of audits to make sure
you're doing the right thing.
'Cause if you think about
it, an inaccurate answer may
or may not cause them
to deny you insurance,
but it could cause them to
deny you payment afterwards,
if they find out this is
not accurate response.
So playbooks for this or
incident response playbooks
including this, I think is a great point.
So let's do a little drill down
on ransomware in particular now.
So it certainly seemed really different
when ransomware broke in,
it was really just a back
almost 10 years ago now,
when we first started to see them,
it was pretty much a denial
of service attack, right?
They would capture your files
and maybe your executables
and essentially you could not do business.
But it also included this very sexy thing
of ransom and extortion demand,
which immediately caused
chief legal counsels
and others to say,
"Wait a minute, we have coverage,
if one of our executives is kidnapped,
we have ransom coverage."
Also denial of service, we
may be one of the companies.
We know what our downtime costs.
When the manufacturing lines down,
when we can't deliver the
packages or ship the goods,
we have a good handle
on cost of downtime versus
breaches, which were-
Well, what is the real cost,
if our customer information gets out?
So since ransomware was kind of exciting
and included the sexy stuff about ransom
and encryption and Bitcoin
was floating around in there,
got a lot of press coverage
and sort of caused a
lot of interest in this.
Well, insurance will pay for all that.
And as Ben said,
that's already starting to change.
One key thing, one of the
compliance regimes, HIPAA,
the Healthcare Information Portability
and Accountability Act in the US,
early on said, ransomware
counts as a breach
because if you lost control
of people's personal health information,
such that the attackers could
encrypt it, it was breached.
You lost control of it
just because they chose not
to expose it, doesn't change the fact
that you lost control of it.
And that's what the regulations say.
Now, many more compliance
regimes are starting
to have that same interpretation.
Basically, if the attackers
could get the critical data
and encrypt it,
they could also breach it
and increasingly today,
we're seeing them do both in the past six
to nine months, really
most of 2020 and 2021, most
of the ransomware attacks, if
you said, we're not paying,
they started exposing your information
or you might've paid for it
and they got them running again.
Then they said, "Well,
now you need to pay,
so we don't expose the information."
So the bottom line is ransomware
attacks are just the same
as breaches from how
expensive they can be,
how complicated they can be
and how they really need to be avoided
versus hope that something's
going to pay for it all.
So that's just the
sorta ransomware did
bring some unique aspects,
but in reality,
it's just another malware
or a security incident.
- So a common comment I hear
from a professional incident
responders on ransomware is
that the insured enterprise
oftentimes is surprised,
once they get into the incident.
Exactly, what does their insurance cover
and what does it not cover?
And that motivates the
security team, as well
as the executives to
think about all of this
in advance and try to
understand what coverage
do we actually have, so
that we're not surprised,
when we're in the heat of the incident.
There are stories where the negotiations
between the insurance company
and the insured enterprise
can be kind of surprising
and testing over whether to pay ransom
or whether not to pay a ransom.
So the insurance company
oftentimes has a policy
that says we will pay a ransom,
but we'll also make them the
cost of business interruption.
And the insurance company
can decide a ransom is likely
to be lower than the cost
of business interruption,
if the enterprise tries to recover
from ACA and therefore, there are stories
of insurance companies putting pressure
on the insured enterprise to
go ahead and pay the ransom.
Now, the insurance companies
will make very clear final decision
whether to pay ransom lies
with the insured enterprise.
Nevertheless, the insurance
company is looking at all
of that ransom pay that
I think I can negotiate
that down to something
that's not that large.
And it's gonna be a lot less
than all the business
interruption of trying to recover
from a backup or some
other kind of recovery.
And so the insurance
company might now gently
say something like,
"You know, you got a million dollars
of coverage for recovering
business interruption.
Ah, I think you made some mistakes.
And I think that's why you
would suffer ransomware."
So I'm gonna argue, you're not entitled
to so much harborage for
business interruption.
And therefore, you better just go ahead
and agree to pay the ransomware
and let me reimburse you for that.
And that might not be
in the best interest or desires
of the insured enterprise.
Each insured enterprise
may not want to pay ransom.
It may not like the
publicity of paying ransom.
It may not like politics
or the morality paying ransom,
but the insurance company
may have a little different priority
and that may come as a surprise
to the insured enterprise.
Another complexity around paying ransom
is the United States Treasury
Department has recently
re-emphasized something
that the insurance companies
have always known, but there's
now more scrutiny on that.
And that is that there
are many organizations
like terrorist organizations
and known hacker groups
who have been sanctioned
by the United States government.
And when the government
imposes sanctions it says
and American business like
the insured enterprise
like the insurance company
may not do business
with these sanctioned entities.
And therefore, before the
insurance company can participate
in the payment of ransom, it has to check
with the Office of Foreign Asset Control
of the United States Treasury
see if they can figure out who
they're doing business with,
who they're trying to get
to try to pay the ransom to.
And whether that party is
on the disfavored sanctioned parties list.
That's like difficult
and challenging type of problem
and raises an additional
layer of in effect, red tape
for reaching the final conclusion
that we're gonna pay ransomware.
From the security team's
perspective, it means
"We need to be working multiple layers
of a resolution to this at the same time."
Maybe we're going to pay ransom,
but maybe the insurance company will have
to pull out at the last minute,
maybe we will recover
from the backup or something else.
- So yeah, some of this reminds me back
to lobsters and market pricing,
because less than a year,
before that OFAC Advisory,
the FBI had actually come out
and said, "Well, it's up to the business
to make the risk decision
about paying off or not."
Whereas for decades, standard
law enforcement advice
was do not pay kidnappers,
do not pay them off.
So the guidance at the top
and the law enforcement part is changing
about as rapidly as the pricing.
So let me do a couple of drill down
on some case studies
here that I picked out
and I tried to do a little
bit of numerical analysis on.
So the first one is a small company,
less than 500 employees and the
revenue range you see there.
They were- had a phishing attack where one
of their users fell for a phishing email,
even though they did
the usual phish training
and all that good stuff
and that person got their PC compromised.
The bad guys had control of it.
They were able to go
through that person's email
and they found a spreadsheet
and that spreadsheet had
the personal information
of 28,000 customers, didn't
have credit card numbers
or bank numbers,
wasn't really one of those
type of financial incidents,
but it had telephone
number company, all kinds
of information that could be
used for all kinds of fraud.
And this company took it seriously,
their obligation to their customers.
So they really wanted to go fully
in protecting their customers.
Now it turns out
this small company did have
a cyber insurance policy.
It was 2 million in coverage
with a $25,000 deductible
that cost them $14,000 when they paid it.
As they cleaned up this
incident and notified customers
and did everything,
they had about little under
one and a half million,
1.4 million of invoiceable cost charges
from third party consultant firms
or other things where they had hard cost,
where they had to spend money,
but they had roughly equal to that,
if not, a little more of internal cost
of people's time and other things that had
to be done to clean up
and mitigate the cost
to make sure this could not happen again.
Now, let me repeat that, part of the cost
of an incident is making
sure it doesn't happen again.
It's not, "Oh, good.
The next time it happens,
we'll get paid again."
So when you look at this particular choice
for this small company, they spent
about 3 million of the-
The damage was 3 million.
The deductible was 25,000.
There was a 14K premium.
So they essentially spent 3.039 million
and they could've gotten back 1.4 million.
They still would have a cost
exposure of over 1.6 million
after this,
even after paying insurance.
This company actually
decided not to make a claim.
They felt
that they should've protected themselves
against this anyway.
They also were afraid their
insurance would get canceled.
And if something else
happened, they'd be covered.
So they actually did not
even make a claim here.
Which many of us,
I have a daughter who
made me be very friendly
with auto repair companies
and as many times, I didn't make a claim
when she smashed into things.
So what I used to do at Gartner
and I did here was always,
it was estimate, okay.
How much would it have
cost you to avoid this?
So in this case, it turns out,
they were using Outlook 365
and there had been a update
in the critical security controls
or what are called the templates
for how to do Outlook 365 securely.
In this case,
what the bad guys did was
insert a forwarding rule
in this person's email.
So in the spreadsheet, once you send it
to the intended recipient,
it also sent it to the bad guys
and she didn't notice.
But there's ways to prevent
external connections
from changing those forwarding rules.
Basic, as you know, the equivalent
of group policy objects.
If they had done a pen test
that would have found that path
and found that they were
behind in the latest guidance,
they would have avoided this
attack and roughly, you know,
figure a couple of man month
or so and throw the costs in 125K
and more than the cost of
the policy for that year.
But even with that cost one, one tenth
of what it cost them
to have that incident.
Now, if they really wanted
to go further and say,
"Well, yeah, that was this incident."
But there's other phishing attacks
and ransomware attacks and things
that don't use just voting
rules and Office 365 things,
we could easily close the holes around.
But what if we went to
two-factor authentication?
So everybody for their email,
it could just be a reusable password.
If somebody got phished
and the attacker know had their password
with two-factor
authentication, we'd be safe.
Well, everybody, we all
know that's more expensive.
It's not that expensive
for small companies
from a hardware point of
view and installation point
of view with cell phones, text
messaging, the cell phones.
There's hardly any cost when
you get right down to it.
It's really annoying.
We just used to be,
"We can't get users to
stand though, to do that.
They'll never do that.
They'll scream at us.
The CEO will tell us to stop."
Of course, most people
at home are doing that
for their bank accounts now already
and they're doing it for PayPal
and they're doing it for Venmo
two-factor authentication.
So it's not that hard to get done
that would've caused I'm
being a little optimistic
in 150K,
but say it would have
been 250K, still cheaper
than what they spent
on that first incident.
And still let's say, raise
it up to 5 to 10 years
of the premium, yet they
were protected forever.
So this is small company example
and sometimes it's easier to talk
about the solutions cost avoid
and things that don't scale.
Let's look at a public one.
This was a very public here in the,
where I live, I'm in the
Baltimore, Maryland area.
So back in May 19, 2019, the city
of Baltimore had a major ransomware event
that shut them down completely.
Schools and other parts across the city,
tax payment and traffic revenue
and all that kind of stuff
was over 10,000 computers.
And the demand was for 13 Bitcoins,
where'd they get these numbers sometimes?
Back then, a Bitcoin was worth
a measly $5,000 (laughs).
Now Bitcoin, I don't have any idea,
I meant to check before we did
this, what it's worth today.
But when I did the slide,
13 Bitcoins is like $650,000
that was the ransom demand.
The city said we don't
pay no stinking ransom.
They were not going to pay the ransom.
So they suffered through the incident.
It took weeks, several weeks to recover.
Their hard cost estimates were much
of it was invoiceable
because they did not have
that much internal security expertise
that it cost them 10 million
to get things back up
and running and to mitigate the problems
that enabled the ransomware demand.
And then, they came up with an estimate.
Remember, there's a city,
which you know, county/city
in Maryland, Baltimore
that there was $8 million
in lost or delayed revenue.
Now that's some of that you
could point to hard cost.
Some of it's delayed
revenue, you might end up.
Well, we don't pay for delayed revenue,
it was been talked about
there's lots of exclusions
and terminology and so on.
But basically,
they just figured this cost them
about $20 million, this incident.
So the decision was made at the CIO level
and at the state board of
directors of regents level
and all that kind of stuff
to obtain cyber insurance,
in case this was to happen again.
So for 2020, for $800,000 or
the $1 million deductible,
they got the $20 million
cyber insurance policy
and had no problems that year.
See if you get insurance,
it's like backing up
your hard (laughs) drive.
Pay for the insurance,
nothing bad happens.
The next year,
even though they had nothing
bad happened the year before,
lots of things that happened in 2020.
So for 2021, the premium
went up to 950,000,
almost a 20% increase
for the same amount of coverage
and the same deductible.
So notice that the deductible,
the $1 million deductible,
you'd have to have a major incident
for you to break that.
And if you did all that
mitigation beforehand
and if you're able to institutionalize,
whether we went to
two-factor authentication
or we're going to do a pen test every year
and we're going to keep
ourselves more secure.
You start looking at,
well, how much would it have
cost to totally avoid this
and harden ourselves such
that this particular level
of attack, not saying you'd be invincible,
but for this level of
sophistication and this sort
of phishing-driven attack,
how could we avoid it?
In my rough estimate
between 3 and 5 million
dollars, not insignificant
for an agency this size,
that many computers.
So if you look at that, that's
three to five years worth
of payment of the premiums they're paying.
So, you know, I don't know about you,
but I make a lot of my
decisions on the payback period.
You know, if I make an investment,
how long does it take
to pay back the cost,
whether it's, you know,
replacing a car or whatever.
So in many of these things,
you start seeing a five-year
less payback period.
You're going to start to be able
to convince board of directors.
Now we can do this, and this
will be cheaper in the long run
that obtaining this
level of cyber insurance,
maybe can I obtain a
lower level or something,
but a part of what we can do in security
to avoid incidents has to
be part of the discussion.
We have to be able to provide that level
of information and be part
of the discussion around obtaining
cyber insurance policies.
So there's some other
things to think about.
These, there's not very good
data out here on any of these.
I've tried to collect this
data for several years.
It's hard.
So to kind of think that well, you pay
and they can still go ahead
and just keep your money
or then do the breach
that seems to occur maybe
to 20%, 30% of the time at most.
So paying generally in the majority
of time does preclude more
damage, but not always,
but you know, the other theory I've seen
in other areas is you get
put on the stupid list.
Hey, they fell for it.
They got attacked.
Then say, let's hit,
let somebody else is gonna hit you later.
Really trying to find that out, 10 to 20%,
not that off all that often.
So these are things we'd
like to hold down security
that may or may not
really be true factors.
Will your insurance pay for ransom?
Ben's got through most of that.
So bottom line, when I want to leave
before we start reaching the end
with the recommendations,
you will have to fix the problems.
You have to spend the
same in cybersecurity,
no matter what.
You're not, cybersecurity
does not cap things.
It's not like homeowner's insurance,
where you get replacement
value merely reduces the cost
of an incident by a fixed amount.
And you will still be liable,
if you're doing stupid
things and you get breached,
you don't leave the chicken
salad, the egg salad out
in the picnic overnight, and
then eat it the next morning.
Even if you have
something to help you deal
with the food poisoning you're gonna get.
So, let me walk through
some sorta get back
to work and then we'll get Ben
to sum up sort of really key point here.
SANS is always when you take our course,
what can you do when you get back
to work the next day and
RSA has added this sort
of next month, six month look as well.
So the very first thing is
understand, where's your company?
How does your company make
decisions about insurance?
Is it the chief legal
officer, finance officer,
CEO, operations officer, be part of that.
Security should be involved
in that, understand existing coverages
and be part of any decisions
around cybersecurity
or any of those other
policies Ben mentioned
that might cover things.
Get that point across
to the people, making those
decisions, cybersecurity,
cyber insurance can only
reduce the cost, not cap it.
Then I think equally important is to say,
"Are we really capable of self-insurance?"
Can I stand up and say, "Here's our gaps,
if we close those gaps and
here's how long it'll take
and roughly what it will cost."
I believe we can avoid
these common incidents.
And then, we only use insurance
for what it's meant for, uncommon things,
not everyday occurrences
that might happen to us
'cause we were below the level
of due diligence or due care.
In the long run, you know,
it's a jump-starting opportunity to say,
"Boy, you know, I've been looking
for a way to sneak in
two-factor authentication.
This is it.
This is how we can get it in."
If we can say, getting past ransomware,
getting past phishing will enable us
to avoid all these costs
and incidents in cybersecurity insurance.
Here's my chance.
And a great way to do that.
To work with senior management boards
or CEOs is to do a tabletop exercise.
- Tabletop exercise
enables the security team
to think through carefully,
how's this all going
to play out, when we do have
that ransomware incident?
And important part of thinking
things through is come
to know the insurance team.
As I've mentioned before,
the insurer is gonna bring
a team to participate
in your process of resolving
this ransomware event.
So there can be multiple
phases of tabletop exercise.
There's tabletop exercise
with the security team
and the insurer's team.
And then, at different phases,
you can involve your executives
and even involve the board of directors.
But coming to know,
with some surety,
what the insurance company
thinks its policy covers.
So going through different kinds
of scenarios with the insurance
company's team saying,
"Okay, if it looks like
this, you cover that."
What are you going to say, insurance team,
if we see that the attackers are making
this kind of a demand?
How do we evaluate insurance
team, the various kinds
of risks that are involved
with different scenarios.
So how do you evaluate the
risk if we pay the ransom,
but we still have that possibility
that we'll be re-attacked
or that the data will
still be released anyway.
So walking through this
kind of a tabletop exercise
with your team, your executives,
but also with the insurer's
team can be very enlightening.
And you'd much rather
have this enlightenment,
before the ransomware happens
rather than during that
heat of the moment.
In addition to thinking through
how the ransomware will be resolved,
this tabletop exercise can
also help to enlighten you
and your team on how do
we mitigate the root cause
and avoid the root cause
and actually avoid this thing
from actually happening.
So all of this leads
to a more secure type of
environment in your organization.
- Okay, with that,
that's just about the end of presentation
and we'll leave you some resources
for additional information
and click on any
of the URLs there and get
the great information.
And finally, the best way
we can all avoid attacks is
to get better at security,
get more skilled people out there.
There's an initiative out there
called CyberStart America,
where young kids in high school
and early college age
can get free scholarships
and get two-year Bachelor
of Applied Security
and get high paying jobs
and help fight this fight.
So you see the URL there
for CyberStart America.
If you have kids or your kids have kids
or nieces, nephews,
neighbors, friends, whatever.
Get them interested in it,
let's get more young people
and more skilled people in our field.
So with that, thanks for attending.
And I look forward to working
with you in the future.
- Thank you.