- Hi, I'm Jon Oltsik.
I'm a senior principal analyst
and fellow at the
Enterprise Strategy Group.
And I'm honored to have my good friend
and colleague, Candy Alexander
joining me, hi, Candy.
- Hi Jon, and I am of
course, Candy Alexander,
International President of the ISSA.
- Great, so we are presenting
and this is on the ESG/ISSA research,
The Life and Times of
Cybersecurity Professionals.
We're not strangers here.
We've done this several years in a row,
and this is our fifth annual project.
This year, we had 489 completed,
and these are ISSA
members and ISSA partners.
Candy, you'll go into that.
These are security professionals
from all types of organizations;
small, medium, and large, international.
We don't have the numbers
here, but we will have them
in the final report, and we
don't filter by industry.
So we have lots of different
industries represented
in the final report.
We'll also look at any of the
statistical significant things
that we find in different industries.
So Candy, what did I miss?
- So I just want to extend
a heartfelt thank-you
to our partners at ISSA who
helped provide the responses.
So those partners are CSA
or Cloud Security Alliance,
SANS, IAPP, and the ECC Council.
So again, thank you very much
for your help and participation
for it really needs to be
a cybersecurity professional
response, so thanks.
- Yeah, I concur, Candy,
we couldn't have done it
without you, thank you so much.
It really does make this
a worthwhile project
to have your participation.
So here is the RSA equation,
and our intent is to educate our audience.
We hope that you can learn
from what we're doing,
and we really hope that
you can take this data,
which we really have a lot of pride in
and apply it to your personal career.
And so let me go into
that more specifically,
how can you apply this research?
So if you're a cybersecurity professional,
you're getting feedback on
what your peers are thinking.
So compare where you are
to where they are and then
assess your opportunities,
and where do you need to spend some time?
Where are you doing very well?
What insights can you
gather from your peers?
If you're senior executives,
you get to understand what the
mindset is of your employees.
So kind of what are they thinking of?
How satisfied are they with their career?
Where are they struggling?
Where do they need help?
And really important for cybersecurity is
how can you retain them?
How can you make them happy?
And then if you're a cybersecurity vendor,
these are your customers speaking.
Your customers are going
through a lot of stress.
It's a stressful, stressful job.
So how can this data help
you relate better to them?
And if you can relate better to them,
you can probably build
better relationships.
So Candy, what's your thought here?
- So my little add to this
is that if you are, you know,
either a cyber professional
individual contributor
or a manager in an organization,
look for the golden nuggets
'cause they are in here
as to help providing
justification back to either HR
or business executives or
management for justification,
for either additional
training dollars or resources.
So we will attempt to offer those pointers
as we go through this presentation.
- Good point, okay. So
let's get into the research.
This was a new question for this year.
It was really driven by a focus
group that Candy and I did
with five different
cybersecurity professionals
at all levels of their careers.
So we wanted to understand how they found
their current jobs.
And what you see on the
right side of this is
kind of old school job
hopping kind of stuff,
where either I found a job that was posted
by the organization, or I was
contacted by the recruiter.
The key takeaway to me,
Candy, is that high percentage
of people, the biggest percentage said
it's networking with industry contacts.
Now, if I'm an entry-level
person that's not possible.
But once I've established myself,
I am going to go and look
for those opportunities
where I've worked with people I know,
I work with people I like,
I work with people I can learn from.
And this is a bit self-serving
because networking
with industry context
is what you do at ISSA,
but it's clearly working, Candy.
- It is, it is.
And you know, I would
counter that point that,
yes, it's difficult for entry-level,
but there's no reason why they can't.
You know, get involved in
your local communities.
There's tons of meetups, security meetups.
Go to an ISSA chapter meeting
locally or now virtually
and/or get involved in any
of these professional
organizations like CSA, OWASP.
I mean, it's just amazing how
many resources are out there.
Start talking to people.
- And Candy, with ISSA,
you have special programs
for entry-level people
and people who are trying
to get into their careers, correct?
- Absolutely, if there's
anything that I hear
as a common message
throughout ISSA memberships is
that I as the same
members want to give back
to the profession, and
that means help grow
the next generation coming in.
So you know, if you are
an entry-level person,
not yet in the profession,
start talking to folks,
they want to help you.
- That's a wonderful message
from ISSA to the community.
In this one, this is a
repeat from last year,
but it's really important
to hammer this home.
So we asked these 400-plus
cybersecurity professionals,
how long does it take
to become proficient?
And what you see here is
that the bulk of people
that we surveyed think it's
somewhere between two years
and five years.
So it's a lifelong commitment.
It's a lifelong profession.
And Candy, I is acquainted
with being a physician.
If you become a physician,
you've gone to medical school,
that doesn't stop your education,
you have to continually keep up
with different medical
innovations, different research.
And it's the same for cybersecurity.
- Absolutely, if not
more so, because I mean,
you look at our world today,
everything's based on technology.
And you know, years ago when
I first got into technology,
I was told technology back in the 1800,
even first part of the 1900s,
they changed every 50 years,
technology innovations.
You look at what's happening today.
It's changing yearly,
monthly, it's just insane.
And everything we do in the cyber,
you know, realm is, you know,
to support that technology.
So how else can we keep up
with what's going on in technology
if we aren't constantly
learning, and you know,
we're not even talking about mastering.
So you know, when we look at this slide,
it's really important to
understand as you mentioned,
this is a lifelong investment.
And that's why when we talk
to cyber professionals,
they are all passionate about learning.
And that's what we need,
is to continuously learn.
It doesn't happen overnight.
- No, it does not.
So this is new and this
is really important.
So we asked again, our panel,
what advice would you give
to someone who's interested
in getting into cybersecurity?
And I'll just focus on a couple of things.
So get a basic.
And the key is basic certification.
So get a baseline that
will be requirement.
Don't dwell on certifications,
which we'll talk about,
but get a basic certification.
Once again, join a professional
industry organization,
network with your peers,
and then find a mentor.
So this has been key in my
career in different roles,
but find a mentor, just
track your progress.
People are there to help, Candy.
- Absolutely, and you
know, I'll say something.
And for those of you,
who've seen me speak before
on this topic, don't get caught
into that certification game.
You know, again, the whole key is
basic cybersecurity certifications.
There are five that our
members constantly say are
the top ones to go for
that are more vlauable,
that's CISSP, CISM, CISA, CompTIA A+,
and Certified Ethical Hacker.
So you know, to help you decide
which route you want to go,
get somebody, you know, who's
already in a profession.
And as Jon mentioned,
you know, find a mentor.
And it's not just one mentor, by the way.
I have many mentors,
according to what my need is
for information or knowledge or learning.
So you know, don't get
stuck on the traditional,
you know, "You want to be my mentor,"
'cause that doesn't work.
Look at the diversity
of the knowledge we need
and then the diversity of mentorship
to happen to accomplish that.
- Good points, and Candy, I know this is
really important to you.
Again, this is something
we've looked at in the past,
but go ahead.
- So again, certifications
versus hand-on experience.
It's really important to understand
the whole purpose of the
certifications in the first place.
The whole reason why they
were developed many years ago,
starting with the most notable one, (ISC)²
and the CSSP is we as a
profession, had really no way
of articulating what that we
have a baseline of knowledge,
or what that, you know,
baseline of knowledge is.
So the certifications began with that.
It's a means to articulate
our starting point of what our
experience and knowledge are,
but the key is their
experience and knowledge.
So you know, again,
really, I caution folks,
don't go after every
certification out there,
because that's not going to help you.
You know, you can see
here through our data
that it is experience,
in conjunction with that certification,
that's going to give you what you need.
So they really are hand in hand.
- Good point, this is an important slide.
And this is the first
time we've done this.
And next year, I think we'll go deeper.
But we wanted to
understand the relationship
between security teams and other teams,
other functional groups
within organizations.
Security is a team sport.
So this is really important
on how these organizations collaborate.
Now we'll go a little bit
deeper into the IT relationship
and the business relationship,
but a couple of things stand out,
the fair or poor relationships
with people like the board
or groups like the board of directors, HR,
lines of business.
Security needs to be embedded
into the organization.
We need a culture of cybersecurity.
That means the business
has to meet us halfway,
but that means that security
needs to be proactive, Candy.
- Absolutely, this has been
(laughing) my soapbox item
of this past year.
You know, oftentimes,
we talk about we need
to support the business,
we, security folks.
So we wanna teach them about security.
Do we really want our CEOs to
come to a security conference?
Do we really want them to understand
the ins and outs of security?
I would argue not.
We want them to run the business,
but we want to be able to have
that knowledge-based discussion with them
as to what's the business and
how can we best support that?
When we look at this data, we
can most certainly identify
those target groups that
I would suggest we go
and have a conversation with,
and the conversation isn't in regards
to educating them about security.
The conversation is us getting educated
as to what their business is.
For when we have that conversation, we,
as the cybersecurity professionals
are able to articulate
or understand the business risk, and then,
we are able to mitigate that
risk through security measures.
So you know, when we walk in and say,
"Well, we need to, you know,
comply with X, Y, or Z,"
that's the wrong conversation.
We need to understand the business,
so we can understand the risk
and then propose the mitigation
through security controls.
So this is your target list.
This is the target list of
who you wanna talk with.
- Well said, Candy, I
mean, it's understanding
the business process,
what data is being used.
And like you said, the threat models.
- Yes, absolutely, Jon.
- So now this year, we were
very cognizant of getting,
not just understanding the problems,
but proposing some solutions.
So we asked our panel of
cybersecurity professionals,
what advice would you
give your organization
to improve the relationship
between cybersecurity and IT?
And this is the data that you see.
And there's a couple
of themes here, Candy,
without even going into the
data, it's mood shift-left.
So get security involved
earlier in the process.
And then it's cross-functionality,
if there's such a word.
The IT people need to understand security.
The security people need to understand IT.
They need to work together
as a team with common goals
and common metrics,
not against each other.
- Right, and it goes back to the age-old,
you know, statement.
It's more expensive to bolt
security on the beginning.
I mean, we've all heard that.
But, you know, what does that really mean?
And it does mean shift-left.
When you look at the different
models that are out there
from a security maturity perspective,
it all states bring us in security,
that is, in at the beginning,
when you're doing your
requirements, you know,
collection and things like that.
So you know, often in
the past couple of years,
we've heard the whole thing about DevOps.
What is DevOps?
That's the combination and expediting
of development into operations.
So they've, you know, shortened that cycle
from an agility perspective.
We need to do the same thing
from a security perspective.
So just as they shorten the DevOps,
you know, to combine those,
we need to really incorporate security
into that same mentality.
And very much though, from the
cross-functional perspective,
where, you know, you have,
development, you have operations.
But also look at it from
a quality perspective.
We don't look at quality enough,
and one could really argue
that security is very much
a component of quality.
So you know, again, when
we look at making sure,
if you will, that all
of the bases are covered
from an IT project perspective,
why wouldn't you incorporate
security into that?
Because again, when we
talked about understanding
the business and understanding the risks,
this is where we're going to mitigate them
through cybersecurity and
cybersecurity controls.
And that really needs to
be in partnership with IT.
So the need for a paradigm shift,
if I might use another cliche,
is at the utmost right now.
We need to put behind us
the us-versus-them mentality
and look at it as a cross-functional team.
We each have a part to play.
- Very true, and that rings
true too when we look at it,
look at this slide, Advice
for Improving the Relationship
with Business Management.
Once again, 41% encouraging
cybersecurity participation
in all business planning and strategy.
There's a typo there, but it should say
And again, it's that shifting left.
The more we understand
about the business planning
and strategy, the more that we understand
about who's touching the
data or who needs access
to an application.
Is there sensitive data involved?
Are we moving that
sensitive data to someplace
where we don't have control of it?
Are we using cloud, are we using SaaS?
So the more we know upfront,
the better we can put
together these models,
the better cross-functional
processes we can define.
- Right, yeah, when we
talk about threat modeling,
we have one perception
as a security profession.
But let's really, you know,
understand that we need
to understand the business
so we can create those threat
models for the business,
and then go back and say, "Okay,
you know, business owners,
do you really want to expand
into say, for example, Russia
as a business model?"
Yes, they might be,
you know, a high demand
for the product service,
but let's look at the
pros and cons of that.
So again, not using security
terminology, if you notice,
but you using common lay
people's terminology.
What are the pros and
cons of going to Russia?
And then you lay them out
and of course, put forth
the security controls and costs.
- Yeah, time is flying by here, Candy.
So let's go on to the next slide, so...
And this is data that
we've seen year after year.
And I called it a
cybersecurity training paradox.
91% agree that cybersecurity
professionals must keep up
with their skills or their
organizations at a disadvantage.
So 91%, but 59% agree,
"While I try to keep up on
my cybersecurity skills,
it's hard to do so given
the demands of my job."
That's the paradox.
Candy, how the heck do we handle that?
- So at the beginning of our
session here, we talked about,
you know, we'll point
out the golden nuggets
to use for justification.
So golden nugget alert here it is, guys,
take this slide, take this data,
use this for justification
for your training
and/or additional resources.
- Very true and understand
that your people are
under a lot of pressure,
they've got a lot of work,
and you have to appreciate
that they have to have
time too for training.
- Yup.
- So this is another one we
asked for the first time.
It's basically a best
practice that you get 40 hours
of training per year as a
cybersecurity professional.
We wanted to see how people
were doing versus that 40%.
And I think there's good
news and bad news here.
So there is good news.
At 54% say, "I've had more
than 40 hours of training."
24% said, "I've had about 40 hours."
But a pretty significant percent say
that they haven't had
40 hours of training.
So that's concerning to me.
And then the other thing
is let's define training.
I mean, if you are
watching videos or webinars
for CPE credit, okay, we understand
that you need CPE credit,
but that's not training.
This is all about really
understanding your craft,
improving your craft.
So I think it's important for
cybersecurity professionals
to ask themselves that question, Candy.
- Absolutely, I'll just say, you know,
be aware of the infomercial
that we have now adopted
with this whole new
COVID-19 pandemic world,
just really pick and choose
as to what do you get?
What's your value?
If it's more than a CPE, do it.
Because otherwise, sure, put on, you know,
that in the background
while you're having lunch,
but you know, really look at the value.
- It's true, I mean, it's your career.
And to that point, we asked the
21% who didn't have 40 hours
of training why?
What are the reasons why?
And it comes down to not
surprisingly time and money.
So time, 33%, one third said,
"I don't have enough time."
Well, you have to make the time.
And as an employer, as a manager,
you have to make sure your
employees have the time,
or you can find the time
because their training,
their skill development
is equated to your risk
and the risk of your business,
so that's really important.
And then money.
Some people say, "Well, my
organization doesn't pay for it.
So I can't do it."
And certainly, as an employer,
you have to internalize that
and understand whether you can fund
or change compensation models to fund it.
But also as a cybersecurity professional,
you have to invest in your career.
So sometimes it will cost you,
but an investment will pay
ROI dividends over time
because you'll become better,
you'll be more in demand.
You'll make more money, Candy.
- I agree, and I mean, you
said it all, nothing to add.
- Sometimes I do that,
not often, but sometimes.
So we're gonna shift over
to the cybersecurity skills shortage.
So this is a topic
we've covered for years,
and Candy, disappointing, 57% still say
that they've been impacted
by the skills shortage.
I don't really understand
the 10% who don't know.
Maybe they're small organizations,
maybe they have multiple
jobs, but once again,
more than 50% have been impacted
by the cybersecurity skills shortage.
Those people who have been impacted,
we asked them, what's the impact?
And there's always
this kind of same things
every year, Candy.
But this year it's more pronounced.
So 62% said there's an increasing workload
on existing staff,
and that's been exacerbated
by COVID, by work-from-home.
So that's concerning to
me, if I'm CSO, as you are,
that's concerning to me
because you can't just pile
more work onto people and
expect quality work in return.
The other thing that's
really important here is
the percentage of people saying
there's a high burnout rate
or attrition rate for the
cybersecurity staff, 38%.
So we're piling more work on people
and they're burning out, Candy.
That can't be a good recipe for success.
- Absolutely not, and yeah, I
think this is just the sign,
we really have not identified the solution
and we need to keep working it.
And again, just to emphasize,
if your organization is not doing for you,
you need to do for yourself.
So go get that skill that you need.
And you know, keep pushing back.
Use this information to
get additional resources.
- Yeah, again, and if you're a manager,
this is what your people
are going through.
So how how can you rectify that situation?
How can you address it?
Has the skills shortage
gotten worse, Candy?
44% say yes.
And probably the most
meaningful statistic on this is
that only 5% say has improved
over the past few years.
So there is no cavalry
riding up to save us.
There won't be any massive influx
of highly skilled
professionals that we can hire.
And again, Candy, you
always remind me of this,
is the skills shortage
isn't just about staffing.
It's about skills.
So if the skills shortage has gotten worse
over the past few years, you're
probably less able to defend
the company to recognize threats
than you were a few years ago.
- Right, absolutely, and you know,
the thing that, it's
exasperating to me is that
it's been getting worse
over the past few years.
And now if we're looking at
this data, since the past year,
and it's gotten even worser,
(laughing) then, you know,
we need to find a solution, so yeah.
- And again, you can't hope
that some external force
is going to come in.
You have to take this on yourself.
- Yep.
- So the biggest factors,
this is from a cybersecurity
professionals perspective.
What are the biggest factors contributing
to the skills shortage?
My organization doesn't offer
competitive compensation.
Well, in a seller's market,
that's gonna kill you every time.
So you really can't be cheap here.
You have to be able to hire
people at a compensation level.
That's commensurate with what
everybody else is paying.
That's the reality of it.
But there's a couple of other things
that are much more interesting to me,
because money is always a concern.
So the HR department at my
organization doesn't understand
the skills needed.
Well, there's a disconnect there.
That means the HR department
isn't recruiting well.
And it means that there's a disconnect
between cybersecurity and HR.
My organization's not in
an attractive industry
for cybersecurity professionals.
Well, what can you do to overcome that,
become a cybersecurity center
of excellence, perhaps,
so that maybe you're not
in the right industry,
but you're offering the right things
for a cybersecurity professional career?
And then this one kills me,
job postings are unrealistic.
And this is what we hear, Candy,
from entry-level people is
there's an entry-level job posted,
but it requires three years of experience.
A CISSP, maybe other certifications,
just a disconnect there too.
- Absolutely, when I look at this data,
this very much is a link to
the previous, how, you know,
it's gotten worse over the past year.
So here's my take in my read on this.
HR, you're right, they
don't understand what we do.
Neither does the business,
because often times,
it is the business that says to HR,
"We need to get a security person."
So HR says, "Okay, you
know, what do you need?"
And it's all compliance-driven, right?
So again, collectively
who are in the profession,
we need to educate the business
of as to what our job is,
what is our job?
Our job is to understand
the risk of the business
and offer mitigation strategies,
and then oversee those
mitigation strategies
through security controls.
That includes, you know, compliance.
So you know you can look at
those last three data points
and equate it to that.
This is our failure, as
a collective profession,
to not have educated the
business as to what it is we do.
And therefore they don't invest in us.
They pick the wrong, you
know, job descriptions.
They pick bad after bad, they
pick, you know, a resume,
I'm sorry, a job
description on the internet
that has absolutely nothing to do
with what they really want
or what they really need,
but they post it anyways,
because that's what, fill in the blank.
Acme Medical you wanted, or
Acme Manufacturer you wanted.
So they must know what
they're talking about.
So with bad chasing bad,
we need to stop that cycle.
- Yeah, and the other thing
that you always remind me of is
that people need to be more creative,
not just look for IT professionals
or cybersecurity
professionals, changing jobs.
Look outside, or think outside the box.
- Yeah.
- So are organizations
taking the necessary actions
to address the impact of the
cybersecurity skills shortage?
Candy, Candy, Candy, Candy,
59% said, "My organization
could be doing much more
or my organization should
be doing somewhat more."
So let's hold that thought because
I've got one slide and then
we'll address that specifically.
But here are the areas, the acute areas
of cybersecurity skills shortages.
And Candy, we always see the big three,
cloud computing security,
security analytics,
and our analysis and investigations
and application security.
And just given what's
happened in the last year,
work-from-home, that accelerated
a lot of cloud initiatives,
digital transformation initiatives.
Cloud security came out on
top, but all three of those are
just acute shortages.
- Right.
- Okay, now back to my
organization isn't doing enough.
So we asked people, "What
could your organization do?"
And there's some suggestions here.
So increase the commitment
to cybersecurity training.
Candy, we've been dwelling on this,
that it's a lifelong pursuit
that organizations need
to be sensitive to the training
needs of their employees,
and then employees need to
really jump on training.
So this is one thing you can
do, is increase your training.
Increase compensation, we
talked about provide incentives
for certifications and
participation in industry events.
You want well-rounded
security professionals.
And then I'll just stop at this one,
but create or improve a
cybersecurity internship program.
You know, from the ISSA perspective,
there just aren't enough
internship programs.
Now, if you bring in interns,
let's say you bring in summer interns,
they'll turn into full-time
employees if they're good.
So it becomes a pipeline for you.
Now, of course, you have to train,
you have to dedicate resources
to training junior people,
but that creates again an influx of talent
that you can then train
and hopefully retain.
- Right, so I think when
I look at this slide,
what it says to me is that
businesses and organizations are
just not investing
properly or appropriately
into the cybersecurity
department, if you will.
So you know, that means training.
That means, you know,
compensation, the feeling of value.
So we're talking about
basic investment decisions.
So taking the time to really
look at the compensation,
to look at the value add,
and it really comes down to,
in my opinion, the lack of investment.
You know, we talked
offline about organizations
really are hesitant, and
providing that investment
of training and compensation
and you know, instilling loyalty.
- That's very true.
- The staff are going to
jump-shift as soon as they get,
you know, whatever training
they need or whatever.
But I think we really need
to stop that cycle as well,
and realize that, you know,
loyalty is based on investment.
If I feel valued, then I'm going to,
you know, do anything I can from my boss
because they appreciate me.
So it really needs to,
you know, be broken down
into the very simple perspective
of investment builds loyalty.
Loyalty builds good skilled people.
- So true, okay, we've got
a couple of slides left.
And I know we're getting short on time.
So is the cybersecurity
shortage overstated?
Candy, I put this one in this year
because every time I write
about the cybersecurity skills shortage,
I get feedback from cybersecurity
professionals who say,
"There's plenty of people out there.
We just don't write job
requirements or requisitions well,
or we don't recruit well."
And I would say what this
data has as told me, Candy,
is that both things can be true.
There is a pretty acute
cybersecurity skills shortage,
but at the same time, we're not
managing it or addressing it
as well as we could
creating those problems.
So yeah, some people
think it's overstated.
Most think that the amount of discussion
about it's about right.
- I agree, yeah, it's-
- Okay, and this kind of reinforces that.
So how difficult is it to
recruit new cybersecurity staff?
76% say it's either extremely difficult
or somewhat difficult.
So again, people aren't just popping in
and with the right skill sets,
you have to put the work in to find them,
and that costs money, and
this reinforces that, Candy.
- Absolutely, I have nothing to add,
but let's take a look at your next slide,
because I think that's going
to give us an idea of why.
Why recruiting is hard.
- Okay, good point, so
where is it challenging?
Who is it challenging to find?
Now, remember we said
that it takes between two
and five years to become
a proficient cybersecurity professional.
Guess what, big surprise, Candy.
Those are the people that are
really difficult to recruit.
71% said, "Those are the
difficult people to recruit."
- Right, and again, this
goes back to bad chasing bad.
I mean, how can we get
people with experience
if our entry-level jobs require three
to five years experience?
I mean, that is so
ridiculous of a statement.
So we really need to
look at how we are going
to get folks that experience.
There's been lots of,
you know, ideas shared
in regards to that internship.
You know, getting folks to volunteer,
to do security projects
through organizations
such as CSA, ISSA, and you
know, fill in the blank.
So just because you can't get paid for it
or just because you can't make $100,000
as an entry-level person,
is no reason to be deterred.
Go, if this is what you
want, come after it.
It's well worth it,
because you will fall into
that, 71% box really quickly.
- Yeah, and two quick
things for me, Candy.
Once again, this reinforces
that the more you put
into your career, the more
you'll get out of your career,
because as you increase your skill set,
increase your experience,
you're more in demand,
so you can make the money.
So don't think about money upfront.
You'll make it over time.
And the second thing is if I'm a CISO,
retention, retention, retention.
What can I do to retain my staff?
Because they're in high demand.
So if I'm not doing that,
someone else is gonna grab them.
And we know that from other
research in this project.
So onto the last slide, this
is really just wrapping up
and repeating what we talked about.
There's organizational friction.
So we have to get the cybersecurity
team involved with IT,
with the business, with HR, with legal,
much sooner and much
more, what did we say?
Cross-functionally; the training deficit.
We just dwelled on this
because it's really a problem.
And it's sort of a foundational thing.
So CISOs, are you allocating enough time
and money to training?
As Candy so aptly put it,
you use this data to justify
more budget for training
because your staffers are
crying out for more training,
and you have higher risk
if you don't train them.
And the cybersecurity,
shortage skills shortage
is not an illusion.
There are some aspects
we're not managing well,
but it's real, it's impactful.
And so you have to look
at the data we presented,
assess where you're bad, or
where you're not up to speed.
And then, like we said,
the cavalry isn't coming, what can you do?
And the one other point I'll make,
I'm stealing Candy's point.
It's not just about
staffing, it's about skills.
And that's a relationship
between the skills shortage and training.
So Candy close this out.
- I think you said it
all, great summation.
And I think, again, it's all
up to you, the professional.
Get assistance, get guidance, join ISSA,
come to a meeting, go to OWASP, go to CSA.
There are great professional
organizations out there.
You're not alone.
If you want it bad enough, go get it.
- Really well said.
And so look forward to
more from this research.
This is just a taste of the research.
There's plenty more.
We, ESG and ISSA will be publishing it.
It's available for free.
And so thanks for being here.
This is our contact information.
Candy, it's always a
pleasure presenting with you.
I always learn a lot.
And for the audience,
thanks for being here.