- [Siddhesh] Hello. I'm Siddhesh,
I'm a part of the technical team
at Tala security.
Through this session,
I'd like to help you better understand
client side threats,
the relative ease
at which web applications
have been compromised
and some actionable next steps
on what you can do in the near term
to safeguard against this new age threat.
In this session,
I'll go through an
introduction of the problem,
and then we'll spend around 10-15 minutes
going over a live attack demo.
And then lastly, we're going to finish off
with some of the defenses
that you can apply
to help your organization.
No prior knowledge is required
to understand this session.
And this presentation is for anybody
that uses a website
or is responsible for web security.
By the end of this session,
you'll hopefully have an understanding
of how vulnerable web applications are
on the client side and the increasing need
to implement client side security.
Let's get started.
I'm sure everyone has heard of
the recent SolarWinds breach
and the large impact that it had
on several enterprises.
The part that I would like to focus on
is how software supply
chains are being exploited
and how these attacks
are gaining relevance
everywhere today.
So, let's break down the solarwinds attack
and look into some of the reasons
why it was so devastating.
First of all,
SolarWinds was a trusted SaaS vendor.
Enterprises trusted the company
and the software that they deliver.
It was widely adopted
in a single compromise
led to over 18,000 regions.
And from an attacker's point of view,
these types of attacks
are especially attractive
because they give the attackers
remote control access to their end servers
in a way.
So, this is how the
solarwinds hack went down.
And I'm sure you're thinking,
how does some IT management software
affect web application and web security?
Let me explain by quickly going
over how web architecture has evolved
over the past 10 years.
What about architecture
for the past decade
followed a trend where the applications
were server heavy and
enterprise data centers
handle the bulk of the processing.
The web browser during this time
was more of a graphical interface only.
And as we look in the
past few years to today,
the architecture has
evolved for many reasons
including optimizations
that enterprises want
in terms of speed, as well as
increased computing capacity
on the client devices.
That is your PC and your mobile devices.
As a result, today's websites
integrate dozens of third party vendors
all the way from your user analytics,
marketing tags, CDNs,
open source libraries
and so on.
This has led to third-party
vendors and libraries
loading their content directly
onto your browsers.
And this means that on average,
around 70% of what loads
on end user's browsers,
doesn't come from first
party servers at all.
Enterprises are designing client
heavy applications as a result
that are run through
JavaScript on the browser.
And these browsers are
acting as the modern-day OS.
So, this is how a typical web application
and website loads their content today.
And as you can see,
this diagram shows the
different third parties
and their multiple
locations and data centers
that are situated across the globe.
Hopefully, this sort of explains
why the internet is called the web.
So in this, your JavaScript
loads third-party JavaScript
which in turn may load fourth
and fifth party JavaScript.
This is called the
piggybacking of JavaScript.
And this creates a trust between you,
your third party, your
fourth party, and so on.
And as a result of this trust model,
it only takes one of these libraries
or dependencies or even one server
to be infected in order to
compromise your website.
And this is the main principle
that is leading to website breaches
on the client side.
And as you will notice, your data center
or any of your servers,
they were not impacted,
they were not breached
or attacked in any way.
But still, your end users,
they got infected with
this malicious JavaScript.
Google Researchers that work on Chrome,
they say that if an
attacker's able to inject
any JavaScript in end users browsers,
it is practically game over.
So now, if we combine the principles
of the SolarWinds-style
supply chain attacks
and how websites are using a large number
of third party dependencies.
The modern web has
become the perfect storm.
Here's the breakdown.
We already have JavaScript as the one
common language and framework
that powers the entire web today.
And one JavaScript can
load another JavaScript
and so on,
through the implicit trust model
that we just saw that's
present in the web today.
Finally, many popular JavaScript libraries
are deployed to over
thousands of websites.
In fact, a recent study
that Tala conducted
analyzing over 1000 websites.
The Alexa one k highlighted
the startling number
of third party services
and average website users.
And that number is 34.
What was more concerning
through this study
was the lack of security controls
that the top thousand
websites in the world
have against such types of vulnerabilities
and third party breaches.
This seems a little scary, right?
So, in the next section
I'm going to be showing
you a live attack demo
but before we switch gears,
there's one situation
that I'd like you to think about.
Imagine if one of your third parties
told you that they have been breached,
what is protecting your web application
from being compromised today?
So now, we're going to switch mode
to an attacker's point of view.
I'm going to act as an attacker now
and I'm going to share my thoughts
while we're going through
an attack together.
So as an attacker, I'm going to try
and explore the weakest part of armor
that the web application has.
I know that your WAF only
protects your servers
but the content that is served
from outside your WAF,
that's less protected.
There's a growing saying
in the industry of the past few years
that goes like,
"If you're only having a WAF,
an attacker is having a laugh".
So with that in mind,
I'm going to try to target the servers
that are outside your data center.
All these servers that on the
right hand side of this diagram,
these are much easier targets.
Let me show you how a
typical website attack
takes place in this case.
First of all, these style of attacks
are called Magecart.
And Magecart is also the name
of the most infamous group
that carries out these hacks.
And without going off
on a tangent too much,
let me present analogy
from the physical world.
I'm sure you've heard of the
credit card skimming attacks
that sometimes take place at gas stations.
They go something like this,
where you swipe your
credit card at the pump
and some
attackers or
somebody has put in a
small little hardware
that steals your credit card number
and stores it somewhere.
Your transaction at the
pump, it goes through okay,
and you cannot detect anything
is wrong at that time.
However, after a few weeks
when you check your credit card statement,
there are some mysterious charges
that have been applied
that you've not made.
So, similar to these
physical credit card skimming attacks,
we have web-based
JavaScript skimming attacks.
And that in a sense
is what the Magecart attack is
and what the Magecart group does.
Let's take a look
at the typical steps
in a Magecart attack.
Step one, the attacker
will try and find out
what goes into your web application.
That means listing out
all your third and fourth
party dependencies.
Once the attackers
identified a suitable target,
they'll use all
appropriate means to breach
into the third party servers.
This can be achieved using any of the
standard attacking and hacking tools
all the way from credential theft,
SQL injection, RDP attacks, rainbow tables
whatever you can think of,
and that has been known or unknown.
The attacker will try and use that
to gain control of the third party server.
Now, once the attacker is controllable
the third party server,
they were going to try
and insert their own
little JavaScript in there.
This code is designed to avoid detection
and it would maintain a low profile.
We go over how attackers are doing this
in a few slides.
Now, when an end user
navigates to this website
their browser loads the
third party dependency
and ta-da, you have been infected
by the attackers JavaScript.
By inserting one JavaScript
onto your browser
and attacker can do a lot of nasty things.
They can deface your website,
inject their own ads, do Bitcoin mining.
But over the past few years,
attackers have realized
that the best way for
them to monetize on this
is to try and steal end user data.
That generally means
your credit card numbers,
your username and passwords.
And that's what attackers
will generally go behind.
And this is actually what
happened a few years ago
on a ticketing website in the UK.
Attackers must have thought, "Hey, look"
"A lot of people are going
to book their tickets"
"on this website through
their credit card in"
"and let's try and steal it."
"Or they couldn't book their tickets"
"to their favorite concert,"
"something like a Justin Bieber concert"
"and got pissed and decided
to hack this website".
It's something like that.
But, at the end of the day
they decided to try and target one
of the ticketing websites third parties,
that is inventor.
and they injected their own JavaScript
after hacking into inventor servers.
Now, when end users
went onto the ticketing website
to book their concert tickets and so on,
that credit card information
was being stolen.
And as a result of this type
of attack that the Magecart group did,
they were able to steal over
60,000 credit card numbers
on this ticketing website alone.
For my attack demo,
I'm going to perform a similar set
of steps in order to show the attack.
For my attack demo,
I wanted to use a
well-known public website
to show you how we can attack it
and have some little hack funds.
But thanks to the legal
team, I had to settle
for a demo website that I created and own.
I've not hacked or done anything illegally
against any other website or server.
And this demo is just an example.
So for this demo, this
is the target website
that I'm going to use.
And for the first step, I would want
to analyze the target website
to understand its supply chain
and look for any possible weaknesses.
For this purpose,
I'm going to use Zed Attack Proxy,
also known as ZAP.
And this is a great open source tool
for attacking a web application.
What this tool does is,
it crawls the web application
and understands all the resources
that are loaded.
It can optionally also run attacks
or pen test against
some of these resources.
So, please get permission
before running ZAP against a website.
This is a start page of ZAP
and I'm going to run a scan against
my target website.
I've send the options in ZAP already,
so that it will try and
explore all links possible
and look for all the resources
that are present on this website.
So, let's hit off attack
to start the process.
As this website is quite small,
it will only take a few seconds
for ZAP to trace all the dependencies
or the third parties
that are present on this site.
As you can see,
there are quite a few
first party resources
that are loaded.
And then also some third parties
that you can see are getting loaded here.
Let me show you a graph
for better understanding.
- Yeah.
- As you can see the target website,
it loads quite a few third parties.
And I did my research on them all.
I found out the view analytics,
the one which is on the
normal side of the diagram.
That is actually an open
source analytics library.
And this is great news for me.
Why? Because for the past few months
I have been contributing
to the open source community, quite a lot.
I've gained their trust
in this time-frame.
And just last week I put in a bug fix
and I also slid in another dependency
to fetch one small JavaScript
from my servers.
So now, when you load the target website,
your browser is going to fetch
in infected view analytics script,
which brings us to the
next step of the attack.
The attack payload are
just these five lines
and these five lines is all that it takes
to perform a data exfiltration attack
that I will be demoing.
In this case, the attacks deals
the username and password.
Let me walk you through
this at a very high level
and no programming knowledge is required
to understand this.
The first two lines say,
let's read the username
and password values
when they're typed in by the end user.
That's how easy it is
for one JavaScript on any JavaScript
to read anything from a webpage.
On the next three lines, say,
"Hey, let's send this data
out to bad-server.com."
And that's all there is
to data exfiltration in JavaScript.
Okay.
Let's go to the target website
to see the actual attack.
This is regular Chrome.
And on the right hand side,
I have opened up developer tools
on the side
so that I can explain the attack better.
I will be able to explain what's happening
under the hood side-by-side to the website
in this manner.
So let's go to website.
So, as soon as the website
loads under the hood,
I can see that the
attacker's already loaded in
their attack script
through view analytics.
On the left-hand side,
nothing seems to be a missed.
The website loads properly
and everything seems good.
So let me try and log in.
(typing)
There we go.
The login went in successfully
and I didn't realize anything's amiss.
Frederick Gordon can go about doing
his usual business after logging in,
but what's happening on the back
is that a copy of the
username and password
is sent back to the attacker servers.
In this case, it's my attack servers.com.
As you can see, here are the
username and the password
that was sent back to the servers.
In this case, the attacker
is only printing the logs
just for this demo.
And that's how easy it is
for credit card numbers
and username and passwords to be stolen,
and then later sold to the dark net.
This is steady income for any attacker
and one US credit card
can go for around $7 on the dark market.
So for such attacks, some of you may think
that these attacks are
easy to stop or detect.
Well, not really,
attackers have a few tricks
up their sleeves
to ensure that these attacks
are not easy to detect
and don't go detected
for a very long time.
The average Magecart infection is 46 days.
Here are some of the reasons
why these attackers are so successful
and why these attacks
are so hard to detect.
The attackers would, first of all
use the standard techniques.
They will obfuscated the code
and ensure that no static analysis tools
is able to detect their
malicious behavior.
Here's where the attackers
get a bit more creative.
So, the malicious
JavaScript that they put in,
it will not perform anything malicious,
if it realizes that
your dev tools are open.
They're quite smart about this
and they do not want to get detected
by some security engineer,
keeping their dev tools open
and trying to understand this behavior.
and I'm sure some security
engineer would be smiling
and saying,
"Aha, I'm going to try and use Wireshark,"
"to trace all the network connections"
"that go from the browser".
What time do you work?
Because these attacks scripts,
they only load from one to 4:00 AM
and that to uncertain randomized days
on certain geographies.
And even during that time,
the malicious behavior
only occurs for around 20% of the time.
By that, I mean to say 80% of traffic
at 1:00 AM to 4:00 AM is
still completely clean.
And you won't even realize
there's an attack taking
place to the other 20%.
Lastly, I wanted to add
that the network requests
to fix the attack scripts
is exactly identical
to the other hundred, 150 network requests
that the browser makes
in those two seconds.
How are you going to distinguish
the good and the bad?
It's like finding a needle
in a haystack in my opinion.
And that explains why these attacks
mostly go undetected.
In fact, a few years ago
when Symantec analyzed over thousand
forum jacking attempts
in just a three-day period,
they found that over 57 websites
got hit with Magecart.
The websites that got infected
ranged from a fashion
retailer in Australia
to a fitness reseller in Italy.
And regulators have started taking notice
and imposing very large fines
on the main website directly
not just on the third
parties, but the main website.
And these attacks are causing
significant financial damage
not just in terms of these fines
but also class action lawsuits,
as well as a loss of customer loyalty
and trust in the brand.
So, now that you've seen
how these attacks have transpired
and how they're gaining momentum.
Let's talk about what you can do
to protect yourselves.
And at this time,
I'm just going to try and say that
you have to use the
basic security principles
of defense in layers.
In other words,
using RSA conferences theme for this year.
They resilience into your security,
create layers of defense
around your web application
to increase security and redundancy.
So, you cannot protect against threats
that you do not know about.
On the first step or the
first layer of defense
is to understand all the third parties
that in that integrate
with your application.
Next, let's try and minimize
the number of third parties
that are loaded on your web application.
Layer three, adds an active protection
to our web application
so that it's protected,
even if a third party has
been breached or attacked.
And lastly, you should be
on the constant lookout
for any signs of potential breaches
from your third parties.
Let's double click on each of these layers
to understand these defenses a bit better.
So, as thing you cannot
protect against threats
that you do not know about.
The first step is to
identify all third parties
that your application loads
and more importantly,
all the third and fourth parties
that are loaded by your third parties.
That is the fourth and
fifth party JavaScripts
that have been piggyback on
through your third party.
It also helps to prioritize certain pages
that have sensitive user input
such as login pages and payment pages.
And try and classify third parties
based on
how severe of a breach it would be
to your web application,
if the third party got compromised.
When it comes to security,
like many things,
I'll say learn from the best.
And Google is definitely one
of the good champions on web security.
What you're seeing here
is a typical login form
that you've seen a hundred times
I'm sure, while logging into Google.
On the right hand side,
I have the developer tools open,
which has been set to
filter out only third party resources.
As you can see, that list is empty.
That is Google doesn't have
a single third party JavaScript
on this critical sensitive page.
And that's definitely an easy route
that you can take to protect
your web application,
minimize or reduce the
number of JavaScripts
that are loaded from external sources.
Sure. This is not feasible everywhere.
And sometimes there is
an essential JavaScript
which you require, which is
a third-party JavaScript.
You can consider self-hosting it,
and that would make the
third party JavaScript,
a first party JavaScript
since you are serving it directly.
The active protection layer in my opinion
is the most important layer of defense.
And it addresses the worst case situation,
when an actual third party is breached.
These active protection methods
allow your web application
to successfully defend itself
against these malicious
third party libraries,
in real time.
These protections are for web applications
through W3C and HTML5 Standards.
They're deployed through HTTP headers
or in the page body.
So, here's how the typical
workflow takes place.
When a browser requests,
the web application,
it comes with these protections
that the browser then enforces.
These standards are
enforced by the browser.
So, when your web application
makes a request to
fetch any third party resource,
the browser ensures that these resources
that are loaded are
secure and trustworthy.
You're basically telling the browser
to be responsible for your
web application security now.
The best part is
94% of all internet traffic today
uses a browser that
supports these standards.
And these standards are free to use.
Thanks to W3C working groups.
Let's take a look
at the three most important
security standards
on the client side
and how they would have
protected your website
from the attack that I just demoed.
The first one is Content Security Policy.
Through this header,
you can control what comes
in and what goes out.
For example, you can list
all the third party domains
that are allowed to bring resources
into your web application
and all the domains that
data can be sent out to.
Content Security Policy
would have prevented
the attack that I demoed
by not allowing the script
from my server to load in the first place,
my malicious server to
load in the first place.
And further, it would have also
blocked the outflow of data,
that is the data exfiltration,
because the attack was sending
the data to a new server.
The second one is SubResource Integrity.
And this standard verifies the hash
of a third party script in runtime.
And it blocks the script from running,
if the hash doesn't match.
If SRI was protecting
the view analytics script
from the earlier demo,
then the browser would not
have liked my malicious
modification of the script.
The hash would have changed
and the browser would not
have permitted the script
to execute at all.
And a third powerful standard
is the iFrame Sandboxing.
This is a feature of modern browsers
that allows the third party script
to be fully isolated
from the main website.
And if this was deployed
during the attack demo,
the attack script could not have read
the username and password values.
This is because the
browser would have made
the attacks group run in a
completely isolated context
as compared to the main website,
which had the login form.
W3C and HTML5 standards can control
over a hundred different browser behaviors
that range from security
to privacy and compliance.
As these standards are enforcing
security on the browser.
That is the client side.
That's why they're called
client site security standards.
I'll definitely recommend that you spend
some time to get to know
the standards a bit better
and also to set up some
standards for your website.
I generally don't like to
explain a joke or a meme.
So, I hope you get the irony when there is
a third party service JavaScript
that claims that it can protect
against other third party JavaScript.
The main security downside of using
one defense JavaScript.
Again, some attack JavaScript
that are putting in the same privilege
is that this is not good for security.
You want your defense JavaScript to be
at a higher privilege than the attack.
And when that does not happen
like for JavaScript based solutions
where they're the same privilege,
the attack JavaScript can simply get rid
of your defense JavaScript.
You always want your defense
to be at a higher privilege.
And the W3C standards
from the previous slide
they've been publicly scrutinized
now recommended by the
security industry as a whole,
rather they were even created
by the security industry, actually.
The JavaScript based solutions.
They're also not free to use
like the browser standard
which we mentioned earlier.
So, now that you've added
in sufficient defense to your application,
what's next,
you got to stay ahead of your adversaries
and build a layer
that can keep track
of all the third parties
and preemptively take action,
when you feel that there's
something going wrong
with one of your third parties.
Now, that we have understood
the defenses in theory,
let's take a look at a
sample web application
that is implemented these defenses.
In this case,
I'm going to act as the website owner
and walk you through that.
So, first of all, I know all the resources
and third parties that are
in this website and webpage
have examined them all
and reviews the number of third parties
that are loaded.
The one essential strip
that was really required
for my application,
I'd have protected it
through a SubResource Integrity Hash
so that no one can tamper with it.
Plus, I'm also using a strong
Content Security Policy
to ensure that no extra scripts are loaded
and no other data can
leave my web application.
Lastly, I'm periodically checking
all my third party scripts and vendors
to ensure that they have not
been tampered or breached
in any way.
As we're coming to a
close of this session.
I hope that you have
a better understanding
of client side threats
and the ways in which you can safeguard
against this new age of threats.
For the next steps,
I'll recommend that in the coming weeks,
you try and perform a resource inventory
of your website.
The next few months,
get a CSP, use an SRI
and be ready for the worst case
in case a third party is breached.
And lastly, pass on this message
to other security professionals
in your network and in your company.
So, they too can protect
their websites and web assets.
And if you're interested in knowing more.
Tala Security has been
working in this field
of eliminating client side attacks
for the past five years
and we've published a few
white papers on this topic.
You can access them through the QR code.
And there's also a link to our website
which has a lot of free resources
to help you get started
and secure your website.
You can also feel free to reach out
to me on my email address
or connect with me on LinkedIn.
Thank you.
And there's a Q and a session
that is coming up next.