- Hi, everybody.
Before I bring out my topic for this year,
taking you down the
checklist of things to do
in order to absolutely slow, hinder,
even ruin your security
operations center function,
I do wanna recognize that
as we sit together virtually
here in the spring of 2021,
we have all been remarkably resilient.
The central theme for this
year's RSA Conference,
through what can only
be described as tough,
painful and tragic year.
As a longtime RSA employee,
more than a decade at this point,
I didn't want to let 2021 slip away
without a quick look back to
the fall of 1991, 30 years ago,
when a group with 60 cryptographers
piled into a meeting room at a hotel
in Redwood Shores, California,
at what was the very first
iteration of RSA Conference.
RSA Conference itself has
been resilient over the years,
growing and growing into the
tens of thousands of attendees,
becoming a driving force
behind the world's cybersecurity agenda.
The central point where people
from around the world gather
to share, learn and grow,
and the place that provides a forum
for innovation and partnership.
Please accept my sincere
thanks and gratitude to you
and all your fellow attendees
for continuing to make
RSA Conference relevant,
interesting and valuable.
Now onto the main event,
at least for this session.
I'm pretty sure you're not
here trying to figure out
how to sabotage your security
operations center function.
The purpose behind my talk is
to lay out five discrete areas
where we've seen organizations,
even the best funded and most mature,
sometimes fall into a hole.
If you'd like to fall into any
or all five of those holes,
then have at it.
But my goal is to point out these holes
and to get you thinking about
how you and your colleagues
can do a better job securing
your organization from threats,
both external and internal.
I'll also make this
commitment to you upfront,
thus far you've probably already
seen too many presentations
with far too many bullets,
what I have for you today
is almost all images.
There's only one slide
with bullets at the end,
where I'll delivering some
actionable recommendations
for you to get started.
So let me get started here now.
Regardless of where you and
your organization may be
on your security maturity journey,
most of us realize that we
can't protect what we can't see.
Clear and unimpeded visibility
into everything you manage
is a must have.
But visibility means different things
to different security
operation centers or SOCs.
It's not unusual to start with
a log collection capability
often through your SIEM,
your security information
and event management tooling,
good technology that's been around
for more than 15 years at this point.
And so you bring your set of SIEM glasses
to maximize your visibility.
You've spent good money on those glasses,
you've got the right prescription,
you're pretty sure you can
see things pretty clearly.
And as a bonus, your
SIEM might not help you
only with your security operations needs,
but also with demonstrating
your compliance
with externally-imposed regulations,
where you may need to store
those collected logs for months
or even years.
The fail in many SOCs is to stop there,
to stop with the SIEM and
think that you're finished.
Why is that?
In today world with today's adversaries
if you've just brought
a single set of glasses
to this fight, a single set of lenses,
relying only on your SIEM
to detect the badness
that may be inside your
environment already,
you and your SOC are going to fail.
Let's remember that your SIEM,
however old or new it may be,
is primarily designed to capture logs,
and logs are a look into
the past, not the present,
not what's happening
right now on your network.
Collecting logs is table stakes,
it's the foundation of
many SOC functions today,
but it's absolutely not the end state
for securing your organization,
at least it shouldn't be.
Think about your cell phone bill
and the high level call
detail records it shows,
I made a call on this date, at this time,
to this phone number, and the
call lasted for X minutes.
Logs are the call detail records
of what's going on in your environment.
But what about understanding,
about having visibility
into what was actually said
during the conversation,
who led the conversation?
Who were the two or more people
who were actually using the
phones during that conversation?
To get to that level of detail,
to get to full visibility
throughout your environment,
you need another set of lenses,
you need to collect network traffic.
It's the network traffic which
answers all the questions
in the analogy I just laid out:
the specifics of the conversation,
and the people and the devices
used in that conversation.
Monitoring network traffic is a key leg
to any successful
zero-trust implementation.
If you're zero trusting today
but not monitoring your network traffic,
both North/South, in and
out of your infrastructure,
and East/West, within your environment,
perhaps the internal
traffic amongst servers
and data centers,
if you're not doing these things
then you're not doing it right.
I mentioned devices in the
context of network traffic,
true visibility also
means being able to see
into what's happening on each device
plugged into your network.
What's running in memory on that laptop,
on that server right now?
Which specific processes are
originating outbound traffic
from that device,
perhaps to a destination you
know represents a threat?
With more and more data
traffic being encrypted,
would it be valuable to
see that original data
on the endpoint before
it's been encrypted?
Do I really need a third set of lenses?
Yes, is the correct answer.
Visibility is all about seeing your logs,
your network traffic
and your endpoint data.
It's about consuming these
very heterogeneous data sets
and normalizing those data points
to make it easier for your
SOC analysts to surface
and distill actionable information
out of that sea of data,
and to work more effectively,
it's about bringing all this information
into a holistic view
of what's happening
throughout your environment
from the user, through the
network and into the cloud,
to provide visibility anywhere
and everywhere data and applications live.
This is the XDR or extended
detection and response space.
This is where you need to be headed
if you're not already there today.
Or if you prefer to fail,
just keep on looking at those logs
collected by your old school SIEM,
and don't think about
what you might be missing.
As it turns out,
visibility is just the
start of the journey.
Your SOC team is drowning in data today,
converting that data into information,
into knowledge, into action,
takes a lot of resources.
And here I'm not talking about the tools
and technology you've deployed,
I'm talking about the mental
resources of your human beings.
Working memory, that place in our brains
which effectively serves
as short-term memory
around current tasks,
our work bench, if you will,
is a limited finite resource.
Even your sharpest, most
valuable SOC analysts,
incident responders, and threat hunters
routinely run low on
working memory capacity
as the day goes on.
Working memory can be renewed with rest.
But resting to recharge in the
middle of an active incident
is typically not an option.
Too many organizations
choose to attack this problem
by lining up an impressive
array of technologies and tools,
but ultimately fail to
put them all together
in the right way to maximize
both their investment
and their reaction time to an incident.
It's like you have an orchestra
where the music and the
instruments are there,
but there's something missing.
If you don't have
empowered humans involved,
if you don't have a
conductor to help guide
these overworked, overpressured
humans working in your SOC,
you're not maximizing your capabilities.
I once sat across the table
from a recently arrived CISO,
chief information security officer,
and I asked him if he had a defined set
of incident response procedures.
He got excited and texted
one of his staff members,
who showed up a few minutes later
carrying a couple of
three-inch thick binders
into the conference room.
"What's this?" I asked.
"This," the CISO proudly said,
"is the comprehensive set
of instructions and policies to follow
for all the potential attack factors
we've identified so far."
I congratulated him
on what was clearly a huge
documentation project,
one created with the best of intentions.
But when I then asked
how the humans in the SOC
were supposed to reference
this collection of information,
he assured me that every member of the SOC
had copies of these two
binders at their desks.
"How frequently do you update them?"
"A couple of times a year,
probably." he answered.
When your SOC team and your organization
are in the middle of trying to diagnose
and respond to an incident,
it's probably not the optimal time
to pull a binder off the
shelf, go to the index,
scan for the use case you
think you're experiencing,
find the correct and
approved-by-management response steps,
go to the other binder
where that information actually lives,
and then flip to page 98
to finally start reading.
Doing all that without making a mistake
or skipping a step is somewhat unlikely
under the pressure of a
still developing incident.
Relying on your humans
to memorize those steps
and carry them out perfectly every time
is an even better way to fail.
Orchestrating your response,
having those steps laid out in a runbook,
preferably not a physical book or binder,
but via an online resource,
which is always up to date,
is your path to success.
This is the lead ingredient
of the security orchestration,
automation and response, or SOAR space.
You want those steps to
be universally accessible
by your incident responders.
You need those steps to
be absolutely current
and appropriate for
today's threat environment,
not the landscape from six months ago.
If you don't think about how
to orchestrate your response,
how best to combine your humans,
your workflows, your runbooks,
and the many tools and
platforms in your environment,
which you've purchased and installed,
you're not just failing to
maximize your investments,
you're failing your SOC by
not helping your analysts
conserve their precious working memory
so that they can devote all their efforts
to resolving the current issue.
Remember, the best technologies,
the best instruments
don't play themselves.
You can't have an orchestra
without your humans
and a conductor to guide them along.
That's where a solid SOAR solution,
security orchestration,
automation and response, can help.
That's the O for
orchestration in SOAR model,
but what about the A for automation?
Even if you and your SOC
are fully orchestrating
your incident response,
too many teams still struggle
with far too many manual processes.
And even if you are that rare organization
who has completely
documented your processes,
if those processes require your analysts
to check the right box
or call the right person in
the right order and timeframe,
your SOC team is being
burdened by the process
instead of being supported by it.
We've already established
that a complicated,
manually-driven, hard-to-reference process
runs the risk of your
analysts being overwhelmed
in the heat of the moment.
Human beings tend to make
mistakes under stress.
So why not automate as much as you can
to reserve that limited attention
and conserve the working memory
of your first responders?
Automation at its best,
as you might guess,
is all about speed, reproducibility,
and hopefully, accuracy.
All of which goes hand in hand
with the orchestration
capability we talked about.
For example, automation
working with your orchestration capability
can be leveraged to track
how long a specific step
in your runbook should
be in a specific state,
escalating automatically
when that time period crosses
the threshold you've defined.
But here's the thing,
automation isn't just about
streamlining processes,
it can also be used to
programmatically make changes
to your infrastructure as
part of your full response
to an incident.
Think about the power
of automatically updating a firewall ACL,
removing privileges or
entitlements from a user,
or even knocking an infected
endpoint off the network.
Think about the danger
of automatically updating a firewall ACL,
removing privileges or
entitlements from a user,
or knocking an infected
endpoint off the network.
Automating changes to your infrastructure
as part of your SOC's
incident response function
can fit in very cleanly
along with steps your
analysts need to take.
But this is one area in particular
where understanding
your own infrastructure
and the business processes
that infrastructure supports
is critical.
Don't automate infrastructure changes
until you're certain you know
the potential dependencies
and the potential impacts
of pulling that trigger.
One area where there may be some prior art
to help you figure out this question
is robotic process automation or RPA.
If your organization
already has done some work
in this space, find out who
those project managers are
and what lessons they learned
as they tied systems together through RPA.
I can guarantee that those
lessons will be applicable
to your decision to automate some
or all of your incident response playbook.
Finally, don't focus only
on automating internal tools
as part of a response,
you should actively
look into external tools
and external data to
help your SOC diagnose
what's happening within your environment.
Including a threat
intelligence platform, or TIP,
as part of your tooling
isn't optional anymore.
Whether that threat intel
arrives from the outside
or if it's internally generated,
having a TIP intertwined
with this automation
and orchestration question is essential.
In a perfect world, your source solution
will natively contain a
threat intelligence platform.
That's how tightly these two
features should be designed
and delivered.
Orchestrating and automating
your incident response
are solid foundations to
being the best SOC you can be,
but your extra credit
goal is to figure out
how you can win more information
out of the data you've already collected
throughout your environment.
Data about your devices,
your users, your network
and everything in between.
We humans, and specifically
our human brains,
are pretty remarkable
pattern-seeking machines
that are always on the
hunt to connect the dots
in any complex picture.
We are wired to create
meaning out of chaos.
Sometimes A really is connected
to B, sometimes it is not.
But if there's one truism
where I think we can all agree,
even your biggest brained
analyst will crumble
under trying to make
sense of tens of thousands
of incoming events per second
on top of the gigabytes and
gigabytes of network traffic
you may be ingesting at
any given point in time.
There's just too much data
and not enough information.
Why not make it easier
to see new information?
How can you make it easy
for your extended team
to see the outliers,
which may represent a
higher than probable issue
that could grow into an incident?
Some organizations hear this
and start thinking about big data,
and the staffing and expertise required
to fully exploit these
expensive skillsets.
The good news is,
you don't need a data
scientist on your team,
you just need the right
tooling to help both identify
and contextualize what you are seeing
amongst the avalanche of data
your infrastructure naturally
creates every minute
of every hour of every day.
Too many organizations
don't put all those
puzzle pieces together,
they're simply overwhelmed
with the existing noise
and activity within the environment.
I once had a conversation
with a multinational bank
who admitted they had
flat out stopped listening
to a portion of their network,
stopped actively monitoring it
as they just could not cut
through the data flood.
Under the power of analytics,
just like SIEM is table
stakes for the SOC,
teasing information out of that noise
through correlating different
data points with one another
is the place to start,
but not a place to stop.
Today's strongest threat
analytics solutions
leverage machine learning
to automatically monitor
and alert on potentially
dangerous behaviors of users
as well as devices.
A good analytics solution,
especially in the context
of threat detection,
needs to be up to date with data models.
These models are at the very heart
of any machine learning solution.
Traditional on-premise solutions
must wait for model updates
to be released by vendors,
and may then be further
delayed through change control
and other IT procedures
at the customer side.
That's why you should look
first for this capability
delivered as a cloud-based
software as a service or SaaS.
It won't surprise you to learn
that analytics solutions
are very data hungry.
A traditional on-premise
analytics implementation
might require you to purchase
capacity years in advance,
much of which may not
be needed anytime soon.
SaaS-based analytics gives
you tremendous flexibility
to add new capacity only when it's needed,
and with no local installation needed,
no rack space for the new storage,
no concerns about powering up
yet another piece of
equipment in the data center.
We've spent a lot of time
talking about technology and
tooling, but of course you know
that your most important
ingredients in the SOC
are your people.
And sometimes we forget that human beings
are not widgets to be snapped
into an unflexible process.
We don't wanna strip the gears, right?
Beyond everything else
we've covered today,
what can you do to relieve the friction
that can drive away your best SOC analysts
and threat hunters?
One way to make those
tough jobs in the SOC
a little stickier
in an effort to keep your
A-players around and engaged,
it's to set up job rotations
for your key personnel.
You know, that level one analyst
who's only been on board for six months,
but you've already figured
out that she is a rockstar,
someone you cannot afford to lose.
You don't want to just tell her
about her potential career
path at you're organization,
you can show her by taking
her out of her triage seat
every now and then
to shadow a level two
or level three analyst
elsewhere in the SOC,
maybe a half day, every
other week for example.
Let her see what that next step looks like
and experience that
next level career step.
Job rotations aren't just a benefit
to that frontline SOC
analyst, in my example,
that level two or level three analyst
is not someone you assigned
this shadowing project randomly,
he may also be just as
much a rockstar as she is.
Perhaps you publicly
designate him as a mentor
or a champion within your organization,
recognition that doesn't cost money
or require a formal title change.
It's a role that makes him or
her stand out from their peers
in a good way.
In my own organization,
we leverage mentorships
to dry run potential
future people managers
as the skillsets between
mentors and managers overlap
in several important areas.
Now you may be an organization
that isn't large enough yet
to have two or three levels
of analysts within your SOC.
You may have outsourced
some or all this function
to an MSSP, a managed
security services provider,
that's great.
And it's not a model reserved only
for small or medium-sized organizations,
even larger companies may
benefit from this model.
If I'm describing your situation here,
I strongly encourage you
to plan on comprehensive review sessions
on a regular cadence
with your MSSP provider,
maybe once a quarter.
You want to maximize your
investment by learning more
about how exactly they
protect your environment.
Think of it as a skills transfer
so that you gain more and
more knowledge over time.
Good MSSPs won't be
threatened by this possibility
that you may leave them at
some point in the future
once you can do everything yourself.
The good ones will be more than happy
to have this conversation with you.
Finally, one more approach to
avoid stripping those gears
is to remind your entire
employee population
that securing the organization
isn't just the responsibility
of your folks in the SOC.
All of your employees need
to know, need to be reminded
that they are extended
members of your security team.
Every employee is on the front line,
and your security awareness program
should take that approach.
That security awareness program
is hopefully something you
already have in place today,
something that gets revised
on at least an annual basis.
The more educated and empowered
your frontline workers are,
the better it is for your analysts
and threat hunters working in the SOC.
Okay, that's five ways
to not ruin your SOC.
By the way, mastery of these five areas
adds up to a successful XDR,
extended detection and
response capability.
Look for partners and vendors who get it
and can help you navigate all these areas.
Some next steps for you to consider:
carry out an inventory so that you know
what visibility technologies
you already have in-house,
confirm that you have
runbooks that are up to date
and easily accessible by your SOC team,
and start thinking about
metrics you can deploy
to help your team become
even more effective,
be thinking about upping
your game to start leveraging
that analytics capability I talked about.
Can you combine data
you're already collecting
about your users and devices
to get to the right answer
about a potential incident more quickly?
And always be mixing up the glue
to keep your A-players on board.
A burnout in the SOC often
happens very gradually,
monitor and act quickly
to avoid this scenario.
While my session today was recorded
just ahead of the start of the conference,
I will be here, plausibly live,
for the remainder of my allocated time
to take any live questions you
might wish to throw my way.
I'll do my best to clarify
anything I covered here.
I'd love to hear from you.
Have a great conference.
And on behalf of
NetWitness, an RSA business,
thanks again for being
here with us this year.