- Hello everyone, my name is Jen Trahan.
I am a VP of Product Security,
and I'm here with Wiktor Szymanski.
We wanna say a big thank you
for coming and joining us.
We're gonna go ahead and talk about
information security
make-over and specifically
we wanna dig it into product security.
If you have any questions
during your presentation,
please feel free to ask them
in the chat during our talk.
So when I told a friend I
was going to be presenting
on product security, they asked
me a really great question
and it turns out I didn't
know the answer to it.
So what they had asked
me is how many companies
are actually doing product security.
And while I've heard of product security
for the last decade, and
certainly it's hit a fever pitch
here in the last four or five years,
I actually have no idea how many companies
are doing product security.
So I decided I try to measure that myself.
So, I went and looked at
the fortune 100 companies,
and I put them all in a spreadsheet,
that's right, science by
me, and then I decided,
I estimate who's doing product security
by looking at their active
recruiting positions.
And I was looking for
anyone who was hiring
product security at any level.
And what I found when I
added them all in my very
official spreadsheet, was
that 19 out of the 100,
we're actively hiring product security.
So that's roughly 19% obviously.
So it's safe to say that 19%
of the fortune 100 companies
are actively hiring somebody
for product security right now.
Additionally, when I
looked in certain tech,
mainstream tech companies, I
found it was somewhere closer
to 50% are actively
hiring product security.
So we know that the number is
probably even more than this.
Since we know one in five companies
is doing product security,
let's talk a little bit
about what it is.
Truth is, there is no consistent
or standardized framework
for what makes product security.
I'd say that there are a lot of emerging
and working definitions
on product security,
so if you were to go out
and look on the internet
you'd see a number of
them, I've got them here.
I think the big things is
we wanna call out some key
important aspects at all of
these definitions call out.
So in this case, a super set of security,
a particular product and
system, and then a partnership
with all the stakeholders
as well as across
the entire product life
cycle, and then lastly,
you know, cross-discipline endeavor.
And I think I would add, to though
all those great definitions, I
would add that in my opinion,
product security is an
approach for structuring
your security program around
the threat model of a product
and the entire scope of that product.
So now while we have a
definition of product security,
let's talk about some frequent questions
or some confusing areas
that I've definitely
had some heated debates
with some coworkers about.
One of them is what
about enterprise security
and how does that relate?
And the other one is about application.
So let's walk through the main
components of an enterprise
and what it takes to enable a
business to go about its day.
So we've got data centers,
laptops obviously,
physical offices, things like
email, wireless networks,
sensitive data, mobile
devices that your employees
might have as well as
other systems like VTC.
And all of these are
something that bad actors,
including sharks are very
interested in taking advantage of.
And enterprise security is
really focused on all the aspects
of it enterprise and
really about protecting
the enterprise as a whole
So let's walk through a
product and the aspects
that we need to consider for that.
In this case, let's talk about a product
that might be an e-commerce
product, for example.
And we're going to look at this
from the consumer's point of view.
So if we look here, we've got
our product in the center,
and let's think about what a
consumer might interact with.
So the likely interact with
some of our applications,
they may call our customer care providers,
they are likely gonna provide
us with sensitive data
so that we can ship them
a product, for example.
They're gonna be thumbing
through our applications
and we have content that's
feeding into those applications.
Behind the covers, a lot
of this is probably hosted
maybe in our example
in a cloud environment.
They're developers who work
with all of those different
applications and content pipelines.
We have lots of different
types of operational tools
that tell us from a how
the consumer metrics
how they're enjoying our product
all the way down to whether
or not our systems are up and
running as we expect them.
And just under all of
that, the source code
in the application
development side of things.
So all of this makes up
the product surface area
and all the different
components that make up
for what I would consider to be a product.
And again, just like an
enterprise environment,
there are bad actors,
fraudsters, bots, aliens,
they're all looking to do
something potentially to exploit
these systems and product
security is really focused
around the end-to-end of
security, these products.
And so, as you can see from an enterprise
versus product security,
there's a very significant
surface areas in both
of these circles here.
They likely both require very
robust security controls,
but they might have very
different information
security capabilities needed.
And so, they're both very
important but they may have
very different security requirements.
So now let's talk a little bit
about application security.
Application security is focused primarily
on historically on the top
half of what we have here
for our example product.
So things like the applications,
the sensitive data,
the source code, and
the development pipeline
for getting those
applications to our consumers.
And as you can see, that
leaves a lot of other things
kind of out in the cold
and our favorite aliens
are coming in and they're not protected
by application security, 'cause
we've got some other things
that are out of scope
that aren't protecting
the product here.
Just to kind of double click
into that a little bit more,
application security is
usually focused a lot
on the analysis, and
then we had our big wave
of shift left and that was
great, that's really about
putting security more into how
we're building the products,
and I think that that has
really moved the needle a lot,
but there are other
areas like for example,
an AppSec team is generally
working really closely
with the engineering
teams to prevent things
like account takeover
attacks, for example,
for something like a
consumer, e-commerce product.
They're creating strong passwords,
all these great controls,
but generally speaking, an
AppSec team, isn't interacting
with the customer care
department, for example,
to walk through their manual playbooks
and you know maybe not
working with them for things
like social engineering attacks
that might actually present
a real security risk to the
consumer data coming through
a more manual customer
service representative path
that's not coming through
an application for example.
Or other areas like operational readiness.
Application security teams
are rarely held accountable
for the entire operational readiness,
getting the security relevant
logs, et cetera, into the SIM
ensuring that we have things
like cloud and infrastructure
logs are in the SIM,
that's generally not been
the purview of an AppSec program.
So we've talked a little
bit, I kind of threw out
e-commerce product out
there as an example,
but let's talk a little bit
about what a product might be.
And I'd say at a very high
level, just think about anything
that is built by your
company that is important
to the success of your organization.
Obviously, I'll walk through
some very specific product type
that you can think about,
but you know really
at a high level, something
that's built by your company,
that's important to the success,
so it might just be completely internal.
So obviously things like video games
and video game platforms,
maybe some more traditional
products coming off a factory line.
You can think about cars
and subsystems of cars,
distributions systems, a software
for drop ship for example.
Perhaps you have a brick and
mortar portion of your company
and they have a consumer
merchandise and in store digital
experiences thinking
about those as products.
Medical equipment and
things like embedded devices
are becoming, implanted devices,
are becoming more and more
popular and more and more
important to consumer,
so that would be a really
interesting area to look into.
Hospitality companies
while they have consumer
reservation systems, they
might also have very robust,
internally built critical staff.
Scheduling software that
might be really critical
to the operation of the business,
and I would consider that to be a product.
With the factory equipment,
other things like data science
and business intelligence
systems, ETL, ML, all of those,
those drive business
drive business decisions,
they would likely be considered a product
that you might need to
focus security area around.
And last but not least, obviously
things like IoT devices.
So really again, think
about it as something
that's significant that's
built by your company,
that is you know, really
important to the success
of your company.
And equally, I sometimes
think about it as a brand.
I'll think about a
product as a total brand.
I'll think about not only
the consumer applications
but is there a marketing
site that's also teasing
that application to come
out to market, et cetera.
So, you can also think
about it as a brand.
Great so now we considered
the entire scope
of what makes up a product, in our case,
we've got our example, consumer product,
an e-commerce product,
that might be a collection
of products in your world, but you know,
now we've kind of
considered what that makes,
what makes up that kind of product.
So let's consider what kind
of information security
capabilities it would be
required to have to secure
each of those different areas.
So here we have our example product again,
and what we're gonna do is an exercise
where we're going to determine
what kind of information
security organization and
capabilities we would need
to secure this product.
We wanna do this very
objectively, don't consider
what's already in your
security organization,
just consider what you
would do from scratch.
Pretend you were hired
to do this just to secure
this product or these product
types, what would you build?
So working with our example
here, let's start with the fact
that it's hosted in the cloud.
I think that's a good
place for us to start.
So, we'd wanna make sure
that we have a robust cloud
security program that would make sense.
So we want things like detection
catalog, anomaly detection,
audit logs, identity
management, IM et cetera,
as well as configuration
clients, et cetera.
So we definitely want
to make sure we've got
a robust cloud security program.
Moving into the more
DevSecOps side of things,
this is where we'll find more
of the basics of, you know,
classic application security
and a lot of the DevSecOps
shift left type of application security
that everyone's talking about.
But there are a couple other
areas that historically
I haven't seen more in the
DevSecOps side of things
specifically, I wanna call
out operational security
because things like monitoring
and alerting and dashboards
on the application layer and
beyond, is really important,
and we wanna make sure
that that's baked in.
And then let's think
about what our inventory?
What is the footprint?
What makes up this product or brand?
So thinking through an external inventory,
what does it look like
from the outside world?
What kind of data is
it collecting and what
in classifying that data,
as well as other things
related to our cloud account inventory.
And an obviously a robust
vulnerability management program
would be something that you wanna build.
And last, but certainly not
least, let's talk a little bit
about secure by design.
This would be something we'd wanna do
for a product like this, we'd
wanna make sure we include
all of the aspects that you'd have
in a mature application security program,
but then we wanna make
sure we expand beyond that,
to other avenues that
present risk to the products.
So things like I said, customer support
and we have other things
about feature design
and threat modeling, as well
as technical assessments.
And we'll wanna, you know,
pull all of that together,
and what you would end up
with is something very large,
that would be the end-to-end
of everything it would take
from a capabilities point
of view for an information
security organization to
properly secure a product
such as the one we have
here as an example.
And one of the notes I'd
like to kind of call out
is that if instead this product
wasn't an e-commerce product
you know, perhaps this product
was an embedded product.
You might have a whole
section on physical security
and your physical supply
chain, and how you get
your firmware burned into
your embedded device.
That would be totally appropriate
for that type of product.
So this is really meant to
be an exercise of thinking
about the different surface
areas, the threat model,
and how that maps to the capabilities
of how you would protect and defend that.
Now we've completed what I hope
to be a very objective view
of what it would take to
secure a product like this.
And let's bring it back
to your existing org.
So in our exercise, I'm gonna go through
and talk a little bit about
if I had an organization
that had a product that
we've been talking about,
and then taking that based on what I have
in my existing organization,
and looking at places
where I have some gaps.
So we're gonna walk through this mind map
from the previous slide,
and in each aspect of it
really assess whether or not
your program's capabilities
are denoted here and
actually do they exist?
And so in this case, what I've
done is anything that's red
with a bold edge, are
true gaps in capabilities.
I means I'm missing tools, process, people
that know how to do these
types of security capabilities.
For the things that are
gray, there are more things
that exist as capabilities
within my organization,
but maybe I currently don't
use them for products.
Maybe I use them more for IT,
so if you think of something
like vulnerability management,
maybe I have a very
robust program for a enterprise,
IT laptops, for example,
but in a vulnerability
management program for that,
but I don't have that applied necessarily
to the infrastructure that that makes up
a product, for example.
So going through and
identifying gaps for areas
where I just don't have those capabilities
or areas where I'm not
leveraging what I already have.
And so this exercise is
really important to determine
you know, how well you are
positioned to be protecting
your products as you go
through this exercise.
So far, we've talked about
what a product security is
and how it right relate
to enterprise security
and how it is a super set
of application security.
We have gone over what the
concept of a product might mean
in your world, and then
we've done that lightweight
brainstorming exercise for end-to-end.
What kind of security
program would you need
to secure that product?
And then finally, kind of how
to think about highlighting
gaps based on that brainstorming model
for what kind of security
capabilities you have.
Now I want to transition more
into focusing on the people
that make up a product security program.
So recently, I've had a
major construction happening
in my house, which has been
very educational for me.
And there are many aspects that make up
a large remodel program
and project in my house.
I worked definitely
closely with an architect,
we have framer and builders
as well as everybody loves
their, you know, city
inspectors, we have painters
and dry wallers and
electricians and plumbers.
But thankfully I also
have a security contractor
and they're amazing, and
their fantastic company,
who's done a really great
job of making everything work
really, really smoothly.
And I'm really thankful for
that as I start to think
of all the other subsystems
that make up my house
in the parts of my house that
that need to be taken care of.
So things like physical security
and making sure all of that
is set and egress for a window,
and those kinds of things
I would never know about.
Smoke detectors and fire extinguishers
and other kinds of CO2 alarms, et cetera.
So, you know, they work
with other repair people,
safety specialists, and they
ensure that we're compliant
with the fire department, et cetera.
And as I was thinking through
this, it came very clear
to me the importance of
my general contractor
when he ended up having a small surgery
and he wasn't going to
be able to be on site
for about a week and a half.
And during that week and a
half, we had a very well-meaning
and eager dry waller, who was
trying to get their job done.
And they waited for the
plumber and the electrician
to finish their work, and they were about
to basically dry a wall over everything
as they're supposed to,
but the problem was is that
the inspection hadn't happened yet.
And so we almost had a huge
issue where the inspector
hadn't had a chance to sign
off on all of the plumbing
and the wiring before the dry
waller had covered it all up.
And thankfully this, you know, was caught
before it became a huge financial problem,
but it was during this
time I became acutely aware
of the value of my general contractor.
While he's great at
fabricating things himself,
I've seen him build full walls
and do plumbing, et cetera.
He also understands the
scope of the project
and he has a keen eye
for all of the different
cross-discipline requirements
and why they're important
and what feeds into what area.
And so, that was almost a
costly mistake and it made me
think a lot about the value
of a general contractor.
And so I started thinking,
what is the general definition
of a general contractor?
And it is exactly what my
contracting company doing,
they're really responsible for
the end-to-end material labor
for the construction
project, and they might bring
specialized, talented
and specialized people
to do things like HVAC, et cetera.
But, you know, for the most part,
they run everything themselves.
And when I started thinking
about product security,
I realized that product
security is actually
just the general
contractor of, of InfoSec.
And so, product security
team is responsible
for all of the labor and
materials and equipment
and engineering tools
for securing a product.
They might work with
specialized subcontractors
or SMEs to perform parts
of the security program,
but ultimately, there are a lot like
a general contractor of InfoSec.
So if we go back to our
house construction this time
instead of a house, let's think about it
as our company's product
that we're building.
There's still an architect
'cause we all overuse that word.
But there's still an architect,
there's developer compliance
as well, we've designers
and business owners
as well as DevOps organizations.
Here's our lovely product
security professional.
And they are the interface
between a lot of the other
subsystems that help
keep the product safe.
Such as the SDLC, Secure
Development Life Cycle,
logging and monitoring,
things like firewalls alerts,
And then they work with
a lot of the other areas
within the organization, such
as a security engineering,
the AppSec team and the stock
and incident response team.
So as you can see, they
really are sitting right
in the middle where there
are general contractor
capable of doing a lot of the InfoSec
for a specific product, but they also work
really, really closely with the SMEs
in their InfoSec division.
So we'll go quickly through
kind of the key areas
of what makeup product
security professionals
re-mention kind of day to day.
So they are obviously,
they work really closely
in relationships.
So business relationships
with the product business,
engineering teams with the engineering
that is actually doing all
of the product development,
as well as the InfoSec
team, their own InfoSec team
they have to build really
quality relationships there.
And they store as part of
that, they share procedures,
they help draft standards as well.
And then their job is to
onboard to security tools
and programming, so you
think about things like
cloud tools and intrusion detection tools
and anomaly detection tools,
their job is to onboard
the products that they
work with into the rest
of the information security program.
They also are capable and
responsible for ensuring
security assessments
happen on that product.
And they are also from a
dashboards and metrics.
There's no one in the organization
that should know the security
layout of that product
more than not product
security professionals.
So, they're a great
person to actually come up
with good dashboards and
metrics for measuring
the security of that product end-to-end.
And then additionally, they are supposed
to manage expectations, be
the main point of contact
for security for that product,
so when they have a question
and they need to get some consultation
and, you know, in an
assessment, they manage that
with the product themselves.
They assist in any of the
automation that might be needed
for things like continuous integration
and continuous deployment.
And last, but definitely not
least, they prepare the product
for logging and SIM
integration, and they help work
with threat modeling to
create a threat model
based alerting and run books.
So that's a lot of product
security professional.
Is a lot like a general
contractor, they have to be able
to do a lot of the
different sub-disciplines
and cross-discipline work
of an information Security professional.
So we just talked a lot
about how product security
individuals have a lot
of responsibilities,
but one of the big burning questions
might be how to structure
those products security
professionals within your organization,
and whether you create a
team or not within your org.
And unfortunately I have to say it depends
and I really hate to say
it depends, but it does.
It depends very heavily
on what kind of products
your organization and company
is and how big of a focus
you have on those products.
And so I think the best way
to go is to start by looking
through the unique capabilities
that you might need,
and using that mind map
that we created earlier
to think about where you
might have some gaps,
and where you might need to structure some
of your organization around those gaps.
So did you have a lot
of gaps or did you have
like one or two and you can
just, you know flush out
one of your programs a little bit more
and just start applying it to a product.
And therefore you would
have a pretty good set
of products security coverage
from a capabilities point of view.
Additionally, from a structure
I've seen a lot of teams
since we were talking about this earlier,
so I've seen a lot of teams
and organizations build up
their applications security,
and just extend that
to be called the product
security organization.
I this is a valid approach,
but the important point
I'd wanna make is that we wanna make sure
that the application
security as it extends
to be a product security
is truly not a rename,
but really is taking into
everything beyond your SDLC,
everything beyond the application
and really thinking about
it from a holistic product
and brand point of view, to
make sure you're not missing
other manual areas, other
places that present risk
that have nothing to
do with an application
or the application development life cycle.
Also, you should consider
whether you want to avoid
spreading your apps team to
thin when you expand their scope
to include these other areas.
So instead I would encourage
you to consider leaving
your AppSec team as a
specialized skill area,
and instead of build out a
sub set of product security
specialists as a team and then assign
those products security
specialists to specific areas,
maybe based on product type.
So if you have a lot of embedded,
maybe have a couple of
products security professionals
around those embedded products,
and if you have e-commerce
maybe a couple around
that, or you could do it
based on brand or you
could do based on locale.
And you know, it really
depends on how your company
is organized and how your
products are organized
and your business is organized.
So at this point, we have
talked about product security
and what it is, we've
discussed kind of what
you can think of a product might be.
And we thought about
what kind of capabilities
it might take to secure a
product and looked at all
the potential gaps that you might have
in your existing information
security organization.
And finally, we talked about
what a product security
professional is and how they might fit
into your overall
information security program.
And since product security,
as I've said before,
it depends greatly on what
kind of products you're making,
there truly is
no-one-size-fits-all structure,
but I hope that I've
given you some approach
for thinking about product
security and how it might fit
into your organization and
kind of how you would go
about determining that
and working out whether
than how you might add product
security as a focus area
within your information
security organization.
And so now I'm gonna hand it off to Wiktor
so he can walk you through a case study
of hiring product security
professionals within Europe.
And with that, Wiktor,
can you take it away?
- Hello, everyone, I would
like to briefly share with you
my experience from hiring for
a product security position
in central Europe, which
hopefully will make
this process easier for you in the future.
Well, naturally, each company is different
and your mileage may vary
depending, for example,
on your location and organization type.
So, my story dates to September,
2020, when I was informed
by my co speaker, Jen, that the head count
for the product security team
will increase, great news.
Well, life couldn't be better.
And we were looking for
a candidate in Poland
for the role of product security engineer.
And to be honest, I felt that the hiring
of a skilled individual for
that particular position
will be a piece of cake, why?
Well, mostly because there's
a lot of technically skilled
and motivated people in
Polish InfoSec Community.
And the role is interesting,
and in my opinion
it allows a candidate
not only to demonstrate,
but also to develop new skills
in many areas of InfoSec.
And our job offer was
similar to those published
by the industry leaders,
Amazon AWS, Tesla or Facebook.
It basically required
the knowledge in the area
of application security,
penetration testing,
IT architecture, where
DevOps and container security
knowledge were nice to have.
The offer looked really
solid, and after publishing,
there was nothing more to do than to wait.
And time went by one week after another.
And until this moment,
everything was straight forward,
but things started to go South from here.
And it wasn't even the
fact that the applications
that were sent to us did
not match the job position.
There were no CVS or resumes at all,
and it looked like we were
heading for a bumpy ride,
and obviously we needed
some troubleshooting
to discover the problem.
And naturally when you
troubleshoot you check
the most obvious things
first and step by step,
you get to the bottom of the problem.
Well, I started by checking if the pages
through which people send their CVS work.
And I had asked HR for help
and they said that everything
works fine from their perspective,
and for this particular
recruitment process,
and they use the same
applications and services
as for other ID and
security related positions.
And they did not notice
any problems with the flow.
So, I'm an InfoSec person
I trust, but verify.
And I like to believe that I did what most
of the InfoSec community would have done
in being on my place.
So, I created a fake online profile,
I generated a fake follow
using one of the available
websites designed for that.
I made up a pretty nice resume,
which included a technical
university abroad,
four years of application
security experience,
some industry certificates and I sent it
and you wouldn't have guessed
what happened, it worked.
The HR department was
indeed in there was right
and the tools they used for
the recruitment were working.
So this wasn't the issue,
it was something different.
Now, the only thing I needed
to do was to explain HR
why he didn't want to
invite the only candidate
that applied for this position.
but luckily they were quite understanding.
So, since the last
approach wasn't that then,
I needed to try something different.
And I decided to ask my
friends without looking
at the description of the position,
what do they think of
when they hear the name
product security or
product security engineer?
Just for you to know, each
of them had five plus years
of experience in the field
of information security,
and to be honest, their
answers surprised me.
One of them said that
product security is probably
a recruitment to an antivirus company.
And others said that if the
product we sell is security,
then this must be outsourcing.
I've also heard that this must
be a tech support job focused
on security issues, like
helping to do backups
or configurating at two 2FA.
And one of my friends even
said that, this is a buzzword
he never heard about
and he doesn't know it.
So, ouch, this is what was
even worse than I thought.
And at least we started
to realize that the issue
we are dealing with is the
problem with recognizing
the name and the brand.
So we started to approach
potential candidates
not only to ask them if they
were interested in our offer,
but also to talk with
them about the thoughts
they have about the position,
and their responses were
also really interesting.
So some people said that the job position
is really interesting but
not for the particular point
in their career they are right now.
So they might be interested
in this position in the future
when they get more experienced.
A penetration tester, we tried to hire
said that we are looking for
an IT security Kung Fu master,
a developer interested
in moving to Infosecurity
told us that we were probably searching
for a cybersecurity wizard,
and a consultant thought
that we were looking
for an InfoSec commando.
And this is interesting
because this was a compliment
from his side, he thought it was great.
So, generally they all
thought that we were looking
for a unicorn.
Okay, so we knew what
we were dealing with.
We went back to our HR
with all those opinions,
information and knowledge
that we gathered.
We sit down and modified
our job description.
We also focus more on
explaining to our candidates
what was the role about and
what opportunities it brings.
And finally, after some twists and turns,
we found our candidates.
And you might ask who fits this role?
Well, from our experience
and in a community
which is not very
acquainted with the concept
of product security, the best candidates
come from consulting
firms, where they were used
to do various projects
and have broad experience
in various InfoSec domains.
And also people from small companies
where there's not a lot
of InfoSec personnel,
and you need to get
familiar with security stuff
and handing security things as you go.
So, what I've learned from
that experience and what I wish
I knew when I was starting
the recruitment process
is that product security,
although it being on the market,
let's say from 2013, is still
in its infancy level or stage,
at least in Poland.
And it will take some time for
people to associate the name,
product security, with
what it really means.
And since the concept of product security
is not well recognized at least
outside the United States,
the recruitment process
can be a real wild West.
Good candidates that match the profile,
don't have their Job
searches, alarms triggered
to product security and
hand of candidates apply
for the position but they don't
fully grasp what it's about.
And because of that, you will
probably devote more time
and energy than expected.
Basically more time and
energy if you would compare
this recruitment process to
a process where you recruit
an application security specialist
or a penetration tester.
And to be honest, I don't
see this situation to change
without more awareness being spread
about what product security is during
a local meetups and conferences.
And I think that knowing
all of that would allow me
to approach the situation
differently in the past
and make better decisions,
and I would find the
ideal candidates faster.
So, to sum up, both Jen and
I have been talking about
during this presentation.
If you would like to
apply product security
to your program, right now
you should compile a list
of the most important
product types you have
and numerate the scope
and create a mind map,
with gaps is that you found.
Try looking for suitable candidates
within the existing team, there might be
some InfoSec talents that will make
great product security professionals.
Within the next three
months, try to develop
one full-time employee to
product security area only.
Make him address highest
risks and your company.
After six months, think
about this experiment
and decide whether this
was a good approach
and you should divide more
resources to product security
or maybe product security
is not well suited
for your company.
On the other hand, if you are hiring
for a product security
position outside the US
in the nearest future, you
should write a job description
that attracts people that in your opinion
will fit this role.
In our case, those were consultants
and InfoSec team members
from smaller organizations.
And what I mean by that,
is that you should put
in your job descriptions keywords
that will attract those people.
Something like fast-paced
company, learning opportunities
which bring cooperation with
developers, business owners
and other InfoSec teams.
There is a possibility
to do cross disciplines
between Infosecurity.
And then instruct headhunters
and HR managers to look
for the people who are
interested in those offers.
Within the next three months,
if you don't get any hits,
try updating your job description based
on the candidate's feedback,
and do some troubleshooting.
Let's hope that after six months
you'll enjoy your new employee,
and if you have some time,
please spare it, and share
your recruitment experience
during an online meetup or a conference.
Thank you very much.
If you have any questions please
join us on the Q&A session,
following this presentation.