(music)
- [Announcer] Please welcome Co-Founder
and Chief Executive Officer
of Open Raven, Dave Cole.
- As companies migrated
their cloud last decade,
security was far too
frequently left behind.
Once again, we're at an
inflection point as data floods
into the public cloud
and into a new generation
of data services and the
problems are all too familiar.
We find ourselves in a
position too frequently
where we can't answer
basic questions about data
such as where it is,
what type of data we have
and how it's protected
with the inevitable result
ultimately being data breaches
and increasingly regulatory penalties.
The singular focus of Open Raven
is to restore the visibility and control
of security teams need in
order to keep data safe
at modern speed and scale.
At Open Raven, we focus
on the massive amount
of passive data at rest as opposed
to the small amount of data
comparatively that's in motion.
And we begin by auto
locating all data services
using both serverless
technology and machine learning
in order to pinpoint data stores
that are commonly forgotten
on generic compute with an
inventory and classified data
as well as infrastructure controls
so that data exposure
can be readily identified
in order to prevent incidents.
We make it easy in order
to spot regulatory data
that's simply out of place expanding scope
and increasing business risk.
Sensitive data such as
source code that could flow
across international borders
can be spotted visually.
And lastly partner data sharing
agreements can be written
as policy and code and
automatically enforced.
Our focus on passive data
and serverless design
eliminate the visibility gaps
at far too frequently result in breaches.
We locate, discover, classify inventory
and ultimately protect data
using function as a service
which brings analysis
straight to the data itself.
This keeps it both the
data itself private as well
as it makes Open Raven
cost-effective at petabyte scale.
In contrast to legacy,
security and privacy solutions
Open Raven is up and running in minutes
using the familiar model
of connecting accounts
versus the point of proxy,
sidecar or an agent.
Further, we built our
platform on open models
so that others could
create new data sources
new data class, classification
rules, and new policy rules
all in a familiar language.
The open in Open Raven is
also about transparency
at the heart of our go-to-market
is clear technical content
and community outreach.
Since we launched a few short months ago
we've been translating this
trust into business traction.
As we count among our customers
a top three auto manufacturer,
a top 10 gaming company,
a major FinTech company, and
a leader in software testing.
The impact of our team has been felt
across the industry for
decades, whether it's founding
the Open Web Application Security Project
or creating iconic
products from Foundstone
to CrowdStrike Falcon.
As data floods into the cloud
we refuse to be left behind once again.
Open Raven (buzzer)
(music)