(music)
- [Announcer] Please welcome Co-founder
and VP of Product at Wiz,
Yinon Costica.
- Thank you very much.
Before I founded Wiz with my Co-founders,
we ran cloud security at Microsoft.
This is where we were responsible
for the cloud security products that we,
that Microsoft sells externally,
so customers can protect
themselves in the cloud,
but also the internal security
that Microsoft builds internally.
With the most important
thing that we've learned
is that cloud security
is rarely the result
of one single vulnerability,
one single misconfiguration.
It is actually the result
of multiple problems
that are all combined
together and are interrelated,
and this is what attackers
are actually exploiting.
The problem is that cloud
security tools today provide you
with a very narrow view
of the risk of your cloud.
It provides you a list of vulnerabilities,
a misconfiguration whereas the reality is
that you have a virtual machine
that is externally exposed
that has an exploitable
vulnerability on it.
And then, it has a secret that
allows for a lateral movement
into another bucket that
contains sensitive customer data.
The problem is that security tools today,
scan only for some of these things,
some of the other things they don't,
but the real problem is
that none of them is looking
at all of these things together.
So, security teams need
to manually correlate
and analyzing Tracy's attack vectors
in order to pinpoint to
the risk in their cloud.
And this is what Wiz does.
Wiz can automatically do
all of these analysis.
It connects to your cloud environment
and it analyzes the inventory
and performs a full vulnerability
assessment of your cloud
and analyze identities,
the secrets, the exposure,
and check the configuration
of any resource that
you have in the cloud,
whether it's a PaaS, a
serverless, a VM container
whether it translate AWS, Azure,
GCP, Kubernetes, OpenShift,
we scan all of them but
here is the breakthrough,
Wiz analyzes all of these together
in order to show you what are
the critical attack vectors
in your cloud environment
using a graph-based analysis.
And the way we do it is really unique.
We combine all of this information
using API-only approach
that allows you to analyze
the cloud configuration
and also the workloads themselves.
So we are without any agent were able
to achieve full coverage and
analyze your entire environment
in five minutes to deploy,
unlike agents where you
need to really pull teeth
in order to actually deploy it
on a fraction of your environment.
We have broader context so we
have all of the information.
So again, fewer, more meaningful alerts.
We are just a year, a
little bit over a year old
and we've been selling
the product for six months
and the response has been incredible.
One in 10th Fortune 100,
500 companies is using the product today
and they tell us, this is
a cloud security product,
they've been waiting for.
We are here to make cloud
secure for any organization.
Thank you.
(buzzer sound)
(music)