- Welcome to Inside the Mind
of the SUNBURST Adversary.
My name is Marco Figueroa
I'm a principle threat
researcher at SentinelOne.
Before joining SentinelOne,
I was at Intel for the last seven years.
And it was an amazing ride.
Before that I was at
McAfee then Booz Allen.
But today I wanna enter the
mindset of the adversary.
Supply-chain attacks are here to stay.
We've seen over the last couple of years,
NotPetya, CCleaner and now SolarWinds.
I wanted the rate, the supply chain attack
against pass supply and chain attacks
While describing how
threat actors took the risk
which led to their detection.
The sunburst adversaries
went after core developers
because they knew if they
infiltrated their machines
it would help them
understand the coding style,
help compromise the bill
process and make it much easier.
And I believe every organization
should have that mindset
of the adversary from the
blue team to developers.
Now the anatomy of the SolarWinds attack
this is an ongoing saga.
We know it was special operations.
Every single month a report
has come out on SolarWinds.
Stage one was modifying the build process.
Stage two was, they had
a menu of 17,000 victims
to pick from which included
nine government agencies.
They asked themselves, what do I want?
The first thing they
did was steal the keys
to the Orion platform.
The second was specific
targeting of emails, documents.
The third was based on targeting
the victims source code
as well as software.
Now we're gonna go into
the SUNBURST timeline.
The initial access to SolarWinds, right?
What SolarWinds provided
because this presentation
this premise is based off
of the SolarWinds timeline
released in February.
SolarWinds provided insight
into the threat actors events
that led to the supply chain attack.
Looking at this timeline, I
immediately thought to myself
how is it possible?
In eight days, the threat
actor penetrated the network
and knew precisely where
to inject test code
in the Orion platform.
That was very odd to me.
Immediately it stuck out once
I looked at that timeline
as a hacker.
As I mentioned before, I
first began to research.
When did the penetration I think occurred?
And I decided, hey, let me
put on my red team hat on
and let me do the initial
reconnaissance, right?
But before I go into that, I
wanna say transparency is key.
SolarWinds was likely compromised by SVR
which is Russia's Foreign
Intelligence Service.
I say likely because the White
House in a press briefing
said it has high confidence
in its assessment
of the attribution to the SVR.
But what I think is very
important is the transparency
with this investigation,
this isn't CCleaner
where you had 10 and maybe 15
companies that were targeted.
You're talking about 17,000
companies that downloaded that.
yes, the actors had
their menu to pick from
but you need hard facts.
One of the things that
has limited researchers
has been sharing of samples and artifacts
by investigators on the SUNBURST saga.
And I understand, you know
these companies have NDAs
and stuff like that but this is bigger
than just one company's NDA.
You're talking about
the biggest hack ever.
Raindrop samples weren't initially shared
due to legal reasons, they couldn't do it.
SUNSPOT has yet to be released.
And cyber samples have yet
to be shared by Microsoft.
We'll go into that in a bit.
But now we have threat hunters
waiting to reverse samples
looking for clues for code
similarities in these binaries.
These are hard facts that everyone needs.
You know, investigators
must share this to prove
this isn't high confidence.
This needs to be, here are the facts.
This is what we know.
And we need a point.
I was having a conversation on a call
with a lot of researchers and
I was having this discussion.
And what they said was,
oh, you know the bad guys
and actors, they could
use these techniques.
I'm like what?
Everyone could use Cobalt Strike.
This isn't, it's nothing new.
So I decided to put my red team hat on
and started doing reconnaissance, right?
Your normal Google Dorking.
What I found in in using different tools
was 10 email servers, 13 VPN
servers, 329 all sub domains
which some of the sub
domains was very interesting.
I would recommend you look at them
because now they have
a bug bounty program.
I didn't go into spidering
any of the hosts and that far
but within a half an hour,
I had a clearer picture
and a understanding.
Vinoth Kumar, a security researcher found
a public GitHub repo which
was leaking FTP credentials
that belong to SolarWinds, which
could upload any executable
and was then available for
SolarWinds customers to download.
This is another vector that a threat actor
could have compromised.
And we're not talking about
SUPERNOVA or SUNBURST.
This could be anyone.
And for me, what I found
is looking at this is
there's so many low hanging fruits.
When not only looking at SolarWinds
but other companies,
you can target people.
You can do so many other things.
And I hope all the people watching here,
I hope your company has
a bug bounty program
because it is so worth it.
Now, what I think is the
likely timeline was before
or after 6/17.
I think is before because
you have to grasp everything
as happened with the SolarWinds hack.
And we're gonna go into details.
But when I'm red teaming
and I penetrate a network,
what I told the team that
I'm red teaming with is
I want to be the new admin, right?
But for SolarWinds, once the threat actor
had the credentials
from the Orion platform,
they could move laterally.
Also, they would have had full access
to the cloud infrastructure,
which with credentials
and we know they have the
capabilities to compromise 2FA
because this is how they
were caught by FireEye.
So I want to go into the
initial code injection.
9/12/19 the trial run began, right?
This code modification
was a proof of concept.
They compromise the build,
inject their own code
and then verify that their signed packages
are going to appear on the
client side as expected.
Once these objectives were
met and the attackers proved
to themselves that they could do it,
the supply chain could be compromised.
They started getting ready to deploy
the real attack payload.
They tested the code for nearly
two months waiting to see
if anyone would detect it.
And because no one did,
it was time to move to that next phase.
Now this small snippet
creates a new thread
that runs that backdoor.
The location is perfect for
this kind of code to be added
as the original code
is already dealing with
a long running background task.
So they inject that code,
blends in perfectly.
So no one would really know.
So how was the build process compromised?
The likely details of the
build process compromises
in some spot, right?
Like most persistant malware SunSpot
creates a scheduled task
to execute on boot up.
It monitors the task for running processes
which then hashes the name of each process
And is compared with
the corresponding value.
It finds the MsBuild process
and spawns a new thread
to determine the Orion
software is being built
then hijacks to build
operation and inject SUNBURST.
Now there isn't a OR they use,
just an If Statement to inject code.
You know, as a researcher I looked at this
and I appreciated the
non-sophistication of this attack.
Now we're not talking about the how,
the when, we're just
talking about what they did.
It blew my mind.
All right, so putting my red team hat on.
At my prior company, we had this SDL
that we would go through
which had these processes,
which are standard practice.
But I'm pretty sure those
actors had that as well.
Such a large environment to tackle, right?
You have to replicate everything.
You need the QA, as a threat actor
you had to have that environment,
like I said replicated
and having a QA testing it.
Because patients I believe might have been
the most important thing
because of the length of time.
So it's practice rehearse,
practice rehearse
because you only have one shot.
You can't mess this up.
It's one shot, one kill.
So let's go into the SUNBURST deployment.
So the SUNBURST deployment was 2/20/20.
So let's go into the code
analysis of SUNBURST.
So the SUNBURST Trackprocesses
called by Update
and UpdateNotification is
responsible for querying
the running processes
on the victim's machine
to find the process, service
and drivers name of interest.
So this routine will get a list
of running process objects.
Then pass the three methods
below for identifying
the blacklist, the process and services.
These methods will return back true,
if the blacklist, process
or service is found
causing the malware to break out the loop.
And this was interesting
because I joined SentinelOne
four months before the
discovery of SolarWinds.
And I was proud that none of
our customers were affected.
The reason was that this
was due to that one reason
that we had built from the beginning
that our endpoint agent
had tamper protection.
You know, once many companies understood,
okay, tamper protection a
lot of vendors followed suit
to start doing that to theirs.
And our SentinelMonitor.sys
was hardcoded in the blacklist.
I mean, for me, I went
to some of the engineers
and I was like kudos to you.
You know, that's a chip on our shoulder
to have an actor say mm-mm,
if that's on their system,
we're not gonna attack them.
You know, that was big.
That's something that, you know,
internally we were proud of
because we didn't have
to run and tell customers
how to fix something
and what we needed to do
to correct the problem.
So we go a little deeper.
So the SearchServices
method which leverages
the same hashing technique to
identify services of interest
to disable.
This allows the attacker
to disable certain services
they needed to run this attack on.
And they had that list as well.
I won't go into the companies they have
but that was on the list.
So let's go, I'm gonna break down SUNBURST
and I may explain it
like very simple, right?
How did the supply chain
attack update work?
Well, once you install the Orion Update,
the injected code stayed
dormant for 12 to 14 days.
Everybody knows that now, right?
But they checked the Dev Tools,
it then checks the security services
and disables it via registry.
And then you proceed communicate to C2
and then start the malicious activity.
So putting on that red team
hat knowing that enemy.
The threat actor knew how to defeat
the Endpoint Security products.
And as a red teamer, you start being aware
when you're in different environments,
how to defeat the system.
And this is where having a red
team pays a lot of dividends
because you can allow them
to work with the blue team
and help them assist
how to fix these things.
So they understood which
victims they were targeting.
What is the shocking thing?
And I said it before, there
were no 0-dayz reported on this.
And again, there's reports
continually coming out.
So I look at this and
I say wow, these actors
they knew what they wanted.
They knew who they were targeting.
And in the White House
briefing, they put sanctions
not only against SVR but
they also put sanctions
against 10 Russian companies.
You know, contractors, the same would be
for like your Booz Allen's
or your Raytheon's,
it's the same thing.
So they put sanctions against them.
That shows you how large
this operation was.
Now let's talk about once they
have access to the systems
and you were one of the
targets they wanted to go after
and I call this part
accessing an organizations
crown jewels.
So we're still in that timeline, right?
And Skelton Key details.
Once Orion platform was compromised
the threat actors also had
access to all the API keys.
Which meant the entire cloud
environment was compromised.
I was having a conversation
the first month
that all these reports were coming out.
And one of the conversations I had was,
you know, how do you know that
they weren't targeting you
just because you didn't find anything.
And that's something we're gonna go over.
But the level of access is unprecedented
for a threat actor compared to
other supply chains attacks.
I did discuss with Ccleaner,
you know, if it wasn't
for Talos finding something odd,
they would have never gotten caught.
So I just want you to think about that.
Those AWS and a sort of API
Root Keys enables an attacker
to take over and compromise
many different things.
This enables an attacker, not only to have
full privilege admin
privileges to the account
but it also allows you
to like turn stuff on,
maybe throw some implants
into an environment.
And a company that was compromised
which provides secure certificates.
They have their certificate stolen,
they had their source code stolen.
Just to give you an example
and that's just one.
That's one of many, you will
see this is like I said,
an ongoing saga.
You will see next year,
a report on tracing back to SolarWinds.
So the Orion requires access to an IAM.
This calls for treating
IAM as compromised.
This is hard to do, but
everything needs to be blown away
and rebuilt if possible.
Now many companies cannot do that.
But if you're agile enough
and you are part of that
you need to rethink that.
You know, I had a friend said
this was like Willy Wonka.
And there were in the chocolate factory.
It had anything to pick
from, that was Eric.
So I mean, it's really for me,
this is the biggest hack ever.
So ghost in a shell.
How do you know?
I just said it, how do
you know what's good?
Or what's bad if you do not
have complete visibility, right?
Many organizations are
pressed by business needs
rather than security.
Security is a cost.
It's always in the red for companies
that aren't in security.
So when you're doing
businesses it doesn't matter
what it is.
It's always a cost.
It's not generating revenue for you.
So when a threat actor customizes malware
for your environment,
they already are aware of
how your network is configured,
what they need to do, how
to bypass those detections.
As we've seen with SolarWinds.
Now lastly, how do you
find something malicious
if a binary blends into the environment?
It's hard to do.
If there's no IoCs or IoAs
and your rules do not detect
it, how do you find it?
It's one of those puzzles, right?
Hunting is the key.
So I wanted to go into malware strains
and some of the things that
researchers really want to,
you know, peel back that onion.
So Teardrop and SunShuttle,
which was reported by FireEye
kudos to them, they were
transparent from the beginning.
You know, they provided those URLs,
they provided binaries
to help detect SUNBURST.
And they continue to share
their binaries, right?
Raindrop we discussed earlier,
which was discovered by
Symantec, but because of NDA
they couldn't share it, but
it did leak on VirusTotal.
I don't think Symantec leaked it.
I think maybe another company,
found it after the Symantec report
and uploaded it to
VirusTotal, kudos to them.
And then you have NOBELIUM.
The NOBELIUM report that was
released in March by Microsoft.
When reading their report.
I thought Sibot was a
very interesting sample
that could shine light on the actor.
Sibot reaches out to a legitimate
but compromised domain.
And I believe that's why
they didn't wanna release it
because it was a legitimate domain
but what it does, it downloads the DLL.
And renames the DLL to a dot sys extension
which is designed to achieve
persistence on the endpoint.
But again, I get about not sharing
and having an NDA in place.
And you don't wanna show that, you know
these domains were compromised.
But we know that 17,000
companies were compromised.
What are two more on the list, right?
So that I believe is super important.
Having that transparency.
It is something that we need to do.
And I harp on that because I don't think
this is a one-time thing.
What happens if through SolarWinds
they get into another company
that didn't detect them.
And now they've injected
code into more source code
or compromises other build processes.
I think this is something
that needs to happen
and needs to be shared for everyone.
So here's some of the
key takeaways, right?
And what I said was, you
know, these threat actors
was Playing with The House's Money.
And, you know, going after
FireEye is the only reason
why they were caught.
When they were going after them.
They had to say to themselves,
they're security company
they're probably gonna go
ahead in the tech desk.
And I really think that it
wasn't SVR going after them.
I think it was one of the 10 companies
that was sanctioned that went after them.
Because if you have such
a successful campaign,
you wanted to continue to go on, right?
You want that to always, always be there.
So SVR going after FireEye
was a complete mistake.
I always say, pigs get fat,
but a hog get slaughtered.
They were greedy.
They wanted everything, right?
And those red team tools, I
don't know if it was worse
giving, you know, tipping your hand.
That's just me.
I don't think it was worth it.
Now we talked about
the SDL process, right.
But what I think that needs to change
is planning or assessment.
Planning and assessment must
focus on security, right?
Architecture should
have a security champion
or influencer to provide
direction all the time.
You know, design always
with security in mind.
It's always important to
restrict access, right?
And you've seen that with
SolarWinds intern uploading code
to Github.
I mean, that was shocking
to me to have that.
Now it could be true, I don't know.
But you have to restrict access always.
But fuzzing and diffing before and after
the build process is critical.
I believe if this was in place
this attack would have been prevented
because after the build
process, if you analyze
and you review the source code
and even if you do a quick vimdiff
you would have known that code changed.
And a lot of times I've
been in environments
where you have red teams that go through,
that look for bugs.
And they're rated on how many
bugs they can find a year.
Like that is awesome.
I believe every company needs
to train their red teams.
There's places where I used to work
where you have small pockets of red team
for each organization when it's very big,
you need that right.
One red team for an organization over 15,
20,000 employees pushing code,
how can they touch everything, right?
And this is why I said before
bug bounty is very important.
Is super important because
you're gonna have that army
just like the army of reversers.
You're gonna have that
army for bug bounty.
And one of the things I say
just to touch on bug bounty,
you know, when a bug is submitted
and it's critical, you need to pay
what the market is paying.
And this will level out
where a lot of the bugs
would be submitted directly to the vendor
if they were paying that amount.
A lot of times people sell it to
or hold it to point own, right?
Because they're paying out a lot of money
and that's important.
That's a conversation
that, you know, Katie
and other people have, but
that's just my opinion.
And what I wanted to say is the victims
that were compromised
DTA, don't trust anything.
If you downloaded that
update and let's say,
they didn't pick you
guys or you don't think
don't have that mindset.
You know, try to carpet bomb everything.
Do not trust anything created
after the SUNBURST install.
And like I mentioned before
I had a friend that was a
head of security at a company
that was affected,
stated we don't have it.
We didn't see anything.
And I'm like, yeah, a lot of
companies didn't see anything.
And now you're starting to see
that other companies are
reaching out to the company
that was affected and stated,
hey where have you seen this?
And that was the example
that I gave earlier about
the one company that had their
certificates compromised.
So let's go into the mindset of an actor.
You know, it's a key
takeaway on this presentation
the mindset of an actor's
home through training
and understanding of the adversary.
You know, you're not just
gonna come into the industry
and just have that, oh
this is what they would do.
No, you need to have, I
always say the same thing.
If you're a blue teamer
you wanna do offensive security training.
And if you're a red teamer
you wanna do defensive
training to understand
how the protections in
place and try to balance it.
And you know, I do that today.
I love to go and play both
sides because I constantly
when I'm reversing engineering anything,
or looking at something,
I look at it as an
adversary and vice versa.
Or you should create actor
simulations with your red team,
as well as training for the blue team
and training for developers, right?
A lot of developers were seeing
that they don't have that training
and understanding how to secure code.
You know, I used to work
with one of my friends.
He's like, it works?
Yeah, it works.
All right, that's it, it doesn't matter.
It works.
And I'm like, no, that's
not how it goes, right?
So kudos to that person
because he has gotten
better over the years.
Now you must have visibility
into threat hunting
into your endpoints and you know,
when people are hunting, it's a skill.
You know, they can't do their job well
if they don't have those
tools on the endpoint.
So this is the thing, as
what will the attackers want
if they penetrated your network?
And what are those crown jewels?
If you're not having those conversations,
you need to do that.
And the way you get to that answer
is I feel like this is one of
the most important exercises
that must happen in all organizations.
You know, creating a internal
think tank or a brown bag.
And coming up with worst case scenarios
if you're a hospital, you
know if ransomware hits us,
you know, are we protected?
Is that good?
If it hits the CT scan or MRI,
is that segregated correctly?
Or if you're a car
company it's the same way,
can someone attack our
car and take over it
or even in the systems and
compromise the build process
or put code in there just like SUNBURST?
And these are conversations
that will happen now
that this attack happened.
And for me, that is all from my side,
guys I had a pleasure
to share my research,
until next time.
Thank you for joining.
Have a good day.