- If you've not been sleeping
due to cyber concerns,
and are attending this talk,
I will do my best to keep you awake.
Welcome to RSA.
I would like to thank you
for attending the session.
I'm gonna be speaking about
the way cyber criminals
can attack through simple
uncomplicated means
ranging to complex intricate schemes
but I'm also gonna be talking
about how you can ultimately
protect yourself from both.
RSA 2020 was the last physical
event that I attended.
Ironically, while in
San Francisco for this,
I received notification that I just hit
the 1 million mile mark with Air Canada.
Like most of you, I've not flown since.
And I do not see this
changing in the near term.
Simply put COVID has led
to a massive shift to remote everything,
working, buying and selling, banking,
just to mention a few.
This wide dispersion of cyber interactions
has resulted in an exponential
growth of attacks surfaces.
Given the rapid transition,
as with other similar disruptive changes,
this has also led to less
strategized security responses.
Our journey will start with an overview
of threats as analyzed and
compiled by Blackberry.
Next, I will introduce
an emerging cyber threat
landscape that is coming
at us like a tsunami
something you may not
have given a thought to,
even though like Google
will affect all of us.
And it will affect all of
us in the very near future.
This is an area where you, as
part of the cyber community,
have the power to
personally affect the shape
of this brave new world.
I'll review details of this later,
but if you're worried you
might never sleep again, don't.
As a reward for your patience,
I will be giving away cyber
security secrets and advice,
that will protect you and
your business or company,
from the vast majority of threats,
all of this in the next 28 minutes.
So let's get started.
In a world with increasing connectivity,
and rapidly evolving mobility solutions,
anyone focused on building
or deploying secure
and trusted products or services,
could suffer from a
justified lack of sleep.
Despite the threats we face
from simple to sophisticated,
Blackberry has a long track record
of building and securing
our connected lives.
There are patterns that make
cyber threats more predictable
and a methodology that allows
us to predict ourselves.
In this diagram,
you will see a vault that
contains a few walls.
This is often the reality
on a cyber data landscape.
Many corporations put
in preventative measures
while missing the comprehensive
and holistic solutions
that would provide the missing walls.
Even with a fully built vault,
or protected system without
the proper simple precautions,
you're essentially leaving the combination
on a post-it note on
the door of the fault,
which is not good.
It only takes one breach to
get access to an entire system.
So who am I and why am I
speaking to you about this?
This is one topic that
keeps me awake at night.
My thread management
skills were honed as a kid
growing up with five brothers
and a pretty tough sister
on a family farm.
We had to be agile and find solutions
quickly on many fronts.
I drove machinery, was an electrician,
a plumber, and a veterinarian.
Of course, many of the
threats were physical
cane came from my older brothers.
Early in my career I wrote software
that controlled the banking machine
and I spent some early
days breaking into systems.
Security was always top of mind,
even if sometimes it was getting around it
just for the challenge.
Early in my career, I wrote a white paper
on 20 ways to become a super
user in less than a minute.
I had the privilege of evolving my skills
through work with IBM,
Bell Northern Research,
Cisco, Juniper, Dyson
Engineering and now Blackberry.
I've witnessed technology
disruption across computers,
internet, mobile, cloud.
And I've always been interested
in how we secure this technology.
It's really one of the
most pressing issues
of our quickly evolving
Uber connected world.
Today, I'm Chief Technology
Officer at Blackberry.
As part of this role,
I run an innovation lab
with over 100 people, looking
for advancements in security
across enterprise, automotive,
and government spaces.
A key part of what
Blackberry has always done
is providing privacy by securing data.
Over the last last decade,
we have evolved into a
security software company.
Our most recent acquisition of silence
in the early 2019 gives
us a next generation
Antivirus ML technology.
ML is essential for fighting
cyber challenges of the future.
What does this mean really?
For antivirus we look
across billions of files
and classify what is safe and what is not.
And it allows us to detect malware
like WannaCry years before it even exists.
So, to start off with,
on the threat report
Blackberry publishes are
our threat researchers
publish a threat report every year.
And in February of this year,
we launched the 2021 threat reports
that basically looks at
fact-based projections
on the cyber threats of the previous year.
I'm gonna highlight some content today
but for deeper insights,
I really recommend you download
and read this full report.
The webpage is up on the screen.
You can Google Blackberry
2021 Threat Report.
And again, beyond what
I will talk about here
are there many, many more to
be found in the actual report.
So, a threat activity in 2020
COVID-19 as a vulnerability.
This is an unprecedented year
and COVID-19 introduced many challenges
making us feel helpless.
One thing I felt very personally
and my team were pleased to do,
we helped Canada work on
the COVID alert strategy.
We were involved in doing security audits
and architecture audits of
providing a more secure solution
for this critical service
when it was being deployed.
COVID-19 triggered mass move
from enterprise infrastructure
and security to home wifi,
virtual private networks,
bring your own device, configurations,
this could have been a
very precarious move.
Were VPN concentrators
going to support the fact
that everything was now upside down?
It's like planning
for what happens when
Niagara falls goes backwards.
It's just unprecedented.
And so many people work
together to try to figure out
how to make it work for us.
There's also much more
securely sensitive content
being stored in people's homes.
So, these aggressive dynamics accelerated
what was already in progress
in terms of mobile work trends,
but this acceleration it rapidly
extended the threat service
as organization around the world
were focused in immediate
pivot to this new work reality.
Remote workers were cited
as a cause of breaches
for 20% of organizations since
the start of the pandemic.
And there's an onslaught
of COVID-19 cyber attacks.
Attackers attempt to trick users
into installing a COVID-19
tracker application,
it's actually a ransomware, and
then they have to pay money.
There's misinformation sites,
there's a high number of rogue websites,
but as a security community,
we need to continue
to effectively address
the security implications
of introduced by this large
scale remote work reality.
We've been forced into this
and we need to continue to make it better.
We need to work together.
APT Mercenaries, we've
noted continued rise
in the outsourcing of everything,
including cyber espionage,
to mercenary APT groups.
You know, these are hackers for hire.
This can make threat actor
identification quite challenging
at a high level.
The tactics, techniques, and procedures
of these mercenaries often resemble
highly sophisticated
state sponsored campaigns.
However, the profiles and geographies
of their victims are far
too diverse to be aligned
with a single bad actors interest.
Threat actor identification
can be extremely challenging
for threat researchers with
this use of APT mercenaries.
Okay, the next area to
discuss is cryptojacking.
Bitcoin and therefore crypto mining
has been around since 2009.
Crypto miners receive Bitcoin
by verifying transactions
and solving numerical hashing problems.
The rate at which Bitcoin is mined
has halved every four years.
This having adversely affects
the difficulty of mining,
and therefore the computing power
required to effectively mine Bitcoin.
Cryptojacking the unauthorized use
of computer to mine cryptocurrency,
offers an illicit means to work
around the rising cost of crypto mining.
The infamous Slick Willie
was asked why he robbed banks
and he answered, "Because
that's where the money is."
So, cryptojackers, often
target high powered servers
in an enterprise environment
in order to maximize
their mining activities.
Why do they do that?
Because that's where
the CPU horsepower is.
So these server clusters
are targeted attack vectors
of this crypto mining.
As Bitcoin goes up so does
the reward for mining it.
So, as we're talking about vaults
the gold in the vault is
getting shinier over time
as the value of Bitcoin goes up.
Deepfake threat activity.
I'm sure everyone has seen
an interesting online video
of people posing as
celebrities with a convincing
overlay of the celebrities
appearance or voice,
while entertaining and scary,
this poses serious risks.
And we are now seeing its weaponization
which was accelerated as a world quickly
pivoted to working remotely.
Deepfakes posing as
important political figures
or celebrities have been used
to spread misinformation.
Symantec reports three cases of seemingly
deepfaked audio of
different chief executives.
The story goes, something like this,
a senior official was tricked
into transferring money
after he received an urgent
call from a fraudster
who impersonated the CEO voice
using defect technologies.
And now we're seeing several deepfake
as a service offerings.
As normalcy returns around the world
threat actors may look towards
increasing the weaponization
of deepfake technologies in the workplace.
Securing the electoral process.
This has been quite a year
in retrospect for elections.
Headline from the Guardian
stated, "US security advisor
"claims China has taken most active role
"in election meddling."
If you wanna hack an election,
the most obvious and least imaginative way
is to attack the ballot box.
But there's lots of other methods.
Policymakers and their
teams are vulnerable targets
for having their social media accounts
mined for exploitable information.
Election misinformation through
social media or news sites,
can be used to see doubt in
the integrity of the election.
2021 highlighted the fact
that minimizing interference
is a critical aspect of
maintaining free and fair elections
but it's also becoming
increasingly more difficult.
BAHAMUT is an active threat
group investigated extensively
by Blackberry threat researchers in 2020.
This is a well-funded technically adept
highly secretive and
effective threat group.
BAHAMUT may obscure its activity,
by imitating the same tactics, techniques,
and procedures popularized
by other threat groups.
I don't know if you've read it
but this sounds like a
subplot of cryptonomicon.
Backdoors and exploit shell
code written by BAHAMUT
often includes anti-analysis features.
When it's activities are detected
the threat group quickly changes tactics
and corrects any missteps
leading to its exposure.
Attackers keep evolving their
products to evade detection
so they can keep doing what they do.
Mobile overlay attack.
Social engineering continues
to be a highly effective means
for stealing payment and
accessing information
presented within the context
of an installed application
a prompt for a credit card
or password using well-designed form,
often yield success for attackers.
This trick works especially well,
when time coincide with
an application launch.
We're all busy,
were doing many things
were clicking through.
We don't notice that something
extra is going on in our device.
Quite often if a malicious application
requires additional permissions,
it will grant itself permissions.
It can submit a request to the OS
and then automatically click okay
without any user involvement.
This attack is quite
often used around banking
and information stealing malware.
So this is scary, right?
This mobile overlay attack,
does it feel like a tsunami?
Well, it's not the tsunami
I'm gonna talk about.
Let's just call this one a big wave.
My tsunami is coming very shortly.
Attack on critical verticals,
when you want to be disruptive
critical verticals are a popular target.
It's no surprise that in
times of global pandemic
stuff that people care
about like healthcare
and medical research
are primary interest to cyber criminals.
During 2020 Blackberry
observed increased incidents
of ransomware, attacks against hospitals
and healthcare providers.
Numerous phishing campaigns
aimed at stealing login credentials,
targeted critical sectors.
These attacks on critical
verticals are a great examples
of an opportunistic events that occur
as a result of major disruption.
So this concludes the
high level teaser content
from the threat report.
Please do download it and read it though.
There's some really
great content in there.
So this concludes my threat report teaser.
On my next screen I'm gonna show you
there's gonna be a video
of a woman on a computer.
I am sure nothing bad will
happen to this situation.
Oh my, would you pay?
Many people do, some
people say everybody pays.
But we are familiar with the
impact of being compromised
on equipment that we use
every day such as a laptop.
The effect can vary wildly
from the minor inconvenience
of having to pay ransomware
to a major inconvenience
such as identity theft.
This is life-changing catastrophic events.
I talk to people at security conferences
or I talked to people at
security conferences in the past
and you could just see in
their face the impact of...
I've had one gentleman in London, England,
talking about a room full of computers
that had to be re-imaged
and their entire inventory
across a global supply
chain had been wiped out
and they had to run
manually for two weeks.
I could just feel the emotion in his voice
as he told these stories.
And there's so many of them.
So, just as I pause here,
how well are you protected?
Do you have 2FA and secure passwords,
unique secure passwords on everything?
Do you have a zero trust architecture?
Do you follow the principles
of these privileges?
I wonder, were you impacted
by the solar wind security incident?
How are you protected
now and into the future?
Just imagine, this cyber attack,
imagine the impact of a
similar type of cyber attack,
a security attack but
in a two ton computer
moving at 56 kilometers per hour.
Now the impact has gone from inconvenient
to impacting the safety of
yourself and others around you.
Cyber-physical security is a new risk
in this emerging kinetic IOT space.
This was the tsunami I was
talking about at the beginning.
And by the way, it's also
covered in the threat report
as a special topic.
Connected vehicles which can
contain over 100 independent
developed software components
are difficult to secure
due to the multiple vendors
involved in their assembly.
This year, a number of
international entities
participating in the
automotive supply chain
make enforcing common cyber
security criteria extremely challenging.
Vehicles are increasingly
connected to the internet,
and this will be ramping
aggressively in the near future
especially with the emergence of 5G.
So, connected cars, let's
just lay a baseline.
Things used to be simpler.
With vehicles were in the
midst of a rapid transformation
led by the commodification of hardware
and the rise of complexity
and sheer amount of software
on each vehicle.
The trends are clear.
Cars are increasing their CPU capabilities
and converging on larger,
more capable compute clusters.
The number of connected cars
is increasing dramatically.
The bandwidth to the car
is increasing dramatically
electrification and autonomous development
are all driving increased
software in the vehicle.
This is a major, major
evolution that we're witnessing.
You are literally driving
around in a server right now
when you're in your car.
There's an adage as we,
and we learn this time and time again,
as we add CPU and bandwidth,
features will certainly follow.
But look at this, there's
growing complexity
already today in the car.
This diagram shows an increasingly
more feature rich automobile.
Increased connectivity, local
and cloud compute capabilities
and the introduction of many
new vehicle capabilities.
It leads to a much broader feature list
and emergence of software
as a key differentiator.
I'm not gonna go through
it all, but night vision,
lane correction, heads up display,
you get the trend, adaptive
this, automatic that,
we experience a rapid development
of driver assist functionality
leading to more and more autonomous,
or leading towards more
autonomous features.
Perhaps you have some autonomous features
on your current vehicle like lane assist,
automatic braking, or automatic parking,
it's predicted by 2030 electronics,
plus software will be about
50%, the cost of the car.
But where from a cybersecurity perspective
does this leave us?
This diagram shows a
broader vehicle cockpit,
a vehicle cockpit in
cloud with some threats
for illustrative purposes.
A closer view on the details,
stealing passwords,
open-source vulnerabilities,
man in the middle attacks,
shows us that many of the threats
that we already have been dealing with
are also applicable in the car.
Key threat vectors,
internet based attacks,
4G, 5G, sensor attacks, GPS
radar, hardware attacks,
OBD two ports, USB near-field, wireless,
Bluetooth, key fobs, the list goes on.
Additional threat surface
with this new functionality
means increased need for
resilience in cyber security.
Service-oriented business
models are also taking shape,
which means not only safety concerns,
but privacy and financial implications.
Since we're looking at the introduction
of integrated payment systems.
Complexity of the cloud
adds additional challenges
and many current vehicle
attacks are cloud focused today.
There is hope and work, of course,
there's new cybersecurity regulation
adopted by UNECE WP.29.
It's being introduced
that requires automakers
to adhere to cybersecurity requirements,
and automakers have the flexibility
in tailoring the requirements
into their processes.
The cybersecurity UN
regulation is supported
by international standard ISO/SAE21434.
So, you'll hear that if you're not already
familiar with this WP.29 21434.
But this is an area where
cyber security experts
can help take their knowledge
that they possess today
and the solutions that they use today
take this knowledge to this
new platform to make it safer,
faster, until effective
cyber security protocols
and procedures are incorporated
into the design and manufacture vehicles.
Modern automobiles could
effectively be considered
in secure networks.
Okay, so that concludes my deeper dive
on connected automobiles
and my tsunami that I had
teased about at the beginning.
But we're now on to the hopeful
chapter of my presentation,
Cybersecurity Best Practices Top 10 List.
Some of you know...
I imagine this community
knows who David Letterman is.
So it's inspired by him.
Whether we're building new products
from embedded systems to
vehicles, to enterprise software,
we're looking to improve
security in our systems
that we already have been deployed.
We see common tactics that
are used by our adversaries
to exploit vulnerabilities
but there's also common principles
that we can employ to
protect from such attacks
whether it's simple or sophisticated
we can get much closer
to a much safer system.
Some of these will apply to
you directly and others may not
but it's important that you
study your cyber readiness
from a broad perspective.
Okay, number 10, cybersecurity
best practices top 10 list.
Number 10, trusted foundation.
Building analogy, the value
on the top will not be stable
without a trusted foundation.
Look at your people, your
process, your technology,
your hardware, your
software, your dev practice,
ensure you have a root of trust.
You need a deterministic architecture
that behaves well under stress,
under load, or under attack.
I like to say security
cannot be retrofitted
ask yourself and other experts.
Can I really trust this foundation?
Number nine, use secure components.
Analogy, one week wall
in a vault makes it very,
it makes it less a vault like I would say.
So, it's one wall, what
makes a vault useless.
Proper authentication of software
and hardware components is important.
On a car, you could isolate your safety
and non-safety components
perhaps through a hypervisor.
Laptops and smartphones use
a trusted computing base
for critical items.
You may have heard of the
trusted execution environment.
Use proven components with
defense in depth deployment.
So if we look at system on ships,
they must be secure in architecture
and access ports protected.
Did you shut down debug
ports or default accounts?
Is your memory secure?
These SOC should store a secret key
and act as the root of trust
for secure boot verifying
software before it's loaded.
The operating system must have
multi-level security features
such as access control policies,
encrypted file systems,
ruthless execution, path,
space control, thread level,
anomaly detection, and
applications in a vehicle.
All applications that are
downloaded should be certified
and signed with proper
authorities before they're run.
Assign manifest file
will set the permissions
of these resources.
These application must
always run in a sandbox.
These are the kinds of things
we should be looking at.
Number eight, protect the supply chain.
And you notice that we
added one wall to the vault.
Code scanning or composition analysis
use sophisticated binary code scanning
during software development or delivery
to provide an assessment, which
includes file composition,
what kind of CVEs are
contained in the file if any,
what kind of vulnerabilities
and indicators and metrics
to enable a secure
agile software solution?
This data can be used
to improve the software
to reduce its security risk
prior to production builds.
The other thing you need to look at
is continuous physical
security vendor sites.
Ensure that all vendors and
vendor sites are certified
via vulnerability assessment
and are required to maintain a certificate
of approved for delivery.
And this evaluation needs to be performed
on a continuous basis.
The solar winds incident
reported in December of 2020
reminded the world, that
effective threat detection
is a critical component
of a secure environment.
It also showed a scary attack factor
one that infects the dev pipeline.
I wonder if you were impacted by that.
Number seven secure communications
channels in your product.
Do not leave any clear text
or easily readable data,
do not move data on or off
your device unprotected.
Government secure phones
had something called DDAR
dual data at rest with different certs
applied to each layer of the encryption.
Very, very hard to decode that.
All device communication was
also encrypted data in flight.
This was looked at through a few lenses.
So how strong is your
encryption, but also who is it
that's doing this operation on your system
and what are they allowed to do?
So, encryption, authentication,
and authorization,
all need to be looked at.
And this applies within the end point,
end point to cloud, cloud to cloud.
So, specifically on a vehicle,
this means ensuring all
communication between the automobile
and the external world
is authentic and trusted.
Number six, develop
using secure methodology.
A developer can be paid
a lot to inject malware.
How do you catch this?
Could you catch it today?
You should agree on project
specific security requirements
including the extent of
assessment activities
at the beginning of a project,
tracking and reporting
metrics related to training
product and security teams
should be able to view the
metrics and trends at any times,
maintaining and using common
security guidance catalog
that contains specific
requirements, recommendations,
and procedures for avoiding
security vulnerabilities
and complying with different
customer requirements.
This is really important for traceability
for standards or safety.
Number five, monitor for anomalies.
Ensure that all software
has integrated analytics
and diagnostics that can
capture events and logs
and report the same to a cloud.
Basically is the device running normally
or is there something abnormal
happening in the device?
This will vary by device, but it could be
is there a root user on the device?
How many files are open?
How busy is the CPU, how
much memory is being used?
Is the communication going
off the correct ports?
You need to really monitor to make sure
that the device has not been compromised
and is acting strange due to
some kind of crypto event.
This is incidentally a very
important area of focus
for the use of machine
learning in security solutions
with the volume of data in today's systems
and the speed at which breaches occur,
this is an essential tool
for helping you protect your company.
I like to think of this
monitor for anomalies
as putting a camera inside the vault
to monitor what's going on.
Just in case someone happens
to breach the exterior.
Plan for getting compromised
basically a perfectly secure
system is not possible.
You need to know what you're going to do
in the event that you are compromised
layout details for steps you would take.
If in fact, your system is compromised,
reduce the blast radius, have
a response communication plan,
have remediation recovery plan.
So many times when a
critical event happens,
people are not prepared,
prepare for it and act on it.
This is important
business continuity step.
Do you have critical communications
infrastructure today,
that will continue to work
when your systems have been breached?
Number three, deliver updates
and address vulnerabilities.
We're getting closer.
Let's add one more wall to the vault.
A device that is not updated
as a ticking time bomb.
For being compromised as hackers
essentially have all the time in the world
and all the known CVEs at their disposal.
Future-proof your system
but make sure you have a secure
OTA while you're doing it.
Remember detecting the
threat is only one step.
Actually closing the gap
with a software update
is an important one.
It's quite common for old threats
to go unaddressed for
surprisingly long periods.
We are still seeing reports
of the continued threat
of WannaCry ransomware
even though the attack
occurred four years ago,
millions of people are
still running windows XP.
I doubt they come to RSA.
That's my assertion but I could be wrong.
Number two, drive holistic protection.
We talk about prepare,
prevent, detect, and respond.
Think about all four of those phases
in your cyber security posture.
I know it's a top 10 list
and I snuck four onto one,
but it bears repeating.
Think about these four,
prepare, prevent, detect, and respond.
It only takes one entry
point to lose control.
And number one, cybersecurity
best practices top 10 list.
Number one is prioritize
a security culture.
Security as a community approach,
learn from and leverage
the best that is available.
Defense in depth.
There is a lot of historical
knowledge that can be applied.
If you do not architect a
plan to protect yourself,
you are left with hoping
you are not impacted.
And my friends hope is
not a good strategy.
Watch how others are attacked.
Try to hack yourself, have a bug bounty,
pay people to hack you.
And then we see the wall
of the safe going on,
security is not about
one person or one team.
Everyone can help.
Security education can help
your coworkers, your employees,
your family members,
friends, all be safer.
So, here's the top 10 list at a glance,
adopting these principles in our view
is very similar to making sure
that all sides of your safe are intact
and that you haven't
forgotten to lock the safe
with a good strong password
and make a two factor for good measure.
Adopt these principles will also allow you
to rest assured that no matter
what threat materializes
you will be more prepared.
It may not apply to all your needs,
but there's general wisdom in this list.
So, looking at this list
how did you do for alignment
with these best practices?
So, we talked about the threat report.
We drilled in on connected
vehicles, current and future.
And remember you can help us
make that environment safer.
And then we walked through a top 10 list
to help make us more prepared.
Your data is your data and your
information can be protected
from both lazy and the
sophisticated cyber criminals.
With security technology
and best practices,
please be vigilant.
Well and stay from viruses of all kinds.
Thank you very much for
attending this session.
And if you're still with
me now and not sleeping
like our CSO in this picture,
I can still take questions.