(music)
- Hi, I'm Steve Grobman, CTO of McAfee,
and I'm afraid of snakes.
I'm not the only one.
About half of Americans
are afraid of snakes.
I'm also a believer in data,
and the data tells us this
is an irrational fear.
At least in the United States,
where only around five people
a year die of snake bites.
The number of deaths from stinging insects
is 20 times that amount.
And the number of people
who die in auto accidents,
a thousand times.
So why don't we think twice
about getting in a car
and driving at 70 miles
an hour on the highway,
but are petrified when a snake
crosses the hiking trail.
The answer in this case is evolution.
The studies have shown that
humans, even small children,
are instinctively able to
quickly identify snakes.
Researchers believe this
evolutionary ability
allowed humans to survive by
avoiding threats in the wild.
Our perception of other
risks in the physical world
are also miscalibrated, not
due to biology or evolution,
but rather the way that they're portrayed
in media and culture.
In Texas, where I live,
we have a great example
of this. tornadoes.
We have tornado sirens, tornado shelters.
And when a destructive tornado does occur,
it makes a top story on the news
with graphic images of
catastrophic destruction.
In reality, very few
people die from tornadoes.
In 2020, 24 tornadoes killed
76 people in the United States.
Seven times at number, 529,
died falling off ladders.
If only there was a scientific
approach we could use
to measure risk, to help
counteract or bias perceptions.
There is.
I'd like to introduce
you to the micromort.
The micromort, or micro
probability of death,
is a unit of risk that represents
a one-in-a-million chance of sudden death.
This concept was first
introduced by Stanford professor
Ronald Howard in 1980.
Everything we do has some level of risk.
Take driving.
Statistically, there's a one
in a million chance of dying
in an accident when you
travel 230 miles by car.
Therefore, driving 230 miles
exposes you to one micromort.
Driving 460 miles exposes
you to two, and so on.
We can use the micromort
to challenge our intuition
on what is actually risky and what is not.
For example, scuba diving
is surprisingly safe
and only three micromorts per dive.
And skydiving exposes you
to only 10 micromorts.
I'm talking about
parachuting from a plane,
not base jumping, which
expose you to way more, 430.
This also allows us to
much better understand
how risky some very
dangerous activities are.
A single attempt to summit
Mount Everest, for example,
exposes the climber to 38,000 micromorts.
Or think of that as the
same risk as performing
almost 4,000 parachute jumps.
What does this have to do with cyber?
Many of our perceptions
about risk in the cyber world
are also miscalibrated,
and we need to use the moral
equivalent of the micromort
in the way we think about cyber risk.
Just as we do in the physical world,
we need to use science based on data
to counteract the influence of
social and traditional media
and our raw emotions.
Organizations worry about
all sorts of threats.
Mass malware, we see every hour.
Spear phishing attacks
on critical employees
we see every day.
And the rare nation-state directed attacks
that have the potential to be devastating.
One observation is that
the frequency of an event
is inversely proportional to its impact.
We see the exact same thing in nature,
whether we're talking about tornadoes,
earthquakes, or asteroid impacts.
For example, with tornadoes,
the Enhanced Fujita Scale
goes from zero to five,
with five being the most severe,
yet 89% are EF1 or lower,
and only 11% are two,
three, four, or five.
The impact of a cyber event
has multiple levels of nuance.
We need to consider the lethality
to impacted organizations
independently from the global impact.
For example, we see some
events that are high impact,
even devastating to a single organization
but have limited global impact.
Sony, Target, Marriott,
just to name a few.
Other events such as WannaCry and NotPetya
were catastrophic to numerous
organizations around the world
because they spread fast
and were indiscriminately destructive.
We also need to analyze the
different aspects of the damage
resulting from a cyber event.
For example, a human-operated intrusion
with minimal direct impact,
such as stealing internal
planning documents,
still leaves the potential for any number
of residual back doors and implants.
The indirect cost regaining
environmental integrity
can be immense.
Another area of focus is
whether the risk we face
is passive or active.
What risks are we exposed
to by simply operating
in a technologically advanced world?
And what additional risk do
we expose our organizations to
as a result of our business decisions?
We need to minimize risk
from passive threats
such as cloud-based productivity apps.
We also need to understand
the risk-reward benefit
when we choose to engage
in high-risk areas.
Just as a hiker may
willingly climb a mountain
even though they know
it's inherently risky,
your business might invest
in a new technology,
such as the next generation
container capability
whose threat surface is
not yet fully understood
if the return is significant.
Let's build a model that takes
all these factors into consideration.
The principle components boil
down to these three vectors.
The potential lethality of an event
to an individual organization.
The number of organizations
that could be impacted
and the likelihood of occurrence.
This model is all about risk.
But remember, risk is the
potential for negative outcome,
while an event is the historical record
of what has occurred.
Past events don't predict future outcomes,
but they can provide data
to scientifically assess
the likelihood of future scenarios.
Think of it this way.
Just as we don't know exactly
what natural disasters
will impact us next year,
we can prepare for
different types of events
based on historical frequencies.
Similarly, we don't know exactly
what type of cyber events
will occur in the future, but
we can look at frequencies
of different scenarios along
the vectors we discussed
to understand how to prepare our defenses.
So how does what we should worry about
align with what we do worry about?
To answer this, we analyze
traditional and social media
along with the web
activity of McAfee sites
related to campaigns and threats.
We found that many of the
high-profile targeted attacks
that received much
attention were carried out
against one organization.
Memorable examples include the DNC hack,
Equifax, Ashley Madison and OPM.
Should we focus this much
attention on high-profile,
single organization incidents?
Yes and no.
Clearly some of these
attacks are newsworthy
because they relate to national security,
cyber impact to elections,
or the impact to the
organization's customers.
Additionally, from a
defender's perspective,
how a lethal targeted attack occurs
is important to understand so
that we know how to prepare
for a custom human-operated attack.
But, we need to be careful
not to overemphasize
the exact playbook that is
executed in these scenarios.
Yes, it's important to ensure
that you're not running
a vulnerable version of Apache Struts
on your external facing web servers,
but it's as important to ensure
that no external vulnerabilities exist
that could lead to similar exploitation.
Conversely, some
campaigns such as TrickBot
get little media coverage,
but organizations need to pay
greater attention to them.
They act as the catalyst for secondary
high-attack scenarios.
For example, a human-operated
ransomware attack
engineered to hold the most
valuable asset for ransom.
TrickBot changes its implementation
frequently and impacts
an extraordinarily large
number of organizations.
Why does SolarWinds get
so much more attention
when they both enable
human-operated secondary attacks?
Media coverage can inform us
about emerging global cyber events,
but we need a more science-based approach
to optimize our defenses.
We need to comprehensively evaluate
all events that impact organizations.
If we simplify our three vector
model by dropping frequency,
we can examine the relationship
between impact and scale.
A starting point is to look
at the high-profile events
that we've seen over the last few years
in combination with the cyber
threats we see every day.
We can then map their impact
to the number of organizations affected.
Let's break things into
three simple elements
we've dealt with for decades.
Targeted attacks that affect
a single organization,
indiscriminate malware
such as password stealers
and ransomware, and nuisance threats,
such as PUPs and adware.
One of the things that stands out
is the inverse relationship
between impact and breadth.
But in the last few years,
we've also seen the sophistication
of attacks increase,
which adds new elements to our chart.
Supply chain attacks.
Human-operated ransomware.
And one of my favorites, the mega-worms.
In this last case, this
is not a new innovation.
We've dealt with mass-spreading
worms since the '90s.
The ability for an attacker to
use a wormable vulnerability
to convert victims into attackers,
remains one of the most powerful
adversarial innovations of all time.
These additional elements
have the same relationship
where impact and breadth
are inversely correlated,
but we can see the slope has flattened.
Innovation has provided adversaries
with greater levels of efficiency
to deliver lethality to their victims.
What do we do about it?
How do we defend our organizations?
Unfortunately, there's not
a single set of actions
or solutions that cover
all of these areas.
While it's critical to
focus on the top left
and not become the victim
of a targeted attack,
we also have to ensure
that critical data files
aren't stolen by indiscriminate malware,
or that productivity
doesn't grind to a halt
due to a deluge of nuisance threats.
We need good cyber hygiene
along with user education
to prevent everyday threats,
good threat and artificial intelligence
for indiscriminate and zero-day malware.
And when there's a human
attacker on the other side,
we need a combination of
technology and cyber operators
to defeat the adversary because
no technology on its own
can outsmart or outplay
an advanced attacker.
But we shouldn't forget
that these are overlapping.
For example, even in an
advanced attack scenario
driven by a human actor,
good cyber hygiene such as
a well-patched environment
will make it harder to find
exploitable vulnerabilities.
And good threat and
artificial intelligence
limits the attack tools at their disposal.
We have limited budgets
and our cyber professionals
can't do everything.
So it's critical that
we understand and ensure
that the investments we do
make have the strongest benefit
as compared to the risk
that they're mitigating.
Here's the bottom line.
We can't defend our organizations
by acting on gut instinct.
Just as is counterintuitive
that in the physical world,
an investment in $6
anti-slip bathtub stickers
provides a higher return
on risk mitigation
than a $4,000 tornado shelter.
Implementing multifactor
authentication likely reduces
more risk than mandating
third-party code audits
in an attempt to address
supply chain attacks.
My call to action for you is this,
let's make the best cyber
defense decisions possible.
Yes, watch the news and
monitor your Twitter feed,
but be hyper-conscious to
counterbalance natural instincts
and reactions driven by media and hype.
Ensure that every trade-off
and decision you make
to defend your organization
is based on data and objectivity.