- Hi, we're coming to you as
contributors to the Suricata
and other open source
network security projects.
But most of the thinking here
comes from our experience
during our day jobs at Stamus Networks,
where we have built the
commercial network detection
and response system on
top of sort of Suricata.
My name is Peter Manev.
I'm Chief Strategy
Officer of Stamus Networks
and also part of the Suricata core team.
- Hello, I am Eric Leblond,
I'm the CTO of Stamus Networks.
I'm part of, as well as Peter,
of Executive Council for
Information Security Foundation,
the foundation which is
driving Suricata development.
- Now, folks, a couple of things
that we wanted to talk to you about today
is Suricata and SELKS.
What is the relation there?
Reducing the noise with
metadata classification
of all those alerts
that Suricata produces.
What other data can Suricata
produce and is useful
for finding that needle
in the haystack, you know.
Filter those alerts out.
We're gonna do our small hands-on demo
to show you what exactly we mean by that
with actual hands-on examples.
We're gonna talk about assets,
asset-oriented threats and signs.
We're gonna talk about
classification and tagging.
How to further reduce the noise.
And how to apply kind of,
what we've learned today
and any additional resources for that.
So, basic Suricata 101.
So, Suricata does a live traffic analysis.
It started as an idea 12 years ago,
but evolved to be something
much more than that.
It can, 'cause Suricata can be deployed
to sniff info traffic
possibly or in-lines,
as an intrusion prevention system.
It can, Suricata itself,
can do full packet capture,
and right hold up disk performance,
the kind of performance ranges from,
you can deploy from Raspberry
Pi to 100 gigabit a second.
2017 we had such tests done successfully
with the honey give it
a second with Apple tech
is regarded as multi
threaded it's community-based
and driven development.
It's open source release
of the GPL version two.
It's driven by OSF,
which stands for Open
Information Security Foundation.
This is actually the
organization behind Suricata.
As I mentioned, Suricata
is an intrusion detection
but can be much more than that.
It's core signature by
secure run at full speed
with 60 plus thousand signatures,
it can use much less, it can
use in cases of compromise
making use anything from you
know, domain J three hashes
in a sorts of MD five shall
some matching as well.
It can actually, you can
actually hook up your own
lore scripts into a Suricata
for extended benefit.
And really I think basically
the people that have
not actually used Suricata
will seem the type
of and the extent of the data
that I can produce actually
have a very limited
knowledge of its power.
And I'll actually let Eric
talk a little bit more
about the protocol Network
Security Monitoring part of that.
- So Suricata is above
ideas, but Peter didn't just
sort of a really good
network security monitoring.
For most use case we can state it.
So we get that kind of replaces it.
You have a same kind of data.
You have a long list of protocols,
is protocol from internet
like HTTP, HTTP/2, TLS,
like FTP, SMTP, data source report.
Corporate Network with Kerberos, SMB, NFS
and the new stuff like IOT with MQTT
the old stuff like Industrial
network and dnp3, modibus
all this protocol for all
of this application layer
like we call them insights to data.
You can have a nice reason
document for making document
for every transactions
in all the networks.
So you can use them for
forensic, for analysis,
for scam detection, for certain team,
you can do a lot with them.
So you already Suricata
you have a combination
of NIDS or the network security
and network security monitoring function.
So one thing, because Suricata is miss.
It means that we can miss
both when we are doing
the IDS part.
So the IDS part comes with
application layer or metadata.
That is really important,
because in the old days
when an IDS was triggering an alert,
what we add is just an
layout of this category,
with this name, was between
safety and these destination IP.
If you are looking you one
report on the source part
on the destination part, but
that was really, really small.
So it was not possible to
really understand what was going
on because the context was not developed.
So that's really bad.
So here we can see in this,
I left some word that we have
an left over with DNS
protocol, we have single,
both that we have contains
all the information extracted
by Suricata, above this area.
So we have information about
the validity of the certificate
and that node after node
should be than the low.
Then have the fingerprint
where the photocoagulation.
So where, I got a lot of
information inside of this or that.
So is not, I gonna guess
sure not if you heard
but is done impossible, so
thing is everything is strictly
out of Suricata in this picture.
Next one.
So now let's see another one which is the,
or TLS event that contains
the TLS information
that we have seen on a TLS rule.
So we have found some kind of
data that we have seen before,
but I wanted to highlight little,
somebody little information
that are quite interesting.
So for example, you know we
see that we have first blue box
it's an old fashion protocol,
it's TLS if you want.
So it's easy to discriminate
between new and old protocol.
If you have security issue with JIRA V1.
so it's better to have
this on your network.
Also what we can see
is that the subject on
the issue of DN are equal
which means that it's a
self-signed certificate.
So it's not a valid certificate authority.
It's not secure.
So we've got a bad photocard
and unsecure certificate on this floor.
So that's something that is very suspect.
Next one.
Okay let's speed up.
Okay so let's take another
example in which is this time
in the left.
So that in the left I have HTTP protocol.
Here we see a lot of
information that helps you
to understand what is going on.
Okay so do I talk to you
about a need, ventilation.
there is not that, but let's look at
what we have inside the HTTP.
One of the first thing
is the first blue box,
it's for hosting.
With even for hosting is directly an IPV4.
So it means when we use our direct connect
through this system.
Through this website by
taking the IPV4 address,
on what we can see also,
status to Android.
And we associate it with digital web page.
So we got the first online IPV4 address.
And what we can see in the on start,
which is the HTTP response body print.
So that is what we got the
standard default web page it was.
This is the default web page.
So just by seeing this
we see that we have,
something that looks
pretty bad because we have
had the context that we have
about VRF show us web page is ready,
if you look URL I mean get the PHP
on vendor HTTP port, which is 443.
We've got a lot of that
stuff just by looking
at this HTTP information,
that complement the detection
that has been done in VNL by the detection
on joint inside Suricata.
Next one.
Okay but all this information
that we have seen previously
in the previous slide, where
about information that have
been extracted by Suricata
at the application layer
and the sunshine.
If what we have is information that comes
from the signature.
There is what you want which is metadata,
but it is used high
quality in the signature
but allow you define T value.
Put value inside and then
it can give you context,
about what does signature match was about.
So here we got two important,
very important thing is
about ability project
so we see that the
targeted project is inside
Windows XP and below,
which on for first metadata,
the single metadata
is very very nice.
Which is the Malware family,
so it means the alert
was targeting the Trickbot
Malware so it was checked.
It was time to detect,
the Trickbot Malware
and then we have got two other information
that can be readily restored.
It's like creative atom updating the at.
Updating the at will you,
and then proceed that
your at has been updated,
quite constantly.
The created at, you will
where this at has been,
found on a signature has
been written on this day.
So if you to focus on the recent things
which is usually the most active specs.
You can use these as you
classify you have to say
okay maybe look first at the,
because it is the first stuff but maybe
my ultimate alert restoration
like EDS has changes is not hiding from.
- And kind of a few words
about the open source SELKS.
And that actually is
developed by some networks
SELKS is a certain case
or a kind of base ideas,
IPS and the same ecosystem with
its own graphic rule manager
and basic network capabilities.
SELK says Debian-based live distribution
viewed from five key
open source components,
that comprises name.
So this is Suricata,
Elasticsearch, Logstash,
Kibana and Stamu Scirius Community Edition
which is your first Suricata management
and Suricata hunting.
In addition, it includes
some other components
such as Moloch and Evebox
which were added actually
after the acronym was established.
But now apart SELKS.
SELKS is a contribution
made by Stamus Networks
to the open source community,
it's really available
and it's released under
GPL version three license.
So the source, the
readme, the issue tracker
and the wiki you can GitHub as,
GitHub.com/StamusNetwork/SELKS.
Let's talk a little bit
about the challenge.
The challenge is obvious.
You know, typical day, the
sock involves you know,
hundreds of millions of events,
anything from medium to large enterprise.
So all these things need to be
need to be taken into account.
You have a lot of data
where do you start for
what do you do with it?
So that's always, that
always is a challenge.
And in this case here
we'll, be talking about,
Suricata data that's produced
by Suricata alerts,
protocol data and so forth
and how to best tackle it
that fits some examples of how to do it.
So the first thing you can do,
is basically of course
you do some filtering.
So select the words by way
of filtering them based
on metadata from that.
So we'll actually use filtering
methods to limit the number
of alerts to investigate,
to concentrate on.
Usually Suricata generates
a bunch of alerts
using those context and actually,
make sure you know which
components of the alert metadata
actually are vulnerable.
So for example, don't use severity
because actually it
could be misstating words
of bigger severity
category for my network,
for my organization
network might not necessarily,
be that severity for your organization,
or for your network, a rule writers,
no writers use it and set it
especially having in mind
that there's different sources
of rule sets for writers
for example nowadays.
The default value is actually critical,
when you use severity,
but let's go and look
at a couple of complimentary
approaches that we can try out,
so classification base
and hunting approach okay.
So classification base
is actually zoomed in
on involving some sorts
of filter sets rather
to filter out and
classify, let's say events,
what in CNC Malware select
kind of the more important
or the real threats.
The more important events
are the real threats.
And then the hunting
approaches for example,
increase your pace and increase your odds
of defeating the other
sorry by investigation,
period you have alerts by
combination of factors,
you know combined
different things together
and that formula actually results
into something more
relevant to investigate.
So, let's have a look actually at a,
I would say three such examples,
some hands-on first we're going to use
the Scirious Community Edition
and then Kibana queries
and three small, very
simple example was just
to emphasize the points
of the different angles
you can take when you
are actually hunting.
So the first concept is like filter
out the noise, active hunting,
discover unknown threats
by way of a filter sets with
the Scirius Community Edition
and the other approach would
be actually hunting queries
by application layer protocol.
So not a lot, not a lot
events related whatsoever.
Now, let's go on to the lab demo.
I'm going to share my screen.
Let me see.
I'm going to do, this stop share.
Do you folks see my screen?
- Can you not just keep the slides up?
- Now it should be, it
should be better okay.
So what we have here is actually,
the landing page of
Scirius Community Edition.
We have a switcher up here
from which I'm gonna jump into,
the hunting application, right in here.
So, this hunting implication actually,
will be a way of using the
filter sets as an example.
And we're actually will be doing
active filtering let's say.
As a couple of filters
that I like to show you
the first one is actually very simple.
It's called tearless old version.
So basically what it is is saying,
we're actually saying, show
me any TLS protocol based
alert events but where
the TLS version is older.
And as you can see this is a simple query.
It returns about 160 results.
It immediately zooms into that.
And the purpose of it actually is just to
show all the TLS non-secure
version of sense.
So let's go ahead and actually have a look
at one of the one such
alerts and see what it shows.
So we have an example of an alert here.
We have the extra TLS protocol, dating
then we have payload principal,
we'll have the signature ID
and we actually have the role log itself.
So in here, this is
actually in Json format.
So in here, we have
any unknown information
about the alert and as we can see,
we were actually looking
for all the tillers versions
and that's why the results were returned.
We have the flat included in there
and you can see by the
subject and be sure that,
we have additional information
there, but it's very
very low old rather version of Telus.
Now.
- You should share the
end of substitute it.
It's valid till 2044.
- A bit of a longer there.
- When you consider, one year
is already is already gone.
- You know an accompany with a GMO.
There's a lot of things
we can hang on here
yeah, absolutely.
So the second filter says,
let's say another filter
another perspective,
another zoom in would be
actually let's say hidden an executable.
So what does this mean?
Actually, the filter itself is kind of
self-explanatory very,
I think very obvious.
So basically we're looking
for HTP content that says
it's an image, right.
But it's actually an executable.
So hence the name with hidden executable.
So what does this Well,
okay so, always have a
look at the look at work.
Yeah, sure go ahead.
- We lost for 10 seconds,
so if you can, just start from the point
where you were saying that.
Just after the beginning
of, that would be nice.
- Okay right in here.
So here we have apologies.
So here we have another
perspective of that filter set.
It is basically self-explanatory.
I think a we're looking for
HTP content that advertises
itself as an image, but it's actually,
it is actually unexecutable
and the the filter here
immediately returns 20 results
for such events.
Again, we don't really care about,
MD5s red listed to white
list events would just say,
give us images that are advertising
give us files as images
will actually executable.
And actually if you zoom in on
and have a look at some
of some of those examples.
When we go to the alert
that these are actually
fetched all the logs in here
and let's have a look at the first one.
And as you can see here,
we have the metadata,
which is quite revealing.
Basically it's saying that we have
a Win peg advertising
as a content type image.
We have a payable principle and
interest for responsibility.
But if we actually go to
look at the related events
we can see that this is actually a file,
is called the Window of P and G,
but it's actually unexecutable.
And this is actually the file transaction.
The file information load would check sums
with magic and so on and so forth.
We have the related HTP requests,
that actually provides further evidence
for where will this downloaded?
Was it successful?
We know the content
time metals and similar.
And of course the conversation,
that triggered that alert also
triggered three other alerts.
And here is all the data, you know.
The file transaction DHCP
log itself, just a quick,
a quick simple example
of how powerful filtering
on metadata can be.
What I wanna show you a third example.
We will actually quickly jump
over to dashboards in Kibana.
So the hump, the Scirius
condition was actually,
it's actually a hunting interface,
based off and displaced database of alerts
and alerts metadata.
Here I'd like to actually
show you file transactions.
So basically this is not alert.
This is any filed
transactions on the network.
Suricata is capable of
actually extracting,
that information from
protocols like HTP, FTP
NFSS and them being, SMTP and similar.
And here I've actually
prepared a simple query.
Yeah I go ahead.
- I also think what you
did not mentioned yet
is what we come this time
with this find on the disk.
So you can have a
signature that it's typed
but when it matched, it's
time to find on disk.
You can do like you say insights Suricata.
Every time you see a
file it's likely to disk.
- Absolutely, thank you.
And here in this case,
we have a dashboard actually displaying
all the information any and
all files, regardless of.
So for example here we have HCP and SMB,
application lab protocols that we've seen
file transactions from.
We've created a simple query in here.
So what we're gonna do
is actually activate it.
Basically what it says is,
we're saying from protocols
like FTP, SMB, HTP
NFS some SMTP, please show us,
executable types that
are actually very long,
in terms of name, just a sample query.
Okay you will be surprised by the results.
So as we scroll down,
we can see the results
and we have for sub transactions
and it can actually see that
the names are quite unusual.
So if we look at one such,
such transaction, we can see
this is a file move a file,
a file name makes executable.
It's unusual to have
that name it's a bit long
and kind of non-logical
to say the very least,
we know that it's an executable.
And actually as we scroll down,
this is pure protocol data.
So this has nothing to do with alerts.
We can actually see
that this is a SMB log.
It's the right.
And basically it's writing
from this source IP to 505
and actually this name is unusual.
So we can actually, we have
a sharp 250 fixed checks on.
We can click on it.
That will bring us to Virus total.
I will, you know, in this case
this one was actually red
listed here in versatile.
So again, this is just an angle.
This is just an idea, but
it's not based on alerts.
This is just entirely
searching queries based
on protocol data in this case, SMB.
So those are the three
examples that I wanted to show.
Let me go ahead will
re share my slides now,
here's another example
based on filter sets.
So in this case, we
are actually filtering,
filtering out by like
category in this case
it's called malware command and control.
Simple but yet it can zoom out
from a million to 10 events.
So you have to combine all these.
There's also a different perspective.
This is just the one that we demoed.
So an executable off
of replacing itself was
an image, really simple.
This is an interesting one.
This is basically what
it comes to something
so it's very simple.
HTP requests replies to
just public IPV4 interests.
Usually use some sort of a domain
not actually the actual IP,
but it can return actually
interesting results
for investigation regardless
of sort of destination
or the name of domain.
There's another example here
that we actually similar tools.
We covered older versions of TLS.
You know, if you have security events
security alerts that are triggered
by unsupported TLS
protocol version let's say.
And that's an interesting one.
Actually here we have,
basically we're saying
give us HTP protocol us that actually are
and we're looking for the word roots
inside the payload.
We're inside the packets.
So that comes with an interesting results.
Believe it or not.
So a different, a different angle
and Eric back to you and
why a filtering is great,
but it has challenges.
What do you say?
- So what Peter did showed currently is
a great, for certain team.
But the other one is,
if you have to do this work of discovery,
they doing thing every day.
Even if you have a few data sets
you will need to go over
all the filter sets,
one by one and it may not
be the most efficient way,
to directly jump on the new things
that need to be investigated.
That will need investigation sorry.
Peter next one.
So, one possible approach
to free this issue is to,
simply tag the event.
Tagging the event is really
something that you need to do
because you, in fact you don't
want to surprise the event.
Because if your surprise event,
you will lose some contexts,
but can be a really
interesting in some case to discriminate,
to combine in the search,
to do the right analysis.
So try not to surprise but
use a tagging mechanism.
So to do a tagging mechanism there is some
simple possibility, you
can sure using something
against to search.
We can do queries on update,
you can also work on output of Suricata
with some what forces
you to do the filtering.
But what is really important here is that
if you look what we have
shown you since the beginning
you've got the metadata coming
from this thing that you have committed
into coming from application layer
and both of them are very valuable source
of information when you tie to analyze
on when you analyze a VNF.
So usually when you are doing this work
and finally using VNF
you will see that this combined to this,
combined to this, is in
fact meaningful for you.
You know that if it's repeat itself
you will have something that
is, would still be interesting.
Or if you have this on
this combine, you know
that it would be always be information
with regards to your network.
So one of the best idea you can have here
is to combine this information.
Every time you've got this set of criteria
you drill the holes that will tag
this the event as a superior
event as information.
It will allow you to update the daily job,
first to check that
event, because you know
possibly some best
effort of a coming back,
then you investigate,
you look at the things that you don't know
you do the classification.
So this way you have something that you,
what you have less work
to do, less to focus.
You just have to focus on what is relevant
what is unknown to do the classification
on, it's not responsive
safe, we need look that too.
Next one.
So, Mr. firs is really
nice, but it has some limits
because for example, you
should take one signature
that detect a criminal court for a beacon,
that can eat every five minutes.
So every five minutes we have
a new alert to investigate.
So at the end of the
day, you still have a lot
of to investigate.
So let's take step back.
We have in fact, when we're
all doing, what we are tying
to different organization
is to find if have
asset at risk.
And I said that it's
potentially infected by a state.
So what will be easier
is to be able to see,
okay I've got some signature,
I've got some event
I've got some edits I want to come from.
we set up a list of assets
that are potentially
infected by asset.
This would be really
useful, because it will be
allow us to be limit vendors about earlier
that repeat themselves.
And it will give us a clear view
of what is happening on the network.
Next one.
So I was asked this question long ago
and it was quite a problem,
infact because if you need
to answer to the question,
give me the list of asset
of the list of attacker in one network,
based on net, event.
It's in fact hand written.
It will be for sure the
source of a destination IP
but you don't really know which one it is.
For example, if we take the
first one which is a scan,
because the scan packet
coming from Vertech
you're going to turn it.
But if you're looking, look
at the signature on it,
second signature sorry in this case,
it's check that the answer
is an answer to an attack.
So expect the source on
this nation are reversed,
with compared to the source
on target of the attack.
So you don't, you cannot
find this university
you cannot save a asset
is always the source IP
that is not working and it's
not ever from a destination IP.
So you need to improve that.
Next one.
So that's something I
did introduce by doing
the target keyword insights
work at times 2016.
And it's just a simple
option that you add to
missing a job to save on
the targets of assets,
is the source of a destination IP,
in of a signature.
So by doing this,
we can have the clear information
about what's going on.
Next one, please.
Yeah so when do we have
when we have this key word
on the inside this unit here,
it create alert.source and alert.targets
an object that contains
information about the IP
on top of the source on the target.
One way of doing this,
if you want the list via set
on when detected by the ideas.
You just do, I left target.apmvenue.
Before it was not doing well.
You have some induction to do manually.
So it was only a thing.
So suddenly not all
the signature contents,
target well so if you can put pressure on,
for example proof point,
so we add the targets,
key world to that one set
which is the coupon that would be on it.
Your appointment will be a bit nice.
As soon as it were introduced in a Scirius
community edition.
So incense noticed on
some algorithm to manually
to determining the value and
you can also do that manually
so you can get to the result.
So next one.
So what is the wizard?
Wizard is let it become
obvious to get a preview
of what is happening on
your network, intel offsite.
So here we have a simple Kibana queries,
that the display of table, the
first column is of a target,
a piece of a list of asset.
On the second column,
is the malware family.
One of the metadata that we have seen
at the beginning of the presentation.
So by combining these in one query
we have a list of two assets
on this network that we find that 500,
the fact that one a one
that have one suites hyped
on the other one as the
thing five sites seen,
you know, in it.
So we get to your view
obviously, present on my network
on my asset in one single query.
So that's failure simply if you just show
even if for example, over
three, but detection is a CNC.
We, just have one information on venue
can also combine with by
doing more advanced query
but you can do already
better things by doing that.
- Sorry thank you about that.
So if you're mentioning
Eric, it's actually
it's a repetitive process,
but the repetitive part you
need to actually automate
and you can automate so
that you have to, you know,
it can look at less and less
and more relevant stuff.
The challenges of relying
on just signature data
along there is a few, of
course the classification
can be complex.
It requires some signature
writers to insert the source
and target keywords.
When writing the rules,
some signatures will only
identify possible threats.
So it could, might not be so useful.
There's a variety of signature sources,
all sorts of providers.
So basically you need to
actually sort repair the process.
Signatures are updated
daily and a lot of phases
where you have, as I
mentioned, different providers.
So you have to actually, it's
something that you have to
do repetitively in a high-paced as well.
So you have to review the
sources, the information
that you get from there, update
the signature content as see
if you have to update anything
in the process in there
and then push it out to the sensors.
And that's repetitive that
has to happen on the fly
and in a rapid fashion, wherever needed.
Just taking pace.
So it's a process that once-
- You knew a couple of
times, you can automate.
- Yes go ahead please.
- No, we need to hurry up.
- And so as open network
source for self contribution
as well actually SELKS is one of them.
It's actually open source
Suricata turnkey distro one.
It's actually the first one out there
that is entirely bases information
on Suricata data alone.
We have GopherCap wall open
source PCAP playback tool.
The you're more welcome to read,
alarm and get the information in there.
It comes really handy
when you need to replay
multiple sorts of different
PCAPS just as they were
as they appeared on the
network has double captions
with the timestamps.
We also have Stamus Network App Splunk.
that is free out there for you,
so that the information you'll get on the
on some central, we are
actually we're believers,
we're defenders, we're believers,
we're believers that defender is a hero
so and actually we believe in the future
where those they protect remain safe.
Okay, so we're just wanted to share some
of the open source tools and processes
and toasts that we actually
do daily at our jobs.
And so apply what you've learned today.
First of all, identify
filter sets in queries
that yield interesting results,
with respect to, we need to
set up your organization.
Let's say that you do security monitoring.
There is no golden
bullet, one fits them all.
You have to actually identify those,
what inquiry is actually
your most interesting results
by the of providing Suricata.
The next step will be
understand that the relationship
the results and these hunting queries.
You know, you'll learn as you
go and that's quite normal.
There's you're always
learning a new environment.
Every environment is different.
And invest time into ultimating
different aspects of it.
So once you do it manually
and you're happy with the research
and the results of the research,
you know, then actually
at what exactly is repetitive,
when it could be automated.
Begin establishing a hunting process based
on the lessons learned.
So I also believe strongly in
inactive threat hunting, you know
go a little bit on the offensive.
Don't just be reactive, go
proactive if possible of course.
And then the last step
would be like, of course
improve the current posture
by implementing those noise
reduction process above
drive a direct project
to improve the security
monitoring with all the lessons
learned, implement all the
automation, ultimate on the ones
and then automate a different
idea, a different process.
Don't automate the same thing over again.
Eric Washer was saying Suricata forums,
all our data comes from Suricata
in the demo line.
And I know daily work, you have the links
right there, on the screen.
Eric is something I'm missing?
- No no, I would just
say that if you want like
a quick grasp of what we have shown
it's very fast to spin up a
SELK sunset when it works.
It just a few minutes before you get
the first meaningful data.
So for good tie on, she
wants some documentation
or some training, you get
the forum for Suricata
and you've got the Suricata
ideas training, done by Yosef.
I think that's all.
- And there's plenty of data in the forums
and discussions by the way,
'cause it can reach out to power users
and regular users.
And you might ask a question that somebody
that probably somebody
already has enough support.
So don't be shy.
- Thank you.
(both laughing)
- To RSA conference until
the defender us there.
And thank you very much for Open Source
and all the people that
are actually sharing,
to others.
Cheers for my part.
- Thanks you.