(upbeat music)
- The world is undergoing
most significant shift
in strategic alignment
in the 21st century.
Daily we see the signs
of heightened competition
between major powers.
The geopolitical contest where technology
is increasingly a key battle ground
within suing impacts on security, trade
and industry, foreign
relations and grand strategy.
And the impact of the
COVID-19 pandemic both immense
and widespread continues to
accelerate technology's ability
to drive rapid change.
Yep, humans have always
looked to technology
for competitive gain and the
advancements of technology
has long underpinned
increased global prosperity
and in turn geopolitical competition.
And we've seen the effects
of recent technological change before.
The advent of the microprocessor,
the rollout of the internet,
the proliferation of personal computers,
the world changing
impact of the smartphone
and mobile connectivity is a
key enabler of our lifestyles.
And the remarkable
diminutive semiconductor chip
with its ever decreasing size
and ever growing capacity.
These are but a few
of the incredible technological
developments to have shaped
the last few decades and they are maturing
at a staggering rate.
When you consider the breadth
of these technologies alongside
their many applications,
you start to realize just
how significantly a global connected world
is reshaping human existence.
I try to avoid the term unprecedented,
but the situation we're
currently in warrants it.
When you consider the breadth
of emerging technologies coming
online near simultaneously,
it's difficult to find a
comparative historical reference.
The revolutionary impact,
this transformative state
of change will have on our societies
and on our planet cannot be understated.
And it has already proven
to be transformation
with unexpected and
unpredictable consequences
a transformation that
requires a global response
as it realigns the
international balance of power
and reshapes the geopolitics
of the 21st century.
For those who can harness the current wave
of innovation mitigate
its risks and capitalize
on its transformative powers
will gain significant economic, political
and security advantage.
Part of my role as Australia's
Ambassador for Cyber Affairs
and Critical Technology is
to understand and harness
that transformation in a way
that works to our advantage
and reflects our liberal
democratic values to work,
to understand what really
is at stake and what
are the true risks that
we face as governments,
companies and individuals.
In answering these questions
and understanding what it is
that should be front of mind
as we look to design,
develop and use technology,
it's helpful to consider the current state
of play across Cyberspace
and the Technology Landscape.
(upbeat music)
In 2017 when we put pen to paper
on our first International
Cyber Engagement Strategy
the world looked a little
different to how it does today.
None of us could have imagined
how significantly Cyberspace
and the Technology Landscape
would change in the years
that followed and the
effects of that change.
The geopolitical landscape
has become more competitive
and more technologically complex
with technology enabling
a new range of actors.
Technological innovation is an
increasingly crucial element
in the relationship between superpowers.
Occupies center stage
in our contested international
economic environment.
And the adoption and integration
of technology enabled gray zone activities
into Statecraft has
fueled a more dangerous
and contested international environment.
Governments, companies, and individuals
will power in unforeseen and
increasingly complex ways
and are all working to advance
their technological capabilities.
Some are like-minded and some are not.
Connectivity has spread and
brought with it a wider range
of actors exerting their
influence in cyberspace.
5G networks have become the litmus test
for both technological
and political competition.
We've created entirely new industries,
moved our schools, healthcare
and commerce online
and created communities
that span the planet.
Power derived from controlling
the design, development
and use of technologies and capabilities
is extending national
and corporate influence across the world.
The boom in connected
devices and digital platforms
has enabled constant global communication,
but also allowed the
amplification of narratives
to influence the views of billions
and primed our societies
for disinformation and misinformation.
And digital platforms are
increasingly shaping debates
about what freedom of
expression looks like online
and the extent to which
they should be involved
in political debates in
carrying on their services.
The interconnectedness of technologies
has brought unforeseen risks
and created new opportunities
for threat actors with an asymmetric cost
in favor of malicious cyber activity.
States are increasingly focused
on standards development organizations
as a way of ensuring emerging,
technological trajectories reflecting
their national interests.
Trajectories that can either uphold
or undermine the international order,
and protect and promote human
rights or impinge upon them.
The resilience of technology
supply chains has been thrown
into the spotlight,
especially as we slowly emerge
from the COVID-19 pandemic.
Technology markets lack diversity,
allowing domination by individual actors
and the monopolization of industries
which has lowered
competition, increased costs
and weaken resilience.
And the ubiquity of cyberspace
with its world spanning
reach yet subtle borders
has only added to these challenges.
A domain that has allowed
our emerging technologies
to be cyber enabled and data driven
and spawned increasingly
interdependent innovation
like smart cities, Smart
Grid and driverless cars.
Out of necessity our focus
has expanded to technologies
that we have come to term as critical.
Those that have the capability
to impact upon the security
of our organizations and nations,
our prosperity both public and private,
and the very fabric that
underpins our social cohesion.
These critical technologies
include artificial intelligence,
the internet of things, quantum computing,
blockchain, biotech, 5G, and many more.
These emerging technologies
and their applications
are often enabled by
and reliant on information
that is created, stored
and transmitted through digital networks.
In other words, data of which we produce
about 2.5 quintillion bytes every day.
And as you all know, only too well.
Where there are digital technologies,
where data flow is there is risk.
And where there is risk,
there are also those who work
to infiltrate out networks,
impact our systems
and generate effects
against our interests.
And this risk takes many
forms, cyber, physical, social,
economic, geopolitical, and
individual to name, but a few.
And you'd be forgiven
for asking when mitigating these risks
where do you start.
(upbeat music)
In distilling down the many
risks posed by technology,
the question becomes what
is really under threat
and why should we care?
Is it our networks?
Is it our data?
Is it our tech?
We all might have different
answers to those questions,
and a different rationale
for our cybersecurity and engagement.
But the issues and risks
that exist in cyberspace and
across the tech landscape
do not occur in isolation.
And as innovation continues
at increased speed and
complexity, so do these risks.
When the puzzle is pieced together
and the linkages between
each are more clearly drawn
the final picture of risks
looks a little different.
And the question becomes what
should be the key lens through
which we seek to mitigate the risks
that we find in cyberspace and across
the technology landscape.
And that lens is values.
Many of you may be asking, but so what?
What the values have to do
with innovation research
and development and the goods
and services that we bring to market.
And how do the values
of the humans behind our
innovation effects cyberspace
and the tech landscape that it enables.
We'll look to simply put
value shape technology
and technology built
on liberal democratic
values means technology
that supports a stable
and peaceful international
order protects human rights
and reflects how we want
our societies to function.
And it means a cyberspace
that well not perfect
is open, free and secure.
But there are many who
do not share this vision
of Cyberspace and Technology
and who seek to shape tech trajectories
in a way that undermined
international security
and basic human rights.
I'm talking about technologies
such as facial recognition
and surveillance systems
that can be used to enable
social credit systems
and perpetuate persecution
across countries and continents.
The institutionalized theft
of intellectual property
to advance entire industries
without the R and D burden,
the production of software
that lacks security by design
and is intended to advance the economic
and strategic interests
of authoritarian regimes.
And attempts to rewrite the
architecture of the internet,
to perpetuate censorship, remove anonymity
and allow greater control
of people and information.
These threats to democracy
are more than threats
to the current international order.
They risk reshaping our
industries, markets, societies
and our democratic way of life.
So we must ask ourselves
how we are ensuring
that technology is being
used as we intended.
And fundamentally is the
work we are doing in line
with our core values.
Because value shape technology
and they guide our innovation.
By being present in our standard setting,
the connective tissue between technology
and the market by underwriting our laws
and ethical frameworks,
regulations that decide
whether technology promotes
and protects human rights,
diversity, and equality or
confines more than it empowers
and defining the future
of our economy, societies,
and the international environment.
But while technological change may be fast
the impact of tech-related
change can be slow.
Often it's this creeping Delta
that is the hardest to see,
to understand and to assess.
Sure, events like the COVID-19
pandemic have forced decades
of digitization into the
space of mere months.
And the effects of this
change will take much longer
to be felt and seen
whether good or otherwise.
But if the premise of our
innovation of our work,
and to design, develop and use technology
is in line with our democratic values,
we reinforced the very foundations
of what we're seeking to protect,
our prosperity, our
security and our societies.
And we do it in a holistic way
that individual security efforts cannot,
although they do play a crucial role.
The question then is how?
How do we do this?
And as individuals, as
organizations, as governments
and as an international community.
(upbeat music)
To navigate an increasingly
challenging international environment,
Australia has prioritized and enhanced
that international cyber and
critical technology diplomacy.
We've understood that cyberspace
and critical technology
affect international relations
at all levels, national
security, economic prosperity,
the protection and
realization of human rights
and freedoms, sustainable development,
and international peace and stability.
That our democratic values
underpin our efforts
in cyberspace and across
the technology landscape.
And they provide the foundation
for our international engagement.
Australia's International Cyber
and Critical Technology
Engagement Strategy sets exactly
out how Australia will engage
in this dynamic environment to
shape the design, development
and use of cyberspace
and critical technology
in line with liberal democratic values.
Is constructed around three main pillars,
values, security, and prosperity.
They make clear
that we will always pursue
a values-based approach
to cyberspace and critical technology
and oppose efforts to use technologies
to undermine these values.
That we will always
support international peace
and stability and secure trusted
and resilient technology.
And that we will always
advocate for cyberspace
and technology to foster
sustainable economic growth
and development to enhance prosperity,
all while asking the same basic question.
How do we keep the revolutionary impacts
of technological innovation positive
and mitigate the negative consequences
of this ever-changing space,
and ensure that the future
of technology continues
to promote and protect our democracy?
Well, we're doing this by
shaping critical technology
to support peace and security
both at home and abroad.
Supporting the ethical,
design, development
and use of technologies
so that they're consistent
with international law,
including human rights.
Promoting greater diversity
in technology markets
and supply chains to bolster resilience
and encourage a more
competitive playing field
for technology providers.
Empowering States to choose transparent,
secure and sustainable
technology solutions
and oppose technology-related coercion.
Building international resilience
to digital disinformation,
misinformation and its effects.
Opposing the violation of human rights
or freedoms using cyberspace
or critical technology
or building capacity that
seeks to share our experiences
and encouraging diversity
and gender equality to ensure
that all voices are heard.
And expanding and improving
the policy and regulatory settings
that accompany our infrastructure projects
both at home and abroad.
Ultimately the Australian
government's vision is for a safe,
secure, and prosperous
Australia, Indo-Pacific
and world enabled by cyberspace
and critical technology.
Enabled by our belief that
if we shape technology
in line with our values
we will build resilience into our economic
and national security, our
industries and our societies.
Because the risks that we face
when distilled down a wider
than technical cybersecurity threats
and they cannot be mitigated
by hardened networks
and cyber defenses alone
because the prevention of risk
and threats in cyberspace
alone is not enough.
And rather than build higher digital walls
and stronger defenses we
need to look further ahead
and deeper into the issues
to shape our environment
and the future that we face.
Because technology that
has to be built around
our values will be more
resilient against efforts
to use it maliciously.
It will bolster cyber resilience
to the ever-increasing threat
of malicious cyber activity.
And it will reinforce the
foundations that we are seeking
to protect in ways that individual
security efforts cannot.
But no country and no company
can hope to shape cyberspace
and the tech landscape alone.
If we do, we risk an
unsustainable decoupling
of our industries and the
effects of bifurcation
into incompatible technology ecosystems
that will be felt by all.
(upbeat music)
So we cannot go down this road alone
and instead must turn to our values.
The key differential between
us and our adversaries,
and the solid foundation that aligns us
with our international partners.
Partners that include
governments, industry
and civil society.
Partners who can join us in
pursuing a coordinated approach
to shape cyberspace
and critical technology
in line with our shared
interests and values.
Because technology is a
field of global competition.
And to promote and protect a strong policy
and industrial foundation
based on shared values,
we must bring together
those who share our vision
and understand that by
opposing the risks that we face
we can reap the rewards.
And we need to push back
together against those
who would undermine our efforts.
Those who would undermine
the rules of the road,
the international law and norms
that define responsible
state behavior in cyberspace.
Those who do not want to cyberspace
that is open free and secure.
And those who seek to
destabilize and overwrite
an internet defined by
multi-stakeholder governance.
So we must engage at all
levels, domestic, regional
and international, private, and public
and every stage of the technology
and regulatory life cycle.
We must reach out
to the undecided through
transparent advocacy
and convince them why our approach is
in their interest and that of
the international community.
And we must come together
formally and otherwise to be more
than the sum of our parts.
To present shared interests
and to respect and uphold
international rules
and obligations through
positive, practical engagement
to protect and support the
sovereignty, prosperity
and security of the region.
The key example is the quad.
The key pillar of our international agenda
that brings together four
like-minded democracies.
The United States, Japan,
India, and Australia.
It's a dialogue committed
to deepening cooperation
on cyber affairs and critical technology.
The resilience of regional supply chains,
key cyber enabled systems
and critical infrastructure.
And through our like-minded engagement
we can embrace the huge
economic and trade benefits
that the quad will bring.
With its increased focus on
trusted markets, regional trade,
and innovation built on
shared democratic values.
But we can't just have governments
at the table, especially
as industries become the battleground
for geopolitical supremacy.
With a majority of the capability
and infrastructure that delivers
the internet and digital
connectivity resting
with the private sector
and the lion's share
of technological innovation
done by private research
institutions and companies.
Without these organizations
without you being involved
in appropriate discussions,
we as government cannot arrive
at the correct settings,
and we cannot work towards
the technologies and the
resilience systems that we need.
But we cannot rest on our
laurels and nor can you,
especially as the power
of the private sector
becomes ever more visible, highlighted
by state owned enterprises
working to shift
the scales of tech in
favor of illiberalism
and the targeting of private
non-governmental organizations
who are historically responsible
for the formation of the
internet by countries
who feel that the state should
have more control over cyberspace.
More than ever now is the
time for demonstrating
how we can assist each other
to understand, mitigate
and respond to efforts that threaten
our innovation, infrastructure
and our digital architecture,
and the foundation of democratic
values on which they adopt.
(upbeat music)
To conclude, in order
to protect our vision
for Cyberspace and Technology
the challenge is becoming
increasingly clear.
It is undeniable that we now live
in a markedly changed era.
COVID 19 continues to disrupt the world.
Technology impacts across
the breadth of domestic
and foreign affairs.
Innovation advances at
an increasingly disruptive pace and scale.
And the flow on effects
of technological competition
are playing out more broadly
than in technology markets alone.
The risk of decoupling and of bifurcation
into two technology ecosystems
cannot be overlooked nor understated.
Its effects will be felt by all.
There is without doubt
an enormous challenge ahead for all of us.
One that is more broad
than domestic policy
and that no single government
can tackle by itself.
But we are not alone.
Like all others in our
international society of states
we must continue to address the challenges
of emerging technologies
to understand the benefits
and the risks.
In Australia our international
engagement will continue
to give us a much needed
understanding of how technology
is impacting the world around us
and how we can all shape
it in our interests.
And in line with the democratic
values that keeps cyberspace
and technology working in our interests.
And reinforce our
organizations and innovation
in a way that cybersecurity
and hardened networks alone count.
Working collaboratively and transparently,
we will preserve our values, our security
and our prosperity, and
ensure that the future
of Cyberspace and Technology
looks as we would like it to.
Thank you.
(upbeat music fading)