- Welcome to "MDR: Making
Sense of the Veg-O-Matic
Buzzword Blender."
My name is Diana Kelley
and I'm CTO and Co-Founder
at SecurityCurve.
And co-presenting with me today is,
- Lisa Lee and I'm from Microsoft.
I'm the Chief Security Advisor
and work in our business development area
with our vertical industries.
- Yes, and we both used to
work together at Microsoft
and did some work on
MDR while we were there.
So this is, we want you to,
to know that we are here live
even though this is a recorded session.
Lisa and I are here live today too
as you're listening, as
you're watching this.
So please if you have questions,
just go ahead and enter
those into the chat.
And with that we're gonna get started.
(mouse clicking)
So Veg-O-Matic which, you
know I think of as a blender
I think it's actually
a chopper officially.
But you know, I think of it as
like bringing things together
sort of that like the Lucy show of just
bringing a bunch of stuff together
and I don't know about
you but I often feel
really overwhelmed by the
number of acronyms that come out
especially when there's a new area.
So you know, I felt like
I just had figured out
what MDR meant and suddenly
like people were saying,
"Well there's MXDR, we do MTDR."
And it's like, Oh my gosh.
So the whole reason that
we came up with this talk
was we thought it would
be a really good thing
to just walk through
the differences between
the kinds of offerings.
And to just really kind of normalize
some of the pros and cons
and choices and trade-offs
that you can make when you're deciding
if you need an MDR at all.
And if you do, what kind of MDR you want.
So we've spelled out
the different acronyms
on this next slide so
that you can see them
and know what they are.
You know there's Endpoint,
Network, Threat and eXtended,
the X is extended.
But, that doesn't always
help to really understand
what they mean.
So when you think about Managed Endpoint,
we've got some slides to give
you more visual view of this.
You think about Managed Endpoint, right?
What does that?
That really means the
endpoints themselves.
So that would include your
laptops and your desktops.
It may include servers in some cases.
Definitely it's gonna
include your mobile devices
and your phones and your tablets.
So basically anything that's on the edge,
that's the endpoint.
When you're talking about
Managed Endpoint Detection and Response,
that means that it's gonna
cover both monitoring
what's happening or even
proactive threat hunting
on those different devices.
And then response, if anything goes wrong.
You got a piece of malware
on your, your endpoint
then the MEDR would kick in.
So as you hear these different acronyms,
what they really are
responding to or covering
is the kind of the scope of
what's in the management system.
So the next one is for networks.
And here you're definitely
gonna get servers
but you're also gonna
get the more traditional,
if you think about like an
MSSP or managed security,
very often you probably
go to thinking switches
and routers and firewalls.
And depending on what service you buy
and it's gonna depend
on what's right for you,
what that, that vendor offers.
But network now starts to bring in those,
those cases that are sort
of a traditional perimeter.
And now in the cloud, what
we've got with software defined
perimeter things like your,
your firewalls, your servers.
And those proportions of the
pieces of network security
could also include things
like your SOCK or your SIM,
what's within your SOCK.
And then the next one is MTDR,
which Lisa is gonna cover.
- Yeah, so MTDR meaning,
you know the Threat
Detection and Response.
This one focuses very
heavily on the threat signal.
And so it's kind of that idea,
you know one vendor talks about
correlating the different
threat signals to provide
an automated threat
detection and response.
So it's really focused
on the signal aspect of,
of what's happening and the, you know the,
the automation of that correlation.
Then we have,
- Yeah, when you bring it all
together you may hear MXDR.
So now that you're kind of,
you're catching on, right?
You've probably seen it now.
It's pretty clear that when
they change that second letter,
it tends to cover what's
gonna be part of the service.
And when you get MXDR or
Managed Extended Detection
and Response, most of
the time what that means
is that the vendor is gonna bring together
Endpoint Detection and Response
with Network Detection and Response.
And very often that threat
signal, threat intelligence
and be able to bring all
those together for a really
comprehensive Managed Detection
and Response solution.
And if you're thinking,
"Wow, do I even need to have
a security team?
Do I even need to have a
SOCK if I'm gonna have MXDR?"
Well, the answer is maybe not.
Most companies are still gonna need them
but some companies are looking
at, could MXDR be replacing?
Or if they don't, they
can't afford a SOCK,
they may be looking at MXDR to
kind of cover a lot of that,
that use case.
(mouse clicking)
- So one of the things that we heard from
a chief security officer was
that they thought they had
bought an XDR solution.
They weren't looking for
the managed aspect of it,
but they they wanted to
augment their capabilities
and their team.
And what they ended up with
was really just an MSSP,
just a managed, really
alerting system or capability.
And so, you know when
that shiny pretty thing
kind of wears off, you
know did you really get
what you thought you got?
So in this case, maybe you
didn't get the flying car.
Maybe you just got the car
with a few wings and fins.
But you know it's, it's making
sure that you're really aware
of, of what you're buying.
And we did think that this,
you know Veg-O-Matic blender
was contributing a lot to
that because the terminology
is still so loose in some
cases or maybe just not
being applied in the right way.
So, you know just trying
to make sure that you,
you know the vendor or the buyer beware,
making sure that you're getting
what you intended to get.
- Yeah, just talking it
through your provider.
And this is, it happens
anytime that you get
a new set of offerings.
Very often other vendors
that have been in the space
for a while.
They start saying, "Well,
you know we have a lot
of that capability."
So they wanna offer it too.
And that's not to say
that an MSSP can't offer
a really strong MDR.
We're just saying, make
sure that you've asked about
what you're getting
because if they just say,
"Hey, we've got wings."
You may end up with a
car that actually flies
or you may end up with you
know, a cute looking car
but it's not gonna go anywhere.
It's kind of a penguin of a car.
So, it's really just
about asking the questions
and making sure you
know what you're buying.
And it really is best
for you to figure out
the questions in advance because
any vendor is really excited
about their solution.
So that old thing about you know,
if all you have is a hammer,
everything looks like a nail
and that, that's gonna happen.
So be sure that you've thought
about what your company needs
and what you really want out of a service.
So at a very high level, and again, every
MDR are, the vendors have
different sets of capabilities
that they supply.
MSSPs are moving into this
space and some of them
are truly moving into the space
giving you the flying car.
Some are just not getting again
and have kind of the wings
on there, but not they don't fly.
So we're giving you some some
good top level things to ask
or to think about the differentiate
traditional MSSPs and MDR.
So the traditional MSSPs tend to be
a little bit more portal based.
So if you wanna talk to a person,
yeah maybe you can pick up the phone
but most of what's happened
is that they've got
this managed.
They're managing a lot of
different systems and devices
and your interaction with
the MSSP would be through
checking your, your
dashboard on the portal.
They often are very heavy and automation
in the managed service offering.
They will do monitoring but
they generally stop at alerting.
Again, I wanna be clear
that we're giving you
generalizations and you
have to ask these questions
to make sure what your vendor is offering.
But generally they stop at alerting
so you'll find out that
something's gone wrong
within the system.
You'll get an alert up on your dashboard
but that may be where things stop.
And very often if there is
remediation or tasks that
have to get, to get taken
when there has been a breach
or an incident has been identified,
then that escalates to the customer.
Which is a great offering
and that's what a lot of companies need.
That's why MSSPs have been so successful.
But, some companies are
looking for something
a little bit more proactive,
a little bit more hands-on.
And that's the niche that MDR is filling.
Most MDR offerings have a
combination of human beings
with hands-on keyboards
and software sensors.
Like they may have an endpoint solution,
end point defense on the,
on the end points that they're protecting.
But there's a very human element too.
Since it's human based,
they will act as advisors.
Sometimes you can just call up,
again depending on the service,
you may be able to push a button
if you're doing an investigation
and you can get an expert
on the other end of the,
of that, that line to be
able to talk you through
what you're seeing.
So instead of just here's an alert,
you get this very human element.
They also can be out there
actively, going proactively
through your network or
through whichever systems
you've got them covering,
the endpoints for example.
To look for, for, to do threat hunting.
So they'll start looking at the IOAs,
the indicators of attack or proactively,
which is the, the things that
look like they're gonna go
wrong or look suspicious
even though you haven't had
an actual breach yet.
In addition to, if
there's an, if there's a,
a fast moving campaign, malware campaign
or ransomware campaign or
some other attack campaign
that's going on.
Yeah, they may get IOCs.
They may get these
indicators of compromise,
maybe distributor for those.
And then threat hunters could take those
and look through your organization.
You don't know you've had an attack yet,
an alert hasn't happened
but they'll start looking
for the IOCs for you.
So that, that very
proactive kind of activity.
And then when they do get into response,
that's a very active.
Instead of just saying,
"Hey you've got an alert.
Somebody outta take care of this."
Your MDR provider can go from,
you know either just an automatic response
all the way up to taking
significant action
within your enterprise based on again,
the agreement you have with them
and what services they offer.
(mouse clicking)
- So. why don't we start to look at,
kind of the response end of it.
This is an area where there seems to be
a lot of differentiation
and a lot of variety
in the ways that even
organizations would approach it
especially CISOs and how
they wanna look at it.
And we've kind of broken
this into a spectrum.
And, if you think about
the spectrum looking at,
there's a top and a bottom
and they're two different approaches.
And that seems to be how
a lot of the organizations
and CISOs that we were talking to were,
you know reflecting on
how much they wanted
in terms of response.
In one case they're looking at it
from the action-based side.
And so they may be thinking in terms of,
you know I only want the provider to,
you know provide alerts which really isn't
Managed Detection and
Response at that point
but it's kind of that first stage.
And the next stage you know,
getting more in terms of
how much response they
would provide around the,
you know are they actually investigating?
Are they getting involved in taking action
on specific assets?
You know would they be, you
know resetting certain settings
or actually quarantining something?
You know an asset in that sense.
And then do you?
Does the customer want them to
take a full response action?
And so that's at the
far end of the spectrum
is the taking full response.
So, that's where it's almost
full augmentation of your team.
If we look at the bottom
side of the spectrum,
you know other organizations
or other CISOs might look at it
from a severity based rating.
So they wanna be able to
differentiate between,
you know if it's a severity one item,
you know these really low risk items
or maybe the more frequent types of things
like fishing attacks.
That's where they want
help and augmentation.
And others say, "No, I
want to be on the full end
of the spectrum in terms
of, you know the sev four,
sev five, you know
depending on how many levels
you may have."
And so it's just a
different way of looking at,
you know how much interaction do you want?
And, you know where is that
third party going to step in?
And it's really important to
have a clear understanding
of where that separation is.
You know in terms of who's doing what,
where are the handoff lies
and you know, trying to keep
the blur out of the lines
completely so that your,
your spectrum is very clear
and there's a differentiated line between
where the third party takes over
or where the handoff happens.
And so another way to look
at this as well would be
to think about it in terms of,
you know finding the balance
of the risk.
And so you know, do you want
more expertise and less access?
Or you know, more access and you know,
just finding the balance
of how much you're willing
to have that third party involved.
You know, so it's about that,
that appetite that you might
have for that.
You know is it more
important to throw bodies
at the really simple stuff?
And to maintain your own
team, you know who are
highly paid professionals probably.
You know to keep them for
the really complicated issues
or the complicated incidents.
Also you know, what about you know,
post event or post incident,
you know can the vendor rebuild
or recover your environment?
Maybe they could do that
faster than your team can
in certain settings.
And so, you know what's
going to be the balance there
in terms of you know, who has that?
You know and getting that
kind of rebuilding service
for example, you know
can be really important
and it can be a real big
value add for some teams.
There may be other things where
again that expertise versus
access that needs to be weighed
in terms of, you know
like if you need to reset
all the passwords in the environment,
could the vendor, you know
potentially do that more easily
for you than you could do for yourselves?
So really important again,
just to make sure that you have
those clear lines of distinction,
that clear line of demarcation
between the authority
and the authorization, you
know if there is going to be
some sort of handoff.
- Yeah.
And, and exactly that.
There's no right or there's,
there's no wrong about this.
There's what's right for your company.
So there is again, you just
making sure that you think
through what you want and what's
best for your organization.
Another big decision point
in as you talk to your,
your potential MDR and
we're just conflating
all the acronyms, we're
just gonna call MDR.
But as you, as you're
talking to your MDR provider,
is whether or not you
bring your own stack, BYOS?
Or if you take the stack that
they have because there's a,
there's a few different models here.
So you can bring your own
stack which means that you say,
"These are my endpoints.
These are the agents.
This is the security agent I
like having on my endpoint.
This is what I have for a firewall.
This is what I'm using for the cloud.
I'm gonna bring everything
that I have already
and my own staff, my
technology, my security stack.
I'm gonna bring it to
you and I want you to
Manage the Detection and
Response using my own,
my own, my own stack, my
own, my own technology."
You can also go with a vendor
that they are an MTR provider
but they don't build their
own endpoints for example,
they don't build their
own sensors for servers.
What they do is they
talk to other companies,
they pick and choose what
they think is the best
curated security stack for
organizations and experience.
And then they, they build out
an offering that they think
is gonna be the most comprehensive.
And then there's the,
the next option is a vendor-built stack.
So it could be that the
vendor has built their MDR.
So that's the sensors and
the security components
that are gonna go on the
endpoints in the servers
and within the network.
They've built out all of that themselves.
And then they say, "You buy the service,
you are also buying that stack
because they come together."
And then the last option.
And this one is actually
coming from a lot of MSSP is,
is that they may do a bit of a blended.
They can say, "Well, this is our stack.
And this is what we
recommend and what we use
and what most of our customers use.
However, if you wanna
bring a couple of pieces
from your stack, that's okay.
And we can do that for you too."
So you have the option.
That's the most important
thing to take away
from the stack talk.
The initial is that, all
of these different models,
you know there's a,
you have the choice whichever
model is right for you.
And the next slide I've got those some,
some pros and cons about
them that may help you
to make a decision on one
of these, one or the other.
So looking at the bring your own stack,
where you tend to get a
real, like you know a real
up on this one is the big pro is that,
is that you have a very limited lock-in.
If you decide that you
don't wanna work with that,
that MDR vendor anymore, it's your stack.
You just pick it up and you can go
and you can take it with you.
Now with your staff though, you may have
somethings to think about
here because you're bringing
your own stack and they may need to do
a lot of the same work
that they've been doing
to manage and maintain that stack before.
And then integration is
another consideration
when you bring in your own stack.
Because, if you've done
the work to integrate
those different pieces of your
security stack, that's great.
You can, now that, that is an advantage
for the MDR provider.
But if you haven't done the
integration then you may be,
you may get some things like you know,
some of the black holes or
blind spots that come out of it.
So if you wanna bring your own stack,
if you're a really mature
program within your security
program and, and you
know what you've picked
because you need, you have
a lot of regulatory needs.
Maybe bring your own stack.
You don't wanna replace it.
You don't want what the
vendor is gonna provide.
You want them to manage your stack.
In vendor supply, you very
often have a much tighter
integration because that's
one thing the vendors work on.
But if they're supplying the stack,
now you've got a little
bit of a lock-in because
you could either go and buy
all those tools somewhere else
but you're buying the
tools from the vendor.
And then the stack and
tack can be a little bit
blended there because they,
they may not know how to use
this new tooling that the
M, that the provider has.
So vendor supply, good for an
easy start because they say,
"You don't have to worry about it.
We're just, we're gonna
supply the stack for you."
And you have some pretty low
decision overhead but remember,
you are getting some element of lock-in.
With the vendor built, you
have a very tight lock-in.
Because now it's they built
it and they manage it for you.
So they, they've got both sides of that.
If that's the right stack
for you then that's great
because the integration, of
course if it's vendor built
and they're doing the management,
you've got the tightest set
of integration possible.
You've also got the biggest
benefit for your staff because
in most cases, the MDR
provider is not gonna be doing
most of that resource work.
So you're gonna be able to you know,
lift and and ease some of the
resources for your own staff.
But again, you do have that
lock-in because you've got
the vendor providing
both the technology stack
and the managed services
but you've got that big of a
highly integrated solution.
And then in blended
it's a little bit of a,
of a mix on all of these
because it's gonna depend on
your provider, what you've
blended and your own resources.
So the blended is gonna
be the most up in the air.
We have to think about
what your pros and cons are
but it's gonna give you
a lot of flexibility.
And if you do have
special regulatory needs
within your stack, you're gonna
be able to like in the full
bring your own stack.
You can also have that
supported in the blended.
(mouse clicking)
- So one of the next areas to think about
is in terms of visibility.
You know how much of the,
of your own environment
can the provider cover?
You know how much
visibility will they have
into your environment?
And you know, think about
across the third party systems
that you may have or even the operating,
operating systems that you may have.
You know, Diana mentioned you know,
thinking about the blind
spots that might pop up.
You know are there potential issues
with multi-cloud environments?
Or maybe they won't have visibility.
And you know how much access do they need?
Will they be able to see
different data types?
You know or will they just
be able to see labels?
You know and is there a provider that,
that for your particular environment
that who can see all the way across?
And is that what you need?
So these are you know, just
some sort of key questions
around visibility.
And then the other side of that,
is really on the privacy side of it.
You know looking at,
you know how much access
are you extending to them?
You know in terms of, if
they have access to data,
are they able to see your
confidential data like the PII,
the PHI, the health
information and so forth?
You know and looking back at
your spectrum of decision,
you know that may, that
spectrum may help you decide,
you know what kind of impact
there may be to privacy
because of the access
that you may be providing.
You know is it possible
that data classification
could be a control
factor in the sense that
maybe they can just see the
data classification labels
but not actually have
access to the data itself?
Would that provide enough for the types of
either investigation
or incident management?
You know that they're
able to take the actions
that you require.
And then you're just in terms
of the, the vendor trust.
You know is it possible that
if it's a particular vendor
that's providing the service
and they've already done
the background checks
and the experience checks
and so forth.
And you feel comfortable with the reviews
that they're doing.
Will that somehow offset
some of the due diligence
that you might do of the vendor
or that might be required?
So is that, that gold seal, is that enough
for the review that you need?
(mouse clicking)
And then in terms of the,
the power of threat Intel.
You know just thinking about,
you know is your Intel good enough or not?
Better, more Intel is
always better in most cases.
If you're able to sort through it,
if you're able to correlate it.
You know is it possible
that maybe your threat Intel
is lacking in some areas?
So is there a big benefit here?
So maybe you need that
kind of augmentation.
And in terms of, you know
indicators of compromise
and indicators of
attack, do you need both?
You know thinking about
your own environment
and the types of threats
that you're seeing
and the types of incidents
that you're seeing.
You know the better
detection, you know you're,
it's really going to help you a lot
but the correlation is so key to that.
So for example, if you
are walking into a forest
and someone's telling you that
there are a lot of snakes in the forest,
that's great information.
But if you know that most of
those snakes are poisonous,
then that becomes really important.
So, you know correlating
the different pieces
just becomes very valuable.
And, you know how well will
the service that you're getting
integrate with the existing
feeds that you already may have?
You know, who's monitoring what?
You know this is where
that handoff or that,
that line of segmentation
becomes very important.
So you make sure that
there's absolutely no gap,
no area that's going
uncovered merely because
there was a misunderstanding.
(mouse clicking)
- Yeah.
And that leads to, with your
staff augmentation and that,
that question of who needs MDR.
When I first started hearing about MDR,
I heard about it being
deployed at smaller mid-sized
companies as almost a
replacement for security staff.
And I thought well, big
company would never need it.
But then doing research
and speaking to CISOs,
I realized that no, it
actually again, it's this,
it's this spectrum.
So, at the very mature
or research, resource,
well research programs,
they're interested in MDR
because they want a second set
of eyeballs or in this case
a whole bunch of set of
eyeballs 'cause they have these
live people on the other side
that are also hunting through
your network looking for
anything that's a miss.
So, you know some very big
well resource companies are,
are finding it's very valuable.
Also companies that are experienced
but they just don't have
the, the money or the resources
right now to do FTE hires.
They can find that MDR really
helps augment their very
already experienced program
but under-resourced program.
And then, they're also
for some programs that it,
you know as, as sort of expected,
that they don't have the,
they haven't gotten the maturity,
they need some help with that.
They also need help with resources.
And in that case it can be a real lifeline
to have MDR to augment.
(mouse clicking)
The next thing that you should think about
is how much automation.
So we know that we talked about humans
and what the humans are gonna do
and that they're hunting
over activity within your,
within your systems.
But, there's also a lot of
automation that's included
with these solutions.
And just automation is one of
those things that tends to be
really, really appealing.
I mean it would absolutely,
wouldn't it be wonderful if I?
I want a, I still want
an automated driving car,
you know I hate to drive.
And I would love to have a
car that just push a button
but we're not quite there, right?
These cars run into problems.
They get confused.
They, you know sometimes
do unprotected left turns
when they shouldn't.
A whole lot of things happen
with, with automation.
So just keep that in mind when
you're talking to the vendor
about what they can give
you for true automation
and then what, what you,
where you might wanna limit
or scope that.
Because what can happen
in automation gone bad
is that you break your system.
You create business interruption
and you know now people can't
get to a critical workload
or a critical server or
your mail stops working.
You know, there are a lot
of things that can happen
when you start turning things
on and off automatically.
So talk it through with your vendor,
make sure what you're comfortable with.
Overall automation is really,
can be extremely helpful
and these sort of low impact
decisions and actions.
So if it's, I've got an endpoint
and there's malware on it.
Sure, automatically clean that out.
You wanna do that as fast as possible.
If it's something that's
a little bit higher impact
like reset everybody's
password at the company,
you might wanna have a human involved
in that decision chain.
(mouse clicking)
- So also don't, don't
ignore the questions
and the things that you need to consider
around reports and audits.
And then we'll talk
about some future state
considerations too but, you
know in terms of reports,
you know what kind of output do you need?
Over time can you get
the kind of analytics
that'll really help you?
You know analytics, analytics
on the types of incidents
that might've flared up.
And were they resolved?
You know can you get reports
on the response actions
that were taken?
And can you clearly link those
to a specific individual?
You know, do you have
the kind of forensics
that you'll need?
You know I'd like to think
about it in terms of,
if I had to go to court with this,
do I have an adequate case?
Do I have enough information
to prove what happened,
to prove who did what
when, and maybe even why?
And so that comes into play
also with the audit side of it.
You're making sure that you
have appropriate evidence
for your auditors as
well as your regulators
if that applies to you.
Making sure that those audit trails are,
are sufficient again to show
you know, who touched what?
What did they actually see or access?
And what kind of change was made?
And you know, can you clearly
demonstrate who did that?
Because that's so critical
both in terms of audits
as well as those legal
cases that may pop up.
You know will your audit trails be enough?
Will they be sufficient and
have enough information in them?
And, you know can that MXDR
gold seal that we talked about,
you know is that going to be enough
to stand in for your due diligence?
Or are you gonna need something more?
And so you know, making sure that the,
the steps that the vendor is
taking to review their own team
and their personnel is adequate.
Or that you're doing your own.
Now in terms of future state,
you know is it possible that
an MXDR can really step
in to provide a service
for you in a merger and acquisition?
So for example, if
you've acquired a company
and you're not comfortable,
you don't know enough about them yet
to know whether you trust their team
to identify incidents and
to respond to incidents
adequately.
Could it be possible
that this type of service
could step in, in the case
of a merger and acquisition
and provide that kind of
comfort that you need?
What about, you know the access
that third parties may have
or the trade secrets that they have
and the highly sensitive data.
You know maybe you don't feel
comfortable with the controls
that they have around that.
You don't want anything leaking out.
You know this might be another
one of those in terms of,
you know knowing that they
can take adequate response
in an incident so that,
you know data isn't getting
taken off.
Knowing that they can shut it down and,
and knowing the process that
they would go around that.
And then again, you know this just becomes
sort of a gold seal for partners.
If you know that they're
using a service from a vendor
that you trust and you not
only trust but you've reviewed
their process and their systems you know,
do you feel comfortable
then with that partner?
Does that make you feel better
about your supply chain?
- Exactly.
And the last high level
thing to think about
as you're getting ready
to talk to your vendors
and maybe buy one of these
services or solutions is,
what's your total cost of ownership?
And make sure you get
your metrics in place.
Every year the Ponemon
Institute comes out with
a cost of data breach report
where they show well that
if you can get down your MTTI,
your meantime to identify,
mean time to contain
and mean time to respond
to incidents that's gonna
save you a lot overall
and the cost of the incident.
So, is the MDR gonna
be able to supply that?
We've talked about blind spots.
But what about, can
the MDR also see things
that maybe that you
weren't able to see before?
Are you now able to reduce
your staff which is gonna save
the company money?
Or maybe repurpose your
staff 'cause you've got very,
you know high, high level
resources that don't need to go
do the hunting necessarily.
Now they can do some more strategic worth,
work at your company.
Lots of different ways to get a TCO,
but make sure again that
you find your metrics
so you can validate.
And then this one, and
Lisa you've introduced
your own Veg-O-Matics.
I'm gonna let you talk
to through those last.
- You know we just do our
own alphabet in there.
You know so, a lot of people
like to talk about ROI
but you know maybe what
you need to be looking at
is the value of the service
or the return on the service.
More so than, you know
return on investment.
And so that may just be a,
that was just our fun way of
throwing a couple extra
alphabets in there.
- Yeah, so we hope that this
has helped giving you a good
overview of what to think
about so that you're not just
feeling bombarded by
vendor noise and acronyms.
That just kind of break
it down that these are
really great services
doing different kinds
of detection and response.
And think about in advance,
what kind of problem
you want to solve before you
speak, talk to your vendor.
And make some decisions about,
do we want our own stack?
Are we trying to reduce staffing costs?
What's, what's the right
part of the response spectrum
for us?
Think those through in
advance so that when you talk
to the vendor, you know
you're gonna get the solution
that's right for you.
And don't forget also to
normalize your questionnaire,
so that you can get
apples-to-apples responses.
Sometimes vendors say the same things
but with very different words.
So you wanna make sure
that you've got your idea
of technically what controls
you want, what return you want,
what your own metrics are.
So that instead of you getting
caught in the Veg-O-Matic,
you're gonna be the one
who's, you know upfront
driving the decision.
(mouse clicking)
- And so we hope that we've,
you know given you all of the,
or at least a lot of the
information that you need
to make the analysis.
So how do you get started?
You know, in the next week
you can really sit down
and define your problem set.
Which I think includes an assessment
of your current capabilities.
So what problem are you trying to solve?
But also what capability,
capabilities do you have
toward that problem already?
And consider where you
might be on the spectrum.
Where would you wanna give
access, you know versus
what type of incident or
response would they have?
So where did, where are you
on the spectrum of response
but also where are you on
the balance of the risk?
(mouse clicking)
- And in the next three months
if you do wanna purchase
an MDR after you've defined your problems
and you think this is right,
start talking to the
vendors and assessing them
and building out your RFP.
And in six months, you should,
- In six months, you wanna think about
that shiny pretty thing
that you were looking for.
Did you get the flying car
or was it just a shiny pretty thing?
- Yeah.
You get hitting those metrics.
Have you been better with breaches?
At least breaches may occur even with MDR
but are you responding more quickly?
So starting to look at that
and maybe even if you start
to catch things that you
did before loss occurred.
So, we wish you a lot of luck
with your MDR deployments.
We have some resources
here in the last slide
for you to take a look
at that we think as you,
now that you've got this, this
great baseline or you know,
high level overview or framework,
there's some great resources out there.
I particularly like the
Detect Mappings in NIST.
There's the Ponemon Cost
of Data Breach that I had
talked about.
And then also there's a
CIS Response Plan Template
for the NIST CSF that may
help with responding to
a cyber incident.
So we wish you great luck in your,
in your response and detection work.
And we hope that this help
gave you a better view of
the overall Managed Detection
and Response market.
- So we are looking forward
to answering your questions
as well.
- Yes, thank you so much.