- Welcome to this RSA Session.
I'm Nicolas Fischbach, the Global CTO
at Forcepoint and the
VP of SASE Engineering.
And I'm joined today
by another CTO Nicolai
and we're gonna talk about
the new normal in security.
What's it gonna look like?
Last year, we spent some time looking
at what 2021 could bring,
what are the security trends?
And, we wanna share with you,
the findings so far and especially Nicolai
who's gonna introduce himself in a second,
he's gonna talk about
from his point of view
how is he helping clients
apply some of those findings,
some of those outcomes
through his user base?
Nicolai welcome and thanks for joining me.
- Thank you very much
for having me here today.
- You wanna talk a
little bit about Help AG
and what you guys are doing?
- Yes of course.
Help AG, we're a cybersecurity
systems integrator
in the Middle East, we
deliver services on a number
of cybersecurity topics,
everything from, of course
your solutions to also a
lot of (indistinct) services
for some of the large
clients in the Middle East.
- Thank you.
So what Nicolai and I are gonna do,
and you get two suits we
needed to dress the same way,
we had to tuck (indistinct) to align.
We gonna talk about, we picked five trends
obviously there's, many more than that
but we picked five, kind
of across the spectrum.
Some of them, you will see,
like the first one is
more about user experience
and how security and user
experience are so critical
and kind of happen,
nowadays hand in hand actually
have to happen, hand in hand.
The second one, it's
more about the people,
because people are core and center
when it comes to security,
not just security awareness
you would see that there
has many other things.
And not just because of work from home,
I think, many of us have been
in a working from home
for a year plus now,
it looks like the lock downs are easing
in some parts of the world, but still,
some things will remain and
we are gonna talk about that.
The other macro trend that
we've seen, disinformation.
It keeps happening,
it's probably something
at society level, but,
let's talk about it because
it's still impacting
businesses day in, day out,
and they're using very interesting tricks.
And again, Nicolai is gonna talk about,
what are some of the things
we can do to make sure
you stay on the safe side.
Finally, and it's linked to the people
disinformation, insider threats
is still a growing concern
inside organizations.
Also because of the
shift to work from home,
and also because the bad guys,
being in the (indistinct) state,
organized criminals, dress
the same ransomware crews
I've been using those tricks
to drive more insider threat risk.
And finally, the last one you will see it,
it's about data.
We talked so far a lot
about the users and,
there's kind of an umbrella theme that,
we're gonna use at the end to recap is,
where is your data?
And I think many of you
maybe already found out,
because of some of the breaches lately
and some of the leaks, but,
data is core and center in a way it comes
to any data protection
strategy in organizations.
So is that, we'll dive in,
I'm gonna present more kind of,
crystal ball sinking, some of the insights
that we've been looking at,
as Forcepoint or X-Labs
or research group that
does data scientists
cyber security researchers,
human behavior, psychologists
and then Nicolai,
we'll share a whole like,
he has been helping clients apply, protect
defend against some of those
findings we're discussing here.
Hopefully you're gonna enjoy this session
and thanks for being with us.
So let's dive in, the first one,
the emergence of the
Zoom of Cybersecurity.
Many of us, have switched
from being an office,
or many of us are being
on the road all the time
using productivity tools.
And, Zoom or any corporation
tool has become core and center
for business operations
in any organization.
And people realized that, whereas,
other piece of technologies
have been around
for very long time,
and you look back at the
the regular conference calls
voice only WebEx, SASE
(indistinct) for very long time,
people wonder, why why did
Zoom take off that rapidly?
Why did it grow so fast?
Well, at the end of the day,
it's the user experience on one hand side
and also other hand side
is how easy it is to test
and buy a security offering.
So what we're saying here
is that cyber security
has become a business differentiator.
It's something you need as
part of your business processes
it's not just any more something
that we call it a category creation.
I think the whole buying cycle
what business processes
are on testing, new tools
adopting new tools, deploying new tools
has completely changed.
From an end-user point of view,
the user experience is critical.
Users don't want more friction,
they want quicker time
to value and ease of use.
And finally, before I
hand over to Nicolai,
you will see that this
has actually changed
the mindset at all
levels in organizations,
at the user level,
at the (indistinct) or CIO level,
but also at the exec and the board
of director level.
Because topics like SASE,
Secure Access Service Edge,
are being discussed at that level.
So you see much more business
partnership happening
on security topics on board level.
And that's kind of all the three key items
we've decided to really
push into this topic
of the Zoom of cybersecurity.
Nicolai, what did you guys do about this?
How did you help implement
answers to this problem?
- So there's a number
of discussions we have
with clients, so first of all,
cybersecurity is really
one of those things
that you need to think into any kind
of transformation within
your organization.
I think the last year
we've done more discussions
about digital transformation,
how it impacts organizations
and we've done the 10 years before
simply because organizations were pushed
to doing that digital transformation
due to the situation we're
in with the pandemic.
And key for that is to make sure
that cybersecurity gets thought into that.
Because if you don't start off by thinking
about how could this
impact your organization
from a cyber security perspective
or what kind of risk there
is associated with them
how do you address those risks,
unfortunately, you
could become a disruptor
of your own business and that's also
not an outcome that you want from that.
So that's a little bit
linking to what you're saying
about the board of directors.
I also think that the
boards in organizations,
they have much, much better
security capabilities
and understanding, about technology today
than they've had in the past.
And that means that
they can make much more
educated discussions within the boardroom.
And finally, I also have
to say that we're involved
on those kinds of levels to discuss
with the board on what they can do.
And that's, at least a development
that we haven't seen before.
Another thing that we are
constantly requested by clients
is it's how we deploy
and how we also go to market
with products and services
where customers the same
way that they're ordering
a Zoom subscription to
take that as an example,
also expecting the same
kind of buying pattern
for cybersecurity products as well.
So really subscription-based
service outcome-based solutions
and the same way that
you can choose to say,
well, this month I'm using Netflix
for streaming and next
month I'm using Disney Plus,
if I'm not happy about
the content I'm getting
on one streaming service over the other,
it's a little bit the
same with cybersecurity
that customers want that kind of success.
Of course, a lot of that being decided
of how good is the service
and also, what is the
user experience from it?
Obviously we talk a
lot about cybersecurity
and a lot of different kinds of vendors.
One of the biggest areas
that we're looking at it
also with clients is of course
how do we integrate all of this stuff?
I think we're blessed
with the fact that many
of the vendors, they understand
that they are living in an ecosystem now,
and they're not just in their
own little world anymore,
which means that we have these rich
kind of integration capabilities
whether you call it a platform or sore
if you're one other
vendor or something else
if you're a third vendor,
what's key is to make sure
that you are able to get information
to go from one system to the other.
- Perfect, so this is really
becoming real, which is great.
Next one, let's kind of not switch gears,
but, you go back to the roots.
I'm not gonna say the roots of all avail
because for way, way too
many years or decades,
people kept repeating
users are the weakest link.
And we wanna make sure that you and I,
having been out in the fields,
like it is not the case.
Actually users are play their role
in making security better.
Users should be trusted,
and that's something we
wanted have a conversation
about also like, we spoke
about SASE previously.
There's always the zero trust concept
which is very negative, by definition.
There is no trust, you have to build trust
when maybe it should be
the other way around.
Trust exists, most
employees are good people,
good employees they wanna do
the right things for them,
so that is important.
And the work from home situation
this kind of new, normal
has shown many of us as,
and it was kind of predicted
that users cannot take more friction.
It is complicated enough
to work from home,
this is home office, which has become like
a branch office of one,
in a very complex environment,
where, you have sometimes
the kids working from home
you have shared computer, shared WiFi,
you need to print locally,
things move off USB keys again,
that is very important.
And any security tool,
should actually empower
users to be better,
act like a safety net, for them
to make sure confirmation doesn't happen
but also protect company data.
And the other thing that,
we predicted to be very helpful,
kind of building on the active coaching,
coaching in the moment in DLP tools
is that those real-time interactions
will help make better decisions.
With all the stress or the noise
or the signals or interrupts
people keep getting
all the time,
even sometimes cussing the
beeps coming from Outlook
which maybe I forgot to shut down,
those real time interactions,
this are some in the moment coaching
because it helps people to stop
and think about what they're gonna do
and maybe not do the wrong thing.
So this model where we used to do
like this legacy DLP approach
where people switch from
audit mode to enforcement mode
and the enforcement models
only is a block hollow
is actually blocking the business.
People don't switch DLP from
audit to enforcement mode
because of the risks,
but also it's being seen
as a wall by many users.
So I think what we were predicting,
is that something which
is more risk adaptive,
based on understanding a
user process to company data
or company systems at
a certain point of time
and adjusting the level of
access makes probably more sense.
What do you see is that aligned
with what you see in the field Nicolai?
- Absolutely.
First of all, by blocking,
it's an extremely expensive
way of doing security
because you're actually inhibiting people
from doing what they're supposed
to do which is their job right?
So if you have the capability of getting
to a level where you have
a much better understanding
of what is good and
potentially bad behavior
or a malicious behavior,
then you can choose to say,
well I'm going to allow
everything that's with good intent
which does not necessarily break
my DNP process around some really, really
sensitive data in the organization.
I don't think we'll ever
get to the point where
we are turning off our DMPs and just,
purely trusting our employees to always
make the right decision because
there's some governance risk
and potentially some compliance
around some of the data
that you're working with.
But it would be really, really nice
if we could, in those,
let's say areas where
we're not required to
do these kinds of things
and we can make the decision based
on the intent of the user.
Also, because it's so much easier to do.
But I also have to say, it also depends
on how do we actually
create those processes
that our users are working based on,
as an example, we had
right at the beginning of the pandemic
where everyone was fleeing
home to their home offices
we saw in our digital
risk protection service
we saw quite a big increase in data loss,
and the reason why it was
actually not malicious data loss
it wasn't like people got
hacked or anything like that,
maybe some of it was that.
But the largest part of it,
was simply because people had
fled to their home offices,
had to do the job and figure out that
potentially they couldn't send
that large Excel file on
the exchange environment
because there was a file limitation.
And then they decided to send
that on their private email
address instead, which caused
potentially a data leak.
So these are some things
when we design processes
that we need to do in the right way.
And then finally, what we talk
a lot with clients about is,
that you need to assume breach.
So you need to assume
that one day your systems
will not work, that your
users will potentially
do something that they shouldn't do,
again not out of malicious intent,
but that something will happen.
And if you kind of plan for that breach,
you can start to walk in and you can start
to think about what would happen
if these things happens.
And I think assuming breach
with all of the changes
that we've had in the
last year is something
we should be spending
a little bit more on.
- And you actually
already kind of concluded,
that's gonna be the last point,
but you're good one.
And I think today
people do people's things right.
Amazon prime delivery, I'm just waiting
for the kids to run in, and the
neighbor to start the chain,
so to cut the tree.
And then we'll have all
the people do people things
on the Zoom recording.
Next topic, disinformation.
This has been going on
for quite some time,
it's kind of a macro level issue.
But we also believe it is very specific
to what we see in the enterprise.
People have been doing this
for quite some time,
sometimes the most kind
of handmade, so to speak
to drive, business, email compromise,
some phishing and other techniques.
And spinning nights,
kind of societal behavior
you look at some of the
things that's happened
during the election period.
But the other thing we've seen is that,
some criminal organizations
have turned this
into like a service.
So you can actually, although,
send in the data you want
and they're gonna produce
is the voice recording the video recording
or something to help
spread this information
or actually trick users to do something.
Again under stress,
I think the combination of work from home
the time differences
in some organizations,
the level of stress, the fact that people
don't pay attention as much,
is still a problem.
The awareness is much better,
because there's been many, many examples.
Most of the times, they
actually funny examples
but it's also still very a symmetric,
like many things in security,
it doesn't take a lot of effort to create
and it can be reused.
We've seen that a lot also driving
kind of Crypto Locker, ransomware.
How do you see that there is a kind of,
in region, where you operate Nicolai
with Help AG or in general,
what do people see?
How did they react to this?
And it's that a real problem?
- Well, first of all,
it's something that we see
at clients across the board.
Actually for me personally,
this is one of the things
I'm the most worried
about being also a citizen in the world,
and these kinds of things is this,
this information deep, fake, and all
of these things that we're gonna start
to see being weaponized for real,
there's apps on your mobile phone
that can do certain parts
of this, of course, for fun.
But, but if you can do
it on your mobile phone
and it's relatively trustworthy,
it's probably quite certain that attackers
they will be weaponizing
this very quickly.
Which of course in an enterprise setting
can be utilized in phishing scenarios
and these kinds of things.
So I think awareness is
really becoming a real
business requirement.
So that's something that
I work with clients around
on thinking about how
do they do awareness.
And I think what we see
with awareness programs
they should no longer be a
point in time awareness program
but it should really be
something where you test
and probe and educate
your users constantly
in that kind of awareness scenario,
so that it becomes an ongoing session
also because it's a
very, very moving target
what these things are happening.
And then finally,
I think it's very much a technology
created problem specifically
when we're talking about deep fakes
and some of the more advanced
phishing capabilities.
So I think that at some
point of time that also needs
to be some form of electronic
or a solution for it.
So I can easily see that as an industry
or as a society that
there will be some form
of validation service
around some of these things.
Of course now, I'm talking
a little bit outside
of the topic of enterprise
but I think the whole way that we think
about information and
validating sources is important.
In the setting of business
and here in the Middle East specifically,
we have seen way too
many successful attempts
of getting people to
change account information
for suppliers and these kinds of things,
low level stuff that's happening,
but it's still successful.
And the reason why is because often,
organizations do not have
the right business process
in place to make sure
that that becomes secure.
- And that's an interesting point.
It's just a security technology
that needs to solve the problem
is also business processes needs to start
to account for some of those risks
fairly true.
And that's actually a good lead
into the next topic, which is,
I think twofold,
insider threats and we've been seeing
insider threat becoming more of a problem,
during the pandemic and lock down,
because the security
exposure and security posture
the work environment has changed so much.
And, things have been, kind
of changing here and there,
and not being, probably
controlled in the same way.
But also to the second part is,
it's become like a little bit as again,
like this information,
insider threat-as-a service,
like compromising accounts,
compromising people has
been something that people
have been weighing as a
service to (indistinct).
So what we're saying here is,
really what we were expecting is
for organizations to rethink where
their threats are coming
in this very shifting environment.
I remember having conversation
with CIOs and CFOs and CEOs like
(indistinct) a year from now,
that we're kind of reinventing the network
reinventing security
or reinventing desktops
and laptops overnight, over weekends,
sometimes a company credit card
and shifting data from
on-prem to the cloud.
And users, their environment
has changed as well.
I think, people forgot that everybody
and new technology we kind of,
we live and breathe day in, day out,
but we probably didn't start
in one, two, 5% of people that do that
but everybody else is
just a consumer of those
(indistinct) and security
services, we are awful.
And I don't think people really realize
what the psychological
and the intellectual
impact is on those people
and how do you deal with that?
And that's why the second data point,
or the second point and data point
is quite interesting.
Yeah they're good but they make mistakes.
Some of them go roque, you
always have people going rouge
because their have flight risks,
because of espionage because
they're being compromised,
but most of the (indistinct)
that we were expecting is actually
people making mistakes.
I remember some of the data points,
we were seeing
back in the early days of
the pandemic at Forcepoint
or X-Labs team was picking like,
1.5 millions of emails per day,
that were very sophisticated COVID theme
or Office 365 laid out, phishing attempts.
So people were getting compromised,
And the idea here is also that,
you revert or you turn the table
on the insider threat
where the idea is that we as an industry
we need to help people defend themselves
from being compromised and being used
and abused because they
didn't even know about it.
And I think the other topic that I think
Nicolai you already touched on
in one of the previous items is,
the goal is, you could assume
breach, but I think the goal
should also be as an industry that
we are staying left of loss.
So rather than trying to
address the forensics,
the remediation, the mitigation
when you happen to have a breach,
AK you are, or you right of breach,
I think the tools without
being in the user space
are either creating more
friction should actually
help industries use a CIO,
simplify the toolboxes
have better user experience
and make sure that
this risk adaptive approach
we've been talking about
for quite some time now,
enables organizations to
really stay left of loss.
Again, what's your take on that?
Is that something you see as well?
- Well, breaches are ridiculously
expensive to deal with.
First of all, there can
be legal implications
there can be clean of implications
and all of these things, of course
you want to avoid those things happening.
And of course that's also why we see
so much investment going
into an effort going
into avoiding those
breaches in the first place.
But there is fundamental
changes that happened
in the last year.
Obviously moving back
home and the home office,
again, I think anyone on this conference,
that's on this conference,
we've been used to working
at home or from remote
and all of things even
before the pandemic happened
but we need to remember
that most of our coworkers
in our organizations, may not
have had that kind of experience,
for them it was brand new.
So this kind of like
the hybrid workforce has
that has come up.
I also think that now, as organizations
have figured out that,
that working from home
does not maybe really
impact the efficiency of the individual,
they're going to start
speculating much more
how can they actually utilize this
even after we have all been
vaccinated and the pandemic
has been solved.
And they might also look
into different kinds
of ways of hiring resources,
which means that the
association between the employee
and the corporation may not be as strong
as it used to be, which
potentially can lead
to some insider threat issues.
So I think that's really important.
So having the right visibility
and being able to create the right view
on what distributed workforce
is doing with our data, or with data
is extremely important as we move forward.
And that's really about
being able to detect
before the loss actually happens.
So I think as we have all moved home
and all working in these environments now,
hand on hand I think anyone maybe revisit
if you have that right level of visibility
and understanding what's happening
with the data, no matter where it is.
- Perfect.
And this is kind of our summary section.
it's probably a topic on its own,
but at the same time,
what we talked about here
is a lot about the users,
a lot of other data.
And then at the end of the day
what we wanna protect is your data.
And one of the predictions,
we were making as kind
of Forcepoint X-Labs
at the end of last year is that,
somebody else is probably having a backup
of your data, kind of
jokingly, so to speak.
And the tagline we came up with is like,
you know where is your data?
You're probably gonna find that in 2021.
And I think so far, like four months in,
we've been proven right.
There's been so many breaches
there's been super chain attacks
and they look at solar
winds and the puzzles
there's all the ones we
don't know about yet.
So it is sadly the start state of affairs,
I think we didn't have to
wait till 2021 to find out,
criminals don't rest.
The attack affairs is still going on.
People burn more zero days,
no chain more components
to get to the end goal.
There's still many breaches happening
many organizations,
still don't take security
seriously enough.
We send a little bit of everything,
and it's the full spectrum.
We are still investing a lot,
people have been doubling down,
probably starting last summer in kind
of retrofitting security into
the work from home plans.
Making sure that the policies
for data protection also get applied
to remote devices that, the remote desktop
or that the shared
environment is better secure,
but we've seen everything,
from various stupid and basic phishing
and ransomware to full kind of Sunburst
(indistinct) type attacks.
So what we're saying is,
the work from home setups,
the changes that have been driven
from a digital
transformation point of view
so to speak, in an organization where,
applications shifted from
on-prem to the cloud,
people are investing into
private access type offerings
and so on.
That security posture and that secure
that attack surface actually
needed to be readdressed.
And I think the organizations are still
in the process,
and in the meantime, many organizations
or nation States,
in a criminal organizations
have spent the time to approach,
their pins on the board, here and there
and are just waiting to
probably do more harm.
What's your take on that?
What can organizations do about that?
Because like we saying,
here, it is true that,
SASE application consumption has exploded,
data has moved,
the ownership of the
application has moved sometimes
from the IT teams,
to the business owners, especially look
at CRM tools and marketing
or customer experience tools
and people at the same
time should not forget
about infrastructure security.
We're not trying to say here that
infrastructure security
is the same from the past,
it's still part of your maturity model.
But what we've seen is,
people finally starts to address also
the data protection layer
and this needs to be looked at.
And people handing over to you,
for the final comments, Nicolai,
I think like you said earlier
the whole orchestration automation,
having better tools
making more sensitive data is
also very important because
there's been so much more noise generated
by events by (indistinct) and so on,
that this also needs to be reduced
because you cannot scale
your sock with more people.
So I think to touch on
a lot of things here,
what's kind of your take on this,
probably very kind of wide-scale?
Over to you.
- Well, the pandemic was a
perfect stone for attackers.
I think that's something that we also
from an academic perspective,
it has been really, really interesting
to observe what happened.
So everything from the phishing emails
that were theme that way and
hitting the soft underbelly
of people working from at home,
obviously it was fantastic
for the attackers to
have all of these things.
And these things are by
the way playing out still.
Like right now it's phishing campaigns
around vaccination that's happening.
And you need to remember that
users in their home offices
have very, very different behavior
than they have in the office.
So this really means,
that you need to reconsider
how you do on-prem security
versus what you do in when
people are working from home.
You also need to revisit,
how do you think about SaaS security.
In the sense that that's a whole new topic
for certain organizations as
they start to utilize that.
Also remember SaaS organizations
or companies that deliver access services
are also targets in this big cybersecurity
challenge that we're having.
And I'm not talking about the big ones
but if you're buying
a smaller SaaS service
you need to evaluate if
that specific SaaS service
is secured in a way that you can except
for the data that you're
gonna put into it.
So that's also a new
challenge for organizations
as they move into cloud.
One low level thing which I
think we haven't done enough
where an organization,
haven't done enough with,
is really assessing how your
endpoints are going to do
against what I would call
normal attack scenarios.
So really performing an assessment
of the security robustness
of the end points.
That's something that many organizations
could benefit from.
We generally, when we do
these kinds of services
are able to break through the systems,
it's really only a question of effort
but the outcome of that
is that organizations
can fix those specific issues
or scenarios that we played
out on the environment.
It's also about understanding
where the user is sitting.
So it may not be appropriate
that they do everything at all locations.
It may not be appropriate
that they do everything or have access
to all data at any location
that they're working at.
So that's also an element
that I think is very important
that you create policies
that can follow the rules
and follow the location of the user.
And then maybe a final
thing, a call to action,
if you haven't done
this already is to think
about which kind of disability you have
in this new paradigm.
Because if you haven't got visibility
you're also not really going to catch
what's going to happen out there.
And, you have to understand the fact that
where your security used
to be maybe centralized
in a couple of locations
where the users were sitting
and you had your centralized
firewalls and proxies
and these kinds of things to look at,
now the users potentially are everywhere.
And how do you deal
with creating that kind
of visibility layer?
- True, thank you.
I think super insightful, I hope,
you and the audience, enjoyed
to the end of the conversation
between Nicolai and I,
I think we are kind of proven right.
To summarize on some of those insights
and the crystal ball is always a risk.
but I think, what Nicolai shared with us,
his field experience, what
he has implemented in clients
resonates with you,
and he's gonna help you
make your environment better
make the user experience
better for your users
make your data more safe
make your infrastructure more resilient.
With that Nicolai, let me hand over back
to you for maybe one last final statement
or recommendation to the audience before
maybe we open to QA.
- Not much more for me to say here,
apart from the fact that,
I think we should all utilize
the time and also the fact
that we don't have to necessarily
be physically present.
I'm really looking forward
to being able to travel again
and be able to go to events.
I think there's a lot of benefits
and also meeting face to face
with industry professionals.
So next year I hope that it's going
to be face to face instead. (laughs)
- I agree, I think we all
miss being face to face,
networking and all the cool chats.
- Thank you all, thank you for attending.