- Hi, my name is Jay Jacobs
I'm chief data scientist
and a partner at Cyentia Institute.
I worked on the Verizon DBIR and I've been
a data scientist for a
number of years and working
in security for 20 plus
years and so it's great
to be presenting at RSA.
My co-presenter Ben Edwards,
is a senior data scientist
with me at Cyentia Institute.
He's got a PhD from
University of New Mexico.
And he will be joining talking
about some some stuff later
on in the slides and I'm
gonna start out here, so.
So what we're gonna cover today
we're talking about
application security and some
of the fun things about it and some
of the security aspects
associated with that.
And so this is gonna be a
very, very data-driven talk
and so we're gonna talk about
a lot of application data
a lot of flaws and the fixed times and
a whole bunch of stuff.
And so first we wanna cover
where this data came from
and then that helps
establish the frame, set up
any potential biases in the data.
Then we're gonna talk about just sort of
an introduction, set a foundation about
how secure are applications.
And then, we're gonna talk little bit
about remediation fixed
times things like that
and then we're gonna get
into how does the language
the development language affect security
and what do we see across
different languages.
Then we're gonna get into
some open source stuff talk
about open source libraries,
third party libraries
and inclusion in the applications
and what that does for security.
And then the best part I
think of the whole talk
is gonna be this last section
where we talk about, looking
at that remediation and look at attributes
that can contribute to faster
or slower fixed times now
there'll be the nature versus
nurture part of the talk.
So let's start out and
talk about the data here.
Essentially we're looking
at 130,000 applications over 130,000.
And depending on how we slice
it it'll be a little bit less
than that depending on
what we're looking at.
But this is all coming from
Veracode customers and a lot
of this is covered in the volume 11
of State of The Software
Security report, which
is free to download.
And so we've got this
this bias in there that
these applications are from
organizations that are vested
in security already.
And so this might be
perhaps overestimating some
of the security aspects because they
are already putting money
into and putting their time
into security aspects.
And so, just got to keep that
in mind might actually be
that the whole world might
be a little bit worse
than the data we're looking
at, but I think that's good.
I think that we're looking
at sort of best case
of companies actually
investing in security.
We have over a million
code scans over the amount
of data we have here
and it's a lot of data.
We have over 10 million
findings that has flaws that
have been found typically
from static analysis
other we're gonna look
at some dynamic analysis
and stuff too.
And one of the things that we're doing
is that we're gonna
analyze the full history
of any active applications,
what we've done
in previous state of
software security reports
and sort of look at the last 12 months.
And this year we're taking
a look at the full history
from when an application came
on board for the first time,
to the last time it was scanned right
before we pulled the data.
And again, this is volume 11 of the State
of Software Security
report through Veracode
and we are not, employees of Veracode we
are independent researchers
that work with Veracode
on this so.
Let's get into the actual
security aspect here.
So, let's first talk about
how common our application flaws.
If you think of an
application, what is the chance
that static code analysis
would find some type
of flaw in it?
And so most applications at
some point or another have
at least one flaw.
And then this is completely
independent of application size.
So this might be one, 10 lines of code for
a small quick library in
JavaScript or it could be, 10 gig
of files in Java.
And so, could be any size
and so across there obviously
the larger apps are gonna have more flaws.
But just blanket regardless
of size what we see
is about three out of four
will have some type of flaw.
But on the bottom side we
see about one out of four
has high severity and that's high
or critical severity ranking
in the Veracode platform.
The middle two, if the flaw
is one of the things listed
in the OWASP top 10, we see
about 66 two out of three, 66%
of those have at least
one OWASP top 10 flaw.
And then the SANS top 25
but I think that's now
the CWE top 25.
But when we were looking at
it was still the SANS 25.
I mean, we see about 60% of
things in that top 25 from SANS.
So, and we're seeing that
relatively consistent even
from volume one up to volume
11 hanging right around
that three out of four applications
have at least one flaw.
Now when we take into account the size of
the application we see some
really interesting things here.
If you notice these are trying
to show the distributions
and that the number of flaws
per one megabyte of code.
And this is gonna vary based
on the language things like
that some are a little bit
more dense, some spread out.
But the cool thing is if you notice
the distributions here, you
see how they're pretty smooth.
I think that's a really interesting thing
and that's personally an
artifact of the amount
of data that we have here.
And that it's just sort
of a smooth distribution
from basically one in a hundred million.
So if you look at the left to the right
we're seeing things going
from relatively not dense
at all a whole bunch of
code and very few flaws.
To on the right side of you
see a whole bunch of flaws
and perhaps not that much code.
But, again we're seeing that
distribution any flaws there's
a lot more on the critical
flaws there's less,
but there is this wide distribution
that's what we're trying
to get at here.
There are some that
have a tremendous amount
of critical flaws for the amount
of code that they have so.
And that's sort of what
we're getting at there.
So, getting away from sort
of these general statements
about flaws we wanna take
a look at what flaw types
are most common.
And so at the top here what we see
is things like information
leakage, CRLF injection.
And some of these aren't critical
and we have another problem
too is we classify these
these are taken from CWE, the
common weakness enumeration.
And that trying to put
these things in a bucket
is very difficult and
so if you take a look
at something like
insufficient input validation
the sixth one down that is
sort of a blanket catch-all
but if you take
a look like CRLF injection,
directory traversal.
Cross-site scripting, SQL
injection all of those
are also insufficient input validation.
And so, it's a little bit
hard trying to try to keep
them in their own bucket
and things like that.
But we see a lot of that
upfront, we see a lot of
that insufficient input
validation so that's one
of the key things and that's
obviously in the top 10
for OWASP and things like that.
Some other interesting things,
obviously some of these
have been around for so long
still talking about them
since the dawn of time.
So like on the bottom we've
got buffer overflow, buffer
management errors, things like
that they're still around.
But what we're seeing is that
some of the languages make
that a non issue.
So buffer overflow in Java
it's a really tricky thing
to get in an application
to have that happen, but.
So, it's interesting just
to see this distribution
and talk about them.
Now we can also look at
how dense are these flaws
in the code.
So again, we're gonna look at
the percent of applications
with the flow type across
the X-axis to the horizontal.
And then vertically up
and down, things that have
that appear more often
in application are gonna
be higher up and things that
appear really infrequently
are gonna be lower down.
So like in the top right
we've got CRLF Injection
so it's in a lot of
applications and when it's in
an application, it's in there
repeatedly 10 to 11 times
on average across the application.
In the upper left you see
coding standards when it's not
a whole lot of applications
but when it's in there
it's in there a whole lot.
And so it's just interesting
seeing this sort of flow
from not a lot of apps,
not a lot of spread
in the application up to the upper right
where it's in a whole lot
of applications and we see
it a lot more in the density.
Now this is taken from
the report and we're
what we're talking about
is these flaws and so, you
might be perceived the best
thing here is to just not put
in the code in the first
place which is good but really
for security teams, for
dev ops, for developers
what you wanna do is be able
to recover and fail safe here
on these flaws.
And so you wanna be able to remediate
these flaws quickly and thoroughly.
And so we're gonna talk
about how spread out are
these time-wise, how long
does it take to remediate
and then how many are
actually being remediated.
So when we take a look
at that this is how many
are actually fixed.
So out of all the flaws on
the bottom roughly 72.6%, 73%
of all flaws will eventually be remediated
which means, roughly 27% are still open at
the time we pulled this data.
And that's gonna that's gonna
remain relatively constant.
We're gonna have flaws closed
out but we're gonna discover
some new ones.
We're probably gonna hang
right around this ratio.
And then you look up to like
high severity 82% roughly
about seven out of eight are
gonna be fixed, but we still
have roughly one out of eight
sort of hanging out there.
And so it's interesting to
think about and it's always hard
there's always gonna be
flaws out there that we want
to go in after.
And if we talk about over
time we're gonna get into time
a little bit more later, some of
the actual speed of remediation.
But this is gonna look at
the capacity to remediate.
And so if you think of an application
as a living organism we wanna know
our applications generally
reducing the amount of flaws,
the flaw density that we
see in the applications or
are they getting worse, are
they adding a bunch of features
and a bunch of code in there
and actually introducing more bugs?
So what we see is when we look
at all flaws actually across
all of these categories
there are more applications
that are reducing the amount
of flaws then that are
increasing the flaws, the yellow
on the right.
And then a lot of them have
no change especially as we get
to high severity.
A lot of them just either
close them out right away
and just keep them closed
and anything new comes up
they close them right away.
So they're mainly
maintaining the flaw density
of high severity hopefully to zero.
But we do see it on the
right we see these features
being added things like that
are increasing the amount
of flaw density in applications
which isn't necessarily
a great thing so.
And so it's nice to see the
spread though, there's a lot
of variations a lot of
variety in these applications.
And let's talk about the language though
because this I think gets
into an interesting aspect
because, a lot of people will
generally stick to language
that they know and or they're
used to something and so
they focus on that and we'll
get new applications in there.
And so when we look at
the type of languages
that we see across industries,
largely we see Java and .Net.
Those are dominating the landscape.
It's a little interesting
since we see government sort
of as a odd ball here second
from the bottom, where
we see more .Net than Java otherwise, we
almost exclusively see more
Java than .Net but those two
are absolutely dominating.
Then we see some JavaScript in
the third place, roughly
one out of six applications
are JavaScript depending on the industry
and then the others.
And that's, Python, Android,
PHP, C++ and there's Ruby
and just a whole bunch of other
languages sorta going along
that tail there.
Now if we take a look at
the top 10 flaws that we saw
on that bar chart, I think
these are most of the top 10
there but we're looking at
these top 10 across the languages.
And so what you notice
right away is that none
of these look the same.
So these flaws are gonna
be very very different across languages.
Like in Java you see that CRLF Injection.
Cross-site scripting the upper right.
When we look at PHP you just
see the cross-site scripting.
Python, most of these
specific flaws are down
in the lower left meaning not
a lot of applications have
it, when they have it
they're not very intense
they're not very dense in the application.
But when we take these
languages and look at the top 10
within each language, we get
a very different story here
and I think this is
really, really interesting.
So first you can notice with
the red being a high proportion
of applications, that PHP
really sticks out that there are
a lot roughly three out
of four applications have
had cross-site scripting problems
when it's written in PHP.
Whereas something like Java script
where cross-site scripting
is also number one,
but roughly under a third
compared to three out
of four for PHP.
So you see some really stark differences
here across the languages.
And even looking across
the top two like .Net you
see information liquids
and code quality and the third one being
that insufficient input validation.
C++ error handling and buffer management.
Even though there was a
small proportion overall
of the flaws it is a huge thing in C++
that buffer management.
In Java you have that
CRFL injection problem.
Code quality and the information
leakage similar to .Net
and some of those JavaScript, we get
the cross-site scripting as well as PHP.
Python we get some cryptographic issues
in the cross-site scripting so.
Depending on the language
that you like to work in
and intend to work in,
you're gonna wanna be aware
of different things so you
can't just look at like here's
the top list of all vulnerabilities
are all flaws in code.
You're gonna wanna say hey, since I work
in JavaScript I have to be more aware
of cross-site scripting,
credential management.
CRLF injection than say
someone working in C++
or something like that.
You'd have a different focus.
And this is the same exact data shown
just slightly different, this again
like really highlights PHP.
So if you notice PHP that
sort of darker green one
is what does that cross
site scripting in the top.
And if you follow that dark
green you can see it's sort
of hovering between 20, 25%.
Most apps goes up to 30% for JavaScript
but, largely down there except
for PHP it jumps way up.
And so this was just sort of fun to look
at this particular one and see how
it pans out across the languages.
All right, and now we're gonna
talk about some third party
and open source libraries
and I'm gonna pass it over
to my partner Ben.
- And I'd like to thank Jay for that.
We are gonna talk about third-party
and open source libraries.
Because as we were doing this
analysis, we realized that
of course all this code is
not written by the developers
in house and we probably
wanna think about the effect
of open source libraries and
the flaws that they introduce.
So of course, the first
question that we wanna ask
is what proportion of
applications are actually composed
of third-party code versus in-house code.
And so what this chart shows
is it's really variable.
And of course as Jay
said, language matters.
So across the horizontal
axis is the percentage
of the application that
is a third-party code
or open source code,
however we wanna call it.
And each here dub represents 1%.
And so what we can see again, we have
this huge variation in languages.
Java, almost all of the
density is far to the right
where we have most of the
most of the applications
are almost 100% third-party code.
And then it kind of tails
off far to the left of course
there are some Java
applications at least 1%
that are written totally
from scratch, but it
is generally pretty rare.
And then we have things like .Net where
it's more spread out across there.
Java script we kind of have
this bi-modal lots of things
at 0% lots of things at 100%.
And a lot of this starts to
make sense when you think
about how these languages are constructed.
So for Java, when you bring
in functionality you're bringing down
those classes, somebody
has already written it.
You go to Apache comments
and you find the library
and you bring it in.
In a large part so with
JavaScript as well, lots
of very small libraries
that you're including.
And so that leads to this
large percentage of code
that is open source.
Now if we go down to C++
and kinda surprisingly PHP,
most of those applications
are written from scratch.
So there is some library
use, but the bulk of the code
is actually 0%.
And so, this should totally
not be surprising to us, right.
Because, of course developers
don't need to reinvent
the wheel or as we're saying here reinvent
the B+ tree every time they
need a new data structure.
So the B+ tree is kind
of an example for me
because my sophomore
computer science class,
our professor asked us
to implement a B+ tree
on disc in C++.
And realize that it was incredibly hard
for sophomore computer science majors
and ended up actually saying,
well you just use a library
for this anyway.
And so obviously like when
developers find a problem
that requires difficult
coding, performance code
they're gonna go reach for a library.
And that's really an
obvious boon, but it has
its inherent risks.
And so we want to start
asking some of these questions
like, how has Free
and Open Source Software
used in applications?
What parts are used?
When do they come in?
What are the flaws that are introduced?
You know, Jay talks a
lot about those flaws
that are introduced in homegrown code.
We wanna know more about
the open source code.
And then once we know
about kind of the landscape
of those flaws, how do we manage that?
How do we manage it?
Because as Jay said,
it's not just a matter
of fixing everything cause we're
never gonna fix everything,
but it's a matter of
prioritizing and getting
the right things fixed to make
the application more secure.
So to that end I am gonna
tell you about we wrote
a different report the State
of Software Security open-source edition.
I'm gonna touch on some research
that's in here on some that
was not published in
here, but there's a lot
of good stuff there.
If you wanna go take a look
at that, if you're interested
in this part of the talk
you wanna go take a look,
there's great information there.
But probably most importantly
like language matters
as we've seen before in
open source use as well.
Most laws are not serious,
we're gonna get to that.
And of course there's
a large variance across open
source use by applications.
So let's get to that first question
and that just asks
third-party libraries like
how many are you using?
So if we take a typical
application off the shelf
and say like how many libraries
do you actually import?
The answer of course is highly variable.
So there are some JavaScript
applications that we looked
at the have thousands of libraries.
And as I said before, this
is not totally surprising.
If you'll remember there was a debacle
a few years ago concerning
a library called left-pad.
And it was a library that has
single function it pads out
a string on the left side of the string.
And developer pulled it
off the package repository,
the node package repository
and broke alert number
of applications because
people were relying
on this very simple one function library.
And that's kind of what the
culture around JavaScript
and the ecosystem of JavaScript is.
Very small functionality
packaged up in a library.
And that leads to high
numbers of life or use
when you build these applications.
Now if you go down to something
say like Python, where
the libraries tend to be
larger, more functionality.
We get kind of lower numbers
of imports, lower number
of requirements to get pulled in.
So, 16 is kind of typical but
all the way up into dozens.
And as you can see, there's
a large variability across all of these.
And a lot of applications
have several orders,
there could be several orders
of magnitude difference
between different applications.
And so, like once we've
seen all those libraries
the next question we might
wanna ask is how exactly
are those libraries getting
into the application.
Are they coming in because
the developer saying
yes, I need that library.
Or, is it kind of this more of a backdoor
this transitive dependency where a library
has actually called another library, which
has called another library, which
has called another library
as I said it's libraries all
the way down.
And so we call those
transitive dependencies, things
that come in based on other library calls.
So we wanted to look at, so
for each application look
at kind of the balance
between those two types
of dependencies direct and transitive.
So we did as we classified
each application is either kind
of direct heavy, transitive
heavy or balanced.
And we broke this up into thirds.
And again, we can see a huge
difference based on language.
For .Net, almost all applications
are really direct dependency heavy.
About 90% of applications
almost, the vast majority
of includes are direct.
And again, down at the bottom
there Ruby and JavaScript
these kinds of web based languages
a lot of those dependencies
are transitive.
So you have these big trees that go out
and all the transitive libraries come in
and give you that weight.
And so this makes a difference
because if you are looking
at it from a security
standpoint and you wanna know
where flaws are coming in.
There may be a lot that are included
that you're not directly including.
So, you may hear about a flow
on an open source library
and you think ah, I don't
use that in my application
but it might be getting
sucked in through some
of your other dependencies.
So it really is something
to think about it
is that, it's not just
what you've used it's
what you use uses and so on down the line.
So what kind of exposure does
this actually give applications?
And this leads us to the question
is more libraries really more problems.
And the answer is yeah, generally
but it doesn't have to be.
So what this graphic shows
again, broken out by language
because again, we know that
makes a lot of difference
is on the horizontal axis is the number
of libraries included in the application.
And, as we said before this can be up into
the thousands depending on the language.
And the vertical axis is the
number of flaws introduced
by those libraries.
So, and this is only open-source
laws we're not talking
about homegrown flaws.
This is the stuff that
the library brings with it
when it gets included in the application.
And think there could be
a lot said on each segment
of this graph but, it's
important to point out that we do
have this kind of it's
linear but on a log log scale
so sort of a power law relationship
for languages like Java
and JavaScript Python in particular.
And we can why that's the
case, why it scales like that
is they're some interesting questions.
But I think one of the big
takeaways here is yes, generally
if you include more
libraries you're increasing
that risk surface you may have
more flaws, but it doesn't
have to be.
So in particular if you look at kind
of the lower left corner
of the blob in JavaScript,
you'll see that there are applications
that have thousands literally
thousands of libraries,
with only one or two flaws
induced by those libraries.
And so if you've got this huge
ecosystem that you're pulling
into your application, it
may still be manageable
if you're doing the right
things in the background
to manage those flaws.
And the same thing can be said for a lot
of these other applications.
You know the lower
right-hand corner of Java
there's applications with
hundreds of libraries,
almost no flaws.
.Net has a lot of libraries with no flaws
and so you can manage this issue.
So, the next thing we
wanted to ask is like
how dangerous are these flaws?
And we wanted to kind
of build up a hierarchy
of how rare they are and
how important they are.
So you can think of this bar
graph is kind of like a funnel.
So at the top, it's the
number of the percentage
of applications that have just kind
of any open source library that has a flaw
and that flaw is still open.
And what I mean by open
is it means the developer
hasn't addressed it in any way.
It's possible to have an
application that has a flaw
and the developer says I'm
not gonna worry about it.
Close it, don't worry about it.
But what we see is if you
include open-source libraries
you're really likely to
have at least one flaw.
So when the question is,
how much should I worry
about in a particular flaw?
Well, turns out about 50%
of applications have flaws
that have a proof of concept.
And the way we figured
this out as we partnered
with Kenna security and
got some of their data.
And they have information on
when a particular library has
a vulnerability, has there
been a proof of concept
that exercises that
vulnerability published.
So about half applications go have that.
So the next level down is
worrying about well, it has
a proof of concept but is our
attackers actually using it.
And that's not 25%.
So that is proof of concept
and we've seen it exploited
in the wild.
And so, about a quarter of
applications have this kind
of higher level.
And then last there's one piece
of information another piece
of information we get
from Veracode, which is
is that library on the executable path?
So, is the flaw that's included in
that library actually able to
be exercised by an attacker.
Now this is a lower bound
cause it is impossible
to say exactly whether every
floor is reachable or not
in the code base, but it does
give us an idea that actually
this is pretty rare.
So having a flaw in a library
that is being exploited
in the wild and is accessible by attackers
is only 1% of flaws.
So that's good news for us, right.
So even if you have hundreds
or thousands of flaws,
this gives us a to kind
of look at prioritization
and think about which ones
we should address first.
Now, that begs the question
like how should we address them?
And of course, the easiest
answer is you just update things.
So, in particular we wanted
to look at is how hard it
is to update a library to
a version without a flaw
and what kind of a big jump that was in
the semantic versioning sense.
And the great thing is more
than 80% of library flaws can
be can be resolved by
just updating the library.
And that update is really
small like, less than 2.1 less
than that minor version.
Now so about 20% you're all
gonna have to jump from 1.0
to 2.0, but that will
depend on the application.
Hopefully it doesn't break the workflow
and you can find a way around that.
So, I know there are some
of you out there who might
be scoffing and saying
like hey, it is never
of course that easy.
Once you update the library
that may introduce new flaws
and then those new
flaws have to be updated
and then you're in this endless cycle.
So we took a minute to try to
think about what those cycles
could look like and what the
chain of updates can look like.
And so we came up with five
classes two of which ended
in a final update one is a
single step and one's multi-step.
You can do the same thing
and kind of not end up with
a version that doesn't
have any kinds of flaws.
Either there isn't one available
or you take a few steps
to get there.
And then there's this rare
thing that actually came out
in the data that we had to look for.
Which was is there a circular update?
So sometimes the recommendation
when there's a flaw
is that you should kind
of downgrade and go to
a previous version.
But if you do that and
that version still has
a flaw you may go down the train
a little bit before you jump back.
So, just looking at like how often each of
these occur we get some more good news.
So most of the time, two
thirds of the time you
can fix flaws with one or
several steps broken up
to about one third, one
third, so that's great.
So most of the time you
can get to that end point
where you're including a
library with no known flaws.
And then those circular updates
those bad ones that kind of
are the most complicated and
icky are a vanishingly small
about half a percent.
So we're lucky on that end.
We wanted to do kind of a more
complex breakdown of thinking
about kind of where these
things fall in this bar graph.
So if we think about
these different classes
and where the the size
of the versions end up.
Because I did tell you that,
you know 80% are minor patch
or smaller but that may not
be the case for these kinds
of update chains so we wanted
to look at that as well.
And it turns out that
actually most of the updates
are still pretty small.
So again, a good percentage
of flaws are just
a pretty small update.
And then two thirds of those, end up in
a clean state once you've
done enough updates.
But the nice part is
75% of those two thirds
are still minor version or
less, minor version of patch.
And so we do get this nice
even though you may go down
this update chain, it's
still gonna be small.
You're still not gonna do
too much and so we can kind
of fix open source.
And and thinking about open
source we've given you a lot
of detail, but that's a
practice for developers to kind
of look at and be thinking about
as they're developing their apps.
And so to break that down
and kind of talk tie all
the things that we've talked
about today together,
I'm gonna throw it back
to my colleague, Jay.
- All right, thanks Ben.
We're gonna get into the
really fun part of this
and talk about nature
versus nurture and the type
of attributes and aspects of
development in applications
that will contribute to either faster
or slower remediation times.
So the first problem we
have is trying to measure
how fast flaws are getting
fixed when we talk about
that time aspect.
And what we see is that the
one of the super easy ways
is the looking at the top line here where
this is a distribution of flaws
and that we're we're closed.
And this is a really easy way
to say how long does it take
to close something where
you can look at everything
that's closed and figure
out the median is 86 days.
The problem with that, is
that when you start with
a whole list of flaws you
don't know which one of those
are gonna be closed and
then you have to consider
the bottom line here which
is the open findings.
And essentially these
are flaws that were found
and are still open and the
median open time here is 216 days
and getting longer.
So, the question is are the
flaw that you see at day zero
is that gonna be part of the
closed findings and closed
on average of 86 days,
or is it gonna stay open
for over six, seven months on average?
And so the challenge is
you can't just look at
the close you have to account
for these open findings.
And you do that through a set
of techniques sort of under
the umbrella term of survival analysis.
And so with that we can take a look at all
of the flaws even the
ones that are still open
and account for them, in the
probability that something will
be fixed in some time period.
And so when we take a
look here on the top left
this is where a hundred
percent of these flaws
are still open.
And so in the first roughly what, 32 days
the first month roughly about
one in four of those flaws
will be closed.
And so what we're seeing
is in that first month,
a lot of activity the line is
really steep coming in there.
And what we get is about
one in four being closed.
Now it takes another
five months after that
to get to half.
So you can see the slope of
that line is flattening out
a little bit and we get about
half the flaws are fixed
in the first six months.
And conversely, after
six months half of them
are still open.
And so it's concerning right, but we see
this line flattening out.
And it takes over a year and
a half to get to the next 25%,
where one in four flaws still
remain open after a year
and a half.
And so we see this
remediation, we see a lot
of flurry up front.
We see it go in the first
month a lot, quarter of them
are being closed and it
starts to slow down from there
and then year and a
half later we still have
a quarter of them are open.
So there's some things we
can look at like for example,
if we look at the rate
of scanning how often
is code scanning performed and
what kind of a feedback loop
are we seeing?
And in fact when we see applications
that scan very infrequently
what we see is that median
if I go back here the
average is about six months.
What we see for the applications
that are scanning 12
or less times we're seeing
about 217 days which is
what about 30 35 days
faster that are slower
than the average.
But then you see applications that
are scanning roughly daily
for every Workday over
260 times in a year.
And we see those with an
average of 62 days closing half
of their flaws, which is a
dramatic difference here, right.
So we see a huge shift.
Now, what we wanted to do was to take all
of these factors together,
put them into a model and see
what they did to remediation time.
And so we ended up
gathering a bunch of factors
of development applications,
the organizations they're in
and we throw them all into
a model and they sort of fit
into these two categories
of nature versus nurture
hence the analogy here.
So, you talk about the nature
of applications you've got
the size of the organization.
you know, generally
larger organizations have
more communication paths,
a lot more complexity
then you get the age of
the application how big
is that application?
Is it complex and large or
sort of small and lightweight?
The flaw density typically
known as security debt.
And then on the nurture
of applications we've got,
how often is it being scanned?
Is that scan cadence steady or is
it really bursty right
around the last step of
a waterfall method?
And then do we see other
aspects of security?
Or do they do in dynamic
scans along with static?
Are they doing SCA scanning?
It's the software composition analysis.
They have an API integration
in other words, it's part of
their continuous integration
and they're part of like
a code check-in is
hitting the API and doing
this code scanning.
When we see all of that this
is the output that we see.
We see this the some very
simple bar chart that has
a whole bunch of
complexity on the back end.
So we see things like at
the top here, DAST with SAS.
So the dynamic with static
that gets much quicker
and this is not saying
that scanning dynamic will
cause any of this it's
just saying, I think what
this is saying is that
teams that are dedicated
to security are gonna close
things faster and they're gonna
have dynamic scanning and
they're gonna use the API
and they're gonna have SCA
all of those contribute
to faster things.
That's largely probably some
other attribute of that team
that's really investing in security.
But we do see frequent scanning
where you're scanning very steady those
are also contributing.
And what we see on the
on the negative side
are things like the flaw density
that's the bottom one here.
Roughly 63 days slower when you
go up one standard deviation
of your flaw density.
If you remember in the beginning
we had those distributions
if you go one standard deviation off
of normal, you're gonna go
six to three days slower.
Conversely if you get that
flaw density below average,
you're gonna be 63 days quicker if you're
a standard deviation above
with less flaw density.
Larger applications, more
complex lot of things in there.
And if we look at the
survival curve at the very
that yellow one is basically
bad nurture, bad nature.
You know, poor action, poor environment.
But when you start shifting
it and you get over
to that very dark one where
you've got good actions
you're doing all the good
things and you've got
a good environment, you've
got lightweight applications.
You're gonna have a lot
faster remediation times
and that's what bears out in the data.
So let's jump into the takeaways.
One of the first things
is to sort of absorb
this I mean, like the
bar chart that we talked
about the nature versus nurture there's
a lot of stuff in there
And think about your own
applications and what you see.
And then so for example, the
big things were security debt
and the large application
so consider splitting up
large legacy applications
You know, look at
microservices look towards
maybe spinning up some
different teams trying
to split that out more.
Try to drive down that flaw
density too so really go after
that technical debt you
wanna try and get some of
these really bloated applications down
and really close those up.
And you want to improve
that feedback cycle, we talked about that.
So if you can get a team that's invested
in security you wanna give
them the tools to do that
and that's gonna be more
in variety of scanning,
more tools to get more views
and perspectives on that.
And that's gonna be really, really helpful
and you don't have to go
commercial there's plenty
of open source options here too.
And then, just make sure
that this is part of
the pipeline you don't wanna
bolt this on afterwards.
You wanna make sure that
as code gets checked in,
as you're going through that pipeline
that security is part
of that whole pipeline
and integrated into that.
And with that, we will wrap up
and open it up for questions
and thank you very much for your time.