- Welcome to the session
Patterns for Encryption in Hybrid Cloud.
My name is Mark Buckwell.
I'm a Cloud Security Architect
working in IBM to help
clients move to cloud.
First of all, what we're gonna do is
get a bit of context
as to why encryption is
important for hybrid clouds.
We have both on-premise
and we have multiple clouds
in most organizations.
And so it's not just a simple
solution of creating
one solution that will,
for cloud and one solution
for each of the different data centers.
So, what we need to do is
create a hybrid solution.
And so we're gonna go and talk about
how we build that hybrid
solution for hybrid cloud.
First of all, we're
gonna talk about context.
So one day all application workloads
will be hosted in the cloud.
That's the vision that's,
organizations have.
So, what we want is
all the applications to be
delivered in an agile way
to be faster than our competitors
and for that cloud to scale,
so that's, we only pay for
what we need in clouds.
And ultimately we want to
all of those on-premise data centers
all that legacy
infrastructure to disappear.
But today only 20% of the
workloads that are on-premise
have been moved to clouds.
So we've got a long way to go.
But one of the things that's stopping us
is the protection of data.
As we bring that data into
cloud, what's happening is
we're correlating and
consolidating that data together.
The value of the data goes up and also
the bots, the organization
can get out of that data
in terms of the insights
is also increasing.
But as the value increases
to the organization
becomes more critical to the
operation of the organization.
It also means that the hackers
the threat actors out there
also are willing to spend more time
they're spending months may maybe
a year trying to get in
and go and get that data.
And what we've seen from the
SolarWinds breaches is that
they spent, they came
in and September, 2019
the breach was discovered
in December, 2020.
So they have quite a while
getting access to the
data in organizations.
And we still don't know
the full impact of that today.
So protecting data becomes
more and more important.
So we have a lot of challenges
in trying to protect that data.
What we're finding is that
organizations are very resistant to move
very sensitive data to cloud,
because they have a concern that,
that data will not be
protected in the right way.
And so what do we need to do
to protect data sufficiently in cloud?
Well, we need to encrypt it.
Well, we all told that,
but we also need that
encryption to be effective.
We need it to be trusted and we need it,
that's encryption and key
management infrastructure to be
resilient in particular
because that infrastructure
is needed to make that data available.
So what do we mean by
encryption needs to be effective,
trusted, and resilient?
Well, to be effective,
we need to go and think
about our normal CIA triad,
confidentiality, integrity
and availability.
And we think that the
way of doing that is just
will encrypt at rest.
And that's the simple
answer that's, in clouds.
But unfortunately that
doesn't solve the problem.
And I'll talk about, more
about the risks as we move on.
We also need that
infrastructure to be trusted
because cloud is multi-tenants,
it's shared between other people.
And if there's a
vulnerability in that data
our data may leak to other clients.
And if the key management infrastructure
the encryption infrastructure,
is not trusted maybe some other client
can get access to our keys
and get access to our data.
So it needs to be trusted.
And finally it needs to be resilient
because the keys that you store
as part of that encryption
are stored centrally.
And if you give somebody
access to both the primary keys
and you give them access
to the backups as well
and if you were to lose all of those keys
you lose all your data.
An organization doesn't
exist at that point
because an organization relies on data.
So we need it to be effective,
trusted, and resilient.
So what we're going to do is talk through
sets of risks, five risks that
I think you should be thinking about.
I'm going to talk about some
architectural principles
two principles that I
suggest you start with.
I'm sure you're gonna
come up with many others.
I'm gonna talk about the cloud
basic components of both
on-premise and cloud.
So that will help you
to understand how, what
those components are
and how you can use them.
I'll also talk about,
then build up a series
of encryption and key management patterns
that will take you from using
cloud managing on-premise
from the cloud
and then eventually removing
your on-premise data centers.
So we're gonna talk through that.
Now throughout the session,
if you have any questions,
please put that into the chats
and I'll be answering through throughout.
And then at the end, we're
gonna talk about what's next?
What can you do with the
outcome of this session?
So talking about the first risk.
Well, the first risk that
people are thinking about is
loss of that storage the
physical or virtual storage.
So if the disks were pulled
out of the system in the cloud,
or the virtual server was
moved to another clouds,
just copied, could I
make use of that data?
Could it get access to it?
Or the storage was reused by another
person, another user of the cloud.
So on what we do is we
encrypt at rest the storage
and what we try to do is use our own keys
so that even the cloud provider
couldn't get access to
the data in the cloud.
But that doesn't fix the second risk.
It doesn't fix the second risk
because you're thinking about
disclosure or modification
of that data in the cloud.
So what we're going to do is,
what we need to do is think about,
well, if I'm a privileged user
or I'm a hacker getting onto the system
who's a privileged user, I
still have access to that data.
So what we need to do
is to be able to encrypt
the structured data
that's sitting in the database
or we need to encrypt the structured data
unstructured data, sitting
on the file system.
So, and that's all about
protecting for privileged users
and really the inside of risk.
So there is no need for
you as a privileged user
to get access to that data
and potentially to go
and disclose that data.
Next, we have three other risks.
They're all related to resilience.
So the infrastructure that
we've got needs to be resilient
because if I lose all the
keys, I lose my business.
So that's a risk three.
The second one is more
about, okay, so I'm resilient
but if I want to recover
that infrastructure
is it going to take five
minutes, two hours, or two days?
So we still need, a route to
recover that infrastructure
in a timely manner.
And if we have the infrastructure
spread, for example,
the HSMs that I'm gonna talk about,
if they're on-premise and your encryption
is in the cloud you've got to ensure that,
that's connectivity between
the two different locations
is in place.
And if we can remove that dependency
then we can remove the amount of time
that's needed to recover
in the event of a disaster.
So it's another thing to think about.
And finally, what's in certain markets,
particularly in financial services,
the regulators are
concerned that the data is,
and the services are all going towards
one or two clouds vendors.
Now, if that cloud vendor fails,
then a significant part of the
financial services market fails
and there is a significant risk to
the overall economy of a country.
So what they're trying
to do is to make sure
that there is a spread of
risk around the industry.
And as things change over time, they want
the financial services organizations
to be able to move that data rapidly
without compromising our data.
So leaving it encrypted
and moving it from one cloud to another.
So those are the five risks
we're going to talk about in this session.
So let's think about the
two architectural principles
that I'd like to go and cover.
At the bottom of this stack
you'll see different levels of encryption.
At the bottom, you'll see
encryption of storage.
Normally there are hard disks there,
self-encrypting drives that are very fast
and really happen as a part
of the cloud infrastructure.
The one that's more interesting probably
to you is the volume of block storage
because that's normally has,
can be used the key of the client,
that's using that cloud infrastructure.
I still very fast,
it's two or 5% of the
overall CPU of the cloud,
but it allows you to use your own keys.
So that's, even if that's,
the VMs or the storage
was moved elsewhere the
cloud provider doesn't
and anybody else doesn't
have access to that data.
And it's very fast,
so that meets
mitigates risk one that
we talked about earlier,
it's high performance
and we recommend that
you encrypt low and broad
which means you encrypt everything,
because it's just easy, you
turn the keys and it works
because everything's encrypted.
It has no impact on the applications
because it's transparent
and it does have some
operational impacts in terms of
restoring for backups, because
you have to think about,
well how I
do the backups now, how do I restore them
back to the same states, if
I want an individual file,
but it really has a low
impact in terms of operations.
Now, if we want to do with risk two,
we want to encrypt the files
or the folders to prevent
the privileged users from
getting access to that data.
But the problem is that,
if I've got thousand files,
I might end up with a thousand keys
and that's a lot of keys to go and manage.
And when you build an infrastructure
with tens of thousands of servers
and millions of files and millions of,
perhaps databases, not
millions of database,
but hundreds of databases, but
you're building large infrastructures
you're gonna end up with
a large number of keys.
So what you tend to do is
do this follow the second
principle that says
encrypt selectively.
So what you will do is
only encrypt the data
existing in files and
databases that really are,
have an impact.
They have sensitive data
in terms of personal data
or they have a high impact
in terms of disclosure.
So, and that's,
prevents privileged users
from getting access.
And what you want to do is limit it
to the real critical data because
that will have an overhead
in terms of the management.
So you don't want to,
if the cost of managing encryption exceeds
the cost of the value
of the data, then you,
you probably shouldn't be doing it.
And finally, at the top
level, we've got applications.
So we'll find, again, financial
services we're back to that.
They often encrypt specific
financial services transactions.
So that's a high level as well.
So let's think about the architecture
for the encryption and
key management system.
In on-premise, we traditionally
have three components
we will have a hardware security module.
We'll have key manager and
an encryption capability
that does the encryption.
In the HSM, we have a master key,
that master key can never leave the HSM.
The only way of making
use of that master key
is to go and send a key
or data to that HSM.
And that's how we have a
trusted infrastructure.
So that HSM
is the core of the
encryption infrastructure.
So we can guarantee that
no individual can get access
to the encryption keys
and therefore encrypt the data.
We have the key management server
that will contain key encryption keys.
So the key encryption
keys that are stored there
are all encrypted using the master key
that's sitting in the HSM,
and we will have an encryption capability,
it could be a storage subsystem,
it could be something
that encrypted files
folders, databases, and so on
piece of software
and that will contain
the data encryption key
which we encrypted using
the key encryption key
that sitting in the key management server.
And we tend to go and use
this mechanic protocol
between the encryption capability
and the key management server,
and we use PKCS #11 between
the key management server
and the HSM.
So those are standard industry protocols.
So when we want to start things up
the key encryption capability says,
right I've got an encrypted
data encryption key,
I need to decrypt it,
so can you send me the key encryption key
from the key management server?
The key management server says
I only have an encrypted copy.
So I'm going to send that
encrypted copy to the HSM,
to decrypt it.
HSM will send back an
un-encrypted key encryption key,
that will be forwarded to
the encryption capability
which will decrypt the
data encryption key.
And now you can start decrypting data
and this series of
dependencies becomes a problem
when you want to go and
start things up, because,
you've got to have that
communication in place
that key encryption key
or any keys that are un-encrypted
are never stored on storage,
so they can never be recovered
that only a memory, so if you powered off,
you can't get access to them.
So that sequence is
the on-premise sequence
and is used for encrypting data.
Now in cloud it's a little different
in that the key management server
and HSM are combined together.
You end up with a rest API
that recovers that key encryption key
and that key management
server is multi-tenant.
So each used for multiple clients
and you have to trust that the event,
the cloud service provider,
that the software
they've created,
does not disclose your
keys to another client.
And it's not sufficient to go and say,
oh, hand on hearts, I'm not
gonna go and hand the keys over.
We need a way of technically
protecting the master key.
And so we'll go and talk a bit about
how we can do that in cloud.
So now we've got the components
we'll move on and talk
about the security pattern
or the architectural pattern.
So we talked about the
cloud key manager in cloud
it's multi-tenant
and it will be used to
encrypt objects, block,
VMs or hypervisors,
encrypt address data encryption at rest.
That meets the requirement for risk one,
what it doesn't do is protect the data
from disclosure to privileged users.
It also,
in cloud, we tend to go
and have multiple clouds.
So you'll have multiple clouds.
You might have Azure
for a directory service.
You might have IBM cloud to go and run
some other capabilities
and you're going to
integrate them together.
And sometimes you'll then have
key managers in those different clouds,
and they each use what they
call bring your own key.
And the interfaces they have really
allow you to load up the key as a whole.
What it doesn't do is allow
you to load up the key
parts of a key, and it
doesn't allow you to store
the master key in an HSM or
in a trusted infrastructure.
So what we tend to do is
actually use a what's called
a multi-cloud key manager.
And a multi-cloud key manager
will enable you to go and load up keys
into each of the, bring your
own key, infrastructure.
So there is no person involved
who can actually see the
keys that are being loaded.
Behind that multi-cloud key manager
is perhaps another key manager that will
have access to an HSM,
that HSM has a trustee path
that has been initialized and setup
using multiple key parts,
it's using tokens,
it's using various other
key ceremony controls
to have a trusted HSM in
an on-premise data center.
But really that helps us
managing multiple keys
as we move to cloud,
but there are two problems here.
One is, we've now got this
connection back to on-premise
which if we want to recover the cloud
potentially is a problem, or
we want to recover things,
and also we're locked
into using on-premise.
So we can never get off on-premise.
We can never get fully moved to cloud.
So how do we overcome that problem?
Well, what we'll do is
we'll have a single
tenant cloud key manager,
that cloud key manager
uses an HSM partition
fips 140-2 level 4 HSM
and you have access to that partition
using two sets of smartcards.
Set of smartcards are there to
authenticate you to the HSM.
And those smartcards mean that
multiple people have to be
part of that key ceremony.
And you'll have a set of smartcards
that whole parts of the keys.
So there might be three sets of key
cards and they each have to
go and be brought together
and by multiple people to go actually
go and initialize that HSM partition.
So now you have this trusty path
to get to an HSM in the cloud,
and only you can get to that HSM partition
and the assurance from the fips 140-2
goes and provide some assurance, that's
nobody else can get to
that because that's part of
the solution has been tested.
So the other part is
the cloud key manager.
Now that's normally multi-tenant,
but if we have a dedicated
one in a process that
you can't touch and you
can't remotely log in to it
nobody can get access
to it except through the
to reconfigure it, except
through your smartcards,
we now have a trusted
cloud key manager as well.
So now we've overcome the problem where
we don't need an HSM on-premise
because we have a trusted
part to our cloud HSM.
So that builds up that picture.
Now we still haven't dealt with
risk two which is how do I deal with
the privileged threat actors?
So we need a way of encrypting
files and folders databases.
So we need a way of doing that.
So the way in which we do that
is to add an encryption manager
the encryption manager,
can supply keys, like
a key manager as well,
but also has an agent
for files and folders.
And those files and
folders can be encrypted,
so that even if you're a privileged user
you have no access to
that data on the system.
So that's a core components
and you probably want multiple protocols
because you want KMIP that
was gonna go and deal with the
most of the infrastructures and
DPAPI which is the Microsoft
protocol that allows you
to encrypt things like
SQL databases and do
other things like that.
So that encryption manager now
is there with a multi-cloud key manager
and an HSM that has a trusty path with
a single-tenant cloud key manager.
You now have a solution
that enables you
to go and manage all the
components in the clouds.
So one of the challenges then is, well,
I've got to go and move to other clouds.
I've got to go and move
my data potentially
from one cloud to another.
And that was the exit problem.
So if I encrypt my data in one cloud
as a database, and I've got
multi terabytes of a database
I don't really want to decrypt it
because it's gonna take a
very long time to decrypt it.
And when I move it,
there's gonna be a risk that
is disclosed to somebody else.
So by using encryption manager
I can actually move the
data fully encrypted
and then pick it up in encryption manager
and then just use it as I
did before on the cloud.
So I could move my data from clouds
or from on-premise into cloud.
So that solves that risk two.
But I'm still moving my
applications to cloud.
And I still,
only 20% has moved to cloud,
so there's quite a lot more to do.
And so I've still got storage
sitting in the data center.
I've still got data that
I want to encrypt there
and then move.
So what I can do is I can
use that encryption manager
to encrypt the storage, the
storage subsystems I'm using,
so it could be NetApp or IBM, for example
it's used quite a few places
or and also the files or folders
that sitting on that
storage I can encrypt.
And now I, when I'm ready
even though it's a multi-terabyte database
I can copy that as a whole,
without decrypting it to cloud.
So I now have my control plane on cloud.
So that's the architecture as a whole
that meets the five risks that
we're trying to talk about
and gives us the journey to go and move
from on-premise and colo,
support multiple clouds,
meet the different risks in terms of
you've got the risk one in terms of
the storage and virtual image
encryption, which is fast
and I've got selective
encryption for risk two
have databases and storage.
So that's the complete architecture.
So how does that change the components
that we talked about at the beginning?
So what we've effectively
done is we've combined
the on-premise components into the cloud.
It's enabling us to go and
make use of the clouds,
single-tenant HSM.
And now we have a way of,
using those components
and bring them together.
Both with KMIP interfaces,
PKCS 11, if you want that,
and the rest APIs which tend to be
specific proprietary to each cloud.
So we also, and that's
why you also need to use
some other mechanism other than the cloud
mechanism to move data around
because of that proprietary
nature of the rest APIs.
But there is a benefit
in using that, as I said
because of speed and dependencies.
So let's talk about resilience.
So we talked about the last,
the third risk was about resilient.
If we lost that infrastructure,
we would
we still have to be able to
recover that infrastructure.
Even if we lost a multi
zone region, even if,
a single component or zone went down,
we still have to go
and have a resilient infrastructure.
So what we tend to do is
have a cloud key manager
that's resilient between an HSMs
that are resilient between the zones
and the key databases that
are stored within that
for the cloud key services,
I synchronized in real time.
And when we start that
cloud key manager up
will you be using the smartcards
to go and load the keys up?
So if I ever lost the whole MCR
I still have the key
sitting on the smart cards
and could load them up.
And in fact, I could preload those keys
into another MCR and actually
set up key managements
in another MCR.
What we also do is we
back up the keys offline
to object storage or somewhere else.
And we can do that either
at a regular interval
or a one-off when we
want to go and back it up
perhaps we've done a re-key,
we've changed all the
keys in infrastructure
and we want to do a
backup directly after that
for risk purposes.
And then for the encryption manager
does the same capability
of synchronizing the keys
between the different
infrastructures so that
I can actually move my workloads
and between those different zones.
And again, you have to
think about scheduled
and adult backups as
part of that solution.
So that's how we build resilience,
and we build the resilience, so that's,
even if there is an MCR failure,
we have a way of recovering
the infrastructure and
decrypting the data.
So finally,
what have you learned today?
I hope you that was useful
and gives you plenty of thoughts,
continue to ask questions.
But what I'm looking for you
to do is to go and think about
your current encryption and
key management solution.
Do any of the things that
I've talked about resonates
and does that solution meet those,
support mitigating those
five risks I've talked about
particularly the second risk is,
it's not just encryption of data at rest
it's encryption of data,
files, folders, databases
things that, so they are
doing it in such a way
that the privileged users
can't get access to it.
So while you're thinking about that
perhaps update your strategy
in the next three months
and therefore you can have a roadmap to
better mitigating the
risks I've talked about,
evaluate the cloud solutions
the other solutions
that can actually implement
this sort of architecture
and close the gaps.
So that's important.
But it's not just
thinking about technology.
What's the impact to the organization?
What's the impact to the team,
that's going to manage the keys?
And what I've seen is that,
often people will implement the technology
but they don't have insufficient people
to run the key ceremonies
or that all the people that
run the key ceremonies resign
and they've got no way of
recovering the infrastructure.
And so thinking about the
whole management regime
the skills of the people
and if they only perform those ceremonies
those key ceremonies very frequently
they might not know how to
do it in six months time.
So how do you keep the skills fresh?
So think about those sorts of things.
And hopefully within six months,
you've thought about
right, okay, I've got,
I know what the solution is.
I've got plan
and I'm starting to
implement and close the gaps.
And this is not just thinking
about what you've got today
but it's understanding
the overall cloud strategy
that your organization has
and how do you support them so that,
security is not the
delay for going to cloud.
It's an enabler.
So having that security
or having that encryption
and key management
software in place is an enabler.
So thank you for your time today.
And if you, as I said, if
you've got any questions
please put them in the chat,
I'll be here to answer them
after the session as well.
Thank you.