- Hello, I'm Bethan Cantrell.
And I'll be talking today
about Privacy Governance,
Threat Modeling, and
Representation and Design.
I'm joining RSAC from Redmond, Washington
the traditional land
of the Duwamish people.
While I'm going through
the presentation today
please feel free to jump
into the comments at any time
and ask any questions
or provide any observations
that you may have.
And there will probably also be time
for more discussion at the
end of the conference as well,
but certainly feel free to
express yourself as we go along.
This presentation is
broken into three sections
covering agency and privacy governance,
personal threat modeling
and decision-making
and representation and
design-side privacy.
The goal of the presentation
is not to provide end-to-end
how to guidance on ensuring
inclusive representational
service development.
This is intended as a
useful thought exercise
to help you help the data subjects
affected by the systems you work on.
Each section has a check-in
that provides a summary
reframe of it subject,
and those are listed here.
Privacy governance is important
because it supports agency.
Privacy by design on
its own is insufficient
because it doesn't know
about many of the risks.
Risks are often complex
but intuitive threat modeling
can translate into simple
adaptable procedure
and design-side privacy is representative,
representative listening systems
may drive more representative design.
First, let's talk about
agency and privacy.
Agency is a person's
independent capability
or ability to act on their own will.
When we describe people or
a person is marginalized,
we are saying that they have less agency
compared to other individuals or groups.
As we can see from history
and current events around the world,
folks who are marginalized
frequently stay marginalized
or are pushed further down because systems
whether they're a social service,
a shopping app or something else,
frequently don't acknowledge the values
or risks of marginalized people
and don't create environments
where people can make decisions
to protect their agency
or support their values and goals.
This session will
provide some connectivity
between identity, agency and privacy
in a context that can
help folks create systems
that are agency protecting
using the example of
personal threat modeling.
The attributes that make people unique
are relevant in many digital environments
from employment to participation
in online communities
whether the digital environment
or online services for work,
government services, a social
network or something else,
it needs to be implemented
so there is benefit to people
without opportunity for
individual or systematic crime.
To protect the agency, we
need to protect privacy.
Privacy governance programs are in place
to ensure that a company's commitments
are implemented in a repeatable
and verifiable manner.
Many of us work at organizations
that have implemented systems
to ensure privacy by design
and to operationalize the
company's published commitments
to certain privacy
practices such as these,
transparency choice, data minimization
and data subject rights.
Many such programs don't
just look at compliance
to existing laws or policies.
They also look for potential
harms that may not be addressed
with existing governance controls.
Again, though a relatively small group
of people identifying
those potential harms
on behalf of thousands
or millions of users
is unlikely to be consistently effective.
And while harm reducing requirements
usually do get developed eventually,
that's not always the case
and sometimes a lot of
people are harmed first.
Driving for a more
representative design process
that is employing creative
respectful methods to reduce harms
seems like a very good way to go.
Here, we'll review a
collection of media excerpts
that describe various privacy failures
where people were marginalized
for reasons related to
race, class, diverse gender
and straight up power asymmetry.
Harm may have been prevented
if the decision-making
or design group was more representative.
In the first example, Dr. Khiara Bridges
illustrates in the book
"The Poverty of Privacy Rights",
that based on the way
poor mothers are treated
in many social service organizations,
they don't have privacy by default.
Expectant mothers seeking care
are often only provided with care
if they give up an extensive
amount of information
about themselves, their history
and their family circumstances
if they don't provide that information,
they risk not receiving the care
and also they risk losing
access to their child
as social services could decide
that failure to follow through with care
indicates an unsafe environment.
In the second example,
an elementary school
and its district administrators
repeatedly decided to use an
outdoor area called the cage
to detain a young student of color
in full view of that student's classmates.
And the 3rd example, eight
LA County Deputy Sheriff
used their personal cell
phones at a crash site
to take photographs of
the deceased family.
Their behavior was not legally prohibited.
And as of this article, this
presentation being developed
that policy still had not been passed.
In the 4th example,
a survey asks a gender identity question
but then provides choices
that represent assigned sex
answers effectively erasing
some people's gender identity.
In the 5th example,
police officers arrest,
transport and detain a Black man
based solely on facial recognition
which is notoriously bad
at identifying people
the darker their skin is.
The man and his family went through
entirely avoidable trauma.
In the 6th example, we
learn about dark patterns
where design features are used
to manipulate data subjects and users
and to generating more
revenue for the service.
These articles are all linked
from the resource slide
at the end of the deck.
In this first section,
we learned that agency is our ability
to take action based on our own will.
Privacy is an increasingly
important governance area
because privacy protects agency.
Privacy governance doesn't always know
what risks to watch for
undermining agency and creating
risk in a variety of ways.
And now let's learn about threat modeling.
This slide in the next few
slides include diagrams
that are representing threat
models with different examples.
While we walk through them,
roadrunner will be making some decisions.
In those same scenarios you
make different decisions based
because you have different
lived experiences and values.
Threat models are not
literal design explanations
like blueprints for a house.
There's symbolic models with indicators
for things that need to be protected
in the context of things
that could cause risk.
When we see that modeling,
we can make better
we can better understand
what mitigations to make
for those risks.
Engineers use threat models to
make sure they've identified
and managed security risks during design.
Threat models work for technical privacy
as well as other kinds of risks
including online safety, physical safety
or other things as well.
This circle made them
an orange dashed line
represents a trust boundary.
It indicates our opportunity
to make a decision based on our awareness.
And we use it pretty intuitively.
At the park the trust
boundary may be farther out
and on a crowded sidewalk, it's closer in.
We use this intuition for other people
during suspenseful movies.
If roadrunner needed to go
through this scary looking door
the audience would be
shouting for roadrunner
to pay attention to,
for instance does the door latch work
so that the roadrunner
can get back out again?
Or is there an anvil
suspended over the doorway?
Because we have some awareness,
we have an opportunity to make decisions
based on the risks we identify
and how those risks
weigh against our goals
and our priorities.
There's this idea that IT is very complex
and we shouldn't expect data subjects
or users to understand it.
But the reality is the data subjects
don't need to understand any more with IT
than the average home owner
needs to understand plumbing.
Modeling as a tool that can
help improve that understanding.
We can break down the process
for personal threat modeling
using just a few steps.
This is a very high level set of steps.
We could go deep into the
weeds on risk assessment
with threat modeling, but
this is just an intro.
First enable timely
decisions with awareness.
Whether you're home feeling
safe at the park and relaxed
or looking at your phone
and considering whether
to install a new app
or on a crowded sidewalk,
you have some awareness
of your environment.
The trust boundary
represents your awareness
and starts big and then get smaller
when we see something
that needs attention.
In this case that same scary door
from the last slide is
what needs attention.
When something needs your attention,
identify the deciding
factors for decision-making
like whether we see an anvil.
The 3rd step is to decide
how the potential risks
weigh against your values or goals.
This is also an opportunity
to determine if there's a
way to manage those risks.
And finally take action
based on what you decided
in steps two and three.
We'll also look at a sample plan
for how folks can decide to take action
in the next few slides.
Different people will
have different outcomes
to the same issues
because they have
different values and goals
and that's okay.
This is an opportunity for people
to make their own decisions
about how they manage risks.
In this example model, roadrunner
wants to plan their day
so they look for a horse, go back.
Here's the trust boundary circle again,
a dashed orange line.
Because roadrunner cares about privacy
they are being aware and
paying attention to the app.
When roadrunner looks at the app,
they look at the information the app wants
that's listed in the UX and then noticed
and they compare that to
what the app is used for.
In this intentionally silly example
the app wants roadrunners DNA
in order to provide an
extra accurate horoscope.
roadrunner decides to use a different app.
This example model is
evaluating a messaging service
from an end-to-end perspective
because roadrunner wants to
use peer-to-peer messaging
and the confidence and
also wants the confidence
that comes from a paid service.
roadrunner expects that there will be
more data moving around
because there's payments
and also learns about code
of conduct requirements
when they read the privacy notice.
Data subjects can learn about
those additional data flows
from looking at the notice
and the user experience
and also reading the privacy statement.
Having a more extensive
data flow means that
roadrunner needs to trust
more of that service
to keep their data safe.
That means that they need
to have some expectation
that all of the components
of the data flows
have been appropriately protected
and that the organization has the maturity
and the integrity to have those kinds
of systematic protections in place.
This more extensive example model
is looking at value goals
that go along with a
complex social network
rather than at technical privacy issues.
Roadrunner wants to rejoin
a popular social network
that processes a lot of
personal information.
Roadrunner evaluates description
of social network, UX
and lands on five
concern areas to plan for
misinformation, location
privacy and safety,
conformity, bigotry and group privacy.
Again, the trust boundary
indicates awareness
and the opportunity to
look for information
before making a decision and acting on it.
We'll look at roadrunner's plan
to address these concerns
in the next slide.
Roadrunner has come up with
a set of dos and don'ts
for the risks identified
in the prior slide
and we can see them organized here.
Some of the items on these lists
may have account or profile
controls to support them.
Others rely on roadrunner
to proactively decide
how to act on his values, such
as in the conformity list,
which says do connect to
a diverse set of people
and don't create a homogenous bubble.
Or the location privacy
and safety list which says,
don't post information about
travel away from home or town,
at least until you return.
Closing out the section,
we learned the threat models
are a simple design tool
for clarifying and managing risk.
We can apply threat
models to more abstract
or complicated scenarios
like IT systems or policy,
we can threat model for
different types of risks
in different environments
especially complicated
environments like social networks.
In the next section, we'll
discuss representation,
privacy and design.
Privacy by design continues
to be a necessary component
of trustworthy data governance.
However, earlier in this deck,
we saw six broadly varied
examples of privacy failures
that could have happened
even when relevant privacy
controls are in place.
That's where design side privacy comes in.
Design-side privacy combines
diverse representation,
knowledge of technical components
and adherence to privacy principles.
With the goal of ensuring data subjects
don't experience harm, or loss of agency
as a result of using the service.
This chart shows the
relationship between risk
introduced by a service
and the critical considerations
for the design team.
Can the data subjects
understand the notice?
Is it clear how to manage choices?
As the service types become higher risk,
does the data subject know how
to protect their experience?
Do they know how to manage their choices
within the service environment?
For services where the
data subjects agency
may be directly effected
as with social services
or other projects focused
on marginalized people,
do the potential harms outweigh the value,
have all the (indistinct)
been fully mitigated, or
is there any responsibility
on the data subject to manage some risk?
Advocacy organizations do great work
representing their members
in various environments, including IT.
Disability rights
advocates have a motto of,
nothing about us without us
that aligns closely with the principles
of the design justice network.
The design justice network
continues to develop and
evangelize design principles
that work to reduce
marginalization and harm
across many different types
of service and project environments.
When a project may have tens
of thousands or even millions of users
the design team cannot be diverse enough
to represent the needs of all
the users or data subjects.
There are systems in place
to help scale these already,
such as accessibility,
governance programs,
privacy programs and others,
but developing listening systems
so that the service in no way
undermines their values or
safety can only be a good thing
especially for services
that are necessary for use
like public schools, banking,
health, or social services.
For a person to be
required to use a service
and for that service to do harm
is a harsh reality that
many people face today.
For this reason if a high-stakes service
is critical to your business,
diverse representation is also
critical to your business.
There's a lot we can
learn from data subjects.
In this case, the data subject
is relying on notice and
their own prior experience
with the service to
develop a plan of action
for how to use the social network
while also supporting
their own values and goals.
Roadrunners dos and don'ts
could be used to inform design
for privacy and media controls
and used to support the narrative
of why those changes are
beneficial to a larger group
rather than just to roadrunner.
Going back to some of the examples
we saw of privacy failures,
how might data subjects have helped
inform more respectful
services for expectant mothers,
more care in the treatment
of kids in schools
or in the use of gender
identity and surveys?
As I noted earlier in the presentation
this is not a how to, or a case study
for setting up a listening system
based on a representative
number of personal threat models
for various service environments.
The goal has been to frame a clear message
that people from
people benefit from knowing
how to use modeling for decision-making
and that it's beneficial for organizations
to have this kind of insight
from a representative
cross sample of people
so they can build a service
that doesn't do harm.
In this section, we learned that
representative design
becomes more important
when a service of any type
becomes more sensitive
and or critical to safety and wellness.
Information from the listening system
must augment the existing expertise
of our own diverse design,
development, legal and governance teams.
How a listening system is designed
can vary based on the
implementing organization
and the participants
we just need to make sure it's respectful.
How might a data subject
driven listening system
look for your projects?
Thank you for your time
during this discussion.