- Hi everyone.
And welcome to
"Piñata Time: Why We Should
All Start Bashing Mules!"
It's a panel and I'd like to welcome
our panelists for today.
Starting with Stacie Purcell from Citi.
Stacie's SVP Fraud Policy from Citibank.
Hi Stacie.
Hey, good day.
- Andy Collins, Financial Crime
Executive from Wells Fargo.
- Howdy.
- And we have Paul Gardner,
Manager in Financial Crime
in Suncorp from Australia.
- Hi, how are we doing?
- And folks, if you have any questions
to the panelists or to myself
you can use Pigeonhole,
this application to ask
interactive questions,
and we'll do our best to answer them
during the live broadcast for this panel.
So let's kick it off.
And of course, we're
going to talk about mules.
There are many types of mules,
and I think before we actually
start the mule typology
and discussing those
specific types of mules,
at the end of the day,
every type of financial crime,
you know, you have to think
about where am I moving
my money to, right?
I'm not going to send money to myself.
I need some sort of account.
This might be a collaborator
like a human collaborator.
This might be an account that I opened
under someone else's
name, but in any case,
those are the new accounts
that we're going to talk about.
And we're going to focus on fraud.
So financial fraud and mules,
they're related to that.
And, this is essentially just
to kick the conversation off,
a little bit of a typology that looks
at account opening
versus existing accounts.
So in account opening,
you typically want to fight
several types of fraud.
You want to fight deposit account fraud,
meaning an account, like
a bank account is opened,
and money is deposited to that account.
Credit or loan account fraud.
Meaning I opened an account
and instantly I have access to credit.
First Party Fraud is, "I'm, you know,
"trying to defraud the bank myself",
but look at this intersection
with money mules,
Mule Account Opening, meaning
I'm opening an account,
not because I want to
do instantly some fraud
but I want to use that account
for any type of fraud that will follow on.
And then you have the existing accounts.
We talk about unwitting mules,
and professional mules or witting mules.
So lots of different types of mules.
And maybe before we move
further into the conversation,
let's just describe the sort
of mules that you guys are seeing
and how they're different from each other.
Stacie, we'll start with you.
- Sure. Yeah.
Thanks Uri.
So before COVID, before the
pandemic really kicked off
I think, you know, you saw
more of the unwitting mules.
You had a few professional mules
mixed in there, but I think
with the pandemic we've
seen, what is, I would say,
you know, kind of an
onslaught of a new kind
of mule that's really targeting
the government programs.
So your unemployment insurance,
the economic impact
disaster loans in the US.
Just, there's those programs
that are really just
have been created to get as
much money into the hands
of the people who really
need it as quick as possible.
And these mules, it's really
kind of migrated from a
a small social media type
of effort to get people
to open up accounts for
the use of being a mule,
to really just these large scale rings.
So I think there's been a
big shift with the pandemic
to really move from those
romance scam unwitting mules,
your one-off, you know, business email
compromise recipient mule
account to just large scale
targeted mule account openings,
leveraging stolen PII to
really get their hands
on the pandemic funds.
So I think across the industry,
that's really what we're seeing
especially in the United States.
- Andy, what is your perspective on this?
- Yeah, well, I echo
what Stacie said, Uri.
I would also add that,
you know, the weaknesses
of the government were
pretty much put on display
during COVID, but also
because the fraud actors were
doing the same things
that we were seems like,
they were locked down as we all were.
They spend a lot of
time on online type of,
you know, businesses.
So, we're seeing intentional
mule account openings as well.
The accounts that are being used for fraud
for these third-party
businesses, for an example,
we had a common issue with a few large
property rental firms.
And what the fraud actor was,
kind of had a two-part story.
One was they had a fake property owner
and then the second is
that they had fake renters.
And then the fake property
owner who actually a fraud,
who actually opened a mule account
with our bank and with others.
And then it's used for two things.
The first thing it's used
for is to validate the
fraudulent property owner themselves.
And then once that account
is validated, the fraud actor
then makes fake rental deposits
and moves the money out
before he runs into a
bad credit card deposit,
because it actually comes back.
And so they have pointed that
there's inherent weaknesses
in third parties as well, and
we're starting to see those
in the mule account is one
way to get the money moving.
- Okay, great.
Hey, Paul, what sort of mules
do you see in Australia?
- Yeah, so echoing both
Stacie and Andy's points.
We see both the account opening mules.
So mules that are facilitating
audit takeover and opening
up an account to receive
fraudulently obtained funds,
both from our own customers,
but also from other
financial institutions,
or other sources of wealth.
But we also see a small number,
less and less all the
time of recruited mules.
So those that might be
an existing customer
that have been recruited to siphon
out scan funds or other
funds that have been
obtained by the fraudsters.
- Right.
And what's the split more
or less from, you know,
from your perspective in Australia?
Is it more account opening
or witting or unwitting existing mules?
- Yeah, so having a rerun
on the stats the other day,
we can see that more than 90%
of our mule accounts are kind of new-
- Okay, so newly opened accounts,
rather than trying to
go after existing folks.
10 years ago, by the way, or 12 years ago,
during the economic
crisis, there was a lot
of recruitment going
on globally, you know,
in the US, in Australia, et cetera.
And account opening was a non-issue.
So, like just in like 10 or 12 years,
it flipped almost entirely
and account opening
is now the main thing
from your perspective.
Stacie, what sort of statistics
do you see in the US?
- Yeah, no, I, I think it's probably
on par with what our counterparts
in Australia are seeing.
The majority of our mules
at this point in time,
even just from a year ago, right?
Or let's not go a year ago, we'll go back,
let's say 18 months ago,
right, before the pandemic,
I think banks in the US had a mule problem
but they were existing
mules or unwitting mules.
Right, so you had your unwitting
mules that had kind of been
on your books probably at
least 12 months or more,
that you would get
notified by the other FIs
that there were some
fishy activity going on.
But I think in the last
nine, 12 to nine months here,
nine to 12 months,
we've seen that shift to
account opening is where it's at, right?
The breaches in the
industry have just opened
up doors to these fraudsters
to open up these accounts.
And, you know, it's shifted our focus
like you said, right, for years?
On the credit side,
there was this, you know,
a lot of emphasis on
understanding identity theft and
and synthetic identities
and really jumping on the,
you know, the account opening fraud train.
But on the bank side, you
know, our focus has always
been third party, right?
Third party fraud.
Yeah, our job has been to make
sure that that person sitting
down at that device is our client, right?
And we've invested millions upon millions
of dollars to ensure we have
the right controls there.
And it's not just on our rear, rights?
It's changed our focus immensely to say,
"We've got to stop.
"We've got to stop the mules."
And, really it's game
of whack-a-mole, right?
It's like you shot one down and
then you gotta go over here.
It's quite insane to
see how it shifted, Uri.
- Folks, if you were sitting
on the advisory board
of a cyber crime syndicate
and, you know, basically
your role is to consult,
would your commit to investing
in account opening mules
or trying to recruit existing mules?
What would be your
advice to the syndicate?
Andy, maybe we'll start with you.
- Yeah. Yeah.
I think, I would do what the rest of the
the fraud actors are doing.
And I would focus in on
the account opening and
and the reason for that is
because, well, first of all
there's enough PII out in, you know,
the environment to be able
to use either bad information
or even my own information
for that matter.
But there's so many inherent weaknesses
with third parties and
government and so forth
that I mentioned that are
just now being discovered.
And, to me, rather than to
have to recruit somebody
and go through that, the time
that it takes to actually
have somebody come onboard
and be a unwitting mule,
and then or maybe even account takeover.
Why not just go ahead and attack some
of these inherent weaknesses
that are very evident.
And I think that's what's happening.
This is a whole brave new world
for a lot of fraud actors
that are now just seeing
that the, you know, the
businesses that are being set
up for online and also
for government especially,
that they're just lots of opportunity
to be able to defraud them.
- By the way, you folks are coming from
large financial organizations,
some of the smaller banks,
can really suffer from such a trend.
Because if you think about it,
like if a small organization
let's say a new digital bank et cetera,
is being hit by a gang that
wants to open multiple accounts,
that's going to be problematic for them.
There was a case in California
a year and a half ago
or two years ago where it
was a new digital bank.
They had more or less like
100 new applications per day.
And all of the sudden it jumped to 1,000!
And they said,
"Hey, finally the marketing
team is doing something!"
No, it's an attack.
You have 100 good users and you have
900 bad users every day.
Now it might be deposit fraud,
but it can also be opening new accounts.
Interestingly enough, it
wasn't that it was some sort of
bot account opening,
like, it wasn't automated,
it was a human being,
probably a single person
that was opening 900 applications per day.
So that's essentially
something that can almost
like cripple a new financial organization
or small financial organization,
because you can really cope
with those sort of numbers.
If you have 100 good users,
you have 900 bad users,
you probably have to
stop receiving new users
or maybe stop moving money out, you know,
going out of the bank
or something like that.
So definitely the small
banks are also suffering.
Do we have any specific
interesting news stories, Stacie,
maybe you can share one of yours.
- Sure. Yeah, no, I've got
lots of them, Uri (laughing).
So, you know, in the
past, you know, I had lots
of great stories about
business email compromise.
You know, mules that
we've had and you know,
how we've been, you know,
the stories never match,
and when you ask for answers,
right, they're very colorful.
But, you know, during the pandemic,
as we started to see the surge
of unemployment insurance
payments from multiple states
coming into one account or SBA idle loans
coming into consumer bank accounts, right?
Which isn't the norm.
I'm not saying they're all fraud
but there's a lot of fraud in that
in that piece or
opportunity there as well.
But what we started to see was in this,
in kind of the dark web and
what people were hitting
individuals up to do these
mule account openings,
and then obviously
target the unemployment.
Get the money in, move
the money out as quickly
as they could through Cash App,
Square, Zelle, any PTP, right,
debit card transactions.
Just get the money out
as quickly as you can.
But then the guidance
that they were given was,
then go ahead and file a dispute.
So file a reggy dispute against
your financial institution,
you'll get that money back in
provisional credit right away,
take that money and run, right?
So with your leveraging,
it's one thing when
you're leveraging your own
information to open an account
and can commit this type of
activity, but, especially
if you're using stolen PII,
you could care less, right?
So we just started to see the surge
of this incoming mule
activity, dispute claims,
giving them provisional credit,
and then we never hear
from them again, right?
And obviously it turns out, you know, we
should've never given
them provisional credit,
and this was an industry
wide thing, right?
It wasn't just one FI,
everybody was seeing it.
And, what was even crazier is, you know,
you didn't realize, this was
very early on in the pandemic
when we were all kind of
trying to get our hands around
what we were dealing with.
We started to do the link analysis.
And when you started to look at, you know,
just what was logging
in to your accounts from
all over the world, you
would have one user who had
27 different devices
logging into that account,
checking the balances.
So, you just realize how
large this network was
of just how many people,
what was in play here.
And this was just the beginning, right?
We're talking April of last year.
So it was just kind of
the, you know, that double,
you know, what do they call it?
Like the left hook, right?
It kinda, it stung because, you know,
it's bad enough that
they're stealing money
from the government and as
a US taxpayer, that hurts.
But then to see them turn around and
hurt the bank on top
of it, needless to say,
we put the kibosh on
that relatively quickly.
But it was definitely a new
spin from a mule perspective.
Maybe not as sexy as some of
the business email
compromise stories, Uri,
but certainly a different spin
that we weren't expecting.
- Paul, any interesting
stories from your end?
- Yeah, so in Australia, we've
seen significant evidence
of mules being recirculated
across the institutions,
and predominantly what we saw
in the last eight months
to two years is a number
of mules are opening up
accounts across different banks.
And the reason they were doing that is to
hop the funds and create
a distance between
the originating account to
to obviously the exit point.
And, you know, one of the
things that we found through
collaborating with our
peers in the industry
is financial crime
detection is not competitive
with a significant number of mules.
Many of which had the same attributes.
And one of the benefits we got from that
was actually a benefit
for one of our costumes.
We had 90 year old lady
who was a victim of a scam
and because we'd identified
a number of mule accounts
opened by the same offenders,
we were able to stop the funds
basically her life savings from exiting.
And so that had a real
benefit and that came
as a result of that, you know,
that collaboration across
those institutions,
but also by recognizing that, you know,
the MO was becoming
more and more prominent
through that online origination channel.
- Excellent.
Andy, any stories from your side?
- Oh yeah. There's a
story a minute, sadly.
I think one that I'll relay
to you is a very, very, very,
large search engine company (laughing).
They had a situation
where, you know, ourselves
and other major financial
institutions started
getting a very high velocity
of small dollar deposits
and that very very large
search engine company is also,
as we would expect, a marketing company.
And so they pay
individuals, you know, click
for click revenue, click ads.
So that type of velocity perhaps was not
necessarily something they didn't expect.
Well, all of a sudden we
started having money go
into new accounts that were set up
for the purposes of of moving money.
And what was happening and
apparently is that on their side,
somebody had gotten a hold of the accounts
or the ACH account
numbers used to be able to
validate new accounts
within their search engine.
And so we were seeing and
other banks were seeing 30, 40,
50,000 different transactions per day
inside of these mule accounts.
And because a lot of banks
don't necessarily look
at the inbound transactions,
there weren't necessarily any triggers.
Just lots coming in and then boom,
the money was actually leaving.
And so again, the weakness
was not necessarily
at the bank level, but
you could certainly say
that the absence of mule
monitoring may have been.
But the absence, the weakness was actual
with the third party,
that large search engine,
and they weren't doing
velocity checks, right?
So they didn't know whether
they had to come in and going out.
And, so that ended up being a
very interesting case study.
It took a while to resolve
because they had to resolve it.
- Right, and before we move on,
one of the stories around
the unwitting mules is
romance scams, right?
Can anyone tell me a little bit about that
and how they use it to recruit mules?
- Yeah. I can take that one.
So what we often see is our,
we'll have clients who
are almost tricked into,
through an online dating
service or something
to that effect, into
entering into relationships
with people who are perhaps not being
as honest as as they should be.
They convince their clients
that the funds they need to,
you know, utilize their bank account
for whatever reason, right?
There's a number of
reasons that are leveraged
but they want to use our
customer's bank account information
to move money for their sister's surgery.
And, you know, because
of the laws in the land
where they live, they can't
move the funds to their account,
yada, yada, yada.
And then, and so the individual,
our client believes that the
funds are for a good purpose,
and it's for one thing but
they're actually stolen funds,
either through business email compromise
or unemployment payments,
you know, social security,
whatever the case may be.
They're unauthorized
funds, they're stolen.
It's stolen money.
And our customer is given instructions,
"When you get the funds, you know,
"send it here, move it here."
So our customer legitimately has no idea
that what they're doing is wrong.
The sad thing is, is that
even when you confront them
with the evidence that what
you're doing, you know,
you're taking part in, you
know, illicit activity,
quite often it's a hard conversation,
because they're adamant
that this is legitimate
and they're their fiance in, you know,
insert country name here
is legitimate even though
they've never seen them
in person or, you know,
spoken to them over the phone.
So, it's a hard
conversation and they legit,
a lot of times there's
a lot of money movement
before you put the kibosh on it.
But it's a very sad situation often
that we have to deal with every day.
- Yeah, and Uri, let me also add in,
I know this is not
romance, but we're seeing
it seems like grandparents'
scams are picking up as well.
And, I know that my father was recently
nearly a victim of that where, you know,
his grandson, my son called him and said
"I've been arrested in
West Virginia for a DUI.
"And can you please send
money $5,000 to bail me out?"
And my father's index
finger was really close
to hitting that enter button if it wasn't
for my, you know, watchful
mother who was looking
over his shoulder and
saying, "What are you doing?"
And anyway, it was really well done.
And I just, I bring it up because
I've heard several different
instances of people
even locally being attacked the same way.
- Right. All right.
I guess one of the main drivers for US,
the newest mule industry
is a stimulus fraud.
And what we see here is the percentage
of claims for basically
fraudulent, you know,
from almost zero to 56% in
the state of Washington,
or the fact that at some
point in the state of Arizona,
82% of the population were unemployed.
Which, of course, just suggests
there was a huge wave of fraud.
Why, you know, is fraud
hitting the government relevant
to the banks in the US, you know,
what's the relationship
between the two, Stacie?
- Yeah, so, you know,
there's a lack, you know
across the board, I think it.
With the pandemic, it really
brought to light that there
was a push to, as soon as you could,
get the money into the hands
of the people that need it.
Unfortunately with that
drive and that sense of,
'We've got to help the people",
there was a lot of missing due diligence,
a lot of missing fraud
controls that enabled
the fraudsters to take
advantage of it, right?
And then you couple
that with perhaps a lack
of focus and visibility from the bank side
to what could be done from a
fraud app perspective, right,
a new account opening perspective.
It was almost the perfect storm, Uri.
I think without having
the right controls to
validate the legitimacy
of an unemployment claim
or the legitimacy of an SBA loan,
under a certain threshold,
if you didn't have
those eyes on it, those controls in place,
those velocity checks in place, right?
If anybody took the time
to read the SBA's review
internal audit of themselves
that was released last year
it was eye-opening.
And so we, I think for a lot of us,
it was get the money in
the hands of the people
who need it at all,
you know, at all costs.
And unfortunately, as you can see
from those numbers on
the screen with Arizona,
that's exactly what it was, right?
It's millions, hundreds of millions
of dollars in stolen funds.
So, I think the environment was ripe.
It was like I said, the perfect storm,
the environment was right for the taking
and that's what they did.
- Yeah, in all of these
billions of, you know,
funds from state level government agencies
had to go somewhere and
obviously not to the real
bank accounts of those
criminals, but to mule accounts,
which was driving a lot of
the account opening activity.
In Australia, did you see
something similar, Paul?
- Yeah, so we, you know,
during COVID, the government
executed the Early Release
Superannuation scam.
And those in the US may not
have heard of superannuation
but it's basically your
savings from your income.
And what we really saw was
eminence that, you know,
something that a scheme
or a saving facility
that is not really designed to be used
until you hit 65 years of age,
was also not designed to hand
out $10,000 here and there.
And there was really no effective controls
from a velocity perspective,
from an identity perspective,
and from a transactional perspective.
Much of which we take
for granted in banking.
So, we saw quite a bit of that
and the use of mules
for other wealth funds,
plus your own to exit those funds.
- Okay, I'd like to move
to the second driver
which is faster payments.
And the US has seen a lot of
movement around faster payments
in the last few years because of Zelle.
Andy, you know so much about Zelle
and certainly whenever you
have a new sort of scheme,
you also need the money
mules to go with it.
What can you tell us about
money mules and Zelle?
- Well, I can tell you that
when we first launched Zelle
we got our proverbial lunches eaten,
it was a you know, blood fest.
And the reason that it
was was because we set up
Zelle originally to do
what it was supposed to do,
which is move money as
quickly as possible, right?
That's the idea.
We want to be able to move
money now, not wait for it.
And so I know that when
we first launched it,
we had some real failures.
One of them was that we moved money
without giving ourselves a breather.
The breather which we call the
kind of a review and release.
If something flags make sure that
if it's kind of sitting in
the middle of, you know,
being naughty or nice that you look at it.
And because, it's one thing to, you know,
for the naughties that
are evident, to stop them.
But it's the ones that are in the middle
and the middle just ate us out.
And so that desire for consumers
and also banks and then
also the competition
with index to move money
as quickly as possible
is really what Zelle is still all about.
Well, because money is moving so quickly.
And because as with anything else
the mitigation tools being
established to prevent fraud
from occurring is moving much slower
than the capability of
moving the money fast, right?
So banks have been spending
the last several years
catching up and making certain
that those good fraud tools
and mitigation are in place.
Well, a lot are, but
then the problem still is
that if you're not looking out for your
transactions that are
incoming on the mule side,
then you're probably not looking
at everything that you need to.
Outgoing money is certainly a risk,
but I think banks are
beginning to open their eyes
that incoming money, especially
when it's coming all kinds
of different ways and very
quickly at ya' is also as much
of a risk because it has to go someplace.
- Right.
So "Piñata Time" Why We Should
All Start Bashing Mules".
And Stacie, why would banks
care about all of this?
It doesn't really hit the bottom line.
It's not a fraud issue.
What's the real risk?
Why focus on trying to detect
those mules from your perspective
- The reason, a couple of reasons, right?
First, it's the right thing to do, right?
You don't want to allow
your institution to
be the one that allows
fraudsters to move money
in and subsequently out, right?
So, it's the right thing to do.
I think, as you look at
the, in the United Kingdom,
as faster payments came on
board, kind of the shift
to really make sure,
it's not just making sure
that user sitting down is your client
and that they're authorized
to make that transaction.
It's making sure that
we are all responsible,
that we know what fraud
we have on our own books
and that we're not
allowing it, these accounts
to be leveraged to receive
those funds, right?
So in the UK, there is a
drive to make sure that
you know what's coming into your accounts.
And I think in the US
there's going to be a shift.
And I, unfortunately I think
the pandemic is going to
help us get there a lot
quicker than we would have,
but there's going to be a shift
from a regulatory perspective.
And I think there's going
to be more eyes on us
to make sure it's not just
knowing your customer, right?
It's making sure that your customer is
doing the right thing and it's monitoring
those incoming payments
to see these red flags.
So I think there's going
to be a shift there
but from a reputation perspective,
I think it's regulatory and reputational.
You just don't want to be known
as the company that allows, you know,
the FI that allows money
to flow freely (laughing)
in and out of your bank.
So I think that's the push
to all of us to do better.
- Right. So sounds very logical.
Let's actually start talking about how.
How can we do all of this?
So there are a lot of ways and, you know,
tools and methods to, you
know, do this mule bashing.
Starting with, you know, user data,
you know, trying to understand when users
open an account,
information about their KYC,
and national database linking,
device recognition, you know,
link analysis around the
phone and other attributes.
Obviously after an account is opened,
what is being done inside that account?
It can also provide some clues
and then behavioral biometrics,
when someone is opening an account
is the person familiar with the
data that they're inserting?
Are they familiar with the
process of account opening?
If they're saying that
they're like 70 years old,
does it match their actual
behavior as they operate
on a mobile device or move the mouse,
and move between fields
and things like that?
So these are some of the analysis layers
that banks are using.
Paul, let's start with you.
What actually works well in
terms of detecting mules?
Can you talk a little bit about
your mule detection program?
- Yeah, so ours is very much light,
but the most successful
thing that we use is
behavioral biometrics
by applying, you know,
known behaviors of mule account openers
and leveraging that to then identify
other accounts that have been opened
using the device or otherwise is critical.
I mean, the first use of that technology,
we found 50 mules in the first two alerts.
So behavioral biometrics is key
and then also leveraging
some old fashioned analysis,
and looking at what we're seeing,
and taking advantage of the known knowns.
Understanding and leveraging
that information to shut
down accounts that are
behaving very much like mules.
- Okay. Stacie, what's
your experience here?
- Yeah, I think it's just as Paul said.
It's a layered approach.
It's looking at stopping
them from coming in the door
using behavioral
biometrics, using, you know,
some key third party tools
to ensure the validity
of the information from
an ownership perspective,
for instance, phone
ownership, things like that.
And then once they're on
the books, it's really
looking at the incoming
payments, making sure there's
name matches on the incoming payments.
It's having, you know,
utilization strategies, right?
Most people who have normal
consumer bank accounts
aren't pulling in large sums
of money and immediately
depleting them while not having any
normal consumer activity, right?
Mortgage payments, bill
payments, things like that.
So, it's building your
strategies around what does
a known mule look like and anything
that meets that criteria,
you know, just pop it out
for somebody to take a look at.
And it's really not as difficult
as people have made it seem.
It's relatively, I think it's going to be
easy for people to do
- So, Stacie, you mentioned
the other biometrics
and also Paul, can you
give a little bit more
grander explanation of what it
does for that specific thing?
- Sure. Yeah.
So the tools that we leverage
is really looking at,
so especially for our account opening,
it's looking at are they
cutting and pasting the name
of the applicant into the application,
because that's not normal behavior, right?
You don't typically do that.
So that cut and paste behavior
becomes incredibly important
as a giant red flag that you don't want
to let this guy in your house.
So, and then once they're on
the books, it's really, again,
looking at the behavior, the age analysis
is a big one, too, right?
Does the activity that
they're performing really stay
in line with what you expect?
And Paul, I don't want
to steal all the thunder.
I'll let you go ahead and jump in
on how you can leverage it.
- Yeah, and I think it's learning
and leveraging the networking
analysis that's undertaken.
So in addition to the cut and paste
and the other activities
such as the $15,000 scheming
straight out, it's also
looking at, well, you know,
this device ID has been used previously.
So let's go and find all
the accounts that have
been opened using the same
device ID and shut them
down because we know that
it's fraudulently used.
So therefore we can assume this is-
- Yeah, you always leverage
the behavioral piece to
identify the one account and then through
link analysis, you then-
- Find additional ones.
- Right, yeah.
You just identify 10,
20, 30, 40, 50. Yeah.
- All right.
Let's move to getting a buy in.
So we're all excited about,
you know, detecting those mules
but we need the budget for this, right?
We need to create a
program and hire people
and maybe use some technology for that.
We're going to run a small simulation
and Andy is going to
be the head of product
that has the budget for
something like this.
And Paul and Stacie, you are, you know,
the mule detection program
advocates internally.
And, you know, go ahead and
explain to Andy, you know,
why you need this sort of budget
and what you're going to do with it.
- So just to be clear, I'm
the guy that needs to be,
I need to echo the voices that have stood
in the way of progress with this, right?
- Exactly. Yeah.
But you should be reasonable, you know,
listen to these guys
and hear them out, Paul.
- Okay, yeah. Thank you.
Well, Andy, you've got the cash
so we need to influence you.
One of the key points we know is that most
of our most vital weak points
exists on the customer side.
And that includes in
the detection of fraud
but also the detection of mules.
And what would you say
if I told you we could implement something
that would reduce fraud
losses and mules by up to 40%?
- You've already got my attention.
(all chuckling)
- Fantastic.
Well, what I'm proposing and
I'll let Stacie fill in as well
is that we embark on a proof of value.
So we use a behavioral
biometrics solution to,
in real world conditions to detect
and shut down the old accounts
and fraudulent behavior.
So we use that proof of value
to boot up business tests
to justify a more substantive investment.
- Yeah, and, I would
add Andy that, you know,
I think it's important that we put money
up against this from a short-term
and long-term perspective, right?
Short-term, let's stop getting these guys
on our books, right?
So let's put in the right
controls to behavioral biometrics.
Let's invest in those controls,
keep the bad guys out, right?
Save our reputation, keep us
out of regulatory scrutiny,
but then from a long-term perspective,
we need to develop and utilize tools
to mitigate the mule
problem from our books.
So get rid of the mules,
sitting on our books today.
So short-term, let's stop
them from getting in the door.
Long-term, let's get
rid of them and protect
ourselves from a reputational
risk and perception issue.
But also from a regulatory
oversight perspective, let's stay
off the radar as well, because
we're doing the right thing.
And that's the most important thing,
let's do the right thing.
- Okay, can I go back to Paul 40% again?
Paul was that a 40% reduction in the
in the customers fraud
or the bank's fraud?
- Yeah, that's a 40%
reduction in the banks fraud,
but also that has a direct correlation
with fraud against customers
because we're detecting
those mule accounts.
And neither of these
things occur in isolation,
so we're helping out customers.
- All right, folks, we need to wrap up.
Andy, I hope that you were convinced.
- Yeah, I'm getting there (laughing).
- And at the end of the day,
everyone is in the same boat.
And just like, you know, 10 seconds call
to action by Stacie, maybe,
what would be your, you know,
let's say that you have like
a "Superbowl" commercial
and you need like a
sentence just to summarize
and wrap up all of this.
What would you say?
- I'm going to steal the Nike slogan
and I'm going with, "Just Do It", right?
I was gonna go with
Spike Lee, I think it is,
"Do the right thing", right?
(laughing) I think that that's
probably not it, but yeah.
Let's just get it done.
Invest now ,it'll save you
down the road, really will.
- Okay.
Hey guys, I hope that it
was insightful, interesting.
We're happy to connect around all of this
and bash those mules.
Thank you very much.
- Absolutely. Thank you guys.
- Thank you all.