- Hello, I'm Anastasia Marchenkova.
And today I'm gonna talk to you about
quantum computing and the one weird trick
to breaking RSA cryptography
called Shor's algorithm.
So I'm gonna cover Quantum 101,
the current status of quantum computers,
the roadmap that we have
to 10 million qubits,
Shor's algorithm and how it works.
And the risk to the current
encryption standards
that we have now and how we mitigate them
with post-quantum and
quantum cryptography.
And even a little bit about
the skillsets that you need
to get involved with quantum
computing in the future.
And please ask questions while
I'm doing this presentation
so I can cover them at the end.
And just any questions that you have,
just toss them in, and we
will get to them at the end.
So I'm a Quantum Researcher at Bleximo,
and we are building application
specific quantum chips
or quantum ASIC accelerators
as we call them.
So I've been in the
quantum computing field
for over 12 years now.
And I started my work in 2009,
researching quantum
telecommunication at Georgia Tech.
And my work was in
increasing the coherence time
or the length of time that
quantum information can be stored
in neutral rubidium atoms,
and we even proved that
quantum entanglement
could be preserved when
transitioning these photons
to different wavelengths.
And that was a research
that helped other quantum
computing modalities
or hardware expand,
and work my research into into
their own research as well.
So then I went to the University
of Maryland for my PhD
and I really got really excited
about quantum computing's
move into the industry
because when I started that
wasn't really happening.
Since then, I worked in two
quantum computing companies
using superconducting qubits.
And now I'm also a YouTuber
doing quantum computing with the vision
of getting more people actually excited
for and using quantum computing
now that this has all
moved beyond the lab.
So take for example, Shor's algorithm,
which we're gonna cover here,
which is often the first algorithm
that people hear about
when learning about quantum
and Shor's algorithm is kind of the key
to the future of cybersecurity.
And it really shows
and leverages the
differences between quantum
and classical computing's
approaches to factoring numbers.
So quantum isn't new.
So even though the industry,
and there's a lot of
hype going on right now,
quantum is actually not new.
And a hundred years ago,
we started seeing that
the world was quantum.
We started seeing weird effects
and some experiments that
could not be explained
by natural laws.
And these are non-classical correlations.
So meaning that quantum physics
violates the classical laws of nature.
And let me tell you, Einstein hated this,
and he did not believe it
because it was kind of inconvenient
and it disproved the laws
that we thought we knew
about the world, the classical world.
So Einstein incorrectly believed
that quantum physics was predetermined,
which made him more consistent
with the world of classical computing.
But quantum is it's own thing.
So about 40 years, we decided
we need to harness this power.
And quantum computing was really proposed
in the early 1980s,
and they proposed this
quantum mechanical model
of the turing machine,
and Feinman and others later suggested
that the quantum computer
could actually simulate things
that a classical computer
could not do, and faster.
About 30 years ago,
we actually discovered the
first quantum algorithms.
So there's one in 1992 called
the Deutsch-Jozsa algorithm.
And it's one of the first
examples of quantum algorithms.
And it showed that quantum computers
could actually be much faster
and outstrip classical
computers for certain problems.
And in 1994, Peter Shor
developed this quantum algorithm
for factoring integers
that had the potential
to decrypt RSA encrypted communication
called Shor's algorithm.
Okay, so five years ago
is really when the
quantum computing industry
really took off.
So we realized we can
build quantum processors
that actually harness
quantum computing power.
So we built this new system
of computing using quantum bits or qubits.
And the last few years
in the industry have been
really exciting because of this.
So while the technology is
still in the early stage
we do really understand
the fundamental physics
behind quantum computing now,
because we discovered
this a hundred years ago.
So a lot of the work right now
is going into exploring
hardware implementations,
processes, scaling,
and understanding how to better control
these quantum states.
So this new system of quantum computing,
what are quantum computers?
What do they actually do?
So a quantum computer is a system
that uses the quantum
properties of its qubits,
like superposition and entanglement
to perform computations.
So not only does the qubit itself
have to be a quantum mechanical system
and quantum mechanical in nature,
we also have to be able to
take these quantum properties
and utilize them to
perform these calculations.
So let's first start talking
about the qubits themselves.
So in the traditional binary
approach to computing,
you have the zeros, the ones on and off,
and information stored
in the bits that are
presented by that logic.
But in quantum computers,
we're based on qubits, quantum bits
that exist in a probability
or superposition of zero and one.
So you can have a 50%
chance of it collapsing
into a zero, 50% chance
in collapsing into one,
and you don't know which one it will be
until you actually measure
and break that superposition.
So, but what can we do here?
A qubit is a two level system
that's based on the 0 and 1 states,
but it can exist in the superposition,
but you can't really think
of it like a regular bit
when we can assign a value
of 1/2 and call it a day.
So it's special feature
is the superposition,
meaning it can exist in
both states simultaneously.
And there's really a lot of
possible ways to make a qubit.
So as long as you have something quantum
that has two states that
you can control well,
it can probably be a qubit.
So everything from polarized light
to especially prepared to
imperfections in diamonds
and other systems that we have right now
are superconducting in qubits
or trapped ions or photonics.
So all of these hardware
implementations can be qubits.
So entanglement is another
fundamental quantum property
we need to harness to
do quantum computing.
So when we say the
particles are entangled,
it means that the quantum
states are linked to each other.
So the state of one can't be described
without the state of the other.
So that means they're not separable.
So this is a very purely
quantum phenomena,
and it doesn't exist
in the classical world
because it's almost like
information is spread
across the particles,
and they're not separated from each other.
So if you take two
particles that are entangled
with each other and measure one of them,
the state of the second changes,
even at a distance.
And yeah, this violates
the laws of nature,
and it's just not very intuitive.
And again, this seems very, very strange
to someone who's very used
to the classical world.
So since classical computing emerged
in the mid 20th century,
we've had a lot of progress
in the computer design
and processing power has
roughly doubled every few years
and that's called Moore's law.
But even if Moore's law keeps holding,
there's a lot of classical of problems
that actually classical
computers can't solve efficiently
no matter how large supercomputers get
because the way that we solve them
on classical computers is different
than the way we'd solve
them on quantum computers.
So a theoretically
perfect quantum computer
can handle two to the N states.
So it's a superposition of all
and bit numbers with N equaling
the number of qubits that we have.
So that means that 100 qubits
can have the same computational power
as about 10 to the 30 bits.
So if we look at this in
terms of classical memory,
and how long how much it
would take to describe
a quantum computer state,
it really shows how powerful this is.
So if we assume that
each number is one bite,
and N equals 30,
it's a gigabyte of memory at N equals 40.
So 40 qubits is a terabyte,
and N equals 50 is already a petabyte.
So you see that,
even though we can simulate
small quantum systems,
we can't really simulate
large qubit systems
because that's how quickly
the power of a quantum computer scales.
So when we control these qubits,
we do them with gates,
and these universal gate quantum computers
have really broad applications.
And these systems work on
building really performing qubits
where we can do these basic
circuit operations in gates.
And we can put them
together to do any sequence
and run more and more complex algorithms.
But quantum computers have
their own set of gates
that are very different
from the set of classical computing gates.
So in classical computers,
we have gates like AND,
NOT, OR, NAND, FANOUT
to perform any of these computations
but these are irreversible gates
because information is lost in the process
of applying some of these gates.
So when we do an OR gate on two bits
and we output a one, we can't reverse it
because we don't know, in this case,
if the first bit was a one
or the second bit was a one
or both bits were one
because of the OR gate that we applied.
And FANOUT requires cloning of a state.
So we FANOUT the bit
to a lot of other bits,
but in quantum computing
we have something called
the no-cloning theorem,
which says it's not
possible to exactly copy
an unknown quantum state.
So we can't do that either.
So for quantum computing,
instead of using classical operators,
we use quantum operators or quantum gates.
And these are used to evolve
the state of the qubits.
So, as I mentioned,
quantum computing gates
have to be reversible
because irreversible operations
actually destroy the entanglement
and superposition of the qubit.
And we can't do that
until the end of the algorithm
when we actually wanna measure the system.
So there's a whole set of
these common unary, binary,
and ternary gates that
operate on quantum states.
These gates like the
XYZ and rotation gates,
the Hadamard gate,
they can change the state of one qubit.
And the Hadamard is the gate
that actually puts the qubit
in equal superposition of zero and one.
There's also two qubit gates like CNOT
and they can entangle two qubits.
And what the CNOT really does,
it's a Controlled NOT gate,
and it flips a state of the target qubit
if the state of the
control qubit is a one.
There's also a CZ gate
which does the same thing as CNOT,
but instead of bit
flipping, it does a Z gate.
And there's also SWAP gates
where we wanna swap the
state of two qubits,
which is important because it plays a role
in efficient hardware
implementation of quantum computing,
even if it's not directly
used to create algorithms.
And there's also some three qubit gates,
the Fredkin and the Toffoli gates.
So those are controlled SWAP
gates or the control NOT gates,
which also gives us additional flexibility
in applying these gates to
quantum computing systems.
So in traditional computer
science terminology,
the algorithm means set of instructions.
But when we actually talk
about quantum algorithms,
we mean instructions
that actually harness
these quantum properties
of superposition entanglement,
and can potentially solve these
mathematical problems faster
than a classical machine.
So right now, there's
actually only a few dozen
or so well studied quantum algorithms,
but we're still in the early
days for quantum computing,
and a lot more being discovered every day.
So the ones that we do know though,
the well understood quantum algorithms
can have a huge impact on
very important problems.
So for example, optimization,
chemistry, machine learning,
quantum computers are really good at that.
So, for example, for properties
of atoms and molecules
which is really necessary
for materials research,
drug discovery, and other
applications like that.
They can be found by solving
the Schrodinger equation.
So the problem is the problem gets harder
than more components and atoms you add.
So exact calculations
are actually really hard
above just a few atoms
and even approximate solutions are hard
above a few dozen atoms.
So you can't model these large atoms.
And when I'm saying
large, I'm talking about
like caffeine or aspirin that
has just a few dozen atoms.
Like we can't actually classically
simulate those systems anymore.
They're too large.
So Shor's algorithm is also just one
of these dozens of quantum algorithms.
Other algorithms like Grover's algorithm,
they can actually speed up
search on an unsorted database,
which can be really impactful
because the amount of data that
we need to process right now
in the world is growing really fast.
So it could be useful
for internet search
companies, telecom data.
There's also algorithms
like quantum approximate
optimization algorithms
and quantum unconstrained
binary optimization.
They can really do really good job
solving optimization problems
like traveling salesmen
and tenant placement
problems and graph coloring.
So these problems become really quickly
classically intractable
or unable to be solving
these classical systems,
but they have a ton of applications
ranging from logistics, manufacturing,
drug development, new materials even.
So algorithms like Variational
Quantum Eigensolver or VQV
have major impacts in quantum chemistry
and beyond chemistry.
The solution of these
large eigenvalue problems
that have more applications
that really affect our day to day life
like designing new materials,
whether that's new materials
that help maybe airplanes
stand up to higher heat or strain,
so maybe we could fly faster
or create new batteries.
So there's a lot of algorithms.
Well, there's not a lot of algorithms.
There are a few sets of algorithms,
but they have a really broad application.
And so that's why people are so interested
in quantum computing as a field.
So let's then talk about Shor's algorithms
since this is the first algorithm
a lot of people hear about,
and it demonstrates this difference
between classical and quantum systems.
The two common crypto systems
that we have right now
that can be affected by quantum computers
are RSA and elliptic curve cryptography.
So when you're online,
any information that you exchange
will be encrypted, hopefully,
often with one of these,
and both of these are really vulnerable
to attacks by quantum computers.
So RSA relies on the hard
problem of factoring numbers.
And multiplying two prime
numbers together is easy,
but taking a very large number
and factoring it to get two
prime numbers is very difficult.
So it would take longer than the age
of the universe to factor a 4,000 bit key
with a classical computer.
But we're seeing that a
quantum computer could do it
maybe in a hundred seconds.
And that's how fast and how
dangerous this Shor's algorithm
could potentially be.
So we have our hardware,
we have our gates,
how do we actually apply these gates
and write quantum algorithms?
So we have to find the prime factors
of a number that can undo
this factoring problem
much more easily than
a classical computer.
And again, this algorithm
was created in 1994.
So we already knew that we could harness
these quantum properties to do this.
How Shor's algorithm actually works
is by finding the period of a function.
And this finds the non-trivial
prime factor of a key.
And there's five steps
to Shor's algorithm,
but only one of them, actually step 2,
is the quantum part.
The rest are classical.
So there's five steps
to this algorithm here,
Shor's algorithm.
And a lot of the other steps
are just checking steps
and doing greatest common divisor steps.
But step 2 is the important one.
Step 2 is the quantum part.
And what we're doing is finding the period
of this function and mod N,
squared mod N, et cetera.
So what's the period of a function
is when you apply some operation,
and the results go back up and
down like a frequency wave.
So we can do this actually,
and look at this as a key here.
So say we wanna factor 25.
And I know that's a very,
very trivial example here,
but it shows you what we're doing.
So we wanna factor 25
and we choose a random, positive integer
that's less than N and we choose seven,
and we do this equation,
this M mod N, M squared mod N, and go on.
And we see that since it's a modulus,
the remainder one is divided by 25.
The answer can vary between 0 and 25,
or 0 and 24, but the
answer can't be above that.
So even as the numbers get bigger,
we can fit more 25s,
and the remainder oscillates.
So this function, as we see on the right,
as we do this,
actually has a period
associated with it's four,
because once we get 7 to the 4th mod 25,
the remainder is 1 again.
So when we put this
back into the equation,
we can actually get the
factors out of this.
So the key to this algorithm
really is to find the period
of this function,,
and then go through and do the
greatest common divisor step
in the last step.
So what known classical
function do we have
that relates to frequency and time.
It's the Fourier transform.
So we have a quantum version
called the Quantum Fourier transform.
And what it does is it
maps the time domain
to the frequency or the Fourier domain.
And frequency is exactly
what we wanna know here.
And we wanna do this really quickly,
because of the oscillation
here of this period,
of this function.
So again, this is a
trivial example using 25
or a number like that,
but it shows the proof of concept
to understand why an algorithm
that uses these quantum steps
is a lot faster classically
and how a quantum computer doesn't
just brute force factoring.
It's not parallelizing.
It's not trying every possibility at once
and just going through a list of numbers.
We're actually doing
something very different
in the quantum step here.
So now that sounds super exciting.
So we're harnessing the quantum world.
We have these algorithms
with a big impact,
but when can we actually run
large quantum algorithms on them
and get the results that outstrip
these classical machines,
and when should we
really worry about this?
So in the end, we need about 2,500 qubits
to break elliptic curve encryption,
and about 4,000 to break RSA encryption.
But these are logical qubits
and not physical qubits.
And the difference between
this is that quantum computers
in real life have a lot of errors in them.
Managing errors is
important in quantum systems
because quantum states
are really delicate.
We're really right now in the
NISQ era of quantum computing,
which is the noisy intermediate
scale quantum device era.
So our chips really have a dozen
to a few hundred physical qubits,
have a high error rate,
a low coherence rate,
and they may need a lot
of error correction.
So quantum information can be stored
for short amount of time
called the coherence time.
And we need to apply all the gates
and read out the data before
the quantum bits decohere.
So you'll often hear
that the quantum states
lose superposition when observed.
Well, what observation
really means is measurement,
and a measurement can
be a controlled readout,
or it could be even interaction
from the environment
with a particle that
interferes with the qubits.
So from my work in superconducting qubits,
we have cryogenics that
cool the qubits down
to a very, very low
millikelvin temperature,
and RF shielding to
stop this interference,
and lengthen the coherence time.
And the problem is that quantum computers
can't do the error correction
in the same way that
classical computers do.
In classical computers, a simplified view
is that we can copy the string of bits
that we wanna send a few times,
and then if the bits disagree,
we can look into the copies
and see what's the majority.
But due to the no-cloning theorem,
the states that we have,
the quantum states,
we can't exactly copy these
unknown quantum states.
So we can't do the same thing,
but we do have an error
correction techniques
known as quantum error correction.
And what it really does
is it takes these states
and encodes them into a
larger quantum system.
But that means the more
complex a circuit gets,
the more error correction we need,
the more qubits we have to use.
So, as I mentioned for
algorithms like Shor's algorithm,
it would take about 4,000
qubits to break an RSA heap,
but these are perfectly logical qubits.
And Shor's algorithm is actually
a very complex algorithm
and circuit with a lot
of sequential gates.
So you have to do them in a certain order,
and that's called a deep
circuit versus a shell circuit,
where you can do maybe gates in parallel
and they don't have a lot of steps.
So because of this error correction,
we have to spread the information out.
We have to keep the states coherent
for very long amount of time.
We actually need a lot
more error correction
than for shallow circuits.
So John Preskill noted in his
lecture on quantum information
that 10 million physical
qubits would be needed,
and maybe 10,000 logical
qubits would be needed
to break RSA encryption.
So we're still pretty far
away from that milestone,
but a lot of people,
and this is a chart from
talking about the research
and how the field is going,
and what quantum information
scientists think that,
when can we actually get to the point,
get to this point to
have millions of qubits.
And it seems like around 15 to 20 years
is something that people are
thinking to get to the scale
to actually have a threat to encryption.
The great part about it is that
there's a lot of really cool algorithms
that need just a few
dozen, a few hundred qubits
that can help with these drug discovery,
with machine learning, even before that.
So we can get a lot of value
from the quantum computing systems first
before worrying about
running Shor's algorithm.
But even as I'm talking
about the qubit counts,
the number of qubits
really isn't everything.
So it just one factor for power.
And I've already mentioned coherence time.
So these qubit counts
don't really mean anything
if they're poorly constructed.
And we have something called
the DiVincenzo's criteria
that tell us what a good
quantum computer should have.
So we need well-defined qubit,
so well characterized qubits.
We have to be able to
initialize the qubits
to an initial state.
So we have to be able to set
them to a good zero, one state,
and we need a set of universal
gates to apply to the qubits
so we can do any sequence,
any set of complex algorithms.
And we need long decoherence times
to preserve the quantum
information for longer.
So, as I mentioned,
we need enough time to apply the gates,
to do our algorithm,
and actually read out the data after that.
And we have to have the ability
to reliably measure these qubits,
because if we can't get
the data at the end,
that's also kind of worthless.
So a few super fault tolerant quantum bits
with long coherence times
where every qubit is
connected to every other one,
ones that have good gate fidelity,
which means, low error
rates in applying the gates.
There's so much more valuable
than hundreds of poorly connected,
fast decoherence qubits
with a lot of crosstalk.
So trapped ions and superconducting qubits
are some of the leading
candidates right now
that do really well on these five factors
of the DiVincenzo's criteria.
So a lot of companies
are focusing on them,
but there's a lot of other contenders.
And some of them like NMR are
well known to not be suitable
for scalable quantum computing
but nuclear magnetic resonance was one
of the first initial proof of concepts
for quantum physics.
But there's other qubit types
that may not fit the criteria now
only because we haven't done
enough research on them.
And there's some physics problems
still to be discovered there.
So besides just looking
at the qubits themselves,
there's also criteria
for how the whole quantum
system has to behave
to make a good quantum computer.
So IBM introduced this
quantum volumemetric
because this classical
computers, transistor account
and quantum computers, quantum
big counts, aren't the same.
So the quantum bits decohere
and loses quantum
information very quickly.
And what the single
number this quantum volume
does is being more mindful
about calculating performance
of a quantum system.
So it takes into account
features like number of qubits.
That's still important,
but also gate and measurement errors,
crosstalk, the topology
or the connectedness
of the chip.
So we actually see here in the chart below
the latest stats are that
Honeywell 10 qubit system
actually has a higher quantum volume
than IBM's 27 qubit machine.
And so this really shows that
the number of qubit counts
is really not everything.
So where are we at
forgetting the qubit ranges
to actually destroy encryption?
And note this huge range in the roadmap
that I've shown right now.
And I've already talked about
needing millions of qubits
to rake RSA encryption.
And we are still looking
at different hardware
implementations here.
So IBM is doing superconducting qubits,
which are Cooper pairs or electron pairs
or any other fermion with
the superconducting qubits.
PsiQuantum is using a different approach.
It's doing photonics.
So they're claiming 1
million qubits in five years,
and they work differently.
So the thing is every
hardware implementation
has its own challenges and weaknesses.
So the important thing is
when you're reading these articles,
keep in mind that a lot
of these wont tell you
the weaknesses of their systems
and how there can be
problems with scaling.
So even though this is far away,
we already know that security
actually takes a while
to upgrade.
And let's think ahead
how we mitigate the
quantum computing threat
to our security.
So NIST has actually
released this competition
for Post-Quantum
Cryptography Standardization
a while back in 2016.
And in July, 2020,
the selection criteria began.
And there were about
26 algorithms submitted
and a few weren't viable after
we had some public review.
There's 15 left in this round.
And they're part of
pretty much three families
that are lattice based,
error correcting code based,
and multi-variate based crypto systems.
So NIST does think that
the eventual standard
will have multiple
recommendations for encryption.
So in case someone manages
to break this down the road,
like I mentioned,
there's only a few dozen
quantum algorithms right now,
and we're still working on and
discovering more over time.
So maybe there's something here
where these crypto systems
could be broken later on,
and they'll probably
recommend more than that.
But the timeline for
that is the new standard
to be announced around 2022
to give people enough
time to upgrade security,
because even though we
talk about 15, 20 years
to get to the point
of breaking RSA elliptic
curve encryption, there's,
because of all the money being
poured into the industry,
maybe the scaling,
the scaling will go much
faster than we think.
And we'd rather be prepared
because in previous changes,
an encryption has taken 10 years
and a lot of money to upgrade.
So we really wanna get these standards
going as quickly as possible.
So what are the properties
of this winning standard?
So one, it must stand up to
quantum computing attacks,
obviously, but it also has to
stand up to classical attacks
because classical
computers are also better
at some other things
and better at things in quantum computers.
And it has to be fast.
So we don't really wanna
slow down communication.
This encryption needs to run
everywhere, and on the web,
on smartphone sensors, a lot of devices.
So if we have the limited compute power,
we don't really wanna
slow down the encryption.
So a way of mitigating the threat
also is using quantum cryptography.
So as opposed to post-quantum cryptography
which uses classical techniques,
it uses math techniques.
This quantum cryptography actually
uses quantum mechanical principles
of the superposition entanglement
to create the shared key.
And the positive here
is that since it uses the laws of physics,
instead of our knowledge of math
and our understanding of
mathematical algorithms,
it can't fundamentally be broken
because we're using the
laws of quantum mechanics.
So one of these ways
is the BB84 Quantum Key exchange protocol
that creates the shared keys.
So physically, we can think
of this being coded in photons
and the polarization of
the photon is the state.
So what we wanna do here is Alice prepares
a bit string that she wants to send
and randomly selects
the polarization basis.
So she can select either
horizontal or vertical
or a diagonal one.
And for horizontal, that's the zero state,
the vertical is a one,
or if you select the diagonal,
up into the right is zero and
down and to the right is one.
So physically we can think
of these bits being encoded
in photons and the polarization
of the photon is a state.
And you can see that here
in the angle of the wave traveling.
So Alice prepares this sequence of photons
sending the polarization.
So let's say she selects
the bit string 01,
and chooses a horizontal
vertical polarization,
then the first photon she sends
will be horizontally polarized.
And the second one will
be vertically polarized.
So then Bob chooses whether to measure
in the diagonal basis or
horizontal or vertical basis,
and doesn't know what Alice
has done at that point.
But the problem is that
means he loses information
when he randomly chooses the wrong basis.
So if you choose to measure
a diagonal polarized photon
in the horizontal vertical detector,
he's gonna get a random answer
and destroys the original.
If you choose the correct basis,
we'll be sure that the readout
result is the correct one.
So we detect and record the results here.
And this can really be imagined
with a polarizing filter
and fancy sunglasses.
So works by only letting certain photons
through the correct polarization.
And the lack of a photon
means the polarizing filter
blocked it from transmitting.
So then Alice and Bob publicly compare
their encoding basis.
So using the chart above,
Alice says that for photon one,
I used the horizontal basis.
If Bob used the wrong
basis and reads this out,
the results he got was random,
and they discard that bit in the sequence.
So they keep only the
bits where they match
the measurement basis and
they prepared the photon
in the same basis as a measurement basis.
And the shared key is
that remaining sequence.
So the cool thing about
this is that you can come in
and listen to it on the
photons if she wants to,
but she's kind of in the same position
as Bob is to choose a random basis.
But however, as soon as she
interferes with those photons,
Eve introduces additional
errors into the measurements.
And so Alice and Bob can check for errors
by choosing a subset of the
key and publicly pairing it.
And if there's more errors than expected
and more than expected
losses on the channel,
they discard the key.
So this has already been going on.
We have these quantum key
distribution networks.
And why don't we always use them
if it's so secure and it's
using the laws of physics?
But it requires specialized equipment.
So for example, for
these photon detectors,
you need that, you need beam splitters
and other equipment to make it work.
So we can't put that all into
a device like your phone.
And just because the encryption itself
is fundamentally secure
by the law of nature,
it doesn't mean that no
attacks can ever occur.
So that's even seen in our system.
So right now these encryption
techniques are secure,
but there's side channel
attacks and there's weaknesses
in the implementation
of the crypto system instead weaknesses
in the algorithm itself.
So even though you can be sure
that nobody has directly
intercepted the photons
in the process of creating the key,
and these quantum key
distribution protocols,
these attacks still do
exist on quantum systems.
So NASA has been doing research on this
because they want to use
these provably secure systems
between earth and low orbit satellites.
DARPA Los Alamos National Lab
has created a small
quantum networks as well.
So even though those two
are fundamentally different,
both will have their place
in strengthening security in a future,
this post-quantum, large
quantum computing future.
But 90% of enterprise quantum investments
will start hiring quantum
computing consultants
to figure out what problems
that they can solve
with quantum computers
that would bring value.
So it's worth noting
that quantum algorithms
are not the solution to every problem.
So a big misconception
is that quantum computers
work by trying every possibility
at once or that they
speed up every problem.
And that's not the case.
So quantum algorithms are faster
for certain set of problems.
And even though we only have
these dozens of algorithms,
the impact they can have is huge
since optimization
problems are everywhere,
and the differential
between quantum computing
and classical computing is massive.
So if you wanna participate
in the quantum revolution,
what skills do you need
to move from programming
classical machines
to quantum software?
And actually it's not
as much as you think.
I personally believe you should need a PhD
to actually use a quantum computer.
And if quantum computers
become mainstream,
there just aren't enough
quantum physicists
in the world to run and manage
all these quantum computers.
So of course this is
isn't a list of skills.
You need to become a PhD researcher,
but it can get you started.
So linear algebra is key.
Quantum gates are just matrix operations,
and you need complex numbers.
And because imaginary
and complex numbers are
the core mathematical base
of quantum mechanics,
they appear explicitly
in fundamental equations like
the Schrodinger equation.
You need a little bit of set
theory, but not too much.
And there's some quantum
specific notations
that you need to learn.
So Dirac notation or bra-ket notation
is just a simpler representation
of vectors and matrices of the
state of the quantum system.
You have the Hilbert space,
which is a special kind of vector space
that has some other special properties
like preserving the inner product.
It takes the inner product
of two vectors and outputs a scaler.
And that's important in quantum computing
in that it describes the systems
containing the wave functions.
And you'll need to learn the symbolism
for quantum operators and gates.
So that's not something you
need to do for getting started,
but when you look at the
linear algebra and the gates,
you'll see how that all connects.
So you'll be surprised
that just for running quantum programs,
you actually don't need that
much quantum mechanics itself.
So on the software side,
let's take a look at the quantum
computing cloud landscape.
So today's cloud quantum
platforms are mainly hosted
by large tech companies
like Amazon, Microsoft,
IBM and Google.
And actually many of
these are Python-based.
There's also languages,
higher level languages,
like Q# and Silq.
And then there's OpenQASM,
kind of quantum assembly
that's being integrated into
the IBM cloud platforms.
And I think Microsoft also has a connector
to be able to do OpenQASM code as well.
So Amazon's AWS bracket provides access
to three different quantum
computing platforms,
and they also have
simulators for prototyping,
and it makes it pretty easy to prototype
and then put them
on these universal
gateway quantum computers.
And Amazon has just started getting
into the quantum computing race,
but so far their chip is not
available on their own system.
Azure has recently launched
their own quantum platform
with a goal of having the
hardware and the software
all under their quantum
development kit solutions.
And they provide access
to the Honeywell and
IonQ trapped ion systems.
And IBM has access to their own chips
up to 15 qubit chips available
for the public to access.
And Google is also building
out their own superconducting
quantum computing chips,
and they've released Cirq
and TensorFlow quantum
to allow the public to start
coding with quantum computers,
but they've not actually
released public access
to their chip, just the simulators.
So to apply what you've learned today,
next week you should debunk the myth
that quantum computers paralyze
or brute force solutions to problems.
I've mentioned this multiple times
because this is a big
misconception in the quantum space.
And I hope I covered enough
interesting algorithms
for you to actually look into them
and see what might be
interesting to your business.
So in a year, you should
start working on a skills plan
to be able to program quantum computers
in your language of choice.
It's great that we have a lot
of these Python-based frameworks
and you can start learning the gates,
and have this minimum skill set
to actually start getting business value
from quantum computers,
and thinking about how
you can take problems
and make them quantum.
And in three years, you
should identify problems
that quantum computers can
use to extract business value.
Thank you very much.