- Hey humans, I'm Aaron Rosenmund.
And with my full-time job
I'm the director of security for research
and development for
Pluralsight and part-time,
I work for the Air Force
in defensive and cyber operations.
And welcome to my talk
on ransomware, creation,
detection and response.
Now what do I mean by that?
What do we expect from this?
I'm going to walk through
what it's like to create ransomware
as the author of some malware that I made
for training that was actually leaked out.
And that gives me a bit
of a unique perspective
but then talk about some
of the lessons learned
from that creation and those
detections that were done
by different anti-viruses
and some things I was able to
pull from those detections.
And then after that, after we find
out how those detections
imply ways to then
invade those antiviruses,
once again, we'll talk
about what you can do for
instant response to ransomware.
And the whole purpose of this
before we start is to make sure
that you understand the engineering
and practices in malware
detection response capabilities,
but also so that you understand
that you don't have as much
of a false sense of security,
which is another theme
from all the research
that I've been doing,
whether it's air gaps or
whether it's anti-virus.
I don't want you to feel like
you're safe if you're not.
And before we continue,
please make sure that if
you have any questions,
feel free to chat in them,
we're remote this time.
Thanks to COVID so go ahead
and put those in the chat,
and I'll answer them
throughout the presentation.
So I know you're probably
reeling from when I said,
I created ransomware.
That sounds really bad.
It's not anything that
can actually be harmful.
It can't be paid, but let's
talk about how that happened.
I guess took really
far the know your enemy
become your enemy situation.
And I wanted to understand what
all of the requirements for
ransomware and so for a training event
or I wanted to make a
really realistic simulation,
I made some malware, it was
in a contained environment,
and one of the students released it
even though there was an NDA
saying that they should not.
And when it did get released,
it just went on Twitter
and like everybody took it
over and it ended up
getting uploaded everywhere.
And this picture is actually
from Malpedia who did some reversing
on it and called it Ironcat.
I wrote a blog about how it works.
You can go to my website,
find that if you want.
So this ransomware and gets released.
And the very first thing
is it goes on Twitter.
And of course now our hunter team got
a hold of it and starts reversing it,
saying, oh no did REvil or Sodinokibi.
Did they go to Golang?
Cause I used Golang to make this malware.
And then it kind of spread
around and different people,
just translated from Russian,
this is Malpedia picking up.
There's the picture that we got
because of the note that was
dropped, it was called Ironcat
because it had different
strings in it that related
to Ironcat, which occasionally
is my hacker handle online.
And then of course the different
software that will profit
off these sorts of things
started releasing things
and that they could clean
your device of ransomware,
which I thought was excellent.
Because if you look through it,
there's no way to fix
this once you get hit.
And so this lets you know,
that every single one
of these companies, while
also saying that I by myself
was this was this advanced
criminal actor organization
with like advanced evasive
capabilities is also
kind of not really telling
you the truth when they say
that they can fix this problem for you.
That was kind of a really neat
perspective to get as well.
And finally, what happened
is Microsoft named
a whole malware family after that.
And so that exists.
And we'll see this again later.
And then eventually everybody figured out,
hey this is not actually
our REvil or Sodinokibi.
It's actually just someone spoofing it.
And the reason they thought I
was spoofing it is because I
used a previous ransomware response.
Nope, I kind of neutered it
and took the capability to pay out of it.
And a lot of the different
language that was in there
for being able to go to the site
and like pay Bitcoin
and that kind of thing.
But a lot of the note was still the same.
So that's why they
thought it was the same.
But when they were looking
through it and obviously reversing it here
they're finding all these Ironcat strings
because of the way that it operated.
And when I just talked about is,
I wanted to understand
is do you feel safe?
Do you feel safe because all
of these different groups pick this
up and immediately antivirus companies.
And we had detection and all
this stuff that made it like,
okay when ransomware gets
out, detections are ready
and the consumer is protected
and enterprises are protected.
But my real question is,
was that really true?
And that's what this talk's
about, is is that true?
And what are those detecting on?
Is the detection actually correct?
Or is it even really effective at all?
Like is there ways to bypass
the detection that are really
really easy for adversaries?
I didn't know.
And that's what we're gonna kind of figure
out as we walk through this
and to really understand
I'm gonna start with, what
was the Ironcat ransomware?
What does it do?
Okay, so actions taken by this exe.
The first thing was that really based
off the way I wanted to be able to use it
for the training environment, I set it up
so it used arguments.
So when you run it, you had to put in
what mode you want it to run in
whether it's encrypt or decrypt,
and then the key that you wanted
to use to encrypt the data.
And so this ended up being
something interesting
because it made it harder to reverse.
And we'll see that later too.
But every time you didn't put
it in the correct argument
or ran it with no arguments
or put in the wrong argument
it would give you kind
of a different message.
So you can see the BeepBoop,
here with the error
you can see the cheeseburger situation.
And I'm Ironcat, and you're not,
so that's why it was called Ironcat.
And the main actions that
this thing took were to
use AES to encrypt the files.
It dropped the payload
called pay_the_piper
which was that kind of spoofed note.
And then at the very end,
after encrypting those files
it dropped four batch files
into the C Windows folder.
The first one was a Sethc
back door and then it ran
a batch file to create a
registry backdoor using Utilman
and then deleted the volume shadow copies
like normal ransomware would
and then clears all the events logs.
Now before all that could happen it also,
they simulate real ransomware
and have network traffic
send out a packet to what was at the time,
a in range domain only called Fakebook
that simulated Facebook.
And it was a red herring IP and the header
and also like some
different UTF characters.
I think there were Chinese
characters just to kind of throw
off people for attribution as well.
So that's what it did.
It had a base 64 encoded
password that was sent
in that packet.
So hopefully if you found the packet
you could then decrypt your malware.
That was the whole point.
Now, when this was uploaded it started to
spread around in VirusTotal
from the top right
you can see there were
multiple different files.
So for this specific training event
we had one that had a
specific file and programs.
It was inetpub, which is for
www-data for websites on IIS
whether it was the user's
file and different kinds
of user files.
In each one of these that was uploaded,
I then uploaded all of
them myself afterwards
also so that they would be detected
and I had something slightly
different about them.
And so really the only main thing
is its exactly the same code.
The only thing that was
really different was the path
that it went to encrypt.
And so here we can see it matches the rule
for QNAP, which is interesting.
Like why is it making that match?
And just some of the paths that it found.
And we have that someone else reporting
that it's Snatch ransomware
and intezer picked it up
and this Thor Yara rule.
Now, as we go through,
this is a different
file and this one had 39
out of 69 detections and
intezer again, Thor again,
same thing with the Snatch malware
and then like slightly different reports
on what actually ran.
And now when we go to the SQL versions
this is trying to hit a SQL server.
It was 38 instead of 39.
So that's one less rule
with the exact same code.
So who's missing what, right?
Like that's what I started
to want to understand.
Also in this one, there was
no automated signatures.
So though this was uploaded
around the same time.
There were no Yara signatures
for this one specifically
and I wanted to know why.
Next we have the same results
but this one does have the
Thor Apt Scanner picking it up.
And for whatever reason,
for this specific sample
it detected that there was a Registry Add
for the debugger backdoor.
But only on this one even though
that code existed in all of them.
And then again, I took the original file
changed it to just .hta,
I didn't actually change any code.
And all of a sudden I have more detections
and instead of Qnap, it's Yomi Hunter.
I have no idea why but what that tells me,
just inference the same,
just the name of the file
generates a different kind of analysis
and is used in the detection of malware.
So that was like an interesting hint
for how these detections are
done by the different engines.
And so when we look at
I users hta, sure enough
Microsoft still had this as Ironcat.
So that's a pretty good detection
but many others had it as
something completely different
than they had it previously.
There's all these different files
but let's talk about the
anatomy of ransomware.
How should detections be done
if we just think about
what the requirements are
for making ransomware in the first place?
Well, you wanna target
a specific set of files.
Ideally, I have files that
are important to the user
to the organization because
you want to properly
perform your business, right?
You're gonna open, change those files
and you're gonna re-save them like over
and over and over rapidly.
And it probably requires admin access
unless you only need
user access just to get
to that specific user profile,
if that's okay then fine.
But ideally it has admin access.
The next part is the drops backdoors,
generally that's so the
actor can get back in
and continue access whether
that's after the ransom's paid
or during, sometimes I've seen the mess up
and have to get back in,
and that's not a 100% requirement.
It doesn't have to be.
But then the next piece
is you really want to
delete backups, delete
volume shadow copies,
so the victim can't recover and delete
the Windows event logs just
kind of cover your tracks
because why not while you're there?
Also you need to get a key
back that is associated
with that deployment of ransomware
so that when the customer hopefully pays
you can use that key to unlock those files
for them to continue
your business practice,
depending on who the organization is
and what their actual intent is.
But that's kind of another requirement.
Also, you can't break the system.
So knowing that all of
those things have to happen
we didn't really see that
in any of the analysis.
But why, like what did it miss?
Well didn't see the
batch drop of the files.
It didn't see the event
logs that were deleted
and VSS copies deleted.
C2 domains for the DNS
request it didn't catch that
or at least say what
DNS requests were made.
There's no mention of like
keys being in the packet
even from the people
who did manual analysis
nor the Sethc back door.
And the file extension was
initially missed as well.
Like if you saw the reports
before my blog came out,
they didn't catch it,
they said DoT encrypted
is actually kind of using
different ransomware groups
saying this is the file that's dropped
even though it wasn't true
which is also just really interesting.
And why, why was it all missed?
Well, if I go back and think about it,
adding the arguments as a
requirement really made it where
when it tried to run in
the sandbox, it couldn't
because those arguments weren't provided,
so instead you just get, these sandboxes
getting silly messages from Ironcat
and no real execution happens.
So kind of by accident,
this was a defensive
evasion or sandbox evasion method.
So that's one interesting finding.
And also a lot of this is focused only on
static binary analysis and Golang
it's kind of difficult to analyze for now.
It depends who you can talk to
but it's just different looking than
like a C++ program that's been compiled.
Okay.
That's all of the kind of
characteristics of what happened
with this creation and some
of the static analysis.
So let's talk about detection,
like what was good in the
detection that made sense?
Well, one thing that was good is,
as kind of as time went on,
these samples are analyzed and intezer
found that it was unique codes
when they cross looked at
code and use fuzzy hashes to understand
what code is being used.
Now, again, it was interesting cause this
doesn't actually match any of the hashes
of any of the files that I had.
I don't know who uploaded this
or what it was specifically
but it still seemed to match
in like what it did and
with the name tags stuff.
And so it was saying it was
unique code, which is accurate.
I didn't make all of
it from scratch myself.
And it did properly
recognize it as Golang.
Where, when you look
at VirusTotal's report
it thought it was .net. for some reason.
Now JOE sandbox really did
detect that there was a
a Tor address in the text file
which tells me a lot of this
analysis is being done based
on clear strings in the binary.
And then beyond that, it was just saying,
hey the biggest reason
we think this is bad is
the signatures cause other
people found signatures
instead of that.
And that's the top thing on there.
So, okay.
Maybe we remove the Tor file.
We don't have to worry about it.
Now, Malware Bazzar did
actually categorize this
as Sodinokibi, and that's
interesting because again
it's being categorized that way
because of that spoof ransomware note.
Now they also got Ironcat
after a while because
of the changes, but
this all tells me maybe
things that these
antiviruses are looking at
as tells for detection.
And then finally Yara
signatures were created
that was able to download and
we'll be able to test those
out and see what they were doing also.
So based on all that information
what were these detections?
Well, there was an automatically
generated Yara signature,
probably the ransom note strings
definitely the Tor address.
One thing detected that
there was a registry add.
So that's something to consider.
Batch file execution probably
should have been a detection
but I didn't see it anywhere.
So that's something to keep in mind,
for if I want to try to make this evasive.
And in my mind, what you should detect on
is probably concurrent access to files,
like very quick access
to files by some binary,
especially on signed binary.
And so now the thing that I want to do is
what's the least amount
of change I can make
to then evade these antiviruses.
So I'm gonna make small
changes in this demo that's
about to come up, I'm
gonna make small changes.
And then we're going to
see what the reaction is.
I'm gonna change function names.
We're gonna look at a custom ransom note.
I'd need to remove that Tor address,
probably we'll end up having
to remove the registry add.
And then if I wanna use
a different backdoor,
here's an option.
And if I really have to, I'll have to get
to the behavioral analysis.
So let's check that out.
Now, those evasion ideas
are just a hypothesis.
Now let's take a look at
how this actually plays out.
Keep in mind the idea here is that based
on the variations in the
detection that I just went over
what are the least amount of changes
that I can make to completely
evade Windows Defender,
the Yara Signature and VirusTotal?
That's my goal.
So first up, I want you to
see what I'm working with.
It's the same original files.
So here's the md5 for the iaiusers.exe,
iai here stands for Ironcat,
of course, or I am Ironcat.
And here's the original
md5 for the variation
that encrypts just a
specific different folder.
Now those are the same md5s
that you saw on VirusTotal
and you can also see here.
And this md5 has 52 out of 70 detections.
And then the one for the file location
in a different area has 38
out of 69 detections on VirusTotal.
Well last but not least
the Yara Signature.
And I'm not really sure
how much effort this is
it did say it was automated.
But then when I look at it
it has a user called Florian Roth
but I'm pretty sure he
just made the automation.
You can look at automation
as being a really heavy toll
in itself, but either way here's
the original Yara signature
and it's highly effective
against all of the original
samples that are in this folder.
So that means at the very
least, that the different names
and different hashes and
different target files
aren't throwing the Yara
signature off that sense.
So it seems like that
was a pretty good job.
And a quick look at that
signature file shows
that there's nine detection
sequences with the criteria
for detection being that
seven of them are matched.
And the file has to also be
smaller than a specific size
which brings to mind another point
like maybe I just need to make
really hefty sized malware
and not worry about detection evasion.
But that's probably a
different talk completely.
Next for the test machine.
And rest assured there is no tomfoolery
or hijinks going on here.
It's a fully patched Windows 10 with
fully updated signatures.
When I dropped the known
malware on the desktop
it's instantly detected and removed
and here we have a lovely
Ironcat malware family alert.
So great.
It seems like we're super safe
and Microsoft's on top of it.
Well, when you look at
many of those detections
that we just talked about earlier,
it seems like a lot of
them alerted on Sodinokibi.
Probably based on the copied ransom note
from a incident response that
I did to an REvil incident.
So maybe based on that conclusion
or what I'm seeing there
with those detections, if I
change the ransom note that will
at least throw off these
detections a little bit.
So here I changed the
ransom note to say even
more things that an Ironcat would say,
and it's completely
happenstance that cats don't
have very good written English either.
And it has nothing to do with
my terrible typing skills
and occasional issues with attention
to grammatical and spelling accuracy.
In general this is not
completely different
from the original file on the left with
exception to this ransom note.
Now I recompile this
into iai as back view one
and it's time to test out on
the sweet Windows Defender
detection capabilities,
and to prove that this
isn't a box of mirrors,
you can first see the threat detection
from the previous file.
Then check out that real
time protection is on
as well as cloud protection.
And I did not turn on the
sample submission here
'cause I don't want this to get burned
before I even finished the demo.
Now I'm copying the new
malware onto the desktop
and well, there's no detection.
But that's okay, evading
these hashed based detections
are one thing but surely there's no way
that this will be allowed to run, right?
I mean, it's just the exact same code
with a different message from a cat.
Well, let's find out,
you're on the desktop.
I set up to run the executable
with required command arguments.
And well, of course this
wouldn't be a live demo
without a few mistakes.
I'm just trying to make sure
this is realistic for you.
One requirement for the
Ironcat sample to run is
for it to be able to resolve
and send a HTTP packet
for fakebook.com.
Okay.
So this seems like I forgot
to enable the Hyper-V adapter,
no biggie.
Enabling that, I give it another shot.
And it also means that
that cloud protection
is also fully enabled,
still no detections.
And then here we go to run it.
And oh, there's a pop-up there.
Oh no, no, that's not Windows Defender,
it's just letting you know
in a friendly way that files
are waiting in the queue.
Files waiting in queue to
be encrypted, of course,
but there's still time.
And as it finishes encrypting,
now we see an alert,
but it seems like it actually
ran quite a bit there
before that alert happened.
So using the get.mpthreat command,
you can see that this is
actually a different alert
from the original Ironcat alert.
Instead, this is a behavioral alert,
that seems like it's
something that's gonna be more
difficult to get past than
just changing the hash.
So it seems like we have execution.
And when I take a look
at these sample files,
I see that the note did drop
and the text of this document
here was indeed encrypted.
All right, I'll exit out of that.
And when you exit out of this window
there's all the telltale
signs of ransomware execution.
The desktop images is
different and links are broken
and there's notes left in every folder.
And that by itself is interesting.
This is saying that an
up-to-date Windows Defender
is essentially only checking
the contents of the ransom note
in the strings of the
binary for detection.
And if you change that
well now at least I have
execution on the box.
It may actually get detected,
but it's a little late
because the ransomware
already kind of happened.
But I want more than that.
I don't want to just trick Defender,
I don't want this to be detected at all.
And it should be more of a challenge
to get past these
behavioral detections right?
Well, now it's time for version two.
So what do I change now,
going over what I know
I realized that this is
string based detection.
And so I'm going to go ahead and change
significantly unique
strings that occur elsewhere
in the binary.
And it also seemed to have issues
with access to ntuser file.
And when I look at the name
of the behavioral alert
it was called accessibility elevation F.
Well one of those batch
files that's dropped changes
the Sethc executable,
which is the binary in
Windows System32 that's associated
with accessibility features.
So that's fine, I may not be
able to use that back door,
but I can use a different backdoor later,
for now I'll just remove
that as a function
because even if all I do is
achieve ransomware execution
that's still the end game goal.
And one last touch.
I noticed that some of the
manual reverse engineers
found absolute paths
reflecting the folder structure
I used when creating the project.
This time I'm gonna use
the -trimpath option when
I compile to make the path
strings relative instead.
But before I go straight
to the Windows detection
I wanted to check on the
Yara signature detection.
So first I'm gonna go back
to version one and check
to see that yeah, the Yara
signature is still hitting seven
of the nine sequences,
which was really the cap.
So we got rid of two of the sequences.
And honestly, if you think
about what just happened
that's saying that this
Yara signature that was
generated is doing a better job
than a fully patched
Window Defender signatures.
So now when I test the
version two that I just
compiled changing all
those other unique strings
we did nothing, zero detections,
which honestly was much
easier than I expected.
So now that I have the box
checked for Yara signature
evasion I need to test
Windows with these changes
and see if I got past that
behavioral detection as well.
So I reverted this device back,
I'm using hyper-V and now
run the second version.
And of course, again I
forgot to turn off the
external networking,
but this at least shows
after I get it working, that my addition
of error strings for the
HTTP error is also working.
So there was some change
to the code there as well.
Now this time it runs and guess what?
Big reveal, zero detections,
no Ironcat detection
and no additional behavior
detections with full run-through.
One last test is VirusTotal,
and surely with its sandbox
execution and nearly 70 engines,
it's not gonna be as easy as just changing
some clear text strings that
happen to occur in the binary.
Well, almost, with version two
I now only get 12 detections
from groups like FireEye
recognizing this as Snatch ransomware
which I saw before in
the original detections.
Now this got me thinking,
what's my baseline.
I wanted something to test
that was really noxious,
that really wasn't malicious.
So I made a hello world application
and I dropped that into
VirusTotal as well.
And sure enough, four
of the engines detected
the hello world app as malicious also.
So that's really the best I can do,
four or less and we're seeing
that those four basically think
that everything's malicious.
If I get to four or less than
and it's these four players,
I'll be happy with that
because I'm then getting past
the major players like ISA
and FireEye and bit defender.
Okay, but before getting into some
of the behavioral modifications
that I think I might have to make based,
on the slide that I presented previously,
I had one last idea.
Developers are often told
that they should use
descriptive names for functions.
And I think that probably applies
for malware developers as well.
And I don't disagree normally
but what about if I don't do that?
If you're creating ransomware
and the function name is
encrypt or ransom note
that seems a bit on the nose, doesn't it?
So to test this out, I
changed function names
and other strings that say ransom
or the word crypt to
friendly no, or like entropy.
And the last thing I wanted to do,
there was still some function code
for the registry utilman
backdoor that was also dropped.
Though it wasn't used, I think
it was still in the binary.
So I wanted to remove that as well.
And after those changes,
the code still does
exactly the same thing.
It still deletes the volume shadow copies,
it still deletes all the logs
and it encrypts everything.
So now it's the big moment, it's time.
This is the end of this demo.
It's time to hold your breath.
If we were doing this in person,
I'd be really, really nervous
and considering whether
or not I should have done a
live demo in the first place.
And though, as this is loading,
SecureAge APEX instantly
decided that this was malicious.
I'm pretty sure it just thinks
that because it's a binary
that's not Microsoft, it's malicious.
For reference calculator
when you open it up in like
Process Explore, has one
detection VirusTotal.
So I'm not super upset about that,
but by the time this is done
processing zero other engines
detected the sample, not FireEye, not ISA
not Bitdefender, not any of them.
The sample that all I
did was changed strings
it's just as effective as the original.
And all I had to do was what basically
constituted string replacement
and remove code for batch
files or backdoor tactics
that are like 10 years old.
I'm sure if I replaced them
with something that was newer
or more obfuscated we
would be able to get by
with that as well.
In fact, I can avoid dropping
batch files completely
and just do all of it through the binary.
And just like that, Ironcat's back.
Okay, so I don't feel really safe anymore.
After I went through this
and created all of that,
what I actually feel is that maybe my
antivirus isn't protecting
me like I thought it was.
I know this isn't accounting
for having something like
Advanced Threat Protection or Endgame
actually installed on a device.
I didn't have that software,
but for the average consumer
for the average enterprise user,
being able to just change a
few strings as a malware author
and redistribute really
completely bypasses
that entire industry of appliances
and that's kind of concerning.
But what it does do is it
places a really high importance
on better behavioral detections.
So when I talk about
that, it's EDR solutions,
it's centralized logging,
that password that was input
with the argument would
have been caught if all
of the arguments and all of
the commands that were ran
in a terminal were passed
back to centralized logging,
they wouldn't have been deleted.
We wanna do that log
analysis on Windows devices.
And we have to be able to chain processes
and track like file
execution, that sort of thing.
On the network side, JA3
hashes would've caught
the weird signature
for the network traffic
leaving the binary before it had executed.
There's certificate anomalies.
Like the fact that this one
didn't even have a certificate.
Well as full packet capture
would have helped us understand
what that Base64 string was doing.
And we would have been able to catch that.
Now that's not necessarily
how real ransomware works,
but there needs to be a
heavier focus on these things.
It seems like anti-virus
shouldn't provide us the sense
of safety any longer.
So now let's talk about response.
I don't want to like provide
all of that capability,
and I purposely didn't show
a ton of the source code
and won't provide that cause I don't want
this being reused over and over,
but let's talk about it when
this ransomware does happen,
what are some interesting
things I've learned
about doing response?
And one of those things is
as you come across different devices
you'll notice that when they encrypted
that is a touch time,
the date modified time,
and you can use that time to kind of chain
the events together to understand how
the adversary's moving
through the network.
A few of them that I responded
to, it's not all I ever do,
but they were live, the
adversary was still there.
And I was able to kind of track them back,
kick them out, figure out how they got in.
That was root cause analysis for me.
Another piece of this and
something that's really exciting.
And maybe you already
know, but if you don't,
that because of that requirement
to leave the box useful
and this will be talked
about here in a second.
Again, I'll show this off,
but there's an HTTPERR log,
that isn't part of the
Windows logging system,
that can show things that
try to scan the devices.
And in this case, if you see that Trinity
it's kind of small there,
maybe you see Trinity
as a get request, it's
actually a signature
for in map being ran in your network.
Same thing goes for, we can
use the firewall log on Windows
the local firewall log,
isn't just in the
Windows event log system,
to understand what
network traffic's going on
on that device also.
And if you take care, you can
go into the advanced firewall
and enable that, one change
the size limit for that log,
as well as enable it to log for things
that are successful as well as failed.
And this is the place
where you can do that.
Often in enterprises, already default.
When you do that you can
collect all the information,
start to track that internal activity.
This is Graph Tool and
Elastic that I was able to use
on those logs to put
all this stuff together
really draw out what access
happened, even after the fact.
And one last piece,
I'm gonna show this off here in a second.
Here's a few logs that
are really, really helpful
for checking SMB activity
and remote desktop activity.
And I say this because what
has to happen especially
in a live situation is when
ransomware is detonated,
that actor then has to disconnect.
So yes, the logs were cleared, but as soon
as that actor disconnects,
there's another log generated.
And in this case, that
log actually was generated
with the IP, with the
network address in this case,
the external address that
was being used by that actor.
And this is where you can find that,
and I'll show you here in a second.
Also, I made a tool that can
put all this stuff together
and help you do these incident
response capabilities.
And we'll look at that also.
I'll give you a demo of that right now.
All right, for this demo, get with me.
And here you are, the worst has happened.
Ironcat strikes back or
insert whatever ransomware
of your choice, you're
jumping onto the box.
And the same idea applies.
First just in case you haven't been there,
and some may think this is really simple
but none of the links are gonna work
because they're also encrypted.
And the recycle bin is
generally unaffected.
So you can still get to
the file system that way.
It's an easier way to get in.
I've even done in some response where like
when I was doing in remote,
the Windows archi didn't work correctly
or didn't pass through
the way I needed it to.
So this was the best way
for me to get around.
Inside the event viewer you'll
find that for the most part
the logs are all gone.
This is going to be the case.
But in my experience
when ransomware was done
by live actors, and sometimes
even when it wasn't,
the order of operations
requires them to disconnect
from the session whether it's SMB or RDP
after the execution of the
malware that clears those logs.
Now hyper-V uses RDP.
So I'm going to disconnect from hyper-V
reconnect to hyper-V,
and then open up the event terminal again,
go to terminal services under Windows,
local session manager.
In that location, you can check
the logs that are generated
from the disconnection of the RDP session.
This RDP session that existed prior
to the logs being cleared and
right here with event ID 24,
this is where you're
gonna find the IP address
of the connection that existed
while the logs were cleared.
And this is what you saw in
the slides just prior to this.
Kind of two keynotes there.
But one last thing I wanted to show you is
remember the requirement of ransomware
from the actor's perspective.
They just wanna make money.
Well, usually speaking,
they just wanna make money.
So ideally your machine is not brit.
That would be kind of counterproductive,
which for the most part means
that the System32 folder
under Windows is left alone.
In here in the System32 folder,
you will find the folder named log files.
And inside that folder,
another called firewall.
Now this is the best
part about these logs.
They are not Evtx logs
and they're not part of the
Windows event log system.
So the log clearing that the
actors did, didn't touch these.
Now, if you wanna open these up on the box
which I don't recommend,
just scrape them off,
and look at them later,
but if you wanna open them
up on the box, you have to use
the administrative notepad.
But once you do take a look at these,
you get a lovely historical accounting
of all of the connections
made to this machine,
especially of the setting to
log allow connections as well
as drop connections, which often times,
that I've found inside of
a enterprise environment
is on by default.
And though this mashup of texts is lovely
in its own, right?
My main job isn't
actually to make malware.
I just thought it was interesting.
What I actually do is incident response
and cyber defense and
red team operations that
sometimes includes making malware.
But I've also created this
tooling to process this file.
It enriches it with
local and external DNS.
It uses GoIP and threat information
and aggregates it all
from multiple machines
into an Elastic stack so
that it looks like this.
So what you're seeing
here is the same logs
that you saw collected, but
from two devices that were
involved in the live
ransomware incident last year
that I responded to, and with
the location changed here
for the source location
to protect the innocent.
Those local firewall logs were collected
and then provided this map
of every connection made
externally with country codes,
known IPs on threat list or Tor nodes.
So if it's green, there's no threat,
if it's red, there would be a threat.
It didn't detect anything
on a known threat list
when I had dumped it into this
Elastic instance this time.
But you also get protocol and
path distribution analysis
by firewall actions.
So you can see like a spike there
and drop packets as well
as counts of ICNP type.
And really just any way you
can split up this information.
And I'm sure there's a lot
more to be done with it.
The more devices you collect,
the more you can build
out the attack pass through the network.
In this case, RDP and SMB
were the primary means
of lateral movement.
When you search for 3389
you get a positive internal
to internal connection.
I say positive because there's
a green dot right there
on Jacksonville, Florida
which is where I changed the location to.
And when you put this into a list inside
discover with the same kind of search
and only look at the
source and destination IPs,
you can see what other devices
they were connecting to
and you can do the same for SMB.
And this has been an incredibly
effective tool for me.
And I plan to keep
expanding on its capability
right now I'm calling the tool Revenant
and you can find it and download it
and use it yourself with
the GitHub that's associated
with this presentation,
that will be at the end.
So that being the case that
I'm showing you how to respond
what can you do to try to prevent this?
Well, it's all the things
that we already talked
about for detection and response,
but it's also reducing
your attack surface.
I've seen RDP is an entry
point too many times
now to count.
We just looked at client to client traffic
is something that you can
monitor and stop this,
the lateral spread of that.
You do have time while there's live actors
in your network.
Monitor file access, and write IO and
the same like C2 and
log review and all that.
But one really key point
that I want to focus
on is emulation, emulation, emulation.
You have to test it,
and you have to test what
your capabilities are,
and what you can and can't do.
And with that, you need to
apply that knowledge right now.
So let's talk about
next week, you wanna go
and make sure you have detections
in place that allow
for antiviruses to fail
and you have behavioral
capabilities that are
more difficult to bypass.
So that what the attacker
that you're defending against
doesn't just have to change some strings.
In the next three months,
let's talk about these TTPs that we looked
at for instant response and
develop your tools internally,
so that you can track this
activity, once you do find it.
Then within six months, use
the resources in this GitHub.
And please absolutely whether
it's the Revenant tool or
whether it's the already
released malware that you
can download yourself to test
like this is safe malware.
There's a blog about what it does.
You can use this internally
to test your environments
and run exercises with your team.
Thank you so much for joining me at RSA 21
and happy hunting.