- Hello and welcome to
today's expert panel session,
Super Apps and Digital Wallets:
Securing the Unstoppable Force.
My name is Lee Cookman
and I head up our product management
for ID proofing at TransUnion
as one of the world's premier providers
of data and technology with
regards to identity and fraud.
I spend most of my time finding ways
to make businesses
successful at saying yes
to good consumers and
with greater confidence.
With me here today, I'm very excited.
We've got a number of expert panelists
who are just thrilled to have together
in one place at one time
to share their perspectives
on innovating into this
new dynamic environment
and staying ahead of the fraud,
security and privacy
concerns that come with it.
Today I have with me Julie Conroy,
she's the research
director of AITE Group's
Fraud and AML team,
Neil Campbell, the director
of SecureNow operations
at Fiserv,
and Loren Russon, the VP
of product and technology
at Ping Identity.
You'll get to know each of
their voices as we go along here
but before we get started,
let's have each of them say hello
and share a little bit about
their bio's and warm up here
as we get started in the content.
Julie, why don't you go first?
- Sounds good, happy to be here.
And as we said, I am the research
director for AITE Group's
Fraud and AML practice.
I'm lucky enough to spend my days
talking to fraud executives
at financial institutions,
at e-commerce merchants, at FinTechs
and learning about what
their challenges are
and offer successful solutions.
I look forward to
bringing that perspective
to this conversation.
And now I'll turn it over to Neil.
- Hey, thanks so much Julie.
I'm Neil Campbell.
I lead the operations team
for SecureNow at Fiserv
and spend my days trying to make sure
only the right people access online
and mobile banking applications.
Loren.
- Hey, thanks Neil.
Yeah and it's Loren Russon.
I work for Ping Identity
and I've been there for about 10 years.
And I have to say I've
been in the industry
for probably 20 plus
I think I come honestly
with my gray hair here,
but I get a chance to talk
to customers quite often.
And you know, really they
help provide perspective
which I hopefully can be valuable
for this conversation today.
- Awesome. All right.
Well, it seems like it
wasn't that long ago
when to obtain new software applications,
you had to pick up a CD-ROM
and load it into a giant tower.
And then right behind that
came the world of apps, right?
Our expectations started
to increase where right now
you know, we just expect, as
soon as you think of an idea
you should have an application available,
accessible with your hand,
wherever you are within seconds.
And that should be a
gateway to open up linkages
to people, finances,
sports school, anything,
anytime, anywhere you expect
to be able to get access to it
and to interact and to perform
end to end transactions
of all kinds, conversations with grandma
or making or checking
your balance at the bank,
things of that nature.
And here we find ourselves
relatively early in the rise,
the adoption curve of what
many are calling Super Apps.
And so we just wanna baseline real quick,
level set before we get started,
talk about what a Super App is.
And I think of it kinda
like fraud in some cases
where it might be one of
those things where we say
I don't know how to describe
it, but I know when I see it.
So in all seriousness, though,
we see these kinds of apps
emerging across the globe.
It is not geographically limited, right?
Everywhere consumers are
interacting with their mobiles.
We see the emergence
of these types of apps
because the opportunities are rising
and our expectations as
consumers are changing with that.
Providers like Amazon,
Google, WeChat, even Uber,
they're constantly innovating
on their platforms.
Once they have a strong audience
and based on their core services,
something unique that they
brought into the market,
they began to expand and
with the number of consumers
they have coming to that hub,
they realized they can
be a hub for messaging,
payments and transfers, banking, retail,
digital commerce of all kinds.
Surveys recently have shown
a great deal of optimism,
both with businesses,
interacting through those hubs,
as well as consumers who come and enroll
and use the services on those hubs
and make that a central
point of interacting
with the businesses that
they wanna connect with.
Consumers are provided the benefit,
the simplicity of a single
hub for messaging, e-commerce,
retail, finance payments,
and rather than toggling
between app after app
and relogging into each
one of them as you go,
they can accomplish a
bunch of tasks in one place
and begin to interact with
the services that make sense,
can actually happen together
in an integrated fashion.
Businesses are excited
about it too, right?
They can take advantage of
deep-pocketed big tech firms
that are handling shared services,
things like authentication
and great user experience
and things that they continue
to invest and innovate on.
And the businesses that
are supplying services
within those platforms, those frameworks
can take advantage of that
and invest more and more of their finances
and their time and their
innovation into the products
and services and things
they specialize in,
what they bring uniquely to the market.
But adoption of these technologies
by consumers and businesses
is not gonna be without challenges.
We're already seeing some of those, right?
Security and fraud are
at the top of the list
for concerns for businesses and consumers.
And on the consumer side,
there's the added perspective,
especially depending on the
geographic region you're from,
your concerns about
privacy and data sharing
may be also near the
top of the list as well
for concerns in innovating into the space
and beginning to make this truly a place
where you would go to do all
the sorts of different things
you do in ordinary day-to-day life.
So with that, I just wanna dive in,
'cause we've got a lot we can cover here.
And there's a lot of wealth
of experience and knowledge
with this group here.
So we've got several questions.
I'm just gonna guide everyone through
and see if we can generate
some good conversation
on some of these topics.
So we'll kinda open up with
a pretty simple one here.
Digital payments, they
become the norm globally
during the pandemic, consequently
mobile payment movement
has taken even a stronger hold
as have related fraud
challenges that come with that.
But looking back over the
course of the past year,
what do you think has
changed in linking that
to where we're headed with
the Super App conversation?
Julie, I'll let you go first on this one.
- Sure, sure.
So the pandemic really
put the pedal to the metal
on digital transformation
in financial services.
We performed a survey that
we conducted late Q4 of 2020
in which we asked consumers
a whole bunch of things
but one of them was the extent to which
they had tried new
digital products like P2P
or mobile RDC or digital channels
from their financial
institution like mobile.
And 39% of the consumers that
we surveyed had tried these.
And the vast majority realized
that these are really easy,
they're very convenient
and they intend to stick
with these new digital first behaviors
after all all of this is behind us.
So I think that the pandemic
really has accelerated
our movement towards a
digital first environment.
It's not just through digital banking
or interacting with merchants.
You know we saw e-commerce
volumes jump by 25%,
but also, you know the
US market in particular
has had a whole bunch of stops and starts
with contactless payments
at the point of sale.
And it took a pandemic
but we finally are seeing
that those contactless payment behaviors
are taking hold here
as they have in the rest
of the globe as well.
So we've definitely seen
some very substandard changes
to consumer behavior.
And Neil, I know you guys
have some good perspective
on this, I'd love to hear your
perspective on this as well.
- Thanks, Julie.
So I think we've seen an acceleration.
You used the term, pedal to the metal.
I think that's really accurate.
We already we're seeing a trend
away from brick and mortar
traditional financial institutions.
And I think that's just the pandemic
has accelerated that transition.
Julie, also you mentioned
these applications
tend to be sticky
and I think they are
incredibly sticky by design.
Once you set up your bill payment,
you're very unlikely to
go to another system.
Once you add an individual
payee or download your contacts
into a specific application for payments,
it's so easy just to stick with that.
So I think we've seen a
ramp up and we will maintain
those transitioned customers
and just continue to transition
away from the physical locations as well.
And with that, I'll turn it over to Loren
for his perspective.
- Yeah, thanks Neil.
You know, I've been thinking,
the comment about contactless
payments I think is spot on.
And I remember reading
a statistic that's like
51% of mobile phone
users now use contactless
for all of their transactions.
And I thought, you know,
if you have the majority
which is getting very
close if you consider 51%,
you know that starts to create that trend.
I think mobile wallets is spot on.
And I've been thinking
about my own behavior.
You know, mobile point of sales
has been really critical and, you know
as we couldn't go into buildings,
we could at least meet
people from outside.
And so I think it's just the ease of use.
I think we have the
technology for the adoption
and then the ability for
us to be able to transact
a lot more easily with our mobile phones,
I think has really helped
steer at that acceleration
that you guys have talked about.
- Great, thank you.
Great perspectives.
So let's move on to
our next question here.
Let's talk about some of
the trends giving rise here.
Do we think that the
digital payments trend
has given rise to the gradual
adoption of Super Apps?
How has that momentum gonna carry forward
into the Super Apps world?
Julie, what are your thoughts?
- I definitely think that this
is kind of bleeding into it.
And again, I think it's
coming from bottoms up
consumer expectations that, you know
as I have this hub of so much
of my transactional activity,
be it purchasing activity with Amazon
or if I'm a gig worker and
this is not only the mechanism
that I use to do my job from day to day
but if they can also provide
me the opportunity to get paid
in real time via an app, and
there's a ton of utility there.
And so I think that
organizations are realizing
that there is opportunity to create
not only additional stickiness,
but additional revenue
streams and additional points
of loyalty and utility
with your customer base.
So I think we're definitely seeing that.
And also just as you see,
the gen Z coming of age
and entering the consumer economy.
Now these are the folks that grew up
talking to Alexa and Siri.
And so there is definitely
this expectation
among that demographic
that whatever they wanna do
is gonna be at their fingertips
and available in a mobile device.
- That makes sense.
Julie, I was gonna add
on that of, you know,
when you consider that
it is that gen X crew,
I mean they're pretty natural.
I mean they love mobile
device, they trust that device.
And I always thought, well
none of us devalue our money.
You know, we hold to that very closely
and we look for anyone we trust
and the closer we trust our phones
the closer we trust that
digital transaction,
the more that device
becomes a representative
of all transactions that we do.
So I do think this digital
transformation is coming
because of transactions,
because we're transacting
in something that matters a lot
to us, has high value to us.
And so we trust that platform
and then you add another app for chat
or you add another app
to approve somebody,
you know, get them consent,
all those transactions I think
just start to become common in that single
or that Super App we talked about.
Neal, I don't know if you have
a perspective on this or not.
- Yeah, absolutely.
I think that's really good point Loren,
that the device becomes a
trusted medium unto itself.
And then the Super Apps provide a portal
into many different services.
And I was looking at the federal reserve
reporting within the United States,
22% of US residents are either
unbanked or underbanked.
And those numbers are actually much higher
in some other countries.
They're much lower in
some other countries,
but globally we're talking
about an incredible size
of a market that's being underserved
in a traditional banking system
that I think the rise of the Super Apps
will actually create
incredible opportunity
to bank in a non-traditional way.
And so I think that we're going to,
it started with payments, right?
But I do see it proliferating
into every aspect of of transactions
and beyond financial transactions as well.
- That's a good point.
That's a really good point.
- Yeah, that's a really
unique perspective.
Kinda carrying on from there,
you know, what do you
think needs to happen
to ensure high adoption
of digital payments?
You guys were talking here about things
that kinda forced it
during pandemic period
for a number of folks,
depending on where you live
and what the norms are in your area
but what behavioral changes do you think
we can expect to see consumer level,
corporate, cultural level,
as we look at higher
adoption of digital payments?
- So I can jump in first here.
I think you have to be
creating true utility
with these Super Apps.
It's not just a build
it and they will come
because Super Apps is the new buzzy term.
I think you go back 20 years
to the birth of digital wallets.
And I remember in the early to mid 2000s,
every brand out there, a banking
brand or a payment network
or what have you, they had
their own digital wallet.
And at the end of that decade,
the only digital wallets
that actually survived were the two
that never called themselves a
digital wallet to start with.
It was Amazon and it was PayPal.
And they survived because
they were creating
true customer utility and
solving a true pain point
for customers, both consumers
as well as merchants.
So I think the same dynamic
is very much at play
in this Super App space.
You have to be providing compelling value
and reasons for your
customers to engage with you
on these multiple different
transactional vectors.
And also I think one of the obstacles
that will have to be overcome
is that while there's great utility
for smaller merchants to plug
into some of these things,
if you're a really big merchant,
you're not gonna want to
necessarily cease control
over your customer
relationship to somebody else.
You know, you want those
customers' eyes on your app,
not going somewhere else.
And so that's gonna be an interesting,
I think tension that we'll see
as we see these concepts
expanding across the ecosystem.
Neil, I know you have some thoughts
about some of the
challenges and opportunities
on this front as well.
- Hey Juliet, I do.
I think specifically when
I look at the question,
I think about what needs to change,
we have corporate and cultural.
I think corporate culture
is going to need to change
in order to really be effective.
And that is finding the
balance of cooperation
between different entities.
You mentioned some won't
want to give up control
and I think that's absolutely accurate.
They won't wanna give up control.
And it does to be really effective though,
we're gonna have to find
standards that can be met
across platforms, and there
needs to be some level
of portability in order
to really take hold.
You think about what phone
number portability did
in the mobile space.
I think there has to be
portability of service
and transactions to some degree
to really expand this out.
Otherwise it will be
multiple large entities
trying to compete with each other
and just fragmenting the market.
And that's gonna have to
kind of follow a balance
between cooperation and also be legitimate
with consideration to antitrust, right?
So we need companies to
work together on standards
but not so closely
together that it takes away
the competitiveness in the marketplace.
I think that's a fine
balance that companies
are currently far on the,
we're not going to trust each other
or work with each other so much.
And it needs to get
more towards the center
and not so far that we're
approaching a level of collusion.
And with that I think I'd ask Loren
to share his thoughts on it.
- Yeah, well Neil
I was gonna just riff
off what you said would,
you know that notion of an ecosystem
and it's gotta be open
and we've got to move away
from being proprietary on how we hold data
and how we share information
'cause I think that partnerships
among different companies
will help create that Super App.
I think that ecosystem matters a lot.
And what I find interesting, especially,
you know in the Western hemisphere
is that we are very finicky
about the number of apps we want.
It's like the latest
app, we wanna grab it.
And I think that's why our
phones have four or 500 apps
as it seems sometimes because
they're always after the latest greatest.
And I think that openness in ecosystem
will help make that possible,
you know, rather than have
to go to a single vendor,
a single solution, we have
that openness that's there.
And so I think corporations
are gonna have to change
you know they have to monetize
not based on proprietary value,
but on the ease of use
and on the flexibility
of their application platform.
- Yeah, that's a great point.
And just thinking about
what you guys are talking,
it's getting very futuristic
thinking about, you know
what are the opportunities
that you can expand into?
And then where are some of the challenges
getting there along the way?
But really what I wanna make
sure we spend some time on
is this next topic here,
the next couple of questions we have here
to really get into the fraud, security
and privacy questions because for me,
I think you're like, you're talking about
it's overwhelming to think
about having four or 500 apps
and all the different
things you're trying to do
between all of them and
keeping up with updates
and setting your profile up
and all of those sorts of things.
There's a lot of convenience
that comes with a single app
but I have to be able to trust them
and know that I can rely on them.
So as we think about, you know
what the top security challenges might be,
bringing all those
different services together
into one place,
well what do you think those
top security challenges will be
around identity, privacy,
and protection of sensitive data, right?
Because the breakdown of trust
can be really a central
problem that could break down
the entire trust of the
service and the makeup
of all the benefits we just
listed become a liability.
So Loren, maybe we'll
start with you on this one.
- Yeah, well I was gonna come on too.
I mean, in particular, the
privacy and consent requirements
'cause I think privacy is gonna continue
to become more and more important
and a company that holds everything
kind of that honeypot concept,
where if I hold everything
I become then that target
where the risk of the
data that I'm holding
becomes more and more important.
And I think being able to detect fraud,
being able to make sure
that I can identify
if it's a bot or if it's a human,
if I can look at, you know,
is this a high scale attack
and then be able to protect
the data that I'm storing
and then more so how do I
engage the user in the right way
to ensure that their privacy
is being maintained and consent.
And it's almost to that
point where, you know,
we can no longer really hold
somebody's personal information.
We've got to enable personal identity,
is a trend that's happening
in the identity space
to help enable end users
to protect their data.
And then corporations now are
really holding only metadata
and really information about the user
or about their transaction,
but not the data itself.
Hello Julie or Neil,
Julie do you have a comment?
- I can jump in and just...
I think you raise a really important point
about the trust factor.
And I think that goes hand in hand
with making sure that there's
a very clear understanding
among the customers
that are using your app
about where liability sits in
the event that there is fraud
and as you get more
and more services piled
into these Super Apps that
liability will differ.
And so having the
understanding as a consumer,
that if I'm getting payments into this app
and I'm storing funds with
this Super App provider,
do I have the same type
of Reg E protections
that I do in a banking environment
so that if somebody does,
commit account takeover
and empty out my account,
does the app provider have to
reimburse me for those funds?
Or do I, as the consumer
hold the liability?
Or with payments, you know
in the event that you're
using push payments
via an app to send money to somebody,
do you have the same kind of protections
that you do under Reg Z?
That's if it is fraud,
that you'll be kept whole.
And, you know, I think we saw, especially
with some of the mobile
wallets in the early days
there was a lot of fundamental
lack of understanding
among consumers about where
that liability should start,
about what their recourse was
if in the event that there was fraud,
and it's created some pretty
bad headlines, bad press,
you know, bad customer experiences
when those expectations were disappointed.
So I think by having a
really clear understanding
of what this is, and then
a very clear education
of your customers will
be critical for this.
Neil, anything to add?
- Yeah, Juliet.
I think of that,
you know you're talking about
the consumer understanding
or the user understanding liability.
I think that the risk here
is so great that it can be a
if there a fraud and it makes headlines,
it can create a virtual run,
instead of a run on the bank,
it can be a run on the service
and a service that's thriving today
could be virtually dead
tomorrow based on headlines.
And I expect that we'll see things
like authentication powered by, right?
I think we're gonna see some decoupling
of the primary service
and then some of the security controls.
And in general, I think we're
gonna see a plug and and play
to different providers so that if it's
if there is an issue,
then the institution that's
providing the overall service
can decouple from the authenticator
or the security control itself
and try and put an arm out and say,
that wasn't us, that the
distrust you feel should be
towards this organization over here.
It'll be interesting to see
if that actually plays out or not.
But I do think that companies
will look at more of a
chain of custody of events
for a Super App
because there's so many different
potential areas of fraud.
And there's gonna be a real concern
that a name gets solid based
on one particular integration
or one particular use case
like a pay at the pump
gets exploited for a specific brand,
than that brand name
that could be providing
hundreds of different services,
can really be brought down
just because of the local service station
and the interaction
that they may have had.
So I think that will be part
of the risk that we see.
And it's gonna be real interesting
to see how the market responds to it.
- Yeah, I was gonna comment Neil,
you're right that attack surface
has changed significantly.
It used to be, you know a corporate portal
or you know, maybe a web app
but now that you're
putting up mobile devices
and, you know pay at the pump,
and you pay at the grocery store
and you've got these mobile POSs,
they have had attack surface,
I think has expanded greatly.
- Yeah, the internet of things, right.
It becomes your, is your refrigerator
the future exploitable apparatus.
So, it's gonna be interesting.
- Yeah, no kidding.
And I think we've all seen
those situations arise
where we can imagine some of them
and some of them we
hadn't imagined, right?
Like I'm sure several read
the story a few years ago,
where there was a business
whose customer financial records
were accessed through
the internet of things,
connected thermometer from
their fish tank, right?
So there are things that we can imagine.
When designing that fish tank thermometer
there was never the thought, I'm sure,
that there might be a
data breach experience
at some business or financial institution,
but that can become the path
that gets exploited down the road.
So certainly I think learning
from situations like those
that, you know, we're all wary of that
when thinking about
how do we put our trust
into this kind of a Super App environment,
and is that any more risky
than it is with me interacting directly
with businesses that I do today?
Just to kind of continue
to pull that thread though,
around fraud and identity resolution,
what do you think is required to establish
a strong trust infrastructure?
One where you can authenticate
and use those Super Apps
and digital wallets with confidence.
So we just kinda continue
that conversation
a little bit further.
Neil, do you have
additional thoughts on that?
Maybe we'll start with you on this one,
- Yeah, sure.
I think the standards and where they start
and how they roll out globally
is really the starting point.
And if I think about where
will the strictest standards
come from and will those be
adopted for ease of use, right?
And we've seen that in
EU standards coming out
and then banks across the world
following those standards.
It's just easier to build platforms
to a single strong standard
and then be able to move
into a global footprint.
So we see that, and I
think we'll continue to see
the standards where they're generated from
and making sure that we're building this
to the strongest standards possible.
And with that, I'll turn it
over to Loren for his thoughts.
- I was gonna (indistinct)
when it comes to technology
and looking at how do we
solve some of these problems,
I break it down into a few things.
I think we first need to assess fraud.
And that's really, is it the device?
Is it the right user?
Is it, you know, any behavior
that we see as anomalistic,
but assess the fraud first.
Next is we verify and so
you gotta verify the user,
you gotta verify the device are
really who they say they are
or did they come from a trusted source?
And then you start the
registration process
where now I register who I am.
I also register the device
and pair it with the
right level of security
and then strongly authenticate.
And that can come not with
username, password anymore,
but really that adoption of
biometrics as well as face ID.
You know, those I think
have really strengthened
how we authenticate a
user based on the device
or the environment of
context that they're in.
The next would be authorized transaction
or authorized access.
And so really look at authorizes a user
to be able to see my data,
or a corporation needing
to authorize access there.
And then it really is just
then continually audit
and monitor and it's almost like
you bring the zero trust
concept to the identity world
and be able to essentially provide
a secure trusted process
but also be able to ensure
that just enough access is provided
for just right set of
capabilities that they need.
Julie, I don't know if you
have anything to add to that.
I'm sure you do.
(Julie laughing)
- Yeah, I think you
make some great points.
Yeah, I think with all of that,
we also have to keep in
mind that to get consumers
to engage and stay engaged,
it also has to be easy to use.
It has to have a positive
customer experience.
And so, you know, having the
appropriate levels of friction
at the right time, and
it gets even more complex
because as you go across
geographic boundaries,
you have places like the Nordics
where consumers expect friction,
they want friction, they
wanna feel protected.
And then, you know, at the
other end of that spectrum
we'll have the US where
it's just the opposite
and there's very low
tolerance for friction.
And so that's really
where digital identity
becomes very important into these concepts
and having the ability to
really maximize your use
of that metadata that
comes with the transaction.
And, you know, you were
talking a bit about
the opportunities and risks
associated with the internet of things.
And I think from an
authentication perspective,
the internet of things actually presents
some really interesting
opportunities going forward.
As you look at the fact that, you know
if you can see that Loren
is coming in from his PC
and he is within 20 feet
of his recognized Alexa
and within 20 feet of his
recognized smart thermostat
and within 60 feet of
his recognized smart car,
then all of a sudden you have
this very good understanding
that yeah, this is Lauren.
And so we need to let him
do whatever he's doing
and not put friction in his way.
And conversely, if you don't see
any of those trusted signals,
that's the appropriate
time to put friction in.
And we're not quite there yet
but I think we're moving pretty rapidly
towards that future state.
- Yeah, I know, I love it.
Yeah, I mean we think
the whole identity space
is becoming more personalized
and it's not just about securing
but it's about creating a good experience.
And I think you can get both,
it's kind of that festivals world
or, you know, that
synergy that is created.
So yeah, I really appreciate your points.
- Yeah and it's interesting
just as we think about that Julie,
bring up the example of certain markets
may actually be pleased to
see some degree of friction
or maybe certain types of transactions,
were pleased to see some kind of friction.
I'm sure those of us who
work in fraud and security,
especially, we're always very disappointed
if there's such a low hurdle
that we feel that our data
could have been compromised
but in the reality too
think to some degree,
the last several years, the
ship has sailed a little bit
with some of our private
information, right?
It's already been made
available to a large degree.
So if the new Super App has opened
and leverage is just the history of data
of things that have been
compromised, I'm a great example
you know, without using brand names,
I've shared documents online
in a personal level and photos as well.
I have a public email address
from a major distributor who
experienced a data breach.
You know, I connect with
other professionals online
in a place there was another data breach
and man, I love tacos and all these cards
were breached as well, right?
So a lot of their information's
already out there.
Can we talk about maybe
as our last topic here,
what role do we think
biometrics AIML can play
since just having me
creating a harder password
or answering instead of three questions,
can I answer seven questions about me?
Maybe aren't going to be the best approach
for some of these large markets
and ours being a good example of it.
- Yeah, I can jump in on that one first.
And I think as you look at, you know,
first the questions don't work
because the bad guys have all
the answers to the questions.
And often they have a better ability
to answer those questions than
the genuine consumer does.
So that's where, you
know layering in things
like, you know, device
fingerprints, behavioral biometrics,
email tenure, email reputation,
all of that great data that
we have available to us
by dint of engaging in
this digital channel.
You know, when you bring
all of that together
it really does require
having the machine learning
to make sense of it all.
And then, you know as you
are having to do things
to step up authentication
either because it's a
higher risk transaction
or you have some question marks
about that initial risk assessment,
that's where things like
device resident biometrics
are great because we as consumers
are now very well-trained
to do the facial recognition
or put the fingerprint down.
And so it's no longer viewed
as quite such a degree of friction
and you get into even
some of the gaming space
and they sometimes will
make it part of the game,
which is great, that's the win-win
from a customer experience perspective.
Loren, I know you spent a
lot of time talking to people
about this concept, so we'd
love to get your thoughts there.
- Yeah, for sure.
Well, I was gonna just
respond to your comment
about context in your last response.
And I think that's a big part
of what artificial intelligence
machine learning providers
that it's aware of
things that you're doing
either behavioral or the
context that you're in
around devices that
you trust or not trust.
And I remember attending
an analyst conference
a few years ago and the analyst said,
you know, why aren't we better modeling
how we interact on a human basis?
And so they're those people that we trust
because we have deep learning
and they understand us,
they understand what's important to me.
They understand the things
that I want to protect
and maybe some stupid trinket,
but to me it has high value.
And it's that what AI and
machine learning can give us
is collecting all that metadata
and being able to ensure that
there's context and trust
around it and then be able
to also model the behavior
according to what you value most.
And I think that that's a big
part of why AI is introducing
'cause it's going to give
us that implicit knowledge
and implicit understanding of
what's most important to us.
- Yeah, I think that's great.
I do wanna mention, I think AI is great
for zero day event as well, right?
We do a lot of time modeling.
What are the known behaviors and actions?
And how do they differ
from fraudulent attempts
and artificial intelligence
will ferret out differences
and behaviors, anomalies,
that we wouldn't even think
intellectually to put in place.
So...
- Excellent. Well, I know
we're running up on time.
That was an amazing conversation.
We covered so much in a short period here,
'cause I didn't even watch it back myself
and re-listen to some of
the commentary from you all.
Really appreciate your time.
I heard some great stuff
today just thinking
about the future and where we're headed
but especially what are
gonna be those challenges
in adoption of the Super Apps.
And I think from a business
and a consumer perspective,
gave us a lot to think about
here as far as cooperation goes
being mindful of privacy
and thinking about the critical role
of things like biometrics and so forth
and kind of a zero trust environment.
So thank you again,
appreciate our time from
Julie, Loren and Neil,
and appreciate all of you attending today.
Thank you so much
- Right, thanks Lee.
- Thank you Lee.
Loren, Julie, it's been a pleasure.
Thank you.
- Likewise.
- Thank you.