- Hey, hello, thanks for joining.
This session is on
resiliency, specifically,
building the business case for resiliency
and making sure that we get those outcomes
above and beyond making things available.
My name is Wolfgang Goerlich.
I am an advisory CISO for
Duo Security, part of Cisco,
but before that, I've
done a lot in continuity,
way back to when you had
to restore from tapes.
I've done a fair bit in incident response,
way back from when good
security was a firewall maybe
and an antivirus, and for many years,
I was doing consulting, right?
I was, hey, let's put
together a plan for you,
let's go ahead and run some tests,
and helped organizations
get ready for, for example,
pandemic planning, so
as you might imagine,
when 2020 rolled around, I
reached out and I was like,
hey, how's it going, right?
Remember that plan we wrote.
Remember that pandemic exercise we did.
Remember that time when
we set up a strategy
for working from home.
How did that go?
I really hoped, really
hoped, maybe naively,
I've been accused of being naive,
I really hoped that people
like, oh man, this saved us.
We're so ready, we're so prepared.
I really hoped that I'd hear, oh yeah,
we followed that document
and we're right up
and operational, but even organizations
where I'd run literal
pandemic tabletop exercises
using the CDC toolkit
for zombie preparedness,
which, by the way, if you haven't seen it,
highly recommend it, even with
organizations that did that,
a lot of them didn't realize the outcomes
that we had hoped, and so in this talk,
I'm gonna share a couple
different organizations,
different business cases
to highlight how to
make the business cases.
I'm gonna highlight where
people are going wrong,
especially in not getting
the outcomes we want,
but also, my team looked at hundreds
of business continuity plans,
disaster recovery plans,
incident response plans.
I want to boil down some of
those lessons learned for you
so after you make the business case,
you can avoid some common mistakes
and then talk about how to
drive downstream outcomes
from a good resiliency business case.
It is really important that
I give some context here.
I am gonna be talking about
recovery and continuity,
I'm gonna be talking
about incident response,
I'm gonna be talking about
good problem management,
I'm gonna be talking
about this in the context
of making our technology more resilient.
Why?
So that our business can operate,
so our organization can run key processes,
so we can execute on our strategy.
What this talk is not is
organizational resilience,
supply chain resilience,
personal resilience.
Those are incredibly important topics
well worth discussing here at
RSA, but for scoping purposes,
we're gonna be focused in more
on the IT side as we go forward.
Another key thing to point
out is that the stories
you're about to hear are
based on true events.
These three case studies are
composites that are typical
of what are in the market today.
These are not representative
of any particular organization,
environment, friend, client,
someone in the audience.
I'm not talking about you,
but these are all things
that I've ran into,
wrought into three composite case studies.
With that, let's talk about the first one.
Let's talk about a financial
services organization.
This financial services organization
is a money management firm.
It's trading on the open markets,
and when we first encounter
this organization,
we find a couple different things.
One, we find their continuity
plan is a call tree.
Needless to say, communication
plans are important.
However, having a communication plan
and a call tree in such a document
that's maintained separate of
anything else, always a risk.
Why?
Because people come and
people go, people change,
the numbers change, and now
we're maintaining things
in multiple different places.
Also, again, if it's just a call tree,
we're probably in a bad spot.
One of the reasons it's just a call tree
is that there's an operations manager,
really gung ho, great heart, great spirit,
who has been named as
the business continuity
and disaster recovery manager.
Now, you may wonder if
that's the right level
for this type of resilience,
we'll get back to that,
and the third component
of where they're at
is that they're testing their exercise,
their attestation that their plan works,
is an annual fire drill.
Really important to do a fire drill.
It's great to empty out the building.
Probably does not speak to the ability
to keep technology
running in a major outage,
probably does not speak
to the ability to recover
to something like a pandemic, right?
There's a lot of scenarios
that are missing here,
and the triggering point,
the precipitating event,
is an audit finding.
Third party audit looks
at their plan, says,
you know what, this does
not meet SEC requirements,
we need to address this.
So when we think about
building a business case,
there's really four main components.
There's the strategic context,
and we discussed that.
There's an audit finding
we need to think about,
high availability is important
for a financial services firm,
from a money management perspective,
we can figure out what
happens when we're down,
especially if the market's moving,
especially if there's a high trading day,
and that gets into the second
part of the business case,
which is the financials.
How are we going to
justify any improvement?
In this case, audit is a pretty big lever.
However, you'll find that the
compliance business cases,
oftentimes, the quickest to fund
but the hardest to fully fund
because from an audit perspective,
compliance perspective,
we're not protecting revenue,
we're not generating revenue,
it's not an area where
people such as the CFO
are gonna be inclined to fund.
So, we've got a hot business
case, but a business case
that may be limited in terms of funding.
Some other ways that we
could justify some funding
is, hey, how much money is on the table?
How much money do we stand to lose
if we're down for a period of time?
And then, traditional
security math, right?
We got this much money, we're
spending that to protect it,
there's your business case.
The third component of a business
case is your stakeholders.
Here we got internal audit
and external audit, of course.
The CFO is gonna be involved, and the CIO
in terms of making sure
technology is up and operational.
The COO currently owns this.
From the perspective of
being an operations function,
we're gonna want to get the CISO involved,
and then finally, we got
the management approach.
What are they gonna do
in terms of addressing
and setting up this capability?
I would argue that we need
to move this under the CISO.
There's also a good
discussion that can be had
about what does this say
to have this capability
at an operational level and
a project manager level?
It probably says that
continuity recovery and response
is not thought of as an executive issue.
Definite thought of as
a board level issue.
It may point to some
friction between the business
and the technology stack.
We'll want to delve into that
as we put together the business case.
And it probably means that
the way they're managing risks
is divorced from the technology risks.
So those are our main ways
that we're gonna go at this business case.
We're gonna justify it in
terms of closing an audit gap,
we're gonna find some budget
in terms of avoiding downtime,
and we're gonna move forward.
Now, this particular
client of organization
has the CFOs like, look,
what we gotta do is make sure
that we can withstand an asteroid.
If an asteroid slams into the ground,
I want to know that we
can keep on the market,
I want to know that we can resume.
In the asteroid scenario,
everything's flattened.
Great scenario to build for.
Does leave you with some
open questions, right?
Such as what happens if the
building is still available?
What happens if the
technology is still available?
What about all these different scenarios?
Shall we just build for the asteroid
or shall we also build
for little meteorites?
What happens about the zombies?
Have we considered the zombies?
In the next level, once we
got the business case in place
and we've got funding to move forward,
what we need to start thinking
about is how we're gonna take
all the potential disaster scenarios,
map them to a few high-level scenarios,
building outage for a period of time,
people working remote
for a period of time,
power, technology loss
and then map those back
to what we're gonna do
to protect that technology stack.
With an eye towards the CFO,
with an eye towards making sure
that this is budget-friendly,
especially given this is a
compliance business case,
we're gonna make sure
that we are really
prioritizing the IT assets
that are driving most of the
value to the business, right?
So, in this firm, this would be IT assets
for money management, for
trading, for reconciliation,
those sort of things.
Prioritizing on those will allow us
to better align our recovery strategies
with what matters to the business.
Now let's talk a little
bit about other outcomes
besides just keeping the lights
on when the asteroid hits.
Throughout this talk, I'm
gonna reference several times
a report that Cyentia did with Cisco
called the Security Outcomes Study.
What they did was they looked
at close to 5,000 respondents
and asked them a very key question
that we always want to
know, what are you doing
and what outcomes are you getting?
What outcomes are you getting
and what tasks are you performing
'cause there's a lot of different
tasks that we can perform,
including disaster
recovery and continuity,
as I just was discussing.
And then we figure out what
correlates by how much,
so what Cyentia found,
one of the many things,
is that organizations that had
good continuity and recovery
were much more likely
to gain the confidence
of the executive leadership.
My hypothesis there is it's
better to have that conversation
of, we're doing this with
this asset to protect trading
than it is to say, oh
yeah, there's a server
that could go down, or at
AWS, we've got some issues
with some of our instances, right?
It's better to be talking
about what matters
to the organization, and I
believe that's one of the reasons
why we see this outcome.
Likewise, another outcome
that's oftentimes seen
is the ability to keep
up with the business.
Again, I believe that ties back
to understanding what any
piece of technology means
within context of the organization.
A light bulb moment went
off in this process,
so you got your business case,
we've set up our scenarios
and strategies, we're
implementing the technology,
and a light bulb moment went
off for me when I realized
that if we are prioritizing IT assets,
if we're doing a business impact analysis,
if we're doing those sorts of things,
that gives us great
insight and intelligence
that can flow down into our
seam, that can flow down
into our vulnerability management program,
that gives us some
really good ways to say,
hey, this particular asset
that just had an alert
probably doesn't matter
because it's not tied
to a key process, or red alert,
that should be thoroughly investigated.
Why, because that is on the
direct path towards trading,
which, again, is how this
organization makes money.
So, using BIA to drive
prioritization, using prioritization
to drive other risk management functions.
And not too surprising,
the Cyentia study also
found that organizations
who had very effective recovery
and continuity programs
were also much more likely to
identify and manage top risks.
Again, I would argue that's
because they've got the context
of how those risks matter and
play out in the organization.
So, that is kind of under
recovery and resilience.
Let's talk about the next business case,
which will get us more
into incident response.
In this particular business
case, what we're looking at
is a software as a service organization.
Their starting point is,
hey, plan, what plan?
We don't need continuity
when we're distributed high environment
where everything is just failing over
and automatically spun up and spun down
and DevOps is awesome.
DevOps is awesome, however,
we do still need to think
about resiliency in here.
The primary business driver
is customer acquisition,
getting new customers,
retaining customers.
As you might imagine, downtime
is directly correlated
with losing customers and losing deals.
So the CISO is very focused on uptime
and is very focused on
code-level security,
making sure that the
product is very secure.
It's a great place to be,
however, as you might imagine,
that's a little bit in the weeds,
considering all the other
impacts organization might face.
So for example, you can have a
completely pristine code base
and still have features and functionality
that allow an adversary
to misuse your product.
You can have a completely
pristine code base
and still not have enough
resiliency in the backend
so that's usually have an outage,
and that ends the precipitating event.
An outage occurs, and now
we have a conversation
about continuity and recovery.
When making this business case, again,
we're gonna think about
those four things, right?
What's the strategic context?
Availability, uptime,
crucial for SaaS growth.
We may want to delve
into any unplanned work
or wasted effort that might be going on.
We may want delve into looking at this
not only as availability
issue, but also looking at this
as an incident response issue.
So responding to outages
and responding to attacks.
So, broadly, that's the context.
Financially, we're driving
this with customer retention.
One of my favorite ways
of making a business case,
by the way, because we're
able to speak to reliability,
we're able to speak to availability,
and we're able to tie that
down to incoming revenue
and customer retention,
which can provide us the pool
of money to invest in a recovery scenario.
Key stakeholders are the
product owners, the DevOps team,
and the CISO, and the management approach
is going to be viewing
this as a resiliency
within the DevOps function
and a governance within the CISO function.
So the CISO will own governance,
and will set availability
and set recovery times
and metrics and SLAs,
the DevOps team will run to them,
but will be predominantly
focused in on uptime
and good engineering, good SRE, right,
site reliability engineering.
A key point here is when
we think about peer support
and buy-in for security,
which organizations
that are more resilient
are more likely to have,
when we think about peer
support and buy-in for security,
what we need to be thinking about is,
what's in it for them, right?
And good business cases
like the business case
we're talking about here with the SaaS,
good business cases are
satisfying a business need
or a team need first, and by doing that,
they're providing security
as a secondary outcome.
I think it's really important
for me to say again,
just to emphasize, business cases
must satisfy the business need first,
and by satisfying that business need,
provide security as a secondary outcome.
Here, what we're looking at is
when anything is suspicious,
because it's broke or
because it potentially
is being attacked, go
ahead and address that
by running some scripts
and bringing things back up
in a quick way, which
gets to the second point,
which is how do we
minimize unplanned work?
How do we minimize wasted effort?
Well, we do that with automation,
we do that with automated scripts.
So, if the environment looks weird
and we're like, hey, that
shouldn't be happening,
why is that box running that service
and calling out to those IP addresses
that are on our known bad list?
Why are things coming in from Tor?
When things weird are
happening, right, take action.
How do we take action?
We run an Ansible script,
we reload an instance,
we push things out to a
known good environment,
we roll back and then roll forward
with whatever security controls
and new functionality we need to.
So, business cases that
satisfy that business need
through automation, those
business cases have an outcome
of minimizing wasted
work and wasting effort.
The light bulb moment for me
with this particular business case,
so you have the business
case of high availability,
you go ahead and map out your scenarios,
well, things could be broken,
things could be attacked,
there could be a disruption
in our down services,
or there could be disruption in the cloud,
you map those out and you come up
with some recovery scenarios.
We're gonna do this,
this, that, and the other.
We're gonna do those in
an automated fashion.
The insight that I had here
was that high availability,
specifically around the DevOps model,
high availability leads to high security.
So if you've had the opportunity
to see some, say, Sounil
Yu's DIE concepts,
that's exactly what I'm
talking about, right?
Distributed, immutable,
ephemeral infrastructure.
We've got a distributed environment,
we can lose multiple nodes
without having an impact.
If we got an ephemeral environment,
we can have multiple nodes compromised
and wipe those, reload those
without losing any data
and without missing a beat.
The key point here is that if we can erase
and rebuild the environment
faster than the adversary
can break in and stage tools
environment, we win, right?
Security wins, and that's
exactly what happened.
After they had this business case
and they implemented these scenarios,
there was a zero day exploit.
Not in the code, right?
Our code's good.
A zero day exploit in some
of the underlying systems.
That zero day exploit allowed
the adversaries to get in
and stage tools, so they got
in through the first layer,
started staging the tools.
Think about what an
adversary is gonna do next.
They're gonna try and
move laterally, right?
They're gonna scan, figure out
where else they can pivot to,
and as they scan and pivot,
that is being picked up, right?
It's being picked up on the network level.
That's weird, we don't usually see that.
It's being picked up on the host level.
It's being picked up on the API level,
especially if you've
got a good service pack
that enforces like a YAML file.
Oh, if you call, and
I'm expecting a dollar
and you're sending me a
whole bunch of strings,
probably something weird.
So it gets detected by the capability
the organization put in
place for resilience.
What happens?
Automated response.
Kill that node, reload it
with an Ansible script.
Good.
Now it's still vulnerable.
We're not patching,
it's a zero day exploit,
so that instance is still vulnerable.
The adversaries are out.
Now they may notice they're
out and break back in.
Okay, but the minute they go
to scan or move forward again,
what happens?
It's detected, they're
wiped, they're erased,
and it's that concept of
using high availability,
using resiliency to drive IR,
which is fascinating to me.
If that happens a few times,
obviously, we want to
get the IR team in place,
we want to do some investigation.
If it happens once or twice,
maybe it's simply a outage.
Let the SRE team use it and look at it,
but the underlying concept
here is high availability
and rapid response as a way
to mitigate incident response
and get ahead of things
and prevent the criminals
from moving forward into our environment.
Stopping them at the front
gate with a set of technology
that's predominantly
driving the business value
for the DevOps team,
and secondarily, providing
a security benefit.
So, with that, now that
we've looked at how IR
can tie into this resiliency case,
being automated using scripts,
let's talk a little bit
about the third business case,
and this one's in manufacturing,
so here we got a manufacturer
and they've got a few things going on.
Bit of an out-of-date
business continuity planning,
a good continuity plan but not one
that's necessarily aligned with standards.
Someone clearly took their CSSP example
and went, I can write
this, okay, it's good.
There are some parts in
the disaster recovery level
that are very good, so
plant level recovery,
if an asteroid hits, or
more likely a hurricane,
they can recover and move
things over, no problem.
However, if it's something
in back office technology,
we're gonna have other issues.
And then within the
back office technology,
we find there's a significant
amount of applications,
a million and one apps.
Everyone's been provisioning applications.
We don't necessarily know
what all these services do
and don't necessarily
know what they all mean.
We also know on the horizon
that there's a budget coming up
for a network refresh, and
the precipitating event here
is a customer demand.
One of their main customers
comes to them and says,
we want to see your plan
and we want you to get a certification
so that we can continue
to do business with you.
So, the strategic context here
is they need to meet this customer demand,
they need to address the customer need,
they need to achieve, let's
say, TSEC certification
so that they can accomplish this.
Financials, of course, are gonna be based
on customer revenue.
My favorite way, obviously,
to build a security business case
because when we're tied
directly to real revenue,
we're tied directly, especially
if it's a major customer
who's making up a significant
amount of the revenue,
you've got a lot more headroom
to build a good a recovery
strategy, and of course,
you've got a lot more momentum behind you
from the sales leadership and everything.
So, all right, the key stakeholders
will be sales leadership,
plant operations, and the CISO.
Management approach is gonna be
the continuity recovery
program under the CISO,
but the network program, the
technology implementation
under the CIO being overseen
by plant operations.
And some additional aspects
we need to consider,
obviously, they're in manufacturing,
so cost is always an issue.
We want this to be very cost-effective,
especially we can find
additional cost savings
out of implementing this,
and needless to say,
we want to make sure that
this level of technology
addresses the fail-over
scenarios we're concerned with
and keeps things up and operational.
So, in this business
case, in moving forward
into the next step with implementation,
one of the key things is doing
a business impact analysis.
Now, a business case should have a focus
on the primary business need, right?
The customer, and then
by satisfying that need,
as a secondary outcome,
increased security.
So satisfy the customer,
increase the security process environment.
However, we also need to think
about additional secondary outcomes
that the business case can have.
What additional ways can
move forward with this have
in terms of benefits for the
organization, and in this case,
what it was was the BIA, the
business impact analysis,
when we did the application inventory,
when we look at what
these services are doing,
what they mean in context
of a business process,
what they mean in context of
the business strategic intent,
when we look at those things,
we find a lot of redundancies,
we find a lot of opportunities
for consolidation,
for cost reduction.
So not only are we
delivering this main benefit
of keeping things up,
but we're also delivering a second benefit
of providing an inventory
that allows for a cost reduction
program to move forward.
Incredibly important.
As well as doing the original thing was,
was give us a standardized
plan that's easier to audit
and easier to defend.
We find that according to
the Cyentia study again,
that organizations that do have continuity
and recovery programs,
strong resiliency programs,
are more likely to be
run cost-effectively.
I suspect again it's because
of that additional context,
and I suspect if you want
to achieve that outcome,
what you need to do
is when you're building
your business case,
make sure that, as a secondary outcome,
it is providing insight into
where cost savings may exist.
Now this particular
organization follows this plan,
it has a business case, implements it
as part of a network refresh,
so we're not necessarily having to create
a new funding source.
As part of the network refresh,
implements some of the recovery strategy
that's identified in that plan.
So, when we're implementing it,
owned by the CIO and plant operations,
that budget funds the
technology stack refresh
and funds the recovery structure.
The way that they go about this
is effectively segmenting
off the key lines
for that key customer, adding
telemetry and monitoring
to those lines, making
sure if anything happens,
that it's detected, and
if anything's suspicious,
that that connection's shut down.
Very similar to the SaaS app,
but instead of going ahead
and shooting an instance in
the head and reloading it
and refreshing it, in this
case, what we're doing is,
when something's suspicious,
they're simply stopping
that network connection
and isolating that rogue IP address.
So that all gets done,
fast forward six months,
malware outbreak, right?
Malware outbreak, fast-moving worm,
they're infecting a whole bunch
of boxes, and as you know,
in manufacturing, it's very
common that we've got equipment
stretching back to the
late 90s, early aughts,
Windows XP boxes galore,
serial connections
and everything else, right?
The good old days, the good old days.
So this malware is
moving from host to host
to host to host.
Every time it touches one
of these lines that are,
have recently been
redone, are instrumented
for our resiliency and also instrumented
with recovery strategies,
every time it touches one
of those lines, of course,
the line sees that traffic,
it's suspicious traffic,
we're not supposed to be scanning,
trying to connect to us
over these protocols,
and it would block that
backend IP address.
Great example, great example of resiliency
leading to better security.
Also, what I thought was very interesting
and the light bulb moment for me was,
not only was that useful
in preventing the breach,
however, in the incident response,
the incident responders got
involved, looked at those logs,
looked at the traffic sources,
and used those secured lines
as, effectively, another
source of intel to figure out
where the infections were coming from.
Reconciling with our asset
inventory, tracing down the boxes
but using those lines as one more feed
to figure out what was going
on in their environment, right?
Using them as a detective control.
Really interesting way to view
a system in a business case
that started off with we
need to save this customer,
we need to do right by them.
So, not surprisingly, from
the Cyentia perspective,
they found that organizations
with good resilience are more likely
to avoid major security
issues and incidents.
As part of this, also feeding
into problem management
with good intel and good insight.
All right, let's talk next
about where things go wrong.
My team read 176 business
continuity plans,
so you don't have to.
I almost feel like I
should feed them to a bot.
You know those, oh, we fed
a million plans to a bot
and it wrote our plan.
(sighs) Actually, now
that I think about it,
I think I read the plans
written by a bot. (chuckles)
Here's some of the ways that organizations
who have a good business
case and good intentions
fail to capture some of the
benefit of these business cases.
Top three failures.
One is the wrong person.
I talked about this a
little bit earlier, right?
Giving the BC role to
someone who's in operations,
but we want to make sure that
the person who's in charge
of this has the trust, the
ability, the budget, the acumen,
the staff to actually go
ahead and act on these plans
and drive them forward over a longer term.
Number two is the wrong technology,
recovery at the wrong level.
Oh, we got front end load
balancers, don't worry about it.
Okay, that's great for your front end,
but what happens about
that database server
that is a single instance
and not in a recovery zone?
Oh, (chuckles) right,
whatever your accepted
threat scenarios are, from
asteroids to pandemics
to cloud outages, whatever
those are, you need to make sure
that you've got a corresponding
technology strategy
that's going to address those,
and technology that supports
and enables that strategy.
So that's the second thing we think,
and then the third thing is,
now that we've got this
great recovery strategy,
let's test it.
We see a lot of times that the
goals for testings are wrong.
People are testing
things that don't apply,
they're running a fire
test instead of testing
when the data center's out,
they're testing working from home
instead of testing what happens
when our cloud has an outage,
they are the wrong drills.
Several other ways things
could get mucked up, right?
People, oh, it's outsourced,
don't worry about it.
The cloud provider handles it all.
Remember your part in this.
Non-standard language, oh
yeah, we've got RTO, RPO,
but they're not using the
terms the right way, yeesh.
That oftentimes goes part and
parcel with wrong approach.
Again, I'm not saying
things have to be ISO 22301
or the NIST standards.
They don't have to be,
however, as a starting point,
you have a greater degree of success
if you start with a
standard-compliant approach.
Oh, it's high availability,
don't worry about it.
We got our servers in HA zones.
Okay, but does that cover
all your recovery scenarios,
and does that cover all
your threat scenarios?
Overly broad plans, well, did I mention
we got a cloud provider
that handles everything?
We're all good.
Or the opposite is overly specific plans.
I tend to think about
this as the black swan
versus the unnamed goose.
The black swan event occurs,
we dress for that, awesome,
but we also want to make
sure that whatever else comes
that's bird-shaped, we're prepared for.
And then finally, handle
these in isolation.
I'm gonna talk more about
that in just a moment.
When we think about
integrating these things
with other aspects of security,
there's several steps to do.
First part is knowing what
matters and what to do with it.
Critical outcome from
resiliency and continuity.
We can tie that, the risk
ranking prioritization,
asset inventory back to
our operation centers,
we can give that information
to our incident response team,
and we can give that
information to our GRC team.
A surprising outcome from this
was that the Cyentia and Cisco report
found that organizations
were having greater ease
at retaining top talent,
and I think that's because
we're not wasting time
investigating something that
we think is a critical asset,
only to realize it's some
un-patched printer somewhere.
We've all had those days
where we spent a ton of time
on something only to
realize it doesn't matter?
That's what we want to avoid.
There's some additional
integration points here.
Flowing down that asset
prioritization into our seam
for logging, monitoring,
detecting, alerting response,
flowing that into our
vulnerability management program
so we know which patches
are most impactful.
This piece of technology
is running our core process
versus this piece of
technology is, I don't know,
running that service somewhere, right?
Having that visibility.
Also, if we know that the
technology is critical,
we can then begin to say,
okay, what does that mean
for perhaps a malicious sysadmin?
What does that mean
for perhaps a compromised privileged user?
Probably doesn't mean anything very good.
A lot of the resiliency
that we talked about
is based on non-human entities, right?
An asteroid or a pandemic or a malware,
but if it is a human entity,
the same ideas apply,
so flow that down to PIM
and PAM, as well as use this
to prioritize alerts
coming out of DLP, UEBA,
and other technologies.
I would be remiss if I didn't point out
that we don't want to separate resiliency
from the organization.
I'm talking about resiliency
as an IT security function,
therefore, within the
domain of cybersecurity,
but resiliency affects
more than IT and infosec.
We want to start with the
business case for continuity,
recovery, and response.
Start there but take care not
to separate and isolate it.
Now once you've got
those recovery strategies
that map back to your scenarios,
exercise the heck out of them
so that we know they work.
You can start with a story
and just talk through it,
you could do a tabletop,
you can do a tabletop
and tie it back to standards and tactics,
you can tie that into a framework
and do a full pull exercise,
and you can take this all the way up
to doing a full pull exercise
and automating that exercise
with a chaos monkey or
chaos engineering approach
and moving into continuous improvement.
We're not gonna move
everything to level five.
That would be ridiculous,
but knowing that we have
these different points
can take any given scenario
and figure out how
important that scenario is
and the extent to which we
test it, and when we test it,
we want to make sure that it measures up
compared to the metrics the
organization sets in place.
So build the business
case, set the metrics,
test those scenarios.
So wrapping up this talk,
let's talk about something
other than IT for a minute.
Let's talk about something
a little bit more old school
in terms of technology.
I'm gonna ask you to do me a favor.
The next time you're in a building
and you step in an elevator, look down,
just look down for a minute.
Check out to see who the
elevator manufacturer is.
I'm willing to bet it's Otis,
and if you don't know the
story of the Otis elevator,
you should definitely take a look at it.
It's really fascinating.
The namesake is Elisha Otis.
Elisha Otis in the 19th
century would set up platforms,
go to the top of them, had
crowds around him, cheering,
and then that platform would
be pulled up with a rope,
and when he's at the very top of it,
they would swing a sword, a sword.
There's not enough swords in security.
They would swing a sword, cut
the rope, and he would fall,
on the crowd would gasp,
and at the very last minute,
he would be saved by an elevator.
Saved by a brake, right?
Otis elevator succeeded
by inventing the brake,
and they patented in 1913.
It was that security control,
the brake of the elevator,
that allowed us to reach
for the sky, right?
Enabling the last great migration,
moving from country to city,
moving from the ground floor
to the sky level, all that was enabled
by resiliency, by a brake.
Today, we are in the midst
of the next big migration,
where people are not
necessarily moving from cities
but moving online.
We're in the midst of
the greatest migration
in our lifetime, where we are
seeing the first migration,
arguably, from largely
physical to virtual,
everything being online,
and because of that,
IT resiliency has never
been more important.
Because of that, the brake,
the brake that we're building
is going to be what enables
the wonders that are to come.
What to do next with
information we talked today?
Well, know your drivers, right?
Know your strategy and the
environment that you fall into.
In the first three months,
do some gap assessment
and figure out what type of
improvements need to happen,
figure out where your
headwinds and tailwinds are,
and build that business case as discussed.
Now, when you build that business
case and you move forward,
don't just implement business continuity.
Please, as you close those
gaps, think about resiliency
in the broader context of security,
tying it in with security
initiatives like we talked today,
and make sure that you're
testing those things regularly
because if we don't test and
we don't verify our scenarios
and we don't get those outcomes,
that's when things happen,
and suddenly, those plans
that we've spent so much time
to put together don't
actually come together
and don't actually protect us.
Thank you so much for
joining this session.
I hope you have a great
RSA, and by all means,
reach out with any questions or comments.