- Hello, my name's Bill
Malik, I'm with Trend Micro
And I'm here today to speak
with you about the Zero Trust
challenge for hybrid cloud.
Now, what is this gonna involve?
In the course of this
talk we're going to ask
a little bit about what Zero Trust is,
a lot of definitions out there
and I wanna level the playing field.
Then we're gonna look particularly at what
hybrid cloud lacks that
Zero Trust can help with.
This really will explain the
core of this presentation
but in order to balance this,
there are no panaceas,
there are no silver bullets.
We're gonna ask some things about
what Zero Trust cannot do
and what hybrid cloud
does not need from it,
so that'll balance things out.
In order to expand our horizons a bit,
I'm gonna delve into some future
problems for hybrid cloud,
in edge computing and 5G in particular
that are gonna cause us to have
to extend our understanding
of information security architectures.
And then we'll finish up
with a couple of slides of
recommendations and next steps.
As for me, I've been at
it for four or five years,
I started work as a programmer in Boston,
wrote code in COBOL.
Yes, I did the Y2K
problem, like many others,
which YBM in Poughkeepsie wrote
code for operating systems.
Joined Gartner, who there for 11 years,
managed the information security service
and also the application
integration in middleware service.
In the turn of the century,
I became a member of a
consulting organization
then was CTO of Waveset
and after leaving that
following sun's acquisition,
I spent most of the time as
an independent consultant
and I joined Trend about
three and a half years ago.
So that's me, that's our
task and let's step in.
What is Zero Trust?
In order to understand the management
of an environment this complex,
I'd like to start with a story.
This is about two people who
are excellent watchmakers.
They both make beautiful watches
and each watch has a thousand parts.
Now Tempus, the watchmaker,
assembles the thousand part
watch, one piece at a time
Hora breaks down the task,
he builds a watch when
he has 10 assemblies.
And assembly consists of 10 sub-assemblies
and each sub-assembly has 10 parts.
So they put together there watches
but when they're interrupted
they have to put the watch down
and whatever they're
working on falls apart.
So on the average Tempest
gets 500 pieces done
before he puts it down and it falls apart.
On the average Hora he
gets five pieces done,
when he puts down the
thing he's working on
and it falls apart.
They both create the same watch,
with the same number of parts,
they both have the same skill.
The difference is because
Hora uses a methodology,
because he compartmentalizes the tasks,
because he understands the
relationships of the components,
Hora makes 4,000 watches
for every watch that Tempus completes.
This is a paper on the
architecture of complexity
that was published many, many years ago,
I have the reference in the deck.
Bear this in mind as we go
through what's necessary,
to secure a cloud.
If you get interrupted,
we don't want you to lose
more than a handful of parts,
we certainly don't wanna have to start
over from the beginning.
So, what is it with cloud
that requires all this
additional care and feeding?
Well, first thing is there's
always gonna be something
that you remain responsible for in cloud.
Even if you're using a
business process as a service,
you're still gonna be
responsible for making sure
that the service level
agreement is being fulfilled,
that you're paying for
what you're asking for.
Of course, the more you
put in the more you control
but at no point does
it completely go away.
And we're gonna remind ourselves
of that as we move forward,
notice the cloud does
take some responsibilities
off your desk but not all of them.
So let's begin by looking
at what Zero Trust is.
Zero Trust dates from the
actually the late 1990s,
when it was known as the concept
of Network Access Control.
The philosophy behind Zero
Trust is there is no perimeter.
There is no boundary of trust.
There is no reasonable
assumption of people
who are inside that mythical boundary,
are somehow trustworthy
and therefore don't need
to be authenticated.
In a Zero Trust world
there are no perimeters
and the cloud has no perimeter.
There is a source of trust
and this is problematic,
it's why the name is
kind of difficult for me,
when I initially ran into it.
There is one source of trust
and you go to that source of
trust to authenticate yourself
and to get the appropriate permissions.
So let's say minimal
trust, maybe a better name.
You assume a minimal need to know,
you will need multi-factor authentication
to provide security in critical tasks,
such as super users,
such as permissions that
involve control over,
devices that themselves have
critical security functions.
Zero Trust includes the actions
of logging and verifying
and auditing and reviewing those logs.
Making sure that what is going on
is what you expect to go on
and other processes don't happen.
And one of the principles
of Zero Trust very much
is to establish and maintain
the separation of duties.
We don't wanna have a single individual
responsible for too many components.
This involves some changes
to our traditional mindset
about information security.
Traditionally, if you were
on the private corporate internal network,
it was assumed that everything
there was trustworthy.
In the Zero Trust philosophy,
nothing is trusted by default.
We assume that the identities
are who they say they are,
in the Zero Trust world
we verify everything.
In fact, in Network Access Control
if you attempt to link to a network,
the system, the network
before admitting you
will scan your device to see
if you've got current patches,
you've run an antivirus scan.
Your antivirus scan is, they
relatively current and correct
and from an approved vendor
and so on and so forth.
You assume that users act responsibly
in the traditional security model
and we grouse about the fact that
the user didn't follow a policy
or our awareness and training
program isn't working.
Well, maybe a better
approach would be to say,
users are busy and they
have other things to do,
so while they're gonna do
their best with security,
it's not what they're being
evaluated on professionally,
it's a component.
And so therefore we're going to nudge them
towards not making mistakes.
And finally, in the
traditional security model
we try to model, we try to
detect security attack behavior,
we look for indications of compromise.
Well, in the Zero Trust philosophy,
we're gonna make it harder for
the attacker to do anything
rather than looking for a particular
indication of compromise,
we're gonna put everything
in its own segment
to the extent that that's feasible.
So how do we get there?
Well, in order to verify identity,
we're gonna rely on
multi-factor authentication.
In order to restrict network access,
we're gonna segment, we're gonna use DMZs.
We're gonna be parsimonious
about what resources
are available to users
on what networks.
And we're gonna use
applications safe listing
to prevent updates,
to prevent the installation of road code,
to close down the
attractiveness or availability
of shadow IT or shadow
cloud or even shadow OT.
Now, this relates to SASE as
a component of Zero Trust.
One of the keys of SASE,
secure access service edge.
It's a concept that says you're gonna put
security controls in the cloud
since that's where most
of what happens goes on.
One of the concepts there
is to use a CASB, cloud
access security broker
and a secure web gateway
to make sure you know what
applications are being accessed.
And going beyond the traditional VPN,
we wanna have application
specific connections.
A lot's been written about
why VPNs are not the greatest,
why they don't really
solve as many problems
they pretend to.
I won't go through those arguments now
but it certainly is a topic
that we should discuss at some other time.
Anyway, so this together
brings Zero Trust,
and I've introduced the concept of SASE.
And we'll get later into edge computing,
seeing how all this comes together as
the next big things roll out,
one of which of course is 5G.
So, why does hybrid cloud need Zero Trust?
That's our next topic and the answer is
because there are a lot of
security issues with cloud.
New sets of services
coming up all the time,
DevSecOps, the sec is often
silent in polite conversation,
increases the speed with
which new apps show up
in the environment.
These new capabilities
provide new routes of attack
for the bad guys.
I'm trying to stay away
from the word hacker.
Back in the old days,
a hacker was somebody who was very good
at solving hard problems with computers.
The notion that a hacker
would do so for profit
or reduce so to cause trouble.
So that's a relatively late innovation,
so I'm gonna be a little
bit of a curmudgeon and say,
the cyber crooks are the
ones we're worried about.
There are many teams making
acquisitions in infrastructure.
They're making decisions about
security policies sometimes,
not even making them explicitly,
making them by default.
Experience has shown that the default
security posture is inadequate,
hence the need for a
Zero Trust environment.
Compliance requirements are increasing,
there are legal and regulatory issues
that organizations face.
These will get stronger,
we're beginning to see these
enter even in the world of OT
and finally, there are far
too many security tools.
And this is a problem for a lot of folks,
I'm gonna deviate from the
agenda just a moment here.
Most organizations use about
30% of the capabilities
of the information security
tools they have installed today.
And the reason is not because
they missed something,
the reason is because
when they bought the tool
it was fit for purpose.
And in the intervening months and years
since they installed the tool,
the vendor has continued
to add capabilities.
So there are a lot of functions
in the security products
you've already installed
that you probably haven't turned
on, may not have explored.
And in some cases,
tragically may have actually
bought alternative products
to provide a function that
you've already bought, paid for
or train your users on.
So a lot of challenges for cloud security
is getting more complex.
And this generates a lot
of different pain points,
here are some of the ones
that a person managing cloud
will have to worry about,
audit and governance.
Where's the data going?
who's operating on it?
If I'm using a SAS based service,
are there any residency
requirements about that?
There was an issue some years ago,
where an organization was
handling financial data
and they had subbed it
out to a SAS provider.
And the SAS provider had subbed that out
to a team working in a country
that was not on the approved list
for the handling of that kind
of financial information.
Well, guess who the problem ends up on?
You're not gonna go to the
sub subcontractor and say,
"You have refused that work."
And you're not gonna go to
the subcontractor and say,
"Didn't you know
that this data was supposed
to stay in this geography."
No, you're gonna have to look at a mirror
and said, "I didn't make it clear enough."
DevSecOps challenges the
traditional notion of change
and release management.
I'm a big fan of iTOL,
I'm a big fan of COBIT by the way also
but change in release is really the gate
by which you get stuff from
the world of development
and test and experimentation
into the world of production.
And although we've
certainly accelerated it,
I surely hope that you have not taken away
any of those controls.
The controls still need to be in place,
we still need to know
what's going out there.
We still need to be able to go back
to a point in time and say,
what set of application functionality
and what set of data was
available at a point in time?
How can we recreate the environment
that led to this transaction,
leading to that result?
Interesting problem, especially
when the data is not here
and the processes are not
here and all we've got
is some kind of an audit
or transaction log.
The pain points for information security
include shadow cloud, include Zero Trust,
which related to identity management.
The two are not synonymous.
The definition of a CASB includes
the notion of identity management.
The problem with that definition
is that identity management
is one of those things that we
in the high-tech role of
information security call hard.
Identity management is a tough problem
and you don't wanna
bundle a piece of it in,
with one other function,
you'd rather have the CASB
light capability interfaced
with a more general
identity management solution
that the enterprise
can run, one of global.
Garbage collection is
an interesting problem,
it has real implications for 5G
and I'll get to that later on.
There are pain points
associated with procurement
and contract admin.
How do you know you're
getting what you paid for?
not paying too much?
How do you know that the acquisition
conformed to your
baseline is for security,
for management, for collection
of performance data?
Did we really need that bump,
was the transaction level so high
that we had to instantiate
another 20 images
at that point in time?
And how long did it take to clear it up?
And when people buy cloud on their own,
are they conforming to our
procurement guidelines?
Well, if they don't know what they are,
the answer is probably not.
And if they do know what they are,
one of the reasons they went
to shadow cloud was probably
because they didn't wanna go
through all of that stuff,
just like with shadow IT.
Performance capacity
management monitoring,
those issues are generally
harder with (indistinct)
because you can't put your
performance monitoring tools
into Google's or Azure's
or IBM cloud data center
and have them install them on the servers
where your stuff happens to
be running at the moment.
And then there are skill
and organizational challenges.
First one that comes to mind is G,
we moved everything to cloud
and saved a lot of money
on servers and storage, G.
I'm an employee and I'm kind of expensive.
If I take my salary and double it,
that's my fully burdened head count cost
for this organization.
I wonder if they're thinking
about saving money on people,
the same way they thought
about saving money on servers.
That is, am I likely to be replaced
by an outsourced third party individual?
And when an organization
takes the step to go to cloud
and to go through that and
to declare this success
because they downsize their data center,
the people that work in the data center
rightly, are gonna be concerned,
well, are they gonna downsize us next?
And where do those skills go?
Many organizations has
gone so far in cloud,
they cannot come back anymore.
They no longer have the skills
to handle change a release management,
performance and capacity management,
the installation and maintenance
of physical hardware.
Now, who has responsibility for what?
The people in the organization
may have new duties
that may be rotated
into other assignments.
They now need to know
what constitutes effective performance.
Note that Zero Trust
does not enter address
most of these capabilities.
And that's the split
between where Zero Trust helps
cloud and where it doesn't.
There are some problems in other words,
Zero Trust doesn't solve.
So why do you need additional security?
Well, we've talked about the
increased range of threats.
The pace of attacks is going up.
The scope of attacks is increasing
and there are the issues I
mentioned with compliance,
payment card industry
standards are still in place.
HIPAA regulation, their
GDPR is getting stronger
and being enforced more rigorously
and internal audit and
compliance management.
Are we really spending the
money we thought correctly?
So where does Zero Trust work in cloud?
Well, hybrid cloud needs Zero
Trust for identity management.
In real time, I got to know who you are
and I got to know what you're
allowed to do right now.
That depends on an identity
management infrastructure.
Quick bit of history,
we have a few minutes.
In the beginning computers
were used to manage money
in business, that was the first
use GE, calculated payroll
in order to save on the
costs of a line of clerks,
rows and rows of clerks
tabulating payroll and so on, manually.
Numbers are easy, they are dimensionless,
they're simply a quantity,
they don't age, okay?
So the fifties and sixties
were about digitization
in the sense of handling bucks.
The seventies and eighties we
began not just computing bucks
but we began computing stuff,
things, parts, bill of materials
and its successor database,
bill of materials, bump and d-bump.
Which led to enterprise resource planning,
which read the supply chain management.
Now, the interesting thing
when you're managing stuff
as opposed when you're managing money,
is that stuff ages, it wears
out and has a sell by date.
It has a serial number, it has a history
and it has a maintenance requirement.
It has an expiration date maybe.
And it has certain parameters
that may require it to be tuned
and updated at a certain time.
So it varies over time
but because these are physical things,
they vary with an exponential
decay kind of a curve,
they age at a certain known rate.
In the nineties
we began looking at other
ways we can actually manage
the capabilities of a person,
that got us into the issues
of, can I solve single sign on,
(indistinct) solve
distributed administration.
Those two things came together
in identity management.
The problem with people is
people are non-linear and they
very non-linearly over time.
You have one job and then
you go through some training
and you go to another job.
Well, your permissions don't change.
When you go from one job to another,
it's not like you quit and started.
There are some tasks
that you gotta finish up
before the permission is let go.
There are some permissions
you're gonna keep
across the transition.
There are some new tasks
that you're gonna pick up immediately,
other new tasks that you're
not gonna be able to start
until you complete some kind of training
or background check.
And ultimately there are some
permissions that you have now
that will stop the
minute you lose that job.
So identity management is
a really complex problem.
Things that are in consistencies
may not be inconsistent at all.
And so managing identity
is a really hard problem
and doing it across multiple platforms
is incredibly complex tasks.
That's why there are
only a couple of vendors
that can even do this
anymore, rely on them.
Network attacks, big
problem for hybrid cloud
because who knows what
networks are involved there.
You have a limited set of controls
from your end as the enterprise manager,
as to what's going on
and shadow cloud is a
significant problem as well.
That's where a user
installs an application
and maybe unbeknownst to them,
they end up subscribing to cloud.
You put your Apple Watch
on, you bring it to work
and the next thing you know
you've got Apple cloud
capabilities on your work machine
because your watch found
its way through Bluetooth
to some local access point.
These are tough problems to solve
and Zero Trust makes it easier
because along the way people,
systems are gonna say,
is this permission allowed?
Is this access legitimate
given that individuals
requirements and business needs
and current set of authorizations.
So what does a Zero Trust not to do
and what does hybrid
cloud not need from it?
Well, looking at the security
challenge different way,
there's the visibility of
what's going on in the cloud.
There's the question, do I
know the rates, the speeds
and feeds of my portfolio
of instances right now?
Am I able to update
them through compliance?
Am I able to secure them as
they come into existence?
Do I have the ability to bring up
yet another secure instance?
And I'm gonna mention this point again,
every cloud instance is perfectly
secure when it's created.
It is only by the intentional acts
of the people working
on that cloud instance,
that it is rendered insecure,
that it is rendered visible
to unintended persons,
that it ends up on the internet
with access to everyone.
That is a huge problem.
And unfortunately, Zero Trust in itself
does not really address that.
If you've said the services
universally accessible,
then Zero Trust will diligently
grant universal access.
Now, we'd like to see products
that can nudge and say,
are you really sure
you want this to be
accessible by everybody?
Are you really, really
sure you want to be,
click here if yes and the
OK button is that big.
And that's the kind of human factors
we'll need to get it.
The first people to think
through, what are we really doing?
Because what a cloud
builder is thinking about
is not about how to secure it.
They're trying to help organizations
that are doing cloud native,
bringing new stuff to the new world
in these various exciting new forms,
using DevSecOps to drive new
workloads with minimal delay,
going with serverless capabilities.
There is a Kubernetes joke
involving the Suez Canal
that I'm not gonna tell
but that's on the left side,
that's cloud native applications.
Cloud migration is the organization
that's in the process of migrating
from a traditional data center
or a blended environment
into a hybrid cloud norm,
cloudFast, if you will.
It doesn't mean there
won't be anything left,
it just means we're gonna be parsimonious
at stately and appropriate
in our progression from
this here data center
into that there cloud.
And then finally on the right,
the set of strategic priorities is,
are we doing as well as we can do?
I'm developing a talk to be
delivered later this year,
that actually looks at what
cloud operational excellence is.
Back in the nineties Gartner acquired
a company called Real Decisions,
they did benchmarking.
The goal of Real Decisions
was to help people figure out
how efficiently they were
using their data resource,
their processing resource,
their network resource.
And what they found was,
generally as a rule of thumb
the top 10% were an
order of magnitude better
at making use of those
resources than the bottom 10%.
Whether it was people or
staff or organization,
network hardware, a
software defined networking
whether it was software defined storage.
Whatever it was, the
difference between good and bad
is an order of magnitude,
which means you need to
know what you're good at.
And if you wanna use cloud,
you don't have the option
of backing out of it,
you've gotta figure out how to get better.
So we need to look at that.
Now I gonna dig in a little
bit some vulnerabilities,
shadow cloud, the problem
there, texts cheaper than ever.
Just like shadow IT, shadow OT,
individuals can purchase capabilities
for very small amounts.
Stuff that doesn't even
reach the threshold
of a purchasing decision.
Stuff that shows up on an
individual's credit card.
I use a service to
post-process my audio work,
when I do blogs, I pay
$11 and 70 cents a month
for that capability.
If I had to install the software
and train up on the product,
it would be probably
two months of training
and hours and hours of
work on the machine.
In multi-vendor environments,
digital platforms with
heterogeneous of ours,
this is the process of
digital transformation.
The fact that you're
gonna have shadow cloud
hanging around there is a real risk.
It can become a portal for attack,
it can become a path
for exfiltration of data
and the existence of these,
whether they're integrated
in a full digitally transformed enterprise
or whether it's just some
simple SAS application
with a new feature, you don't know,
for sitting inside IT,
is these things happen.
You do not know if you've been attacked,
if somebody made a mistake, if
it was simply a side effect,
you do not know what's going on.
Shadow cloud really
puts things in a pause,
so, yeah, the first reaction
is can we lock it down?
Don't think about perimeters,
think about actions and user needs
and what you can do to nudge
them towards correct behavior.
And here's the message,
misconfiguration is the
biggest problem you've got.
Every cloud instance starts
out perfectly secure,
it is converted into an
insecure environment,
following the procedures
that your technical team
has well-grooved.
So here a big pitch for
process improvement.
Here's a big pitch for
first failure analysis.
Here's a big pitch for process innovation
to rectify, to correct
those kinds of issues.
So lastly, I wanna get into
some of the exciting new stuff
that's happening, edge
computing, I jumped a slide.
New stuff that's happening,
edge computing, 5G
and how SASE, these are
gonna stress hybrid cloud.
So what is going on with edge computing?
What Moore's law, we all know,
the number of people who think Moore's law
is about 10 doubles every couple of years.
It turns out in reality,
there are three flavors of Moore's law,
a processor density at
constant cost doubles,
about 18 to 24 months.
Storage density doubles
about every 12 to 15 months,
network capacity doubles at a
nine to 12 months frequency.
In other words,
there are three different
flavors of Moore's law.
Let's take a look at the implication
of these exponential growth curves.
The area I've highlighted
here on the bottom right
at months 120, shows that after 10 years
processor capacity has gone up
by about a factor of 10.
Storage capacity at
constant use has gone up,
I'm sorry, (indistinct) a hundred,
storage capacity has gone
up by a factor of a thousand
and network bandwidth
is 10,000 times greater.
That's been our experience
for more than a decade.
This means that you no longer
want to have a large computer
with resident data, that
is an inefficient model.
What you want to do instead
is to move the data to
the relevant processors.
Here are the conclusions.
Move the data to the relevant processes
because large amounts of
data can get there quickly,
we've got the bandwidth.
Latency is still a problem
for time applications.
So you wanna have the processor
is close to the action,
close to the devices
that are being managed.
Think self-driving cars,
think V to V environments
or V to E inside of crowded cities.
You wanna have lots of
data globally available.
You wanna move that data
to nearby processes,
those are edge machines.
It may persist there, it may not.
Note that interestingly enough,
edge computing partially solves
the problem of the outer join.
If you don't remember
what the outer joined
problem is, go in piece,
it was a tough thing
basically from the day
that SQL was invented.
So what SASE does is it says,
let's recognize the reality
of the new environment,
securing the establishment inside,
solves less than half the problem.
More people are doing work
off enterprise and enterprise.
More workloads are running
in various forms of
infrastructure as a service,
then in the enterprise data center.
More apps are consumed via SAS.
More data is located out the enterprise,
more traffic for public cloud
than the enterprise data center
and more traffic then for
branches heading to the cloud.
We are not a centralized organization.
There's a vestigial data center
at the enterprise headquarters
but everything is outside.
So protecting the perimeter
from an internal set of controls
is gonna miss me most of the action.
So we wanna get from SASE to Zero Trust.
SASE was defined in 2019,
a lot of vendors have
jumped on the bandwagon.
A lot of people are more confused
that's why we went
through the introduction,
secure access service edge.
Zero Trust is you never trust,
it's not focused on a particular
tool, it's a philosophy,
it's a design principle.
SASE on the other hand
is directly related to taking advantage
of security based right in the cloud.
The SASE vendors,
themselves will identify
themselves as SASE
and it must be deployed by a
cloud provider in the cloud.
So SASE is a instantiation of Zero Trust.
The common goal is to secure the business
with contact sensitive and
identity based policy management.
Zero Trust does that
generally as a design,
SASE does that specifically
as a particular dimension.
You can compare vendors of SASE products.
You cannot compare
discussions of Zero Trust,
except on terms of
intellectual completeness.
One last task I mentioned
is, I wanna get through this,
it's a detailed problem but
it goes back a long way.
John McCarthy in 1960
identified a problem
called garbage collection.
The programming language
lisp would operate
by defining trees and then pruning trees
for branches that were not needed.
The garbage collection problem
was these pruned branches
were not associated
with a potential free
space, storage location.
And therefore, they had to be dealt with
asynchronously and offline.
The problem was kind of solved
but all of us remember the days
when certain machines had to be restarted
after a few days or a week
because got jammed up, you
didn't have available storage.
Well, the garbage collection problem
is gonna to be coming
back in a big way with 5G.
The reason is, 5G is going to
be creating new cloud images,
new networks dynamically, new
storage spaces dynamically
and new suites of applications dynamically
for each user of a 5G phone,
for each machine that is
relying on a 5G set of services.
And those that move around,
for user walking through a city center,
they will be jumping from one
suite of cloud-based services
to another suite.
They will be crossing a
boundary every few hundred yards
and that entire stack
will have to be torn down
and reinstated in the new environment.
The problem isn't cleaning
up the cloud remnants,
we got that down.
The problem is the metadata,
the tables that tell you
what's the number of the next instance.
What's the total number of available slots
to handle instances of a
particular application.
When those tables fill up,
then things go haywire.
We saw two years ago when
satellites rolled their counters,
we saw it again in the
last year and a half,
when certain aircraft
have to be cold rebooted
after about 140 hours of service.
we saw it when certain
printers started to fail
because they had exhausted some counters.
It wasn't because they
had data hanging around
is because the metadata didn't exist.
And that problem is not gonna go away,
it's gonna get significantly worse
because of the presence of 5G driving
the rapid creation and
sanitation to take down
of all these new cloud environments.
So what have we learned today?
First of all, define your
processes and procedures,
refine them, clarify them, audit them
and then automate them.
Make sure you put the controls early
in the development and
integration life cycle.
Consider boosting the strength
of your identity management program,
identity centric security can not be done
on a domain specific basis,
it has to be universal.
Take a look at the gap analysis
for infrastructure and operations,
functions for governance.
Ask senior leadership who does this,
they give you a name.
Ask the it organization
does so-and-so do this,
who does this?
And then look at the gaps and
say, what do I need to fix it?
You gotta know what
software you're running,
including stuff that's been rented
not just stuff you built yourself
or stuff you purchased long-term.
Make sure you align your procurement
with the informal buying centers,
provide information, provide guidance
and upgrade your tool set.
See what your vendor
capabilities are lying there
that you haven't been aware
were added to technology
you bought three, four or five years ago.
Take a look at SASE as an
evolutionary step forward,
as a way to protect your enterprise
as it becomes more cloud-based
and less enterprise-centric.
And take a look at Zero
Trust network architecture,
get rid of the notion of a perimeter.
Consider how you would pilot that
and consider bringing in somebody
from the industrial control
systems and OT sides
because they're thinking that
the perimeter will save them.
Make sure you architect your
solution one step at a time.
I don't want you to put
it down and fall apart
and have to start over from scratch.
Piecemeal doesn't work, make
sure you've got a solid plan.
So I would like to share
these references with you.
The paper by McCarthy from
1960 is right there at the top,
documents on SASE and cloud are available.
And I'll be happy to take questions,
put them in the chat and I will
be answering them as we go.