- Hello, everyone.
Welcome to this session,
The Rise of the BISO Role.
My name is Manuel Chowrimootoo.
I'm currently a BISO at
Cogeco Communications.
Cogeco is a telecommunication company
headquartered in Montreal, Canada.
And the objective of this presentation
is to share with you my story
on this role that I took
a year and a half ago,
helping cybersecurity practice
to start from scratch in my company.
I want to share with you this experience,
what is the role of a
BISO, what is a BISO,
and how we implemented that practice,
show a few of the challenges, the success,
things that worked, didn't work.
So if you find yourself this role
you will have some information,
and also have your
feedback as well on this.
So let's start it.
So here is our agenda.
It's pretty packed full
with the time we have,
but we'll do the best
to get it done in time.
So first of all, we
choose the role of BISO,
what we did to get started,
and what did to implement
cybersecurity as a service
in the company I work for.
And then, we'll discuss
about the focus on value.
That is very important
indicators for the executive
that will pay the bills
at the end of the day.
And give you some key takeaway.
So first of all, let's
define what is a BISO.
BISO is an acronym that stands for
Business Information Security Officer.
So in my role, I work within
the information security team,
representing the interest
of the business mainly.
That's a key part.
So it's a very recent
role in organizations,
and why I wanted to
give that presentation,
actually, when I came to
my first RSA Conference,
last year in 2020,
I just started on this role
and I was trying to meet
other BISOs as well,
to share challenges,
to understand what was happening,
and get some information.
Unfortunately, I could hardly find one.
Of course, when I started,
I made some search on Google
and, at that time, it landed
me only on a very few articles.
If you make a similar search now,
you will start to get a bit more hits
than from what I could get in 2020.
And the quote I'm sharing
here from CISOSeries.com
summarize really very well
one of the main function
that I do everyday as a BISO
is to be a business enabler.
Basically, I don't say no to any team
that needs to to bring a
software on the network,
but always yes, but...
And I think that's how
it is most everyday.
And you will see more in the next slides.
As I say, it's a very new role,
and if you hit search on Google
you can get a few articles.
I want to share with you here
some of the articles that you can find
and I highlighted in green
the main one that comes in.
As you see, things that
come a lot are a bridge
from the centralized security
function to the business,
understand the goals of the business units
and what it will need to protect,
and being a link between
business and technology.
So to give you a bit of
background, I'll say to you,
I joined a team that just
started out within my companies.
So 15 individuals started
in September 2019,
forming a new corporate cybersecurity team
under the leadership of the CISO.
I joined that team four
months later in January 2020.
And my mandate when I landed was basically
those four points I'm sharing here.
First was to get the team
known with the organization,
get the service catalog known.
There was a pressing need to
deliver cybersecurity services
to the organization.
I had to connect with the
different business units,
understand their needs, what
they needed from security,
what they understand, what
they don't understand,
and what we could do to help
and organize the deliveries
and provide regular support
to the business unit.
So that was basically
the high level points
of time and dates,
and based on that, I had to weed out
how we were going to do this.
So to explain to you how I'd
function in the company I am,
so this is our structure
and operating model
that would be, and it
can be very different
in your organization
or in your experience.
And this is what I live through.
If you look on the left-hand side,
we have the corporate functions.
So for instance, internal
audit, procurement,
legal, enterprise risk,
product management,
and some other IT teams that
are at the corporate level.
On the right and side
are the IT teams with which we deal with.
And I bring the role here
so we can see the difference
between the CISO and the BISO,
which the first question
that can pop into your mind,
"Why a new role again in security space?"
The CISO interact more
at the strategic level
between the corporate functions
and the CIO and the CTO,
the IT leadership.
And in my role as a BISO, I do
a little bit of the similar,
but at a more tactical
and operational level.
So I will deal also with
the corporate functions,
but with IT architecture
and operations team
within the business units
we have different business units,
three mainly in different locations.
To give a very concrete example,
let's say for instance,
interaction with internal audits.
So the CISO will sit
on the audit committee
and interact with the VP internal audit,
understanding the high
risk of the companies,
the critical risks,
and having all the high level information
at this point, and be
the strategy of course
on how we can help
to attack those risks, literally,
and be the strategic plan with the CTO.
At my level, I will take in a notch more
more on the field at a tactical level.
So I will interact with
the director of audit
and the auditor's directly,
understanding what kind
of findings they have,
what are the critical ones,
what are the important ones
that they need to be solved,
that need to be remediated?
So then, I can work with them
and the IT architecture team
within the business units
to have them implemented
and support to close them on the field.
And that's why we have
those two different layers,
more of the tactical and operational level
compared to the CISO.
So the first year we had to do work
to meet the key partners.
So I defined the key departments,
as I just showed in the previous slide.
So I had to meet, for instance,
with director of procurement,
the senior buyers,
project management office individuals.
So to get ourselves
known in the organization
where they didn't really know us,
I had to plan a tour of duty,
or cyber roadshow as
we call it internally.
I had to get to know each department,
understanding the structure,
how many people are in this department,
what is their workload,
what are their previous experience
with cybersecurity, if any,
what did work well or not well,
and understand their process
very important as well.
So I plan my meetings around,
but that had to be my deck.
I had to go with with tools.
So I prepare a cybersecurity
deck to present our practice,
who we are, how we prepared we are
what we can do, what our service offers,
and also understanding what they need
to see if what we offer
are meeting their needs
or do you have to fine tune?
So that was one of the first step.
So that helped us to get started,
and I had to literally take
the show on the road now.
So having book my meetings,
having my cyber deck enhanced,
I could go meet with the business units.
So in this role, as the face
of the new cybersecurity practice,
I introduced myself to the tactical
and operational operational teams
by organizing face-to-face meetings
when this was still
possible in early 2020.
Since then, we had to
move everything virtual.
And the goals of all
this meetings I've had,
with for instance, the
internal audit or procurement
or legal was really to
first increase awareness
of the cyber security practice.
You have security team to reach out to.
We wanted to reach out to
departments responsible
for implementing IT assets,
who is bringing softwares on
the network, for instance,
and get security onto the
business unit's agendas.
So during all these interactions I had,
the key focus for me
was always to take out
and understand the people, the process,
and the technology at a high level,
understanding who is doing what,
what are their processes?
How can we work with those teams?
For instance, the procurement
team had a guideline
so we could embed
ourselves in their process.
What technology are
they using to interact?
They have specific type of
forms or evaluate, for instance,
which is a tool used by
our procurement team.
And if they are not, maybe
we would need to build one.
So at least having this information
was going to help us to better interact
with the business units.
After the road show,
I collected a lot of information,
learned a lot on what they needed,
and of course, they needed
a lot of very quickly.
So I really have the need to implement
a service request process
to really be able to interact
with the business units
because everybody has needs
everybody in security,
but you need to be able
to capture those requests
to ensure that our source (indistinct)
reach their objectives and our success.
So I built a structured
process at the beginning,
so we had a general mailbox
so they could reach us
out, phone number or email.
And we built a request form
initially on an Excel sheet
to be able to capture what they need.
So we built that template,
organized a folder structure,
we built a resource assignment process
to be able to staff the different needs,
and also defined the
different follow-up actions.
So my take out here from
the first experience,
it felt, of course,
overwhelming at the beginning,
but we did learn a lot along the way.
And my take out here was
to reevaluate regularly
and we found the process
to better accommodate
the BUs, business units.
For instance, I was saying
we had an extra sheet.
We quickly had to decommission it
and move to a more
user-friendly version forms.
So with drop down menus, once
we understood their services,
our services, what they need,
so we could easily build prebuilt menus
on a more user-friendly form.
Needs and priorities
are constantly changing,
so we had to reprioritize a lot.
It could be that one day
this is what comes in
or there's a new request or a new need,
I need to un-staff an architect here,
send him somewhere else,
and renegotiate the
deadline, for instance.
Agreeing on a timeline, the
deliverable is very important
'cause everybody needs your help,
but you need to know what they need.
When can you deliver?
So quickly, we learned that sometimes
we had a one-time assignment,
sometimes it will be project iterations.
I could have a request to coming in,
saying they need someone
three hours a week
for the next six months.
Can we provide that support?
So these are things to consider
when you build such a thing.
Building relationships
is really important.
I had to reach out to regularly
to all the key players.
I built up committees on a monthly basis
with some of the key stakeholders
so we can discuss the risks, their needs,
their issues, tech decisions.
I also have all the regular
touchpoints on the phone,
so I can talk regularly
to all my business partners
to see what's happening,
what's going on.
I regularly showcase
the cybersecurity service
offerings regularly,
as I say, would be the practice
so new services are coming all the time.
I would say every month
every two months we have
new services we showcase.
I follow up regularly
on different requests
and concerns, and
communicate at all levels.
Communication is key in this job.
I need to face with IT management
my cybersecurity members, the requesters,
the partner teams, as I say, audit, legal.
They all speak different languages,
so I need to be able to speak
security on their level.
So that's very important.
And the coordination aspect,
it may sound obvious,
but it's very important to work on.
We had to also define a focus plan,
and I think that's very important to do
to align with the CISO
and CTO strategy plan
because otherwise we'd go
in all directions at once,
and sometimes it's better to
take a multi-layer approach
and build a strategy along the way.
An example, defining the mandate
and the area of focus in a timeline.
For instance, the first year,
maybe you want to integrate cyber security
within the procurement process
and have it flowing at
a more mature level.
The next year, or six months,
you want to go on the PMR process
and so on and improve along the way.
Having senior management
support is really key
to get cybersecurity presence
of the key decision committees
on the tables, and the need
to really take you seriously
because at the beginning,
you will come in,
they don't know you,
so when you talk to a
lawyer for the first time
from the legal team,
they will literally tell
you, "What do you want?"
So having senior management support
help us a lot along the way
when we have our interactions.
From personal experience, I wanted to say
that we have to be aware of
the one size fits all approach,
which is kind of the
first way you want to go
because you need to
serve internal auditors
procurement, legal,
different (indistinct) units.
So want to have a funnel to capture this,
which is great at start,
but you need to be able to
tailor what you're doing
to the strategy of the business units
to their size with the company.
We quickly had to be the
catalog of success stories
'cause when we come, everybody
wants to work with you,
but they don't know you.
They don't know what your capable to do.
So along the way we started
to build that capabilities
and showcase our different success stories
with different departments,
different projects that we worked on.
And having of course the short-term
and long-term strategy is also key.
It gets back to the point
I was mentioning earlier
to have a narrow focus and a timeline.
Now, we implemented
cybersecurity as a service.
So having all these requests coming in,
there are two key things
that we really do every day
is to manage the requests first.
So responding to the needs.
So the first step, review the requests,
correcting upfront
documentation and information
to know what it is about.
So I know ahead, do I need to
send them a network architect,
a cloud architect,
or someone for the sub planning.
Applying resource allocation
and timeline, very important.
So we use a request tracker
tool that help us to do that,
to be able to ensure delivery of service.
To give you a corporate
example of services we did,
we did lots of architectural reviews,
(indistinct) discount for PCI compliance,
third party reviews, log monitoring.
So I follow up regularly with what I call
our internal clients,
and hold regular meetings to make sure
that we deliver on time what they need,
and stay also in touch
for the post-delivery
because that's a market
tech feature of work,
give the review
they've gone to the next assignment,
but I still need to keep
in touch with my requesters
to see what's coming next,
whether they're happy,
what can we do better the next time?
So always keeping informed and ahead
of the business unit's needs
and the corporate teams.
So for my experience here, as I say,
implementing and
communicating a streamlined,
rigorous process was key.
We spent a lot of time refining it,
fine-tuning it, making it a more seamless,
an easy tool to work with for
our different stakeholders.
Defining key performance
indicators is important.
At the beginning,
I remember we were always
saying best efforts
was our service level objective.
It works at the beginning, but
in the long run, it cannot.
You need to give a timeline
because otherwise you cannot
manage what you cannot measure.
So we defined this pretty quickly.
Once we had enough data
to see how much time
it takes to use a scan
review, for instance,
or third party review.
I would say to be aware of over-promise
and under-deliver trap.
I call it a trap because,
at the beginning,
you want to get their trust.
You really want to over-promise.
So that's why we hold
onto the best efforts
to avoid committing on a deadline.
Say, "Yes, you get it next week."
And what happens if you say
next week and you don't deliver,
you would get complaint right away.
So I would say to be aware of that.
Second aspect on a cyber
security as a practice,
as we call it, is to manage risk.
Manage request, manage risk as well.
So connecting regularly
with the audit, risk,
and governance teams is very important
so we can identify the high risk issues
and open findings to
help us staff the needs
and tackle what is the most important.
So working together with those teams
to propose and enforce the implementation
of security measures and techniques,
controls was very key.
If you can really to attend
being able to attend external
IT audit closing meetings is great.
We still try to get a spots
on those meetings yet,
but it can give you so much information
to be able to sit there
to help us to support the business units
to implement those
recommendations, for instance,
or to challenge auditors as well.
So from our experience,
I would say connecting early
with internal audit teams is key.
It will help you to
collect so much information
on critical and high risk
to prioritize your requests
and the efforts towards the
more higher risk carriers,
and also to coordinate
with governance teams
to review the risk register
on a regular basis.
So to really sit with all those meetings.
The focus on value.
So another thing is that, your executives,
you want to know how well
you're doing, what's happening.
So we need to be able
to bring some reporting
on those activities,
and it was my one of my responsibility.
So there's always two sides when it comes
to give reporting, quantitative factors
and quantitative factors.
On the qualitative factors,
it's harder to measure,
but we are voicing the
potential risks that we see,
and the BU concerns that I
collect on my regular meetings
to senior management on the
field to collect those polls
and to bring them up a notch.
So establishing and communicating
corporate safety strategies
as well is very important
'cause what we see
on the field can help to
build those strategies
to fill the strategy up.
So kind of a top down approach
and bottom up approach.
Solving problems is key.
As I say, we're not here to say no.
We're here to say yes,
so we have to be creative sometimes
to propose alternative solutions,
mitigation strategies to be
able to work with a vendor
that could be lacking
some security controls.
For instance, work on action plans,
could be an example
Considering the budget
constraints as well,
and getting all the players on boards.
So as you see, you will
see news travels very fast,
good or bad.
It's gonna come.
You will know.
We wanted to create a
culture of responsibility
and transparency as well,
and being able to get all
the key players on board.
On the quantitative side, we
built reports and dashboards.
Of course, as you know,
management, they like dashboards.
They want to see things from what I call
a red, yellow, green perspective.
So we build those tools.
So we wanted to define metrics to showcase
the value we're adding.
'Cause that's the point.
That happens after a few months.
It's what is the value you're bringing?
So we were able to commit to
timelines for key deliverables.
For instance, at some
point we started to see
that it takes us an average of two weeks
to provide a security opinion.
So then, great.
Someone needs an opinion
to offer security requirements
for your software.
Two weeks would be (indistinct).
So we commit to formalize timeline.
We also implemented reporting tools
to highlight our team's
contributions and success
and number of effort hours.
So we create a report
reporting based on the audience
because we want to see
more high level dashboards
and we highlight the red flags.
The business unit line managers
or the requests they want to see,
the status of the project, where we are,
what is the deadline, how many days?
So we put up digital comments
on these every week, even twice a week.
So we get always the last
pulse on how are we advancing.
So we were able to be those reporting.
That really helps you
because, at some point,
you have so many requests going on,
it would be very difficult
to have everything
on top of your heads,
and having key information
centralized and live
is really, really helpful.
Now, let me give you some key takeaways
of my experience here
as a business information
security officer.
The day-to-day is actually
not as easy as it can look.
You will become the in-house
cybersecurity sales
representatives, literally,
selling the best out of it
and trying to settle issues
sometimes, and negotiate.
So you have to wear many hats sometimes.
I don't even know all the
time to describe my job,
what I do.
Some days I will be a project manager,
a negotiator, a cyber expert on network
because I'm being front end
in the meeting like that,
or third party analyst.
But you come in, you
capture the key information,
and you can bring the expert
that you need at the table.
So that's a good thing
if you like to see things
from a wider angle.
Priorities can and will
changed at a moments notice.
So you have to be very flexible.
So I'd like to say that
every day is an adventure.
I wake up, take my coffee,
see the meetings I have,
and I plan the day, the direction.
It can go in a different one.
It's all right.
We still keep things on the focus.
After five, I can check back the points
I couldn't get done,
and follow up on them.
So you need to think long-term.
At the beginning, you would
tend to think short term
to get success,
to deliver, deliver,
but you need to see what are
the new services coming ahead?
What is the strategy of
the different departments?
Because, even if management
priorities will change,
you want to see what's
coming next to be ready
for the new upcoming initiatives.
And actually, something I've experienced
is that people skills is
actually much more important
my role than the technical skills.
The reason why is because I coordinate
with so many internal
parties and external parties.
You can't know everything
in security, of course.
So your background will help you to go,
but you have to be
someone who wants to work
across the board.
So being able to connect
security and business,
understanding, being able to
have a meeting at eight o'clock
with a lawyer, at nine o'clock
with someone from procurement,
and then with network security,
and then a vendor, and so on and so on.
Being able to change tables
and having those people
skills is really key
when you have to deal with
different type of individuals.
The main challenges I faced
was to be able to bring the right people
at the right table at the right time.
Sometimes you will be on a meeting,
and then realize, had I known,
I would have brought a network
architect for instance,
or cloud architect.
So being able to filter
out things ahead of time
so we can bring the right people
and avoid too few meetings
and more delays is key.
It's difficult, but it's key.
With time, I was able to
find ways to reach this goal,
when I go to meeting, to
have the right people.
You would become the man in the middle,
defending your teams,
representing them on different occasions.
And something I've noticed
is that the non-active
departments like legal,
procurement, they need
a lot of reassuring,
especially when your contract closes.
They always want to verify
the security aspects.
Okay, they understand what's happening.
That's something that I
find interesting as well.
On the apply slides, as you know, RSA,
we like to give a plan as in
what you can do as actions.
I would say the first thing you can do
when you get back to your work
is to identify your
contact for cybersecurity
if you have not done that,
or if you don't know yet.
Who is your contact for
questions and concerns?
And requests, the cybersecurity
team service catalog,
what do they do?
What do they offer?
How can they help you?
And what are the cyber security
policies that they have?
So collect those documents and contacts.
And in three months, review the policies.
If you have any questions,
ask the questions to the team.
See what kind of channel they have
for you to provide feedback
or to ask for services.
How can you reach out with
them and better interact?
Thank you.