- Hi, this is Shannon Lietz.
I'm super excited to be here
with the RSA Conference
for 2021.
My talk is called The State
of the Union of DevSecOps
and I have been a prior speaker with RSA.
I started in the industry quite a bit ago.
I've been giving talks on
DevSecOps for some time.
My interests are all
very centered around technology and
I have a couple of little
girls who like to do ballet.
I'm really keen on helping
the industry to transform
to deal with some of the things
in security that are needed
such as metrics and
having more women in tech.
Just a little bit about me.
I work currently at Intuit and I
prior worked at ServiceNow and Sony
and many other companies as well.
Today I'm gonna talk to you a little bit
about the state of the union of DevSecOps,
the good, the bad and
the ugly, if you will.
And
feel free to drop a line into chat.
I'm gonna be taking
all of the information.
And if you have questions,
feel free to put those into the chat.
As I ask questions, feel
free to answer in the chat.
And here we go.
So
when you start to think about the journey
that we've all been on for security
and technology and DevSecOps,
and this is a slide to
help us get oriented,
it's been a long journey,
decades, if you will.
Software quality
started the journey for what I believe
is the security transformation
that's been going on.
And in 1976, there was a paper written
that helped to frame up the -ilities.
It's a great paper.
And if you're interested in it,
chat me and I'll send you the link.
This is a big monumental cornerstone
of how we've gotten to
the point in security
where we are today.
If you look along the way,
the software quality -ilities,
essentially security was baked
into software quality,
but not at a primary level,
actually one level deep into
integrity in that paper.
Along the way, you can see
that we saw firewalls and
vulnerability scanners.
Actually there's a whole
bunch of work that was done
on intrusion detection systems
along the way,
and that started to
create the advancements.
And in 1992, there was some work done
around vulnerability
scanners and firewalls.
I think it's really critical to understand
that as part of this effort,
you can see, as an example,
OWASP started to come in 2001
with applications and
application security.
It was basically right
around then that we saw
that the internet was really
becoming more prevalent.
We saw more investment in software
and software security was
starting to become more
of a big issue.
Site reliability, Google
got started on that journey
and they've been on that quest ever since.
And you could see a variety of
different dimensions to this.
In 2012,
I was working with a bunch of different
folks and we realized
that DevOps was something
that was really here to stay
and that the cloud was here to stay
and that software was never
gonna be the same again
because they were really
software-defined infrastructure
and capabilities.
And so that transitioned
us into things like
trying to figure out how
to make security built in.
DevSecOps got started around then
and we've been on that quest ever since,
and now we're in 2021.
It's not yet a 10-year journey,
but we're slowly creeping
up on it in 2022.
And it'll be interesting to see how that
transforms us over the next
couple of years.
And to be able to talk about it,
I think the question that I get is,
"okay, great, so we're in DevSecOps
and there's a lot of
companies that are doing it,
maybe not doing it.
Is it a marketing term?"
So today I'm gonna talk
to you a little bit
about the success, the
failures, the epic battles,
what's next, what is
happening in the industry?
And I've got some data points for you
to help you to understand how to
determine where you are in the journey
as well as understand what
else is happening around you
to be able to take that into perspective.
So the successes,
everybody always wants
to know the successes.
I think one of the biggest
things that has come
up with the successes is that
truly DevSecOps has led to alignment,
better alignment of security
to the business, to development,
to being able to articulate
what is happening
from a security endeavor
and really trying to
figure those things out.
Then when you think about alignment, this
picture started kind of my
quest and my journey was,
DevOps was helping to frame
up how you got to build
software, and then how
it eventually became
something and how you actually
made this become a customer capability.
And then along the way
you kinda went through
the prototyping phase
and you checked your code into
software versioning systems.
So you can see how GitHub and GitLab
and some of those companies
have come to life perforce.
And so there's that continuous
integration, the test suites.
All of these things became
part of that pipeline.
It's known as the continuous
delivery pipeline.
And then along the way
and when we were thinking
about DevSecOps, well,
what did it take to
really look at software
and essentially build security in?
I've seen things like
the secure software
development life cycle.
Those things are definitely part
of what helped to influence
some of this picture.
And in aligning what we were
doing with the business,
it was basically, how do we actually help
the business to understand
when they're building trust
back into the software
and how they're doing it from
a shift-left perspective.
And this led some of
the shift-left thinking.
So in every great story are
the stars of that story.
The way I think about
this journey is really
about trying to figure out
who the stars of a story are
and articulating the story around them.
And when you start
thinking about successes,
the secure software supply chain is really
about customers, software
enablement, and employees.
Essentially, these are the basic elements.
There's a whole bunch of
complexity that's underneath these,
but at a top level, if you were to
take the software supply chain,
really divided into these four categories
and essentially think about
how we're doing as an industry.
We've got much more security
in our software supply chains.
It's not ideal yet,
but there are successes and
wins that have happened.
As an example,
being able to build security checks
and capabilities such as scans
and SAST and DAST into the pipeline
to check software before it
becomes a production capability
has been something that's
really been a monumental effort
and actually something
that's helped us to be able
to look at these successes in that way.
Employees are becoming more aware.
There's a lot more focus on enablement.
The cloud is an enabler.
And when I started with
this journey in 2012,
if you looked around at that
time, there wasn't a lot
of security capabilities
in the cloud at that point.
And today, that's not true.
Most of the clouds out there that we
take advantage of, the cloud providers,
their capabilities have a
lot of security features
and capabilities that
are available for anyone
to be able to create a single line of code
and add a key to a
specific type of encryption
or you might wanna have monitoring.
Those are something that you can turn on.
And in many cases,
the cloud providers are now
doing these things by default
and it's really exciting to see.
So along that thought process,
I found a bunch of different
inputs for us to talk about.
One of the ones to think
about that was really exciting
was to see that
Forrester has been studying
the application security testing market.
What's really neat is to see that SAST,
something that security professionals
have been well aware of,
have been learning about,
have taken on in terms of complexity,
that it's starting to to make
a transition and be transformed
such that SAST tools are now
starting to be more focused
on the developer as a customer
and
really making it so that that
tool chain is easier to use,
but there's actually an ability
for the findings to be ticketed,
that work management as part
of the development process
is really thought about
with those tool chains.
And I think that's a critical element.
Another critical well success
we've been able to achieve
if you look at the success that's going
on along the way for DevSecOps,
it's top-level support.
A great piece of information
that I found was from Gartner.
They said that we're basically seeing
that DevSecOps got 20 to
50% of its target audience
that's already been attracted and working
on the DevSecOps transformation
in their organization.
And in their hype cycle,
you can see that DevSecOps
is pretty far along
and in a maturing phase of its journey.
And that's really keen to see.
I think that that helped
us to really see that
not only
are we
making this transformation
as practitioners
but that you're seeing buying behaviors
and you're seeing attention in this space
to bringing software the
security it deserves to have,
and that's important.
Another thing that was
said by Gartner was that
"DevSecOps is in early mainstream".
That is really neat to
see after eight-ish years.
I would say
when you start to see
something going mainstream,
you see that people are
talking about it continuously,
that you're having the debates
and the banter that goes along with it,
those are also crucial milestones
and knowing that what we're
doing is making software safer.
As part of early mainstream
we're seeing more and more
software being published
with the vulnerabilities being lessened
and that companies are doing things
like blocking their bills
when a security issue comes to life
so that the number of defects
are actually reducing quite a bit.
And so I did a little bit
of a study to go figure out,
well, where are we with the journey
from the vantage point of
tooling and capabilities?
And I have a bunch of other
slides and former presentations
where I talk about some of the products
that actually lie in this space and
I did a little bit of investigations,
mathematics in the background
'cause I'm a big geek
and like to do the mathematics
of figuring out where things are.
And in assessing these
different places, you can see
that DevSecOps is having a profound effect
in getting security into the
right places of the pipeline,
that there are more and more products
that are getting matured,
that they're starting to make strides.
The green boxes here
are really the ones that are
the most heavily focused on,
in terms of products,
that they're being adopted readily
that you see practitioners
that are talking
about the concepts in these areas.
The yellow boxes are not quite there yet.
You are seeing things being invented.
You're seeing open
source start to show up,
but they have a little bit of ways to go,
and that, that is a
pretty healthy place to be
when you have about two to five years left
before plateau in a space.
I don't know if I fully agree
with DevSecOps being ready
to plateau necessarily,
because I think there's
still so much innovation
to make this space
more graceful, more elegant,
that the products are,
while they're wonderful and complex,
that they could be more
easily
accessible.
And that along this pipeline
you could get to the point
where some of these start
to converge and you could see
consolidation across
some of these dimensions.
As an example,
seeing that code analysis
is starting to make its way
into software version control
with things like GitHub and GitLab
and some of the places
where you might check code
into a version control system
is a really neat thing to see
because the products in code analysis
do help us to make sure
that software that we build,
not just the stuff that we integrate
but the stuff that we actually
build as practitioners
is being thought about at the time
that it's being checked in and
a pull request is being made.
It's also neat to see
big products out there
that are becoming unicorns
in this space, such as Snyk
and some of the other things like
Code Dx.
You have a lot of different
dimensions to this problem.
And I think it's really
neat to see that there's
a whole bunch of practitioners
and vendors that are trying to
make this space even better.
So another piece of the puzzle here
is DevSecOps product categories
are starting to really show up.
And I thought this was pretty neat
because basically transformational,
I mean Gartner is saying that this
is a transformational effort
that you should be investing in DevSecOps,
that it will really truly bring benefit
and value to your company
in extraordinary ways.
We've always believed that
in the work that I've done
with peers in the industry,
and to see it being stated at this point
in the 2020 Report was really exceptional.
I think that's a big success and win
for the people who have
started to adopt it
that have been really pushing on:
What is DevSecOps?
How do we actually make software better?
How do we really fully
understand our supply chains
and get to the next level?
The next one here is...
And I pulled...
This was really great.
I found something that
helped us understand
what the CAGR is for
DevSecOps as a marketplace.
And whenever you see
whether something is
really successful or not,
you see a buying behavior
that's looking for new products,
that's looking for ease of use,
that's trying to really morph the space
in terms of the feedback
and the feature use and development.
And this is an exceptional growth rate
for 2021
to 2028
for DevSecOps and in the DevOps market.
To see that security is
really being embraced,
that we're getting more traction,
it's I would say, as a
security practitioner,
it's sort of a dream come true to see
that more and more folks are starting to
understand that they need
to have their products
not just be customer-worthy,
but security-resilient as well.
So the other thing to note,
and this is a really great thing
is anytime you're doing something
that you believe in and
you see academic interests,
you've kind of arrived.
Academia showing up and being able to look
at Grey Literature to see if
they should invest their time,
their conclusion was
that there's increasing
attention in this space,
that there is an ability
to do more in innovation.
And their assessment,
which was a little different
than the marketing assessment
and I always kinda like
to compare the two,
is that DevSecOps is in its infancy.
Now, while they're looking at literature,
they're looking at at quite a bit
of the information that's out there,
I thought this was a really good study.
If you wanna know about it,
just ask me for the link.
I'll put it in the chat.
You can go and take a look at this.
I thought it was pretty incredible work.
And I found other articles
in academia as well
that are starting to study the space
to help us to understand where
we could see more traction.
There is opportunities
to reduce false positives
in some of the products
to make them more
developer-friendly, accessible,
that there is an opportunity
to bring more adversary
knowledge to the forefront
and have developers be able
to determine what their
traction is gonna be against
adversaries on the end
and have that ideal state of
being adversary-resilient.
Another thing to think about
too is workforce investment.
Where are we really seeing successes?
And this is a lot of jobs, by the way.
6,400 jobs, just in the last little bit
and 8,400 jobs posted on LinkedIn.
If you think about these things,
just getting workforce growth in a space
and starting to see the job show up
means that companies are really investing,
that they know that this is important,
that they're actually
making that commitment
by opening up the workforce
to being able to do this work
and to spend effort on making sure
that it's part of their business.
That's another counted success.
Another one to note too is
just how much money people are making
in DevSecOps and their salaries.
Looking for the understanding
of what the average salary is from talent
was a really cool thing to see
because now all of a sudden you can see
that there is an investment
that is price-positioned,
that there is more and more effort
being made to secure software,
that we're seeing that
the supply chain itself
is getting this investment.
And while academia believes
it's in its infancy,
that does mean too that
there's career growth
in this area of expertise.
You're seeing things like
DevSecOps architects.
You're seeing stuff like
DevSecOps engineers.
You're seeing a
promotion path associated with DevSecOps
and career growth overall.
Now, let's talk about the failures.
Everybody always wants to talk
about the failures and the epic battles.
So successes are nice to see
'cause that's actually
what helps us to know
that we're going in the right direction,
but failures can be quite
a bit interesting too.
And one of the things to think about is
with upskilling as an
example, and career growth.
I just talked about the benefits
and the successes
associated with DevSecOps
from a career perspective,
but what we're also seeing,
which is the other side
of the coin when it comes to DevSecOps,
is that while there's a lot of jobs open,
upskilling and career growth right now
are also a challenge in this space.
So going back to these
6,400 jobs and 8,400 jobs,
how fast are they being filled?
Is there demand in this space?
And actually what you're finding
if you study it a lot, like me,
is that you find that there is a need
for more DevSecOps skills,
that we're seeing more DevOps come forward
and they have compliance skills
but they don't necessarily
have the monitoring skills yet
or the testing skills yet.
And we have to, as an industry,
start to focus on those
as a primary reason why we'll
have better software security.
If we start to invest in those areas,
we'll have upskilled folks.
They can actually do more.
They can automate more.
They're gonna be able
to build security in.
And we as an industry have
to find a way to really
create that organically
with the help of vendors,
with the help of academia,
with the help of making
sure that there's a way
for us to distill a career path and a role
that allows people to determine the skills
and the craft skills that they need.
Another thing to think
about that's not been
a true
failure but maybe one
that actually has been holding things back
is,
and I found this, it was a GitLab study,
13% of companies are
giving developers access
to the results of their dynamic
application security tests.
Only 13% was concerning
from my perspective.
Access is a big thing.
Sharing is really critical.
And as security practitioners, I know
that I grew up in this industry being told
that we needed to keep the
understanding of security
close to our chest, and
we needed to make sure
that only a few people knew about it.
And that may just not
have been the way forward.
We need to make sure that developers
own their security decisions,
that they're making product choices
and they're picking up
things that are actually
gonna make their software resilient enough
based on the adversary
profile of their software.
And so I think that you have to liberate
information about defects and bugs
from a security perspective.
It'd be interesting to
hear what you think.
So in the chat, why don't
you tell me what you think?
I think it's a place
where we should liberate
the information for our developers
so that they can understand
how to fix things
and how to prioritize and
to really build that up.
But everybody is entitled to
their decisions around this.
It is something that I
think will help the industry
for us to all provide more
and more of this information
and even make the tools accessible enough
that they can be self-service.
Another area that's been a failure
so far has been false positives.
I hear it every place I go.
Every time I talk about
DevSecOps, every discussion,
there's something about false positives.
I also think the false
negatives are a thing as well,
but false positives is really plaguing
the DevSecOps space.
And in particular,
if you look at it,
the code review
tools that are out there,
just really overwhelming
in terms of false positives.
Now false positive from the standpoint
of a developer or a business person
bringing something in is very different
than a false positive understanding
by security practitioner.
We'll talk a little bit
about that in epic battles
because there's sort
of a language barrier,
but I think it's really
important to understand
that DevSecOps is truly
being held back by this
and this may be something
that we need to figure
out how to solve through
things like orchestration
and there needs to be a
little bit more investment
in trying to understand
what DevSecOps orchestration
could do to help alleviate
some of the stress and pain.
Now
somebody's false positive is
it's a debate, back and forth.
And I also think that the other reason
why false positives exist
is that there's really
a lack of understanding
about what the true
resiliency problem is or that
the adversary opportunity
is not fully understood or appreciated.
So there's still a little bit of debate
about whether it's really a false positive
or it's just being misunderstood.
And I think there's gotta
be some more clarity
in that space as well.
Audits, if you've been doing DevSecOps
for even a little bit of time,
I've been doing it now
for a long period of time,
audits are definitely a critical issue
and cause quite a bit of consternation.
It seems to be that most of the standards
and regulations out there
are written truly for
somebody to be able to do an audit
at the end of a life cycle.
And in this case, it really
does become detrimental
because if you're trying to
build security into the pipeline
and you're actually
being asked to do things
that are manual or that
you're having to spot check
and you're having to work
in that runtime behavior
to prove out the security of your software
or your supply chain,
what you're gonna find
is that that actually
will also pull you back,
that people will actually
chase what they're being asked
to be audited against
as opposed to some of the new
forward-leaning activities.
And so from a dearauditor perspective,
this was something that came up.
I haven't seen it get
much traction just yet.
I really have been pushing on it.
And you'll notice here,
it's only got 24 stars,
but if I could ask
anybody to put investment
into a place that's
really gonna have returns
it is in this space that we need to solve,
that truly, we've got to
advance our audit criteria
around the cloud, around DevSecOps,
around what we expect in
terms of control behaviors
and really make it become more
of a resilience mechanism
so that we understand
that we're making risk
decisions that are based
on true adversary behavior,
that we are taking risks
based on what we understand
the adversary risk are taking.
And I can't say it enough,
this is a true thing that we actually have
to disrupt to be able
to make a stride forward
to get to the point where it could become
or DevSecOps could become more mainstream,
from my perspective.
Now, onto the epic battles.
All right, so
everybody always likes to
hear about epic battles.
It's probably my favorite
place to talk about too.
We talk a lot about culture
in DevOps and in DevSecOps
and culture in primary is always an area
where everyone talks about,
it is
all about the culture
that actually creates these opportunities
for us to do things like DevSecOps.
And I'll tell you, the epic battles,
one of the great books
that you can go read about,
and if you don't have the link
send me a chat and I will
give you a link to this,
but "Epic Failures in DevSecOps"
was written a while back
and there are some great stories in there.
And there's some really, truly
interesting data points for folks
that are trying to go
through this journey.
Where are the frameworks?
Where are we investing
in terms of making it
easier and more accessible?
Do we wanna solve that for the industry?
Is it something that's gonna be...
Is your DevSecOps program
gonna be a one-size-fits-all?
Is there a place to do it right or wrong
or do you just need to use
the tools and the capabilities
and really form your own?
Language is another critical area.
And
an epic battle here is
whenever you see people
talking about something,
you see them have an understanding
of words from their perspective
but maybe not the full
community's perspective,
and language is an issue.
I had this pop-up in
the last couple of days
and I thought it was
really relevant because
the question was, if security
is everyone's responsibility,
then why does DevSecOps exist?
And I think it's really
crucial to understand
that everyone's responsibility is security
when you build something
and you have to make sure
that what you did is secure enough,
that you understand the
adversary opportunities
and you rationalize that.
It doesn't mean that
any one particular role
is gonna take over security
of the company or the security of
a product line that has
many, many people in it.
It means that as
practitioners, we each have to rationalize
the security decisions we make,
that we're understanding
how to make those security decisions
and that we're part of this team
that helps to make software resilient.
I think that we have to spend more effort
on not trying to have language
get in the way of these things,
but to help enable us.
And another area, it really is...
I saw this in the GitLab Report as well
and this was kind of interesting.
We had a whole bunch of data points
about who thinks they own security.
And the truth is, is that in this space
it's really owned by everyone.
Security, the word,
has many facets to it.
Operations folks are making sure
that in the stack that the
products are actually getting
operational security elements,
that there are things that are happening
and decisions being
made by developers like,
Hey, which encryption should I be using?
Security practitioners should
be offering up solutions
and things that could be
used that are gonna make
the products more resilient.
And so they may be building some
of the security capabilities.
And then, testers.
I love seeing when testers
believe that they're doing the
security job of the company
because truly they're making sure that
customers are getting the best products,
but it also means that
security is starting
to make its way into quality decisions
in a way that it hasn't been in the past.
And that's really, I think,
while an epic battle,
a serious opportunity to have another win.
So target states' also
something that I think
is really been misunderstood
and it's still something that
we're all battling about.
What do we mean by a target state?
I see that everybody's kind of
counting DevSecOps a success.
And I don't wanna disrupt that,
but I think it's really
crucial to understand
that the software supply
chain is so much more
than the continuous delivery pipeline
and we might be being a little bit myopic.
This is
a data point for everyone, is
to look at things like this,
where you're actually looking
at supply chain attacks
and this was mapped out.
Again, I'll provide the link
if you're looking for this paper.
When you look back at all the
materials that are out there,
MITRE's been doing a lot
of this information work
for quite some time to
help people to assess
and build decision frameworks around this.
And I think it's a critical importance
that you can see in that bottom
right-hand corner, that
primary production software,
that is the continuous delivery pipeline
but you can see that
there's attack opportunity
across the supply chain
in so much more than just that one box
and we have to take
that into consideration.
So the battle for target
state of DevSecOps
is something that I believe
that
is the reasoning and rationale
behind why academia thinks
that it's still in its infancy,
but that the marketing
folks are still thinking
that it's gonna be something
that's gonna be plateauing soon.
So I think there's just a
little bit of a disconnect there
and a mismatch that we have to solve for.
Adversaries are still an epic battle.
When you start to look at what's happening
and what are the top hacking vectors
and where are things happening,
web applications are really
high on the list right now
in terms of where attention is being paid.
You also see things like
desktop-sharing software.
And I will tell you in studying this,
this is one perspective,
and it was primarily a
perspective given by companies
that are really studying this space.
If you study other parts
of the supply chain,
you'll find that they
have the same elements,
but maybe in the reverse, like
actually if you look into the anti-malware
and some of those spaces,
you see that they're actually showing
a different perspective of this data
in a different dimension.
And it means really what we're seeing is
adversaries are leveraging
some of the things
that are great about what we like,
which is the advancements of clouds.
They're using it in a very adversarial way
and we have to get that
to be a forefront for us.
Perfectionism is another one.
I'd say I'm sure you're aware of it.
Spending a lot of time
on trying to make sure
you get every single thing done
and that software is
perfect before it comes out
can really hold back the
DevSecOps' maturity phase.
I think we really have to
solve for adversary resilience
and we have to get to the
point where perfectionism
in certain places is really crucial
versus that everything has to be done,
this notion that we're gonna have
a checklist approach to DevSecOps.
I'm not quite sure I'm there yet
and I could be talked into a lot
of things with a lot of data,
but for me,
this is a great
reference design and diagram
for folks that are trying
to envision a new set of
capabilities that are gonna help us
to make software more resilient.
But I still think it has to get put back
onto that supply chain
and not just around the
continuous delivery pipeline
for us to get better at it.
Measurement's another one where
we're all battling for it,
really, who is doing security metrics?
And sadly, I did this
check to find out how much
we have to go for this and I'd say,
DevSecOps metrics are really,
really at their forefront
in the infancy stage.
I'm hoping to
start to provoke more
conversation around this.
I wanna start to create
an exchange on metrics
and try to help the industry
to make sure that we're talking
about things like secure ability
and adversary resilience.
It's been a quest for me for some time.
I've always been very metrics-driven.
It's one of the things in my background
that you'll find that I'm
a big believer that if
you wanna do something,
well, you've got to figure
out how to measure it.
And I think this is an
area where we really have
to battle it out and get to the point
where we're in agreement on metrics
that are really gonna move the
needle for software security.
So what's next?
What's the one last bit
of this stage and puzzle?
I think that adversary management
which is something that I'm
now doing for my organization
is a next generation of things
like red team and DevSecOps
and really having that conversation about
how do you balance
customers and adversaries
in terms of business decisions
and where you're gonna
spend your investment
in terms of the controls
and things that you're gonna
deal with,
and that in particular is a
sweet spot right now that I see
becoming a new conversation.
If you look around, folks
are now starting to talk more
about adversaries and
monitoring and things like that.
Security OKRs and metrics,
big on my list.
If you haven't read it,
read "Measure What Matters"
by John Doerr, fabulous book.
There's a lot of stuff
out there about OKRs.
Developers are really embracing OKRs.
You see that Google spent
a lot of effort on OKRs
and I think metrics are really part
of what is gonna break
that glass ceiling in terms
of making DevSecOps a forefront
and something that's really gonna
change and transform us for the longterm
in terms of the industry itself.
And then, fewer better suppliers.
I keep saying it over the years.
I think this is another guiding light
that we've got to be focused
on moving forward towards.
Security observability.
If you haven't spent any time
in the observability space,
there's a whole bunch of new
work that's going on there
and I think that's a critical element.
The secure software supply chain,
it's not enough to say it's
a software supply chain.
I really think we do have
to add that word to it
that says it's a secure
software supply chain
so that we put the emphasis there.
We are seeing
really big attacks in the industry
that are starting to focus
primarily in this space because
it's not mapped out well.
We're
focused too heavily on the
continuous delivery pipeline
and we've got a perspective
that's too myopic, I believe.
And we've got to back up
and really look at the whole
dimensions of a business
to understand what could get
in and where do we wanna spend
and invest to make something more secure.
Folks are spending and
investing in this area
and I'm seeing things that
may actually need to be
put in place for enablement
technologies, like laptops.
How safe are the laptops when
you're bringing new libraries
onto those machines as
development machines
and you're connecting
into these environments?
We really do have to find
more effort in the industry
to make innovations in this space.
So if you want to go and start to do work
around making strides
and and understanding
how to bring DevSecOps into your company,
the next thing you should do
is really figure out how to
drive DevSecOps outcomes.
Figure out what you need to achieve
and create a common set of definitions
I think it's critical for that to happen.
Within the next three months,
I think that once you've kind of embraced
whether or not you're doing DevSecOps,
what you could be doing about it,
whether some of these battles are
also happening in your organizations,
what you also could be highlighting.
Now you might wanna get involved in things
like finding out what your
critical objectives are,
identifying the metrics,
getting some OKRs,
defining security resilience,
understanding the adversary
dwell time and baseline
for 30 days on your
applications and your software,
really articulating
that as a understanding
of what you need to do
and whether the investments
you're making in security
are really bringing
that number down or not.
And that will be, I think,
instrumental in what you do
for the next six months to several years
is that your DevSecOps tools have
to actually be more accessible,
that it has to become more graceful.
Orchestration is gonna become a big deal
when it comes to DevSecOps.
We can't just have all
these point solutions.
It's too hard to bring all
that information together.
We've got to solve for
a view of the software supply chain
that makes it so we can
make DevSecOps a forefront
and that software security is
really the ultimate challenge
and goal that we're all taking on.
So I'm really excited about this topic.
Wanna definitely have more
conversations in the chat.
Feel free to ping me.
I'm gonna sit here and have
some more conversations live.
And
if you're wanna start getting
more involved with metrics,
please ping me privately
on Twitter at DevSecOps.
You can also reach me on LinkedIn.
I'm always looking for folks
to collaborate within the industry
and help to change and
transform the industry.
So thank you for your time today, and
really excited about seeing what's left
on the agenda for RSA this week.