- Hi, my name is Michael Jabbara
and I lead the global strategy
and operations team for the
risk function within Visa.
My role really centers around looking
at how the payment landscape is evolving,
what nutrients are shaping it
from a security perspective
and then ensuring that Visa
and its ecosystem partners
have the right technology,
the right analytics
and the right expertise
to navigate the kind of
the changing environment
to make sure
that we are continuing to
deliver the most seamless
and secure payment experience possible.
And as you can imagine, the past 12 months
have been an incredibly
exciting, transformative
and disruptive time when thinking
about how to deliver that
optimal disguised experience
while managing risk in a
robust and holistic way.
So I'll walk you through
into some of my thoughts
on the pandemic, ways to manage
that and a potential framework
for you to leverage in your
respective organizations
to think about managing
the digital experience
in these very unprecedented times,
to over the use the word one more time.
And so COVID-19, I think was a really
a bit of a wake-up call
to a lot of the organizations
that we work with
in terms of the importance of
delivering services digitally
to consumers whose needs and
expectations rapidly change.
Essentially overnight,
digital transformation
became a business imperative
and it was what separated
entities that were able to survive
and maybe even thrive in the pandemic
to those who are left behind.
And as a result,
we saw in almost a matter of
days, business priorities shift
to deal with this rapidly
evolving environment.
And one of the most
interesting things was really
around the rapid change in
consumer behavior that we saw.
It was kind of this great leap forward
in terms of how people made payments
and interacted with
their service providers.
If you look at the middle of the pandemic,
we had a situation
where the payment volume
and the physical channel had
actually decreased by about 20%
while the payment volume and
digital channels had increased
by about 40% when you exclude travel.
That was during the pandemic over time,
as we're seeing the signs
of recovery and our return to normal.
Some of that mix has changed a little bit,
but we're still seeing
the digital engagement
at historic highs.
So, more recently, we're
seeing a payment volume
in a physical channel about
breakeven year over year
while the digital channel
is still experiencing growth
of about 30%, again,
when you exclude travel.
So these digital interactions
are really becoming the norm
and it kind of is imperative
on us to kind of think
about what is that security foundation
to ensure that we are
meeting our consumers
where they expect us to be.
And so, given these rapidly
changing consumer expectations
as well as the increasing sophistication
of Forresters that we're
seeing in the landscape today,
it's not really surprising
that many organizations
foresee risk management
becoming increasingly complex
over the next couple of years.
I, myself personally think that despite
of all the change that we've
seen over the last 12 months,
the amount of disruption
and transformation
over the next 12 to 18 months
will far outweigh that simply
as we manage to navigate kind
of this return to normalcy.
And we've actually seen in a study
that Visa had conducted with
Forrester that about 80%
of companies are gonna
be increasingly focused
on risk management over the
next couple of years exactly
just to navigate that change.
Kind of the other 20%, I suppose,
are gonna be taking a bit
of a laissez faire approach
and kind of just hoping
for the best, which I
certainly don't recommend
on a personal note.
And that's especially true
because we kind of saw how the conditions
of the pandemic created this
really ideal environment
for fraudsters to thrive.
So between kind of the rapid digitization
of everyday interactions
and experiences that
we deliver to consumers
and then these social economic
and political unrest that coincided
with the pandemic,
it really was a kind of an environment
that allowed new, organized
and innovative fraud schemes
to come to the forefront
and in a way kind of almost act
as a headwind to this massive
digital transformation
that we had been experiencing.
And I wanna spend a little bit
of time just kind of talking
through some of these new fraud
schemes, or not exactly new,
but some of these fraud schemes
that are top of mind for us,
I think most of you are pretty familiar
with these but I want to
give you a perspective
on what we're seeing from the Visa side
as well some key takeaways in this area.
And the first one is really
around e-commerce skimming.
So during the pandemic,
we saw this increase
in the injection of malware
and the websites of commercial
and service providers everywhere
and that led to a significant increase
in the number of at-risk
accounts that were compromised
through that channel
as you can see are 85%
of those alerts come
from the digital channel,
kind of showing the focus
shifting for fraudsters as well.
And the other interesting takeaway
here is that the level of sophistication
of these skimming variants
has also increased over time
where now we're seeing their
ability to kind of hide
from detection, from
developer tools or self delete
to prevent that detection once
they've successfully exfiltrated
the sensitive payment data.
So there's kind of this
arms race that's happening
in this space that we're
always trying to get ahead of.
The second is around social engineering,
which has been obviously
around for quite a while.
But what I thought was
really interesting is kind
of how it evolved as the pandemic went on.
So what we saw at the beginning
in that February to April
timeframe is this proliferation
of fake merchant websites
that popped up selling fake COVID cures,
fake tests, respirators
and solicited payments for goods
and services that were never delivered.
And then we saw this transition
towards more phishing and vishing attacks
that were aiming
to solicit sensitive
financial services information
by pretending to be the bank
that you have a relationship
with and these attacks
weren't kind of as generic as
what we had seen previously.
The fraudsters had taken
the time to research
the financial institution
that their targeted victims had banked
with and manipulated their caller ID
so that they see him
as if they were a legitimate institution,
and that could have
resulted in a whole host
of fraud losses for some of these clients.
And then more recently,
kind of that next iteration
of that next phase was really centered
around unemployment fraud and
economic disbursement fraud
where were seeing fraudsters
compromise sensitive data
that they purchase on the dark web
and cobble together
identities to siphon off some
of these economic funds and
really test out and explore
the vulnerabilities that we see
in state unemployment systems
and in our disbursement systems.
The third is really
around kind of ransomware.
Kind of the interesting takeaway
here that we had over the pandemic
was the increasing targeting
of financial institutions,
especially those that were medium
or in the long tail
and we saw at least a couple of instances
in which these ransomware attacks
specifically targeted
sensitive card data, data
that was then later turning
up in dark web for sale.
And so, kind of in our mind
kind of ransomware attacks
on financial institutions
are pretty much equivalent
to data breaches where that
account information now
has to be regenerated to prevent
further losses downstream.
Enumeration attacks are also
a kind of this interesting attack factor
that we have been
focused on more recently.
As you can see by the graph, in the onset
of the pandemic, we had seen
the significant increase
in the number of enumerated transactions.
It was about 20% year over year or so.
And then over time,
that trend has modulated
or plateaued a bit.
And I think part of the reason
for that is that they're
kind of fairly inefficient
kind of method of fraud.
While these integrates
transactions were increasing,
the fraud that's associated
with the enumerated accounts
was actually decreasing over time.
And so, the fraudsters were not effective
and actually monetizing these credentials
through this attack vector.
Having said that, however,
we're still seeing
kind of a tremendous amount
of operational costs
that are being imposed
through these attacks.
Our data for instance, shows
that for a merchant who suffered
in enumeration attack, their approval rate
doesn't return to its pre-attack level
until two months after the
attack had been stopped.
So kind of imagine the revenue
and sales losses that these merchants
kind of endure as a result of this.
And this is another reason
why we're continuing
to focus on this vector quite a bit.
And then the final one
is really around
nation-backed threat actors.
Kind of hostile regimes
have felt the fiscal strain
of the COVID pandemic
pretty significantly.
And as the pandemic had began,
we had seen increasing alerts
that some of these groups
were gonna be targeting
financial institutions
through cash out attacks.
Fortunately, that hasn't
really come to fruition,
but we posited that the
reason for that is likely
due to them targeting
cryptocurrency related schemes
instead as a way of
generating illicit revenues.
And so with kind of these
types of threat actors
coming to the forefront
during the pandemic and
coupled with very dynamic
and volatile spending patterns,
that kind of there was this expectation
that we're gonna be experiencing
a pretty significant spike
in the overall fraud volume as a result.
But thankfully, what we
actually had been witnessing
was that the overall fraud
volume actually decreased
by about 4% year over year.
And I think part of that was driven
by our ability to shift a lot
of the merchants that
were primarily focused
on the physical channel
like wholesale clubs, and
grocery stores and pharmacies
to the card, not (indistinct)
a fairly secure manner
in addition to the expanded adoption
of secure technologies like
tokenization and contact list.
Now, at this point,
you're probably thinking,
well if we managed to
kind of weather the storm
of the pandemic and fight back
these fairly sophisticated
innovative fraudsters,
do we really need to be in this session
to learn how to manage risks
during a digital transformation?
It seems like we're doing
a really good job already
and that's a totally fair point.
I definitely want you to stay
in your seats because the second part
of this story is really
around kind of this component
of consumer behavior that we hadn't talked
about which is the fraud
rate did decrease overall
and it was certainly driven
by kind of these proactive
changes that we'd made.
But another part was also
really due to the shift
in the channel mix
where folks started to spend
a lot more money domestically
which tends to be more secure ways to pay
versus going across border
and spending money internationally
which tend to be less secure transactions.
And so if the transaction
mix between domestic
and cross-border returns
to its pre COVID ratio,
we would actually expect the
fraud rate to increase by 4%.
And given that internationally
there're beginnings
of return to normalcy as
vaccinations become more prevalent
and people start to travel internationally
more, that shift will kind of play out.
And on top of that,
you'll have kind of some
of these fraud vectors that
we had discussed really acting
as a tailwind for increasing the amount
of fraudulent activity that's
occurring to the ecosystem.
So we really have to be
very proactive to ensure
that security foundation
that we have are put in place
to kind of continue the acceleration
of this transformation is there
and it kind maintain the trust
of our consumers and the
services that we provide.
And, kind of the other factors to consider
is that a lot of firms
generally don't feel
like they can execute on their
risk management priorities.
In that same study that
we did with Forrester,
you could see that the two most
critical kind of priorities
from a risk management perspective
around protecting sensitive
data and keeping up with some
of these emerging risks
that we had discussed,
only about 1/3 of organizations feel
like they are very prepared to do so.
And, that's somewhat
of a concerning number,
you would want it to be in the 80s, 90s
for you to feel comfortable.
And so what we really have here
it's kind of these confluence of events,
we have a pandemic led acceleration
of digitized consumer
experiences and transactions,
you have increasingly
sophisticated, organized,
funded fraudsters that are
gonna take an advantage
of the vulnerabilities
and these newly digitized
consumer interactions,
and then you have firms who don't feel
like they are prepared to deal
with the evolving risk
management landscape
and kind of (indistinct)
this kind of proactive coordinated action,
it's really going to be a bit
of a challenge to kind
of maintaining the space
of digital transformation that we had seen
over the last 12 months.
And so the key around that is really
how do we can consider risk management
on a holistic level and think
about these three ways that we
can manage risk holistically
through that digital transformation.
And the first one is really
around kind of thinking
about what your ultimate end
goal is and really refining
that strategy then kind of pointing
your technology investments
in order for you to promote
and further that strategy,
and then finally coming
with a governance structure
that allows you to kind
of execute on the strategy
and realize the benefits of
your technology investments.
So I'll go through each one
in a little bit more detail.
And so, the first piece
is around strategy.
Been an incredibly overused word
almost as overused as
unprecedented, but at its core
and my mind is really a roadmap
for you to achieve your goal.
And the first part
of what I think is important when it comes
to strategy development,
especially within a risk context
is that risk organizations
tend to build their strategies
in a fairly solid way.
So, the business has a strategy
and then the risk team is
over here kind of doing
their own thing and they don't really meet
in the middle unless
something goes terribly wrong.
So the first part I think
is just really thinking
what is the overall
organization's approach
and goals, and then how
does their risk strategy
that you're building actually help promote
and further those goals?
So kind of think about as an example,
the overall company's goal is to deliver
a seamless consumer experience
taking a risk lens to it
kind of breaks it down to
well, I wanna make sure
that every legitimate transaction
for my customer is approved
and I want to make sure that
every fraudulent transaction
from my card holder is the client.
And then from there,
having that as your
organizational North Star,
you have this set of inputs
that have outlined here thinking
about what are your competitors doing?
How are regulators thinking
about kind of these types
of consumer experiences
and this example of authentication,
how does something like an
SCA in Europe apply to it?
Looking at your consumers
and how are their behaviors changing,
and some of the ways that we'd outlined
at the beginning of this presentation.
And from there, really coming
out with a holistic picture
about what are the key drivers
that are going to either
help you meet that objective,
or are gonna be an obstacle and which ones
are gonna be kind of the most impactful,
either positively or negatively.
Again, the other kind of key things
to remember about strategy
is about making choices.
You can't kind of have everything,
you have to think about
what's the best allocation
of your assets is gonna be.
And then, out of that
let's say kind of prioritization exercise,
you come out
with three to five key
strategic initiatives
that you want to really focus
on and dedicate yourselves
to so that you can meet
your objective goal.
Once you have those three to
five key objectives in mind,
then the next part is really
about aligning your
technology transformation
to further those objectives along.
And I think this piece
here is really important
because kind of what we've noticed
is that traditionally, we're very fond
of kind of building these
point solutions to deal
with specific problems.
So, 18 months ago, ATM
cash-outs were a huge deal,
so we'll build a solution
and then kind of resolve that issue.
And today, account enumeration
for instance, is a big deal.
So we'll build a point
solution and figure that out.
But 18 months from now,
it's gonna be a different fraud vector.
And so the idea is really
how do you enable yourself
to have a flexible tech
architecture that allows you
to be much more responsive
and much more agile to these
new emerging fraud vectors,
so that you're not always
kind of chasing the rabbit.
And I think you do that
through these three core
capabilities or pieces.
The first part of it
is really foundational.
It's your actual infrastructure,
your technological infrastructure.
And I'm just highlighting
kind of four pieces here
from a computing capacity.
If you're a risk analyst, it runs a query
and then they have to come back
in the morning to find out
the outcome of that query.
It probably means you don't
have enough computing capacity
in you to expand
that to handle kind of the
additional data that you have.
You need to kinda take a look
at the data sources that
you have available to you
both in-house through
your different systems
or through some of the
different acquisitions
that you have made and kind of normalize
that so you have a single view
of how the transaction hits
throughout the life cycle
as well as think about what
are some third party data
that you can use enrich
your existing dataset
so that you can further
refine your models.
And that's where analysis
velocity comes in
and then your ability to make
really quick decisions based
on numerous amounts of experiments
to hone in on the key data elements
that are gonna give you the
best, most optimized outcome.
And a big part of that of course,
is gonna be around the
algorithms that you're running
through your AI and machine
learning capability, making sure
that you have kind of the right data,
that you are training the
models in the right way
and getting optimized outcomes
so that you now have the tools
to build the capabilities
that come in that next layer
where you're digesting this data
and processing it correctly,
you're able to build fairly
flexible rule model engines
so that you're not building
a point solution to solve
for a specific fraud site,
but rather you can kind of
relatively deploy these models
in a much more flexible
and much more agile way
that would then allow you to prioritize
what alerts you want to
be automatically handled
either kind of ignored or actioned
in which alerts you want
an actual live human being
to go and analyze and
determine what actions
should be followed up next
and then see that end-to-end
case management flow,
so that based on the
outcome of these alerts
you're feeding that
back into the algorithm
to improve it and allow it to learn better
so that your outcomes
are becoming much more targeted over time.
And then finally, kind of thinking
about, well how do you output
that to your ultimate end user
in a way that provides them
with the right information
at the right time and is
easier for them to digest.
And once you have these capabilities,
you have these building blocks together,
you can start to deploy them
in ways to automate your
really core processes.
And I've used a kind
of three examples here
of types of risks that I think
every organization manages
on in one way or the other.
Where now, for instance,
if you're dealing with fraud
risk kind of going back
to the earlier point,
you're seeing this new kind
of fraud pattern emerge,
you're isolating those transactions,
you're seeing the
pattern that they follow,
you're implementing rules that
detect for those transactions
in your larger dataset, and
then you're deploying it
so that your ability to
manage these new incidents
is much more automated
and much more efficient
than it would be if you had
actual human beings doing it
and if you were actually had
to build a new capability
from the ground up to be able
to action these new vectors.
And so we're seeing
that really kind of across
the different risk types
that we are managing.
So, we're thinking about
what are the core outcomes
that we're trying to achieve?
What are the processes
that are supporting them?
And how can we make these
processes more automated
and more efficient
because we have built
that technology foundation
to begin with?
And then finally, there's
kind of the third piece
of managing risk and
digital transformation,
which is really all around governance.
Kind of one of the interesting findings
that we had in that study with Forrester
is that most organizations
are investing more in their technologies
when it comes to risk management,
whether that's next gen
capabilities, or it's analytics
or kind of automation tools.
And yet as you saw,
there are still a pretty
significant portion
of them that feel like
they're not able to deliver
on their key priorities.
And I think a key part
of the disconnect is we
tend to overinvest in tools
and under-invest in
people, and in processes
and in governance.
And I think that's usually
one of the missing pieces.
And so what we wanna really emphasize,
for me at least, governance
is really around how do
you take a consistent set
of standards and processes
that allows you to align people
across different functions
across even different organizations
so that you're pursuing
a common goal or a common path?
And what I focused on
here is really the ability
to distribute the intelligence
and the analytics that
you were able to derive
from your technology transformation
to the right stakeholders
so that they can action it
and turn those insights
into actual performance.
And so the way that you work
with your clients, share that information,
the analytics, the
benchmarking, the best practices
so that they're acting as
a first line of defense.
How do you get together
with ecosystem partners
to think through kind of
coordinated efforts to reduce
and mitigate fraud
kind of in your shared
marketplace internally
within your own functional teams?
How can you provide the
information necessary
for them to make business decisions
that optimize the trade off
between risk and reward?
And then, within your risk
teams that are distributed
around the world, how do you work
with them to localize the insights
and the inputs through their
respective market environments
so that they are benefiting
from the global scale
but they're able to tailor
that to their unique market?
So taking this holistic
approach, combining the strategy,
the technology and the
governance to make sure
you have a solid risk
management foundation
is gonna be really critical
during this time of transition
as we're kind of moving
from the COVID pandemic to what comes next
and seeing how this consumer
behavior that we had seen
during the pandemic stabilizes
and reaches a new normal equilibrium.
And I think one of the key highlights
here around risk management strategy
is that you're not doing for
the sake of checking the box
or they're gonna make your auditors happy,
should make your regulators happy.
The ultimate goal
of this approach is
positive business outcomes.
If you're able
to have this holistic
risk management framework
in place, you're less likely
to have operational failures
that increase your operating costs,
you're more likely to
have a higher loyalty
and higher client's
stickiness with your customers
and that ultimately will
drive higher profits
for you and improve profitability
for your organization.
So the key when designing
these pieces is to always think
about the ultimate business outcome
that you're driving towards.
And so, for the last
section of the presentation,
what I really wanna do is
kind of give you a high level,
let's say checklist of some of the things
that you can take back to
your respective organizations
and just measure yourself against and see
on a scale of one to 10
how strong do you believe
you're covered for some
of these dimensions I'll go through
and then for areas where you think
you could do a double click, kind of think
about how do you incorporate
this into your future roadmap.
And so the first section I wanna talk
about is really thinking through
your customer specifically.
I think a lot of times we think
about the customer experience
in a very disjointed manner
versus kind of an end to end manner.
You think about the
authentication side is handled
by different side of the house
than the folks who are managing risk.
But for me, you really have to think
through kind of what is that risk reward
for this customer interaction
and make that decision holistically
versus just trying to
optimize for one metric
over the other.
Another is also empowering them with tools
so that they can fight
fraud more proactively.
I think customers today
are increasingly getting
in a whole host of new
financial relationships
with their providers and
they want a sense of control.
And so if you give them tools like alerts
and transaction controls,
they're more likely
to remain loyal to you.
And we've actually seen fraud
alerts do significant work
in reducing the overall
fraud amount with some
of the customer accounts up
to 30%, in a recent study
that we did.
And then finally, kind
of think about ensuring
that trust is a key part
of your value proposition externally.
So, Visa itself has
done a kind of campaigns
where we just highlighted
the security features
of our products
and we actually saw a
sustainable increase,
not only with the usage
of our payment products,
but also in the activation
of them as well.
The second is really around investing
in technology and people
and we spend a lot of times talking
about the technology transformation,
but again, as the kind of
the fraud landscape evolves,
the way that we tackle it has to evolve.
One kind of specific call out,
again is really around continuing
to invest in analytics and data.
We've been using AI
models to really manage
this turbulent time and ensuring
that as we've seen kind of these increases
in illicit transactions,
we're able to decline
the fraudulent ones, but keep
the legitimate transactions
going through to make sure
that we're managing consumer
expectations correctly,
as well as investing in your people
so that you have security experts
that can help you manage this transition.
We did something similar
where we've built a risk operations center
that we refer to as the ROC colloquially
and they combine this deep knowledge
of fairly sophisticated statistical models
with these fraud techniques
and they're able to
intervene at the right time
with the right tools to minimize fraud
before it even impacts our clients.
In the last year alone,
they actually stopped
about 3 1/2 billion dollars
worth of fraudulent PV
that saved our clients
just a tremendous amount
in terms of operating and customer costs.
The third is really around
kind of, again, going back
to the concept of strong governance
and how do you think
about processes that
reinforce your strategy
and reinforce the ultimate end point
that you're trying to get to,
one is kind of dedicating time
and resources to make sure
that your people are educated
on the latest and greatest
of what's happening
in the front landscape
working collaboratively
with industry bodies to innovate at scale.
I think the things that we've done
through EMV for instance,
are a great example
of what can happen when we
collaborate to stamp out fraud
with the adoption
of EMV chip that has significantly
decreased present fraud.
And then finally, just making sure
that there are documented
repeatable processes
for managing changes to what you enhance
and making sure that your
products are built secure
from the start to kind
of reduce the incidents
of vulnerabilities that could be exploited
by the ever clever fraudsters.
And then finally, kind of
thinking about that North Star
which is your strategy,
which should be ever evolving
and kind of thinking about
those strategic frameworks
that you will leverage to make sure
that your resources are being allocated
in the most efficient way
and kind of how do you address some
of the potential gaps
that you have in your
existing capabilities
when you compare them to
the trends that are shaping
the landscape where you
operate using these forums,
these industry forums
where you can learn, and share
ideas and gather feedback.
I'm very much looking
forward to a whole host
of other sessions during the conference
that I think will really
inform my strategic thinking.
So, definitely take advantage of that.
And then being able to kind of
distill all that information
in a clear to understand
roadmap that shows you,
your organization and your
key external stakeholders
where you think the landscape is headed
and what you're doing to keep ahead of it.
I think that kind of
builds not only commitment
about accountabilities and make sure
that we're all moving
in the right direction.
And then finally, some
even more concrete terms
or some more concrete recommendations
that I wanted to share, kind of quick wins
that you can do right
after this session is over,
I think these are fairly straightforward
and most likely obvious to a lot of us,
but it's always a good reminder,
it's always a good
hygiene to keep in mind.
And the only one that I'll
kind of explicitly call out
is just our risk operation
center or the ROC
as we call it.
So, always give us a call when you think
that there are threats or
attacks that you're facing
and we'll be more
than happy to provide
assistance and support.
And so, as we like to say,
let's work together to
ROC the fraud world.
And with that, I wanna thank you
for your time and for your attention.
And please, feel free to
continue sending questions
through the chat as I answer them.