- Welcome to RSA.
I'm Linda Grindstaff,
Vice President McAfee
in our office of the CTO.
And I'm excited to be here
with you today to discuss
"Through Your Mind's Eye:
What Biases Are Impacting
Your Security Posture?"
Be sure to enter your questions in chat
as I'll be answering questions
throughout the presentation.
Let's get started.
(mouse clicking)
Cyber security personnel
such as yourselves
have many things on your plates
to address every single day.
You may be feeling like this
woman here in the picture
as you're dealing with what
alerts need to be investigated,
what systems need to be patched
for the latest vulnerabilities,
to what do you need to tell
your board of directors
in that upcoming meeting?
We all make thousands
of decisions every day.
However, our brains
don't give each decision
equal attention.
We take mental shortcuts.
These mental shortcuts are known as biases
and allows us to be able to
react quickly to situations.
Security and biases are not
topics that are typically
discussed together.
However, we all have biases
that shape who we are.
As a result, our decisions
in and out of security
can be impacted.
So let me ask you, "Do you
feel that you are biased?"
No need to answer out loud.
But, the biases that we do
have have influenced and shaped
who we are today in
both good and bad ways.
(mouse clicking)
So what do you see when
you see these pictures?
Do you see vases or faces?
Do you see a young
woman or an older woman?
Or a duck or a rabbit?
I know many of you have seen
these types of pictures before.
And my point of showing you
is that while we're all
looking at the same picture,
you may see one or both of
the objects in the pictures.
This is representative of
what happens in real life.
Many of us are at the
same meetings together
but we leave with different perspectives
about the discussion based on our biases.
And these cognitive biases
influence us in many ways.
For those of you that
don't know a cognitive bias
is a result of our brains
attempt to simplify
processing of information.
The formal definition
in the dictionary says,
"It's a systematic pattern
of deviation from norms
in judgment."
But we as individuals create
our own subjective reality
from the perception of
those inputs that we have.
And our construction of reality,
not the objective inputs
are gonna dictate our
behavior in the world.
So let's look at the different
types of cognitive biases
that could be affecting your
company's security posture.
And as I go through these, I'll
close with some tips for you
on how to overcome those biases.
One side note as we go through
the biases that you're going
to see is that they're
not mutually exclusive.
You'll see many overlaps and
things that you may hopefully
relate to you in your
day to day activities.
(mouse clicking)
The first area is availability bias.
Availability bias is a mental
shortcut that our brains use
based on past examples,
relating to information
that's available to us
on a specific topic, event or decision.
This information could come
from things that we saw
in the news, we heard from
a friend, something we read,
something we experienced, for instance.
Basically it's something that's recalled
in our memory quickly.
And when we hear that
information frequently,
we are able to recall it quickly
thus our brains feel that
it's important to us.
And then our brains think,
"Well information that we recall
fast must be important, more
important than alternatives."
And with all those urgent
interrupts that we have
and the volume of things and
decisions that we have to,
to think about and to figure out
that need to be made by all
of us on the executive levels,
in our CISOs and our administration,
it's very easy to get caught
up in the decision-making
based on the past information
that's available to us
or the present information
that we see in the news
or things like that.
And so how does this bias impact security?
For risk assessment.
Availability bias may show up when
your company board of
directors looks for an updated
risk assessment.
Rather than focusing
on the entire company,
data could be presented
with respect to an area
for which another company had a breach.
For example, we've seen SolarWinds
in the news a lot lately,
in the first part of this year,
And the risk assessments,
had they been looking at
all aspects of the business
in depth and not just
focusing on supply chain
because that's what we had
heard about in the news.
Are there issues in your
environment that require
more attention than what is trending
that you see in the news or
that people are talking about?
Risk assessment is also related
to overall preparedness.
We see availability bias
play out in organizations
preparing for things such as a high impact
but low probability events,
instead of preparing for
high probability events.
High impact and low probability
events are things like
an airplane crash or a volcano
eruption or shark attacks
or even a meteorite hitting earth.
These events have a high
impact but a low probability
to occur.
We tend to remember
those events more though
than higher probability events.
For example, when was the
last time that we heard about
a ransomware attack?
Or the last time someone's PII was stolen?
Those are more of a low
impact or excuse me,
high impact but low probability events.
But we tend to not remember those as much
as the high probability ones.
And so what happens is that
that our environments and our,
our administration and
people in our organizations
they tend to prefer to
prepare for the wrong things.
And if you listen to Steve
Grumman's keynote earlier,
you saw that what we
should be worrying about
doesn't always align with
what we do worry about
and we're focused on the wrong
things as an organization.
In the areas of decision-making,
your CISO or the cyber security
analyst may make decisions
in favor of hot topics in the news.
And these topics may
overshadow other information
that they know but aren't
exposed to as much.
So as a result, decisions
are made that aren't well,
well-rounded.
For example, if there was
a recent IOT related issue
similar to what we had back
in 2016 with the dine attacks,
your analysts may over-focus
on IOT related items
and neglect things like investing
in new security solutions
for say your mobile devices.
Around incident response.
During an incident,
emotions are running high.
And typically we need to
address the incident quickly.
Availability bias may show up
in that we are not actually
looking at the bigger
picture as to what's going on
during the incident.
And focus on scene only
where the incident occurred
without ensuring we don't
have another issue waiting
in the wings.
Let's say somebody broke into
your home through a window.
Your first thought may be
to secure all of the windows
quickly.
But, if you didn't look at
all of your security risk
you may forget that you
can shake your garage door
and it'll pop right open.
And these are just a few examples
where when you're looking
at incident response
that you really need
to focus on everything
that's happening.
And our analysts are typically
exploring data thoroughly.
However, executives may not always have
in-depth information.
So if you're at the executive level,
I would definitely recommend
that you're reviewing
all the facts beyond what is
available quickly in your mind
so you can get the full
picture of the incident.
How prepared are you for those risks?
If you're an analyst or in
a position of influence,
I would recommend summarizing the facts
so that they accurately
reflect the probability
of those events occurring
as well as considering
all possible events.
(mouse clicking)
Another bias that we see in cybersecurity
is confirmation bias.
Confirmation bias is when you
look for things to confirm
your own beliefs.
Or you were, may remember
things that only confirm
to your beliefs.
Similar to what we just
discussed with availability bias.
For example, your newsfeed
maybe full of things related
to your political beliefs
based on what articles
you've been clicking on, liked or sharing.
Chances are it's not filled
with things that oppose
your beliefs.
Where we tend to see confirmation
bias in cyber security is
in decision-making.
Are you considering all of
the different points of view?
Or are you just looking
into your close group
of trusted advisors
who may think like you?
Are you willing to push and
challenge your own beliefs
to ensure that you're doing the
right thing for your company
and making the best decisions possible?
What's your company's security hygiene?
Are you diligent about updating systems?
Or do you believe that it
won't happen to you based on,
because it hasn't happened yet?
Are you using an XDR
solution in your environment?
Or you do you feel that that's
just the latest buzzword
of the industry and you
don't need it because
your current systems are
serving your needs just fine?
Do you feel that you're more
secure when you're in the cloud
versus on-prem despite
human error can affect both?
For risk assessment and preparedness,
how do you approach
cybersecurity preparedness?
Are you passive, reactive or progressive?
Similarly to hygiene, do you
feel an incident won't happen
to me so you look past
the data to confirm that?
Or are you looking for that
data and so you're feeling
like you may have a repeat
incident if you don't do
everything possible?
Whatever data you're looking for,
is it confirming your beliefs?
Or really focusing on
the data that's showing
all of the facts and the evidence.
Are you looking at everything
that you personally know well
from when you were early in your career?
Or are you looking at
what's actually happening
in your environment?
I've seen some analysts
ignore some of the alerts
that come in because they
weren't quite sure how to deal
with those newer alerts.
So they just end up falling
back to what they know
from early on in their career,
or really just looking at the information
that's readily available
instead of actually looking at
everything that's possible.
Around pen testing.
Sometimes companies may
hire third-party companies
or they themselves may have
penetration testing performed
in their environments.
When you define the scope
of your pen testing,
are you looking for the gaps or the holes?
Or are you just focusing on the weaknesses
and the strengths?
When the results come
in from the analysis,
do you address everything
that is recommended?
Or are you only focusing on
the items that you believe
will impact just you and your business?
I know it's hard to look
beyond what we believe
because in our eyes that's ground truth.
Our beliefs are all we have
and that's what we feel
is the right thing.
But it's important when you're
making security decisions
that we're looking beyond
what we want to hear or see
and not only looking at what
shows up in our news feeds
but also looking at the
full complete picture
of the facts and the evidence,
(mouse clicking)
Unconscious or implicit bias
are where social stereotypes
about certain groups of
people that we form outside
our own conscious awareness.
So just as you see this
picture here on the left,
that is similar to our mind
and our mind is like an iceberg
where our conscious mind is
what we can recall quickly
and what we are aware of.
So that would be similar to the iceberg
that's sticking out of the water
of what you can see and what you know.
But just like with an iceberg, only 10%
sticks out of the water and
the bulk of it is underneath.
That's very similar to our brains
in that the subconscious mind
is what's slightly underneath
the water speaking with
our conscious mind.
And that our subconscious
mind stores our beliefs,
our previous experiences,
our memories, et cetera.
And so when you have an
idea or maybe a memory
from the past, that's coming
from the subconscious area
of the brain that our
conscious mind asked for.
But our unconscious mind
is deep inside the brain
so just similar to an iceberg
it's a very deep down inside
the, of the ocean.
Everyone holds unconscious
beliefs about various
social groups, activities, or things.
And these biases stem
from our upbringings,
they stem from the
influences that we've had
in our lifetime.
And so therefore we had the
tendency to organize our world
by categorizing them quickly.
And it allows us to often
think in just a very fast way
and to make quick judgements.
And this is true for all of
us as humans around the world.
Unfortunately, unconscious
bias is often associated
in a negative way, but it
could also be positive.
And just with availability
bias or confirmation bias
we see unconscious bias
arise in cyber as well.
(mouse clicking)
In decision-making, I've
seen executive blindly trust
the IT team because they're
perceived as being the experts.
And we all know that there
has been a cyber security
skills shortage over the years.
No disrespect to my IT or InfoSec friends.
However, I recommend reviewing the data
and asking for a second
opinion before blindly trusting
or jumping on the bandwagon
to agree or disagree
with something.
Often it's easy to go with the majority
to not rock the boat.
But if you feel that
something needs to be changed
or needs to be addressed differently,
don't be afraid to go against the flow.
Mark Twain is, has been quoted as saying,
"Whenever you find yourself
on the side of the majority,
it's time to pause and reflect."
And that's something to think about is,
is the majority always right?
Sometimes it is and sometimes it isn't,
but it's always good to ask that question.
With respect to risk assessment,
some people feel that older
workers are more of a risk
to a company than younger workers.
Because older workers aren't up to date
with newer technologies.
But some people feel that
younger people are more of a risk
because they engage in risky behaviors
like sharing passwords with friends
or sharing the same passwords
across applications.
And as a result, security
analysts may focus
on the wrong area as the
source of a security risk
or issue based on their biases.
And not actually again,
looking at the data at hand.
For incident response.
If there was an incident,
how would you respond?
Would you blame the
unsecure IT environment
that you feel you have?
Or would you feel that, that
the incompetent end users
were the problem?
Or would you look at the
facts and the evidence
inside and outside of your beliefs
to determine what exactly happened?
How would you and your team
respond to the incident?
If your security operations
team felt that IT
hadn't done their part
prior to the incident,
you may actually be
looking in the wrong area
for the source of the, of
the incident that happened.
Many of us have heard of the
acronym called PEBKAC before.
And for those of you that
don't know what it means it's
the Problem Exists Between
the Keyboard And Chair.
And a lot of times we tend to default that
the problem is PEBKAC but,
or is it really lie somewhere else
in one of our responsible areas?
And it's not actually
the end users fault here.
For policies and procedures.
When was the last time
your cybersecurity policies
and procedures were thoroughly reviewed?
Let's say that you feel
that your SOC analyst
is just amazing.
And you trust everything that they say.
Well because you're implicitly
trusting your analyst,
you may not think to
dive into the details.
And as a result, you could
have a firewall running
without defined rules if
you've actually never checked
that data.
For IAM, the identity
and access management.
Security analysts and software developers
may blame users for
issues and fail to look
at their internal infrastructure
or maybe their own code for the problem.
And instead be focusing
again on a wrong area.
To overcome unconscious and implicit bias,
be sure to look that or look and make sure
that you're sticking with facts
and asking all the stakeholders,
including those you may not
like or agree with for inputs.
It's important to get the full picture
and sometimes people that
you may not agree with
may actually have a good
opinion and a good possibility
of somewhere you need
to look and investigate.
And also be sure to look
in the mirror at yourself
because we all carry biases
whether we like it or not.
Did you make a mistake or are
you excusing your behavior
instead of actually facing it?
Don't be afraid to follow
in the words of Mark Twain
and pause and reflect to ensure
that you're not actually
just going with the majority
because that's the safe option.
Make sure you're hiring the right person
with the right skills,
making the correct decisions
and then addressing the
incidents in the correct way
using the data to help guide you
and not following on your
gut instincts always.
(mouse clicking)
Safety bias is another bias that we see.
And safety bias is focusing
on the shortcomings
so as not to take a risk.
Many studies have shown that
we as humans would prefer
not to lose money even though,
even more than we prefer to gain money.
You may have heard about experiments where
people were offered
various amounts of money.
And for example what if I said,
you know I was gonna
offer you $100 dollars now
or I'll give you $500
if you wait two years.
Most people will take the sure thing now
rather than waiting to
get more money later.
But what we've seen in
studies is this changes
when people are faced
with a loss decision.
For instance, if I said you
would definitely lose $100 now
or you could have a 50%
chance of losing only $1,000
most would say they'll take
the option of losing the risk,
actually of losing that $1,000
instead of going for the sure thing.
And so what we see is
safety biases slows us down
in progress of decision-making
and hold us back from
healthy forms of risk-taking.
And so, where we see this
insecurity is around our DevOps.
Is your DevOps team applying
traditional network controls
to your cloud activities?
Or are they looking at how
they can refactor your
applications for the cloud
to take your organization
to the next level?
For your risk assessment.
When was the last time you
reviewed your security products
and their capabilities?
Are you keeping with what you
have because you've already
purchased those solutions and
they're working just fine?
For example, do you know
if your current solutions
have a vulnerability
scanner that can identify
advanced vulnerabilities?
Have you ever checked?
Because things are working
just fine you may never
think to check.
And because it's not
talked about in the news,
you just keep going with
what you currently have.
For your policies and procedures.
Remember my 100 and $500
example, that same thinking
causes companies to invest in
solutions that may be overkill
to address their specific high
impact and low probability
risk factors.
So they may be having
way, way extra products
that they don't actually need
because they're pre-planning
to prepare for that next
shark attack that you know,
has a low probability of,
of actually happening.
For decision making.
When you have a lack of
information or ambiguity,
you can see system owners
are being reluctant
to upgrade their systems.
They don't necessarily want
to apply the latest patches.
They may have an unwillingness
of end users to configure
safety features.
And there could be a lack
of interest from developers
to add in new security features
to existing applications.
And as a result system owners
err on the side of caution
because they don't wanna
break anything since again,
they don't see a bigger impact.
You know, we haven't
had those problems yet
so why do I need to put
those latest patches?
Or are they error on the siding of costs
and saying you know what,
we can't afford to add in
those new, new upgrades or new products.
And so again, they just don't do anything
and take the safe route.
For identity and access management.
As you move from your on-prem
to your cloud solutions,
have you considered what
software applications
need to be refactored
to run as cloud native?
What new identity analytics
solutions need to be put
in place so you're
preparing for the future?
Have you thought about
all of those or again,
are you just kind of going
with what you have today
because it's the safe route?
Some of our social scientists
have also called the ostrich,
ostrich effect here with safety bias.
And if we think of it, you know
the ostrich effect is based
on this myth that ostriches
bury their heads in the sand
when they sense danger.
And so is your team burying
their head in the sand
when they need to make a risky decision
because they don't wanna take that risk?
So instead they just keep
going the way it's been done
for years and years because
again, it's the safe route and
you haven't had a breach yet.
So to overcome safety bias,
one of the things that I do recommend is,
is to get some distance
between you and the decision
being made.
So for example, imagine a
past self already having made
the choice successfully
to you know, make a change
that there won't be a
loss in that environment.
Another idea is if you feel
that there is something
happening in your environment
related to safety bias
is that you can also balance
out your team members
with more risk taking team members.
Those who are more comfortable
with taking that risk
or even bring in a third
party that can help you
provide that unbiased opinion
and take a risk for you
and look at and help you
move to that next level.
(mouse clicking)
There's many, many
biases that are out there
and I know that we've spent
time going through some.
And I just wanna touch
briefly on a few others
that could arise in your environment.
And remember like none of
these are mutually exclusive.
They all definitely overlap and,
and relate to each other in many ways.
So if we look at the, the framing effect.
The framing effect actually
is very similar to safety bias
in a lot of ways.
And because the framing effect
is how something is framed
and how it's positioned to you.
So for example, if something
is worded in a negative way
to emphasize the potential for loss,
then you may be afraid to take a risk.
So you may have seen commercials
for services that say
one in five companies lost their data
while using another service.
But instead of focusing that
there was four companies
that didn't lose their data,
they focused on the one
that did lose their data.
So that way you would think
about them to protect you
instead of another company.
But if they positioned
it as, four companies
didn't lose their data
with that other service
that's not going to sell or sound,
make their company sound in great light
and then you might not be
as reluctant to use them.
Another example is let's say
that you needed an operation
and a doctor came in and told you that,
"You know you have an
80% chance of recovery."
But what if the doctor came in and said,
"You actually only have
a 20% chance of death
if you have this operation."
It's still the same
operation, it's the same data
but it's all about how
it was framed to you.
80% chance of recovery
or 20% chance of death.
They still equal a hundred percent.
But would you think differently
about how you approach
the operation if that
doctor came in and said,
"You only had a 20% chance of death?"
Pay attention to how
statements are phrased
and that way you can
overcome any kind of instinct
or reactions in making that decision.
Affinity bias.
Affinity bias is gravitating
towards what we know
or what we are comfortable with.
So an example of this is where outside of,
of work or environment, is
let's say that you see somebody,
you're out and about maybe
when you travel or something
and you're far away from home,
and you see somebody with your
college alma mater shirt on
and you're in another city.
You instantly feel a connection to them
even though you may have
never met this person.
And what this does, is it
creates an in-group bias.
Because instantly you know,
hey, we went to the same school,
we experienced a lot of the same things.
And so what happens in, in
cyber related to this is
it could be around new product offerings.
Are you still using those same solutions
that you've been using
for the last 20 years
because they're familiar to
you and they're comfortable
to you and you like maybe your sales rep?
Or are you using the latest
solutions that are new to you
and are you taking that risk?
But, again it may not
feel comfortable to you.
You also may see this in cyber in that,
you may feel that your direct team alone
has all of the right answers
and no one else knows how to
secure your environment better.
So you don't need to get
a third party perspective
or opinion because nobody
knows your environment better
than your team does.
But again, that's where
your affinity start to come
into play and I would
challenge you to look at
your environment and think
about where that might be
popping up.
Similarity bias.
Similarity bias occurs, is
when we have or us as humans,
we're highly motivated to see ourselves
and those who are similar
to us in a favorable light.
So similar to the affinity
bias, we create those in-groups
and those out-groups.
So those who went to
the same college as us,
those that live in the same
city, same state, same country,
et cetera, may you know,
we create those similarly,
similarity biases with them.
And we may treat them
differently or we may,
may trust their opinion or
distrust their opinions.
And so as you're looking
at the people on your team,
do you know what do they look
like in terms of similarities?
Are they similar to what you
have in terms of thinking?
And what kind of diversity do you have?
Or are you looking for the
skills and the individuals
and the products in areas
where you need to be
in one to two years?
Or are you still looking at what you have?
Because again, it's
similar, it's comfortable
and it feels right for
you because it's safe.
As we look to a loss aversion.
This again is related to a sunk cost.
And this is observed where
companies have already invested
in their traditional IT infrastructure,
so why move to the cloud?
This takes time.
It takes resources.
So instead of doing that,
companies will keep buying
the same new servers over
and over and spending
a lot of money to keep those
on-prem solutions running.
Instead of being able to look and say,
"Hey, maybe we need to cut
our losses and move to a new,
new solution."
And distance bias.
This is prioritizing what
is nearby whether it's in
physical space, time or other domains.
And so prior to the pandemic
when we were all working
in conference rooms and in our office
and we had conversations together,
how many times did you see
that people in the room
failed to gather inputs
from their remote colleagues
on the phone?
Or did you make a decision
based on what you needed to do
right now instead of considering
those long-term effects
on what was best for the company?
Did you say, "Well you know
what, we don't have the money
this year, so we're gonna,
gonna shut this particular
service down?"
Instead of understanding what
those long-term impacts are
to the company and doing
their full analysis.
(mouse clicking)
So tips on, on removing bias.
And as you saw in each of the
biases that I highlighted,
they're not mutually exclusive.
There's many overlaps between
all of the various types
of cognitive biases.
And I wanna give you some
more tips on how to remove
those biases.
The first one is acknowledge.
Acknowledge that the biases exist.
Security is not just one
product as you all know,
it's a culmination of
products, processes, technology
and all of that depends on human behavior.
And unfortunately, human
behavior lends itself to biases.
That's just a fact of life.
The second area is seek
and review all of your data
objectively before making a decision.
Don't base that decision on
a split second gut feeling.
Don't base it on what was done previously,
on the opinion of an expert.
Consider how all those
options were framed.
When looking at that, that's gonna address
your availability, your confirmation bias,
as well as that framing effect.
The third area, include
everyone that needs to be
an inputter on a decision or
even how to handle an incident,
including those who you may not like.
This is gonna address
your confirmation bias
as well as your unconscious bias.
Your fourth area is to
utilize third-party companies
to help evaluate in an unbiased way.
By having a third party company come in,
they can look at your situation.
They can look at your posture.
They can do your pen testing.
They can look at things that you know,
aren't necessarily things that
you may have thought about.
And then you can make the
decision based on the data.
(mouse clicking)
The fifth way, is really
looking to the future
without attachment to the past.
So this addresses your safety
bias, your loss aversion,
affinity and similarity bias.
So ensuring that you're
also using monitoring tools
that have capabilities to
understand human weaknesses
and provide those proper analysis
based on the user behavior.
So look for things like UBA
or user behavior analytics
to help with that.
(mouse clicking)
And the last tip is, don't
group human behaviors together.
Instead, really look more
at individual behaviors
including your own.
Educate your employees that
cyber issues are often due to
cognitive biases.
And attackers target this in combination
with technical flaws to exploit systems.
We often hear that fishing
is still one of the main ways
that attackers get into an environment.
And that's true because
they play on our weaknesses
as humans.
They play on our biases and
they get us to click on those
links which start to download
things that we definitely,
definitely don't want in our environment.
(mouse clicking)
So applying what you have learned.
Next week, acknowledge that
those possibility of biases
and flaws in your environment exist.
Examine where you may have
biases influencing your secure,
cyber security posture.
This is going to require
personal insight and empathy.
It's not gonna be easy,
because again it takes a lot to admit
that we all have those biases
and that they all are there
and we may have made the wrong decision.
But it's better to make the wrong,
correct that wrong decision
than find your company name
ending up in the newspaper
because of a cyber security
incident, we definitely don't want that.
(mouse clicking)
Over the next three months,
you want to educate others
where and how biases could be impacting
that cybersecurity posture.
There is a blog on this topic,
out on our mcafee.com blog site.
Just search for the title
and you'll see it out there.
And you can share that with
your colleagues to educate them
on all the topics that
we've touched on today.
You also be sure to review
your cyber security posture
and adjust it as necessary.
Things change,
techniques change, attackers change,
our environments have changed.
When was the last time you reviewed that?
And be sure that you're
keeping up to date.
It's never too late to start
if you haven't looked at it
in a while.
And within six months,
be sure to build habits
across your teams to ensure
that you're consciously
removing biases.
This is not a one and done thing,
because biases don't go away.
They continue over and over.
And as soon as you have new
team players come into play
and new challenges and new
things that you need to consider
in your environment, you
always want to rebuild
those habits and keep revisiting them.
Because you wanna make sure
that your cyber security posture
is the strongest that can be.
(mouse clicking)
And so in summary, awareness
is just one of the cognitive,
sorry, awareness of your cognitive biases
is the first step of it.
And being sure that your
teams know what's going on
and know what is out there
and making sure that you're not at risk.
Our adversaries are well aware that humans
have these weaknesses and
will try to exploit them.
So what can you do to remove
biases as much as possible
inside your organization and
improve across all levels?
We definitely don't want
to see your company name
in the news.
We definitely want to help you.
And so please take this to heart
and how can, you can remove
biases from your environment.
Thank you very much and I look forward to
answering your questions in chat.