- Hello. My name is Susan Symington
and I'm a computer scientist
at the Mitre Corporation
and I'm absolutely
delighted to be kicking off
this session in trusted network layer
onboarding and life cycle
management for IoT devices.
We have two talks prepared for you today.
I'll be talking first about
introducing onboarding
in the generic sense with no reference to
any particular products or protocols.
And our second speaker will be Elliot Lear
of Cisco Systems who'll talk about some
specific onboarding solutions and
provide some details on those.
So let's get started.
With more than 40 billion
devices estimated to be online
in 2025 it's really not
realistic for us to expect
to be able to manage
those devices manually.
We need scalable mechanisms to
securely manage those devices
throughout their life
cycles and in this session
we're focused on the point of
the life cycle when the device
is being provisioned with
its network credentials.
That's the critical
point in the life cycle
because if that provisioning
isn't performed securely
then the device is at
risk of being onboarded
to a network that's not
authorized to take control of it.
And the network is at risk of having
unauthorized devices attached to it.
So I guess we're all pretty much familiar
with the onboarding problem
just based on our experience
with the typical home network.
You bring home a device
and you wanna put the
network password into it,
but if it doesn't have an
interface it's pretty hard to do
and it's even harder to do that securely.
And our home networks are insecure
in the sense that all the
devices share the same password,
so if that password falls
into the wrong hands it's very
easy for unauthorized devices
to connect to the network.
Ideally we want to have unique
credentials for each device
but with 40 billion devices
it's not gonna be realistic
to provision those credentials manually.
And right now there
aren't really good options
for zero touch automated provisioning.
So to address this challenge,
we want a trusted mechanism for
provisioning network
credentials to IoT devices
and we'd like that mechanism
to be open, standard,
secure, scalable and automated.
And let's think big let's
not just stop there,
but let's have as an added bonus,
it would be great if that
provisioning protocol
could also support
additional capabilities to
secure the device
throughout its life cycle.
Now what is trusted
network-layer onboarding?
It's a great question
because if you look through
the literature there's not a
clear consensus on the meaning.
So here's how we define it.
Network-layer onboarding
is the provisioning of
network credentials to a
device and it's performed
when the device is deployed
not when it's manufactured.
Trusted network-layer
onboarding is when the device is
provisioned with
credentials that are unique.
The device and the network
can authenticate each other
before the provisioning.
The provisioning occurs
over an encrypted channel
so there's no danger of eavesdropping.
No humans are given access
to the credentials and the
credentialing can be performed repeatedly,
an unlimited number of times throughout
the device life cycle.
So let's take a look at the
steps that are involved in a
typical network-layer
onboarding, a generic onboarding.
Okay. So what you're
seeing on the screen here,
on the left you have an IoT device,
on the right you have a network.
The device wants to connect to the network
but it doesn't know what
its network password is yet.
It doesn't have the credentials to do so.
So we're showing a wireless network
but it could be also a wire
network, it doesn't matter.
Before the network onboarding
begins we assume that the
device and the network
are already provisioned
with bootstrapping credentials.
When the device comes
out of the manufacturer
we expect it to have
these credentials on it.
An example of bootstrapping
credentials are a
unique identifier for the
device and a private key
that the device can use to
authenticate its identifier.
Now the first step in the
network-layer onboarding
is some kind of introduction
of bootstrapping credentials
between the IoT device and
the network so they can
trust each other to some extent.
Now an example of this would
be somehow the network has to
get the public key of the
device and device has to get the
public key of the network and
this could be accomplished
if they both have certificates.
It could be accomplished in a
zero touch fashion, in theory.
But for some onboarding protocols
it might require a human to perform
that introduction of the
public key for example,
and we call that human
a trusted onboarder.
Not all onboarding
protocols may need a human
and some may, some may
not, it's an option.
So the next step is the
device and the network
authenticate each other and
they create a secure channel
and they use that channel
for the network to
send the onboarding
credentials down to the device.
And now that is a network-layer onboarding
in a nutshell in its simplest form.
But remember before I said that
we would like to be able to
support additional security
capabilities to protect
the device throughout its life cycle.
So we'd like to add another
step before we do the
provisioning where we
pass some information
between the device and the
network to accomplish that.
I have three examples shown here.
The first is an attestation token.
The device could perform
some sort of attestation,
maybe measuring its hardware or firmware,
send that up to the network
and the network could use that
token as a basis for a decision
to decide whether or not
it trusts the device sufficiently
to permit it to onboard.
The second example is
device intent information.
This would be something
like a MUD URL from RFC 8520
and the device would send
device intent information
to the network so the
network can be aware of what
communications the device
is permitted to perform.
And it could use that to enforce those
communications on the network.
A third example is
application layer
bootstrapping information.
The device could send
application layer bootstrapping
information to the network.
Now I haven't mentioned
application layer onboarding yet,
but you can think of
application layer onboarding as
analogous to network-layer onboarding.
It just happens at the
application layer rather
than the network-layer and just as the
network-layer onboarding
requires that bootstrapping
information exchange that
I spoke about earlier,
application layer onboarding requires a
bootstrapping information exchange.
So what better way to support
that information exchange
than to do it as part of the
network-layer onboarding protocol.
So the next thing that
happens is the device connects
to the network using the
credentials that were
provisioned to it.
Now if device intent
information had been set up,
then the network is already
configured with access
control filters to
enforce the communications
that were the rules that were sent to it.
So in other words the router
is not gonna let the device
send or receive any
information or any messages
that it doesn't need to
perform its required function.
Now if application layer
bootstrapping information was
signed up in the previous step,
then right after the device
connects to the network,
it can automatically begin performing
application layer onboarding.
And by that we mean the device
and an application server
would authenticate each other,
establish a secure connection.
Then the application
server would download the
latest version of the
device's application to it.
Also as part of application
layer onboarding
the device could establish
a secure association
with a lifecycle management
service that could then
manage the device for as long as it stays
connected to the network.
Now let's take a look at what
points in the device lifecycle
that onboarding is relevant.
We've broken the
lifecycle into two phases.
In this slide we talk about
the supply chain phase
and the next slide the use phase.
In the supply chain phase
the manufacturer has a huge
responsibility for supporting onboarding.
The manufacturer has to make sure
that the device is outfitted
with the onboarding chip set.
It has to install bootstrapping
credentials on the device
and it has to establish yourself
as the owner of the device,
if the onboarding solution
is gonna support something
that's called proof of ownership.
Also interesting during this phase,
the manufacturer may have
to pass the device to one or
more integrators to
enable those integrators
to perform an integration.
And that means those integrators
would have to onboard
the device to their networks
to perform the integration.
So it's kinda interesting
to me that the first time
that the device gets onboarded,
may actually be during
the manufacturing process.
In the use phase the first
real owner of the device
gets the device and
performs application and
network-layer onboarding and
application layer onboarding,
as I described earlier.
And the device reaches the
operational phase and hopefully
it stays in that operational
phase for most of its lifetime.
However periodically the
device may need to be
disconnected from the
network and re-onboarded.
Maybe it needs new credentials
or maybe there's been a
breach so it has to have
its credentials refreshed.
And then later when
the device is no longer
wanted on the network or
maybe it no longer works,
it's disconnected and decommissioned.
And if it's no longer wanted
at all it reaches end of life.
But it's possible it could
be repurposed on that same
network, I mean, on a different
network by the same owner
or it could be resold to a new owner and
re-onboarded to a new network.
So you can see onboarding may
need to be repeated many times
during the device lifecycle.
Now everything I've talked
about so far is documented
in a paper that we posted last year
and it's available online.
We're in the process of updating
that in response to comments.
And that paper was developed
as a result of some
document based research we performed,
but also a series of discussions
that we held with the
variety of onboarding stakeholders,
device and chip manufacturers,
network equipment manufacturers, users,
service providers and representatives
from various consortia.
And we benefited from their
different perspectives
and also their considerable
expertise and experience.
We tried to document everything
we learned in this paper.
The paper also provides a
taxonomy of onboarding solutions
meaning it talks about
different characteristics
and capabilities that any given
onboarding solution might support.
And the most important
of those characteristics
and capabilities are related to security.
Now a lot of the security characteristics
we identified are pretty
standard typical ones you
expect to be associated
with the security mechanism,
but others are noteworthy.
For example, network
selection is the ability
of the onboarding solution
to tell the device not
only what its credentials are,
but what network it should onboard to.
Cause it's possible that a
device could have a choice
of several different networks
that it can onboard to
and we don't want it to
be duped into onboarding
to the wrong network.
Also the trusted onboarder,
as I mentioned earlier,
that's a feature that
some solutions may require
and others may not.
And proof of ownership
is a capability that
if a onboarding solution
supports proof of ownership
then it's possible for the device to
cryptographically verify
what entity is the owner.
And it can use that
information to determine
whether a network is authorized
to onboard it or not.
We also looked at
characteristics that weren't
related to security and
we looked at these from
three different viewpoints.
The user, the manufacturer and
the service provider viewpoint.
Within the user viewpoint
we broke that information
down basically into two,
the home user versus the enterprise user.
And we found some
interesting distinctions.
The home user is much more
concerned with ease of use,
whereas the enterprise user cares about
things like bulk onboarding.
Can you onboard lots of
devices quickly with zero touch
and does the solution
support device intent
and proof of ownership, things like that.
Manufacturers are very
concerned with how complex
the onboarding solution
is for them to support.
What demands it places
on the IoT device itself,
how much secure storage is
required at memory power,
things like that.
What bootstrapping
information they have to
install on a device.
And also whether the onboarding
solution supports things
like device intent or proof of ownership
that may require the manufacturer
to have responsibilities that extend
beyond just simply
manufacturing the device.
So now I'd like to tell you
about an onboarding project that
we've recently kicked off at the NCCoE.
The NCCoE's mission is to accelerate
the adoption of secure technologies and
we collaborate with innovators to provide
real world standards-based solutions
for business cybersecurity needs.
We held a workshop back
in November on onboarding,
trusted network-layer onboarding.
And as a result of that workshop,
the feedback we got there,
we drafted a project description
that it's available online.
And in that project description
we describe our intention
to demonstrate network-layer onboarding
and then hopefully other capabilities too.
Now where we are in that project right now
is right near the beginning.
Soon we'll be forming a team
of collaborators who are
committed to work with us to
design, build, demonstrate
and document example onboarding solutions.
Now we don't know
exactly what capabilities
will be demonstrated
because that will depend
on who our collaborators
are and what technologies
they bring with them.
But in the next slide I just
wanna quickly give you an idea
of the types of things that
are potentially available
for us to demonstrate.
As I said, we want to
focus on network layer
onboarding and demonstrate
that we can do it
in a trusted fashion and
that we can do it repeatedly.
We'd also like to demonstrate
additional capabilities
such as device attestation.
If we could use devices
that are capable of doing
the secure boot and
then taking measurements
of their hardware, firmware, software
and sending that up to the network
in a attestation token then
the network could evaluate that
token to decide whether it
wants to permit the device
to onboard at all.
We'd also like to integrate with
trusted application layer
onboarding as I described before.
And also support some
security capabilities
that would protect the
device on an ongoing basis.
For example, device
intent, as I mentioned,
lifecycle management, mutual attestation.
For example, if the device
wants to access some sort of
high value data on the network,
the network could require
the device to provide an
attestation token that
proves that the device is
compliant before it allows
it to access that data.
And that could work in
the other direction too.
The device could require the
lifecycle management service
to perform attestation before
the device is willing to trust
that lifecycle management service,
to update the device.
And we can imagine any
other number of capabilities
we could integrate with, for example,
access management or device
profiling or behavior analysis.
So hopefully by now you
have an appreciation of the
importance of trusted
network-layer onboarding
and you understand some of the different
capabilities and
characteristics that any given
onboarding solution might offer.
And if you wanna learn more,
you have the links to the
two papers that we have,
where you can look at that more carefully.
So in the near future
you should think about
what onboarding solution
characteristics are
important to you and your use case
and perhaps draft some
requirements, specifications,
so that when those
solutions become available
you'll be ready to adapt them.
And when they are available
you definitely should adapt them,
as soon as you can.
In summary, onboarding is a linchpin of
IOT device and network
security to protect the device
not only just during
credential provisioning
but it can also play a
crucial role in protecting
devices throughout their life cycles.
Now before I wrap up,
I wanna thank the folks listed
on this slide for providing
some of the content
in my presentation and also
in Elliot's presentation.
We're very grateful to
them for their help.
And I wanna thank my colleagues
at the NCCoE and at the MITRE Corporation.
And most of all I wanna thank you,
my audience, for your
time and your attention.
And next I want to introduce
Elliot Lear, principal
engineer at Cisco Systems.
- Thanks Susan, that was
really really informative.
My name is Elliot Lear,
as Susan mentioned,
and I work at Cisco Systems on
IoT security, onboarding and trust.
And now I'm gonna talk
about three of the standards
that have been developed
over the last few years.
In fact they're just finishing up.
So what you're seeing is
a sneak peak as it were,
as the technology begins to diffuse.
So the first technology that
I wanna mention is something
called a Fido Device Onboard Technology.
It's so new that they just approved it
in the last few weeks.
And this technology primarily
covers application onboarding,
as opposed to network-layer onboarding.
And we'll just talk about it
briefly to give you an example.
The other technology that we're gonna talk
about is a cloud-based network application
and an application layer onboarding,
something called bootstrapping
remote key infrastructure.
And since that's such a mouthful
everybody just calls it BRSKI.
But we're gonna start off with the
onboarding technology at
the bottom which is the
Wi-Fi Alliance's Device
Provisioning Protocol or DPP,
which is also known as Wi-Fi easy connect
and it's an optional
component of Wi-Fi six.
And you can see based on
some of the information
that Susan presented earlier
where these different
technologies fit, right.
You have the trusted onboarding
a trusted application layer
onboarding for two of them.
A trusted network
And I won't be talking very
much about for instance,
device attestation, even though that's
a very interesting area.
So let's get started with DPP.
We're gonna get right into
it with some diagrams.
So the way that DPP
works or was envisioned
to work initially is
that you have a cellphone
and that cellphone scans
something like a QR code,
that QR code contains a
unique piece of information
that only the device
on the left would know,
that printer that you're going to onboard.
And the cellphone would
communicate directly
with that printer to prove to the printer
that it has this one piece of information.
And then once that's done,
a configuration phase
occurs and during that
configuration phase the
network credentials are passed
from the cellphone to the printer.
Now this technology was originally
designed for the consumer.
It has recently been
updated for enterprises,
where rather than passing,
say a WPA three or SAE passphrase,
what can be passed during
the configuration phase
would be a certificate
that could then be used
with say EIP or EIP radius authentication.
And once the configuration
phase concludes,
what then happens is the device just joins
the network as it would,
using whatever information
was passed during that phase.
So what's in that funky QR code.
What is this secret
sauce of DPP as it were.
This is what you would see in a QR code
and it contains some optional information
like a Mac address, a serial number,
but mostly what you see
there is a public key.
What happens is that the device here,
your phone, proves to
the device on the left,
the onboarding device,
the thing if you will,
that it has the public key by
encrypting some information
in the public key or essentially doing
a Diffie-Hellman exchange, a CDH exchange.
And then the device then proves back
that it has the private key.
Now those of you who are
paying very close attention
will note that anybody
who has that QR code
can onboard this device.
Now one of the nice
things about DPP is that
it's pretty darn simple in this regard,
in terms that this is the
only thing you need to
onboard the device.
As originally envisioned though,
you had to have the cellphone
or something like that,
but we can get a lot
more involved with DPP.
And instead of say, having
the device directly talk
to the cellphone, maybe
it's talking to the
routing infrastructure
which is off on the right,
and you can look at that
Wi-Fi router as maybe
one router talking to, or
maybe it's a bunch of routers
in your enterprise that are
controlled by that system above.
And you could imagine the phone
that's taking in that QR code,
talking to that system above and saying,
providing that and thus the
exchange takes place through
backend communications to the router
to allow the printer to onboard.
And so the nice thing
about DPP is that it's
rather minimalist and you
can build out additional
capability on top of it,
which makes it unique amongst
onboarding technologies,
in that it is minimalist.
The other ones are fairly
complex in my opinion.
So let's in fact get to what the
advantages and disadvantages are of DPP.
So the first advantage is that
it is one step provisioning
as it's currently defined
and as people assume
there would be this thing
that you scan the QR code.
It can work with or without
internet connectivity.
And you know in the home,
maybe you can assume that
internet connectivity is there
all the time but you know,
if you happen to be in
a military installation,
may be a little less so.
So you need a little flexibility and
DPP provides that flexibility.
Ownership transfers, such
as there is ownership
in the context of DPP,
is merely a matter of resetting
the device and then using
that same code again.
And I keep saying QR code
but all you saw there
was a public key, right?
Well you can communicate that public key
out of band through
whatever other means to it.
It doesn't just have to
go through a QR code.
And the other advantage
of DPP is that it doesn't
require that a PKI be present
through the manufacturing process.
Now people differ in terms of opinion
as to whether that's a big deal.
But if you think it is a big
deal and some manufacturers do,
this is the one onboarding mechanism
that doesn't require the PKI.
On the other hand there
are some disadvantages
and those disadvantages include,
there are some chip set limitations.
If you actually want to use
the phone those are being
overcome based on new
generation's of chips.
As currently envisioned it was really a
one-step onboarding process not a
zero step onboarding process.
And this is a bit of a trick
for certain environments,
where they really don't have the people
who can do the onboarding
on site for instance,
so they have to do
something a little different
or enhance the DPP flow.
There's no native
anti-counterfeiting capabilities
and this is primarily developed
through wireless technologies.
Let's move to our next
technology, which is BRSKI.
Now BRSKI is based on
something called a voucher.
And what happens is that
the manufacturer is going to
essentially generate this voucher
and send it off to the device,
basically with a signature saying
here's some information that
you should know about this deployment.
And that might include a
trust anchor for instance,
that the device can use to
trust the local deployment.
But how does does this information
get from the manufacturer
to the local deployment,
and that's what BRSKI is all about.
So it starts with the device
sending a voucher request
into the local environment
and then that information
gets forwarded to your registrar,
this might be your AAA server.
It goes up to the internet and
along the way this guy here
has noted that everything looks good.
This guy here has received,
as part of this exchange,
a trust anchor that it puts in the
voucher request and then signs.
All that goes up to the
manufacturer using the internet
and the voucher comes back
and gets delivered into the device.
And now based on this
trusted introduction,
you can use other protocols
like enrollment over
secure transport to configure
a normal device certificate
for the local environment
and then use normal
AAA functions like ETLs
for the device to onboard.
So the benefit is that this can indeed be
zero step provisioning at least in the
first instance of onboarding.
It has some basic
anti-counterfeiting mechanisms
that manufacturers can
employ and customers can take
advantage of to know that
they're getting genuine equipment
because it's all certificate based.
It leverages much of the existing
enterprise infrastructure.
Many of the commercial AAA
servers already support EST
and BRSKI is merely an extension to EST.
Some disadvantages are
that it requires an online
manufacturer service and it
requires internet accessibility
and ownership transferred is
required which complicates
matters in a long supply chain.
And it requires a certificate
infrastructure inside the
manufacturer and it does indeed
need a little bit more work
to support wireless in terms of scale.
Now let's talk about FIDO's
device onboarding technology.
Now this was based initially
on a contribution from
Intel which was known as
STO and now this is now FDO
and where it says review draft online,
actually that's now an
approved FIDO standard.
And one of the key goals of the
FIDO specification is ownership transfer.
And in such a way that you
can have a late binding
and that late binding means many things.
One of the things it means
is that you can simplify
device configuration for
various locales or customers
by having some amount of information
arrived at the local deployment.
And this might include firmware updates.
It might include configuration updates.
It's a very flexible architecture
but it is primarily focused
on application onboarding.
And so what you see in this
slide is with and without
and what you end up
having happen without FDO,
is for the manufacturer ,
it can mean having to
have custom products,
custom SKU's for different deployments.
And we see this for instance
in smart cities all the time
where you have very custom and bespoke
per customer configurations
and the theory being,
well maybe there aren't so many customers,
but as it turns out
there's a lot of cities
and this gets to be more
complex as manufacturers grow.
And so the technology
is intended to simplify
configurations with that late binding.
So FDO can be zero step.
It has the same sort of
anti-counterfeiting measures
because it is also
certificate-based as say BRSKI had
and it leverages much of an existing
enterprise infrastructure
and that late binding
is really really something
that is quite nice.
From a disadvantage
standpoint it does require
a manufactured reference
rendezvous service.
This is akin to the manufacturer
service that BRSKI offered
and that requires a little
bit of an additional
infrastructure investment
somewhere along the way,
either in the cloud or
at a local deployment.
Ownership transfer is required
but on the other hand,
FDO has gone to great lengths to allow for
supply chain management
to not be quite so painful
as say, BRSKI is today.
And this is a major disadvantage in a
network onboarding talk,
FDO doesn't really support network and
onboarding is primarily focused on
application layer onboarding.
So these are the three
technologies that we've introduced.
It's a sneak peak.
They're all really really new,
even DPP which had its first
instance a couple years ago,
was just refreshed in December.
Each of these have their
strengths and weaknesses
and we will see other technologies.
For instance, we know
that there's more coming
from the connected home IP Alliance,
and there are lots of other
technologies out there
that will be developed
because this is a very
nationed area of exploration,
but now is the time for you to explore.
So here are some next steps
that you might want to take.
And the first is to have some
notion as to how many devices
are already connected on your network.
These might be through 802.11 networks.
They might be Bluetooth devices.
It might be what we might call the sort of
dark IT infrastructure that
you might not be able to know,
so you might even have
difficulty counting these things.
There's new technologies
like thread for instance,
that are coming down the
road that use gateways.
Do you have visibility?
So one challenge that you
should be taking on is
making sure you're
establishing that visibility.
The second thing is to make
sure you have a nice strong
infrastructure in place
once a device is onboarded.
After all if you don't have that
authentication infrastructure
in place what was the point
of doing all this secure
network onboarding?
Finally, we recommend that
now is a good time to talk
to vendors about their plans
because there are a lot of IoT vendors,
you're gonna wanna have
a lot of conversations.
Right now the standards
as you heard are somewhat,
let's apply the old joke,
the nice thing about
standards is that there
are so many of them.
It's a good time to talk to
key vendors and ask what their
plans are and particularly
talk about your needs
as to whether you need zero
touch, one touch technology,
whether the internet can
be there for you or not.
And with that, I'd like
to thank you very much.
And I look forward to seeing you in person
at a future RSA conference.
And thanks to my
co-speaker, Susan Symington.