- My name is Allen Phelps.
Thanks for joining my session.
This session is entitled,
"Understanding the Impact
of Foreign Influence Activities
on Research Programs."
And as I said, my name is Allen Phelps.
I'm the CEO of Trust Farm, LLC.
We're an advisory firm on insider
threat management programs
and insider threat
management as a service,
and wanted to walk through
a very important topic,
known as the foreign influence
and how that impacts research programs.
And honestly it infects
any company organization
than it has proprietary information.
It's applicable to
all organizations that
may have information
that they would like to
protect from outsiders.
As I start off
I wanted to share with you
a really important metric
which is the 5%, we call it the 5% rule.
And that means based on our experience
of 2,500 insider threat investigations
where foreign influence was involved,
5% of the employee population
of that organization was
working for the best interest
of themselves or in the best
interest of someone else.
And what that means is not that 5%
of your employee population is bad.
It just means that based
on the other metrics
if you're trying to
identify the scope and scale
of your insider threat
problem, 5% is a good number.
Now, there are different
levels of insider threat
insider risk.
To that 5%, it ranges from individuals
just looking naturally for another job
and then may be looking
to join a competitor.
And in that case,
that is less severe or risky
than someone that's actually working
for a foreign adversary, for example
to actively steal proprietary information
including your trade secrets.
But 5% is a good number.
We always here and we asked what,
how big is this problem?
And in our estimate,
based on our experience
in investigations is
that 5% of the population
in any organization is thinking about
the best interest of someone else.
So today we'll talk about
some three,
basically three major objectives
that we want to accomplish
and leave with you.
The first one being, as
you can see on the screen.
What are foreign influence activities?
It's always good to
understand the definition of,
and have a level
a level set on
what foreign influences and how we use it
in our work and how you
can reference it in yours
and why you should consider it as part
of your threat landscape
for your organization.
The second key lesson in objective
that we'll discuss is really understanding
how the Global Talent
Recruitment Programs such as
the Chinese, Thousand
Talents Programs that you've
probably have already heard about.
We'll talk about how Global
Talent Recruitment Programs
as an example of a foreign
influence threat activity
can impact research integrity
in research security
and generally information security
as
in general
terms.
And then we'll talk about
how you actually apply
that threat information,
that understanding of
the foreign influence
threat and what are some
of the best practices that
your individual organization
can put into place in order to
mitigate those types of risks
including the foreign influence risk
and what you can do to
reduce your overall risk
at the organizational level.
So there's some things that
you could do from a policy
and procedure standpoint
and just employee,
employee contractor education to help
mitigate that risk.
So I always like to start
off with a definition
of foreign influence activities is
as you know foreign influence
has been bantered around
the news media and others
almost always related
recently to elections
and other political issues around
in the United States.
But foreign influence is really any formal
or informal program a
project or initiative
that's either sponsored openly
or overtly
or covertly or secretly by a
government backed institutions.
And what makes them,
the reason they're
called foreign influence
from our perspective is that
they're designed to target
assess, recruit and exploits
insiders, right?
These programs are designed
and these activities
are designed to compromise
security controls
and compliance controls in order
to gain unauthorized access
to proprietary or classified
or even trade secrets
or intellectual property
research materials
and most often other personnel
within the organization.
So foreign influence activities
is any formal or informal initiative
or attack
on your organization in order
to compromise the human being.
And that's how we define it
so there are I'm sure government agencies
around the world that can
have their own definitions
but just so that we're
all on the same page
foreign influence activities
when we refer to them as an organized
approach or initiative to
compromise your research.
And it's the human element that
makes it a little different,
obviously in cybersecurity
and information security,
all have some sort of
insider threat component to their programs
but they may not actually have
the foreign influence threat
or risk on their assessments.
And the reason we think it's
an incredible important area
and not to ignore is that
foreign influence focuses
on the integrity of the
individual or the human being.
So you can have the best
malware and the firewalls
and all the cybersecurity
and IT infrastructure
to prevent things like malware.
But the risk of course is
if you have an individual
that has authorized
access to your systems,
you can actually be defeated
and be compromised via
those employee actions.
And so,
we would, part of the takeaway here
is to make sure that you have
considered foreign influence
and appreciate and understand
how individual employees
and contractors and supply chain partners
external partners can impact
your overall readiness
to protect your information assets.
So,
one of the top examples
or most prolific examples
of a foreign influence activity
that we can talk about
in your,
I'm sure in your work
that you've have at least heard about
Talent Programs or Talents Programs
as they're often referred to.
We use the phrase, Global
Talents Recruitment Program
as to
to encompass all those areas
around this idea
of recruiting the
individual to do another job
outside of their current employment.
And so from a definition standpoint
you'll hear the words, talents.
And it refers to those
foreign influence activities
that promote the recruitment
of researchers or employees,
contractors or external partners
working in academic corporate
and government sectors to
gain unauthorized access
to innovative research
programs and projects.
And again, talents
is a sort of a shortened form
for Global Talent Recruitment Programs.
And so, as you think about this risk
and this threat
if you hear the term
talents, it basically refers
to that foreign influence program
that related to a Global
Talent Recruitment Program.
Talent programs are of interest
in and should be on your
risk radar primarily because
of the invisible hand
often the invisible
hand that sponsors them.
And so through our analysis of hundreds
of talent recruitment incidents
where an individual
a trusted individual with
access to research assets
or information assets
get involved,
they get involved with an initiative,
a foreign influence activity.
And when we dissect that
and understand really
what had occurred is almost
always sponsored by a government
or a military organization
interested in leapfrogging technologies
through IP theft and misappropriation.
So
as you've probably seen in the headlines
around the world that the
talent recruitment programs
will lead to a theft of a research asset
or an information asset
with the underlying goal
from the sponsoring insider
threat or the foreign
influence threat actor.
The ultimate goal is to
leapfrog in that technology.
And that's an important
key takeaway because it's,
understanding the motivation
behind certain programs
will help you identify
what's behind it.
And so you're not, it's a little different
from a typical insider threat
where you're worried about sabotage
or something at the local level.
If you have a government
and where a military organization coaching
and directing those
activities of the insider
you are really up
against the nation state.
And that requires some additional help
and expertise and resources.
But I wanted to walk you
through because our analysis,
and again, we've done, excuse me.
We've done hundreds of
these investigations
related to foreign influence
activities specifically related
to the
talent recruitment programs.
And we've come to the conclusion
that there is a predictable life cycle
or process related to the Global
Talent Recruitment Program.
And as a recruitment
process, as you can see
there is a step-by-step sort of playbook
that we've identified and oftentimes
the tactics can change.
But for the most part,
there's a predictable pattern
of behavior that we've uncovered
and through our
investigations and analysis
of managing these
incidents for organizations
across research platforms,
corporate academic
and federal government.
And just kinda walk you
through what that looks like.
So
if we consider the nation state interest
in leapfrogging technology,
it starts with understanding
how the intelligence cycle works
and the intelligence cycle starts
with an understanding of gaps.
And so the nation state
or the foreign government
or foreign military
organization identifies gaps
in their own capabilities
whether it's a military modernization
or some sort of economic interests
that they're trying to advance.
And when you identify those gaps,
what the nation state or the
government is trying to do is
determine what they're missing
in order to meet the strategic goals
of their other country
or their politicians
or whoever is actually
making the decisions
on where they wanna go as a nation state.
And so that initial first step
is to identify the technology
that needs to be identified
and determine what technologies
will fill those gaps
in their own domestic programs.
And then what makes the talent
recruitment programs work
and so effective is that
these foreign governments
these nation states will
put incentives attached to
the targeted technology.
And so what that means
is you'll see governments
like China and Russia and others
that know that they
have gaps in technology.
And then they incentivize
basically the collection
of information or details
or information in order
to close those gaps.
And so they'll put usually dollar figures
associated with the
bounty to collect those
the targeted technology,
and that allows multiple
groups from a nation state.
So when you think of a
foreign influence activity
you can see different types of
threat actors coming at you.
So you can have academics coming at you.
You can have
corporations
working on behalf
of a nation state, including
even military organizations
as we saw in the United States
targeting technology sectors
in order to gain access
to that information that
they need to fill their gaps.
Once the incentives have been identified
the nation state typically
then pushes that out
to their constituents as it were.
And the call goes out to say
if you are in a position
to collect this technology,
we would encourage you to do so.
And if you're successful in doing that
we will then reward you with
a financial incentive package
and benefits and we'll talk about that.
Once the incentives have been broadcasted
and test out to the various
information collection teams
formerly and informally,
then the hunt for who
actually has a technology
in the United States and Western Europe
and wherever in the world actually occurs.
And so there's an analysis that's done
at the nation state level
and those organizations
that are tasked to
collect the information,
to start looking at
corporations, universities,
government sector, military sector,
look for the supply chain,
partners in the supply chain
companies that are
involved in supply chains
the universities that
are involved in research
both basic and fundamental
and applied research.
And the idea there is to,
to identify organizations
that actually have
the technology to be researched.
Once they identify the organization
that owns that technology or
has access to a supply chain
that ultimately leads to
the targeted technology
then they'll start looking
at the individuals.
Again the talent recruitment
program it only works
if you can find an individual
willing to participate
in the information collection platform.
And so the idea is
once you understand
what organization has it
then you use social media and other ways
and other open source and
the alumni associations
and other ways to identify
who's actually working
at those organizations.
And so we see a lot of
attack and approaches
to targeted organizations
through the social media accounts
of individuals working
for that organization.
So as you think about
your information security
or your cybersecurity
policies and procedures,
one of the things to consider
is to make sure that you
that you train your employees
and your contractors
and your supply chain partners,
not to put too much information
out on their social media
related to the proprietary or
protected information at work.
And so oftentimes we find good
old fashioned trade secrets
and intellectual property sitting
in the social media accounts
and postings of employees who ultimately
should have known better not to do that.
The reason you wanna prevent that is
we know that nation states
and foreign influence activities actually
look at those social media accounts.
And try to identify those
individuals that have access
and of course, social media allows them
direct access and
communication opportunities
to reach out and start the
recruitment process in earnest.
And once an individual gets
recruited into a talent program
often they're tasked
with and rewarded with
identifying others
within their organization
or parallel organizations
that can provide similar
or compliment the information
collection process.
And so we begin to see if you analyze
enough of these incidents
you start seeing one
talent recruitment members
start recruiting other
or
they start hiring folks to join them
in their lab, in the US
or wherever it may be
in order to expand the
number of individuals
with access to the targeted information.
And so it really becomes a
network recruitment process.
And so our guidance is if
you actually do find someone
that has been recruited by a
talent recruitment program,
that's usually a good indication
that there's gonna be others
within your organization.
So that 5% rule
kinda comes into play
because if you have a
single talent recruit
that probably means you have one
or more
that are working against you.
And of course, the
reason we all care about
or as risk managers
you should care about a talent
recruitment program is that
it almost always leads to
the trade secret theft
or an intellectual
property misappropriation.
And we'll talk about that in a second.
So the talents, when you
interview enough of these,
and I've been in a position
both of my corporate career
and my advisory and consulting career
to do a lot of these investigations
to include actual interviews
of subjects of interest
in individuals
that have been alleged to have been
recruited by a foreign influence activity
including the global talents.
And it's always a mixed
a mix of personalities
as far as did that person
was that person witting that relationship.
Certainly, they knew that
they had a part-time job
or a co-employment, but oftentimes
they are the subject of
interests or the person
that has been recruited
is kind of shocked when
you have to explain to them
that they've been exploited
by a foreign talent program.
Now
looking for, designing your cybersecurity
your information security program
to look for talent programs is important,
but identifying somebody that has a talent
recruitment platform affiliation
is just the beginning.
We care about
participation in the talents program,
because of what our
experience has taught us
is that if you have a global
talent recruits working for you
that typically means that they have
mishandled the proprietary information
that the organization has invested in.
And so out of the 2,500 investigations
that we've been involved
with either directly
or in a consulting role
every single time we've
seen a talent recruit
we see them see those individuals
uploading, downloading
printing out, basically mishandling
the proprietary and protected information
from their employers.
And again, I'll reiterate
the reason you care about
the global talent program is not because
you don't wanna lose your employees,
which is obviously something very few
organizations wanted to.
But most importantly
it's an indicator that
they're probably misbehaving
there's some misbehavior
related to how they're handling
your proprietary information.
So how many talent programs are there?
We estimate there are roughly
3,000, primarily because of,
if you recall
the diagram on the lifecycle,
every time we'll see an incentive
put out by a nation state.
We see many organizations
coming after that same target.
And so the global talent recruitment
it's a very large, it's
not just a single entity
that's coming after your organization.
There were literally hundreds of thousands
of organizations that are trying to
or individuals trying to get access
to your proprietary information.
We have analyzed
what type of technologies
that they're looking for.
So if you look at the
US critical technology
or critical infrastructure
functions, and you look at what
what is being targeted
by the Global Talent Recruitment Programs,
it's almost identical match.
And so,
defense in national
security, banking and finance
the food supply chain, utilities, water
the classic critical
infrastructure are almost
always involved
in being targeted by
the foreign influence activities.
And
if you're wondering,
if you're a part of an organization
and you're trying to figure
out if you're actually
being targeted by such a
foreign influence program
like the talents program,
if you happen to work
or are involved in the supply chain
of any of those critical
infrastructure sectors
there's a good chance
that you are being targeted
or will be targeted.
And so you have to assume then
from a risk management perspective
that there's a likelihood
that you would be a target of
a foreign influence attack.
And,
we have found it in almost all the sectors
listed there on the screen.
And so,
and again, one of the, as a risk manager
one of your jobs is trying
to keep it, keep an eye on
things that might surprise
you and make sure that
your security controls and
your compliance controls
are such that you can
identify issues that pop up
sooner rather than later,
so that you can remediate
and manage that risk of properly.
I always like to share tactics,
techniques and procedures
because I think it's a
really important thing to do.
And we do see a difference
between the China
or the Chinese talent recruitment programs
versus say the Russians or the Iranian
talent recruitment programs.
The main difference and
there are other countries
that come after advanced technologies.
I just highlight those three countries
because they seem to
be the dominant players
that we run across.
And I would estimate 85 to
95% of all talent recruitment
recruitment activities
seem to benefit China.
That's not an assessment
against the country.
It's just the fact is that
I think it's a numbers game.
There's so many talent
recruitment programs
coming out of China
that it only makes sense
that the number of recruits
that are participating
would be benefiting the
government of the PRC.
The main difference that we see
from an analytical perspective
between the Chinese talent programs
and the Russian and Iranians
is that the Russian and
Iranians act more like spies.
And so what I mean by that is
when they identify somebody
with access to information of interest,
we see them moving off when
more to a covert relationship,
so that the relationship is protected
from outside observers.
We don't see that on the Chinese behavior,
the China talent programs
that behavior seems to
be a numbers game, again
where there's so many people involved
that they're really from
a risk security standpoint
and an operational security standpoint.
There doesn't seem to be a
fear of being discovered.
Certainly, you don't
wanna anyone to get in,
I assume that they don't
want their talent recruits
to get
indicted or prosecuted.
But the reality is that
there's so many people involved
in these talent programs is that
if you lose one, you probably have,
I don't know if there's
ever been an estimate
but there are many more that have access
to the same information.
So there's this idea that
there's a power in numbers.
And so really understanding where to look
and identifying where
to put your resources
is pretty critical to
them to match that risk.
There is a Wolf pack.
What I call the Wolf
pack nature to talents
and the talent recruitment
programs in that,
and this is just a graphic
that I'll share with you.
This is
an investigative charts relationship
based in
visualizer that allows
you to help visualize
how big this problem is.
And so the target in the
center of this graphic
represents a targeted company.
Outside there are smaller targets
those are professional associations.
Those are university alumni associations
professional groups and
the little dots around
all of those are individual
insiders, if you will.
And so if you happen to
be the center of attention
so if you have a really great technology
or if you're involved in an
advanced technology field
that is of great interest
to nation states,
you will see multiple people
multiple entities trying to gain access
to your networks, into your information.
And so when you think about the,
how big the insider threat program is
based on foreign influence,
I hope that you recall this because
this is a really typical
graph that we come up with.
Once you start identifying
individuals involved.
And so,
like I mentioned previously is that
if you have one global
talent program member
that had been someone
insider that you trusted
that got recruited by a global
talent recruitment program
you probably have many
more that you haven't seen.
So it's a bit of a, it's
kind of a lead indicator.
So if you do discover this
risk within your organization,
it's really important
that you take a look at,
take a look left and right
and to see who else may be involved.
So some of those other examples
of foreign influence activities,
most is just a massive
volume of activities.
If you can just imagine how many folks
are coming after your information,
there's just
so many ways to lose
intellectual property these days.
But one of the things
that they have in common
are the goals to advance
political, military
or commercial objectives
at the expense of others.
It's always cheaper to steal a technology
than it is to innovate it from scratch.
And so we see that activity all the time.
As I mentioned, social engineering,
the LinkedIn hunting, if you will,
of your insiders is occurring daily.
There are more formal
social outreach programs,
cultural outreach programs
that are authentic and legitimate,
but oftentimes can have
a secondary purpose,
which in most cases,
advances the belief system
of a foreign power.
We see lots of foreign
influence activities related
to mergers and acquisitions,
venture capital funding
and other financial investments.
And so,
if you're a great researcher
or you're working on
something really important
and you have trouble
finding capital funding
to commercialize your idea
or just seek good old
fashioned research funding
we see researchers that are highly capable
reaching out to go find the money
that they're looking to go get.
And then another type of
foreign influence activity
that we see is what we refer
to as innovation competitions,
where
there is a open
basically an open casting call
for anybody that has a good idea
or has access to proprietary information.
You bring that idea to
these competitive platforms.
You basically make a pitch for the capital
or for the investment during
that process, of course
you have to share your secret
sauce or your trade secrets.
And so it's a risky behavior.
Sometimes they get the
investment, sometimes they don't
but in all those cases, you have to share
your proprietary information
sometimes without any return.
So what's the impact?
As you can imagine,
the misuse loss, theft
and misappropriation
of
IP assets can be harmful,
primarily because
most organizations rely
on information assets
to be competitive or to
remain as an on-point entity.
So it's important that we
understand that if you lose,
if you have a foreign
influence activity occurs
and you have someone
that misuses or steals
your intellectual property
there's always a problem with that
and consequences that go along with that.
The coercion of trusted researchers,
that's once you lose,
once you lose the ability
to trust your particular employee,
unfortunately,
it's hard to get them back on track.
It's not impossible but we often see
human resources get involved.
Once somebody has been compromised
by a foreign influence activity.
The compromise of your controls
is probably the biggest thing
for the attendees in this.
And so you can work really hard
and have a great security
controls and integrity standards.
But if an individual
decides to participate
in a foreign influence activity
all that can go out the window
and there are consequences
not only for that individual
but also the employer, right?
So your organization can actually
if you have research agreements
and complaints agreements,
and with the government
or partners,
if you have an insider that breaches
those terms and conditions,
the organization itself can actually be
in jeopardy.
We almost always see a violation
of complainants policies.
And of course, some
non-disclosure of foreign research
relationships or the funding
is an issue related around
this idea of conflict of interest
and conflict of commitment.
And so,
if you do have somebody involved
either an employee or a
contractor that gets involved
in one of these foreign
influence activities
then it almost always results
in a compliance investigation.
And there's things that
happen after you get
when you go into the
remediation mode, excuse me
you'll have to,
there are decisions that
related to what to do about
once you find it and you
assess how bad the impact was.
So how do you, how would you apply this?
How do you apply this
mitigation effort, if you will
and apply some best practices
to your organization?
We recommend because we focus
on research organizations
we recommend implementing
a research security management program.
Of course, even if you don't have
a hardcore research capability
you can call your program
insider threat management
program, IP protection
intellectual property protection program,
and
whatever that formal
name is, the idea is that
you have a dedicated formal program
to assess that risk, apply controls
and remediation capability
to take a look at
how to reduce the compliance risk
and how to improve
and to change risky employee behaviors.
That's probably the key there
and establish the governance
framework in order to
ensure that that risk
management process is there.
And it integrates with
all the other controls
and complaints, policies and
procedures that you have.
And so it does take a dedicated
effort in order to plug in
a research security management program
or insider threat management program.
'Cause it runs across all
functions within a business.
And you wanna make sure
that your program enhances
the policies.
So having a policy without
training for example,
is sort of certainly not a best practice
because you have to prepare
your employees and your contractors
and your supply chain partners
or your external partners.
You wanna prepare them to
actually identify when a risk
or a threat comes into their world
and take the appropriate action
so that they do not compromise themselves
or most importantly the organization
for which they they work for.
And you can accomplish that by training.
Training and building awareness
around educating the workforce
on foreign influence
and how to avoid that.
I often say when we get involved
in these incidents is that
this was completely avoidable.
If you had an employee
that was aware of the risk
if they were aware of the risk
and they still did the
behavior that was compromising
as an investigator that
is called an intent.
And so that changes
the conversation moving forward.
So if you have someone that intentionally
harmed your organization or
took advantage of their position
that's a much different, a
much different conversation
than somebody that excellently
went to work for a foreign power.
There were some internal
and external drivers
of organizations have to pay attention to,
certainly, if you get federal
or State research grants,
those granting agencies
are put in more scrutiny
and rigor around
how they expect the
receiving grant organization
to behave and by extension
what the expectation
of the user behavior is.
And so understanding what
your requirements are
to comply with those compliance
monitoring enforcement
standards are pretty critical.
There is an increasing
interest in State quarter,
an increase in State quarter
interest in research integrity
from a financial and reputational
stewardship standpoint.
And of course the public for those of us
in the United States, is this idea of
ensuring that our tax dollars
are not being exploited
by another outside country
at the benefit
of the taxpayer.
And of course, there's
been lots of headlines
related to research or misbehaviors
that are driving some of the changes.
So there are some internal drivers
in addition to the external drivers
of why an organization needs
to apply some best practices
and they differ by
the industry or a sector
that your organization might be in.
But in academia, for
example, having an unfunded
and tenure tracked researcher
is always a bad thing.
And from a corporate
or government organizational standpoint,
this idea of having an
internal researcher pressure
to have a fair and balanced approach
to risk mitigation is critical.
The reason you wanna apply
some of these best practices
kinda follows the risk mitigation practice
in that you wanna reduce
the likelihood and impact
of an intellectual property, trade secret
and proprietary information loss, theft
and misappropriation
and you wanna shorten the time
between identifying the
incident and then assessing it
responding to it and remediating it.
And for those of you that are involved
in information security or
cybersecurity, that is very
that tracks with the normal
threat identification
and assessment and then
responding to that incident.
And of course, the goal is to make sure
that you reduce the
risk to the organization
so that it doesn't become a victim
of foreign influence threat activity.
So that's what I have today.
I appreciate
your attendance.
Again, the key takeaways
for influences are real.
The threat actors are out there
and it should be managed
both at the organizational
and individual level.
There are responsibilities
for both is the best practice
implemented research
security management program
or something similar to reduce that risk
and identify it and
respond to it effectively.
And the idea is that if you
improve your risk controls
and your security controls,
this is a manageable threat.
Understanding how your
employees, contractors
and others involved in your organization
can participate in
foreign influenced attacks
educating them to not
get involved in things
like the Global Talent
Recruitment Programs is critical.
So thank you very much for your time.
I appreciate your attention
enjoy the rest of the RSA conference.
And,
thanks for calling.