- Good day.
My name is John Brandt,
Information Security
Professional Practices Lead
here at ISACA.
I would like to welcome all
of our conference participants today
to today's session titled
Upskilling, Credentials
and Soft Skills: Closing
the Cyber Workforce Gap.
Today I'm joined by my
two esteem panelists,
Caitlin McGaw and Greg Touhill.
Caitlin would you like to
introduce yourself please?
- Hi, I'm Caitlin McGaw,
CEO and founder of Candor McGaw,
an executive Search and
Career Management Practice
for IT audit cybersecurity
and IT GRC professionals.
- Greg.
- Hello everyone.
I'm Greg Touhill.
I am a board director at ISACA.
I'm also in my day job,
I'm the Director of the CERT Division
at the Software Engineering Institute
at Carnegie Mellon
University in Pittsburgh.
And previously I served as the president
of AppGate FederaL,
a cybersecurity and advanced
technologies company.
And before that I was the Chief
Information Security Officer
of the United States government.
And I'm looking forward
to our conversation today.
- Thank you very much.
I wanna begin this morning
by sharing new research from ISACA
that measures where we
are with the current state
of the cybersecurity workforce.
Particularly the skills gaps,
the higher managers are noticing
and the long time it
takes to hire open roles
in those cybersecurity teams.
ISACA's 2021 state of cybersecurity
was released this week
in conjunction per say.
This annual research is
released in two parts.
The first examines the
cybersecurity workforce
and the second, which will
be released this summer,
looks at the threat landscape
and current trends in
combating cyber attacks.
More than 3,600 cybersecurity
leaders participated
in this year's annual survey
which represents our largest response
and 44% over last year.
We found that it's recorded each year,
there are mains challenges
in finding qualified
well-rounded candidates.
Research also shows
that understaffed teams
remain strongly correlated
to an increasing number of cyber attacks.
Despite years of effort
by industry, government
and academia and many taxpayer dollars
to develop a stronger pipeline
of cybersecurity candidates,
little has changed.
One problem remains that
while cybersecurity
jobs are in high demand,
few organizations offer
entry-level opportunities
leaving few entry points into the field.
How can we once and for all
begin making a significant impact
to the ongoing skills gap.
Before we begin discussing these gaps
and possible solutions,
I wanna briefly share some responses
that ISACA received
to its 2020 State of Cybersecurity Survey.
With this particular question here,
how would you describe
your current staffing
of your organization's cybersecurity team?
61% say that their cybersecurity
teams are understaffed.
14% saying significantly.
Only 34% say that their teams
are appropriately staffed.
Of interest here that
although that number is low,
it does represent a slight uptake
from last year of 3% points.
Does your organization have unfilled
or open cybersecurity positions?
And more than half of respondents say
that their team still
has unfilled positions.
And this is just a growing trend
that continues year after
year and really a pain point
for everyone who is involved,
trying to make a difference.
On average, how long does
it take your organization
to fill a cybersecurity position
with a qualified candidate?
In one glimmer in good
news, only 16% reported
it takes longer than six months
to fill an open cybersecurity position
in 2020, 29%...
last reported that it takes
longer than six months.
However the three to six month timeframe
is still very prevalent and increasing.
In 2020, 30% had said it did
take take three to six months
which represents a double-digit
gain from the year prior.
On average, how many
cybersecurity applicants
are well-qualified for the position
which they're applying?
50% of those generally
surveyed do not believe
their applicants are well-qualified.
It can be pretty disheartening
to be a hiring manager
and feel that only 6%
of the applications you
receive are from qualified
or are from candidates
who are fully qualified
for that role.
Two more data points to add
that are on the side are that only 27% say
that recent university
graduates are well prepared
for cybersecurity challenges
that the organizations are facing.
And only 31% say that their
HR teams regularly understand
their hiring needs.
What are the biggest skills gaps you see
in today's cybersecurity professionals?
While technical skills
remain in highest demand,
employers are seeking
well-rounded candidates
with solid soft skills.
The biggest skills gaps is shown here
on the screen begin
with soft skills at 56%.
And as you'll see,
technical related skills
are a significant distance behind those
and vary everything from
security controls down
to basic IT knowledge.
When we hear that cyber
professionals lack soft skills,
what does generally entail?
I wanna first start with Caitlin
if you would take this question.
- Thanks, Greg.
John, sorry.
I think there are some things that come
up all the time, such as, verbal
and communication skills and writing.
But things that I hear about particularly
from CSOs is emotional intelligence.
Being able to understand
and manage your own emotions in order
to effectively communicate, empathize
with others as well as resolve conflicts.
And in fact, the CSO
that I was just talking well said
he'd take emotional intelligence any day
over certifications.
Not that certifications
are irrelevant, but just
that it's so much harder to
train emotional intelligence
and enthusiasm rather than the skill set,
the hard skill set.
And another thing that
comes to mind is resilience
which folds in a lot of
different sorts of attributes,
such as optimism and persistence or grit.
Continuing to push through
even when you faced challenges,
because gosh, cybersecurity is,
can be a frustrating business.
Things can go terribly wrong
and people have to be able to
sort of get back on the horse
and get going to solve
those huge problems.
So I would highlight
those two amongst the many
that we often hear about.
- Thank you very much.
Greg, would you weigh in on this?
- Yeah, I will give a big
amen to Caitlin on that.
Having served in a wide
variety of organizations,
for example, at one point I was head
of the Air Force's cyber training programs
and commanded a wing
of 12,000 Airmen as they
were entering their careers.
But then I've been an
operational commander,
I've led the federal
government's cyber programs
as the Chief Information Security Officer.
And we've seen all of that
with the different environments
that I have been involved with.
And that grit and
perseverance, those are things
that you really need to
nurture with individuals
and particularly in
the cyber career field.
And our survey shows
that, the demand out there
about 79% are looking
for folks who are individual contributors.
And we say that cyber security
really is a team sport
because you've gotta
work along a wide range
of skillsets in order to
have an effective risk management program
for your cyber environment.
So having those soft skills,
the communications, the empathy,
the grit, the perseverance,
the ability to work as a team.
And it's often a pickup team
based on different situations
and that kind of flexibility
and adaptability,
that's a collection of skills
that leaders need to nurture.
And often you may get a new employee
that is not necessarily fully
experienced in those areas
but as a leader, you've gotta help
those folks gain those skills
and nurture them along the way.
And it's a twin edged sword
because you're not gonna
really have an opportunity
to find that perfect
employee right off the bat.
Sometimes you're gonna have to say, okay,
so what skills and attributes I must have
and then where can I grow
that employee into meet
the needs of the team.
- Fantastic responses
and a lot of value there
and things that we've heard before.
Something I didn't hear
mention though in particular
which I, if we could just extend this
for a second here is
critical thinking, right?
In particular, the analytical
data interpretation.
And I think that in
today's modern landscape,
especially with this
emphasis on misinformation
or disinformation, right?
So two questions come to mind for me.
One is that the part of
typical job description
that's out there is
typically highly focused
on the technical attributes
you're looking for, right?
And while we've seen
some better men on those
with job posting shrinking in size
and not necessarily
looking for the unicorn
who's done everything.
It begs, the question is...
Is if soft skills is
remaining the largest gap
there, are employers actually changing
how they're hiring, right?
And what's happening with
regards to the programs,
the talent pipeline if you will. Caitlin?
- Well, I think, let me
address first, you brought up
sort of the job descriptions.
It's interesting that I'm
seeing more job descriptions
that are actually folding
in, bullets around sort
of the soft skill attributes
that companies are looking for.
But I think something that
continues to be problematic is
the search for the purple squirrel.
The aspirational job
description, which tends to rule
out too many people, women in particular,
if they don't see a
really strong correlation
between the skill sets that they possess
and those listed on the job description
will often be discouraged from applying.
And then to Greg's point about management,
I think managers really
absolutely have to understand kind
of what they need in the job
and who can really do it
because there are many ways to expand
that candidate pipeline,
if you think creatively about
what it really takes to do the job
and what could be trained
from a hard skills perspective
with a moderate investment in training.
Greg what do you think?
- I'd like to pile on to that?
At the end of the day,
there's a couple of
things that I've learned
throughout my professional career.
And one that's really
important is one I learned in
the military where leaders lead people,
managers manage stuff.
And in the cyber business,
you've got to be both.
You've got to be both
a leader and a manager.
And you can come to the
table with a certain amount
of skills out there, but
you also have to recognize
that you're gonna grow in your skillset
both as a manager of stuff
like processes and procedures
but also leader of people.
And the key thing that
helps folks along the way
and if I'm a hiring authority,
I'm looking for the proper attitude.
And there's lots of different ways
that you can look during
the interview process.
Does this person have the right attitude?
Does he or she have the
ability to go out there
and be dynamic and embrace new challenges?
Do they have a willingness to learn?
Are they eager to better themselves?
All of those things, it's
very difficult in a resume
to push forward those types of things
but candidates can really
posture themselves well
by demonstrating the potential for growth.
The willingness to extend
beyond just the job description
and demonstrate that they're
willing to go out there
and compete well.
Such as going out and
getting certifications
from ISACA or other organizations
to prove not only their ability
to expand their horizons
and demonstrate their technical powers
but also to go above and beyond.
And attitude will always
trump the paper route.
So as a hiring authority
and somebody who's hired a lot of folks
and had to recruit a lot of folks.
I'm looking for folks that
are showing me the potential
to do even more than what
they've done in the past.
And I can go and I can teach
you how to be a better leader.
I can teach you how to be a better manager
but I can't teach you to
have a positive attitude.
I can help just to emulate that
and I can show you the way.
So as we're recruiting, we're looking
for that person who is
demonstrating the potential
to learn and grow.
- You know, if I can
add just one more thing.
I think that those are excellent points.
And to that, it's on the
candidate side to sort
of demonstrate their skillset
and to bring those stories
about their good works
and their attributes forward.
But it's also on hiring leaders
and Greg you strike me
as an exemplary one,
you actually try and help people,
but I've seen so many hiring leaders
in my professional practice
who just simply aren't good interviewers.
And maybe more comfortable
interviewing candidates
around the technical skills,
but in fact aren't very
thoughtful at times
about the questions they could ask
and the listening they
could do around sort
of the soft skills and the traits
that the candidates might bring forward
if they were asked other
sorts of questions.
So just to kind of put that
out there to hiring leaders
to also really think about
the questions they're asking
and what they're listening for.
- Yeah and let me go to one more pile on
before we hand back to John.
I'm actually looking for folks
that provide me diversity, equity
and inclusion in my workforce.
And for those folks who feel like,
I'm under qualified for certain portions
of this particular job.
If you've got the hard skills
and you can contribute
as part of that team,
I still wanna hear from you.
I still want you to apply
for those types of jobs and
go through that process.
And don't be deterred just
because you may not have 100%
of all the skills I'm looking for.
So for our audience members
who have looked at jobs and said,
hey, I don't meet 100%,
so I'm not going to apply
or I'm not probably the
right person for this.
Let me as the hiring authority
be the decider on that.
Tell me what you bring to the table.
And the best thing you can do
is not sell yourself short.
I can teach you a whole lot.
I'm looking for somebody
who has potential to grow.
And a lot of my peers are out
there thinking the same way
because it's a challenging
market for hiring.
And I don't wanna necessarily
wait for six months
or four months to get
somebody who's perfect.
I'm willing to get somebody in there
who can hit the ground running
and deliver some capability,
but really can grow to that 100%.
Back to you, John.
- Those are two outstanding perspectives.
And I think that I would
just add on to that, right?
To wrap up this point before we open it
to our first opportunity for questions is
that to recognize that
largely speaking, even today
that the workforce represents
a million of people
who just took different journeys, right?
And some of the best analysts
out there didn't come up through
what would, someone would coin
the perfect technical
pipeline or whatnot, right?
Because they look at problems differently
and I believe speaks to
both what you had said.
And at this time we'll
open up for questions
from the audience specifically
related to soft skills.
Okay, we're gonna advance.
Well soft skills are a
great asset to be able
to communicate and lead.
Critical thinking skills are also required
to be successful in cybersecurity roles.
What are some of the hard skills
that a cybersecurity
professional needs to pair
with these softer skills?
We had touched on these briefly, right?
I had introduced it previously
when we had just talked
about a critical thinking
there, but really taken it.
And we're focusing specifically on
those hard skills related
to cybersecurity profession
which, well for a level setting, right?
Is very broad.
If they could be SOC related jobs,
they could be pen testing.
It could be on the
compliance in governance side
of things.
Greg, we'll start with you on this one.
- Well, thanks John.
As we take a look at the types of skills
that folks in our sector are looking for.
During my military career, I
was involved in both education
and training.
And we defined education
differently than training.
Training focuses on how
to do certain things
but education focuses
on understanding the why
and being able to integrate
the two is the acne of skill.
And when we are looking
to bring folks on board
into our cybersecurity
organizations, typically
it's very easy to gauge levels
of accomplishment on the how.
The hard skills, the search,
the demonstrated capabilities
that have been illustrated
in their resumes based
upon certifications and accreditations
that the individuals have.
Some organizations including the military
here in the United
States are actually doing
what I called the last Starfighter tests.
Where they're actually doing
hands-on demonstrations
of capabilities.
And I think that's way cool
and we need to keep on doing that.
But on the soft skills, those things
that we're also looking
for, we are looking
for folks who have the
ability to communicate well,
orally, in writing, in email
and be able to give briefings
and be able to articulate themselves well
because that helps build better teams.
So we're looking for skills like that.
We are in fact, looking for folks
who are able integrate themselves
into very inclusive teams,
because if you're going in
like in an incident response
to a cyber event, you're gonna roll in
with a database administrator,
a network administrator,
generally somebody from
the supervisory team
who's gonna choreograph activities.
And you're gonna have other specialists
who come in often as
part of the ad hoc teams.
So we're looking for folks
who can integrate well as part
of teams and generally be
very flexible and adaptive.
So as audience members, if
you're building out your resume
and you're looking to
position yourself well
for a cybersecurity position,
consider putting in examples
of how your education has prepped you
with certain skills and abilities.
How you, even if you're
an individual contributor,
how you've worked as members of teams.
How you've maybe been involved
in software development
or using software.
What kind of coding skills you have?
what kind of languages you speak?
And, Oh, by the way your oral languages
are just as important as
your coding languages.
Because more and more
in a global community
and the internet brings us all together,
having language skills that
go orally, as well as coding.
Boy, you can write your own ticket.
So it's an exciting time.
And I look forward to hearing what Caitlin
has to say on this as well.
- Thanks, Greg.
I'm just, I wanna dovetail right
into Greg's commentary on the flip side
with hiring leaders, looking to again,
how do you do that effectively in terms
of drawing out the candidate
to hear about their,
how do they think?
How do you get to that?
I used to work with Motorola extensively
for many, many, many years.
And one of the things that impressed me
about their hiring process was the fact
that they would bring in professionals
and have them do a case study.
They get 30 minutes to prep
it, write down your notes
and then 30 minutes to
present it to a hiring leader
who kind of listens and walks through it
and it has a dialogue.
And what you see from that is kind of
how did this person
approach problem solving?
And one of the things
that was interesting now
this was particularly an audit
and I'll just speak to that.
But they would take a
financial operational leader
who knew nothing about computers systems
and give them an IT audit case study.
Why did they do that?
Because not that they want
to stress the candidate out,
but they wanted to see
how did the person
approach problem solving
in a context that they
weren't totally comfortable.
So I think the case
study, short case study
can really give you an
opportunity to dialogue
with candidates in a different way.
So I'm just throw that in as an add on
to Greg's extensive answer
there, which is awesome.
- Those are excellent points there.
And I think that when I
hear you both speak here
from both the hiring managers
perspective, as well as,
if you put yourself in the shoes
of the candidate is humility
comes to mind, right?
At the end of the day,
Greg great commentary
on education versus training.
And I think that something
that gets lost out there at times, right?
Because first of all, all professions
we're just, you have to embrace this thing
were lifelong learning is
never gonna go away, right?
And part of that's gonna
happen professionally.
Some of that happens
personally, based on experiences
and whatnot.
But to recognize, we don't
know what we don't know
but at the same time, I
like the recommendation
of the case studies or whatnot
and also involving other
people perhaps in some
of the interview process
or at least to review how
they were previously scripted.
Because some of the, I
think the newer folks
to the industry might have
a different perspective
and kind of help shape
those things to really draw
out the best side of candidates.
We're gonna transition
here, real quick here
and focus here specifically, right?
How a cybersecurity student or a candidate
that's transitioning from another field,
are these soft skills something
that can actually...
Do we really think they're gonna learn
them in a university program?
And I'll preface that by saying that,
every program that I've
either been part of
or evaluated, there's
gotta be a selling point
to that, right?
What's the value there?
And for cybersecurity, the inclination
is it's gonna be
cybersecurity related things.
But as we've talked about this far
all of these soft skills
are largely important
and have we potentially undervalued
the general education
components leading to which.
Caitlin?
- Yeah that's a really, really good point.
I was actually, I went
out and they was looking
at various cybersecurity master's programs
and even undergraduate programs
and see CS in preparation for this.
I was actually pretty surprised
that at top universities
in the master's programs,
there wasn't much outside sort
of the hard skills teaching
and the undergraduate
electives in CS still
aren't necessarily the ones
that are to foster strong
soft skill development.
But, I think well-run
programs should optimally,
if they're going
to create well-rounded
security professionals,
be obviously stressing team projects
where people have to learn
to collaborate, negotiates,
solve problems together
and involve presenting
and writing the kinds
of reports that industry is looking for.
So I can't speak to that
as any expert around
university programs per say
but it seems that those
things can be taught
if the right components are built in.
But adding to that, on the student side
here you are in this amazing setting.
And gosh, I mean, learning
those soft skill components
can be done through joining
student organizations
where you can take a leadership role
or at least volunteer your
time teaching perhaps,
high school students coding
or teaching computer literacy
out in the community.
And so you build empathy
for learning how to work
with non-technical people.
Listening to their problems
and trying to explain technical stuff
in non-technical terms.
There's just a whole
myriad of opportunities.
One of my favorite information
security leaders told me
that she learned soft skills,
conflict resolution, negotiation
and just understanding people
by working as a bartender
throughout college.
So I think there's that huge opportunity
if you take some customer facing roles
and internships to learn
a tremendous amount
about soft skills that will
augment the university program.
- Yeah and I'll pile on there too.
As we take a look at the ISACA survey,
the data shows that 27% of
the hiring officials say
that the recent university
grads are well-prepared
to do everything that's expected during
their position in their tenure.
Nobody expects I think that
when you come right out
of school, you're going to
be ready to hit the ground
to be the master of everything.
You're not gonna be there.
What you have to do is make sure
that you have that well-rounded education.
And it doesn't matter if you're
coming out of high school
or a university program,
you have to be balanced
and we can train you to
do a lot of great skills.
We can also help you be
educated on some other things
that could round you out.
Ultimately though it doesn't
matter if you're coming in
from another career field too
and you're being up-skilled
into the cyber career field,
you need to be balanced
and you should be striving to be somebody
who works not only within
your job description
but being to branch out well
beyond that job description.
And a lot of the things that Caitlin
was saying just resonates extremely well
for me in my professional career.
We're looking for people who can think
and move quickly on their feet
and are adaptable to change.
If there's one thing about the cyber world
is change is inevitable and the job
that you'll have in five
years, you'll be inventing.
It hasn't been invented yet.
- Fantastic points by the both of you.
This is a great transition here.
So we talked about the
flexibility and the grit.
So we're focus here for a few minutes here
on upskilling teams in
elevating your staff, right?
Which seems to be increasing based
on the respondent data here is you
have these trusted, you
know, corporate resources.
You know what they are
but how do you then teach them, right?
Those hard skills is we've
heard from both of you
and I've done it as well
is all those intangibles
that you bring that to the table.
I could teach you to do most things.
Now arguably maybe the glide
slope is a little longer
in some cases, depending on the aspect.
So from your perspectives,
what positions at an enterprise
or a natural transition
into cybersecurity?
Greg?
- Well, I found during
my professional career,
there's several different positions where
I have seen folks successfully transition.
And the organization that I
saw the best transition were
from the Air Force security police people.
The folks that were
manning the flight line
and guarding the airplanes
but when they hit the staff Sergeant level
they came eligible for cross training.
Some of the smartest cyber
pros that I've ever worked
with were former Air Force
security police officers.
I've also had folks who
were in the information
management career field,
administrative staff.
They understood the processes
and the procedures, the
culture, the language
of the business,
but then when we layered
on technical skills,
they made a seamless transition
into the cyber career field.
And I had one lady, she was exceptional.
And when she ultimately
retired, she was one
of the government's most senior
cybersecurity professionals.
And she started out as an
intern clerk, worked her way
up to secretary and then
just exploded up the chain
as she got technical skills
added to the repertoire
she brought to the table.
So as long as you understand
the culture of organizations,
we can teach you the technology.
And we've seen folks from
multiple career fields
make the pivot into cyber
and do so extremely well
and auditors and controllers.
I'm seeing more and more
folks in the auditor
and the accounting fields,
making the pivot as well
because they've spent
so much time analyzing
and doing all of the
business process analysis.
Once we pair them with the
technical skills, look out.
Fantastic. Well we're
running short on time.
So I have one last question here
and I'm gonna leave this...
I'll put this out to you, Caitlin.
How do we expand the net so
we are attracting more diverse candidates?
- Yeah I think there's some
really important pieces there.
First. I think just from the
get-go, being willing to look
at people that fit the need,
what really needs to get done in the job
and where can that person come from?
I mean, beyond, I mean, IT audit,
IT crime justice, military.
I was gonna pile onto
Greg's commentary there.
One of my best people who's moved
into security actually came
from a Navy mission logistics role
and he had brilliant skills to transfer.
But within the organization,
if you think broadly,
there are people that have the
soft skills, the creativity
the analytical skills to
move into cybersecurity
if they're offered the training
and those people could
come from risk management,
they could come from marketing,
they could come from public relations.
The hard parts, the hard side
of marketing is entirely
analytically oriented
and looking for anomalies
and things that stand out
and patterns that should be absorbed
and recognized as well as the writing
and the speaking skills.
But engineering and as I
mentioned, logistics are all places
that people can come from.
But the key thing is to
have a welcoming culture.
I mean, from the start
of outreach to candidates
and especially if you're
trying to recruit them
into security from other areas and working
with diverse populations as well,
that are underrepresented in security,
the process from the first outreach
through the recruiting,
interviewing, onboarding
to the day-to-day work, the culture
of the team has to be
welcoming and accepting.
And I just can't stress that enough.
But I think also a couple
of things is you've got to
get the better job description so
that you don't discourage
people from applying.
You have to have hiring managers
who are thinking more broadly.
So I think those would be some
of the points I would put in there.
- Thank you very much, Caitlin.
So as we wrap up here.
key takeaways from the presentation.
These are, nothing here is hard and fast.
I think I'm hoping that
this panel discussion
was thought provoking
and really meet hiring managers
and candidates alike or
prospective candidates, right?
Because you know people continue to move
within the industry.
The catalog, what it is you're asking for
and what it is that you
bring to a particular job
or what you might need there.
Surely expanded criteria
is been a common theme.
We've looked at looking at non-cyber staff
that already understand
a corporate culture
which just there's a lot of value there.
Something we didn't get a chance
to touch on here, training programs.
ISACA offers a wide range
of opportunities from new entry points up
to your mid level and
executive level folks.
With that, I will open it up to
for more questions for our panelists.