- Hi everyone.
This is the session,
"We're All in this Together."
It's a session about
"Technology Abuse and Design."
My name is Erica Olsen.
I am the Director of
the Safety Net Project
at the National Network
to End Domestic Violence.
And I'll be moderating this panel.
Before we start I'm gonna
turn it over to our panelists
so they can each introduce themselves.
- Hi everyone. My name
is Jennifer Landhuis.
I'm the Director of SPARC which is the
Stalking Prevention Awareness
and Resource Center.
We are a project of Aequitas.
And we provide training
and technical assistance
all over of the U.S. on
the issue of stalking.
Hi, my name is Natalie Dolci.
I'm a Senior Violence Prevention
and Response Specialist
at the University of
Washington Safe Campus
and a Co-Founder
of the Technology-Enabled
Coercive Control Working Group
in Seattle.
- Hi everybody, I'm Tom Ristenpart.
I'm a Associate Professor at Cornell Tech
and Cornell University
in Computer Science.
And I co-lead our research lab
on understanding technology abuse
and intimate partner violence,
as well as help run our
Clinic to End Tech Abuse
which does direct survivor
support on technology issues.
- Great, thank you all so much.
And thank you for being here.
I'm really excited to have
this discussion today.
So for those of you joining us
this session will provide an overview
of technology abuse and the importance
of trauma-informed technology
design for survivors
to increase safety and privacy.
This will be a discussion
between advocates,
technologists, and
clinic service providers.
For those who are not as
familiar with anti-abuse work,
I just want to take a
quick moment and provide
some context and definitions
for words that we'll be using.
We may use the terms
"victim" and "survivor"
interchangeably throughout this talk.
This session is focusing on victims
of intimate partner abuse
which includes much more
than physical violence.
Intimate partner abuse
includes a number of behaviors
that are perpetrated by someone
to maintain power and
control over another person.
Abuse may consist of financial, emotional,
sexual or physical abuse.
And it can be a pattern
of stalking and harassment
of coercive control and what
we'll be focusing on today,
technology, technological abuse.
On average, more than one in three women,
and one in four men in the US
will experience rape, physical violence,
and/or stalking by an intimate partner.
Professionals who work with survivors
are usually called Advocates
or Victim Service Providers.
And you'll hear those
terms frequently as well.
During the session,
we will discuss best
practices for incorporating
survivor-centered approaches
to technological design,
anti-abuse testing and
related policy development.
So with that is our intro,
so everyone has a basic understanding
of what we're talking about today.
We'll move into defining these
issues a little bit more.
I'll dive in by providing a
brief overview of tech abuse,
some examples of what this looks like,
and the importance of security
for survivors of abuse.
Now, as technology has become
woven into our daily lives
it has also become a common tactic
within intimate partner abuse.
Stalking, sexual violence,
and online harassment.
Abusers misuse technology in order
to commit and cover up
those behaviors and crimes.
We see technology misused and used
to monitor, track,
surveil, harass, threaten,
and isolate survivors.
We also see it misused
to impersonate survivors
and damage a reputations,
often impacting their employment
and their relationships.
As technology evolves,
we see the tactics of a misuse evolve too.
An example of this is somebody accessing
IoT home devices remotely to
control thermostats and lights
to purposely impact the victim's bills,
using technology as a tactic
to further financial abuse.
On top of this,
the vast amount of data
that is available about all of us online,
it can continually compromises
survivors' privacy.
For victims of abuse,
their privacy is closely
linked to their safety.
It is critical for technologists
and security professionals
to understand how
technologies can facilitate
stalking, abuse, coercive
control, harassment, and violence
both online and offline.
Current anti-abuse strategies
don't always fully account
for the dynamics of intimate partner abuse
and the serious impact that tech abuse
can have on survivors.
Strategies need to include
robust, survivor-centric,
and trauma-informed approaches
to technology design
and relevant policy development.
So with that, I'm gonna
turn it over to Jen
to talk a little bit
about stalking and tech
as a tool for spying and monitoring.
- Thanks Erica.
So we kind of see survivors
present in two different ways
when it comes to tech abuse.
We have, on one hand
we've got the survivors
whose partner might be misusing
a legitimate technology.
So one that wasn't designed to surveil
or monitor somebody else,
but being manipulated to do so.
So for example, things like Find My iPhone
or some other types of location apps.
So what we know is like
many aspects of technology
they're often designed
in a way that assumes
that people who share an account together
or share a home together
are safe with each other.
And so one of the aspects that
we have to be thinking about
is for those that want to try
to opt out of that technology.
So say for instance,
we have a victim whose partner
might be monitoring them
through something like Find my iPhone.
To turn that technology off,
they might not even know how to do so.
They might not have permissions to do so.
And if they do so,
it would be obvious to the other person.
So that might increase the likelihood
that harm or danger could
happen to them as well.
So you have those examples of
those who are being monitored
through a legitimate technology
and then that's just being misused
by the stalker or the offender.
And then you have the other category
where people are being
monitored or surveilled
through technology that's designed
for those particular purposes.
So what we sometimes see
is things like stalkerware.
So for instance, we just
got a call last week
from somebody who had
left an abusive partner,
had gone to stay with a family member.
And the call came into an advocacy center
saying that they were certain
that there were some kind of way
that the offender was
"hacking into their phone."
That's the language
that we hear oftentimes
from victims and survivors.
And in this case, the victim
would show up certain places
and the offender would show up there
often enough that it wasn't a coincidence.
And the victim also
believed that this offender
was reading the text messages
that she was sending back
and forth to her family.
So she had reached out
to an advocacy agency
at first for help.
And what we have to understand
is there's not a ton of
training and education
for folks who might be going on
and advocating on behalf of survivors.
And so you might have
individuals who aren't equipped
to be able to deal with
these types of issues.
Then she was referred to
a law enforcement agency
who told her essentially
if she didn't want to report a crime
which she would, did not,
basically there was nothing
they could do for her.
So then her next strategy
was to try to reach out
to the phone company to say,
"I believe that somebody is
monitoring and surveilling me."
She wasn't the account holder.
So there was no way for her
to change anything with the phone.
And frankly, she faced disbelief
by the phone company who said,
"There's no way this
kind of stuff can happen.
Are you sure it's not just
a coincidence?" et cetera.
So we see survivors kind of fall
into two different categories.
Those that are being monitored
through legitimate use apps
and then those who are being monitored
through apps that are designed with,
you know, not quite as
legitimate purposes.
And then what we often see happen
is regardless of what the technology is
that survivors are facing roadblocks
in trying to access help.
They're facing roadblocks in privacy.
They're facing roadblocks in people
who are responding to them,
so the criminal justice
system or advocacy agencies.
And then roadblocks with
the tech companies on not,
you know, if they try to access help
or call somebody for help
rarely are they met with
a voice at the other end.
And so there's lots of different aspects.
Not that we'll get to all of these
but at least give you an idea
of what we see happening in real time.
- Thank you, Jen.
I love the clear examples
and I think that's so helpful
for people to wrap their
head around this issue.
Natalie, could you talk a
little bit about your work
and the campus intersection
and prevention?
- Sure.
Our office supports students, faculty,
and staff at the University of Washington
who are experiencing a
variety of safety concerns.
When we're working on tech abuse
we see a couple of
different threat models.
We see the threat model
of folks who are targeted
because they're an intimate
partner violence situation,
a stalking situation, sexual harassment.
We also see the threat
model of researchers
who are targeted for ideological reason.
Perhaps they study racial justice,
climate justice,
gender justice issues
and are experiencing harassment and doxing
as a result of that.
There's a couple of things
I'd like to uplift in
this discussion today
which is that it's really paramount
that we start to integrate
the threat model of
intimate partner violence
and to the design processes of technology.
We need to consider coercive
control and potential abuse
in product development.
But also we need to
consider a response plan.
I think particularly what
Jennifer was just talking about
really highlights that when
people are trying to seek relief
it seems that there hasn't
been much effort spent
on what that response process looks like
or the user experience for
those who've encountered harm.
I think an example would
be a case study where
a PhD student had an ex who
was sending intimate images
to her department and her doctoral advisor
using a spoofed email.
He was obviously embarrassed
in front of the doctoral advisor
but also found other
professional consequences
such as conferences she had signed up for
were also targeted by this stalker
and were asking her to
no longer participate.
The far too common response path
is that she is increasingly isolated.
The email platform does
nothing to assist her
and the perpetuation of
this crime that's occurring
and that her doctoral
advisor felt alienated
and no longer wanted
to meet with her alone
feeling just nervous
about the whole situation.
And I'd invite the audience to consider
an alternative path where instead
that same survivor was put in touch
with specialized victim advocacy services
that cooperated with the
university's CISO Office.
Considering the opportunity
for an email platform
that had a specially trained response team
that could work with people
who were experienced in
the unlawful distribution
of their intimate images
and prying for that behavior quickly
and considering a conference
that had protocols in place
to protect speakers and privacy
rather than participating in
attrition or a brain drain.
And I think that when we fail to consider
appropriate prevention and response,
we actually allow our
platforms and our workplaces
to be weaponized by the abuser
rather than supporting the survivor.
And that there is a real
opportunity to flip the script
and make those needed changes.
- Thank you so much for all of that.
And Tom, Leslie, would
you dive in and say,
what does this mean for
designing threat models?
- Yeah, yeah.
It's a great question.
It's a really hard one.
So we've been doing research in this space
for like maybe five or six years
and definitely just want to echo
some of the things that Jen
and Natalie were both saying,
which then when we started talking
to IPV support professionals,
this issue of technology abuse came up
over and over again.
But at the same time,
there were not a lot of technologists
out there who could help and
assist with these issues.
And certainly there was
a lot of frustration,
palpable frustration with
how the tech industry,
you know, tech companies specifically,
we're not necessarily dealing well
with the type of threat models
that victim/survivors
are facing every day.
And so when I think about this,
I think there's a really
big landscape of things
that we need to make progress on, right?
One is how do we and
perhaps most urgently,
how do we help survivors
in the short term, right?
Dealing with the existing
technology landscape that we have.
And for this,
we need those type of tailored responses
that Natalie was mentioning, right?
I think having people have
very difficult situations.
There is not a one-size-fits-all solution
in terms of helping
out any, all survivors.
And so we've been working a lot
on this type of tailored
advocacy kind of model
where you kind of understand
the situation of the client,
just as a concrete example of the issues
that Jen was mentioning,
vis-a-vis like spyware, stalkerware
being installed on devices, right?
Sometimes it's just not a good idea
to remove those apps, right?
because that might trigger
the abuser to physically,
to escalate to physical violence
in these kinds of things.
So that's like one
really, really important
set of work that we need to do.
Another is how do we help
companies basically do better
on these dual use or misuse issues.
And I think for that designing
against these threat models,
is really important.
Which tangibly for companies means,
"Hey can we actually do design reviews?"
Where you're saying,
"Hey, how is this interface gonna play out
in a domestic violence situation?"
Right? Like when you have
a bad actor in the home
who knows the passwords
of the of the victim
who can get into their
accounts, et cetera.
Then there's holding these kind
of worst bad actors accountable.
People who are making spyware
and advertising for abuse
cases is a big problem.
And then finally, I just want to mention,
I think a really understudied area
that is understanding
how to do prevention,
how do we kind of intervene
with potential abusers
and kind of steer them
towards healthier paths
on the technology use in relationships?
- Thank you all so much.
There's so much to discuss about this.
I'm pretty sure this
could be an all-day event
but I'd like to walk through
a couple of the questions
that we've talked about.
And, and we know that we,
that all of us frequently
get from working with people.
First, I wanted to go
back to you, Natalie.
Could you talk a little
bit about stalkerware?
We've already mentioned
it a couple of times
and I know it's something
that we get asked
about all the time.
And it's also a technology that's secured,
several security companies
have documented significant increases
throughout the pandemic.
So I'd love for the audience
to hear a little bit more
about what stalkerware is
and how we're seeing it misused
and why it's such an invasive
type of misuse for survivors.
- Sure.
I think, I really agree with
everything Jennifer said
as far as you know,
when we think about technology
abuse is sort of a pyramid.
I think that broadest band
at the bottom of the pyramid
is lower tech forms of abuse.
Where perhaps the abuser
knows the survivor's password,
perhaps the abuser, you know,
they were logged in on the
same computer at some point,
they guessed their security questions.
So it's typically not the
most high tech forms of abuse
but sometimes they evolve
or there are some more expert abusers
who use more sophisticated things
such as stalkerware
which is really designed
to surveil someone's device remotely.
And that's something that can
be downloaded onto the device
and not even have an
app necessarily appear
on the home screen.
And it doesn't necessarily
provide a persistent notification
to the individual whose device it is.
So this can obviously create a feeling
of 24-hour persistent uncertainty
when it seems all your
communications are being monitored.
So, though our research indicated
that the majority of the time
it is sort of those dual use apps
or a lack of robust password management
that is leading to
these security breaches,
since the pandemic,
there have been some disturbing reports
that have come out such
as from Malwarebytes,
that found that they
detected a 1000% increase
in the stalkerware with their scanning.
And that's obviously, you know,
people who are using that service.
But I think that it's a higher
risk time for stalkerware
to be on your device because before,
if you were in a domestic
violence situation
you would be meeting face to
face with your DV advocate.
You wouldn't need to
meet with them by Zoom
or have all of your communications
going across a device.
You might have an in-person
meeting with an attorney
about your divorce plan,
or you know, custody issues.
But if it's all happening via Zoom
and it's all being monitored,
then you can really see how the abuser
is surveilling every aspect
of their communication.
So I think what we've learned
is that this is an area
that absolutely demands more study,
and there is a Coalition
Against Stalkerware
that is looking at some recommendations.
And I know some folks on the
panel are involved with that.
So I'd invite them to jump in.
But I think that
multi-disciplinary partnership
of the coalition is a
really inspiring model
for efforts in this stage going forward.
- Yeah, I absolutely agree.
Thank you for that.
Jen, could you talk a
little bit about another
common question that we always get
is about the laws?
Tell us a little bit about what tech,
how technology abuse
is addressed by US laws
and what gaps may exist.
- You know, I think when we look at laws
trying to address technology,
it's like we're always playing catch up.
We're always behind the
eight ball a little bit
because we have some
really antiquated laws
that we're using to try to address
some really up-to-date technologies.
And then the strategy in lots of states
is to try to pass new laws
that by the time they get passed
are now out of date as well.
So there's always that difficulty.
And I think the other
difficulty we have is really
just kind of demystifying
the use of technology.
I think one of the things that we hear
from survivors all the time
is if there's in-person things happening
or very real threats made by somebody,
you know, as they're
across the room from them,
that's one thing.
But if it happens just
through the technology
or via social media,
then it's not taken as seriously.
And so I think one of the strategies
that we really have to focus on
is understanding the harm that can happen
from use of secure technologies.
And even if there is an in-person contact,
it's still as life-changing,
it's still as scary,
it's still as threatening to those people
who are experiencing it.
So I think some of our strategies
have to be kind of two-fold.
Number one, demystifying the
technology, first of all.
We also see that in response systems,
people who are less likely to
go forward with the tech case
because it seems so
hard to get the evidence
or more difficult
and not knowing who to
reach out to for help.
And then we have the strategy of,
"Okay so if we have the information,
what kind of laws do we
have at our disposal?"
And then of course,
jump into, if you have a company
that's not inside the US,
do they have to obey court
orders and subpoenas, et cetera
that are US-based?
No, they don't.
So that can be difficult as well.
So all those different
strategies can play into it
but I think definitely,
always feeling like we're playing catch up
in that particular response.
- Absolutely.
So Tom, digging more into
the various threat models
and the gaps that exist,
can you talk a little bit more about how
intimate partner abuse
that the threat models
for intimate partner abuse
differ from the from the ones that focus
on state surveillance or
broader privacy issues?
- Yeah, for sure.
And I think this is a
really important point,
particularly at RSA,
which is a conference that's built around
the computer security industry.
I think we can, everyone,
I'll come to some other examples
but the stalkerware, spyware example
is an easy one to highlight
this difference, right?
You know, up until a
couple of, few years ago
most of these spyware, stalkerware apps
were not flagged by
antivirus tools, right?
And we've seen a nice shift in that,
over the last couple of years
as companies have started flagging that.
And I think that really
emanates out of the mindset
of like, "Oh, what is antivirus
supposed to be preventing?"
Right? Anti-virus is
supposed to prevent malware
that's you know, worms or ransomware,
or kind of this other
commercially motivated
criminal enterprises
that is profit-motivated.
And this issue of like
intimate partner abuse
or actually other forms of
kind of interpersonal attacks
were pretty much off the radar.
And so I think that it's something
we need to shift a
little bit thinking like,
"Hey, there's a lot of other interesting
threat models out here
that are really directly
affecting people's wellbeing
and IPV is a significant one."
Similarly, I think you can look at,
other things like on social media
and misinformation and
abuse and harassment online.
It's really hard to catch that type of,
catch the type of issues
that are facing survivors
because it's such an
intimate context, right?
Like we hear from survivors about like,
"Hey, you know, I reported.
My abuser sent me a picture of a gun,
which I know in this context
means he's threatening me.
Right? And I report it
to Facebook or whomever."
And you know, they're like,
"Well, it's just the gun."
Like, you know, the
context is missing, right?
Such a really challenging issue
to deal with the very nuanced
context-specific issues
in intimate partner violence.
So I think in general
there's a big gap here
between abuse threat models
and regular computer security models,
which is actually one of the reasons
I was so fascinated by this area.
I mean, I think it's really interesting
but we need a lot more focus and attention
thinking cleverly about how we can build
into our design processes
like reviews for abuse,
or like as I mentioned before
for abuse of user interfaces
and these types of things and just think
more thoughtfully about this.
- Thank you.
Now Jen and Natalie,
coming back to you both,
how have you both seen these
issues with threat models
play out for survivors
who are being abused
and are trying to address
that by regaining control
over their devices,
seeking legal resources,
or just maintaining their
privacy in order to feel safe?
- Yeah, I think,
when a person enters looking the process,
looking for accountability
through the criminal legal system,
there are sort of barriers at every turn
when tech abuse is the primary concern.
Speaking of the criminal
path locally where I am,
the majority of these
crimes are misdemeanors
which means they typically
do not get assigned
to a detective and there is
not investigative support.
So to unmask a perpetrator in these cases
often requires multiple warrants
which is not ever going to
happen at the patrol level.
So survivors might find
that their electronic
protection order violations,
meaning if they have a protection order
and a person is sending, you know,
encrypted messages or you know,
creating new accounts,
if there's no investigation into that
then there is not going
to be any accountability
for that perpetrator.
So that's the criminal piece.
Looking at the civil path
if someone's pursuing a
Civil Protection Order
we see that the courts have
not caught up whatsoever.
We see survivors putting a lot of labor
and making digital evidence analog.
There may not be any way to
upload video or audio files
to the court records,
so they're transcribing it.
They're trying to get
photo stills of videos.
They're trying to educate the judge
about social media platforms
that the judge or commissioner
may not be familiar with.
So you can see some real
equity issues happening here
where the survivors were in
a position to project manage
their own case might be more successful
in getting a Protection Order
than a survivor who's not.
And unfortunately,
we also see abusers manipulate the courts
to their own advantage.
I've seen multiple cases
where the abuser will file
intimate images into the court record
and they are not filed under a seal.
So now we have used the
court to perpetuate the harm
of the distribution of intimate images.
So there is the need to improve capacity
of cross-systems in terms of understanding
how to investigate these types of harm.
But there's also the need to have
considered processes that can allow
for as much privacy as possible.
- If I can only add to
what Natalie has said,
in the long and short of it
it is expensive and it's time-consuming
and it's not always accessible to folks.
And if you think about it,
it's one of those times
where we essentially rely
on victims to project manage
or build their own cases.
And what the solution people
often recommend to survivors
is to just stop using the technology
which isn't obviously victim-centered.
It's not a possibility
and it's not something that
survivors are gonna do.
And so thinking about that as you know
the tongue-in-cheek people thing,
people say to victims all the time
is, "Well, just stop
using the technology."
It's not realistic and it's not fair.
And so how do we help
survivors have that right
to continue to access that
technology but in a safer way?
- Yeah, thank you both.
And that is such a great point
that you ended on there too.
We are big advocates
of empowering survivors
to take control of their technology
and to know how to increase their privacy
and safety on their
devices and their accounts
`coz taking away their
technology does nothing
to hold a perpetrator accountable.
It does nothing to even increase safety.
Abusers don't go away that easily.
And we know that.
So thank you for that.
So do any of you have some examples
of best practices that you would encourage
for broad industry adoption
and any thoughts about the challenges
that the industry faces
and really addressing this better?
- I guess I could just start.
I mean, I think one,
this has to get on the
radar at companies, right?
I mean, most companies hire security teams
and they have people
dedicated to computer security
and you need to invest also in anti-abuse
in Trust and Safety, right?
I think that's something
that across the board
companies are becoming more recognizing of
but this isn't just Trust and Safety
for your average user, right?
This is Trust and Safety
for particular targeted people
which based on the statistics
that you were giving earlier,
that's a large fraction
of your users, right?
One out of four women and one out of
or one out of three women
and one out of four men.
So, you know, hiring people
to actually think about these problems,
review your designs,
understand that every
time you open up interface
that's used to communicate
between two of your users
that will be abused.
And so you need to think about
how it's gonna be abused,
what, you know, how to try to add friction
to those abuse use cases
and how to add the recovery mechanisms
for what happens when abuse occurs
and what recourse our users can have.
There's a lot of challenges here
and you need to invest in it.
- Yeah. I think there's a real opportunity
to move from compliance to culture change.
I think it's not sufficient
to have a legal department
that will at some point
respond to a subpoena,
but instead if you have people
who have given you their data,
who are your customers
who are consistently having
these issues on your platform,
there needs to be some kind of
way to provide that feedback.
And I think having
gender-based violence experts
in a design process as
like an advisory council
would be a really great idea
because these are gonna be the people,
whether they're survivors
or they're advocates
who are really going to
be able to flag like,
"Hey, that's a concern."
You know, I think a recent
example and you know
this is a platform I
love and I use, you know,
I use Signal but I've known some advocates
who have thought about
maybe starting to use that
with clients but then they were concerned
because then your contact
section gets a ping
if you've joined Signal.
So then they were worried,
"Okay, well then their abuser might know
that they're using this other
separate private encrypted platform
to speak with someone on."
I think if we had ways to communicate that
"Hey, this actually can
disrupt the kind of privacy
we're seeking,"
I think those would be really
productive relationship.
- Thank you so much.
And this speaks to, this
goes back to something
you had mentioned earlier
to know about the importance
of people within the industry
and all outside of the industry
to really work together
and the importance of
those collaborations.
We're a founding member
of the Coalition Against
Stalkerware you mentioned.
And I know all of us on the
panel here have worked closely
with a number of tech
companies over the years
and continue to,
and being part of those conversations
about both the design of the platforms,
the reporting flows,
all of that,
and the options for survivors,
the notifications,
how sensitive, how informative they are,
all of that is incredibly important.
And I think it's a big part of our work
that we've really enjoyed
and have learned a lot about.
And we definitely need
to see more and more
of those kinds of collaborations.
Before we turn to the live Q and A,
I think it's always important
to just take a quick moment
to talk about a few
things that you can do.
If anyone who's listening to this session,
if you know somebody who
could be experiencing abuse
or someone discloses abuse to you,
what would you do in those situations?
`Coz it can be very hard
to know exactly what to say
or where to point somebody.
But considering the statistics on abuse,
as we've mentioned,
we should all be prepared
for this conversation.
It could be someone in your family,
a colleague or a customer who is concerned
about your products and their
privacy because of abuse.
So I always tell people
that one of the most
important things you can do
is to not judge the
person or the situation,
and to trust the person's instincts.
They know that person and
know the situation better
than you ever will,
better than any of us ever will.
So if they believe that
it is unsafe for them,
then it probably is.
If they believe that they're
being monitored by someone
it's definitely possible that they are.
Even if it seems
unbelievable to us, you know?
I often hear people say like,
"Oh, I don't think that
person was that techie."
And unfortunately,
we know you don't have to be that techie
to misuse and take advantage
of many of the technologies
that are out there that
abusers are frequently using
as a tactic of abuse.
It's always helpful to point people
to the National Domestic Violence Hotline
so they can talk to an advocate
and find programs that are local to them.
So, any other words of
advice from the panelists
that you might have for the audience?
- I think the only ones
I would add to that
is to echo the, you know,
validate and believe
what people have to say
as well as make sure you're
respecting the victim's privacy.
Don't go advocating on their behalf
without their permission
is really important.
And obviously, as I mentioned earlier
don't tell them to just stop
using the tech. (laughs)
Not a good strategy. (laughs)
- Yes! Very important.
Anything else?
- Yeah. Just a caution against
being too prescriptive.
What might increase
one's survivor's safety
would put another survivor in more danger.
For example, suggesting that
they just block that person.
They may want the information
if that individual
is escalating or threatening to come over
and that may not be what's safe for them.
So just discuss options,
but be a little wary of advice.
- Yeah. You took the words
right out of my mouth.
I was gonna say be careful
about taking actions,
particularly if you're a
computer IT person you're like,
"Oh, I can fix that for you
`coz I know how to do that."
Without proper safety planning
that could be really dangerous for people.
So, getting them in touch
with support services
and then also providing information
about how they can empower themselves
vis-a-vis their technology.
Super important.
- Thank you.
All those are all incredibly
important points to end on.
So I really appreciate it.
I wanna take a moment
just to say thank you
to all of our panelists for
such a great conversation.
And please can you get
the audience members
can ask them questions in the chat,
and we'd be happy to answer
anything individually
through this and then after this
we all have our contact information
available on the website
and we hope to hear from you
if you have any other questions.