- Welcome, and thank you
so much for joining me
as I walk through this case study
on information security dashboards.
Now I understand there have been hundreds
or more presentations at RSA
and other conferences
on security dashboards,
and I wanna be upfront and let you know
that this is not a metric session.
This is a real life example
of how I built a dashboard
and then it failed and how I recovered.
And to tell the story, I
turned to one of the most
recognized slogans in advertising.
When you care enough
to send the very best,
this was born on a three
by five inch note card
in 1944 by Ed Goodman.
I mean, Ed was a Sales
and Marketing Executive
at the Hallmark company and he
just jotted down his thoughts
on what Hallmark stood for,
caring, quality and the best.
And now it's number 15 on the
top 50 slogans of all time.
And it's my standard disclaimer
that this information
does not necessarily reflect
current or past employers.
And lastly, I hope that you will learn
that they didn't tell
me at least in college
that storytelling would be so important
as a security leader.
And so hopefully that's something
you learn out of this as well.
I'll also encourage you
to type your questions
into the chat window at any time,
and I'll be happy to answer those.
So when I started at this company,
they had a good security
foundation all ready in place.
I was actually hired to re-imagine
the program and mature it.
The company had just made a
change to a pure SAS model.
And so that certainly
impacted some of our policies
and procedures and controls.
So when I stepped in, I performed
a NIST CSF self-assessment
which highlighted the areas
of highest risk and from this,
I was able to create
that multi-year roadmap.
So similar to Hallmark,
how do you build your security
brand at your company?
I mean, building a roadmap
with clear measurements
from the self-assessment, that
was pretty straightforward.
However, how do we
ensure the prioritization
of the items in the
roadmap that that's align
with the goals of the leadership team?
So this is how I approach this.
First, I took an
inventory of the policies,
procedures and tools that
were all ready in place.
I mean, many of the
tools, they were turned on
and had one or two features running,
but they needed a major health check.
The SIEM had to be totally rebuilt.
The outsource SOC was not
being held accountable.
The EDR tool was over
seven versions behind,
the vulnerability scanner was there
just to check the PCI box
and it wasn't performing
authenticated scans.
So it had many false
positives and this caused
the infrastructure team
to not trust the tool
and thus not patch critical
items such as Microsoft Office.
And remember, these are all
behind the scenes activities
to build your brand and
the maturity of the program
without any additional funding.
If you come to your
first board presentation
or major leadership presentation,
and you can show what
you've all ready done
without their knowledge
or permission to improve
the security of the enterprise
and without additional funding,
they're gonna be much more apt to trust
and to listen to you.
So my next question is
how do I show the value
that the executives really
care about regardless
of how relevant I think
it may or may not be
to actual cybersecurity?
So for me, when I look at this,
I tend to offer personalized
security awareness training
for different teams based on the risks
such as your HRS team.
Maybe if they've made
direct deposit changes
for the bad guys, you can
target training to them,
or the finance team after they've paid out
a business email compromise,
and didn't realize it.
Again, this helps you gain
that additional trust.
Then, taking the always
fun cyber insurance calls
with many underwriters
and using your dark web
monitoring company to search
for personal information
on each of the executives
on their families.
Again, you are building trust
that money just can't buy
and you're not costing the
business any additional funds.
And how many of you are involved
with your industry ISACs
I mean, these are invaluable
if you are actively involved
and actively sharing information.
And I don't just mean
sharing hashes from attacks,
but information specific to
tools that you are using,
how they may or may not
be working web attacks
that you're fighting.
I mean, when I think of threat intel
I think of yet other feed into the SIEM,
which may or may not provide
value to our organization.
But for me, the real value of the ISAC
is the sharing of specific
tools and third parties
and their vulnerability.
So now that we have built the brand,
how do we create this dashboard?
I think the easiest way
to build a dashboard
is directly from your
audits and framework.
I mean, why reinvent the wheel?
So for us again, and many of you,
if you and your teams and your enterprises
are aligned with the NIST
cybersecurity framework,
you can look at each of those five pillars
when you're building your dashboard.
I mean, think about the identified pillar.
Certainly you have some sort
of change management meetings
and you're tracking metrics
from your change management meetings,
with the approved and
unapproved, and emergency changes
or your vulnerability
management program, right?
Where you can show the
number of unpatched machines
or non-standard configurations.
Moving on to the protect pillar
when you have your
security awareness program,
or your patching program,
you can show metrics
from the success of each
security awareness campaign
that you're launching and
track that on your dashboard,
your patching metrics.
And if you're doing full
disk encryption across
the enterprise, those metrics
Moving on to the detect pillar,
certainly you have an employee
detection and response tool
a SIEM you should be producing
some sort of metrics from those.
Again, only measure what is
valuable to you and the team.
There's many things that
reports those tools have,
they're not valuable that
are more on the techie side.
We're looking for more
measurable, valuable metrics.
If you have a SOC whether
it's insourced or outsourced
certainly they're providing you
some sort of monthly reports
on your number of cases, the
criticality of the cases,
time to resolve.
And so you can track those as well.
And lastly, the recover pillar,
your quarterly, your
annual disaster recovery
and business continuity testing
to show the value of that
maybe your tabletop drills
that you're doing all monitoring that,
and putting those numbers
onto your dashboard.
So now you're ready for your
first board presentation
at the new company.
Now this is no matter
what meeting you're in,
but especially in a board
meeting, they're very bright,
very smart, very busy individuals.
And like anything else
after three to five minutes
if you haven't captured their attention,
they're gonna revert to their phones.
So what we need to do is, when we come in,
we need to ask for their help
because as you and I all
know, technology alone
cannot and will not
protect us from everything.
So how do we keep it
relevant and captivating?
We need to ask them how
they've been personally
impacted by cyber security,
with identity theft,
and email scams and
phishing and their kids.
But remember also, our board
members really are smart,
but they probably don't
understand our jargon.
So again, making it personal is key.
And one of the ways we can do that,
is by building common ground.
This is something that I've used
in many of my work presentations
and it really seems
to get very positive feedback.
And that is comparing cyber
health to human health.
I mean, they really are similar.
Think about why do
computer systems get sick?
We observed some of the same
causes and stages of disease
as we do in the human body.
And attackers do go where
security is the weakest.
So if you think about bad
genes that folks have,
well in the cyber world, we
have software or configurations
that could be, you know have unreliable
or obsolete components.
And these are some technical
security vulnerabilities
that internal flaw that
these software programs have.
Or failure to practice basic hygiene.
We talk about washing our hands
and how that can help prevent infection.
Similarly, we allow our team members
to go to unreliable or risky websites
or use unapproved software
products or components.
Then this can lead to infection
or create a security hole.
Think about unbalanced, nutrition,
I mean the diet of our organization
and its business processes.
Think if you have disorder
in your documentation,
or you don't have a clear
responsibility matrix.
Maybe you don't have an
inventory asset tracking system
or you don't really do change management.
These leads to all sorts of
losses and security incidents.
But on the other hand,
you can have excessive red tape, right?
And bureaucracies and authorization levels
that will inhibit the business.
And so you have to have balance
there just like nutrition.
Lastly, stress.
I mean our bodies certainly we can do
to stressful conditions.
And if your staff are always overworked
or overburdened with red tape,
they're probably gonna neglect
your security procedures.
And just like with a healthy lifestyle,
the effects of these precautions
that sometimes they can't
be seen immediately.
And therefore they often
really go underestimated.
The next question that I get
very common, very frequent
is what's the magic number of slides
you put in your board presentations?
And I hope you know, there
really truly is no right or wrong
number of slides.
You just need to use the
least amount of slides
that can convey the message accurately
in a way that everyone in
the room can understand.
To do this, you really need to present
to your CIO and CFO first.
And this is regardless
of reporting structures.
It doesn't matter who you report to,
you should, in my experience,
and my recommendation
is always to present to
the CIO and the CFO first
for their feedback.
They are usually very, very
valuable with their feedback.
They've been in these
presentations before,
and they can give you
some really great
information and pointers.
You need to keep your
report in your dashboard
simple and free from acronyms.
Many of the board members,
they understand accounting frameworks,
even if they're not an accountant,
board members tend to really
understand the numbers
and because they've come
from other industries
where they use that same
accounting framework.
And so we need explain the what
and why behind our framework
and compared to other
frameworks, just like accounting,
and tell them why it's important
that we're following this framework.
Lastly, our board members they
love having benchmark data
and asking the question,
"Why would we be doing something
if our competitors aren't?"
And so again, this is where
you can really heavily rely
on your ISACs in trying to
get that de-identified data
of how many of our peer organizations
are also using the NIST
cybersecurity framework.
It's probably pretty high.
And again, that's gonna
help you build that trust.
You didn't go out and
invent this framework,
it's something that can come
in and be independently audited
and that really will
help you gain that trust.
So when I presented first to our CFO,
he told me, in line of the
NIST cybersecurity framework
after I explained what that was,
and gave the background of the industry,
he told me he really wanted us to focus
on the protect aspect of the framework.
And that was the exact
feedback that I needed.
He said, "let's assume the bad
guys are all ready inside."
And so with those clear
set of instructions
that it helped me group our
initiatives in the buckets
with dollar amounts to show
the true cost of our program
and the cost over the next few years
as we mature the program.
Going from maybe a one to a three or four
on the NIST maturity scale.
And since phishing was the number one
and continues to be the number one way
that ransomware is deployed,
we had our marching orders.
We said, let's go phish.
But, before we can go phishing,
we need to focus on another P word.
I mean, you can't go to
a security presentation
in the last 20 or 30 years
without talking about patching.
And typically patching is handled
by the infrastructure team
but reported on by the security team.
I mean, this is like
the perfect tattletale situation, right?
And as a result, most security
and infrastructure teams
just don't get along.
I mean, just think about
your brothers and sisters,
or even your kids.
So here was the backstory.
And when I came in, again,
a patching tools in place
and vulnerability scans were
run but they were inaccurate
because they were running
without authentication.
And the real focus of
those scans had always been
to only scan and patch PCI assets
that fall into the PCI scope.
So I had to take a step back
and how do I approach this delicately?
I mean, the bad guys don't
care if it's a PCI asset
or not it's all on the network,
it's all network-connected.
How can I approach this
so that the infrastructure
and the security team actually
get along and collaborate?
And let me tell you, I didn't
do it right the first time.
So the way I like to solve
these type of challenges
is just like performing
a root cause analysis
when you have an incident,
when you have an outage.
And this is really how I
try to attack these issues,
let's get in a room, let's
take out the emotions
and the finger-pointing and
just write down the facts.
And so here's the facts to our situation.
Too much effort was being
placed on testing the patches.
I don't know if you've experienced this.
Some companies have an entire
team that that's all they do.
Five days a week is test the patches
of all their different systems ongoing.
And as soon as they stopped,
it starts over for the next month.
Is that really a good use of your team?
The next fact was, well
things have changed
since I came into the
company, we have no customer
on-prem applications, we
are fully cloud-based.
So what are you testing?
What is there really to test?
What are you testing with
the patches each month?
So we decided that we are
going to patch everything now
every month, but roll it out in groups.
And maybe some of you
are all ready doing this,
again, it's not rocket science,
it was a real light bulb moment for us.
We're gonna roll it out to a group of 10,
and wait a few days, not
a week, but a few days,
roll it out to 20 or 30 more workstations,
roll it out to 50.
And after that, it's been two weeks,
we're gonna roll it out
to the whole company.
And now when we run those
vulnerability scans,
each month after the
patching has been done,
we're gonna give that report
to the infrastructure team
one week prior to
publishing in our dashboard,
that was something that I did
not do right the first time.
We never wanna go into a
meeting and can be blindsided
by something that's shared.
And yet I did that without
even realizing it, right?
I was so excited to put
up our first dashboard.
They had never had a security dashboard,
and I didn't think anything
that it was gonna hurt anyone out there.
And I published this dashboard
and the patching metrics
were horrible and the infrastructure team
really felt thrown under the bus.
So by giving it to them a week prior,
we can weed out any false
positives, and we can collaborate
on maybe some of the stories
of why some of the
vulnerabilities are where they are
in the report.
And so it's more of
collaboration, less name calling.
So if you're not doing
something like this,
again regardless of reporting structure,
I would highly encourage it.
So now that we can actually
move on to phishing,
again at this company, we
had a program in place,
but it was being run infrequently,
maybe only quarterly,
and with very limited
visibility in the results,
they really weren't shared with anyone
except the security team and
the same campaign was being run
for the entire company.
So the entire company would
get the exact same email.
And, you can just lean over the cube
or I guess virtually, right?
Chat someone, "Hey,
they're testing us today.
Be sure you don't click on that."
In addition, that email was
so specifically crafted.
It had to go through 10 levels
of approval from HR to legal,
all these different teams to make sure
it didn't offend anyone
before it was being sent out.
Again, there's balance there,
but the bad guys don't
get those approvals.
They just send it out again.
The results were not being shared
outside of the security team.
And there wasn't a wall of
shame which is a good thing,
but there also weren't
like recognition or prizes
for the best catch for those
that didn't click on it.
So you kinda think of the
positive reinforcement.
There was really nothing,
it was all really done
in a vacuum, again more
as just a checkbox.
So did we catch anything?
To report on that, to put
this in your dashboard,
you really need to know
your industry average
'cause that's the first
question you're gonna be asked
when you report on this at any level is?
What's normal?
What's average? What's right?
As security professionals, we
all know that one is too many,
but we have to be realistic
and we have to set a target
because we're all humans
and it's going to happen.
And so, again, going back to your ISAC,
and checking with other
peers in your industry,
there's a lot that goes into it
because you can have an organization
that may still be sending
that same campaign
out to the whole company, so their numbers
are gonna look great
because once the first few people get it,
they do share with everyone else.
And so to me, that's
not an accurate metric,
but again you have to take
all of those and average them
to see what your industry
average should be for click rate
or respond rate or failure rate.
So for us, it was 3%.
We found out at the time, in
our industry of our peers,
similar organizations that
about 3% of the team members
were failing their regular
phishing exercises.
So we had a very clear defined target,
and we were ready to go phishing.
So we published, talking about
visibility and transparency,
and something that's huge for me.
And it had never been done before,
we published the monthly report
to all directors and above
again, this is for each department
they got to see the names
of their team members and
whether they passed or failed
their phishing tests for that month.
Let me tell you, when you
do something like that,
you better get ready for
the fallout and be ready
to defend yourself.
We would spend our entire team
would spend at least a week
every time we sent the report out
doing nothing but research,
we would research logs
from our web filters,
the mobile device system,
our email gateway,
EDR, all of our systems
because we constantly
heard responses like,
I didn't click on that and
you can't even prove it.
Or I was out of the office on that day,
there's no way I clicked on that.
Even better, we would hear that employee
is on extended leave,
or the best response that person
doesn't even work here anymore.
What these team members and
directors didn't realize
was that according to our
identity access management policy
when a team member exits the organization,
their email is disabled,
it's forwarded to their direct manager.
And so the manager would get the emails,
and click on the links.
And of course, as you all
know the phishing programs
still report that back as a failure
for the intended recipient.
Something else we
learned is that employees
do check their mail on their days off,
even if they're hourly and
they aren't supposed to,
unless you have some way to prevent that
with a mobile device management system
or identity access privileged system.
So we publish those
reports, we've defended them
and we see the numbers continue to rise.
And so with that, how did we
convince our executive team
to tie those phishing metrics,
those dashboards to bonuses?
It was through some hard conversations
in all seriousness, I had conversations
with our leadership team and
just really let them know
that I don't need another
dime for my security budget
if we can't get our phishing numbers down.
I mean, we are spending
millions on technical controls,
but our team members just keep
clicking on anything we sent.
And this was really eye-opening to our CIO
and the entire leadership team.
They had never had someone seriously say
that they didn't need any more budget.
And then follow that up with
the suggestion to hit others
where it impacts the
most, in their salaries.
Now don't get me wrong.
I understand there's many different areas
of risk to a company.
And our team members are very busy,
but they weren't motivated to slow down
and read their emails carefully.
And as we all know,
money really does talk.
And so we set this policy
that for each director,
they are now responsible for their teams
and any team with an average
above a 3% failure rate
in a 12-month calendar, well,
will have a reduced bonus.
So we've rolled that out
and something changed.
Now, remember the purpose
of security awareness
is not to shame, but to educate.
And we were using a best-of-breed
industry-recognized solutions,
but our numbers just continue
to trustingly increase each month.
And we thought, wow,
we've done the training,
we've tied it to bonus,
and the numbers just continue to go up.
Where is the breakdown?
So we started sending test
messages amongst just our team.
We saw that a high number
of the test messages
were being blocked by 0365.
We also saw that no attempt
at safe-listing worked,
the messages were being blocked.
In addition, the messages
showed being opened and clicked
within seconds of being delivered.
We thought, well we've got
some great team members
and all that, I think this
is statistically impossible.
So we set up multiple test
scenarios to prove out
that the sandboxing was the
root of some of these issues.
With that, we set up multiple
calls with Microsoft,
with our email security vendor
and our phishing test vendor.
And after weeks of making
changes and tests and calls,
we decided, unfortunately it
was just time for a change.
This really was hard,
we really did like our
phishing test vendor.
They provided great reporting
and great customer service.
And me personally, I really liked layers,
I do not like to use the same vendor
for multiple security services,
but because of all of
our research and testing,
we had to make a change,
and we had to really embrace the change.
So we did, and the results are in.
So with all of this said,
we think how in the world,
are we gonna regain the
trust of our leadership team?
Because we've had to go
back to them and tell them,
"Hey, this solution that we're using
through a long chain series
of events is not accurate.
The results we're seeing
each month are not accurate
for multiple reasons, and
so we need to start over."
So we did, we stopped all
reporting for two months,
we stopped all testing for two
months of our team members.
Instead we internally tested
and deployed a new system.
And this time, the system that we use
was with the same vendor
that we currently use
for our email security gateway.
We couldn't get any false
positives to fire off,
everything that we said came
through and showed accurately.
Some that we clicked, some that we didn't.
And so we thought, how will we start this?
We wanna start off on a positive foot
for the entire company.
And so why not take
this new platform again?
Remember, our goal is
education, not shaming.
And so why don't we
launch this new system,
and do the employee, the
annual training with it first,
instead of just straight
to phishing testing.
So again, not the hour-long
PowerPoint that everyone
clicks through while they're
drinking their coffee,
watching a TV show, but a
five to seven to 15-minute
at the most humorous interactive video
with a short quiz at the end.
And so we launched that
across the board and after all
or at least a high majority
of our team members
had completed that training.
We sent our first campaign
and we crossed our fingers.
And with a sigh of relief,
we were back to normal.
The test results were back to normal.
Actually they were much better.
The first round failure rate was less,
we had less than 1% of our
team members fail the test.
And we thought, well, this could
be because of COVID, right?
A lot of people are on edge,
Maybe that they're just
being extra paranoid,
but it gets even better,
the new service that we used
was a managed phishing test service.
And so they could do
all the research for us
when we did have people complained back
that if there was a false positive.
And so with this trust was reestablished.
I mean the executives would even call
when they accidentally click on a test
and let me know ahead of time.
So how can you take all of
this and apply it positively
in your environment, in
your day-to-day work?
I would really encourage you
when you go back to your
organization after this,
that you would review the
accuracy of the metrics
in your dashboard.
Maybe it's one of those
things where you've got
all these different inputs
from all these different teams,
and maybe you've got some
great BI system or something
that's putting these together for you.
I would really encourage
you to review the accuracy,
do some very targeted
testing amongst a group
and test the clicks on the not clicks
or the failures in the past
and see if your metrics
that you're presenting
really are accurate.
I would also encourage
you, and this unfortunately
has to be done on at
least a monthly basis,
because as we know, as we
embrace cloud and SAS systems,
those rules with our
SAS providers can change
without us even knowing.
And so I would encourage
you to inspect those rules
that you have in place,
safe-listing rules,
blocking rules between
your phishing vendor
and your email security
gateway on a regular basis.
This should be unfortunately
like it's almost
like patching where
something you have to inspect
and check once a month
After you've done that,
I would encourage you
to set up a time where
you can verify your brand
among your C-Suite.
Do they truly understand the value
that you're bringing to the organization?
It can be through current or future,
even non-project initiatives.
So again, it's always great
when security can come
into something that's not
a security-focused project,
then provide value maybe
through a single sign
on initiative or something
that can save the business time
or reduce some steps in a process
and add security at the same time.
And then within six months,
you really should be updating
your dashboard to reflect and align
with your security framework.
And whether it's the ISO
framework, the PCI framework,
HIPAA framework, a high-trust NIST,
you really need to make
sure your security dashboard
aligns with your security framework.
And then always, always, always question
the parameters around your
security awareness program.
Are you rewarding those members
that are constantly passing,
they're constantly reporting the phishes,
are you doing the best catch
every week or every month
where you're giving out
a gift card or something,
or are you just putting up a wall of shame
of those that fail?
Again, I thank you so much for listening.
I would encourage you to put
questions in the chat window
and I'm happy to answer those for you.
Again, hope you have a
great conference, thank you.