- Hey, good day, everybody.
This is Kean.
Thank you very much for listening
to my Bitcoin wallet story.
Well, I'm an independent
security researcher
and a member of the Honeynet Project.
So during my free time, I am involved
in sort of Honeybag tools development
and play around with
different deceptive-based
defense mechanism.
Well, personally,
I always have these big
questions in my mind.
Mmm, what if you and I,
we put our personal file on the internet
and then we just leave it there,
maybe for 90 days or 60 days.
Mmm.
What will happen to all of them?
Well, this is going to be formed
the fundamental concept
for what we are going to explore today,
which is,
who stole my $100,000
worth of a Bitcoin wallet?
Well, let's share all these stories
of the honeytokens.
For the next 30 to 35 minutes,
we'll share about three things right here.
So first,
let's take a quick look about the tool,
Honeybag.
This is a new open source
tool that we develop
for this purpose.
Secondly,
how we created all these kinds
of $100,000 worth of a Bitcoin wallet,
and then how we placed it on the internet.
Thirdly, let's take a quick look about
all the interesting stuff and all the pain
and exciting moment that we have
about this use case.
Last but not least,
I would love to share
with everyone right here
about some of the learning experience,
some of the do's and don'ts.
Well, let's do this together.
But definitely feel free
to ask any questions.
I will definitely love
to answer your questions
and hear your thoughts.
Yeah.
Let's do this together.
Now, nowadays,
we always know that
lots of security company
perform internet-wide scanning
in order to look for insecure devices,
insecure configured system
or servers on the internet.
And then lots of big brain
behind the scene always thought,
had a thought, how can
we secure it nicely?
Well,
yet on the other side of the wall,
the dark side of the internet,
those bad guys, they
are looking at the same,
so-called internet scanning result.
And those guys, they are trying to harvest
those kind of results
with a malicious intent.
For example, the folks are
looking for insecure server,
which contains tons of credit card
personal information on it.
Or he could be looking
for some internal servers
which belongs to a certain company.
And all this kind of information
can be leveraged later
in order to infiltrate
into the corporate environment,
into a private server farm
and some sort of stuff.
Well, the bad guy are
looking for juicy information
on the internet.
Well, for me,
I always love to tie this to
so-called a real-life scenario.
For example, a street thief,
when they try to break into the house,
will carry an empty bag.
Now they break into the house,
and then they'll put all the jewelries,
all the gold and silver, into the bag.
Carry the full bag out
from the crime scene.
Now,
what if in the laws of movie,
some of the folks are, they will try, or,
so-called the investigator,
they will put certain GPS tracker devices
into those kind of bags.
Once the bag moves from a single location
to another location,
the GPS tracker will send certain ping,
or certain signal,
back to the controller or
so-called the investigator.
Well, this can be used to, kind of,
keep track about where the files are going
and where it's appeared here and there.
Now I would love to tie
this scenario, this analogy,
to so-called cybersecurity
defender's point of view.
As a honeypot researcher,
honeypot hobbyist,
I always think that,
if anything that we can do in this case
in terms of cyber
defender's point of view,
what if we can put certain bait
or bait files into those kind of bag?
And whenever the file gets
stolen over the internet,
it will send us certain
information afterwards.
Now, this concept is not brand new.
This is about honeytoken,
it's about baits,
it's about breadcrumb.
Yeah, multiple terms are
which popular in the industry right now.
Well, it was still back to
the same fundamental concept,
which is about a bait.
Yeah.
Let's take a quick look together
about a real-life example,
which are back in 2017.
I came across with this public blog,
which are post by a very
well-known security guru,
Mr. Didier Stevens,
on SANS blog.
Back in 2017,
he observed these very
interesting observations.
Someone, or I will say that the bad guy,
tried to pickpocket Bitcoin
wallet from his web server.
Back in 2017,
end of 2017,
Bitcoin price was all-time high.
Well, I mean, that was back then.
If I remember correctly,
the Bitcoin price was
around 19,000 U.S. dollar,
for Bitcoin, back in 2017 again.
Yeah (laughs)
Oh, at that time, Mr.
Didier Stevens observed that
there were a lot of internet
scanning activities.
People tried to pickpocket Bitcoin wallet
from his web server.
And these are patterns
that came back from time
over a couple of few months.
One thing that really
catch our attention is
the picture that he posted on the blog.
This is the web server log.
Personally, I would love to say that
this is a very beautiful and very sexy
web server log (laughs).
In brief, a bad guy,
continuously hitting
on his web server log.
He's tried to, tried his luck
by guessing those kind of correct wallet,
crypto wallet filename,
with hope that there
are some crypto wallet
appear or located on this web server.
Now, how can we read this correct easily?
The first column will be IP address.
The second column will be the date
and the timestamp.
It followed by the HTTP get method,
followed by the URL as well,
with the history around response.
Over here, we'll be seeing a lot of HTTP
404, not found response.
And last but not least,
followed by the data
size and the user agent.
Some guy just continued to try his luck,
try to brute forcing or guessing
different Bitcoin wallet filename.
In this case, of course,
he was hit with a lot of 404,
not found HTTP error code
because there was no any
Bitcoin wallet over there.
Well, the things that catch
our attention the most,
is the patterns of the
brute forcing activities
or the pattern of the,
by guessing those kind of
crypto wallet filename.
Now, just for context,
for common, in a common practice,
crypto wallet could be named as
wallet.dat,
or wallet underscore backup.dat.
In this case, bad guy
tried to look for a zip file,
which contain the crypto
wallet in this case.
They are looking for the files
with the filename called wallet.zip,
or backup/wallet.zip.
Now as a honeypot researcher,
or the honeypot hobbyist,
anything that we can do right here?
Can we try to feed the bad guy
with the data that they need
and then make a fake content in it,
and eventually this
zip file, or this data,
that are accessed by the bad guy,
and it will send us certain information
about the bad guy behind the scene.
This sort of forms,
so-called a concept for us
which we would like to
introduce our new tools,
a new open source tool,
namely, Honeybag.
Honeybag is a tool which allow,
which helps all of us
to create a bait file.
A zip file in this case.
We can easily embed it with any content
or such as files, folders into it.
If someone access it,
it will notify you, it
will notify us, yeah.
The main goal for Honeybag is to,
definitely about the notifications.
We like to let this, so-called a bait,
sitting quietly over there.
If someone accidentally
or intentionally access it,
it will notify us.
We hope that this can be helpful
for our security community
in terms of the cybersecurity
defense point of view.
And we hope that this can be useful
for data breach detections
or deceptive defense-based mechanism.
Let's take a quick look together
about how Honeybag works.
In an easiest way,
Honeybag will contain
three different components.
It could be, it would be pretty easy to,
to use in this case.
So the first component will be
this Honeybag command line client,
which you have seen on
the screen right now.
The second component will be
the Honeybag simple DNS server.
For the third component,
we can set up RESPONDER
in order to work together with Honeybag.
This can,
these three components can
work well with each other,
that, eventually, it just
can give us a good result.
Well, I would say,
what you have seen on
the screen right here.
This is just a simple Python script
for our Honeybag client.
We can easily generate a bait zip file
with any embedded files
and folders into it.
We can, for example,
we can insert or we can embed
a PDF file, document file,
or text file, or pictures,
or anything into the zip file.
And this will,
Honeybag client will generate,
so-called a final zip file for us.
Now I will let us shift gear a bit.
Let's try to take a look
about the final zip file.
How the final zip file looks like?
Now what you're seeing on
the right screen, right here.
Our zip file,
this is a so-called the simple tree view
about one of the zip
file that we generated.
The zip file namely as secret.zip.
It contains a folder, a secret folder.
We can easily customize this name.
And then it contains just a single file.
The file is supersecretdocument.pdf.
I know,
we have a lot of secret
right here (laughs).
During the generation process,
Honeybag will automatically slot
two different new files
into the secret zip file
or under the secret folder.
The first file will be the file
ended with a file extension .url.
The second file will be the file
with the name desktop.ini.
Both of these files will serve so-called
the alerting mechanism for our Honeybag.
And this is how,
wherever someone tried to access the file,
this alerting mechanism
will be kicking in.
So for the first of file
which is the desktop.ini,
and this is one of the very common file
that every one of us will be encountered
in Windows operating system.
In fact, in a legitimate usage,
desktop.ini is associated
with how Windows display the folders
on the Windows Explorer.
For example,
for a folder,
if you want to customize
the icon for the folder,
we can do it in a,
with this desktop.ini.
Desktop.ini will try to
look for the icon file
on a local system.
Well, credit to,
thanks Canary token,
for a very interesting technique.
Instead of letting desktop.ini
look for icon file locally,
you can tweak
this mechanism to let desktop.ini
looking for icon on the external location.
It could be some icon file that's sitting
on a certain domain, or a website,
or it could be an icon file
which are located somewhere
with some IP address on
somewhere out of the internet.
So with these kind of tweaking,
in fact, this is very handy for the,
our alerting mechanism in this case, yeah.
For the second file, the .url,
we're going, we use almost a similar,
a so-called mechanism,
which is for your LAP.
The icon file tried to
look for the icon pictures,
or the exact file itself,
on external locations.
It could be IP address sitting somewhere.
Now we have this, secret zip file on hand,
and once we place it somewhere
on the computer networks,
or it could be on the internet.
What if a bad guy get this file,
the secret.zip file?
Now he tried to unzip the zip file
and click into the folder.
What will happen in this case?
In this case,
Honeybag the zip file
will trigger two alerts.
The first alert will go to our
Honeybag simple DNS server.
And then the second alert
will go to the RESPONDER
which we set up, we can set it up on,
we host it on certain IP
address on the internet.
Now for the Honeybag simple DNS component,
DNS server component,
there is a little listen on DNS traffic.
It will perform certain logging
with just simply on the SQLite database.
In this case, we will start to collect
some information such
as the computer name,
the user name, the domain name
from the Windows machines
which used to access, or used to unzip
and open our zip file.
Well, for the RESPONDER perspective,
we can collect, maybe, it could be
source IP address, the username,
computer name.
And if we're lucky enough,
we will able to get some NTLMv2 hashes
or NTLM hashes in this case.
It's going to be small little pieces
of the information here and there.
IP, source IP address.
but eventually all this information,
it can gel out together
and it can form a very beautiful
and very useful investigation
picture for all of us.
Now, a little bit,
a caveat right here.
For our alerting mechanism to work,
desktop.ini and the .url file,
both of them,
they are more applicable
for Windows operating system as for now.
Well, let's see an example.
If someone tried to get,
able to get a secret.zip file
and he or she opened it and access it
in Linux or in OS X,
Mac OS X environment.
We will not able to receive
any alerts as for now.
Yeah, we are always looking for new idea,
new techniques which we can apply,
building mechanism for
Linux and OS X machines.
So if you came across with any of these
interesting techniques or new idea,
feel free to reach out to us.
We would like to hear about this
and hopefully we can implement
this in the Honeybag.
And for this is an open source tool,
so hopefully it can be
useful for our community
and especially in terms
of the cybersecurity,
I mean, cyber defender's point of view.
Yeah.
Now things are getting interesting.
Since we have this zip
file right now on hand,
well, I will say that,
this technique is not really brand new.
There were numbers of blogs and articles
about this type of technique
with .url or desktop.ini approach.
But for Honeybag, one
of our highlights is,
this is an open source tool.
We can easily generate a
zip file with any folder
or any embedded files
and folders as we like.
You can easily customize.
So for example,
we can turn just a single file,
zip file,
or it could be thousands of zip files,
since it's just a Python script.
We can easily integrate in other
scripting language as well.
I mean, yeah, or system.
While we have these
tools on hand right now,
the next question will be,
how can you play with it
and get the best out of it?
Well we have lots of thoughts,
lots of discussions.
How can we create this kind of use case?
And we came across with
this very interesting idea.
Everybody gonna love Bitcoin wallet.
Yeah?
So what if,
if we place a $100,000
worth of a Bitcoin wallet
and we just leave it there on the internet
for 90 days.
What will happen to all of them?
Well, once, after we had this idea,
I came across with a very huge roadblock.
Personally I don't have
$100,000 worth of Bitcoin wallet
on my hand (laughs).
Now, if anyone would like to donate this,
$100,000 worth of Bitcoin
wallet to me or Bitcoin to me,
thank you very much in advance (laughs).
Well.
After we searching around
and then we came across with this
very interesting alternative,
namely, Bitcoin Testnet,
which is a BTC Testnet.
We prepare 10 Bitcoin wallets,
and each of them is unprotected.
When they contain,
each of them contain one
BTC Testnet in this case.
Now some differences between BTC Testnet
and BTC, which is Bitcoin.
BTC Testnet is meant for testing purposes.
For lots of,
it's very useful for lots
of blockchain developers
or wallet, crypto application developers,
because the BTC Testnet and BTC,
they are using the same
mechanism at the back.
But while BTC testing,
it doesn't associate with any real value,
for example, tied to any currency value.
While Bitcoin itself is associated,
could be to the currency
such as the U.S. dollar in this case.
While we are looking at the addresses,
the BTC Testnet and BTC addresses,
the prefix with a
so-called different prefix
at the front of each addresses,
in terms of the wallet perspective,
for me, they look pretty similar.
Yeah.
We can use some similar
crypto wallet application to open it.
But the best things about BTC Testnet,
they are freely available on the internet.
We can get it freely from
different faucet on the internet.
But if you go for the same approach,
I would really suggest that,
once we finish use it
for different use cases,
please transfer it back to the faucet
so other developers or other members,
I mean, anyone in the
community can use it later.
Yeah.
So we have this use
case back in early 2020.
During that time, one BTC, one Bitcoin
will be equivalent to around U.S.,
10 U.S. dollar.
Yeah.
So,
well, I want to bring it up this human,
this wallet, the terms.
You know, human psychology perspective,
wallet is something always interesting.
It's interest, it's a
placeholder for valuable,
such as cash, note,
credit card or identifications or cards,
which appear, which will
be appear in a wallet.
In real life,
what if someone encountered
this wallet on a street,
or on a desk in a restaurant,
will someone take it
and try to contact the owner?
Or will someone just take
it and take all the cash,
all of it?
So what if we leave all
our 10 Bitcoin wallets
on the internet.
What will happen to all of them?
So we decided to put all
these 10 Bitcoin wallets
on a multiple, open directory server,
web server on the internet.
We just let them sitting
quietly over there.
We just want to wait for
things to be happened.
Of course, we try to make
this web server look real.
So we put a lot of many personal info,
files on the web server.
A bunch of documents over there.
So the web server looks kind
of pretty real in a sense.
Now, once we have all
of this kind of set up,
what we really expect is,
this full screen of very sexy
and very beautiful web server log.
And we really expect
that different hackers,
or different trackers
or different bad guy,
try to fight with each other
for our Bitcoin wallet.
We hope that they can
keep continuously grab
different copy of our Bitcoin
wallet from our web server.
This is our expectation.
Well, in reality,
in reality, it's so disappointing.
Our web server is just simply quiet,
for the first 30 days or 35 days.
From time to time, we have seen
some cat and flies (laughs).
We sit there and say hi.
If you're lucky enough,
you may come across with a Google bot
or Bing bots talk to us.
This could be due to the reason that
this pretty new web server that we,
which appear on the internet,
it could be a new resources.
So no one really noticed about this.
So first lesson learned,
just be patient, yeah.
We start to have a different approach
about how can we improve it.
So we decided to go for
more corrective approach.
So we try to put miscellaneous
information on Pastebin,
such as, hey buddy, this
is my secret crypto wallet.
Please don't download it.
Once we put the word,
please don't download it,
things are getting interesting.
'Cause people are starting to
download it and to access it.
Now in overall, what happened in 90 days?
Interestingly, all our 10 Bitcoin wallets
which we created with Honeybag,
all the zip files were stolen.
Nine of the 10 Bitcoin wallets
gave us certain information
about the bad guy behind the scene.
And we have one missing crypto wallet.
I suspect that this could be due to
the wallet was accessed in a Linux
or in a Mac OS X environment.
So we have never received anything back.
An interesting observation.
The fastest record for
one of the stolen wallets
is almost less than a minute
after we posted on Pastebin.
This could be due to,
maybe certain automated bot,
or it could be a human behind a keyboard.
Who knows?
For the next five minutes or 10 minutes,
let me show you about
one unexpected scene.
Yeah, there was someone
just totally wipe out
our Bitcoin Testnet wallet.
Well, the whole story started
around March 23rd last year.
We created this Bitcoin wallet
and we placed it on the internet.
Within, I would say less than 24 hours,
surprisingly and unexpectedly,
the value in our Bitcoin wallet
become totally empty, becomes zero,
which is what you can see
on the screen right now.
Somebody has just wiped
out our BTC Testnet wallet.
Hey buddy, this is BTC Testnet.
There is no value into it.
Why you wipe out our entire BTC Testnet?
And now let me try to take a quick look
about the three different
components right here,
so we can form a nice timeline
investigation panel together.
Back in March 23rd,
ahh, 24th,
we, someone access our web server
and retrieve the wallet.zip
file from our web server.
This case will be,
he got a file from /bitcoin/wallet.zip.
Our web server responds
with a HTTP code 200.
In this case it indicates
a success download.
Followed by the common user
agent for Firefox version 74.
Well, these things happen in 14:40 UTC.
Two minutes afterwards,
we start to observe that we
received these DNS requests,
pretty long DNS requests,
which appear on the screen right here.
Now, this DNS request is,
the format itself is
pre-crafted for all of us.
And then the first column will be
the value which belongs to the username
or the Windows operating system.
We should, in this case,
will be a Mr. Blue.
Second column will be,
so-called the computer name.
In this case will be the DESKTOP-AFMMB6K.
And the third column will be
the DESKTOP-AFMMB6K as well,
this is the domain name.
So once we get these DNS requests,
this indicates that the bad guy was
unzip our zip file,
look into the zip file,
click into the secret folder in this case,
under Windows Explorer
on a Windows machine.
Now things are getting interesting because
of the whole alerts are
continuously appear for 20 minutes.
Now we realized that,
hey, the folk is try to
looking into our crypto wallet
for around 20 minutes during that time.
For the third component,
this is about the RESPONDER perspective.
Well, we collected so-called NTMv2 hashes.
In this case, the username Mr. Blue, is
exactly tie with what we have
seen on the DNS log just now.
And the computer name appear
to be the same as well.
Now these hash can be useful
for certain analysis later.
In overall,
in that timeline, the
investigation timeline,
was around 14:40 UTC.
Our wallet was stolen from our web server.
Two minutes afterward,
we received the first DNS alert,
indicates that somebody was accessing our,
our folder and zip file.
It continuously with,
appear with this SMB alert
in our RESPONDER log.
Well, 35 minutes
from the first moment our
wallet.zip file gets stolen,
Mr. Blue wipe out our BTC Testnet wallet.
Until right now, I have
no idea why he did this.
It could be, I guess,
could be, he found out what we did.
Since this is a bait,
and he just piss off (laughs)
about what we have done right here.
Now I'm just joking (laughs).
Lesson learned.
It is always good to
have a different pieces
of this evidence.
We can gel all these kind
of evidence together.
Eventually this can give us
a very good investigation
timeline or the pictures.
I would love to share a
couple of do and don't.
First lesson learned, right here,
just be patient.
Initially we expect a very beautiful
and very sexy web server log.
We hope that it,
the folks, the bad guy,
would try to fight with
themselves and try to grab
a copy of the Bitcoin
wallet from our web server.
In fact, we had to wait
for more than 35 or 30 days
to get the first result.
It's always the pain
and the fun for honeypot researchers,
cybersecurity researchers.
It always takes, take time
and then we can harvest a good result.
Well, I will suggest that
customize our own unique deceptive baits.
All these kind of, all these baits,
the more unique it is,
I believe that the impact
will be better definitely.
Yeah.
I also would like to
suggest that we should
put up the warning banner, in
this case a warning message.
Hey buddy, this is a restricted area
or restricted resources.
You are not authorized to access this.
While someone try to bypass
or ignore totally about this
kind of warning message,
well, things can be getting interesting.
One last thing I want to
mention right here is,
never underestimate
for the great impact of this.
For us, initially,
the design of the Honeybag
is meant to be more applicable
for Windows operating system.
Well, surprisingly nine out of 10
of our Bitcoin wallet
return certain information
about the bad guy
behind the scene.
This is unexpected result,
and definitely never underestimate
about a great impact out of it.
The more unique it is,
the more tailor-made it is,
the honeytokens, the impact
can be really useful.
I will, let's say, start
to deploy your own unique
honeytokens today.
If you like to give it a try,
please feel free to try
on our Honeybag new tool.
A tool that will help you
to create a bait zip file,
archive file,
can easily embed any
folder or files into it.
It will ask you, notify
you if someone access it.
The GitHub page is here.
So you can feel free to
download and access it.
Now we also would like to welcome
if anyone like to
contribute to this project.
If you have any new
techniques that we can apply,
alerting mechanism in the
Linux or in OS X environment,
yeah, please share with us.
Yeah, feel free to ask any
questions for today's session.
I would love to thank RSA Conference
for this wonderful opportunity
for me to share about,
for us to share about our new tools,
the Honeybag tool right here.
And thanks for listening
to my Bitcoin wallet story.
Thank you very much.