- Hi, my name is Steve Black
and I'd like to thank the organizers
for inviting me to present today.
If you have questions,
please put them in the chat.
From time to time my first
year law students ask me
why they have to study property.
And from time to time when
I'm speaking with a CEO
or a CIO, they will ask me
how they avoid getting sued
following a breach.
I'd like to give you one possible answer
to both of these very serious questions.
So it's an age, old story.
Somebody breaks something, and
then somebody suggests that
there ought to be a law to fix it.
Except in this case everyone
is rushing in to fix it.
And if you were one of my law students
I would tell you that this is wonderful
because more law means
more work for lawyers.
And the map that I'm
showing right now tracks
some of the many laws that we look at
so that clients can number
one comply with practices
where they do business
and by that I mean if
where they're collecting
data from citizens
and number two plan which countries
they want to do business with
or which countries they want to avoid.
And number three advocate
with those governments
for the types of laws that they want
and seriously think about that.
If more than 100 countries
all try and pass laws
they're not going to agree 100%
and some of those countries
will try and outdo others
and some won't really
care and it's a legal mess
or a legal playground depending
on your point of view.
On the other hand if
you're one of my clients
it really is a mess.
How in the world, pun
intended, do you comply with
all of these laws?
From Japan to Brazil to China
to the U.S and in the U.S
we've got many many laws
and many more coming
as states see the impending
railroad coming up.
And so today's quotes
that I'm going to show
on the next slide are courtesy
of the Princess Bride.
And quite frankly, this is good advice
when you're dealing with
more than 120 countries
all trying to regulate similar practices.
So I actually do love legal history.
It wasn't always the case
but I have found a new passion in it
so we're gonna start back in
1753 with William Blackstone
who wrote that property
is that relationship
between a person and a thing, my pen.
And then we're gonna fast forward.
Right that makes sense to
a lot of us we think about
you know, I own this or, you
know, I wish I owned that
we're talking about things primarily.
And beginning in 1913 there was a shift
and Wesley Hoffeld wrote that
property is really
relationships between people
and what he was talking
about are rights and powers
and privileges and immunities.
And for example, if I own a piece of land
and you're trying to trespass
I have the right to exclude you
who has no right to be on the property.
And then by 1961, we arrive
at this understanding that
property is a bundle of incidents
and we're gonna talk about
more about those incidents
but you can think about
those as a bundle of rights.
And what we're going
to do with those rights
is going to be very interesting.
So if you can with me for just a moment
let's think about this.
You've got a whole bunch of countries
passing a whole bunch
of data protection laws
and they give people rights to do things
with their data or, you know,
keep other people from
doing things with their data
and that makes property
because now I've got the rights
to the data and suddenly
we've got property.
Before this worldwide
interest in data legislation
data was just data.
Does it really have to be property
and I'm hearing my first year law students
ask that question.
So in 1986, a Mr. Lucas bought two lots
in coastal South Carolina.
And he was gonna build single family homes
on those contiguous parcels.
At the time, there was
no regulation to stop him
from doing that.
But two years later in 1988,
the state legislature enacted
the beach front management
act, which kept him from
building any permanent
structure on his properties
and he filed suit and
said, hey you know what?
Even though that may have
been a waffle exercise
of state authority,
you've, you've ruined my
vacation property, right?
You've taken away all economic value
and he thought that that was a taking
under the 5th and 14th amendment
and we're not gonna go through
the constitutional
intricacies of this suit
but we will note that
both the Justice Scalia
writing for the majority
and Justice Blackmun
writing for himself in
a dissent said that,
I mean they used the
phrase the bundle of rights
and Scalia said
understandings of our citizens
regarding the content of,
and the state's power over
the bundle of rights that they acquire
when they're (indistinct)
title is interesting to us
and so that's Lucas V. South
Carolina coastal council
and that was a 1992 case.
So we're looking at
legislation creates rights,
rights create property.
Even if we're not intending to
necessarily create property.
So if we're going to use
these types of words,
we probably ought to
figure out what they mean.
So some of the rights that we talk about.
We'll start with the right to exclude
'cause that was in the Lucas case.
One of the big things that
the dissent was harping on
was yeah but he still had
the right to keep people
off the property so let's talk about
what the right to exclude really means.
With land I can tell you
to stay off or get off.
Does that mean the same thing with data?
So if it's property I should
be able to exclude others
from my personal private
information but once they have it
what then?
Both the CCPA and the GDPR
give private individuals
rights to exclude but does that mean that
I can make somebody forget what they saw?
And that's a question yet to be decided.
And this slide I'm gonna admit
is a little bit obtuse even for me.
So Obiwan does the
little Jedi trick, right?
And the stormtroopers completely forget
the question that they were asking.
Does data work like a Jedi mind trick?
Can I make people forget what they saw?
Now land is much easier.
You know, if you're on my
property I can kick you off.
So if exclusion or privacy is to have
any real meaning for us
doesn't that require us
to perform Jedi mind tricks?
Or do we consider the right to exclude
after the data has been seen
to be completely illusory?
Okay so this slide actually
has a different title
I mean this is fine here
but I'm gonna call this data is sticky.
So I don't know if anyone's
ever had one of these little
sticky hands that you know
they stick to the wall
and stick to your sister and
all kinds of other things.
What do I mean by stickiness?
So if I own a car and I
want to sell it to you
once the sale is done I
don't retain any rights
and there's that word again, in your car.
I can't walk over and say, hey
great car I used to drive it
I'm just gonna take it
out for a spin again.
We really frown on that in the law.
But data is weird.
Data is sticky and again this is my term
not any legislative, you
know, action or whatever
so if you're gonna use it in an article
you can cite to me, I'm
perfectly okay with that.
Section 1798.120 of the
CCPA says this, quote,
a consumer shall have
the rights at any time
to direct a business that
sells personal information
about the consumer to third parties
not to sell the consumer's
personal information.
And just one more time for good measure
so we can appreciate that.
A consumer should have
the right at any time
to direct a business that
sells personal information
about that consumer to
third parties to not sell
the consumer's personal information.
If I sell a car I give up all rights.
I could transfer IP to you
and mostly give up all rights.
The mostly is in some
countries, they recognize
an artist's moral rights
and that really means that
if an artist is creating a body of work
and someone that they licensed the work to
or sell the work to is
using, or misusing that IP
to harm the artists'
image or their reputation
then maybe they can,
you know, claw it back.
U.S really doesn't
subscribe to that theory
but we do have this data stickiness
and this legislative stickiness
is fairly unique in the law
and it begs the question
whether data can be sold at all.
And we should talk
about slicing and dicing
and we had a lot more
time in this presentation
maybe even days, we could talk about
how other types of property
can get sliced into different pieces.
So for example, if I own
land I could keep the land
for 10 years and then give it to you
and, you know, we would each own the land
but at different points in time
or we could do something different
where I get 40% of the
land and you get 60% now
so we're sharing it now or, you
know, if we wanna go into IP
I get to use the performance
rights of the song that you own
but not the publication
rights and so on and so forth
and now that I think about it
some types of property are weird too.
And property has a right
of non-use or idleness
and what do I mean by that?
So if I buy land or a car
I don't have to do anything with it.
That birthday gift that
your aunt bought you
for your last birthday,
you didn't really want
and you still haven't opened the box
it's perfectly okay to keep it in the box.
The property police are not
going to make you use it.
Data, can you really tell
people not to touch it
and what does that mean?
Once you've seen it that's
the use of the property.
And now we're just getting warmed up.
So data is a complex concept
from a legal point of view.
It represents information about a subject
held by a collector or
information about a subject
held by a collector that
is now being processed
by a processor but both
subject and collector
and the processor have
interest in the information.
So we can talk about data mutuality.
So for example, I have
a social security number
because the government made me get one.
I have a driver's license
for the same reason
and I have credit cards.
All of those have numbers
and the question is
are those numbers mine or
the governments or the banks?
And we may wanna know the
answer to that question
because data equals privacy.
So if we understand the
concept of mutuality correctly
we would understand this
quote from a 1960 case
entitled Bradley V Cowls which said
guarantee of the right of privacy
is not a guarantee of hermetic seclusion.
We live in a society geared toward,
geared in the opposite direction.
A society that makes public demands
and imposes public duties.
So in Bradley the name
and address of the mother
of a 14 year old who had
been murdered was published
in an interview with two
of the men who were accused
of committing the crime.
Does a private citizen
have rights in her privacy?
And the Bradley case cited two other cases
and the first was Ike
V. Park Dog Food Company
which held that at least in Illinois
you can't take someone's photo
for your own advertising campaign
and that's what the dog
food company had done.
They'd taken somebody's photo
and used it without permission
to promote a product.
But Bradley also cited Anoreno in which
a magazine ran a story that was entitled
if you love me slip me a gun.
And they printed the photo
of a widow whose husband
had been a police
detective who was killed.
And again, does a private
citizen have rights?
So strangely enough, these cases lead us
to an interesting question.
Who owns a paparazzi photograph?
So before the current climate
of rampant data regulation
we would have said the federal
copyright statute said that
the person who took the photo
is the owner of the photo.
Except in 2017, Chloe Kardashian was sued
by Exposure Photos, a
paparazzi site that took
a picture of her with her sister
and Chloe reposted the picture
cropping out the copyright notice
and the two ended up settling
but a little bit later,
Gigi Hadid another
international supermodel
had a similar conflict with the magazine.
She posted one of the paparazzi photos
that they had featured
of herself on Instagram
and cropped out the copyright notice.
They sued her.
She said, I didn't
infringe on your copyright
because it was a picture
of me and in fact,
the only reason that it was
an interesting picture of me
is because of my body of work
and because I'm so famous.
So if anything it was
a collaborative process
between the photographer and me
and we're back to this
concept of data mutuality
which is hmm, who really
does own, you know
something that we're fighting about here?
That case was dismissed because
Exclusive, the paparazzi company,
didn't file a copyright registration
and so you know we still
have this issue out there of
what do we do with photos
that could be personal data
at the same time they could
be the subject of copyright?
And as long as we're at it
let's talk about sharing information.
So if you really wanna know these things
and you have some free time on your hands
September 9th is the
most popular birthday.
And according to one site that I looked at
Mary Smith is a name shared
by just shy of 20,000 people
and California is our biggest state.
So what, a lot of people
have that information.
As you begin to combine the
information together however
then we start to say, well
is this really identifying
a particular person or persons?
Do we share the data that we
consider to be most private
and personal?
And as long as we're talking about sharing
and people who aren't
really interested in sharing
we have to go back to my poor
1L law students who ask me
if they really do have to study property
and we have to talk about
a couple of rules that may
or may not have anything
to do with data whatsoever
but are favorites of professors
who like to torture students
and in the interest of not
torturing you overtly today
I'm gonna keep it really short.
But the rule of capture usually starts
with a case like Pearson D Post
in which a couple of individuals decided,
hey it looks like a wonderful Saturday
so we're gonna go out fox hunting
and that's with the hounds
and the horses and the
horns, and, you know
the idyllic British
countryside and off they go
and they find a hapless fox
and they start chasing it.
When lo and behold out of the woods comes
the other gentleman who
happens to see the fox
takes the shot, kills the
fox and carries it off.
At which point the hunters
on the horse then say,
wait a minute that's our fox.
And the gentleman with
the gun says really?
'Cause I'm holding it and it's dead.
And this is where the torture
begins for law students
but it's an interesting case for us
because is data like a
fox existing in the wild?
The second rule that we
really should talk about
is the rule of finding.
And you'll recall that we talked about
property being relationships.
So the question is, if I find something
I can have greater rights
against some people who aren't finders
but lesser rights against people
who are owners of property
and that you know boggles
our mind how you can have
more ownership in property
depending on your relationship
to the others who may have
rights in that same property.
What does that mean with data?
Is it in the wild undiscovered
and ready to be captured?
Is it lost and ready to be found?
Did I abandon it
and do these old legal rules
even make sense for us?
So while we're asking these questions
maybe we ought to start figuring out
what phrases we really need
to become familiar with.
Starting with, what do
we mean by ownership?
So John Locke wrote quote
he that encloses land
and has a greater plenty
of the conveniences of life from 10 acres
than he could have from
100 acres left in nature
may truly be said to
give 90 acres to mankind.
I am not sure about his math there.
For his labor now supplies
him with provisions
out of 10 acres which
were but the product of
100 lying in common.
So the question we can ask
is, is data like fallow land?
Or if I collect it, is it mine?
If I observe it is it mine?
If I derive it or combine it, is it mine?
If I create it, is it mine?
And all of those questions may have
the same infuriating answer, it depends.
So we could assume and I'm just gonna
pull some cases out here
and if you are interested
ask me in the chat or
contact me via email later
I'd be happy to give you
the sites to any of these
but you know, if I create a
theme song for you or a logo
or a color, not many of us know that
you can actually create
a color and trademark it
or a dance move is it mine or is it yours?
In 1971 Carolyn Davidson
was a graphic design student
at Portland State.
In 1969, two years earlier
she had met Phil Knight
the then assistant
professor at Portland State
who would go on to
found Blue Ribbon Sports
and then a little company we know as Nike.
Knight knew Davidson was in
search of some extra funds
as all students tend to be.
So he asked her to help
him out on some projects
at a rate of wait for it, $2 an hour.
Woohoo.
So she charged him for 17
and a half hours of work
and was paid by check of $35.
He was staring down a deadline.
He had shoe boxes in Mexico
that really needed a logo
and needed to be printed.
He needed a decision so
he grabbed her rendering
of the swoosh and said, quote,
I don't love it but it will grow on me.
True story. That starts us
asking some of these questions.
Yeah if we think about data mutuality
and if we think about others creating data
or sharing data who really he owns it
does your email address
really belong to you?
And by the way, Google if you're listening
I have some other theories
for you and call me, right?
You have my email address.
Literally you have my email address.
Or on the other hand if I happen to own
the Twitter handle real Donald
Trump does it belong to me
or can it be shut down
at any point in time?
If you work for a company that does
a lot of data collection, what do you do
if the law says the data
belongs to someone else?
Hold on for two slides
we're gonna get to the
answer to that question.
So some of the data protection
laws refer to household data.
That's interesting concept
as long as we're creating
new property out of nothing
what in the world is household data?
And this is data that
can identify individuals
who live together in a household.
And then my question is, so who owns that?
What if I live in a
household with children?
You may recall that the
law protects children
and their data and their online presence.
So can I consent to the
use of data that is shared
with children without implicating CAPA
or any of the other children's
data protection schemes?
If that wasn't clear for those
of you who work for companies
that collect data or who
have apps that collect data,
and you think, aha we only sell to adults
so we don't need to worry about
children's data protection schemes
you may be sadly mistaken.
Once the law starts labeling
things as household data
if there are children in the household
your life just got complicated.
You're welcome.
Some of you, we live in households
with the significant other.
What's hers is hers so what's mine is hers
and if there's a question it's hers.
Can I consent to have
someone use household data
that I share?
In the legal world we
would usually take a belt
and suspenders approach to that
and so what we would do is make sure that
everybody who possibly could own something
signed off on our use of
something and as a data collector
what does that mean for you?
That gets to be a thorny
problem because number one
your clients may not want to
tell you if they have children
or a significant other and
you may be thinking correctly
in some instances that
I really don't wanna
ask that question and
number three you're thinking
maybe the law is bad by
even having shared data.
And the question is, can we get around it?
Because once we think
about data as property
we start to think about
data as shared property
and I have an address and
that can be a physical address
in which case all the
persons who live here
in my physical address share
that piece of information
but I also have online addresses
and if I share those at any point in time
do they become shared data
and as a data collector
do I need to start thinking about
my processes of data sharieness?
That's not a word I just made it up.
And for those of you
who are thinking ahead
because that's the kind
of person that you are
you're thinking about, hey Professor Black
some of these data
protection schemes require us
to erase data and how
do I erase shared data?
And my answer is, that's
a really good question.
This slide also has a funny
subtitle but just for me
which is robots are cool but really
should they be writing
slogans or more to the point
if my robot/AI/whatever
creates data who owns it?
Well this slogan was
actually written by AI.
In the U.S the copyright
law usually says that
if you create a creative work
copyright automatically attaches.
To whom? To the creator.
Who's the creator of AI derived poems?
If that's not interesting
or scary enough for you
let me go a step further.
So what if my driverless car
which for our purposes today
I'm gonna name Frida takes
photos of all she sees
around us with her 27 cameras.
When she's not driving me
around in her free time
she collates those into travel videos
and uploads those to YouTube
where they go viral
among all her followers
who also happen to be driverless cars.
I don't know who watches
viral AI car videos
but somebody is going to.
So she gets 10 million followers
and YouTube starts sending her checks
which aren't really
checked because seriously
how can my car cash her own checks right?
So they're auto-deposited.
Okay that's the dorky part of the humor
and I'm just gonna stop.
Auto-deposited for those of
you who are watching this later
you're gonna pause here and think about
what in the world is he talking about?
Let me ask you a question.
If that AI generated data
starts generating money
whose money is it?
As a tax attorney can she
claim me as a dependent?
So these are gonna be
really fascinating questions
that are gonna come up in your future
and this is what happens when
you make data into property.
So at this point, I'm gonna refer back to
how we started all this mess.
Somebody breached a computer system
and took data that didn't belong to them.
However the organization
that own the computer system
didn't really own the data either.
So what we're really doing is
giving you the data subject
some rights and privacy
against someone who
didn't steal your data but who let
somebody else steal your data.
And you might ask me why don't
we just go after the thief
and I'm going to remind
you that data thieves
usually don't work in
extradition jurisdictions.
They typically work out of the
non-extradition jurisdictions,
or they flee to one
or in some cases they are a
non-extradition jurisdiction
and it's hard for us to punish countries.
So we're left with you having
rights against a company
that did nothing wrong
except they let somebody
else steal your data.
And now let me see if I can
answer some of the questions
I promised at the beginning
of this presentation
to both my 1L property
students and my CEO friend
and you too Google.
When legislatures began regulating data
they quite unintentionally made data
into a new form of property.
We do that a lot.
It's easier for us to
take something unknown
and to put it into a familiar box.
And the process is familiar.
We've been doing that
with contracts and torts
and know-how and all
kinds of intangible things
because property is a familiar box to us.
Things have value, they can be transferred
and it's easy to have a, quote, owner.
But data as property is weird
and we have a lot of weird property
especially when we consider intangibles.
But data gets some unique
properties and people like me
like to write about it
and judges like to struggle with it a bit
and we're off to the races.
So is that the answer to the 1L question
because it's interesting?
Wait.
With data as property we now look at
and I'm not gonna point anyone out,
but Google and Amazon and
Microsoft and the U.S Post Office
and the census and my
favorite ukulele company
all of whom collect data and
we say, hmm is that yours?
And they might say, well no but look
it was running around the
forest and wild and free
so I caught it and used it
like John Locke said I should
and is that gonna be a problem?
And that could be the end of
the presentation, but it's not.
Several years ago I brought in
a university tech transfer office
to an entrepreneurship
class I was teaching
and they told the class
that all the information
and all the data, and quite frankly
all the intellectual property
belongs to the university.
And my students were
horrified and you know
our client and venters were horrified.
How can they claim that they cried?
What about the rights
of inventors and freedom
and privacy and all
those other good things?
And wait I said, and watch the magic.
Can the university market
the IP? Do they want to?
And how much is the
royalty that they want?
So if you have a very good
friend with a very fast car
and the friend hands you
the keys to the car and says
just be sure to bring it
back with gas in the tank
and, you know, maybe watch the windshield
are you happy that you don't own the car?
So as a strategy matters
we asked the question about
who owns your data?
We will still collect data
and we will still use it
but we ought to be concerned
with the law saying
that's not really your data
and the way that we encourage
our clients and our customers and others
from whom we collect that data to trust us
so they will continue to hand us the keys
to the very fast car.
Thank you very much.