- Thank you so much
everybody for being here
for my session on why resilience
has become a cybersecurity superpower.
I'm Lisa Young, I'll be your
host for this talk today.
And I was invited here because of my role
as an I.S.C2 Board Member.
I serve on the Board of
Directors for I.S.C2.
And I also work for company,
I'm vice president of
cyber risk engineering
for a company called Axiom.
But I wanna make sure that you know
is that the opinions in
this presentation are my own
neither those of my employer or I.S.C2,
so thank you again for being here.
Okay, so hold on a second
let's get the controls, right?
All right, everybody, so this is me.
So I'm not gonna spend a
lot of time on this slide.
I just want you to know that
I am quantitative risk
data-driven problem solver.
And I believe that cyber risk
management is a team sport.
So everything that I talk
about today is gonna be
how do we make our team stronger?
How do we build our muscle?
How do we make sure that, you know,
we bring fresh ideas and fresh talent
to the cybersecurity workforce
and to our talent pool.
The slides for this
presentation will be available
and what that means is
that I've put in some links
and some other things, some search quotes
and some things on this slide,
I've put in my LinkedIn email
and the purpose there is for
you to get in touch with me.
I do interact a lot with the community
and I wanna make sure that
if there's something that
I've said that's not clear
or you wanna know something about,
please by all means reach out to me.
All right, let me start first
with a couple of definitions.
And I believe this is
important because cyber,
the word cyber is an adjective, right?
And so it modifies the word
that, you know, follows it.
And it gives more specific information
about the thing you're talking about.
So cybersecurity, cybercrime,
cyber risk, cyber
resilience, cyber threat,
so we use the word cyber a lot.
But what I wanna put it in the context of
is all of our relating to
computers, information technology,
any kind of digital communications.
And risk just as a term
means exposure to danger,
harm or loss.
Risk may or may not materialize.
And when you put those
two things together,
typically cyber as the
modifier in front of risk,
means that it's unauthorized
access or unauthorized use
or there's some other nefarious elements.
So I just wanna set that up.
But the reason I start
there is because cyber is,
I always like to enrich
the definition of cyber
to cyber-physical.
And the reason I do this is
that cyber-physical and digital,
because we live in a digital world.
Even though digital meaning non tangible
is connected to our physical world.
So this notion of cyber-physical, okay?
Is very important of from a
building your cyber muscles,
building your superpower
in risk management,
building your resilience superpowers.
And I put a little reminder
on the bottom of this slide,
everything that is in
our digital world today
is based on the O.S.I model.
So the O.S.I model is the Open
Systems Interconnection model
and it's the basis for
all digital communication.
I'm not gonna talk about
it in this presentation
but if you wanna think about
anything related to digital,
digital communications, our
connectivity, cyber-physical,
it really is about the O.S.I model
and it's the basis for
all digital communication
whether that communication
is authorized or not, okay?
And this slide just sort
of builds it out further
and makes it more real, right?
So when we think about hardware, software.
The connectivity between
hardware and software
our smartphones, our smart
home, our manufacturing,
healthcare, transportation,
our cars, right?
I mean our cars talking to one another,
our cars talking to tollbooths,
our cars talking to,
you know, this notion of
cyber-physical systems
in our digital world.
Sometimes you hear the terms,
I.o.T, internet of things.
Sometimes you hear
electronic control units,
printed control boards.
All of those things are about
the cyber-physical world,
and there's a lot of
untapped, both connectivity
and complexity in what we do today.
So one thing I'll mention is
that if you have any questions
by all means, put them in the chat window.
I'm gonna try to remind you
as we go through this presentation,
that as you think of things
or you just want something answered,
please do put them in the chat window.
So my personal sort of sense
here is that, you know,
I'd like to set the context for cyber risk
and I'd like us to think
about cyber-physical
digital world and taking
ecosystem view, okay?
That notion of conditions and consequences
and I'll talk more about that.
And I really do believe that
all roads lead to risks,
but I don't believe
everything is a risk, okay?
So I realize this is a
little bit of a busy picture,
so I'm gonna spend a little time on it
because I think it really
is the basis for moving
from a sort of a mental model
of cyber as a technology problem
or cyber as a limited scope problem
and expanding the view to risk management
and then getting to the
resilience sort of mindset.
So starting from the left,
let's talk about services and products.
Every organization, whether
it's public, private,
government, military,
for profit, non-profit,
whatever kind of organization
that you find yourself operating in,
it delivers a service or product
meaning it exists to serve some mission
or deliver a service or deliver a product.
And within the context of that
business or that enterprise,
or that organization, again
for money, for non-profit,
doesn't make any difference.
You do activities.
Now in this slide, I've labeled
those productive activities
or business processes.
Some organizations call them projects,
some call them functions,
some call them initiatives.
There's a lot of
different words to be used
to describe the things that
we do to deliver the services
and products to our
constituents, our customers.
And those products and
services use assets, right?
So in this diagram, the
things in the middle
are the people assets, people as an asset,
people to deliver the service or product,
people's brains to think
it up, information assets,
technology assets, facility assets.
That's where the service
or product is performed
or delivered or transported or stored.
Supply chain.
Third-party risk management.
Supply chain could be partners
who help you do part of the
service or product delivery,
or they could be the supply chain,
they could be the raw
materials that you use
in the delivery of your product.
And the examples on the bottom right,
but all of those productive activities,
business processes and
functions use assets
for the purpose of delivering
the organizational mission.
And what we do as security professionals
is we do a lot of the activities
that are in the bottom right.
And I call those in this diagram
I call them risk
management processes, okay?
You could call them cyber
risk management processes.
You could call them what they
are, application security,
you know, access management,
identity and access management,
all kinds third party risk management.
A lot of the activities
that we do in this domain
are designed to keep the
assets in their intended state
so that they can continue to deliver
the products and services, okay?
Now risk management, okay?
Risk management, so thinking about moving
from a controls based
sort of management of risk
to a uncertainty based or a
forward-looking view of risk.
Every time you hear the word risk,
you should think about uncertainty.
And risk management is the ongoing process
of adopting some kind
of a holistic approach.
And the reason why I'm so
keen on moving from cyber
to cyber risk to risk to resilience
is because we do need
to take a more holistic
and multidisciplinary approach
to solve some of our problems.
The reason why the theme
this year is resilience
is because it is an all
encompassing sort of mental model
about how do we get to
a place of being able
to keep our knees bent
and make sure that we're proactive, okay?
So this notion of establishing
a repeatable process
to minimize and mitigate loss
is the definition of risk management.
Now drilling down a little bit,
this notion of risk assessment
is often the shortcut term
that we use.
We call everything a risk assessment,
a risk and control self-assessment
or a risk and a risk
assessment, a gap assessment,
a compliance assessment, a risk, you know,
we use the term risk assessment a lot.
But let me just ask you to back up
and say risk identification I
think is equally as important
as risk assessment, okay?
And risk assessment is usually comprised
of the functions of identify,
analyze, and manage.
So risk assessment is
often a term that we use
to mean risk identification,
risk analysis,
or, you know, risk
management, risk response,
risk treatment.
What I wanna say here is I
believe that risk identification
is one of the most important
sort of superpowers
that you can develop,
that you may not be actively doing today.
You may be doing a risk
and control self-assessment
or a control self-assessment.
But what I'm gonna say
is risk identification
is about looking at the conditions.
The tips and tricks for doing
some of these techniques
are in the boxes on the
bottom right of this slide.
So for identification, you
might look at that R.C.S.A
as a risk and control self-assessment.
You may also do interviews,
you may also ask people what
they're concerned about.
You may also do some brainstorming
or tabletop exercises
to identify what people are concerned.
These are the conditions that
people are concerned about.
Conditions are things like
threats, vulnerabilities,
areas of weakness, insider
threat might be a condition.
And a lot of times we
spend time on understanding
what is the probability of
some threat materializing
or what we might also
wanna take a look at is
how susceptible are we.
How susceptible are we
in our organizations
to some weakness, okay?
So there's that uncertainty factor.
And then the other side of the equation
for risk identification and assessment
is this notion of consequence or impact.
And consequence or impact
is what the organization
would feel, what would happen.
And I'm gonna go through
some specific examples here.
I just wanna set the stage that
if you're not doing a
thorough risk identification
before you do some analysis,
you might learn some things.
Okay, so this notion of the risk ecosystem
I do believe we should
take an ecosystem view
because many things in our environments
and our external environments
are connected, right?
So the risk ecosystem, I'm gonna talk
start at the top left here
on the vulnerability management process.
And generally speaking,
and I am generalizing
'cause I know there's a
broad and wide audience
for this talk.
But generally it's around
day-to-day patching,
release management, issue
management, problem management.
You know, there's a lot of
different things it's called,
but it's about making sure it's an input
to the risk management process.
It is a process on its own
and you do need to manage your
vulnerability process well,
however, it also should feed the risk
or issue management process.
Same thing with threat hunting.
When you think of threat
hunting, threat modeling,
if you're a cyber threat intel analyst,
you know, many of the activities
that you do are inputs
to the risk analysis or the
risk management process, right?
And understanding the specific
threats are more valuable
if you have a process for
getting the information
to the people who can actually
do something about it, right?
So it's not sufficient
just to hunt for threats,
unless there's an intake process
by which those can be prioritized, sorted,
compared against other risks
and threats in the environment,
other vulnerabilities to
which you might be susceptible
and then decide a
prioritize course of action
because we know that we can't
fix everything all the time.
And then on the bottom right
we've got this notion of
controls management, right?
So putting all of these
things in the context
so they can be prioritized,
it's not just finding a gap
or finding a vulnerability
or finding a threat
and then going straight to the action.
It's actually using some kind of criteria
whether that's risk
appetite or risk tolerance
or using some kind of risk taxonomy
to make sure that you've done a thorough
and complete identification
of all the things
that you're susceptible to.
And looking at these things
in the context of the
business and mission.
And also there's this notion
of which of these things
are in our control, meaning
which of these we can plan,
do check at and take some action on,
and which of them are
outside of our control
and how can we build our
preparedness muscles, right?
To make sure that we can
do something about them
should they materialize as an incident
or a realized risk, okay?
So again, I'm gonna ask you
if you have any questions
about what I've just said
to please do put this in the chat window.
I know this is a lot to throw at you
and it's a lot of moving
parts, not just only focused.
So we've set the stage now for
risk being about uncertainty.
That's why this notion of
looking forward, emerging things,
things on the horizon
are all part of the risk equation, okay?
As our threat intel, as our
vulnerability management,
as our other things that we know.
Now we have a more complete
picture of the ecosystem.
I'd like to move to the
topic of resilience, okay?
And moving from risk to resilience
is about building your
capabilities and your muscle.
But let me start first by
describing what resilience is
and what it might mean and some analogies
to help you think about this.
So resilience is an emergent property.
And what that means is
you don't buy resilience.
Now, let me just stop here for a second
and I'm gonna come to
this in the next slide
but I just wanna say this here
because we haven't gotten to it yet
and you can't see my slides yet.
In the business continuity
and disaster recovery world,
the word resilience is often
a synonym or a substitute
or you know, a synonym
for business continuity
or disaster recovery.
When I say resilience, I
mean much more of preparatory
as well as after something has happened.
So I mean more like a slinky.
So this little diagram in the beginning
in the middle of my
picture here is a slinky.
And normally I have a slinky on my desk
to help me with risk but today I don't.
I do have a Magic 8-Ball
but I don't have a slinky today.
But what the slinky reminds me is that
we need to be flexible and be resilient.
So I don't mean resilience
in the business continuity
disaster recovery,
I'll say more about that in a minute.
But resilience is a property.
And we take our definition,
I take my definition
from the physical sciences world, right?
It's about ebbing and
flowing, bouncing back.
And it's about when you
think about building
your resilience muscles, right?
So building a resilience capability.
It's about what I said before,
understanding the connection
from the business,
strategy objectives,
what I wanna accomplish,
who I wanna serve.
What are the risks that could
keep me from doing that?
Keep me from meeting my strategy,
keep me from meeting my objectives.
And then how do I adapt?
Because sometimes the
risks that are realized
or the incidents that occur are uneven.
They're not either, or they're not binary.
There's different situations,
changing conditions,
different kinds of disruptions.
And so this notion of being resilient
means that you can be like a slinky
and be a little more adaptable, right?
And so what are some other ways.
The analogy that I like to use
for resilience is health, okay?
You don't go to the store
and buy a bottle of health.
You become healthy, health
emerges when you eat well,
sleep well, take care
of yourself, exercise,
get regular checkups.
In the cyber world or the risk world,
the cyber risk world moving
from risk to resilience
means you plan for something.
You can't plan for everything
so you have to be adaptable.
You make sure you check
and you don't just check
once a year or once a quarter
or once every so often, you
plan, you check, you do you act
in a repeat wash, rinse,
repeat over and over, right?
So you understand your
connection between your mission
and your services and the critical assets.
You understand, you know,
you've identified your critical suppliers.
You do a robust job of
identifying all the risks
that your or type of
organization might be subject to
and things that you
haven't even thought of.
You do some scenario
analysis and planning.
You do coordinated management of things.
So maybe your vulnerability
management is coordinated
with your incident response.
So for example, you do
some root cause analysis
on your incidents.
And you look at all the
root causes of the incidents
that have occurred over a period of time
and you say, which of those indicate
that we need a better
vulnerability management process,
a quicker vulnerability
management process.
And I'm using that because
it's a very concrete example
but many of the root causes of incidents
are caused from vulnerabilities
that have a solution, right?
So where do we wanna put our resources
instead of looking at threats.
And I think threats are important
but where do we wanna put our next dollar?
Is it to shore up something
that continues to happen over and over?
You wanna make sure that your management
and deployment of people is robust
and that you're putting them
on the highest priority
problems based on risk, right?
That's a resilience superpower.
Also management of external partners.
You know, do you have really
robust and good criteria
for understanding the
value that the partner
or a particular product provides
in the ultimate delivery
of your mission, okay?
Okay, so as I said before,
the traditional business
continuity and disaster recovery
is a very important part of resilience,
but it's not all of resilience.
What I'm talking about is operational
and organizational resilience.
It's really about that
multidisciplinary approach
where you prepare, well, let me back up.
Before you prepare, you
anticipate, anticipation is done
through the notion of
the anticipation is done through
good robust risk identification.
What scenarios would impact us and how?
Then you prepare for those
knowing that you can't
prepare for everything,
then you adapt if something
happens or changes,
and then you withstand,
recover and get back to business as usual
as much as possible, okay?
So in this diagram, which you've
seen before on the bottom,
I changed those risk management processes
to resilience management.
It's like a continuum,
the better you get at risk management,
the more resilience
muscle you actually build.
Okay, so now that I've
got that out of the way,
I'm gonna give you an example
of the resilience ecosystem landscape.
This is from a top down view
rather than a left to right.
So on the top are threat to
exposures events conditions,
in the middle are your products
and services and assets,
on the bottom of your business,
are resilience processes, okay?
And in this particular example,
you see in the lighter colored box,
the cyber attack in this
case renders the technology
and information assets unavailable.
You may not know the reason
why, maybe it's ransomware.
In this case, it might
be terrorism or crime
might be the motive, but
you don't know that yet.
But all of a sudden you need
to take a holistic approach
for your business continuity,
disaster recovery,
knowledge and information management,
situational awareness,
incident management.
So your resilience processes
have to be unified, okay?
All right, so I'm gonna say any questions.
I know that was a lot,
but any questions here?
So let's talk about
building a resilience
superpower capability, okay?
So when faced with many of
these dynamic challenges,
the most successful cybersecurity programs
engage a diverse and holistic approach.
So, you know, there's a
clear lack of diversity
in its forms within the
cybersecurity profession,
both racial, gender, thought leadership,
all kinds of reasons,
but we need to engage
multidisciplinary teams.
And earlier this year,
I.S.C2 formed its first
global diversity equity
and inclusion task force to support that,
to advance meaningful
progress in this space.
So let's talk about why
that's really important.
Who are cybersecurity professionals today?
Well, they're largely millennials
which means they're between
mid 20's to mid 40's
and 72% of them are male, okay?
So in the United States, now remember
there are several research papers
that I.S.C2 has done in this space.
In the United States, and it
is a little bit U.S centric
although we're expanding
our research globally,
cyber racial diversity is closer to parody
than gender diversity, okay?
And this is a big deal because
this notion of inclusion,
we need to make sure that we
include different thoughts,
different viewpoints, different,
you know, just really a multicultural
and also multi-disciplinary
approach, okay?
So it's not just gender and
racial but it's also education.
In the U.S, in most occupations
about half of the workforce is female.
But in the U.S, only one in
four computer occupations
are held by women and only
one in five of those in cyber
are held by women.
So let's talk about the gap in
cybersecurity as a workforce.
Globally, it's 3.12 million
people that we should
and could and can hire as
we grow to build our muscles
in risk and resilience.
You know, Asia Pacific probably
has the largest gap, okay?
But in the United States and
I'm sorry, in North America,
we have nearly 400,000
open unfilled roles, okay?
So let's talk about the top
10 technical hero skills
and then I'm gonna give you
some additional superpowers
that have nothing or little
to do with technology.
So, first one, Cloud security.
You know, we know a lot about you know,
Cloud is a hot topic right now
because people are looking
for concentrated expertise.
Many of you may have heard
the saying a few years back
from Wendy Nader on
the cyber poverty line.
Organizations that are smaller
or don't have resources
to do some of the things
that I've described to
build their superpower,
their resilience muscle might
want to look at Cloud, okay?
Some others are data analysis, right?
Malware analysis, coding, and programming.
These are all still important skills.
Intrusion detection, access management,
administration, control design.
Okay, one of the underserved markets
I think is risk analysis, risk assessment,
risk management, risk identification.
And that's the number one sort
of both on the technical list
and the non-technical list
that people say is needed in this field.
And risk management, cyber risk especially
requires a multidisciplinary approach.
But let's talk about the
non-technical superpowers, right?
What I call the secret
resilience superpowers.
Okay, so analytical
thinking, critical thinking,
problem solving, you know,
this notion of creativity.
These are all things that it takes
to solve these thorny
problems that we have, okay?
The ideal model, this is a graphic
about how to solve problems.
There actually really is an
I.D.E.A.L model I-D-E-A-L
if you look it up.
Identify the problem, define the problem,
explore the problem, action the problem.
They use look back in this graphic.
I actually prefer learn.
I think we should fail
first, learn something
and move on to the next thing, okay?
And then, you know,
ability to work on a team.
This is not a solo, this is a team sport.
There's one more to
this list that I'll add.
And for those especially in the millennial
or younger cohort, and that is
sleep, you need to make sure
that you get plenty of sleep
as an emergent property
of taking care of your
health to be more resilient.
Okay, so tips for recruiting
and retaining diverse teams.
Consider upskilling or reskilling staff
that works in your organization.
Hire for attitude and aptitude.
I personally believe
that security principles
and engineering principles
and a lot of these skills
can be taught if you hire people
that wanna be on the team, right?
Invest in training, make
sure that people understand.
Assign a buddy or a mentor.
And I'll cover a few of these in depth,
but you know, professionals
are more successful
if they have a mentor or
people they can talk with
about problems in the space, right?
You know, recognition builds confidence.
When I said fail first,
what I mean is give somebody a hypothesis,
give a team a challenge problem.
I mean, we do this when we have off sites,
you know, one of the ones, my son is also
when he was in robotics and
in school, in elementary
and middle school, they have challenges,
you know the spaghetti
marshmallow challenge
where you have to build a tall structure
using only spaghetti, uncooked
spaghetti and marshmallows
and maybe some scotch tape.
You know, let's start small
and tackle some of the big problems
by learning how to fail quickly, fail fast
and learn from that
using the I.D.E.A.L model
and then keep on going, right?
Okay.
Professional development.
You know professional development
isn't just training and certifications.
And I know that seems odd
from a person who sits
on the I.S.C2 Board.
I believe in certifications,
I have my own and I maintain them
and I pay out of my own pocket
every year to maintain them
and get the continuing
education that's needed.
Because I believe
that it's important to
continue to develop yourself.
But one of the strategies
that employers could use
is to entice people with
professional development, right?
Make sure you're addressing their needs.
Make sure you don't keep them in a role
if they want to do something else
that you rotate people around
so that you can create a different lens
that people are looking
through and looking at
when they're facing
these challenges, right?
Okay, next one is,
okay, stop waiting for unicorns.
I know, I know.
But wait, I gotta show you this
because this is my favorite right here.
I happen to like unicorns.
However, I will say to you,
stop looking for unicorns.
Hire for attitude, hire for aptitude.
You know, there are many
myths in cybersecurity.
One of those is that you have
to have a four year degree.
That is a myth, okay?
It's just not true, but often
it's a barrier to entry, okay?
Some of the job descriptions,
you know, are not realistic.
You need to look past sort of titles
and hire for attitude
and hire for aptitude.
Broaden the net.
Look for people who are in other fields,
teachers, veterans
who are transitioning to
the civilian community,
liberal arts grads.
There are so many other communities
that could bring something to
the traditionally millennial,
you know, male dominated field.
Also, if you know,
many qualified recruits
have digital experience.
And the reason I say this is
think about electronic music
or digital music.
You know, many of the people
in many of the creative arts
now are using digital tools
and digital software, and
they have a lot of skills
that could also be used
in this field, right?
Okay, add creativity to recruiting.
Yes, by all means go after
recent grads, go after people.
But look at people who are
consultants or contractors.
You know, I like the gig economy
because I like sort of being
able to purchase and buy.
I've also worked in the gig economy
and I like being able to have
the schedule flexibility.
So if someone's a
consultant or a contractor
and doesn't wanna work full time,
it doesn't mean you can't
use their skills, right?
Other departments within
your organization,
other companies in the same industry,
same skills different industry, right?
Hardware, security vendors,
and career changers.
You know, many people,
especially over the last year
have taken stock in their
own careers, their own lives,
and decided they wanna
do something differently.
So give them a chance if
they have the right attitude
and the right aptitude and
they're willing to learn,
invest in them, right?
And if 2020 has shown us anything,
it's that the talent pool
can virtually work from anywhere, right?
There are some jobs that
do require in person,
but this widens the net for you.
You no longer have to
look in your backyard,
you can actually look broader than that.
All right, so I'm at my last
slide, next to the last slide,
which is, you know,
let's talk about what you
could do next week, next month
and in three months.
If you have critical open
positions in your organization,
can you collaborate
with the hiring manager
especially if you know, a
little bit about the job,
especially if you know a
little bit about, you know,
what the requirements are
that may not be obvious
from reading the job description.
Put the word out on social media,
put the word out to people
who you want to work with
who are in your network.
Volunteer to be a mentor to
a new person in cybersecurity
if they're not from a traditional
cybersecurity background.
And also seek out a
mentor yourself, you know,
I have three mentees at the moment,
but I also get mentoring myself
even at the stage of my career
because I think it's so important
to continuously bring a new
and fresh perspective to cyber.
Next month, maybe you could offer
to test your speaking skills
by arranging a lunch and learn
in discussing or collaborating,
or start a book club,
you know, and read some of the old sort of
what do we call them, the
classics of cybersecurity, right?
And take an inventory of your own skills
and look where you
might add some new ones.
And then in three months
you could research,
enroll perhaps in a certificate
or a technical program,
or just take some classes
that will broaden your own perspective
especially if you've been in
the field of cybersecurity
for a really long time.
Okay, so I know you've asked
questions along the way
and I appreciate that
and you can ask some more
questions now, should you wish to.
My LinkedIn profile is here.
There are other links in this presentation
that are ways to reach
out to me, to contact me.
And I'd like to say, thank
you for your attention
and thank you for your time.
And I hope I've convinced you
that building your muscles
in risk and resilience
is the way to develop superpowers.
So thank you very much.