(upbeat music)
- Hi, I'm Rob Lefferts,
Corporate Vice-President
for Microsoft 365 Security.
I help build the products
and services that we deliver to secure
all of our customers and organizations.
- And I'm Bret Arsenault,
Corporate Vice-President,
Chief Information Security
Officer for Microsoft.
Essentially I protect
the Microsoft digital
assets as well as I'm responsible
for crisis response and
business continuity.
- So today we're going to
have a conversation when
those two sides of the coin
back and forth dialogue,
you as the consumer of
products and services,
and me representing the product
teams that help build those.
Just up front I got to say,
I feel very fortunate to have
your feedback, your guidance.
I think of you as the
first and best customer
whenever we have a crazy
idea, we like to run
across the hallway down the street
and make sure that we get the feedback
from you and your team about
how that's going to work.
And I think there's two
main topics we want to delve
into the first of those about
Zero Trust and how we think
about that philosophy
and approach to security.
And the second about the
crazy world we live in
and how COVID has impacted
the way people work
and how that changes
the world of security.
And what did that look
like as we come back
and then finally wrap up a
little bit of recommendations
go dues that folks can take away
with it with themselves as they go on.
So first supply chain,
the crazy news stories of the past year.
So as Microsoft CSO, I
love to hear what you think
how it's changed your approach
to security and how you think
about how to make sure you
protect Microsoft's data
and our customers' data.
- Yeah, no, that'd be great.
And first, thanks for coming
and hanging out with me here.
Obviously we spent time a lot together
design and review and feedback
and the things we need.
I think the supply chain
thing, like you said,
we've been monitoring it for a while
and it's evolved much like just
box product vulnerabilities had evolved
and how we think about it.
But at the end of the day
it doesn't change our fundamental goal
which is to protect our assets
our customer's data, and make sure we have
resilient systems that
people can count on.
And so I think for us,
this is really reinforcing to a strategy
we started on about a
little over four years ago
which was called Zero Trust.
And the idea with Zero Trust really is,
it started it wasn't just related
to supply chain, but it benefited from it
which was just this
assumed breach position.
Just assume that you've
already been breached
and what are you to do.
And that's that protect,
detect and respond.
And for us, we really simplified it
'cause I think the industry
and vendors and suppliers
third-party ourselves as well,
this is just our internal
view of how we define it.
So we simplified it down to,
it's gotta be about healthy device,
strong identity and persistent telemetry.
Which I ask every one of
my vendors to make sure
they show you how they
can make that happen.
And so this has really resulted
in this Zero Trust or bust
you know no exceptions model
that we have across the entire company
which we hold everyone accountable to.
And so I'm really fortunate
to be able to influence
and share my perspectives on what that is
and what we need from the
products to make sure we
can meet those requirements.
So I think the feedback
loop is amazing though,
it's great 'cause we
get to work on design.
Then we get to work under the deploy
and then does it work in use?
And so, you know
our goal is just to continue
automating this work
and reduce the dependencies
that we have on third parties.
I think most of my peers
in the industry are really big on this.
Can we do reduction of
suppliers just because
of the reduction in entropy, right?
The more sophisticated or
more complex the system is
the easier it is to find seams.
And so you get economies of scale
and a bunch of other components
that are part of that.
- Sure.
- So as I said, my CSOs are similar.
I've had a call with
them today and you know
it's a reduction and of a supplier
and continue to drive
this Zero Trust mentality.
So from you from the product side
and I'll put you in the hot seat.
- Alright.
- So tell me what have
you done for me lately?
What are you doing for me on Zero Trust?
- Well so actually I
really love that model
about complexity and thinking
about how the organizations
can manage complexity.
The first thing that we like
to think about is making sure
that we do get as broad a view
as possible, and really think
about the end-to-end approach,
make sure that we work
with you about what is that
going to look like because
it's been this ongoing trend
of increasing complexity
and increasing sophistication
in the threat landscape.
And so the part that has gone along
with that in the security industry
is increasing complexity of the tools.
And what we have really pushed on
to try to do is help unify
all of those tools together
so that we can help you have a sort
of a more coherent view
about what's going on
in the estate across identity
and devices and end users,
all of those elements that
you were talking about
for Zero Trust and bring it
together in a single umbrella.
And then the second thing,
and this really is where
it pays off to sit closely
with your customers and listen to them,
is thinking about how
do we protect everything
that you care about?
When we started this journey a decade ago,
we were very focused on
Microsoft products and services.
How do we protect Windows?
And you made it very clear that in fact
Microsoft has one of the
biggest Mac Estates out there,
and that we had to think about everything
in your environment
and how we tie that together
across multi-platforms
like Mac and Windows, multiple
clouds working together
and how our tools XDR and SIM,
which are Microsoft Defender
and Azure Sentinel working together.
And then finally the,
perhaps the most important it
part is bringing some humility
to the table and a real eagerness to learn
from you and from our other customers
about what are the most valuable things
that we need to do in order to
solve your security problems
and to really help.
So let me actually turn it back over.
What's your, what advice would you give,
to customers and partners
listening to this
on what they should go
do first and foremost?
- I think really when I
think about this one is,
everything that we build is
your point about simplifying
and getting an end to end
view is super important.
When I go back to this device
identity and telemetry,
we really care about the telemetry
for one thing that's
super important is just
driving what the experience
is for the users.
And so we really have to really work
on the things like it's amazing to me.
I see, I guess my biggest piece of advice,
I see perfection get
in the way of progress
with so many people.
And so when we started
on this two FA journey
like multi-factor authentication
or two factor authentication
a long time ago.
You know, we kept looking
at the perfect system
and then we tried to make it all software.
And some finally, you know
working with the Hello for Business team,
we got to this idea where we would just do
the facial recognition
and then expanded into other forms
of two factor authentication.
But the idea was, you know,
as opposed to smart cards
and all these things that
made it really secure
but allows a user experience,
we wanted a great user
experience that was also secure
and having all the telemetry to tell us
whether it was working or wasn't working.
And so I'm amazed at how
many people, you know
like would get hung up
on not doing any two FA
until they could have a
hundred percent two FA.
And so getting on that path
of working through that was super helpful.
And, you know, we did start
with Windows Hello for Business
and then we used Authenticator to go
to the Mac and all the other non platforms
and worked with industry standards.
But we got to this model
where we had the telemetry
where users actually, the idea is
that users love it in the it
department actually trust it.
If I can get to that for everything we do,
then I feel really, really good about it.
- Yeah. Actually I think
back to some of the stories,
I think I've heard from you
about the employee feedback
on the early versions of two
FA systems with smart cards
and their experiences
of trying to use those.
- Yeah well I think we were the classic
hammer and nail scenario.
Like we had the cards like
everybody thought I said,
"Oh, let's make it software.
We'll just implement it
in the computer itself."
As opposed to stepping
back and saying, you know
really this is idea being
envisioned led as opposed to,
"Oh, two FA's really good
for high privilege accounts.
Let's just make two FA everywhere."
I would literally see people recoil
when we'd say two FA everywhere.
As opposed to, what if I changed
it to eliminate passwords.
'Cause eliminate passwords, every user,
I think it's the only time in execratory
they've ever gotten an applause.
It's like when we eliminate passwords
we're driving to the same set of goals
but how you get there
so radically different.
And so this idea of eliminating
passwords is super important
and that was really that third leg
of the stool around ensuring
we have all the telemetry
so that we can get feedback
real-time from our users.
Is it working?
Is it not use?
Is it not working?
And not just count on
customer satisfaction surveys
but actually real telemetry to tell us
whether we're doing
the right things or not
was super important. And the
other one, I think that's one
of the things most customers ask me is,
how did you turn on device health?
And how did you turn on, you know
two FA without an uprising
from your employees?
And there's some percentage
that are always gonna do,
you know, it's I fear change
and whatever it might be.
But I think when we gave
people a choice, when we said,
yes you have to have,
you don't have a choice
and you have to have a
healthy device to connect
to the environment.
That doesn't mean I have to provide it.
If you want to bring your own device,
that's fine we can manage that.
If you want to use a home PC
but you don't want us to manage it,
that's fine too, we'll give
you a virtualized experience.
So I get a healthy device
because it's all virtualized.
And so our users have a
lot of different choices
between mobile non-Windows, et
cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
And so, you know, having the telemetry
and this concept of digital empathy,
providing users choice, and
again, making that thing
in the back of your
head, you got to do both.
You got to have the people who love it.
And IT department said trust it.
- Not that there's any
spirit of competition
between the product teams,
but let me ask you this
important question,
as our closest and perhaps
most demanding customer,
what do you think is your best dollar
spent on security tools
or maybe differently
if you had a tight restricted budget,
where would you spend it for?
- Which I do.
- Which you do.
- That's because you
keep taking my budget.
So, no, I'm just teasing.
- Why do you say that's
definitely not true.
- Definitely not true I get it.
Well, I think it, I think I'd break down
the problem a little bit
into the three areas that
I actually spend money on.
And so I look at commercial
off the shelf products
that are provided by suppliers
such as you across Microsoft,
even outside of Microsoft.
Then I look at the things
that I build custom
'cause they either don't meet
my needs or they don't exist.
And then I look at one of the biggest
investment areas is talent.
And they're sort of in interplay,
when you say what's the best dollar spent
is what lets me be most
leveraged across all of that.
- Sure.
- Right?
And I will say, if I was
to ask my team, which I do,
I pool my team on,
where do you think we did the
best with spending our money?
And you know, where could
we have done better?
And what are we thinking about next year?
Right now the secure operation center
on the team would tell me
that the Windows Defender is
by far the best investment
in the dollars that we spent so far.
I'm not saying that just
'cause you're interviewing me,
you know, I've said
this in front of our CEO
and others and customers before.
Because it does help me unify
was a complex environment
where I had over six solutions
and now I'm down to, they'll
be down to one this year
where we have an amazing
set of capabilities,
an amazing set of visibility
across the environment
that I didn't have before,
but it also lets me retire
some custom stuff I had to go, right.
That was amazing technology
that now is just commoditized.
And, you know, because we can amortize it
across the entire customer base.
And then lastly, and
probably most importantly,
all that means that it's not having
to train people on five systems.
And it means people who
are being more effective
and more efficient every day.
And it means people who are happier
because the jobs and
the work they're doing
or the value add part of the thing
versus some of the other
things they were doing before.
So when I look at, you know, simplicity
and then view better use of
people's time and resource
happier employees and less custom code
that I have to maintain for a long time,
yeah by far it's been the best solution
that we've prior for the last two years.
You have some hot competition though
from the Sentinel team,
but I'm just telling you
you're doing a great job.
- Well, I admire that team
and what they're building.
And so I am gratified, but
I do like the way you put it
this idea about like freeing up the team
so they can focus on more strategic issues
and making sure that we're giving them
as useful tools as possible.
As I do have to ask you to
put a dollar in the tip jar
'cause you said Windows Defender.
And in our series of rebranding,
we're up to Microsoft Defenders.
- It's terrible.
I don't know that,
I don't understand all the branding stuff.
- I made a promise that I
won't change the product names
for at least another 12 months.
So really we're locked in.
- Fantastic. I'm sorry.
- No worries.
So as I think back over the past year
with the sudden change
in how everybody worked,
it was really interesting to watch that
for a number of companies
that were further ahead
on that Zero Trust journey, they were
it was an easier transition
because they were already
in that mindset of like,
Oh, all of my employees
might be running around
on the internet anyway and
I'll just act like that.
As we're starting to think
now about people coming back,
I'm sure that it'll be
a little bit different
because some people will
come all the way back fast
and then some will want to
work in a different way.
But what do you think the future
of work will look like that environment?
And how do you think about securing that?
- Yeah, I think we, I mentioned
that we did a lot of the COVID response.
So sending people away
from their work environment
when we did shelter-in-place
and those things was pretty
rapidly over 72 hours
you go from 10% on premise
or 10% remote workforce,
to 97% remote.
Like I would look at the badge
ins by building every day,
you know, and I would start
with as well in this scenario
I do have great sympathy,
both sympathy and empathy.
Like we were very lucky
in the tech industry to
be able to continue to
work through most of that.
And many people have seen
and we've been fairly
productive through that process.
And then, you know, you
look at service industries
and transportation
industries and not everybody,
it wasn't an equitable impact financially.
And so whatever we can do to
help those things be better
and be more effective,
I think we, you know, we need
to continue to work on that.
I do think, as you mentioned
if you're already on a
digital transformation
you'd largely made your work more digital,
it was much easier to, you know
make that transition to remote work.
And if you did it in a way
that incorporated Zero Trust,
where you again,
you don't think of the network
as ineffective control plane
you think of identity as a perimeter
and device health is the key to it.
And then collecting telemetry all the time
for both user experience
and anomaly detection
it wasn't a massive transition.
Like I mentioned
10% remote workforce to
97% remote workforce.
The biggest complaint
I heard from customers
with their VPNs are getting hammered.
Back to our point on patch
Tuesday in particular.
And so, and for us that
wasn't the case like we had,
I can't remember exactly what it was
but it's less than, I know it was less
than 5% increase in VPN
capacity was required
because we already were doing that.
And as people, you know
will return it'll be interesting.
It's a lot more work, the
return to work at their stages
and there's, and well,
because sending you home
you are responsible for what
you had to do in your home.
But when we bring people
back into the workplace
now you have to have, you
know, social distancing,
the sanitary environments
and all these other things that
you didn't have to plan for.
- I hadn't even thought about it.
- Yeah it's much much more work,
much more work and switching
and changing offices
and using technology to go
do that and ensuring that
you don't have four people sitting
in the same office when they come in.
And so there's a lot of
things to use technology for.
And there's also a lot of examples
where we want to make sure
and maintain the security
and privacy of everybody in that scenario.
Like even the question today,
did you get a vaccination yet?
And they said, how did you get it?
That's really a very encroaching question
to ask somebody that, right?
'Cause you could have helped
me, whatever it might be.
You could be asking age.
So it's really a very different
workplace to come back to.
But I think from a
technology perspective, again
if you think of the devices,
I think people get confused.
Like I hear this all the time.
Oh, it's such an easy job
being the CSO at Microsoft.
- Who said really?
- Sasha always tells me that.
Nobody says no, but I
mean, it's the, you know
you just have to protect Windows.
- Right.
- And it's like we just
have to make, you know
Microsoft Defender for
Windows, but it's not right?
- Piece of cake.
- Yeah, exactly.
And so, you know, we
run, I think last time
I looked there was like 31
versions of operating systems.
Plus as you know, we have the next version
of operating system for which
all of our third parties
haven't yet tested on.
So I think that, and you know, we run iOS
we run Android, we run Mac
some windows phones still.
And it's, supposed to say that either way.
I mean, but we do have an
amazing diverse environment
that represents both from an end point
but the cloud services we use as well.
And so really I'm just
like any other customer
any other large global enterprise customer
with a mixed environment.
And in the Zero Trust model, you know
shifting that idea that my
control points go to the endpoint
which includes services, devices,
and all the telemetry around those.
And again, the cornerstone being identity
is that new perimeter.
That's really key that we
have to keep doing that.
And so I think that my ability to do that,
in a way that's cost-effective,
in that can continue to utilize
the talent more effectively.
'Cause I'd love to say
I have infinite budget,
but even if I did the
talent, doesn't exist,
with 3.2 million jobs will be
left on open in this space.
And so I, we just don't have
the talent to go do that.
So how do we get technology
to give us better economies
and utilization of the
talent that we have?
That's, those will be the
things that we'll focus
on with anything.
And that is hard.
And for a lot of people
haven't done that switch,
just think about our environment,
10 million endpoints on multiple OSs,
versus network security
which is 9,000 devices,
all operating system agnostic.
- Yeah. That's actually
a huge scale problem.
- It's big yeah, big difference
but so much better fidelity of data
and so much better ability to see things
that you couldn't do before.
- Well, we actually, when
we talk about that strategy,
the not approved marketing phrase for it,
is a big brain in the cloud,
which is essentially this,
Oh we're going to scatter as many sensors
as we can into as many
corners of the environment
like all of those 10 million devices.
And then we're going to get
aggregate all that data together
in one place so that we can run
machine learning around big data.
And then try to give you
a more insightful view
of what's happening
across all of that stuff
even when it's wandering
around outside of the network.
- Well, I think in, and of course
while respecting the
privacy issues around it
but when you can take a global footprint,
you take over, you know,
whatever, how many billions
of authentication we do in
a given day and then the
you know, billion plus
devices that we look at
so we can see that.
And then allow me to take
your global knowledge
and then apply it to my local environment.
That's that's like the win-win for me.
- Yeah. Well, and a big part
of how we hope we can
help your security team
as you were saying earlier,
get onto those strategic tasks
because they get that benefit
of that global perspective
that global view and hopefully
we've helped fix some
of the day-to-day automation stuff.
So that then they also have the time.
- Yeah, no, I think you have,
I think it would be interesting though
when you think about return
for work and that sort of
this is what we're doing for our employees
and things we're doing in the proc
you lay it on a few of the big pieces
but it would be the top
three things you think
about from a product
delivery when you think
of a return to work scenario.
- Well, it is interesting
'cause a bunch of it is this continuity.
So I'll break it up.
There's like things that
are gonna be the same,
things that are going to be different.
And a lot of the strategy that we're on,
as we've been discussing,
the Zero Trust model
really continues forward.
But I think it puts even more emphasis
on this thread we keep pulling at,
which is the security
teams being more efficient.
How can we really make sure
that we help them do their jobs better?
Certainly the big brain in the
cloud is a big part of that,
but really AI to help
them get insights faster,
automation to help them
do the job more quickly.
Any place where we can
automate an investigation
or automate the remediation of something
that happened on an end point is something
that we really want to go after.
There's been a lot of investigation
in the years in security into this notion
of correlation and keep
bringing up telemetry.
If I can find a piece of
data from the identity system
and combine that with something I see
from the end point and see
this user across those devices
something weird happened, then
it can have a real insight.
But what we've learned over the years is
that if you just do that blindly,
you end up with very sparse data
or unnecessary false positives.
And so making it really useful
is actually been this back
and forth with your team,
on are these the insights
that really helped you
and how do we actually
take the investigation
and actually run it more the way you would
so that we can produce insights
that are much more useful?
And then mapped up into the framework
that your team understands,
like the MITRE ATT&CK framework
and using that for
simulations to help drive how
we measure the quality of the tool.
- But I think before, let's
talk about that for a sec
to be a little honest with the crowd here.
So when we first were doing this,
I think I see this even
when we built our own AI
and automation, which is
when you first go do big data
or big brain work
and what you end up
getting is more detections.
- Yeah.
- And what you end up doing
is giving your SOC team,
your security team,
a longer list of work
that they already had,
that they then have to
go vet and find out.
And so then you go, okay
how do I tune it so I get
rid of the false positives?
What's interesting, and this
is like the evolution I've seen
from the products we've done with you,
which is super helpful, is
like I see when people tell me
they're still trying to
turn to no false positives,
that tells me on the maturity curve
they still got a ways to go.
'Cause what's more interesting
is when you get to
benign positives, right?
And so, but that's super important
because once you've, we
got our false positive way
way down now I have
these benign positives.
So that's like the difference
between like, you know
spam versus actually malware, right?
It's kind of that kind of a thing.
And so the idea that you automate the find
then you automate the fix.
That's when we really have it.
- Sure and that's where
we're starting to dig into.
We certainly have that
capability in the product.
It is one of those things
where I've heard this
from you and for this
from other customers.
There's some stuff that
is so clear and obvious
we should just go do it.
Like yes, quarantine that phishing email
just take care of that.
Or the executable that we
thought was appropriate.
And then all of a sudden acted funny.
Yes, just quarantine that and isolate that
take it off the box.
But there are a lot of
operations where we still
want to look for approval
and human interaction
and make sure that we get the
blessing of the security team
that this is the right
security direction to go into.
But you actually, with the
false positive conversation,
I love it because when I
start talking about AI and ML,
I think a lot of security
folks get worried
that there's this vision of, you know,
the machines are going to
solve all of these problems.
Like if we can just make them smart enough
then security will be solved.
And I'm pretty convicted that
that's not where we're going.
That is actually this journey of feedback
from your team to our researchers
around what looks good
and what is most helpful.
And then the big data
machine analytics is actually
this force multiplier on,
hey, the making those turn
into insights you can use
every day rather than...
- Yeah. I think this is where
marketing hasn't helped us.
I think that this idea of
artificial intelligence
if they would always just called
it augmented intelligence,
I had this great great opportunity to work
with Kasparov the chess player,
the first one to play IBM in chess, right?
- Yeah.
- And today the best chess
masters is not computer
to computer or computer against human.
It is human aided by computer.
And that's how I look at the SOC.
I don't want a tier one SOC analyst.
I want that should go
away because no person
enjoys being a tier one.
So they want to be a tier two
or they want to be a Hunter.
And so having augmented
intelligence with all that stuff
that you're doing so that those people
can be much more effective,
that is I think one, it
makes them more happy
and more reassured that it's
not about getting, you know
having everything be
automated because yeah
people aren't comfortable, right?
That's that idea of, turn on audit first
before you turn on enforcement
and it's the same idea with
augmented intelligence.
Then these people can just
be so much more effective.
And there's case after case after case
of all the highest end people,
chess players, formula one
drivers, et cetera, et cetera,
that are, it's always with a
computer aided augmentation
of human skill set
that you get the performance
out of something.
- Sure, and multiple
points of view and go fast.
- I'm sure the world's not going to change
to augmented intelligence,
I just wished we didn't set it that way.
- We'll get marketing to there.
The last thing on this point,
I just want to highlight
refer back to underscore
the thing you said around,
okay, let's when we come
back to the workplace,
let's actually not change our stance
around how these machines operate.
Let's continue to operate in
a mode where the user feels
like they're out on
the internet and where,
in fact we've been able to
contain the connectivity
between those devices
and other things that might
even be more sensitive.
And it seems like that kind of a shift,
is something that we really want to
build tools that help companies do that.
- Well, I think it's a
design goal though, right?
I think it's, from my perspective
if you assume it's internet
or you assume breach,
you design differently.
- Yeah.
- Right?
And I think that, and that's how you get,
you need our employees
to think differently.
You need our staff to design differently.
And the reality is that not
everyone is coming back.
Like some people are going
to continue to work remotely.
I think there's going to be some,
there'll be a couple of things
that I think are interesting
we haven't figured out yet though.
Impossible travel is one
of those common things
you do with data.
And so now we're going to see
a much more diverse time span
of work employee work like
for, you know what I'm saying?
Like, people won't just work
from home in their local town
they may move two hours
or they move more than
your, more to family.
So the idea of what's local, what's not,
that whole premise is
going to break up as far
as you know, how people think
about what home based is.
And that's going to be interesting for us.
- Yeah. I've started to see
that already where it's all
of a sudden the like get
together for a meeting.
The "where are you" becomes a very
interesting opener of the conversation
- Well I've called you.
And you've been, you know, in
Les Bois the Valley of Trees
you're eight hours away by car
but only one hour by time zone,
but it does change, right?
'Cause the meeting's changing.
So when you're figuring,
when you're looking at that
as a behavioral pattern,
is that a normal pattern or not
or what kind of flag does that raise?
So I think that'll be one of the things
that'll be super
interesting for us to go do.
And then I think it'll be
really important that we ensure
how do you make sure those
are still inclusive meetings?
And that mixed modeling,
that's not a security issue
but it's a fundamental concern
I have 'cause I just that's
you don't have happy and
productive workforces
if they don't feel like they're
being included and heard.
So how do you do that in that
all remote is an equalizer.
But 10 people in a room
and four people out,
is a very different
dynamic, as we all know.
So how do we get the great
balance we've learned
and still make it all work, but
that's not a security issue.
That's just me pontificating.
- Well, you know, we're
solving a lot of problems here.
We fixed artificial intelligence,
we got a new way of working.
- Got a new name for
candles are all burning.
It's all good.
- So back to the basics, the
fundamentals, ground people,
key takeaways on things
that they should go do
today to go secure their organizations.
- Yeah. I, you know, I always feel bad
'cause it's so uninspiring when I say it,
as I mentioned before.
The pedestrian like the AI
and all the other stuff is amazing.
And we do massively leverage those things.
But the pedestrian part of
the job, you can't forget.
Like when I look at numbers that less
than 20% of enterprises
have a a hundred percent
multi-factor authentication,
you got to get that done right?
People aren't patching
more than 60% of breaches
are caused by patches that were available
that never got applied.
And so, you know, you still
have to do the basics,
you got to get things patched
and you got to keep them updated.
It's necessary, but not sufficient, right?
And you get to really
think about this idea
and particularly security practitioners
about progress as a path to perfection
not perfection before you make progress.
Like don't hold people there.
- I can just interject there.
- Yeah please.
- I love that.
I always ended up talking to,
when I talked to security teams
and I look at their to-do list
on the basics and the fundamentals.
- Yeah.
- My instantaneous reaction is like,
man you're never going to get done.
The list is too long.
You will just never get
to the end of that list.
And then as a tool builder,
that gets me excited
because it makes me want to help more
on how can I help prioritize that list
and give more insight
about the threat landscape
and build tools that will
give the security teams
the view of all of a sudden
there is something new on the landscapes.
And so we have to shove that issue up
to the top of the list
and take care of it first.
- Yeah. And I do think,
I think even my own
team struggled with that
like when I look up
some of those long lists
when I first came into
this thing, which was,
it's also really important to step back
and ask yourself to your point,
how do you use technology to
automate a lot of this stuff?
Because I always see, I
see the list of requests
for people and everything
else, and they're valid.
But I think it was, one
of the venture people
was always telling me like,
figure out how you can use technology
to get four times the
output with half the people.
Not because you're going
to use half the people
but because of the design contract
and the things you invest in
are the things that give
you those kinds of return.
- Right.
- And so I think that
that's super important
that people really do spend time on
is there a way to simplify
your supplier strategy?
So again, you're not,
you don't have people
that are your most valuable resource
or even most expensive resource as well.
So that you can get force
multipliers out of that.
And so I think that's super important.
And I also, like I said,
I've seen the satisfaction
in people who aren't just running through
the same process over and over.
Like they're doing more interesting work
and I think that's also super helpful.
- Makes them happier.
- Yeah, it does.
And that's really key. And I
think the other thing though
that security people need to keep in mind,
so, you know, it's just said
stay current progress over
perfection, automation.
And I think lastly, this point
about digital empathy
that you build a listening
system that just like
we have a feedback loop
with me as a customer
and you as a supplier,
I'm a piece of a Mac, I'm
a supplier or a vendor
but I'm also with the user base like that
people make sure they build
that kind of telemetry
into the system because you
become part of the solution
with your user base.
So that'd be the last thing I'd mentioned.
- Great, Bret, thank you for the time,
the conversation, thank
you for all the feedback
over the years and working
with the product team.
Thank you everyone for your time.
- Yeah. Super exciting.
Thanks for letting me come.
And obviously we spend a lot of time
giving requirements, seeing if they work.
And I think it's been super helpful.
Hopefully it's helped
make our products better
for customers that are using them
'cause we get to test them here first.