[Applause]
so some of you guys know me from 2600 or
Twitter or whatever I github so I do
this for a living I do this for a hobby
I mess with a lot of Linux stuff Linux
routers arm chips you name it so alright
so what is the firewall appliance
what is this USB far will appliance that
I I'm trying to do something with so
it's basically a dedicated network
security platform with software with
hardware meant to protect users now
devices and points basically save
resources and and devices from really
bad environments protect an Internet you
know protect an infrastructure
enterprise infrastructure so usually you
have your firewall it it does more than
just fireball it would have application
data it will have a proxy it will have
many different services instead of
having multiple independent you know
isolated functional units it will be
stored in one location and it would
probably have a failover server for is
it would probably have just whatever the
enterprise need so there is now is
Apache whatever it is this is usually
mostly for you know for customers that
have a lot of money it's not for a small
office it's not for home users is not
it's not for even mid businesses is for
something you know 500,000 users are
hired this is a specialized equipment
that is you know what a firewall and
antivirus a you name it it's in there
and it's Linux I'd you know
at the bottom of it it's Linux with
different clients customized
customizations most likely a lot of you
guys actually working on this stuff so
so so basically this is what I was
talking about so this is the Faro
management the central user management
for access for the web for access for
verification of downloads and
anti-malware and just web protection
with proxies any emails that might be
sending out through MCC you know
whatever protocol you they'd configure
it to be you know segmentation routing
VPN encryption you know it's a it's a
very powerful machine if you look at the
write it you know it talks about you
know plot cores or higher xeon sir xeon
processors or you know they're usually
stacked in a rack away from their users
themselves somewhere in a server room
somewhere but this is not what I'll be
talking about today
this is I'm talking about a portable
version of these this device for the
personal the personal user for something
that's running on arm something that's
not necessarily as powerful as this
obviously you guys have dealt with Linux
and play with certain things and Linux
where you could see the performance and
some of the aggregation of things that
you could add within applications and
customizations of software so that's
where you know this really this talk is
really about so so this particular
hardware was on eBay I was looking
around I was poking around and I was say
well this is interesting I've seen a
previous version of this this is a you
know some you know USB device I knew of
a USB version I spoke with a friend
we got another you know we got a copy of
it we
we we purchase multiple online started
poking around you know I wanted to find
out you know what is this software this
inherits the antivirus what's a VPN
client cannot mess with it can I change
it can I modify it any kind of
integration even the original code may
be debug a little bit of what's what's
actually happening if there's some
customization but it has a lot of
features you've see it on the on the
right here or says it has an anti-virus
as spam protection phishing protection
spyware intrusion detection firewall
built-in proxy VPN all in this little
tiny arm little tiny device that's
pretty cool I think everybody wants one
of these so if you look at the bottom
the USB version is in the person's hand
and I knew I knew of it because there
were other people in github and in the
past and two thousand and six thousand
seven they've broke into it you know the
vulnerabilities release there were some
information I knew about it long ago but
this new version was very was very
different I said you know this is
probably the last version it created of
it and is if you could look at it it's
an ExpressCard or at least a four factor
so I sort of poking around so we're
looking and doing more research and to
what the the original USB version is and
you know is there perhaps maybe has the
same vulnerabilities you know I started
I started looking around I saw that you
know the operating system it is on there
the version I sort of you know before
even purchase of the device that the
secondary the one I just show you
the ExpressCard version I started
looking around I said well you know
there's a lot of vulnerabilities to a
lot of these is suffered I mean things
have changed since 2007 and six you know
I hope they they kept that up to date
and if you see the top the the three
boxes one is blue
green and red it's mostly the same
device with specific software customized
to just be so as a firewall to just be
sold as a antivirus or anti spyware and
then the the blue one is the full the
whole enchilada basically so it you know
if you can look stuff you can look this
thing online there's you know you go to
the FCC ID you start poking around
there's people posting things on it it's
been hacked before I'm not you know not
doing anything new nothing's out of it
there's no kind of a box yet so I'm
interested in the new device because I
don't want USB to I don't want you as b1
there's a obviously a bottleneck there's
a bandwidth bottleneck if I have a
gigabit connection or I have some form
of really fast internet connection and
there's really old device from 2006 or 7
7 can't keep up you know can't keep up
with my bandwidth so this is why I don't
really want this particular device so so
that the previous device was actually
version 2.0 this is version this is the
original version and this was also
hacked early on they figure out that in
the processor it was Intel was an Intel
PCX a270 it was the same processor that
was on the I don't know if you guys
remember the gum sticks processor the
gum stick border they used to sell back
then I mean I've been playing around
with arm for a while so I don't know if
you guys do remember that but you know
you could somewhat create your own
version your own homebrew version of
this and so people did there was a
particular seller named Andy and he used
to sell Janis PA which is basically a
version of of of this of the original
device but you know customized to run
tour
so you know and this is the early days
this is the early days of really slow
tour you know basically running whatever
you want to run you know whatever script
or ever shell script you want you know
basically your own portable version of
this and this is sort of what you know
what I'm looking for but not for this
particular version again this is the
original and this works over over you
know I think it's a hundred megabits so
it's not really fast again bandwidth
bandwidth problems I don't want it's a
really old processor too early arm five
and six I'm not interested so I'm I
think I've cover everything here ok so I
started looking around start poking
around eventually get the card I started
looking at what is actually running in
the card you know there at you know the
actual vendor provides the the software
I mean at least to some degree what we
partially running because what's
actually on the device so you or at
least the pay version not their own
custom software so you can see snorts
there and they even talk about their own
version of snort I you know if you can
see that right there was they're still
being sold on Amazon it was just me
trying to get more but the the idea is
really just trying to find out if this
is really Express card or just as USB
2.0 and there were no real documentation
I couldn't find anything about the
driver I couldn't really find most of
the stuff is really old you know I'm
trying to poke around trying to debug
something trying to see where I could
start and then I open it let's hook it
apart and you can see it from the bottom
the bottom slight there that it's I've
discovered that it was really not USB
2.0 not Express card as USB 2.0 and it's
a USB 2.0 in a weird in a weird form
factor
got really pissed off I said alright
this this horror sucks I really don't
want this but I'm still interesting so
once I see I want to see what's inside
you know this probably hasn't been
hacked there's probably haven't been
open you know what's inside what's going
on and and why is it you know it's this
form fact it's just so weird I get more
information on the previous yogi the
yogi USB 2.0 and you know is I started
looking in at the end this driver for
Windows it works on Linux as well if you
do a virtual virtual driver has his own
specific application it it's pretty
interesting it creates a network just by
connecting the USB through your machine
just like most OTG you know USB
on-the-go devices nowadays though you
know if you plug your phone to your
network or to your computer instead
it'll network you know for Android or
wherever it is we do it will basically
do the same fact so so what I ended up
doing I modify the card connected USB 2
to it and I got it working on machines I
don't have Express card so you guys
could see I plugged in a jack to it
started poking around so start looking
more into the software was actually
happening what what are some of the
software that's installed there using
open source a lot of open source stuff
that you guys provided they have an open
source package you could download if you
buy a particular version of the of the
device you see pictures on the bottom
there or me opening a device let's let's
go into that and this is the processor
for the device it's an old freescale arm
6 processor so it's a better view of the
card somewhat of my mess of me wiring
does USB plug to it
and just a better view of the card so
but you can see the USB OTG and this is
what makes this you know again this is
on the go USB on-the-go and this is what
makes this particular model work the way
it does where you plug it into your
computer and it becomes a network car
instantly so start poking around I see
the vulnerabilities for the older
version the the second version which is
you can see it on the bottom application
application one application - which is
the Pico and then the Pico Pro and it's
pretty interesting remote execution
through through its own shell through
its own you know you are all encoding
its or CGI so this is the interface this
is where the configuration happens is
where the vulnerability is and it's it's
been documented on the previous version
it's it's pretty interesting so one of
things I want to say is this device when
in his in its day it was supposed to be
updated by the manufacturer so the
manufacturer would keep updating your
device and will keep it up to date and
it will push the update anytime I went
online the manufacturer it's no longer
around there they're around whether or
not so it's not going to receive an
update when you purchase degree
purchases devices is going to be the
first probably the first version of this
and it's probably a vulnerable one so I
was testing this firmware to that of the
firmware that was on the USB version
just so the Roth USB they're both the
same thing so for a lot of people I
guess this is more of you know the
interesting meat of the talk it's really
you know shell execution you know so I
started triggering it's made a couple of
script sort of playing around with
just linux shell and busybox because
that's what's running on this particular
britain in this particular machine so i
started sending these particular
commands is this windows cos linux shell
commands you know so asterisk that
guests sign mostly all the redirect io
and you know if you if you open if you
know about linux you could run multiple
commands up ones you could send special
characters that would trigger particular
behavior within the operating system and
if the cgi cgi-bin actually allows it to
go through it would it would you know
cost some serious havoc on the on the
back end on the server i mean this this
happens today i'm a lot of servers if
the programmer doesn't cash the stuff it
doesn't put do a lot of just testing and
you know and this is for pearl I mean
this is CGI Ben but in in we're still
having this problem today for for pearl
and all these are the languages where
you have to create a filter to kind of
block you know special characters and
meta characters to go through the web
portal so that it doesn't get parse it
doesn't get executed and it doesn't
triggered the remote execution so this
is really what this talk was about I
started poking around through my script
I found multiple ballot validations that
actually worked that I was able to get
in so I was I was able to get in um I
want do a live demo of what it looks
like so
so this is Windows I do apologize so
this is a device so you could turn it on
and off
you you know but it really does it it
takes your traffic and it sense a
director to the card and it's sort of
the car starts listening in to
everything you do and it goes from it
creates Australia
the minute you plug it into your
computer it creates a private network
it's similar to poison tab from Sandy
come car or one of you guys are familiar
with that but none malicious this is the
protective version of it plug it on the
other side
okay
I had a disabled before
it's okay it's in my history so
but I wanted to show you first was the
what happens when you plug it in so when
you plug it in you see the connection as
USB 2.0 it almost is maximum speed and
so here's the MAC address of a card here
is the IP address that is given into and
this is the IP address of the little
tiny device
oh it's like the
so there is the portal for it I had
bridge i had logged them before but this
is how it looks like it might ask me for
credentials that's probably why it
failed but this is why I didn't really
want the device so this is really not do
you know something that I really want it
you know so here gives you more
information about what the device is
like what the processor is it's zero
number and then this is the diagnostic
portion of what I was saying where you
are able to to run your own commands so
I will open this separately I don't want
to spend too much time so this is a demo
and I don't have that much too much time
the idea is basically you go here you go
to diagnostic you you you provide an IP
address and you know it sensed you to
wherever it's really not this device is
not really what I want to show I created
a simulation of this I created a bird a
better version of this and I've created
different versions of this particular
device in different in different
platforms so I took a look I took a
gander at the device and I'll show you I
created a script
I'll show you hopefully still open on
the window here okay
sorry switched from Firefox to Chrome so
but anyways I created a way we're good
that's how old this device is it's not
true
so they are among the device again if
you eventually get in there I created a
way to bypass this whole system this
system is really archaic it's really old
it's a lot of limitations now I wanted
to speak about some of the limitations
they did hardened a device enough that
if you try to create two input some of
those made it made of characters that I
mentioned before it would understand hey
you're a hacker you're trying to do
something that our regular usually
wouldn't do and I'm going to you to lock
the machine if you do it certain amount
of times and eventually you could kill
this little device but it has this you
know it does it does have a kill switch
for other things inside internally but
anyways I created a script you know from
this group hopefully I'll be able to
show you okay perfect so this is what
that ping command looked like if you go
directly to the CGI bin for it so you
see here I've added the special
character present 0a echo % 0 9 and then
an HTTP requests or a SEP header that
allows me to run execution from the
device it
this is the file that I entered on the
device I'll switch over to my scrape
because this is kind of slow
that's why I created my own scrape it
says it's verifying every command you
send you know and it takes forever but
you can see it right there
it's a this is the original script and
it kind of looks like
sorry yeah it kind of looks a little
different than this
I guess there it is so this is this is
my skirt so if you could see here I've
taken that whatever inputs coming from
the HTTP request and I'm saving it to a
file if you can see it there obscenity
to a file and it's in that file dumping
both the both my basically shell input
but also the error and the the return of
what of an echo basically the output of
the shell the standard output so I will
give it a command other than what I just
gave it so that the Vice is running s
route natively
gets it in an intro I'll just show you
from here so that's everything that's
running you know and basically I have
full access to the device and I could
see I could look at all the script and
like a look I mean that's me right there
obviously that I hacked but there's a
lot of firewall rules you could you
could be basically Bob's your uncle here
you could basically do whatever you want
it has port knocking and has snored it
has different versions of this you know
really old arcade box busy box
implementation and again this is this is
kind of you know this is really not what
the talk is about so I wanted to create
something very much like this I wanted
to create something that's customized
and personalized for myself that I could
run basically snore I could run some of
the devices that are running on here I
could run my own antivirus you're my own
you know anti-spoofing and plug it to my
device and I said well white you know
it's 2018 like there's tons of arm
devices that could do this
okay so I modified our Raspberry Pi to
do basically the same idea of what this
device is doing and so i use i mentioned
before i use the sammy camp cars hack
instead of creating my own industry ver
to create a a USB portable card I
basically just dump all the traffic
directly to the Raspberry Pi and my
traffic gets analyzed like I send my
traffic to tour it communicates through
the Wi-Fi access or whatever Wi-Fi card
I want to put in there so I want to get
something higher-end more powerful I
could you know I could definitely get
better reception I could do a lot more
than that little card was was doing you
know this is quad-core arm seven and
this is in fact arm eight the latest
Raspberry Pi that has a higher clock
higher clock and better better
performance overall but you know I
implement it and I'm trying to create an
operating system for it you know and
that's one of the things I want to get
it done before the talk and I couldn't I
couldn't get it I couldn't get
everything in there but it's basically
the same idea of what this device is
doing and then I said you know why stop
in a room you know whereas berry pie you
know I at first I had some limitations I
had to remove the raspberry PI's hub
which it's a pain in the bud you can see
it here so this is basically the the
lighting is from light source in the
back of the Raspberry Pi and I created
the same the same thing I plugged you
know I USB connection to it mini mini
USB so I had to find a tracing for the
Raspberry Pi to bypass the hub
so eventually you know coorporate
whatever Wi-Fi access I wanted to put in
there or whatever card or whatever the
Vice and and so here would you see the
logo for the Raspberry Pi that's where
actually where the is basically be
marked for you so the two dots right on
top of the Raspberry Pi logo it's it's
the is the hub and here you will see jj3
is basically the the opposite side going
directly straight to this to the seat
CPU you'll probably see it in the next
slide but the whole idea is well I could
I could do with the Raspberry Pi but I
can also do a go to restroom part W it
is more portable it has less processing
power but it's the same idea eventually
I kept going this is some of the slide
from the presentation before but
eventually I went into you know USB 3
and I said well I want higher
performance I want you know better
bandwidth I kind of got there so this is
the the raw 64 this is the it hazards b3
is probably one of the cheapest models
that exist today that you could buy
maybe less than $40 on on Amazon and
what allowed to do the same thing one of
the things that that I came across was
the the OTG goes from usb to or from
years b3 2 USB 2 so then I realized well
my bandwidth is being limited you know
so I wouldn't further and I started
messing around with the the Tegra the
Tegra x1 which is inside the this is how
you get a regular by the way this is how
you would you go from a micro to a
regular USB this is how you implement a
Wi-Fi card but this is only working on
USB 2 but as I was saying I eventually
went into a into the shield and from the
shield I was able to run my own version
of Linux with my own moti
basically USB on-the-go and and I was
able to do the same the same the same
thing I was able to do it on Android
with a root and Android to eventually
jailbreak the device to potentially do
it on another device and I was looking
for another version of a cheaper version
because a Nvidia shield about 179 dollar
device eventually found something much
better I found something called the
arcade 33 33 99 in the $33.99 I have to
find that
okay that's what here again sorry is
Windows sorry for my slides so they have
their own Linux distro and you could
compile it and make sickly use this
particular device to to create the same
thing this is what's inside a device so
is USB USB 3 the same capabilities under
$100 you know you could attach it to the
back of your computer to eventually do
this in it has built-in Wi-Fi it has the
same capabilities that's you know
there's the Nvidia shield that's the t1
would have so I kept looking there's a
development board from China there's a
it's it's it's just as cheap as this
particular device but the idea is to
basically get your gets to this are
thinking so there's a lot of
customizations there's a lot of things
that happen with arm and USB 3 and
devices that are able to go basically do
on-the-go would USB 3 and it's very it's
very powerful you could create your own
network you own private you know
firewall your antivirus protection all
in a separate machine than the one that
you're running you know for example
there's Windows machine and be
constantly protected you don't you know
an attacker will have to bypass and
attack the original device the the one
is connected to the Wi-Fi that giving
you access and is routing your traffic
and most like is going through tor or or
is going through whatever script you
want to create and this is why I want to
create an operating system to eventually
you know harness the power of our
particular chip for a particular
firmware and and basically put it out
there as a product it's something that
you could use and you create something
with and play with it becomes more like
a platform similar to you know an
Arduino or even the Raspberry Pi that
you see here and that's the idea that's
sort of creating something in the middle
that it don't only communicate all the
communication for you is protecting you
at the same time and it's building you
from viruses from
from fishing from spine from any kind of
attacks any kind of vectors that you
know could attack your particular
Windows machine or Linux machine or
whatever is on the other side and you
could attach this to a router you know
through the same OTG they have a
secondary point of a vector so that if
they're doing you know through the on
the public side on the antenna side
they're doing a just basically an
identity of what devices actually
connect to the internet
they'll have to really go through
certain loops to try to get to attack
that particular router so that's
basically the the concept it's you could
create your own high-end network
appliance running on somewhat high-end
equipment in 2018 and be completely to
the point where an attacker might not
know what you're actually using if this
is a Windows device or you know you
could you could hide the porch you could
you could even implement a honey spot a
honeypot right on the actual device and
most like know be the wiser so one of
the things that I'm trying to do is to
create a form of standardization there's
there's a lot of problems with the
processors and in certain linux
libraries they're not available for
certain processors that haven't been
ported over to arm issues with
compatibility just all around just linux
problems that i'm trying to provide a
distro and you know basically we'll be
the first ones to basically know that
i'm creating something like this I don't
know weathers are working or something
similar to this but it's a starting
point it's some it's a platform you know
that could become the next pineapple you
know you know from hack 5 or or
something better you know I mean so you
could you could think of it well you
know the pineapple is probably doing the
same thing or something similar to Wi-Fi
you know why wouldn't it do that to
protect you instead of attack you know
instead of using it as an attack vector
when I use it as a form of protection a
form of
putting something in between you and and
the internet and the rest of you know
all these other attack vectors that are
out there out there so you know that's
that's my idea poke around find out
what's what's out there find out you
know you could create your own version
of this and and get your feelers out you
know get your this is the this is what
I'm working on right now this is the
Nvidia shield with the Tegra with the
Tegra processor the circuit processor is
probably one of the fastest armed
devices in the market right now there's
nothing as powerful as this device it
has 24 GPU cores you know it has eight
eight ARM cores on its own for that are
specifically accessible to you and then
another four there arnaud that are
basically big brother or big little
configuration not big brother so this is
this is what the Tegra development board
looks like and this is a little more
more expensive this is about four
hundred dollars to sort of play around
with it but it's very capable it's it's
a it's a very powerful machine it could
make a really powerful tablet I know
Google made our tablet base head it is
and and obviously the the shield not the
shield is switch the Nintendo switch is
running on this platform so they've
they've shown different vulnerabilities
and different attacks to try to bypass
the bootloader for for the Nintendo
shield version of this and you could
eventually turn your Intel no shield
into one of those devices that I
mentioned so that's basically my goal if
you already own something you know you
already have the hardware if you already
are playing with armed devices you're
already playing with Linux and you
already have the capabilities of
programming and creating something new
this is this is basically what I you
know I want to get that started I want
to start perhaps working with people you
know creating a platform creating a way
tool to kind of work on this together to
kind of get your hands dirty and and get
some serious collaboration
create some serious protection you know
for yourself you know forget about the
rest of the world I mean eventually
could it could trickle down but for
yourself you could create even a tag
vectors from it by creating a form of
protection this is a very powerful Linux
machine the Nvidia community has a huge
following behind this as development
boards as I just showed you there's
there's a little early distro
specifically for the Tegra 4 the Tegra
x1 the this machine is very very
powerful and this is where I want to
create the distro I want to start with
this because this is the highest the
Hyatt the higher end and kind of go down
from there and it's a very capable not
just for protection but you could use
this you should use the encryption or
you could use the the GPU to do cracking
to do password cracking while you're
searching the web you know you could do
crypto crypto mining as well it's a very
powerful machine that you could adapt it
to pretty much anything I have it on me
here it's not bigger than my hand
it's a very it has two USB 3 ports that
are allow you to plug in whatever device
you want and it has the on the go it
basically it's a portable computer I
mean you could attach this to the back
of your laptop but our USB 3 cable and
no one would know them no one would be
the wiser
I know what you're doing and you know
why is there and again it has the same
Wi-Fi capabilities it could connect on
your behalf it could create a private
network between you and your computer
and send your traffic's and your traffic
through tor automatically through a
separate device instead of using your
machine it's it's it's a great platform
um I hope you guys got something from
this or you can start working on this
and perhaps you know help me create
something or
something for yourself I will be putting
the distro on github after the talk
it's private right now but basically uh
just to show you some of the problems
and it's just some of the debugging
perhaps you could start a small
community similar to the dd-wrt or open
wrt when you know a lot of these devices
first came to to the surface that's
basically my talk you guys have any
questions what's the power draw you're
seeing is it getting powered from the
laptop over USB then well it depends on
the device so the arcade $33.99 there I
wanna mentioned the second cheapest
version of this it could it could draw
from your from your device but it
depends on the laptop so if you have one
of the new laptops that could provide
the higher USB 3 power it will provide
it it will provide the higher end power
is basically power and data through one
cable and you're good to go
any other questions
the OS is really tiny it's it's about
the size of a busy box or something to
that you know it's a better extent hi
hey I had a question if this is the same
target as the the Asus thicker boards
using the rock 64 that when I mentioned
that before and that OTG goes from USB 3
2 USB toe and it's just part of the
manufacturer they build a cheaper chip
that could basically do the same as the
one I mentioned but is a lesser it's a
lesser purpose kind it's not the same it
doesn't work it doesn't have the same
function so yeah that the ticker box it
has a similar check but not that one has
this the rock 64 that that board that I
mentioned that I purchased that
basically left me down so so in terms of
issues with open wrt DVI Verity I know
that that the community the open wrt
communities struggling to get a sustain
good board and probably the Firefly here
donated the Firefly it's the same chip
but it's it's configured in a whole
different way the configuration is very
different from the raw 64 from the
tinker board it's it's in such a way
that you need a special you boot
configuration for the flood for that
particular board and there's not a lot
of support just things may have a china
the guys in China are probably taking
their time kind of importing some of the
things that the rockchip has created on
there you're better off creating your
completely own kernel from rock trip and
implementing all the patches that could
make this work for you but yeah thank
you
all right that's it have a good have a
going thank you thank you guys