this is my first hope and I'm having a
blast I love the message I love the the
many aspects here that are being drawn
together and the the unified theme under
all I think the message that I'm going
to bring is going to mesh very well with
that and emphasize these themes as
Thomas mentioned I'm a big promoter of
amateur radio and and the reasons why
will become clear in a bit throughout
the weekend that we are sharing here one
of the the aspects that we observe is
that all of this technology can be quite
fragile all of this technology is based
on one single commodity and that is
electricity and should anything happen
to that electricity many things will
fail in rapid succession there's an
inherent fragility to the the many
things that make our life possible and
and and pleasurable one key experience
that kind of drove that home for me
occurred almost exactly twenty-five
years ago this week it was summer of
1993 it was a very rainy summer and over
the fourth of July weekend there was six
inches of rain that fell on Northern
Iowa and it became very apparent shortly
thereafter that there was a big surge of
water heading down all of the rivers
towards where I lived in Quincy Illinois
and the projections were that the river
was going to crest the levees that
protected our area by at least four feet
so things had to happen and it was
pointed out to the amateur radio group
to which I belonged that the power
substation was down in the river bottom
the telephone relay station was down in
the river bottom and the water pumping
and purification system that provided
water for the entire
community was down in the cheap real
estate in the river bottom and if it got
flooded all that would go away so
literally overnight the Army Corps of
engineer the Illinois Department of
Transportation the Red Cross Salvation
Army all these organizations came
together to start sandbagging and raise
that levee within the sky island
drainage district which that County was
part of there were over 300 miles of
levees that had to be raised thousands
of volunteers came forth and it would
have been uttered chaos because there
was no way to communicate and coordinate
all of them except with a system that
utilized no infrastructure and that was
amateur radio so we had hundreds
hundreds of volunteers with walkie
talkies writing with Red Cross trucks
Corps of engineer trucks in the police
station in the hospital coordinating the
communications that would not happen in
the overloaded phone system and for two
weeks we raised the sandbags and it
rained again and we realized we would
have to raise them again we ended up
raising the levee at eight feet it was
one inch above the level of the final
crest of the river and it held the levee
on the west side of the Mississippi
River did not it was breached ultimately
it was determined it was an act of
sabotage and the eastern counties of
Missouri for two weeks became the fifth
largest freshwater lake in North America
but that drove home the message that
some of these things that we take for
granted are very fragile and we need to
have plans in mind what we can do to
strengthen them
now one of the are the areas of
fragility which which I'm going to talk
about today actually manifested and
became part of our awareness many many
years ago and we begin with what what is
known as the Carrington event which
occurred August 1st
1859 it was named after Richard
Carrington who is an observe astronomer
in the Royal Observatory in England who
was looking through a device like this a
Helia scope monitoring the sunspots and
it projects an image of the Sun on a
screen so you don't actually look at the
the the bright rays and as he was
looking at the Sun he observed something
that was completely had never been seen
before at that time he observed two
brilliant white spots appearing on the
surface of the Sun and this was so
unusual that he left his post trying to
find an assistant to drag over and show
hey hey hey come here there's two bright
white spots on the Sun well the Sun is
already white no no this is special come
over and by the time he dragged his
assistant over to look at the screen
they had faded but he recorded in his
journal what had occurred the the spots
here labeled a and B were within an
existing sunspot area and were brilliant
white spots and these this this was the
very first observed solar flare but
associated with this solar flare was
something again that it's something that
has never been seen before this was what
we now know as a coronal mass ejection
the Sun got violently sick and as my
ship going to work it's not okay what
happened was eighteen hours after this
ejection of
ten million tons of ionized hydrogen gas
it struck the earth with the force of
ten thousand nuclear bombs this gas yet
the magnetosphere and shifted the make
the the Earth's magnetic field and it
was first observed by telegraph
operators in their offices they all of a
sudden started noticing that the
telegraph lines in their Telegraph Keys
were starting to throw arcs and sparks
growing in sides up to six inches
fearing something terrible was happening
they disconnected their batteries and
found out that they could still send
messages even with the battery's
disconnected what was happening was the
changes in the Earth's magnetic field
was inducing through an inductive field
currents in the telegraph lines violent
currents with with voltages capable of
jumping these six-inch sparks meanwhile
and there's no photographs to Damac this
up aurora borealis were being observed
at places they had never been seen
before as far south as Cuba and Panama
there were gold miners in the Sierra
Nevadas who woke in the middle of the
night thinking that it was dawn because
the sky was illuminated and chickens
started crowing and and all this but it
was a brilliant pink glow to the sky and
nobody knew what it was it wasn't until
they correlated this with the brilliant
Sun Sun solar flare that they kind of
figured that the Sun was involved with
this phenomenon this is a coronal mass
ejection there's another phenomenon that
that we want to talk about and that is
an EMP or electromagnetic pulse and the
first observation of this was with a
nuclear test called starfish prime this
occurred in July 9th
1962 the reasoning for this test was the
Van Allen belts had just been discovered
a couple years earlier
these are belts of intense radiation
that surround the earth and it was
thought at that time they would be in an
impenetrable barrier to space flight
they would destroy any satellite or
manned mission that would attempt to
pass through it
the starfish prime nuclear test was a
high-altitude hydrogen bomb explosion
that was sought to get information on
what would happen in a high-altitude
explosion and also possibly modify or
weaponize the Van Allen belts so this
took place over the Central Pacific
nearby the Hawaiian Islands and I have
another animated gifs that's not going
to work okay but this is the actual
photograph of that explosion at the
moment it took place over Honolulu you
see Honolulu down and below what
happened at that instant though was
something not entirely appreciated at
the time the explosion of the atom bomb
created a huge burst of gamma rays that
descended down into the atmosphere where
it knocked loose electrons and those
electrons created an intense burst of
radiofrequency energy that then passed
down into the the Hawaiian Islands and
basically anything within line of sight
of that bomb a lot of weird things
happened that we're not completely
understood at the time they had burglar
alarms going off strings of street
lights went out instantaneously there
was a microwave telephone link that
failed and it wasn't until some years
afterwards that the official explanation
came out a lot of the the actual test
information for this is still classified
interestingly enough so even to this day
we don't know exactly the the intensity
of the fields that were
measured at that point in October of
1962 the Russians had to have their own
high-altitude nuclear test they launched
a hydrogen bomb at a similar altitude
over Kazakh Stan and they observed some
different things now bear in mind that
Kazakh Stan was very sparsely populated
there were no transistor circuits
present there it was all vacuum tube
stuff but the Kazakhs observed that in
the aftermath of that atomic explosion
they had power transformers power
distribution transformers simply melting
down power lines were melting and
failing catching on fire and the main
the main power supply to to the Kazakh
region caught on fire and burned down
this was something they did not expect
and it was very shocking now historians
what happened in October of 1962 Cuban
Missile Crisis immediately after this
test the Russians pulled their missiles
out of Cuba one can speculate whether
the outcome of this test had something
to do with that
now this is historically known we can we
we can extrapolate what can happen in
the future from what we know but it is
time for my disclaimer there's a lot
about these tests that we don't know
what we do know about the the historic
EMP tests is they occurred and we can
try to simulate those tests using EMP
simulators to recreate the this
particular impulses that were measured
with equipment that may not have been
capable of fully capturing the effect
what happened in 1962 mostly occurred to
vacuum tube electronics the transistor
electronics said the day we're very
simple not a lot of it there much of the
details are still classified much of the
projected damage that is officially
within the US government project
projections is not correlated by what
happened over Kazakh Stan they saw much
worse results most likely because the
Hawaiian island is very different
geographically than the plains of Kazakh
Stan so my disclaimer is there's just a
lot about EMPs in particular that we do
not know I'm going to provide the best
information that I've been able to glean
from open source data and if you choose
to disagree with me I'm not going to
argue there's there's room for
disagreement but again I'm going to try
to present the best information that I
can we can extrapolate from this
information try to project and predict
what may happen should another EMP burst
occur this over the continental United
States but in the end there's a lot we
don't know and cannot know
what we do know of EMP occurring from a
high-altitude nuclear burst is there are
three spectral components the first is
called II one that's the first component
of the burst and that's due to the high
powered gamma rays penetrating the
atmosphere knockin loose electrons that
is a 50,000 volt per meter pulse okay
point of reference inside your microwave
oven the magnet the electrical fields
are only a thousand volts per meter and
in a confined space 50,000 volts per
meter across thousands of miles it is
however a very brief pulse only about
five nanoseconds wide so this means that
it has a peak of its frequency component
somewhere around the 500 megahertz range
perhaps so that means that the resonant
antenna is going to be something foot or
so in length following a 1 is called the
e2 burst that is approximately 1
microsecond in length about a hundred
times weaker in intensity and very much
mimics the effect of a nearby lightning
strike now who here has had lightning
strike a tree near your house
and you've lost your washing machine
your TV your computer yeah this is going
to be the same thing that happens over a
multi hundred mile area following that
is what's called the e3 effect and that
is a massive disruption of the Earth's
magnetic field and that occurs do they
due to the huge mass of ionized gases
that are rising convectively after the
nuclear blast and those charged
particles in their motion create a
magnetic field that disrupts the Earth's
field that induces currents into long
suspended wires in
Euler power lines this period occurs in
a period of tens to hundreds of seconds
and then it's over and this diagram
shows the the particular voltage
intensity and time profile of what's
likely to happen now the damaging
effects again are going to be related to
the intensity and the wavelengths of
these these effects II one is going to
affect short antennas which are likely
to be the power cords that plug into
your appliances internal wiring perhaps
that may be of the appropriate length to
pick up these signals e two again as I
mentioned is is similar to the effect of
a nearby lightning strike III this is
interesting it's it its effect is to
create DC currents within power lines
which were designed to carry AC when
those currents enter transformers it
gives the opportunity for the
transformer to saturate its open circuit
inductance goes to zero it overloads and
can be destructive there's a specific
distribution of the effects that we can
project from a high altitude nuke if you
have something that is set off at say a
300 mile altitude over the Upper Midwest
the distribution of the effect is
actually in an arc primarily to the
southern distribution with peaks of 50
thousand volts per meter again in the
red zone but even throughout the light
blue circle you're going to see voltages
of twenty five thousand volts per meter
so it could literally blanket the entire
United States
knowing what these pulses look like in
terms of amplitude and frequency we can
build simulators that strive to
duplicate these effects and here we have
the North American Electric Reliability
corporation has built their simulator
and and and what this is you can see a
bar across the top that's a dipole
antenna it's excited from a Marx
generator that is capable of delivering
a 500,000 volt pulse into this roughly
10 meter long antenna and items to be
tested will be placed underneath that so
the question is should an EMP occur what
is likely to survive and the easy answer
is things without a lot of transistors a
battery a battery is big and dumb and
chemical your car battery will survive
the little batteries in your smoke
detector and transistor radio will
survive but the smart batteries in your
computers and cell phones are not likely
to survive because they include smart
charging circuitry inside
what will survive an e-1 pulse a tube
type radio this is the classic how the
crafters s38 Thomas do you have one
yeah very good
okay tube type equipment did not
experience failures in the Hawaiin test
because the vacuum tubes are macro
electronics not micro electronics they
are large scale devices that can absorb
the energy okay this is a very popular
radio among Preppers because it is a
transformer list design it can be
operated from a hundred twenty volts DC
tin car batteries strung together will
run this so if you want to make some
money find one of these at a flea market
upgrade it and change the capacitors put
it on eBay as a
radio you can make some money okay
in 9th 2004 the EMP Commission studied
37 different cars placed them in that
simulator hit them with the EMP pulse
the e1 pulse and found to their
amazement all of them survived ok I read
this and I had such a cognitive
dissonance I could not understand that
because everything that I've read up to
that point says oh it's total disaster
nothing will survive we're going to be
going back to horse and buggy but ok
I've worked in the automotive
engineering world for quite a few years
automobiles are designed to withstand
some absolutely horrific electrical
conditions a automobile and it's
electrical components must be designed
to survive installing the battery
backwards
because because the nuclear scientists
are doing nuclear science and the other
guys are working in auto mechanics
inside every electrical component inside
the car is a certain suppressor it's a
powerful Zener diode it's about the size
of a nickel and the electrical spec for
cars says that it must survive the
application of a pulse of a hundred
twenty volts for four hundred
microseconds four hundred milliseconds
excuse me so those Zener diodes which
are distributed out through the entire
car have to sync that energy and it will
do a wonderful job for a neat to pulse
and evidently it does a pretty good job
for an e-1 pulse also so at first glance
you would say that the the advice of all
the preparedness experts that you get to
a pre 1980s diesel vehicle that has no
electronics in it well yeah that's a
good advice but even afterwards it may
not be such a bad deal okay my caveat my
disclaimer I have to throw in here after
2004 cars have been manufactured with a
whole lot more computer circuitry is
that computer circuitry going to be more
vulnerable than what was made in 2004
odds are yes but I can't tell you how
much more because we've not had a test
done since then as it turns out most ham
equipment will survive there were a
series of tests done in 1985 results
were published in qst magazine if you
want to look that up again by the the
EMP Commission and you would think that
this this equipment has a lot of
transistors in it it's going to fail due
to that pulse and it turns out that none
of it did again the cognitive distance
hits because we're told everything's
going to die
this stuff did not and the reason for
that is this transceiver equipment here
must generate about a hundred watts so
it must not interfere with itself so
there is protection circuit built in to
keep it from destroying itself from its
own internally generated electromagnetic
fields and that also gives a degree of
protection from external fields and
these radios even with the antennas of
their microphones plugged in seem to
survive now my disclaimer those radios
had metal cabinets these little walkie
talkies have plastic cases the metal
provides some protection that the
plastic does not my beloved little
walkie-talkie might not survive but I
have plans for it what will survive in a
one pulse strategic weapons and they
must as we'll get into in a little bit
I've actually seen these planes up close
and the groovy thing is the windshield
and the windows on it have a metal grid
embedded in them just like the windows
of a microwave oven it keeps the stuff
out because you want this flying when
the bombs start going off but what is
vulnerable from the EMP testing we know
that things with a lot of micro
electronics have very small gates which
are not capable of absorbing large
amounts of energy so for that we know
that likely your your satellite
receivers smart meters anything with a
lot of micro electronics in it that is
not specifically hardened for any type
of industrial control it's likely to go
sorry so ways to protect your vulnerable
electronics number one disconnect
everything that's not a new
and that's good advice whether you're
fearing that the North Koreans are going
to launch nuke or if you're in lightning
season and you're sitting on top of a
mountain unplug everything because the
wiring of your house is a great antenna
that's going to collect that energy and
direct it into anything that's plugged
in my personal favorite strategy is to
put a surge suppressor on everything
that is plugged in that's electronics so
your computer your microwave your TV all
that expensive stuff go down to Walmart
get a search press or it plugs in your
outlet and that will swallow
most of the energy of a pulse that comes
in your line when when lightning struck
near my house in 2008 we lost two CFL
lightbulbs and all the neighbors around
us lost microwaves and ovens and washing
machines and expensive stuff number
three shield everything with a Faraday
cage anything that is particularly
sensitive that you care about or that
cannot be protected in any any of the
other ways okay a Faraday cage is not a
cage for ferrets and there's a lot a lot
of misconceptions and myths that go
around about what makes an effective
Faraday cage a Faraday cage simply
stated is a conductive sphere or body
that surrounds your sensitive item it's
made of highly conductive material with
some thickness to it so it will conduct
that pulse around your sensitive item so
that this the item and the center does
not even know that a pulse has occurred
if you go into the prepper literature
they will tell you a lot of things yeah
they'll tell you put your electronics in
an ammo box and ammo boxes made of steel
oh yeah it's good except it's not
because steel is a very poor conductor
of electricity you're you get just about
as much good by digging a hole and
burying your item
not that I would recommend that either
additionally the steel box has a lid
that just folds down on top and does not
create a metal to metal contact so that
gap is wide open for these frequencies
to penetrate other okay okay I'm getting
a headache here one of the other prepper
sites says well if you see the blast
just throw your radio into the microwave
and slam the door if you can do that
within 5 nano seconds you're pretty good
yeah a microwave oven is intended to
shield the microwaves insight from
getting out and vice versa it's better
than nothing but you can do better and
and the other one which really gets me
is the so-called EMP bags and they're
sold on the same websites that sell the
nutritional supplements that we were
talking about earlier yeah if you buy
parts from digi-key they come in these
bags it's kind of a silvery colored
plastic and you can see through them and
in my reasoning if you can see through
them that the metallization is not
really too adequate and there's there's
empirical tests where yeah you put your
mic your cell phone in here and dial it
and it may not pick up but there's also
some some actual tests which we'll get
into in a second science experiment here
okay we talked about decibels or DB
that's a measure of attenuation 10 DB
means that you're cutting things by a
factor of 10 taking out 90% of the
signal 20 DB is a hundredfold 30 DB is
1,000 fold so when we're talking about
how much shielding you get we're going
to talk about DB your file cabinet and
ammo box gives you less than 10 DB of
attenuation now these are verified by
some experiments by a NASA scientist dr.
Arthur Bradley who
has actually gone with calibrated
equipment not a cell phone experiment
calibrated equipment to measure the
attenuation at the frequencies of choice
the EMP bag is only good for about 15 DB
a galvanized trashcan gives you 20 DB so
that's taking out 99% of the impulse but
I just said that steel is not a good
material for a Faraday shield it's not
the steel of the trashcan that's working
here it's the zinc coating that's
actually a pretty decent conductor if
you wrap the lid with aluminum duct tape
the the metal tape that you can get at
the hardware store you double the
effectiveness which tells you that the
gap around the lid leaks a whole lot of
energy in that you can very effectively
knock down a microwave oven is good for
25 to 40 DB but the simplest and easiest
one you get a sheet of aluminum foil you
take it out of your hat take your
sensitive item fold it over wrap it up
like you're making a sandwich that you
want to keep really fresh crimp over
those edges just as tight as you can and
that right there is good for 50 DB of
attenuation how much do you need and
that's something that nobody ever says
okay I'm gonna stick my neck out here
and I will be the first person to ever
say so but I'm going to define that you
need 60 decibels of attenuation of that
50 kilo volt signal to be safe in just
about every condition you can't so you
take your folded aluminum foil wrap you
stick it in another plastic bag and wrap
it around with aluminum foil again
you've now got a hundred DB of
attenuation and nothing's getting
through that personally what do I keep
in a Faraday cage it's things that are
absolutely essential and not easily
obtainable I have another walkie talkie
just like that wrapped in aluminum foil
I have a 40 meter CW ham radio
transceiver if the communication
infrastructure goes down this will still
allow me to send long-haul signals over
thousands of miles to handle emergency
messages things like this were used in
the aftermath of Katrina for months
until they got the telephone
infrastructure back up a multiband radio
years you're going to need information
there will be broadcasters that survive
an incident like this where they get
their information from is another
question but you will need that
information and whether it's am/fm or
any of the shortwave bands there will be
something there that you can listen to
and something of use okay this one and
there are chuckles and and and the the
presentation last night about putting
Linux on one of these ear eaters was
really good you know ideally I would
love to have a tablet that is milled
spec and recognized but the old burns
Noble Nook it's in a rubberized case I
can drop it and it's gonna survive and
the cool thing is it will have multiple
months of battery life because there's
no backlight to suck the battery I've
got a 16 gig card in here with six
thousand books and documents in here
manuals for every vehicle I own every
appliance I own every piece of ham radio
equipment that I own books on medicine
surgery metallurgy welding woodworking
it's all on archive.org just go out
there spend a couple of days downloading
downloading the information that will be
essential in the event that the internet
does not exist tomorrow or you can't
make a trip down to the library because
people are burning books for heat
a multimeter because I'm gonna be fixing
all the stuff to get that that I
couldn't fit in the Faraday cage okay I
do not have one of these but the
vulnerable part of your car will be the
engine computer it's already pretty well
shielded but again it's the vulnerable
part and it makes the difference between
your car being a usable vehicle for
getting around or a $10,000 garden
ornament get one of these wrap it in
foil and you're good go to the junkyard
they're cheap now then for an e3 pulse
the e3 pulse would be the consequence of
either CME or or the the e3 from a EMP
that induces the very high voltages and
the DC currents which will burn out the
Transformers in 2003 there was a small
CME that mostly affected the upper
altitudes of Canada this is actual
pictures of one of the high-powered
distribution transformers that was
burned out from the onset of the CME and
the disruption in the magnetosphere to
the the damage and failure of this
transformer it was 90 seconds there's
not a lot of time to react to that if
you're even aware that it's happening
this has been analyzed and the effects
projected for a CME of half a micro
Tesla per minute of magnetic flux change
which is corresponding to the the the
damage that occurred in the 1921 cime
which was only about half the strength
of what happened in the Carrington event
okay these green dots are where
geomagnetic current exits the ground red
is where it enters back into the ground
so anytime you see one of these circles
you will have a circuit breaker blowing
these two elements here in circles left
and right side that represents areas
where transformers will fail and there
will be long-term power outages if there
is a cm of an EMP blast over Chicago
based on these projected field strengths
this is the damage and you have
nationwide grid down in such a case you
are going to see something on the order
of 350 high voltage transformers
destroyed wanted true trillion dollars
of economic damage the first year and up
to 10 years to restore the problem is
these transformers take about a year to
build there are very few places in the
United States that that make them most
of them are made in in Europe and
shipped over so that's an issue you
cannot replace 350 of them all at one
time as it exists the grid is operating
at about 90% capacity it's more
efficient that way if you lose 10% of
your transformer capacity everything
goes down beyond that you're talking
world global or national blackout
conditions the fragility of the grid is
one thing but it's interdependence II on
all of the other essential services you
have to stop and pause and reflect on
that because you you are you have
effects on the oil and gas industry all
these pipelines are pumped without power
to pump them you lose gas and oil
Communications internet cell phones
landlines all of those operate on the
grid they have battery backups which
lasts for perhaps 36 hours if you're
lucky the really good ones have
sets and diesel storage that can run for
a couple of weeks past that point they
go down water is being pumped without
the pumping stations that run on the
grid that goes down you have no water to
drink you have no water to flush the
toilet banking in finance your credit
card goes non-functional I don't have
any cash in my pocket doggone it that's
a problem transportation if if for
example we have multiple vehicle
failures say in in the tunnels here we
are now locked in it cannot escape the
island emergency services are similarly
affected they are vitally dependent upon
communication and the government
services FEMA and so on which would be
providing emergency services cannot
communicate cannot cannot be transported
basically any grocery store has about
three days worth of inventory and when
that's gone stomach start rumbling worst
case scenario is if you have an e3 event
that sends a search backup into a
nuclear power plant you can shut down a
nuclear power plant in its core remains
hot for several weeks and unless there
are water pumps that continuously cool
that it melts down that's the that's
what happened in Fukushima there are
generators on-site with diesel fuel to
operate these pumps every installation
enough fuel to keep it running
if those gents if those gensets and
pumps are affected by either an e1 or an
e3 pulse bad things happen and you've
got nuclear power plants all over
use of EMP in warfare yeah we know who
the bad guys are most likely it's the
the little loud mouths like North Korea
and Iran trouble is though it's very
hard to do an EMP anonymously you can
follow the missiles with the radar back
to the point of origin the concept of
mutually assured destruction has been
very effective
even though kind of scary for the past
several generations but you know what
it's difficult to predict the psychology
of other entities you can you can you
can project something like a school
shooter who acts in a very irrational
manner to take out as many other people
as he wants knowing that his ultimate
goal is suicide project from there to a
much larger gun but the saving grace in
my mind is that nuclear weapons are
extremely expensive and so are the
delivery systems and those people most
likely to use it are the ones least
likely to afford it but with the
knowledge of the vulnerability of the
grid comes another threat it takes a guy
with a high-powered rifle on a hillside
three or four shots to put a hole in one
of these high voltage transformers the
oil drains out it overloads it overheats
and it's gone this happened in
California in 2014 and nobody was ever
caught and it has all the hallmarks of a
deliberate act as a rehearsal okay 9/11
was nineteen guys with flight lessons in
airplanes you find a hundred unhappy
people with high-powered rifles and they
could do as much damage as a
high-altitude EMP for one one thousandth
of the budget
okay okay
what is being done to protect us the the
2015 transportation bill had seventeen
million dollars set aside for an EMP
study to identify transformers in
inventory that can be moved and to set
aside a strategic transformer pool of
Transformers that can be bought put in
place ready to be shipped around the
country at a moment's notice
so it's not totally hopeless for us to
survive make some plans can you for this
my everyday carry is my MacGyver
pocketknife it's super handy because the
good beer does not come in twist-off
tops
you need to be able to at the very least
provide for warmth use one of these
mylar space blankets be able to open a
can be able to purify water get
information in communication like my
little nook my little walkie-talkie that
is essential essential reading one
second after by William fortune is a
piece of fiction but it's very accurate
and well researched a couple of other
authors Fernando Aguirre SELCO Begich
these two gentlemen were in Argentina
and Yugoslavia respectively during the
unpleasantness there and they have seen
the effects of disruption of systems and
the effect on people who suddenly find
themselves going into third world
existence and hunger one of my key
formative experiences was in 2003 when
Hurricane Isabel hit Williamsburg
Virginia when I was living there it was
a cat5 storm on it hit the Outer Banks
and by the time it rolled through there
were millions of trees down we had just
moved into this cul-de-sac and when the
storm blew over and the Sun came out we
all stepped out to survey the damage
there was no phone there was no power
and there would not be for weeks and we
looked up and down the street and there
were people that we had never met before
that's the reality of suburban suburban
life but we were now meeting these
neighbors and realizing we've got
refrigerators full of food that's gonna
go bad so we rolled the gas grills out
of our garages and fired them up and
started cooking first the frozen pizzas
as they thawed
then the hamburgers then the roasts then
the hams and then the turkeys and we had
a week-long block party
and in the process we made friends
lifelong friends that we never would
have otherwise and and I think that is
kind of a microcosm lesson of how we
need to be facing this because it didn't
matter if the guy down the street had a
rainbow flag and the other guy had a
confederate flag all those flags blew
away in the wind and and even though
worst case projections will be that bad
things can happen and millions of people
will die millions of people will not be
one of the ones who will not and you
will have an opportunity to rebuild your
community and make it a better place
thank you
you