I should probably not give my top and
just let it be that all right I'm ready
ready all right before we start a few
points of order for people watching the
livestream or anyone in the audience who
would prefer subtitles the entire
transcript all the slides and all the
supporting materials for this talk are
live now at NFC Dot toys NFC toys we're
covering a lot in this talk and it
clocks in to just under 50 minutes which
means we won't have time for live QA but
QA is important so I will be taking
questions on paper and electronically
the in-person audience can write their
questions on the flip side of their
feedback form both the in person and
live stream audiences can submit
questions via Twitter too at NFC toys or
via text message for the remainder of
the day I know it's you don't have great
cell phone reception down here but you
can type them in and queue them up and
send them later to one eight five six to
NFC Q&A one eight five six to NFC Q&A
there are slide numbers on each slide
you can reference I will post answers to
questions on NFC toys and reply to you
with a link to your answer if you're
watching this talk in the future church
asking questions via Twitter will be
your best bet for a response this is an
introductory level talk but there are
also more advanced and related talks at
hope this year I linked to the
information about these and others on
NFC toys and finally as the MC mentioned
for the in-person audience I've provided
speaker feedback forms and pens one side
is for Q&A the other side is for talk or
speaker feedback please fill these out
and at the end pass them forward or
leave them on the tables outside it
helps me know how this went independent
of any feedback you may provide hope
directly if you need paper for your own
notes I've also provided blank index
cards so please use the feedback forms
to ask questions and provide feedback
there's extra ones up here up front and
also on the table in the middle of the
aisle all right we're going to talk
about NFC toys which are toys which have
NFC tags embedded in them I want to give
you an idea of why this is worth an hour
of your time but I need to start with a
couple of exam
fools for everyone who doesn't know what
NFC is so a round of applause who has
paid for something using an iPhone with
Apple pay or an Android phone with
Google pay cool all right NFC is how
your phone talks to the payment terminal
you hold it up to and all of those
wireless payment systems work the same
way under the hood part of NFC is a
standard method of wireless
communication round of applause whoo
waves a security badge against the
reader to get into their building at
work all right
NFC is a subset of the RFID technology
that your badge probably uses inside
that badge just like inside and NFC toy
is what's called a tag NFC tags are a
small amount of memory logic and an
antenna they're not really a full-on
microprocessor NFC tags are more like
tiny slow Wireless flash drives part of
NFC is a standard set of tag types when
a tag or your phone talking like a tag
is near enough to a reader generally
millimeters to centimeters the readers
radio frequency transmissions provide
enough wireless power to allow the tag
to communicate back and forth
often just tends to a few hundred bytes
now NFC tags which store tiny amounts of
data Wireless NFC communication methods
to transmit them these are technical
tools for engineers but NFC toys are
first and foremost toys toys are meant
to be fun toys are meant to be played
with everyone understands that toys are
toys so when a toy does something that a
toy would it normally do that's visually
interesting that's stimulating swiping a
toy of Samus Iran from Metroid on a
subway turnstile that perks you up
that's super interesting what other
kinds of data could you put on one well
anything because remember they're like
tiny slow Wireless flash drives you
could have a Maleficent toy holding
within it the original curse from the
grim fairy tale you gotta have a
Tinkerbell toy with a link to the e-book
of Peter and Wendy you could have a
piggy bank with your Bitcoin wallets
private key
you could have a kylo Ren toy with a
playlist of emo songs you could have a
toy car to unlock your real car you
could have a kickoff Countdown's toy
store your world cup predictions you
could have a toy in a geocache with
coordinates to another geocache you
could have a Pikachu toy with the
credentials to your dev environment at
work you could have a larger Pikachu toy
with the credentials to your QA
environment to work you could have a
giant Pikachu toy with the credentials
to your production environment at work
even though they're technically no
different than a bear NFC tag storing
the same amount of data in the same way
communicating the same way the novelty
and playful aspect of NFC toys supports
us in thinking about unique and fun uses
for NFC tags in a way that NFC tags by
themselves don't that said while they
are technically no different than a bear
NFC tag because NFC toys are often
intended to support interactions with
copyrighted digital content they may be
legally different if we want to use them
for our own purposes we should be able
to play with our toys as we see fit and
it's up to us to assert our rights to do
so we're going to talk about three makes
of NFC toys with most of our time spent
on Activision Skylanders because that's
where most of the literature is but
we'll also cover Disney infinity and
Nintendo amiibo there are other makes of
NFC toys and the techniques we'll use
can apply to them but these are what
we'll be talking about today as we talk
about them are going to explain how they
work along with some background
information about the toys to life genre
of video games and pertinent details
about NFC tags in general we'll explore
each one with off-the-shelf hardware and
software referencing a long history of
security research and learn how that
exploration can lead to determining read
and write credentials and then we'll see
how to write our own data to those three
different types of NFC toy and talk
about the legal implications of doing so
while I will be discussing legal matters
I am NOT a lawyer and this is not legal
advice finally I will hand out NFC toys
and works
Sheetz for anyone in the audience who
wants to try this out for themselves and
I hope you will we're going to start
with Activision Skylanders round of
applause who has kids who were into
Skylanders and you had to buy them a
bunch of stupid toys and video games in
the last seven years yeah parents in the
audience okay okay
round of applause who was personally
into Skylanders and bought yourself a
bunch of awesome toys and video games
over the last seven years fantastic for
everyone else who isn't familiar
Skylanders is a video game that launched
in 2011 as a Spyro the Dragon reboot
across every major platform plus a
flash-based web game it's a game in the
toys to life genre as in bring your toys
to life each Skylanders game shipped
with a few starter figures and a USB NFC
reader styled as a portal to play the
game you place a figure on the portal
and that's the character you play as
when you name your character and you
earn points and collect items they're
stored in the NFC tag on the toy so when
you take that same toy to your friend's
house it shows up with the name you gave
it and all its points and experience and
all its history while you can beat the
game with what comes in the starter kit
to reach 100% completion and to collect
every achievement you need to buy
additional types of characters and
expansion toys and Skylanders was a huge
success
sequels were shipped every year
variously offering extra large figures
recombine able figures with twice the
NFC tags or vehicle figures resulting in
over 350 Skylanders toys of all types
earlier we said that some Android phones
one that's ones that support Google pay
can talk NFC and so an Android phone
will be the first of three standard
tools I'll be discussing when you're
exploring NFC tags on your own it's
easiest to look for an Android phone
with Google pay support any Android
phone with NFC support can read any NFC
type one through four tag however the
proprietary NXP Mifare tags can only be
read by phones with NFC chips produced
by nxp you should be able to find an
older Android phone with NFC support for
under 100
so what happens when we swipe an NFC toy
against an appropriate Android phone
this is a ninja knee figure from
Activision Skylanders when swiped
against an Android phone with NFC
support running the app NFC tools it
gives us five pieces of information as
it should some of the expected uses for
NFC are for things like business cards
and advertisements so some information
can always be read from an NFC tag using
standard tools and this represents some
of that standard public information the
first thing we see is that it's an NX P
brand tag NX fee is a major manufacturer
of NFC tags and they've promoted the use
of their NFC tags in games like
Skylanders since at least 2011 we also
see the serial number for the tag called
the UID and the 80 QA and si K which
help identify the type of tag it is
since it's an NX P tag let's see if NX
P's own app and XP tag info can tell us
anything more so I got to say these
screens are kind of empty they're not
telling us much more than NFC tools did
and that is actually a little unusual
let me show you what some other NFC tags
look like in the same NX p tag info app
here's a payment card from my local
arcade while the first two screens are
pretty bare the third one shows us the
memory size which is how much stores the
tag has and how it's set up and the
fourth one shows us the actual data on
the card and it formats it to match up
with the description in the memory size
this is laid out just like the data is
stored on the tag in this case 16
sectors with four rows of 16 bytes each
we can see this because along with the
standard public information that every
tag presents for NFC tags which can be
protected there are also standard keys
and passwords which are commonly used
often to allow for public readers while
still restricting who can write to or
update a tag that this tag uses a common
standard factory default key meaning
anyone can see what's on it here's a
pair of bluetooth headphones which embed
an NFC tag
or easy pairing with your phone this one
is great the second screen explains a
lot of the technical details of the
content like the manufacturer the model
of the head said the kinds of Bluetooth
protocols it supports and more the
fourth screen again shows us all the raw
content that it's getting all that
information from again laid out how it's
stored in the tag in this case four rows
of four bytes each called pages
unfortunately the asterisks here mean
it's read only there's no way to write
to this NFC tag and for example change
what it identifies as for pairing here's
a business card printed by mu which
embeds an NFC tag to support sharing
contact information sending the user to
a URL or app store or social network
profile or even triggering custom
behaviors using if this than that this
tag was set up to send a notification to
my phone when someone taps it and then
direct them to NFC toys this output is
also really detailed the second screen
explains the technical details of the
content in this case the MU URL that
provides all of the custom functionality
through their online service the third
screen has detailed information about
the NFC tag itself and the fourth screen
again shows us all the raw memory
content that it's getting all of that
information from again this is in a
pages structure the entire business card
appears writable meaning we can put
anything we want to on it even replacing
moves online service with our own so
those other NFC tags show me memory
contents and the layout of the data on
the tag but the TN P 3 X X X in the
skylander figure doesn't show me
anything we know that it has memory the
third tab says so so what's up to figure
it out let's use that elite hacking
technique called go poking around the
internet like if we search NX P's
website for TN P 3 X xx we find it in
this PDF describing ways to identify an
X P my fare tags so it's a my fare tag
curiously it doesn't have any other
information but table 2 in this PDF
describes another Mifare tag with 1k of
memory the Mifare classic Wikipedia
describes the Mifare classic
memory sizes so it matches the
description of what the third screenshot
from an XP tag info told us so maybe the
tnp 3 xxx is a Mifare classic compatible
tag
even if tag info presents pretends to
not know what it is Wikipedia also says
this as a common type of NFC tag
Mifare classic is pretty well explored
from a security standpoint if n TN p3
xxx is a Mifare classic derivative
could it be vulnerable to the same
exploits that Mifare classic tags are
allowing us access to the tag so that's
as far as we can get on a Skylanders toy
with an Android phone so it's time to
upgrade to the second set of three
standard tools I'll be discussing
dedicated NFC reader hardware plugged
into your computer we want to look for
hardware that's compatible with the Lib
NFC open source library which supports a
select range of NFC reader chips on
Linux Mac and even Windows with some
futzing we want Lib NFC compatible
hardware because a lot of the dedicated
NFC readers you'll find our windows only
or only expose low-level communication
functions requiring more complex
technical programming there are higher
level easier to use libraries and
various languages which use Lib NFC
under the hood so it provides security
researchers and hobbyists alike with a
standard platform you can find a Lib NFC
supported NFC reader for around $50 in
addition to a supported NFC reader
plugged into our Mac or Linux computer
you'll also need to already know or be
comfortable figuring out how to compile
software yourselves but we won't need to
write anything new so Wikipedia
describes something like 9 different
papers and presentations going back to
2007 which provide various attacks on
and compromises to Mifare classic tags
in addition nxp released so-called
hardened versions of my fare tags quote
in and around 2011 in exploring this
ninja natori we're really just taking
the next steps in a long line of
scholarship
now this ninja new toy is from 2000
12 the Giants line I use it B as an
example because it's bigger and it
lights up but if it's a Mifare classic
tag in disguise we're going to have to
use a compromise that works against the
hardened version of the tag like the one
from this paper published in 2015 which
finally led nxp to tell people to stop
using them now all you need is one known
key but what's a key so remember that
payment card from earlier than its
memory layout this is the same as how a
Mifare classic tag is laid out in
sixteen sectors numbered 0 through 15
each of those rows in each sector is
called a block each block can store 16
bytes 16 bytes x 4 blocks
x 16 sectors is 1k of storage the last
block in each sector stores two
passwords called key a and key B with
access bits in between them which define
which of the keys can read or write the
blocks as well as read or write the
other key in this sector from the
payment card
the first password key a is hidden
unknown next out which probably means
you need to Amina to update the dollar
figure on the card the second pass where
key B is the factory default key and
it's readable which means we can see it
that probably also means we can only use
it to see what data is on the tag but
not change it 16 sectors a key a and a
key B each mean there can be up to 32
passwords you need to uncover to get
access to a completely locked down 1k
Mifare classic tag but what this paper
tells us is that we only need to know
one and do two vulnerabilities in the
logic on the tag it can figure out the
rest from there knowing one in advance
is not as difficult to task as it might
seem like obviously we already know one
for this payment card and maybe the T NP
3 xxx has a similar situation we could
search the documentation and source code
for common Mifare keys and try each one
of them against the key a and key B for
every sector and spoiler alert it'll
eventually work you'll eventually find
one but this is 2018 and you have
slightly newer information available to
you than I did when I did that myself
back into that
14 so let's head back to the internet to
find it so we're looking for a known key
for a Skylanders toy and some not so
creative searching Nets us an
interesting paper comprehensive security
analyses of a toys to life game and
possible countermeasures master's thesis
by Kevin Volk and when you find the
author's homepage you also find the fact
that he worked with toys for Bob
developers of Skylanders for a year now
the thesis never says Skylanders by name
but knowing what we know now it's easy
to recognize that's what it's about and
it contains exactly what we're looking
for and this it says that the first key
the key a in every toy is the same and
what does the paper say the first key is
yes okay so thanks to two research
papers we have a known key and we have
an attack vector and now we just need
software to run it that works with Liban
FC let's look for cipher text only
cryptanalysis and hardened Mifare
classic tags liban FC and a little ways
down the page we have an implementation
of the papers algorithms suitable for
use with Liban FC and if you compile and
run their lib NFC crypto one crack
program with a giant's figure you get a
valid key for block four in Sector one
and you can repeat that for a block in
each of the remaining sectors and just
to make sure let's try it with an even
later model trap team figure and we get
a valid key for block 9 sector 2 and you
can repeat that for a block in each of
the remaining sectors with this you can
get keys a for every Skylanders toy you
can then plug these into any Lib NFC
Mifare reading app or into Mifare
reading apps on your supported Android
phone assuming the apps recognize the
Skylanders toy as Mifare classic tags
and see the full contents of the toy
that looks like this just like in the
payment card you can see the access bits
on every fourth line sector 0 blocks 0
to 3 has the access bits 0 F 0 F 0 F
sector 1 blocks 4 to 7 and
every sector after that have the access
bits 7 f 0 f 0 8 if we look in NX P's
Mifare classic documentation we see that
we have to turn it into binary and we'll
learn this sector 0 the first four
blocks on the toy is completely
read-only every other sector is writable
by its key a we can't ever read each key
a so we always have to know them in
advance key B is all zeros which is a
really common password but it can't do
anything so it's all it's really good
for is being used to exploit other keys
there's more in there but that's enough
for us to know that we can completely
own any given Skylanders toy with a
method to obtain all the keys a we have
full read and write access to every
available block that's 15 sectors 3
writable blocks of 16 bytes each for a
total of seven hundred and twenty bytes
we can write anything we want to but
there's one more thing going back to
that quote we pulled from the Volk
thesis for the toys to work as they do
across multiple platforms and offline
and with every key a on every toy being
different there has to be some formula
or math that sets them that the portal
or the game knows about that has to be
based on some fixed immutable
information about the character like the
content in Sector zero so how do you
figure out what that formula is well if
you're like me or like the security
researchers who also eventually figured
it out you buy and you crack a lot more
toys as RFID and security researchers
discovered across 2014 and 2015 if you
collect enough keys and do some math you
can see patterns and how each sectors
keys relate to each other and come up
with more than one method to generate
the keys Volks thesis even included the
fact that the patterns and the keys
could be discovered documenting that
there were patterns but he didn't go so
far as to document what the patterns
meant so today I present the first
public cleanroom description of an
algorithm to generate the keys a for all
Skylanders figures released to date I'm
publishing this to support new
interoperability of active
Skylanders NFC toys by knowing an
algorithm used to set the read and write
passwords keys a we can interoperable
read and write our own data to
Skylanders NFC toys using our own NFC
harbours and software without tedious
manual cracking on a per table ASIS
thank you on NFC dot toys you'll find a
video showing me writing custom data
using a Mac using an off-the-shelf USB
NFC reader and reading that custom data
back out with a Raspberry Pi using an
off-the-shelf NFC add-on you'll also
find a sample implementation of the
algorithm in Python 2 so that's it for
Skylanders let's talk about Disney
infinity next round of applause who has
kids who are into Disney infinity No
round of applause who is personally into
Disney infinity and was devastated as I
was when they canceled the series Oh
y'all missed out so for everyone else
Disney infinity was Disney's entry into
the toys to life genre launched in 2013
as in Skylanders the toy you place on
their base is the character you play us
in the game unlike Skylanders which is
mostly all original IP Disney infinity
let you play with characters from many
different Disney properties all together
in an open-world sandbox called
the toy box there were also separate
story based environments for specific
environments and characters such as a
Pirates of the Caribbean playset various
Pixar playsets various Marvel playsets
and various Star Wars playsets sequels
were released in 2014 and 2015 resulting
in over 300 NFC toys between figures and
accessories this is a kanan jarrus
figure from Disney infinity as seen in
NXP tag info here again we can see that
it's an NX P tag also specifically a
Mifare classic tag we can see that
there's 320 bytes total on this tag we
can see its ID and it's 80 QA and it's
sa K and we can also see memory content
it's all crossed out and reports unknown
key and it's like that for all the way
down for all 321
but at least we can see the structure of
the storage on the tag which we couldn't
for the sky lender now we're less
fortunate working with Disney infinity
figures none of the ten keys or standard
keys so any exploit that relies on
knowing a key won't work in addition
Disney infinity came out in 2013 well
after an XP hardened the Mifare classic
to get into these figures we're going to
have to upgrade to the third of the
three standard tools I'll be discussing
specialized RFID testing equipment now
phones and live NFC compatible hardware
can get you far but to figure out NXP
tag NFC tags that are password protected
and not exploitable you'll need to be
able to listen in on the wireless
communication between the tag and the
reader and that means using more serious
Hardware the proxmark was an open source
design for RFID test equipment providing
high-end functionality at a much lower
price point than commercial test
equipment because NFC is a subset of
RFID it also it also works for NFC toys
but as specialized RFID test equipment
it also requires a more thorough
understanding of RFID in general
depending on where you get it from a new
proxmark 3 will run you two to four
hundred dollars their community is very
active and it's possible someone has
already figured out the tag you're
looking at although you'll need
technical expertise to translate
something that works on the proxmark to
something that works for a general
purpose NFC reader now a proxmark three
will let us place our own antenna right
up against the antenna in the NFC reader
and the antenna in the NFC toy and
listen in on the communication between
the figure and the base remember all of
this all of these data transfers are
happening wirelessly over-the-air even
though the toy and their base are only a
few millimeters of plastic apart if we
listen in we can get the keys
unfortunately that also means we're
going to need the video game and a
console to play it on since we need the
conversation to happen it was possible
to get into a Skylanders figure with
just a toy a thesis and a research paper
but not so for figuring out Disney
infinity and we'll talk about how that
affects our risk later now when you have
a proxmark listen in on the toy base
communication you learned that Disney
infinity toys use one key
the entire toy both key a and B for all
five sectors is the same neither one can
be read so you need to know it in
advance sector zero is read only and
sectors one through four are readable
and writeable by both key a and key B
four sectors three blocks each means
every toy has 192 bytes of storage we
can use for our own purposes the other
nice thing about having a proxmark is
that it can simulate a My Fair tag I
don't need to buy a bunch of Disney
infinity toys to get a bunch of keys to
see if there are patterns I can have the
proxmark pretend to be a tag with a
randomly generated ID and then have it
listen in on what key the base would use
for it and when you do this for dozens
of keys and regular patterns you find
there's no pattern at all when there
aren't any patterns the only solution
left is to reverse-engineer the
algorithm by figuring out where it lives
and then extracting it from the software
or firmware and as a liberal arts major
I don't really have the engineering
experience for that what I could do
though is what I was just doing but at
web scale so for about 16 months I ran a
web service that accepted a Disney
infinity toy UID
passed it along to a proxmark for
simulation listened in for the key and
then posted it publicly along with all
the other you ideas that had ever been
requested a kind of public UID key
database but finally another security
researcher did have the engineering
experience and so today I can present
the first public cleanroom description
of an algorithm to generate the keys a
and B for all Disney infinity figures
released
[Applause]
this algorithm supports new
interoperability of Disney infinity NFC
toys by knowing the algorithm used to
set the read and write passwords the
keys a and B we can interoperate and
write our own data to an infinity NFC
toy using our own NFC hardware and
software without tedious manual
simulation and sniffing on a per two
basis on NFC toys you'll find a video
showing me writing custom data using a
Mac and reading that custom data back
out with an Android phone using a
standard app from the Google Play Store
you'll also find a sample implementation
of that algorithm in Python 2 now there
haven't been any new Skylanders figures
in a year and Disney infinity was
cancelled in 2016 but amiibo which is
Nintendo's line of collectable figures
playing cards and cereal is still going
strong same thing as before a round of
applause who has kids who regularly
demand new amiibo figures so who has
been forced to pirate amiibo figures
either buying pre clone tags or clone
tags because the amiibos you want always
sell out before you can get one nobody's
gonna admit to that ok
for everyone else Nintendo launched
amiibo in 2014 and in classic Nintendo
fashion treats them as much as rare
collectibles for obsessive adults as
video game accessories for kids
resulting in lines in front of stores on
release days and toys selling out and
never being reissued because NFC support
is built into Nintendo's Wii U new 3ds
and switch consoles no games specific
reader is necessary for any game to
provide a me Bo support you just swipe
the toy right on the controller what
each amiibo toy does is different in
each game some support only specific
figures some store gameplay data on the
figure some will recognize any figure
Nintendo lists over 60 games in the US
with amiibo support and over a hundred
and 60 toys and there are also
additional Japan exclusive figures and
games this is a duck hunt figure from
Nintendo amiibo as seen in nxp tag info
an XP tagged info says duck hunt is also
an NX P this one a type 2 tag called n
tag 2
five with 504 bites made up of 126 pages
with four bites per page similar to that
pair of bluetooth headphones we saw
here's the memory content
unlike the Disney infinity figure nearly
all of the amiibo is readable but some
of it is marked as locked and blocked or
blocked if we were figuring out amiibo
ourselves we'd have to work it like we
did Disney infinity but we're luckier
here in two ways first by the time I got
around to trying amiibo toys researcher
Marcos del Sol vivaz had already figured
out how to derive their password from
the toys UID and services for it and
code have been published across the
internet since second many of us could
probably have independently replicated
his work just like fellow hope 2018 s
figure James chambers did while the
Skylanders math was pretty gnarly the
amiibo math as presented is a bitwise
exclusive or operation it's simple
enough that you can do it by hand with
pen and paper enabling us to write a
hundred four hundred and twenty eight
bytes of our own data onto any amiibo
NFC toy so today along with presenting
that public cleanroom description of an
algorithm to generate the PWD for
current amiibo figures I'm also handing
out a worksheet with an amiibo card and
it's UID so you can generate a PWD by
hand yourself right now in your seat if
you'd like these support new
interoperability of Disney amiibo sorry
Nintendo amiibo NFC toys by knowing an
algorithm used to set the right password
we can inter operatively write our own
data to an amiibo NFC toy using our own
NFC hardware and software without
needing to compute the PWD by hand on a
per day basis on NFC toys you'll find a
video showing me writing custom data
using a Raspberry Pi and reading that
data out using a Windows 10 laptop using
the open-source Google Chrome NFC
library and again you'll also find a
sample implementation of this algorithm
in Python too before I hand out those
worksheets though it's important to
consider those legal subtleties I
mentioned can we get in some sort of
trouble if we do this so a few points of
order again first I'm about to talk
about legal stuff but I am NOT an
attorney
this is not legal advice if you intend
to publicly discuss or publish your own
NFC toy efforts especially if you
explore areas beyond what this talk
covers like the data encryption or the
USB reader Hardware you should end your
US citizen or you ever intend to visit
the u.s. afterwards you should talk with
an attorney first
your local bar association can usually
refer you to an appropriate attorney
often with a free or reduced cost
initial conversation second this is
America where you can be sued by anyone
at any time for any reason and then
you're stuck having to defend yourself
this is lawsuit as threatened model if
you can't afford to defend yourself you
should be taking that into consideration
and third while the next several minutes
may be an interesting discussion at the
end of the day our opinion doesn't
matter everything we're going to cover
is a gray area of the law and I will be
positioning it as such because it's
things that can only be decided by a
judge in a court alright so why are we
suddenly talking about legal trouble
when I've just discussed a long history
of security research an academic
scholarship
some even acknowledged by the companies
affected which actively and directly
discuss security compromises in these
two NFC tags and I'm just taking the
next steps the reason is that legally
some NFC toys may not count as regular
NFC tags let's define NFC toys in a way
that might help clarify this NFC toys
are physical toys which embed NFC tags
to support some sort of interaction the
interaction is typically digital and is
important now there are probably toys
and embed NFC tags for tracking or anti
counterfeiting purposes and we just
don't know about them toys that use NFC
to support interactions typically
digital ones means the toy may contain
effect or involve digital content which
may be covered by copyright in 1998 the
United States passed the Digital
Millennium Copyright Act or the DMCA
most of you probably know it for section
five one two which establishes the safe
harbor provisions for online hosts this
is
when a copyright owner notifies her
upstream provider like your ISP or web
host that you've put their copyrighted
content online and they need to take it
down that's not the part we're concerned
with there's a different part of the
DMCA section 1201 known as the
anti-circumvention provisions 1201
establishes that circumventing or
working around any type of copy
protection mechanism is a crime as is
distributing tools to support others
circumvention x' you can be sued by the
copyright owner whose digital walks you
picked a civil action and also be
charged by the federal government a
criminal action it's a criminal action
this is the damage now it doesn't matter
whether you can or do use an NFC toy
with the video game it was intended for
that it may be intended to protect
copyrighted content is what makes any
possible circumvention illegal so maybe
let's take this seriously and see how
the DMCA concerns us based on excerpts
from the 2013 Department of Justice
prosecuting intellectual property crimes
manual fourth edition to prove a
violation the United the government must
establish the defendant willfully
circumvented a technological measure
that effectively controls access to a
copyrighted work for commercial
advantage or private financial gain
let's take those one at a time willfully
willfully has a specific legal meaning
but let's just go with the idea that
since you're all in this room you can't
argue that you didn't know it might not
be okay for you to do this someone who
just comes across those cleanroom
algorithms might have a stronger case
circumvented even if buying the toy
legally doesn't grant us the right to
crack its keys and put our own data on
it once we have the keys
we're not bypassing anything we're using
the keys as intended now we might be
eligible for other charges under other
laws but that's not a DMCA violation a
technological measure that effectively
controls access now obviously an NFC's
tags keys or passwords our technological
measures but effectively is a great
example of legally is not being plain
English despite sounding like it
effectively doesn't mean what it does to
us
in this room where you're probably
interpreting it as something like does a
good job at in court effectively
basically means does it exist to do this
to a copyrighted work if we're just
talking about the toy right now and the
existing data on the toy then if that
data is just facts and figures
it wouldn't be copyrighted and therefore
breaking into the NFC toy wouldn't be an
infringement finally for commercial
advantage or private financial gain if
you are just using these toys yourself
for yourself and there's no commercial
advantage then there's no commercial
advantage or private financial gain
if you're selling keys maybe that's an
issue but I'm not being paid to give
this talk and the content on NFC toys is
deeded to the public domain so I hope
that's evidence of my lack of profit
motive so here's where we stand if we're
only talking about the toy right now and
only about the existing data on the toy
because we need to tick all of the boxes
if the data on the toy is not a
copyrighted work then maybe we're not
violating the DMCA either civilly or
criminally now it doesn't mean we can't
be sued for this anyway it just means
that if we can afford to defend
ourselves we might have a defensible
case but if part of our legal standing
depends on the toy not being caught the
data on the toy not being copyrighted
well how can we figure that out let's
start by looking at what copyright
protects now if the data on the toy
includes things like the actual
character art and sound effects which
get used in the game those would be
original creative expressions if the
data is just this is an engine etoy with
this health and this experience level
those are discrete facts and figures
they're not creative expressions facts
and figures alone are not copyrightable
so how can we tell if the data is
uncopyrightable facts and figures or
copyrightable content well there's a few
ways some researchers might reverse
engineer the video game or its support
code to understand what data gets read
or written others might reverse engineer
the encryption on the data reading it
from the tag frequently to see what
changes get made but this is a talk
focusing on just the NFC tag and the NFC
toy and it turns out that there's a lot
we can learn just a
without doing any additional work at all
just by very carefully playing the game
and paying close attention to the tag
now I go into more detail on this on NFC
toys but the short version is we can
absolutely collect evidence that there
isn't anything original or copyrightable
on a figure being careful about changing
things in a game means we can figure out
which blocks are likely to store many of
our characters variables these are
blocks that Skylanders Giants rise to
that an ingénue toy during gameplay by
watching the clock we can see that these
two blocks probably store some kind of
playtime counter by testing different
nicknames we can see that these two
blocks store the nickname and that they
change depending on its length by
gaining golden experience we can see
that the same blocks that store the
playtime counter probably also store
gold and that these new blocks seem to
store experience the NFC tags in these
NFC toys are merely storage devices for
numeric text and data that track your
characters progress and can't be covered
by copyrights now there's one other
concern which we touched on briefly
before even if we're not circumventing
the an access control to read and write
toy data the toys are still used to
access content within a game and the
game content is almost certainly under
copyright here's that list again if
we're changing number four to mean the
game content instead of the data on the
toy how does that change number three
are the NFC tags and tag keys and
passwords effective access controls that
protect the game content and I think the
additional argument here hinges on that
particular legal definition of the term
effectively that is the point of the NFC
tags and keys isn't to protect the game
content they're there to only protect
the data on the tag every NFC toy that
protects that controls access to content
in a video game requires at least its
initial presence on an NFC reader to
access that content suggesting the
access control for the game content is
the NFC toy plus the reader plus the
code in the game all together every NFC
toy we've looked at uses keys and
passwords in different ways but they are
all able to perform that same function
in that same combination
despite those differences the Volk
thesis even asserts that using a static
key for sector 0 shows a
misunderstanding of the NFC technology
amiibos don't have read protection
another toy we didn't even get to
discuss the pokemon rumble you figures
don't have write protection you can do
whatever you want with them right out of
the pokeball this suggests that the NFC
tag keys and passwords aren't effective
access controls for the game contents
they don't exist to have any effect on
access to the game content if they can
be misunderstood or not used at all they
are simply there by virtue of an
arbitrary technical decision to make it
easier or harder to work with the toys
as data storage devices so maybe number
three is also a maybe not so we've
talked about NFC toys which are toys
which have NFC tags embedded on them we
talked a little bit about them and about
the toys to life genre of video games
and about NFC tags in general we talked
about various off-the-shelf hardware and
software you can use to explore these
NFC toys and how that exploration can
lead to determining read and write
credentials and how to write your own
data to three different types of NFC toy
finally we talked about the legal
implications of doing so and I have
hopefully established that using NFC
toys for your own data storage is
probably not circumventing an effective
access control probably not a copyright
infringement and that this work is
legally enabling new interoperability of
NFC toys with your own hardware while I
discussed legal matters I am NOT a
lawyer and this was not legal advice so
who believes round of applause that
obtaining credentials for an NFC toy is
legal and wants to assert their rights
to do so
so these are amiibo cards each card has
a meebo NFC tag inside just like the
full-size toys do I will be handing them
out out front after this talk clips to
each amiibo card will be a worksheet
which explains how to compute the PWD
for the amiibo card longhand I hope
you'll enjoy working through it I also
have Skylanders and other NFC toys
available for you and I hope you'll
please take one that's it for my talk
again we won't have time to do Q&A but I
will reply to you NFC Dot toys - any
question submitted please fill out your
feedback forms and either pass them up
or leave them on the tables out front
thanks so much
[Applause]