thank you everyone I know there's
absolutely nothing better to do at nine
o'clock on Saturday night in New York
then come to a talk about patents so
yeah so I'm an attorney at the
Electronic Frontier Foundation my full
title is senior staff attorney and Mark
Cuban chair to eliminate stupid patents
that is actually my job title my Cuban
supports patent work even though he
doesn't agree with everything the F F
does he also thinks there are a lot of
stupid patents we do a variety of things
on patent policy we litigate we've
challenged patents we challenged a
patent on we challenged a software
patent on podcasting that had been used
to threaten podcasters and actually got
that pattern and validated and ended up
going all the way to petitioning an
appeal on the Supreme Court which we
want about three or four weeks ago now
thank you
we also do like regulatory submissions
we blog and and we we go to Congress and
try and get them to either do good
things or not do bad things and I'll get
a get to some of that towards the end of
this talk but this talk is really going
to focus on a series we have the stupid
patent of the month that we have to
highlight problems with with software
patents there are a lot of problems with
the Patent Office that we will start to
get into in more detail and it's been
kind of an educational process it's good
for us to have the discipline to write
every week and we focus on on software
patents which is what because of the
sort of digital mission of vff but
before we get to software patents I
wanted to share with you some of my very
favorite stupid patents so let's go to
the method of swinging on a swing this
is not a joke this is a real patent that
issued I was filed for in 2002 it was I
was by I was filed by the child of a
patent a prosecutor who had a kid who
was very excited about finding a new way
to swing side to side on a regular swing
and helped his kid file this patent
application it was issued they got a lot
of bad press I mean really like what
like it is it is it's kind of silly
patent but not a software patent but
still you know what so this is one of my
personal favorites the user operated
amusement apparatus for kicking the
users products this was and you might
think like it's kind of it's amusing
like you know this is the real machine
maybe this isn't isn't that stupid a
patent but I I still think really no
matter how deep into the sort of white
of the patent system that that there's
always more sort of what to be had and
like I earned this patent it at talks
did before and someone came up to me and
said you know there's one of these on a
road in South Carolina between you know
some town and the beach it's like a
tourist thing and I was like oh that's
interesting I wonder if it's like the
actual patentee and I looked into it and
it's a machine that that this is this
this was on the road and you burn it's
from 1937 and you know this is this a
patent that was issued in 2000 so you
know there were knee like about 63 years
after the machine existed someone
decided to patent it which you know
shows that the Patent Office is not
always the best at finding
prior odd you know sometimes they allow
patents on things that already exist
so this this is a real this is again a
real patent patent drawing a patent and
name and you may think well you know
maybe the claims are a little different
you know in patent law or the claim at
the end of the patent is really the big
important thing this is you know like
it's a particular maybe it's on a
particular kind of brick made to build a
permit now it's really like you read the
claims and there's a bit of patentees
and a bit of a bit of you know sort of
pretend pretend complexity to it but
it's really a patent on bearing human
remains in a pyramid and you know if you
think the pen system is supposed to be
on something new you know I anyone in
this room aware of prior art on this
patent but you know like like what what
is the Patent Office doing like like
really like if you if you if used what
was the examiner like doing and and that
you know what like I just I just don't
know anyway so turning to to our beloved
software patents you know that we come
to the first question which is you know
what is a software patent it's it's not
really a clear definition of what a
software patent is it's it's certainly
not software like you sometimes you see
pseudocode in a software patent but you
very rarely see lines off of actual code
sometimes you'll see like a little a
little snippet here and there but but
generally it's like if you are if you're
at an organization and you have a
problem and you need to solve it with
software and you meet and you say well
what are we going to do about this the
software patent is the thing that
happens in the first 1 minute of that
meeting it's like well you know we've
obviously we're going to need this or
that structure or any server and like
you know all the hard work it's you know
it's just basically do a thing do a
thing with a computer
and we're so yeah if you look at
software patents they'll often be
flowcharts there'll be discussions of
using a processor and memory and like at
that level of generality and you know if
you if anyone who actually programs for
living like yeah you know I do in fact
use processes as part of this this is
not particularly inventive to tell me to
apply processing and memory to solve a
problem with software so what why do we
why do we care about software patents
like when the sort of my opposite
numbers the people who are UVM Utley in
favor of software patents so the the
kind of people from companies like IBM
or the intellectual property owners
organization when they talk about
patents they'll say well you know if
there are no patents anyone can just
steal your work and that's terrible and
there'll be no incentive to innovate and
you know that's not really true because
the the patent system is not about
copying copying is not an element of
patent infringement if you write a
program and you release it and then
someone sends you a letter saying I own
I have a patent on let me say with from
my favorite you know on on using a
computer to send notifications and your
app has notifications and you've never
heard of this person you've never read
this pattern there I'm completely
unknown in the community they had
nothing to do with any of the operating
system hardware anything to do with
anything to do with your app that does
not matter it doesn't matter at all the
question is do you infringe which is
patent there's the claims at the end
that has I claim XY and Z do you do XY
and Z and then is the patent valid and
then that's a question of was it new and
at the Patent Office that often means
really you know did someone else patent
it before because as we'll talk about in
more detail as we discuss some of these
patents the Patent Office is not great
at looking at prior
which is stuff that happened before you
applied prior are can be written it can
be publications but it can also be
things that are on sales so anything
that's in the App Store on github and
some kind of open source project or
whatever if it's available publicly its
prior art but very very little of that
prior rot is getting through filtering
in any meaningful way to the Patent
Office and so you get these patents
where they're they're really broad
they're from people who didn't
contribute in any meaningful way to
what's being done in the real world and
they're being asserted against people
who are our contributors are writing
original software and in the sense it's
very different from copyright copyright
there's their debates and questions
about how broad copyright should be on
software you make tour about Google the
Oracle and api's and reverse engineering
there's issues but at the end of the day
like if you copy a huge amount of code
you're probably and you're probably
infringing someone's copyright and it's
right there in the name of the legal
right copying and if you do it with
permission and that permission may be a
software license particularly in free
license world you get something it's a
free software project you fork it you
have you contribute to it whatever
you're operating within this zone of
permission and creativity and you can't
be then sued by the person who wrote the
eternal or whatever ten years ago
because they've licensed it to the world
under these under these terms
the problem with patents says someone
comes in from outside who has nothing to
do with anything with a piece of paper
and says alright now you owe me money
now now you can't do what you want to do
so let's get to some stupid patents
story too much about reading a little
text but we had one of our very first
stupid patents of the month was from
patent assertion entity called blue
spike that has a number of patents
basically they're they're on
fingerprinting and they've been very
active that's they've sued a number of
companies with mixed success the patent
there was the subject of this article
eventually got invalidated and that was
upheld on appeal
but this they still have other patents
in the family and other patents and
they're still actually suing companies
and they were they were very salty about
this article I got a lot of hate on
Twitter from friends of the inventor who
were extremely outraged that someone
would would critique this brilliant
genius who suggested like that using
reference generators feature selectors
comparing devices and recorders like you
could do it with software you know you
could do with hardware you could do it I
don't know with like water molecules but
you could you could do it with software
so so now he like owns this idea in his
mind for everything and this this kind
of highlights a recurring problem with
software patents in that the the system
software patents often involve claims
that are very very functional it's like
do a thing with a computer you know ever
comparing device or notifications or or
you know whatever and there's sort of
the this the Patent Office doesn't
really have a good sense of what's
amazingly easy and what's hard and so
they'll give patents that kind of have
both problems and that you get a patent
on something that's just mind-numbing ly
mundane like you know sending in a
second mobile will get to a out of
office email patent and then you get
patents on quite challenging things but
the patent doesn't actually tell you how
to do it it just says you know use them
on structures use some memory use you
know use a processor and do it with
software and good luck to you and you
know so people are claiming broadly are
they claiming really really obvious
ideas that claiming broadly are they
claiming basically the solution there
clay this is the problem with software
patents particularly as people get to
claim rather than rather they claim the
problem rather than the solution rather
than this is how I'm going to solve it
this particular way they're like solving
this problem X with a with with software
is my pattern and that so another one we
did we wrote up
this was early last year IBM patent I
found this just trolling the Gazette so
every Tuesday there about 300,000
patents issued every year so if you
check my things about 6,000 a week get
issued something like that and we find
stupid patents of the month in a variety
of ways we look to things that are being
asserted and trolling campaigns we look
for your people send them to us by email
but sometimes I just go and read The
Gazette comes out every Tuesday if you
know the classification system you can
kind of know where the garbage tends to
cluster and I'll just go and spend you
know a morning clicking through two or
three hundred patents to find some
really dumb and make fun of IBM and this
yeah so I just found the Gazette it's
the title is like you know out of office
email and the pen in fairness to IBM so
you know this was issued this was issued
last year I wrote about it right after
was issued in fairness to IBM it wasn't
just the idea of out of office email
there was a little tweak and the tweak
was that you could set up your out of
office email so that it would start
sending the message like a couple of
days before you went on vacation so it
would say I will be out of the office
next week you know this is a major
project you know wait till maybe it can
wait or whatever you want but like from
a technical perspective like this is not
this is not inventive this is just
clicking this is just adjusting settings
and software that if it doesn't already
exist is extremely mundane and extremely
easy to write I often give the example
that if you invented a car you wouldn't
give someone a patent for the idea of
driving the car before 8 a.m. on Sunday
because obviously you can drive a car at
a be like that that's just ridiculous
but you do see software patents that are
basically like that they're like you one
of us stupid patents of the month it's
not
in this presentation but it's it's on
updating computer game software to
update like if you have a game that's in
that's like the NFL or whatever and a
stadium changes may be a team move
Stadium you update the game so that the
graphics of the stadium isn't you and
it's just it's just a pen on updating
software like there's nothing in the
pattern that explained that solves any
new technical problems it's just like
people have been updating software and
over the Internet of course people have
been updating software over the internet
for a little while now but you know this
is a patent that was issued you know two
or three years ago and it was it was
asserted it was sue a he got sued and a
bunch of other companies got sued with
it and so one of the big problems here
is like you're thinking well out of
office email you know I heard it ring a
bell something that exists you know here
is a drawing from the patent and this is
you know the patent was filed I forget
the priority day but it's recent it's
like a 20 20 teens patent patent
application and you know this in 1998
screencap from notes I you think maybe
the examiner should be looking if we
assume the software patents are a thing
that should exist that the the examiner
should at least look at some software
but this patent was examined and on a
patent they'll show there's a list of
references considered by the examiner
they're all patents like the the you're
talking about out of office email and
the Patent Office isn't looking at any
software at all it's only other patents
so so this is particularly punishing for
the free software world where people
have philosophical objections to patent
so they're not filing them it's like a
40,000 you know filing a patent paying
the lawyer all of that it's like a forty
thousand dollar project to to get it in
and that's a really expensive way to
create private it doesn't actually it's
not prymaat if you publish it online you
put it on github or whatever that's
prior art
but the Patent Office will only look at
it if it's a pattern and you know I'm
gonna spend 40 grand to file a patent in
the hope that one day some examiner is
gonna look at it
fortunately IBM was sufficiently shamed
by the media coverage of this patent
that they actually disclaimed it which
is I was quite surprised by I would have
thought they would just ignore us I mean
that's what I would do if I was their PR
person but which means they file a Form
with the Patent Office that says this is
now dedicated to the public so I can I
can give you all the good news that if
you want to write an out-of-office email
client that sends the out of office
email a day or two early you can now do
that without infringing a patent so
that's how IBM reacted IBM you know kind
of figured well well we'll head this off
at the pass we'll will accept a little
bad press and give the patent to the
public that has unfortunately not been
our experience with all of these all of
these place it's a lot of that a lot of
the patterns we write about are by what
are informally called patent trolls
companies that that assert patents sort
of as their business model there's you
know no clear definition of control but
you know in our view if asserting a
patent is your main game then we think
that's pretty trollee but the problem
with patent trolls is you know if your
main game is litigating then you know if
you you start to see every problem as a
litigation problem and so getting
criticism maybe is also a litigation
problem so 2015 we wrote about a company
called then called Eclipse IP they
changed their name I suspect to get out
from the Google results
they're now called what is it electronic
technologies LLC something anyway
something extremely Monday something
very hard to Google and this was a
patent on a kind of notification there
are a lot of patents on just note of
little tweaks to notifications little
tweaks to geolocation like pretty much
any kind of thing you do with an app
there's just this huge cluster of
patents on any kind of small
modification to the feature you can
think of the inventor in this case is a
patent lawyer and that's not uncommon
with a lot of trolli patents there was a
guy that sued Twitter for asserting a
patent on having a social network but
with famous people and he he later in
full disclosure my firm represented
Twitter in that case he later in
deposition admitted he had never an
Alana code
he thought of the patent in half an hour
and you know sort of half an hour's work
social network of famous people they're
famous people on Twitter twittering
fringes that all that went all the way
to a jury that the judge didn't grant
summary judgment so you know without
without being specific going to a jury
is expensive it's very very common in
patent litigation that will cost more
than a million dollars so you know
someone spends half an hour patent
lawyers spends half an hour thinking
about something that costs you a million
bucks not super fair and how of you
anyway turning back to this patent
lawyer we wrote about this this case
eclipsed IP had filed a number of
lawsuits with this patent see in the
same family this was a new pattern that
issued from the family that had been
asserted very widely and we were we were
annoyed because other patents in the
family had been found invalid and this
was under the I'm gonna talk in more
detail about Alice PC LS bank this does
this decision from the Supreme Court
that says you can't have an abstract
software patent where it's an abstract
idea on a generic computer came came
down in 2014
has been really good for a lot of these
really really low value software patents
been thrown out and we were concerned
that they had issued more the pen office
had issued more patents in the same
family even though others were being
thrown out the prosecutor they hadn't
disclosed this to the Patent Office at
the time we called them out but didn't
you know it started to get interesting
after that so so the inventor the
lawyers got hasta Meyer sued me
personally sued EF f and I was pretty
mad his lawyer his lawyers name was
Sanford Esmond goes by Sandy and he had
already been in the news for a trademark
threat against a start-up and I was
Technica people had being kind of
getting stuck into him on the on the on
the comments and I will fully admit that
these comments were pretty immature
sandy Esmond people had people had been
modifying that very slightly but we we
fortunately found a law firm that
represented us for free and we send them
a very detailed letter explaining that
this speech was protected by the First
Amendment
one of the disputes was they were very
upset that we had complained that the
patent office hadn't been told about
this court decision and they were like
there is no ethical duty to tell the
Penn office about a court decision this
ethical duty to disclose power out that
you know only rule only applies to
actual pro art like journal articles and
so on but you know the actual manual for
patent examination and procedure and
Federal Circuit law is extremely clear
like there are decisions directly on
point that is not the case you do have
to disclose do have to disclose legal
decisions that are that are material and
which you know was pretty ironic because
part of their criticism was that I'm not
a patent prosecutor I'm not a member of
the patent bar and so they were like you
don't know anything about anything we
know all about patent prosecution and
their lead complaint was 100% wrong
anyway so we write back we said we were
100 we were really not not gonna give in
I got some I got some pretty negative
press and then and they abandoned the
case three days after they served it
which was a wise decision it was it was
a really really foolish lawsuit in my
view they are entitled to disagree with
our opinions but they cannot use the
courts to censor us so on that topic
courts trying to censor I will turn to
another stupid pad of the month this is
a patent owned by an Australian company
called global equity management si and
it's basically speaking very very
broadly and loosely it sits on a GUI of
managing different operating systems
managing storage and different operating
systems virtual having virtual
virtualization and you so you have
virtual cabinets you have a thing to
click on why they bla I didn't think it
was a very good patent the inventor
disagrees he is entitled to that view
but you know I think I'm well within my
rights to criticize the patent but we
got we got a kind of a nasty Graham
about it and so this is from an
Australian lawyer so I'll read it in my
best Australian accent I demand of
apology for slander and differ Tory
statements does that does anyone know
what F Atari means I'm not sure if
that's a that's a legal term of art that
I'm not not familiar with we have been
consulted by global equity management is
a proprietary limited here and after
repeated - is our client to write you in
relation to the defamatory false and
malicious slander which you and the
Electronic Frontier Foundation made
concerning a client on Eire v org at a
website that's naughty FF - org in the
attached article
the sad statement was made available to
the viewing of the worldwide public with
the intention of portraying our clients
intellectual property a stupid
I mean guilty in addition to numerous
other malicious laws and misleading
statements to be at the 400 p ry ear
coin yes you know and actually filed a
suit lawsuit in the Supreme Court of
South Australia and they got an
injunction temperate they got a
preliminary injunction which they served
on iff asking us to take down take down
the article and to never talk about
their intellectual property again which
you know that's really not how it works
in the United States and fortunately
there is a law called the speech act and
I forget some god-awful backronym as
these things usually are that allows you
to go to court to sue to have a foreign
order declared unenforceable if it's
contrary to the First Amendment and it's
it's basically a law against libel
tourism so you can't just go to
Australia or the United Kingdom get a
judgment against a United States
organisation like EF F and and enforce
it in US courts and so we we sued them
in the Northern District of California a
federal court here they never appeared
even though they actually were filing
they were litigating patent cases in the
same district literally in the courtroom
down the hall and we we won we got a
great judgement explaining why our our
article was protected by the First
Amendment and why an injunction asking
us to take it down and
not speaking about there I mean that for
a First Amendment lawyer and injunction
telling you not to speak about an entire
topic ever again it's just it's just so
far outside what is contemplated in US
law and then just sort of as a coda to
all this that patent got thrown out so I
said the the patent trial and appeal
board which is a body within the Patent
Office ended up ended up finding this
patent invalid
I think the prior art was it was oh I
forget anyway there was partitionmagic
partitionmagic was the was the prior
right anyway so that was that you know
this is these are these are kind of a
distraction we don't want to have to
deal with these lawsuits we just want to
be able to express how huge but
fortunately the First Amendment has come
through for us first I think the the
first case was dismissed because
speculating obviously but that the the
lawyers will sense that it was you know
however much he might disagree with us
that was not going to be a successful
suit and it was not going to be any fun
either at least for him and that the and
then with the Australian suit then the
the speech act in the First Amendment
really came through for us so anyway
turning from stupid part of the month I
want to get to sort of some big picture
patent policy stuff and it's gonna go
just quickly go through mostly talking
about Alice this decision from 2014
about software patents but before that
give you a this super quick idea about
some of the things that have happened in
the last 10 or so years and it's
generally been pretty good I mean the
pent system is still very very flawed in
our view and it is still interferes with
free software in ways that it should
but there have been a lot of good things
eBay is a decision from 2006 that is is
really quite a major decision in that it
makes it it used to be routine that if
you want a patent case you got an
injunction stopping the other person
from doing what they selling or
distributing or whatever and sort of in
the around this time research in motion
got sued on a software patent or
relating to the BlackBerry and they were
looking at an injunction preventing the
sales of blackberries and they ended up
paying six hundred and fifty million
dollars to to that patent owner and that
pressure the injection is really kind of
what drove that I think and so it's it's
it's quite a while ago now but I without
it the world would be even crazier case
IV telefax made it obvious snows made a
little bit easier to show you something
as obvious based on prayer at the
Federal Circuit which is the court below
the Supreme Court that his patent cases
is kind of even though they're not
supposed to is kind of undone it in a
lot of ways the America Invents Act was
a law in 2011 created new processes at
the Patent Office to challenge patents
has been much more successful in my view
than expected much more bad for the
people on the other side than they
expected I think and so that's how we
challenged this patent on podcasting I
mentioned the Startalk and similarly
that's how the the patent on virtual
cabinets got invalidated octane makes it
easier to get fees that has been used in
in some pretty abusive troll cases and I
think is a deterrent if Alice P CLS Bank
get to that at a moment so big big one
and then T C Heartland is a case about
venue it's very in the weeds on law but
it's about the interpreting the statute
that tells you which kind of which which
federal quote you can file in previously
things many of you might have even heard
of this because I got it got so out of
whack
it was even on like John Oliver that the
Eastern District of Texas particularly
the courthouse in Marshall was totally
dominating patent litigation at one
point more than a thousand cases were
before one judge in Marshall that was
about 25 percent of all patent
litigation in the country which is
completely nuts and in our view is
really fueled by that court having a lot
of local rules that tilted the playing
field and that's how they attracted this
business it was a pretty small town it
was very lucrative for a lot of a lot of
like restaurants printers whatnot and
you know that I I've heard Eastern
District Texas lawyers openly talk about
the judges that started to bring this
there as rain makers you know it is
really not the job of a federal judge to
be a Rainmaker for a town but it was
pretty shameless and it's still it's
still a problem of international
companies can still be sued in any
district so if if your Samsung you're
here still gonna enjoy the barbecue down
and Marshall but it's going from about
20 fights it's going from at its peak I
think you got to about 35 or 45 I mean
it was a lot it was like at least a
third of patent suits were being filed
in a detects and now it's back down to
about ten percent just still crazy but
it's not as crazy so Alice our friend
Alice has a great graphic by Hugh Dondre
who works at e FF he Alice is a decision
it came out of a case that was basically
on a patent on what's the word a sort of
settlement off if you have two parties
you want to get one money to the one to
the other but there's you know trust
issues use Bitcoin of course not you use
a trusted third party and it was
basically a patent on on the idea of you
trusted third party and but with a
computer of course and went up to the
Supreme Court Supreme Court said section
101 of the patent Act which is basically
what's patentable you can't patent an
idea you can't patent something that
already exists in nature it has to be a
new and useful machine-or-transformation
you and you and you and you and they
said under the statute you can't patent
a abstract idea that is implemented on a
generic computer you can't just say do a
thing do it here's a good idea do it on
a computer it is not the death of all
software patents particularly the
Federal Circuit as there's a few cases
from the Federal Circuit really pushing
back against the idea that it's the
death of all software patents but it is
it has been the death of a certain kind
of software patent and a lot of them
were the really the worst the kind of
patents that were being asserted against
500 companies at once that we're on you
know voting online or or you know
tracking a vehicle really really broad
broad patents a lot of them got thrown
out so it's been a really excellent
decision it's been a lot of backlash
against it judge more as a judge on the
Federal Circuit around the time of that
before it got to the Supreme Court where
you know basically writing for the
Supreme Court in her dissent she said
that a decision in validating the claims
would decimate the electronic and
software industries and I'm sorry to say
she was correct no software has been
written since June 2014
Manny Schechter chief patent counsel IBM
patents promote innovation Alice
decision as progeny or juicing
innovation you see it might be a missing
step somewhere in there legislation is
needed so that America continues to be a
worldwide innovation leader and this is
the the folks we fight with in the
public policy well they have this
completely unexamined assumption that
patents always promote innovation this
if you weaken patents and Alice in some
ways weakens patents it makes it harder
to get patents that this is going to
hurt innovation R&D and software is is
going up it went up much more in 2015
that it did in 2014 it's completely
divorced from reality as a view but it
is a view that is extremely strongly
held it is a religion from the patent
people so the intellectual property
owners association is proposing
legislation this is the language 101 B
now the only exception of the subject
matter eligibility if it basically
already existed in nature or exists
solely in the human mind and so to give
you an idea of what that would mean
right now we have a client who is being
threatened by hodder & stoughton a UK
publisher he releases language lessons
online and hodder and stoughton claimed
to be the licensee of a patent that is
having language lessons on a recorded
medium in a certain order it's it's a
really really banal order it's basically
having call question-and-answer on a
recorded medium but that would satisfy
this it's recorded meets a tape a tape
is a physical thing it doesn't exist
solely in the human mind so that would
make that at least under 101 it without
be eligible you would still have to
satisfy obvious Ness or whatnot but
we've seen kind of what a great job the
Patent Office does of that and if the if
the Penn office finds itself having
getting patents on language lessons on
tape where the language is structured in
a certain way
like it has to go and find language
lessons structured in that way to deny
the patent if this becomes the wall
which is really really nuts so we we
have this say by alice project where
it's upper ffs org Alice where we tell a
bunch of stories about companies that
have managed to use the Alice decision
to defend themselves against threats
from really really stupid patents and
we're sort of preparing to fight back
because there are IBM the intellectual
property owners organization that AI PLA
which is the intellectual property
lawyers and a bunch of other
organizations are really trying to
pressure Congress nothing has been
formally introduced and that's going
anywhere yet there's a there's a bill in
the house that's been introduced by
someone that's not even on the right
committee so it's not really going
anywhere but the senator Coons in the
Senate is on the intellectual property
on judiciary and which has intellectual
property jurisdiction and he I think
would would be likely to you know
willing to it to introduce something
like this so we're you know we're gonna
be looking for people who actually write
software or know about software and care
about software to be to be ready to kind
of counter messages on this and you may
see early next year us doing call outs
for people to call Congress or do visits
I went to Congress to the hill in June
and did some visits with staffers to
sort of tell them that you know the sky
has not fallen since the house decision
IBM gets nine thousand pet got nine
thousand patents last year it doesn't
need to get twenty thousand this is this
is everything is going to be fine
but it's mostly you know from apps this
is defense there is not there's not a
move to abolish all software patents
in Congress that's not a lot of momentum
for that I think you know that's a
long-term battle that this stupid pad in
the month series is a network is pot off
but for the moment really trying to
defend Alice and with that I think we
can go to questions I think there's a I
think there's a microphone here for the
open source community sorry for the open
source community yes is there
what sort of protections does one have
when one unintentionally infringes on
one of these esoteric gotcha type
patents if you're not selling the
product what can they do to you so
unfortunately if you're there's really I
can't give you a particularly satisfying
answer there is a difference if you've
never heard of the patent there is you
are at higher risk for willful
infringement where there's theoretically
treble damages are available at the
judges discretion in cases of willful
infringement thing about willful
infringement as though is that you don't
get there unless you've gone through the
whole litigation and lost and you know
so by that point you know you've already
you're already out so much money on the
litigation it's but from you know you
can try and document your code well so
that it's easy for people to find so
they can take they can defend themselves
by showing it as as prior art you can
but unfortunately the the problem is
because they come so much from outside
the community there's this if the
pattern were found valid and you know
you you infringe you could you know use
your that that's that's that's enough I
mean hopefully with Alice that will give
you a good defense against a lot of the
kind of patents that the open source
community would be worried about but a
lot of that sort of still in flux the
Federal Circuit's still still grappling
with what Alice means and
so it doesn't it doesn't provide like
sort of a complete software patents of
dead comfort
so I say you have yeah weed you can't be
the man you really shouldn't have to
worry too much about the intent there's
really not much willfulness that you can
you know infuse into an open-source
discovery and so I think you are
relatively safe
well yeah on willfulness but but on
infringement it doesn't matter if you're
if the intent is irrelevant in terms of
punitive damages it is very important
yeah I think there are a lot of open
source projects the cost of patent
litigation itself would be just would be
we'd demolish them yeah I'm just you
know that's my opinion I thank you in
good shape hi so I was wondering if you
could elaborate a little bit on the
Australian lawsuit that you mentioned I
guess I have a few questions that are
sort of around that theme like one of
them is you know did the if I've
actually try to challenge the Australian
court case and and where did that go and
also I like are you personally banned
from Australia did you get arrested if
you were served if you showed up in
Australia yeah I mean I wish Australia
sucks
Wow
yeah we didn't FFF didn't appear and I
honestly don't know what happened they
served us with a preliminary injunction
and that I gave up or we don't know they
never they never served us with anything
else they never properly served us with
the moving papers either so it was a
pretty pretty hot last effort okay hey
so first off thank you for all of the
hard work you do protecting developers I
am a developer slash product owner and I
am responsible for you know a team of
six other people very small but you know
I love my project and I wanted to last
so when my client comes to me and says
my investors
to give me a million dollars if I have
ten software patents yeah what do I do
yeah you look you know I'm not so
judgmental on these kind of things I
think you know I personally think
software patents a bad for the world and
that it's better if we don't get them
but I understand that people operate in
the world that exists you know you may
not want to pay taxes to fund Wars but
you know that's that's the law and
you're the alternative is going to jail
it's not the patents you do you do you
know I think you can you most soft pure
software companies that are that are
either software-as-a-service or selling
suffered our fairly patent light it tint
moist software patents come like the
real volume comes from the Giants so you
know I've been making fun of IBM but you
know there are other Google gets like
3,000 pounds a year Microsoft gets four
or five thousand a year there there are
some venture people that that care about
patents and prefer prefer patents there
it's certainly not all and on software
patents it's a it's a quiet mixed mixed
view that there's been some empirical
research on this asking venture
capitalist what they think of software
patents and and the those that do care
even those that care often it's not that
I really think the software patent is
gonna do you as a company any good it's
just gonna be there'll be something left
in the jar if if it all goes belly-up
and and that's you know that's as a
founder that's really not very little
comfort but yeah and I you know I think
with sometimes I get similar questions
from people who are at the bigger
companies where they're pressure to
apply and help the help the health of
patent lawyers apply and say like you
know like you you got to do your job but
you know if they do start to write
ridiculously broad claims or they're
trying to penned stuff that you know is
and five years ago like push back you
know don't don't let them get away with
it thank you
sure oh good evening do you have a
position on what might be characterized
as standards essential patents you know
like I write a lot of software like in
the actual TV space and you know the FCC
has laws that say you must conform with
these standards yeah but these standards
have patents that come along with them
in order to implement them yeah we
haven't done a ton of work on on
standard essential patents in the last
few years I'm just you know so many
other other issues bubbling but we
definitely are on the lookout for cases
where there's abuse where where people
get so you might have heard a brand of
reasonable non-discriminatory royalties
and some companies take very different
views of their obligations when they
have when they're when they have reined
obligations and first standards so and
it is unfortunately part of why some
companies want to get patents so they
have a little bit of a little bit more
leverage in when standards are being
developed but yeah we're you know it is
it is particularly frustrating when good
standards aren't created because of
patent risk and patent pen where ease
from from bad actors but you know and
it's particularly terrible when people
do follow standards because you know
it's a standard you have 80 to 11 or
whatever and then someone jumps out from
under a rock and says I have a patent
that covers this standard and everyone
everyone and their dog can get sued so
yeah we but but it's it's good to sort
of have it brought up because there's
actually an area that we want to think
about more into my work in
yeah we get we got about three minutes
so we definitely have time for a
question if anyone anyone else oh yeah
someone coming up our local paper of the
Village Voice had a whole issue more
than 10 years ago devoted to how
demoralized the whole Patent Office was
that the patent examiner's were
discouraged poorly paid understaffed and
it was basically a tragic mess is that
your sense of what's going on there now
yeah I mean we try not to make too much
like fun of the examiner's and if you
they don't have enough time the the
average per patent application from from
when it was first filed to an claims
issue is 22 hours of examined our time
and only you know maybe half of that is
on looking for prior odds so you can
understand why they're looking at
patents that it's much more accessible
to them they're not gonna you know
getting onto github and studying looking
looking at at software projects there is
gonna be way more work and take way
longer and they don't have that time so
the system is just not set up to really
do a good job and unfortunately you see
that you see that particularly in areas
that a patent why there's so much non
patent art like sulfur and but and it
varies there's actually some really kind
of disturbing research that patent
examiner's that progress and stay there
longer and get promoted they get less
and less time to do it which you know
usually it would make sense like you're
you're you're getting better at your job
you're supposed to do things quicker but
they're already given so little and it's
very clear that the examiners they get
to stay become rubber stamps and they
have more obvious honest findings of
litigated patents
if the examiner was more senior it's
more likely the pattern would be found
invalid in court if it's challenged
which is exactly the opposite of what
you would you would want to see if it
was kind of a function if it was you
know if the system was set up well and
and with that I will I will end it
thanks for coming out
[Applause]