oh it's so lovely to see all of you how
many people here have no idea who the
hell I am
you're in for a ride thank you so much I
talk over other ones being done I don't
know why you turned away being in a
small box with Richard Stallman but if
it's your choice I get it everyone's got
personal personal choices so there I was
at the South California climate data
protection project last January 2017
that's a little event of climate people
who were working together to try to save
the objective observed data of actual
real climate change in the United States
entire country and a concern that was
valid and real and which time has proven
that much of that data is probably at
risk and efforts will be made to remove
it from public view they brought me in
to talk and give consultation and
generally be a problem because I work
for the Internet Archive archive.org
and so the Internet Archive which as it
says is a nonprofit library of millions
of free books is also the home of the
wayback machine one of the jewels of the
internet not a government institution
funded by donations and nonprofit grants
and provides a snapshot why bfy be a
microphone why not something else
microphone neutral anyway so at the
Internet Archive we have this Wayback
Machine and and it's really this
beautiful thing you type in a URL and
you get to what's there and so one of
the problems of saving web histories you
have to save it when it happens so you
have to know something's important so
part of that is that the archive just
randomly goes through billions of web
pages that that screenshot says 305
billion but that's a that's a blatant
lie it's currently 479 billion and so
they're just constantly grabbing
everything and so I was brought in
because we talked about like well how
can we save it for for later and in all
those pieces right and I had this while
I was in there I got this news and the
news was that my father's surgery hadn't
gone so well and he was having a heart
valve fix up in North Carolina and it
had come down to you know he had he has
three children he one of them was sick
one of them couldn't get out away from
his job and then there was me so I
offered to be the guy who would come
down so I flew basically from California
right to my house in New York and flew
immediately with no warning to spend a
few days with my father and and and the
coalescence was extremely difficult
because they had nicked some things
inside and he was being treated and you
know when you're taking care of a parent
you you know it takes a lot out of you
and you want to be there and you have to
be there all the time especially if
you're worried about the production and
and and and you know amount of a
hospital and health care is difficult
it's it's a matter of like great highs
crushing lows lots of profanity out of
your family and and generally getting it
due but the archive is an extremely
great place and has a Oh wonderful
[Applause]
delighted that the same consistent
quality has greeted me lo these many
years alright so so the you know archive
was extremely nice about this I work
remote why not what worked from the
hospital so I'm where I'm a down there
taking care of my father and his various
elements and its ups and downs and so
you know like the archive you have all
these beautiful things like old 78rpm
records and old shareware cd-roms you
know it's not just books it's the
ability to play old software and look at
old software like that or all sorts of
crazy flyers and and and music pieces
and even of course these beautiful scant
materials and because of the method we
use we scan about a thousand books a day
and we scan them pretty nicely so you
get a like a pretty good look so there I
am taking care of my dad and it's
supposed to be for a few days but it
turns into like a week and a half and
now I'm like oh shit I got to take care
of dad but wait a minute what about the
manuals so then we got to get into the
manuals so I've done a number of
projects over the years involving the
real time taking of things from real
space to prevent their loss these are
technical reference manuals going back
about 70 years for a wide variety of
electronic testing equipment they're
beautiful you either look at them and
you say well of course you have to save
these or why are you saving them I'm in
the of course you saved them they're
beautiful they're evidence of things
before they come from a time of
technical writing we probably won't see
again and so at the time they told me
when I had gone there a year previously
that yeah they're gonna throw them out
in three days and we were able to get a
wide variety of people to show up with
two days notice and go through and box
them find all the unique ones sort them
all through until we had taken all of
the
unique ones and ended up with 1,600
banker boxes and we stored them in a
storage unit nearby and it was I had
arranged for a truck to come take them
to the Internet Archive but I wasn't in
Maryland I was in North Carolina taking
care of my dad there's multiple things
you could do in this situation
to get things right I decided okay I'll
get into my car and drive five hours up
there and then arrange for them to be
forklifted in here's what the manuals
look like when they're getting ready to
go to the archive and here's me don't do
this that moves so the you know so so we
forklifted these little suckers away and
we were able to do it and then I drove
right back from Maryland right back to
North Carolina
basically later that day ten hours
driving to be able to be back with my
dad and and again taking care of him
getting him to walk and doing everything
else and I want to stress right now that
he was taken care of beautifully they
gave him the things he needs he is
healed wonderfully my father is
absolutely fine
so I on the last day I was there though
I had run into another problem which was
oh shit I'm going to Australia on
Saturday and it's Friday and I haven't
booked a flight and I'm sick like I'm
feeling sick
I've got like the flu or something I
don't feel well
so what does what does Jason do Jason
goes back to the hotel room Jason gets
all of the linens that are in the room
stacks them all up on a bed Jason gets
into the pile of linens and items on one
bed turns off all the lights
drinks half a bottle of nyquil turns on
endless bill burr comedy routines and
goes to sleep for six hours to sweat it
out I recover feeling good and take a
plane that I was able to book land in
New York and one hour and a half later
I'm on a flight to Australia so I'm
gonna get to go to Australia alright
stop often with a stop often to buy with
the ridiculous McDonald's Arabic which
still looks weird to me
and then haagen-dazs even more weird you
know do you all know that like
haagen-dazs is a totally made-up word
right it was created in New Jersey to
sound Danish alright so I go to
Melbourne everything's awesome I've got
two wonderful things I'm going to do I
am going to speak at an event about
copyright and I'm going to host
something called a white night arcade
fun where I'm going to host a night of
arcade playing for four or five hours
both these organizations have brought me
in Acme and museum next all right and
then I had a heart attack an actual
heart attack it had blocked a part of my
heart so that line on the left is
supposed to be a lot
longer than it is so something's in
there killing me they told me later I
would either have died instantly or not
but almost but anyway so Melbourne's a
lot of fun because you see I don't know
I had a heart attack so I'm going around
to this place and I'm looking at all the
Amit you have to see by the way the
graffiti of Melbourne is a is a wonder
of the world right and I'm working on my
talk and I've got a really cool rental
place right near the talks and I walked
sixteen thousand six hundred and forty
six steps I am an overachiever as was
already indicated my talk was called mad
facts among copyright fury road it was
about it was basically a warning to
Australians that if they adopt the
American regime it will be a wasteland
of misery and sadness and it was to a
collection of librarians and so they
were not expecting me to do the same
thing on stage when I gave my speech so
people know the trick of like what this
particular people know what this is
right but this is actually like silver
cake mix so I got silver cake mix and
sprayed this shit it turns out silver
cakes mix has a very distinct smell
which the first four rows of this place
apparently smelled like a cake for the
rest of the thing and I pointed out
these kind of things that there's going
to be no copyrighted works reverting to
the public domain in America from 1999
to 2018 I said if your job is to give a
list here in your institution of all the
new copy copyright works that are
falling out take that job because every
January you can go none I want to point
out again I'm having a heart attack I'm
having a heart attack on stage I then
hosted this event and this event was
basically a thing I don't know if people
know of this there's this beautiful
thing created by Bennett fadi who makes
that other fucking game that I hate
frustrating the fuck out of yourself
with Bennett fatty and um he he created
this arcade thing which allows you to
play remixed main versions and you
compete with people you 15 seconds to
like play this game 15 and I was up
there
and I asked for a stool because I wasn't
feeling well so I am up there doing a
presentation for four hours and annoyed
at how tired I am so I'm drinking Red
Bulls to fix that so I did that right
and they they gave me the things and the
next thing I had this lovely dinner at
the top of one of the finest restaurants
in Australia with a lovely lady we had
it you know as you could see from the
two pieces of wood it's great food this
would've been a fine last dinner
so again visiting Melbourne had a lovely
time and and you know again at some
point I stumble and hit the sidewalk I
remember this and people helped me up
and I was like what the fuck is wrong
with me I am so tired these days I must
be getting old
so here's how your life is saved you
don't get to sleep after a week of
having your heart attack but you don't
know that you walk two miles to a clinic
you go to the clinic and the guy says
like here's some Maalox because a lot of
guys you know whatever you've got it's
either hard or not and here's some
Maalox try it nope doesn't work okay I
know a cardiologist buddy so I go to the
cardiologist buddy and his name is dr.
George Lydell and he he measured me for
20 seconds and everything else was
millions of dollars equipment verifying
what he had heard and he's like yeah you
you can't get on a plane in the next day
or two I have to figure out how to sneak
an American into this hospital so he
personally drove me into the hospital
and right up into the cardiac unit and
put me in the waiting line and left a
note and got out of there so he wouldn't
get in trouble
and so and what I remember was I'm
sitting there and the doctors came in
and looked at me and said okay hey you
know dr. George light I already dropped
you off dr. George drop you off let's do
let's do some research and you know
maybe tomorrow we might have to do a
procedure and I was like oh so like the
note says and he was like what note I
said we left a note out front he goes
out the nobody comes back he goes all
right so we're gonna operate in 20
minutes now I have a problem he's using
phrases I don't like phrases like low
chances of paralysis hi I start out
positive hi survivability rate and I
realized that there's a little shake of
the dice that I'm about to die that
they're not gonna but whatever the fuck
this is is not gonna be great so two
things first of all I had called my
office to let them know hey I'm having a
heart attack that's like midnight there
and Brewster insisted I take the company
credit card and charge it wherever I
needed however I needed so that was
handled um and this is my last tweet
this turns out to be what I thought
should be my last tweet which was very
special to me that I was actually able
to have the you know and now none of my
followers are happy about this what the
fuck is this
Jason is nice Wow what's happening
where's Melbourne Victoria
so um and I I said two things to my
companion which I thought were important
one was you were the best of everything
it's not very easy to say goodbye to
someone like that and also you please
you did nothing wrong because one thing
I've encountered with people who are
survivors is they think that like there
was like one phrase one move you know I
spoke about suicide two years ago and
people could the opposite side of what I
talked about which was listening is to
not blame yourself to act like oh if I
had only blank blank blank this would be
different and it's on me it's my fault
it's not true I didn't feel well we went
to the doctor I'd had a heart attack for
seven days and I survived I think this
is dr. sunny Palmer he was the man who
went through my heart and opened it and
fixed it while I was awake it's a
procedure they made a hole in my wrist
and came in through there and knocked
out the the the happy Collett the many
fine tuna melts and Sonny Palmer and in
Australia in Melbourne they really love
they love 80s pop music so there were
like nine people in that room operating
on me there's a television with me
watching my heartbeat and they're
playing Jon Bon Jovi's you give love a
bad name
shot through the heart and you're to
blame so um they asked me if I'd voted
for Trump I asked them if that affected
the outcome of the operation I gave my
own clammed up a political theory while
they went through me at one point he
said I really need you to stand still
for this part and I'm like Roger so he
fixed my heart the so left right turned
out I needed all that so again it's a
weird picture but you can see up there
there's the chunk and then they take the
chunk out and all that starts working
again and I feel immediately better so
you know within within the day I'm
fucking around so they kept me in there
for three days and I will make a little
mention about this so so here's the
thing that happened that I love okay so
their money people came by because I'm a
foreigner in their in their Hospital and
I'm like bring it how much did I just
rack up and I'll always remember this
woman's look on my face and she she was
like well you know because they don't
want to shock the patient
and she was like this could be in the
realm of $10,000 and I was like I could
walk into an emergency room and borrow a
fucking q-tip in America and that would
be $10,000 so it was great and and
what's most fascinating to me under
under this kind of health care system is
how money is just not in the equation
anywhere at all and and the way I've
tried to describe it is imagine if you
went to a restaurant and at this
restaurant there was some waiters and
you're like dude this food is amazing
this is this is really great but I got
this thing like in two or three hours
I'm gonna need to use a bathroom you
have any recommendations well how would
you answer I mean I did pay so I did pay
for it but I think he's like well we
have a bathroom but you don't wanna
stick around here for three hours and I
mean most train stations a restaurant
you could go to like I guess a store
right hey Steve right store you go still
like that feeling of like I'm answering
the question and it has answers that was
how they were I'd be like so much is
this costing they're like I've never
seen a bill one thing that fascinated me
was at one point I said yeah it can't be
worse than treating a gunshot and he's
like I've never operated my gunshot
and I'm like what has anyone here
operated on a gunshot nobody I just kept
asking this I'm like have you ever
operated on a gunshot victim nope nope
nope okay now I will actually say that
what I did discover later is that they
actually deal with a lot of like dude
drinks way too much at 2:00 p.m.
and hits a curb so they do have trauma
just a different kind of trauma so now
what right my life is different and I
will say right now so you're not worried
I am 100% recovered I went to like I I I
have a doctor at Mount Sinai
checks on me every three months he says
I'm as good as can possibly be I've got
no lingering damage I'm not in any way
I'm better than I was I take six
different medications for various
aspects of this I have a stent right
here a little tiny metal thing that just
says no and just lets it stay open my
final bill by the way was sixteen
thousand dollars of which six was the
stent so the rest of it was nine medical
professionals operation and the thing so
that was an easy pay I ended up paying
back my work for the you know so and
thanks to the podcast which some of you
listen to I don't know any money from
that so I don't have any medical weight
on my heart and I am fine I have lost 25
pounds I walk five miles a day I feel
better than most so I'm in great shape
okay but this was a thing that changed
me I didn't expect to die at 47 years
old so you know suddenly I was out so
everything's a bonus everything's
wonderful so the first question you have
to ask is do I keep doing what I'm doing
I mean certainly the whole
thing about tuna melts get that's over
and I've only had me two half dozen
times in the two years since and I eat a
lot of vegetables and all the vegetable
here's the great thing yeah let's give
it up for vegetables that was great
because that was like giving them all an
audition again like hey kale
someone tried to give this to me along
with some political bullshit while I was
trying to sleep with them in college
about 25 years ago and it didn't work
out but come on into the office again
let's talk
that's how avocados came back into my
life that's how apples grapes a lot of
lettuce a lot of difference if they all
came back so I've had I've had some
delicious stuff and a beautiful person
who was in that restaurant photo and I
cook beautiful meals together and our
closest we've ever been because we get
to make meals together so he said you
know the food I didn't just go a lot see
and but the other way you could go is
fuck it doomed and just end it and it
does have that hot that people do do do
that but what I decided was archive.org
was really important work and I was
right where I wanted to be that was very
important to me like I loved the fact
that my first thought was yeah I was
doing just what I wanted to do the
archive this is the inside of the
Internet Archive those are servers in
the alcoves people are always there's
emotional reaction when they see that
and then there's more emotional reaction
when they go like what's up with the
little fucking statues
if you work at the archive for three
years we give you a little statue
because we don't have stock options so
that's what you get and so is my little
buddies they all work there right the
archive is where I want to be I also
work for something called archive team
which is an activist archivist group
that goes in and saves things so that
recent HHS bullshit or where 500px
announced they were closing down or
going back a bunch of years when when
when Geocities was going down this is a
group of amateurs who go in and we
download as much of everything as we can
before it gets deleted because you can't
get it back once it's gone I'm still you
know a mascot for that group and you're
able to help us by using something
called the archive team warrior that's a
virtual machine that sits on your box
and helps us create a low orbiting ion
cannon that attacks a site and pulls
everything down I call it a distributed
preservation of service attack people
draw lots of cool things to indicate
what's going on I don't know we did that
I also decided to keep up with socking
ttan which is my Twitter account that is
a cat with over a million followers
that's gonna make like now you're fucked
in the head cuz you're like really is
that a thing you just said yeah my cat
has a million followers on Twitter so
whenever I see some sort of brand
management asshole talking about our
problem I'm like yeah that's nice it's
less than my cat but sure that's
and and again you'll notice that his
tweets are as deep as they go right you
are my favorite mouse correction
favorite remaining mouse is it everyone
okay meow for help so so yeah let's keep
that fun up right so I'm I've been
parentally an unpleasant person and so I
would say that I'm less pleasant in some
ways but I care about other things and
I've tried to push the caring more than
the punishment I have stayed I have let
some people sleep where previously they
would have a fitful tossing night not
every time but often and I still believe
very strongly in things and I still
fight for things that I believe in so
that's still there but making everything
into a personal grinding hatred is off
the table for me and I tried to focus on
the positive right I mean people are
people people can get you and and and
you all I mean most of you realize right
that most of the mechanisms now in place
for most of the social media platforms
are designed to cause engagement and
algorithmically engagement turns out to
be greatest when you make everybody hate
each other
and so there's a line about the Petaluma
chickens most of the chickens in America
are like are called Petaluma super
chickens it's a certain breed of chicken
that can grow to adult size in about six
weeks it's delicious so the thing is is
when they were being bred they started
to breed for fast growing chickens and
then they discovered that when the
chickens became adults they attack each
other
brutally to the point that in some
places they just literally dabiq the
chickens so that they can't destroy each
other because they thought they were
breeding faster growing chickens but
they were breeding meaner chickens
similarly there are a variety of
mechanisms out there that are supposed
to cause engagement and are just causing
rage and once you discovered that I'm
able to focus on hopefully making the
better I'm somewhat known for the fact
that I have something called the
information cube and the information
cube is a shipping container in my
backyard and this had all sorts of neat
shit in it so this is what happens when
you say yes for 15 years I have a bunch
of old stuff Jason would you like it yes
I have much of old computers sure this
is going away I'll take it what about
this stuff why not you'll end up with 40
by 8x8 of computer history and it
doesn't always look this clean so four
months after my heart attack I proceeded
to pull it apart and what I started to
do was talk to institutions because I
realized if I had died and my four or
five closest friends tears in their eyes
walked into this horseshit whatever love
I had built up over my life would burn
like a wax candle in a furnace and
they'd be like that motherfucker saved
phone bills from when he was 20 and he
mixed them in with a one-of-a-kind son
prototype this is kinda neat the 400th
version of it isn't as neat why why
Jason why so I started to go talk to
institutions the strong Museum of play
the living computer museum the vintage
computer foundation who has a booth down
here and I would say will you take all
of the monitors so they took all the
monitors one group took all of the
vintage computing equipment and the
Internet Archive started to take stuff
that I promised myself one day I would
send them and I said today is the day
I'm gonna send them these are the
magazines I had and they're now at the
vintage computer Federation so you know
these are thousands and thousands of
computer magazines that they're now
holding in their 501 non-profit
organization that will make it available
to others here's one of the shipment
I had a FedEx person say could you stop
doing this now she said it like I mean
like like like that like could you stop
doing this and I went no but I did get a
pie and bring it I hope that would help
but I don't know so I pulled this thing
apart and so much of the narrative of
the collectors that I take it from is
they just want to know it didn't go into
a dumpster and nothing really went into
a dumpster unless it was broken moldy or
dead and um but most of it went to
facilities that should have gotten them
a long time ago right and good fucking
bye
so I did keep some things like here are
some mixed items that have gone into
storage there's a few boxes of these so
I would say I have gotten rid of 90% of
my possessions and I am now working to
get rid of 90% of the remaining
possessions because most of it was me
once I looked at my life hard I said
most of what I'm holding is entrust for
a visualized future so I should pass
that on to groups whose job is to hold
things in trust
I shouldn't be that person so here are
the manuals unpacked reboxed and put on
pallets at the internet archive's
storage which I don't have any direct
control over unless I wish to interact
with them here are books from that
collection that box is one of 30 of
those boxes of software at the Internet
Archive now that's a lot but it's not in
control of me if I if I go again
this is this is someone's responsibility
but it's a segmented a homogeneous
collection they can say yes we want this
no transfer it here do the PUE no in
other words it's now not what do we even
have here oh Jesus Christ it's a
doughnut right
holy crap this underwear in here so that
was very important to me in unpacking
that emotionally so the archive has a
lot of space physical - there are
millions of books here this is who when
we scanned them we put them in there so
my stuff is inside that little open
piece there and it is safe and it is
happy I was reminded of how things can
go the other way with this guy whose
name I've now forgotten he probably
wouldn't want me to tell you his name so
if you look these are two pictures these
are CD ROMs they are grabs of every
movie music and other items off of
Usenet for the course of about 5 years
and the reason it says free is because
he died and they moved his stuff to the
basement and said mom and one guy
because now I'm known for this went
surely Jason Scott wants this not
knowing that he's got fresh new shiny
Jason Scott is Magic Jason Scott but ok
and I said yes of course I'll take it
but I took it within the context of and
by the way and this is what kills me is
if you look you see that writing so on
Windows there's something called the G
spot codec analyzer and what it is is
you run it and it tells you like what
the resolution the codec speed all these
datum about a file and he carefully
wrote the title and what the G spot
codec output was on each CD all seven
thousand four years to the end of a pile
of nothing so I took all of his stuff
and I read it because I have automatic
CD readers I didn't write was on the
outside because the content is inherent
in the item like the amount of metadata
he added was zero so I immediately did
that and I processed all seven
thousand and then I gave them to a young
kid in Santa Cruz who has broken them up
and turned them into art so that it's
something positive somewhere and I think
he'll name it after him so you know it
has been very very educational for me to
have this happen I prefer not this thing
happening again
and I am working very hard not to let it
happen again
ayuh yay for not yay for giving a shit I
think one of the things that kind of
comes out from people is when they want
you know like I said everybody has their
own specific journey as to how they feel
about their disease and their their
stuff right and I wrote a blog entry
because you still do that sometimes
called the other half and it's the other
half of my life which begins now right I
moved out of my brother's house where I
had a single room that was full of lots
of computer equipment I moved into a
beautiful apartment with this person who
I love and I made sure
and she's made sure that this isn't
happening again not in that Hall my
nagging partner but the objective
realization of it is a shitty way to
live let's not live shitty which has
been my theme let's not live shitty
let's be good let's let's not live
shitty let's take care of things let's
matter because we're only here for a
short time and this came with no warning
for me I mean granted it's you know
double-decker I should have been like
this was a warning but this is a
delicious warning but I didn't I didn't
know that this was gonna happen so early
and it did and I you know and I and so
you know I've always cared about
computer history about the stories of
people behind them I've done a number of
documentaries of those documentaries
there's been so many people who have
been lost from them now you know a dozen
plus people and I have full recordings
of them and I put it up on the archive
this this you know this this slight
bummer of finiteness to me can be a
learning experience and in focus now the
other side of it is
like I'm super high all the time and so
for like my co-workers for a while I'm
sure it was incredibly frustrating would
they be like this isn't working and I'm
like isn't it amazing we live in a
universe where things don't work so like
what's happening right now this this
this this little controversy on the
Twitter's on a platform designed to
cause controversy that the hope
conference is not handling things right
or that this should be that or that I'm
looking at is like oh people are
disagreeing Wow isn't it neat how we
disagree so again take that with a you
know grain of Jesus Christ what's with
this fucking guy don't worry I don't go
to church and I don't wear anything but
there's a you know I have this strong
belief that like in the in the realm of
things people have been really amazing
people you know I started a podcast
called Jason Scott talks his way out of
it which was meant to raise money to
kind of pay off some old debts I have
and it has been fantastic on two levels
I've done 33 episodes each of them about
a half an hour and they talk like this
and I have been digging deeper and
deeper with every episode the initial
ones were hilarious stories of meeting
old old people and doing weird shit and
some of them were about the technology
and then over time they're becoming
about like well people call me an
amateur and what's an amateur and what
does it mean to have mystery and where
have I been alone and where have I built
rage and everything else so it's been
wonderful to kind of do that kind of
self-reflection so that's kind of where
I am right now right I'm happy here I'm
in Iceland I'm living well and so if
anything comes of this talk please if
anything is entertaining or whatever
please enjoy the moments you have
because it comes and it changes so
quickly I'm dedicating this talk to my
friend Dan
dildo who tweeted to me this the fucking
day on February and in April UCB say
thanks pals are we didn't get a chance
because a month or so later he laid down
waiting for waiting for dinner on a
Sunday and he didn't wake up no warning
he just died and we have dedicated grove
to him in california and we miss him
everyday and he thought he was fuckin
with me and god that shit fucked with
all of us so this is you know please
don't you know don't don't walk away
from moments because some of it didn't
go well
not only is perfect the enemy of good
seeking perfection in your life is the
enemy of living so please do that
I'm not taking questions
[Applause]