thank you so much that was such a warm
introduction I really appreciate that
this is my first hope I'm very happy to
be here with a topic that is near and
dear to my heart I've been doing sex
worker rights activism for more than 10
years and one thing that I noticed that
has changed is I felt that in the
beginning a lot of these things were
very abstract and on the horizon I felt
more like a distant weather person and
right now I'm a little bit more in the
middle of a hurricane describing those
conditions that we saw coming a while
ago so I'm looking forward to sharing
all of this good news a little bit of
who I am I am a sex worker so I am a
stakeholder and a lot of what I'm
talking about and a lot of what I'm
talking about is surveillance I'm
talking about a government dragnet and
there are people here who are far more
competent about talking about the nature
of that surveillance who is doing it way
better than I could I can show you the
sex worker I view of these things and I
can show you why the rationale of human
trafficking is bogus another project
that I do is I am the founder of harm
redox an Francisco I am a harm reduction
estoy
all my roots are in harm reduction so in
San Francisco I hand out health and
hygiene supplies for crack smokers
including pipes we're gonna be talking
about a lot of the prostitution law you
don't necessarily have to see this whole
slide but I want to cover kind of what
are the laws around sex work and the
truth is the color the criminal Penal
Code is really dense it's really thick
there's a lot of variation between
communities but as a whole it comes down
to these basic principles it is illegal
to exchange sex for anything of value it
is illegal to ask someone to exchange
sex for anything of value it is illegal
to ask someone to ask someone else to
exchange sex for anything of value it is
illegal to appear to be asking someone
to exchange sex for anything of value it
is illegal to benefit from someone
else's exchange of sex for anything of
value it is illegal to be in the company
of someone attempting to exchange sex
for anything of value with someone
it is illegal to come and go from a
place where individuals exchange sex for
anything of value and it is illegal to
make the exchange of sex for anything of
value to appear to be glamorous as a
profession don't hate me because I'm
beautiful
but that said this is not a brothel
there are no prostitutes at this address
these are not the drones are looking for
I am NOT here to recruit I'm not here
for pimping or pandering I'm just here
to talk a little bit about the law Who I
am and why I don't like these laws so
we've been doing a lot of activism for a
long time and when it comes to the law I
listed all those things the Criminal
Code is really dense and thick but when
it comes down to what distinguishes
commercial sex from say recreational sex
our elements of communication and
Association so those are very vague
ultimately I think a lot of these laws
because of how we do prosecute a lot of
these crimes basically violate our
ability to to talk to one another and
our ability to associate with one
another and so there is a long history
of sex worker rights activism in June it
was the 40th anniversary of a French sex
worker protest in Leon where sex workers
actually occupied a church and they did
this in response to heavy fines police
brutality and ultimately a threat to
separate sex workers from their children
this was a beautiful beautiful protest
and I think what made it so beautiful is
that all the women in the community
joined the sex workers and said we dare
you to distinguish us from the people
you're prosecuting and persecuting so it
went very well things changed so when
sex worker rights are under attack what
do we do get dressed
fight back got a beautiful picture here
of cedi lune from San Francisco this was
a campaign poster for a prop que this
was a failed sadly attempt to
decriminalize prostitution in San
Francisco there's nothing there oh let's
try this again
is it there now oh we lost a beautiful
slide okay well in its absence I'm going
to talk to you a little bit about what
it was
basically this was kind of just an
overview of sex worker rights and the
main point I want you to take away is
for hundreds and hundreds and hundreds
of years there have been many penalties
and many ways people have tried to stop
commercial sex no form of punishment up
to and including the death penalty has
ever been an effective deterrent against
people died people are dying
it doesn't stop what's going on there's
also a lot of people who want to on the
sex worker rights activism kind of
create a dichotomy between trafficking
and sex work and there's a lot of good
reasons for that sex trafficking is the
big phrase that people use but it's
really not as black and white is that
the fact is there's a lot of people in
the middle and these laws don't help
anyone whether you are consenting to be
in the sex trade or whether you're not
these policies put people in danger so I
don't know that it's helpful to
distinguish we need laws that protect
people and their lives and their bodies
and that said there's also the kind of
the another chant is we want rights not
rescue rescues not on the table the
rescue is a lie there is no rescue so I
don't know that that's helpful either
I'm going to talk to you a little bit
about legalization and criminal
decriminalization and I'm gonna talk a
lot about the Swedish model I said I
have a little bit of a trivia question
at least this slide is working I don't
know why it comes up here and not there
but hey technology so which American
city was the first to deploy a web-based
anti prostitution sting they actually
call this a reverse sting because that's
when it focuses on buyers so I'm just
going I can't see anybody so how many
people think that it was by sound of
noise San Jose California did they win
no no one thinks San Jose how about
Charlotte anyone think it was Charlotte
got some folks with it Florida was
Florida the first
how about Washington all right and the
winner is Everett Washington in 1995 was
the first to realize that there were ads
on the Internet and they were the first
to go in and start doing that so there's
been a lot of ways that sex work has
been criminalized the first Street based
buyer sting when we started looking at
people who purchase sex was in 1964 in
Nashville Tennessee obviously we had
that first internet-based buyer's sting
in Eugene Oregon in 75 they started
publishing names and pictures of people
in the newspapers now they publish them
on the web sometimes they're on
Billboard's Dear John letters are about
neighborhood surveillance that's when
communities started encouraging people
to go out right down descriptions
license-plate numbers so that started
happening surveillance cameras in
communities started going on and
neighborhood action those are signs
those are community watch groups just in
general going after buyers so there's a
long history of that and it's still
happening there's another slide that
doesn't work sometimes bots are used
this is a very recent article going on
in Texas where they have Ariel Brooke
and Carrie our BOTS who are narcs the
thing that I really don't like about
them is everything that these bots are
asking about are essentially the
screening tactics that sex workers used
so what they're doing is they're
undermining our ability to get
information about who might be wanting
to spend some time and sharing some
companionship anything that we asked to
screen our clients is incriminating so
it's gonna be harder and harder to do
that another broken slide I'm so sorry
we had a little tech problem we didn't
get time to start up there's also a lot
of forms that people use and there are
license plate readers that are being set
up in different communities and when a
license plate reader goes into a high
prostitution zone we often find that
these are marginalized communities these
are communities of people who are living
in poverty and very often these are
communities where there's a lot of
people of color so it's very interesting
how this surveillance is very targeted
right now there's about 55,000 people a
year who are arrested for prostitution
but not everyone is arrested for
prostitution or loitering directly so
there's probably more like 80,000 to
90,000
people a year in the United States who
are being arrested for prostitution even
if that's not the official offense
they're booked for in 2014 to 2015 there
were three thousand two hundred eighty
five people who were arrested for
prostitution in New York City eighty
four percent of them were women of color
in 2014 to 2015 one thousand four
hundred thirty seven people were
arrested here in New York City for
patronizing a prostitute ninety three
percent were men of color and oftentimes
that's because stings are done again in
parts of town that are struggling more
economically so it is targeted these
policies are absolutely racist in
practice the workplace homicide rate for
female prostitutes is 204 per 100,000
that makes it the deadliest job in
America the second deadliest job by the
way is lumberjacking 118 fatalities per
hundred thousand so it is almost two
times as dangerous to be a sex worker in
America as it is to be a lumberjack
the average sex worker is non fatally
attacked approximately once per month
and this is also there's a wide
disparity between people who work
indoors or outdoors these assaults are
often coming from partners but if you're
not able to go to the police there's
nothing you can do about it regardless
of the source and law enforcement
officers are a pretty big portion of the
violence that is directed towards people
in the sex trade here's a raid and the
thing that I really want to draw some
attention to is that that's ice does
that laser even work what on earth was
immigration doing at the rentboy raid in
fact we see immigration is popping up
pretty much everywhere when it comes to
human trafficking raids we see them we
see them a lot we see them a lot they
also they justified
on many grounds we like to talk about
people being trafficked but just because
somebody is working in a country that's
not their own doesn't mean that they
were trafficked and a lot of these laws
have been used to examine people's
documents and to deport them I we look
at feminism if we look it up the concept
of abortion would we say that abortion
is effectively decriminalized if someone
could be deported if they were found
trying to seek one
what is legalization legalization is mr.
Haas it is not legal to be engaged in
prostitution all over Nevada but there
are some counties where you can over
half of the legal brothels are owned by
dentists and I want to talk a little bit
about why sex workers don't like
legalization as a concept if you work in
Nevada there's gonna be a lot of Hoops
bureaucratic hoops you have to jump
through if something can be done legally
it can be done illegally and in this
case it's necessary to go to the
sheriff's office where you will have a
once a week medical exam not the
cushiest of locations you are issued a
card from the Sheriff's Department and
you're in a database so if you're pulled
over while driving that information will
come up so that can be a little bit
scary in many of the counties the people
working cannot leave the facility where
they're working so you can't have your
children with you you will be separated
from them it becomes kind of a company
town situation because you have to buy
all of your supplies from the brothel
where you work even though you're
splitting your profits 50/50 so condoms
blue fuzzy handcuffs you name it you're
buying it from your boss so that is
something that a lot of workers really
really don't like it also reminds you
that legalization causes problems for
sex workers of all kinds one thing that
I didn't differentiate in my language is
that sex work is often the word that we
use for any form of erotic commerce
whether you're touching someone or not
that can be camming or stripping or
phone sex and there's a lot of laws
around a lot of legal sex work that get
in the way of things if you are a
stripper
the way you can work is going to change
from city to city in some places it's
illegal for a stripper to touch their
own body in some places they do have a
whole part of the police department
that's going to make sure a pasty is big
enough or that the underwear
is to the precise specifications so that
means that law enforcement officers can
come right into a dressing room they can
start touching you and start sussing up
how you're dressed and how you're
working some of us may have been
watching the news recently and saw that
stormy Daniels was arrested in an Ohio
strip club one of the justifications
they used for that was human trafficking
in order to prevent the scourge of human
trafficking we had to arrest stormy
Daniels
so in general legalization retains some
of the worst aspects of criminalization
so what we want is decriminalization and
decriminalization means you simply
remove all aspects of that from the
criminal Penal Code so that means we
wouldn't have that kind of bureaucratic
oversight we wouldn't have the contact
with law enforcement and we wouldn't
have as many arbitrary and capricious
laws governing how we practice our trade
the Nordic model is something that's
been traveling around the world
it actually was called the sex purchase
act it started in Sweden 1998 and it
didn't really come from any particular
cause the Sweden wasn't the people of
Sweden didn't really care one way or
another only about 25 percent of the
citizens had an opinion after they
introduced the sex purchase act that
number jumped up to 70 percent but
suddenly sex trafficking was an issue so
propaganda works and this is being
exported everywhere which is kind of
disappointing because there's a lot of
good things happening in Nordic models
there's a great Nordic model of
education and how we provide schooling
or family leave things like that public
assistance so of all the things to
export from the Nordic countries we
picked this and this is where I say
there is no rescue this was never about
protecting people I have a lot of quotes
but this one is definitely stands stands
out in my mind because this came right
from Sweden itself but it should be
difficult this should be hard
any time we point out the consequences
that we face due to these laws that are
endangering us no one really cares
because it was never about protecting
anybody
this this lovely lovely feminist has a
lot of good quotes about that that all
the negative effects are actually
positives because again this isn't about
rescuing people this is about ending
demand by essentially any means that are
required it's not there is no placement
there is no support in the United States
we have estimates that there are tens of
thousands of victims of human
trafficking but there are 150 beds and
shelters for sex trafficking victims
we have no infrastructure in place
whatsoever for anyone who is being
harmed on or is being forced into this
trade against their will all we have is
deportation and incarceration which have
not been known to ameliorate the effects
of trauma the word that we use for this
is carceral feminism and carceral
feminism is a oh gosh you guys I'm so
sorry carceral feminism is a concept
that we can work with the police state
and try to solve things that harm women
or gendered violence against women by
using police and by using a criminal
Penal Code in 2012 there was a national
overview of prostitution and sex
trafficking and in that quote they even
said while it is necessary and just to
assist survivors and that the expansion
of those services is acutely needed the
interventions are not designed to
prevent or to reduce the occurrence of
exploitation it is about ending demand
and boy have these policies proliferated
there are n demand programs in every
state of the United States they're
growing in numbers this happened very
very quickly and generally people seem
to think that if we can just that there
would be no human trafficking of any
kind if there wasn't demand for
commercial sex but I think it's just as
likely that we could end that demand as
we could end demand for food these end
demand policies essentially turn people
into spies against their community
members in Oakland when they started how
the police depart
basically because they're
under-resourced started training
citizens to do their work so they did a
lot of there was a lot of support for it
but there were a lot of people who
pointed out problems and I think that a
human rights attorney was quite right
that we are teaching people to turn one
another in to surveil one another under
very arbitrary ideas what does it mean
to say it looked like you were cruising
for a provider but if you live there
what if you have a friend there this is
very very vague and what happens is if
you are they'll write down your license
plate number perhaps it came from video
surveillance perhaps it came from a
license plate reader and they sent a
letter and the letters are very designed
to be opened by mothers or wives that's
really the unstated purpose is to if you
can't necessarily prosecute somebody
make life as difficult as possible
in 2003 Congress barred groups that
aided trafficking victims from receiving
federal funds if they supported the
legalization or practice of prostitution
this was a very big deal we provide a
lot of funding and support for the
global aids struggle and this is another
gag policy that we have also in that
year President Bush committed 15 billion
to the fight against AIDS but again he
required that all recipients sign an
anti prostitution pledge in 2013 the
Supreme Court finally struck that down
for United States based groups if you're
out somewhere else in the world I'm
sorry you're gonna have to you have to
fall in line with that you cannot
advocate for decriminalization in any
way shape or form you really have to get
on the end demand train
we now have FASTA cess study fight
online sex trafficking act to stop
enabling sex traffickers act that
happened in April it was in the works
for many years and we had a lot of
support from Google and Facebook but
unfortunately there was something that
happen in backrooms if you know what
some of those backroom conversations
were like please let me know because I'm
sure some some folks here might have
some insight into that but essentially
Facebook and Google withdrew their
support and we're willing to to move
forward with FASTA and sista so what
they did essentially was they removed
section 230 of the Communications
Decency Act and this was the
something that prevents liability from
websites that have third-party content
so cesta FASTA wasn't targeted at
workers themselves it was targeted at
websites and the idea that any website
should be liable for what users are
doing on it to that extent is is gonna
have incredible implications for the
internet that we use the reason that
we've had a free internet is because we
do recognize that it's very hard to be
in control of what all your users are
saying it also means that sex workers
are a liability to a website and because
it's so vague it's so arbitrary what
defines human trafficking all of these
laws and nothing really makes it precise
it means that anyone who's doing
anything sexual is a liability they need
to go so even if you're doing legal
forms of sex work you may find that you
are unable to use the services that you
once had to conduct your business
Craigslist erotic services reduce the
female homicide rate by seventeen point
four percent that was a paper that just
came out this year that was really
stunning seventeen point four percent
that's a lot of lives that is a lot of
lives and the reason why Craigslist
could do that no we're here we're all
hackers we know and no one would say
that it's safe to open an email but it
is a lot safer to open an email than it
is to stick your head into a strange car
that's just a fact it is a lot safer to
do your screening over the Internet than
it is to go outside so people are being
forced out doors as soon as cesta FASTA
passed my biggest moment of cringing was
knowing just how much the rate of street
based providers was going to increase
and we saw that within weeks in San
Francisco our outreach teams saw as many
as four to eight times the number of
people who are working outside lots of
people have smartphones and by and large
people who do work on the street beat
will have an ad placed and so they're
hoping to get as many contacts through
the internet and if they don't make
enough money they'll go work outside but
pretty much everyone was using ads and
they don't have that option anymore
the reason why I look at you know does
how much does it matter to dis
English trafficking from sex work it's
because our sex choice is not an even
playing field
poverty removes choices race can remove
choices in our society transphobia
removes choices all of these things
limit the choices that people can make
but sex work is so often a choice of
survival and when you limit those
choices even further you can't even
choose now to work on the internet you
have to work outside that makes it
dangerous and anyone who works deserves
protections it's also interesting to see
that when the internet makes things
better that's still considered a
negative here we have lieutenant Terry
who thinks it's a bad thing that an
individual provider would make almost
four times as much their rate this was a
beautiful screen capture from my pink
book the other thing that we used to use
the internet message boards for was to
share information and resources about
sti's about safe places to work average
hotel experiences is there anyone who
can help me get a pay stub so that I can
rent lots of folks came together and so
most of our individual Commerce was
about supporting one another supporting
our health supporting our safety in some
cases we did see a lot of workplace
cooperation on my red book all of the
providers on the message board said hey
the going rate has been approximately X
what if we all agree right here right
now on this message board to raise our
rates by $50 people did we can only do
that if we can talk to one another and
we lost that message board we lost that
ability to communicate with each other
in another circumstance when I was
working there was an individual who had
had a little bit of a dispute with a
provider and she was willing to work it
out with him but she basically wanted a
new chrome notebook to work on and he
was like no way
and so he emailed another colleague and
because we'd publicized this she said
hey I heard you had a bad time with
so-and-so I just don't think I can work
with you or see you until you work thing
with her and he was like what so he went
to the next person who was me and he was
like oh my you know like I don't know
what's been going on but no one will see
me and because I had gotten the same
message I said I don't know dude better
buy her a Chromebook just do it so we do
work together and we are able to
negotiate and get a little bit more
power simply because we can associate in
addition a lot of our stings in San
Francisco went down the fact that
between 2004 and 2007 at the yield of
the street based arrests could decrease
by half is incredible that shows you
that how many people moved from the
outdoors to the indoors there are so
many organizations that support full
decriminalization
I'm really glad this slide works there's
another one just as big if you can't
read all these names that's okay you
just need to know that I am NOT speaking
alone I am NOT speaking just from my
bias I'm not just speaking as someone
who works with these sex workers
outreach project USA I'm someone who
works with many many people who are
trying to fight for Human Rights so we
have a lot of big organizations that
have supported us one of which was
Amnesty International and I am so proud
of them because they had such a big
decided to come out in favor of
decriminalization they got a lot of
flack a lot of people left but they
stayed the ground so they were
incredible allies for us the EF F hey
hey shout out to the EF F the EF F has
done a lot to help support this fight
when prop 35 passed in California he was
essentially written as like an anti
puppy kicking bill it was about stopping
human trafficking and the only thing
that it did was it increased penalties
that people faced it and it also made it
a little bit more vague and it opened up
that definition of human trafficking
prop 35 in California meant that if I
gave somebody a ride to work I would be
transporting a human trafficking victim
so it meant it was harder to get a ride
if you are again profiting
fitting off of somebody's labor you
could be labeled a pimp so who wants to
be your roommate
if you're a sex worker who wants to be
your landlord that's a liability if you
are a minor and you work with another
minor on a double you are still a human
trafficker of minors even if you
yourself are under 18 years old a lot of
these things are difficult if there are
more than two sex workers in one place
it can be described as a brothel a lot
of these troubles a lot of these
troubles and the EF F I don't think was
you know we weren't able to stop prop 35
but they came out for us and they're
coming out for us again and assess of
FASTA fate there is a lawsuit we're
hoping to stop this and file an
injunction the government obviously is
not a fan but we're gonna see what
happens
unfortunately this is a global
phenomenon it's not just happening in
the United States over in the UK they
are essentially looking at their own
version of a cesta FASTA to prohibit any
form of advertising now over in Britain
it's a very different case it it's
almost e krimpet really essentially if
you are an adult and you're behind
closed doors and there's a money thing
before a sex thing that's private but if
you do something publicly it's not if
you operate a brothel it might not be
and there are a tremendous number of
raids that went on recently so they're
mimicking what we're doing this is
definitely happening
there's also another bill that's kind of
on the on the table right now that's
being sponsored by Elizabeth Warren and
mark Rubio so it's got bipartisan
support and that is to end banking for
human traffickers and what that's going
to do is it's going to empower the state
to work with financial institutions and
to shut down bank accounts this was
happening informally for a while they
called it operation choke point to try
to target you know dubious you know
internet or credit-card transactions a
lot of different trades were being
looked at but definitely anything
related to sex that wasn't official this
would be a federal bill and that would
also mean a lot more surveillance into
how we bank and what we're doing
we're seeing more restrictions in
general around banking it used to be a
lot easier to put a cash deposit into an
account now that's they're making that
trickier especially if you're trying to
put cash into someone else's account so
we're seeing this it's going to increase
and the question is really what do we
gain from that why what is the whole
point if it's not actually rescuing
anybody and I've seen over time that
there's often a target population that
gets a lot of scrutiny after September
11th we heard a lot about terrorism and
it was necessary to surveil people to
prevent terrorism what we got left with
was a lot of really bad laws that didn't
necessarily keep anyone's lives safer
during the environmental kind of like
activist movement environmental
Liberation Front Animal Liberation Front
folks were very heavily targeted they
found excessive penalties to stop a
scourge of domestic terrorism right now
human trafficking is the word that
they're using to justify a lot of
surveillance and no one benefits from
having these license plate readers in
certain parts of town and there's a lot
of technology that's being developed on
these grounds in terms of AI there's the
bots but DARPA is funding a lot a lot of
good stuff to document people's faces
if you post an ad and your face is
recognized and it goes into a database
you may have difficulty crossing a
border at a later point in time and it's
easy to create this because we can say
prevent human trafficking but then human
trafficking is so vague it can be used
on anybody and it's a lot harder to get
it out I'm sorry I missed a lot of
slides but I'm gonna take questions for
as long as I can on any of these topics
and I will be around to answer any
questions anyone might not want to ask
in front of an audience this I'm not the
only sex worker in this room that's not
even possible there are other people
that you're sitting next to who have
been in the sex trade at one point so
always consider that you don't know who
you're around and I certainly keep that
near and dear to my heart
that's
I can't see anyone so if there's a line
of people who are at the microphone
hey Maggie hi so a lot of people have
been following the legal fights against
foster cesta but i think maybe a lot of
the hackers in the room might also love
if you wanted to talk a bit about the
keep that fight up but we're also gonna
take our toys and go home approach what
red umbrella has been doing and what's
witters been doing to be like fuck all
your policies we got this now yeah we
are definitely form as much as we can
twitter was basically twitter did a
giant purge of our accounts because
there was human trafficking on twitter
there's still a lot of profiles that you
can see that are active many of them are
being shadow banned which means they
don't come up in search results you
can't find somebody unless you're
already following them and this has also
been the case on other types of social
media platforms tumblr definitely likes
to kind of shadow people out so that's
one way that a lot of social media is
trying to figure out how to handle
things
so sweater what a group of sex workers
said we need to have something and they
set it up through mastodons and
interestingly enough that was shut down
because CloudFlare there are only two
organizations that have been basically
shut down by CloudFlare Nazis and sex
workers and we don't have a whole lot in
common it's it's actually something
that's kind of always bothered me that
the first groups of people on the
internet who were so censored and pushed
off were sex workers and not Nazis for
the longest time we've always been enemy
number one and even though so much
technology on the Internet really has
been developed because of sex because of
pornography or the money that's
transferred we are the foundation a lot
of the technology we use today but the
technology that we use is now writing us
out of our terms of services completely
so in some regards it's like our allies
have turned their backs on us
in other cases we're seeing some people
who are supporting Twitter got back up
we found a different server there's lots
of services and people that are helping
to create more and more private spaces
the difficulty is that makes it hard for
clients to find
if anyone's ever had trouble like
explaining email to their parents or
grandparents it's very difficult to
explain how to be secure to a 70 year
old client who uses AOL so our ability
to do something private or to get out of
the main pond is only as effective as
our ability to bring our clients with us
so we have to do a lot of things with
euphemisms or underground and that's
definitely impacting people's bottom
line which is why we are seeing so many
more people who can't use sweater
effectively who do have to go back to
the streets and did that get a lot of
what you wanted yeah is it over a
hundred thousand at this point it's over
a hundred thousand yeah I'm sweater has
grown by leaps and bounds thousands of
people were joining every single day so
the interest is still there and if not
the interest at least the support or
being an ally or pointing out that the
user base demonstrates how powerful
something can be yeah I'll take the next
one has to apply to jurisdictions
outside of the US a lot of websites were
impacted the collapse of Backpage
impacted sex workers all over the world
there were Australian sex workers who
reported difficulties because they
couldn't advertise on platforms they
were used to those platforms were gone
so there were lots of people who were
made vulnerable and also to point out
when Backpage was raided it happened
about a week and a half after foster
cesta was passed but it had nothing to
do with that all of these raids could
have been conducted without this
legislation they always were they will
continue to be rentboy was raided
without cesta FASTA my red book was
raided without cesta fuss to all of
these if there's something that's that's
deeply criminal or if the government
wants to shut it down they always could
and they always will but this
legislation I think is going to make it
more difficult for mainstream social
media and Backpage is quite missed faq
page is quite missed it also impacted
personals communities craigslist can't
have any of their there
personals ads and that was a really
important place for the LGBT community
to find people things like that I
imagine that this is going to trickle
because sex workers are not just going
to stay on Twitter they want to find
clients so you have to go where clients
are you have to go where people are so I
imagine that platforms like OkCupid or
other dating websites or tinder are
going to start to get a little bit more
claustrophobic as they start to
eliminate people because sex workers are
using those platforms to find people so
they're gonna have to do a purge we've
noticed that the like Skype or any of
the Microsoft Xbox has a lot more heavy
restrictions on the type of content
they're allowing just because again the
possibility that there could be human
trafficking means they have to purge it
next given some of the difficulties you
talked about with just navigating the
existing banking systems I was wondering
if cryptocurrency is something that
anyone in this space is using to try to
not have to go through conventional
banks yeah there are many sex workers
who use various forms of
cryptocurrencies
some of them we did quite well recently
there's a lot there were definitely some
sex workers who are no longer in the
trade so good for them good for them the
folks were able to use that and use that
well I imagine that cryptocurrencies are
going to continue to grow in many
different ways but they're not always as
evenly accessible it can be hard enough
to get a client to like understand how
to get an envelope for cash let alone
let alone some cryptocurrencies so again
it's not necessarily sex workers can
have it use it accept it but if their
clients don't it can be really difficult
for it to be effective
but cryptocurrencies are gaining ground
in all kinds of sectors so I think the
more people use it in general the more
it's going to be an option for people
who are in the sex trade did that person
get her Chromebook did you repeat that
did the person who you were telling the
story about get their Chromebook oh yeah
we got her Chromebook
[Applause]
the funny thing is that that was someone
who was looking for a niche service so
there really were only like a handful of
us so if your workplace is about six
people it's pretty easy to get them
organized and yeah we that work that
worked well yes hi you mentioned human
trafficking being used as sort of a
scary buzzword and I've definitely seen
that myself it was really disappointing
to see some of the more liberal
politicians in Congress come out and
supportive like susta and FASTA and you
mentioned elizabeth warren so i guess my
question is to what extent do advocates
like yourself have sort of a voice or a
seat at the table in like City Council's
state houses and Congress around the
country oh that's easy to answer we
don't none of these policies our policy
makers have consulted sex worker rights
groups right now human trafficking has a
lot of grant money a lot a lot a lot a
lot of money is going into human
trafficking but no one seems interested
in giving it to organizations even long
established organizations like the sex
workers outreach project USA we kind of
fight our way into different rooms in
California we have a lobbying day we got
as many sex workers together as possible
we all got a bus we went to Sacramento
and we bothered people there's a there's
a good saying by Flo Kennedy she was an
amazing activist and she said if you
don't have a seat at the table bring
your own and so I kind of think of that
we bring our own folding chairs maybe
put it on top of the table and make a
seat for ourselves so we are starting to
be heard there are a few politicians who
are starting to listen to us in New York
City actually there was a summit with a
candidate
Siraj who did not unfortunately win his
seat but he actually made it a point to
sit down and talk to sex workers and ask
about the policies they want so there's
growing knowledge but it's really not
the dominant voice even though sometimes
it can feel like the dominant voice on
spaces like Twitter but not really
Facebook they don't like us there we're
growing we're growing but I would not
say that that seats very big and these
seats are being prime
Merilee occupied by anti sex worker
carceral feminists Vichy feminists if
you're nasty but I hope that we will
have more of a space in the porn
community there was a lot of proposed
policies that were on the table that
were almost certain
in fact some statewide California
legislation and sex workers organized
and defeated it so we're getting more of
a voice but it's not a loud one yet we
do need to be amplified by as many
people as possible so that we can be
heard thank you mm-hmm thank you
first of all you need to know that your
highlighter is amazing thank you so I
was on a team of people who developed a
news game surrounded changes to Canadian
sex work law in 2014 with the defeat of
the bill and then the introduction of
the more terrible one that work you know
currently dealing with right now
and some of the changes to the laws that
we have found that are most damaging I
involve what you touched on briefly the
profiting from profiting from sex work
even if you are not a sex worker and to
areas that you know that we found
particularly effective have been
bodyguards and drivers so basically the
people who are involved in keeping sex
workers as safe as possible so I was
wondering if you could talk maybe a
little bit about that sort of support
network and how you are seeing Systema
and other sort of changes to the
legislation potentially eroding or
dismantling those safeties the same you
know way that we have yeah so one thing
I found about sex work is that there's
so many aspects to the work that it's
hard to do by yourself especially with a
system that's out to get you so one of
the reasons why pimping can be such a
strong business is because it is hard
for a sex worker to do everything you
need someone outside of your work to
help provide security to bail you out to
you know any number of things that you
might need support with so drivers are
folks that either an agency or an
individual sex worker can hire to take
them to work a driver will wait
side and make sure that someone leaves
safely but they are profiting from sex
work even if they're not a pimp in this
case oftentimes these are individual sex
workers who are hiring people who are
essentially freelance contractors who
provide support services and they're all
being labeled as pimps the unfortunate
reality is that many people who actually
are traffickers and pimps are very
organized they're very smart and they're
not the ones being caught it's usually
the very well-intentioned people who
aren't doing anything wrong that suffer
the greatest consequences from these
things and this is a very deliberate in
Norway they had what they called
Operation homelessness that's what they
called it and it was an attempt to get
as many landlords in the hot spot for
renting to sex workers at all they
wanted to get just make life as
difficult as possible and and get as
many sex workers evicted as they could
so that's something that we do see kind
of happening in the United States in
some cities they even have very specific
policies and legislation about renting
to sex workers if you are knowingly
renting to someone in the sex trade you
you're a pimp in the eyes of the law so
while cesta foster creates these
third-party websites they were a really
great place for people to hire somebody
if you're looking to hire a driver it's
it's hard to find them that's a it's a
niche service so you need to go to a
place where people are already in the
know and so cesta FASTA has eliminated
all those places where people could hire
those support services which means we're
gonna be a lot more endangered because
either we have to rely on a pimp or we
have to go it alone
we can't even work with one another
thank you so much you fight the good
fight in Canada thank you thank you so
much so there seems to be a healthy
level of paranoia about facial
recognition a lot of providers won't
show face but there also seems to be
like a massive disconnect between the
way female providers work there's a
culture of screening there's John's know
what to expect with that but with the
gay bravado community it's totally
different and it's hard to figure out
how to change the culture around that
and also it's I'm wondering if you can
comment on like what level of
paranoia is healthy considering things
like voice recognition or geolocation if
you have like a trap phone but then you
also have your regular phone in your
pocket with you and you're traveling
around then you can be identifies that
way also yeah absolutely there there are
so many ways that were being tracked
reverse photo lookup is one thing that
has ruined so many sex workers lives
because they'll put use one photo for
their working profile and they'll use
that same photo on their kind of regular
or their legal name profiles and they
get linked the reason why the face in
the advertisement can be a little bit
more of a liability is simply because
those websites are all being rated and
so all those faces are organized and
they're going right into the hands of
the state but there's so many other
reasons why the face can be tricky or
why people we're covering their faces or
obscuring them prior to any of this
legislation some of the organization
work that I did
had to do with a local group of
neo-nazis who I guess they were bored
started printing pictures of sex worker
ads looking for ones with faces so they
could post them on telephone poles and
things like that so there's a lot of
reasons why having your face available
can be a liability voice recognition is
definitely something that's going to
increase and any of the things that we
have in our phone but I found a lot of
times is that the state can be very very
lazy despite having very big dragnet so
when they have a bunch of information in
one place with a lot of incriminating
information it's it's just there it's
made for them but it's not always been
the culture of people to obscure faces
for some people it's a selling point but
I think we're gonna continue to see that
change one thing I didn't mention on
like the reverse stings like I had to
talk about cheapness in the law
enforcement community is they often do a
reverse staying that's where they'll
post their own ad and rent a hotel room
and it's actually a sting for buyers but
a lot of departments are too cheap they
won't even rent like a Hilton room or
post an ad so they'll wait and they'll
bust an individual provider at work and
use her room like they'll use her room
and all of
her appointments and her phone so you
know they're cheap they like to make it
easy and when they use those ads it's
just because it's in one place but yeah
there's a lot of other ways we're gonna
be tracked and the unfortunate reality
is that that might even be coming from
porn images too soon hi I know I'm gonna
make sure that the next speaker has
enough time to set up so they don't have
tech difficulties like I did so I'm
gonna see if I can take a couple more
questions but if the moderators will
interrupt me if I go on too long I
really welcome that yes I just wanted to
piggyback on the gentleman to who before
me about the activism and political
thing I don't there is you talk about
the politician about all that but do you
guys get involved in the political clubs
where the back rule deal are being
talked about like for 20 bucks you can
join your Republican Club your Democrat
club or whatever club you want and see
those politician like Suresh and Maloney
come in and say Bitcoin is bad because
they is being used by sex worker and we
need to kill it and I was in the room
and I saw all those people go yeah we
need to do that I was like wait a minute
stop down we need to change that and
maybe if you guys were in the room with
us with me or other people we would be
able to say Carolyn we hate you and what
are you guys doing to try to educate the
population we are trying to get as many
people doing that as possible and this
is also a question of like privilege and
marginalization is that I you know I had
the blessing of being able to learn a
lot about how the political process
works and what is expected of me if I do
lobbying so on the ground we just have
to teach our peers where to find the
politics and how to engage with them but
we do do that as much as we possibly can
I'm in California we have certainly been
really involved and I think also maybe
the disappointing thing is that all of
these politicians are our clients
they know they see us um in fact in the
bay area there was just recently a sex
worker who got ripped off by a client
who just so happened to be a Republican
and so she had no shame she just like
blasted him on Twitter and was like this
is his Twitter profile he's a Republican
politician he's all about Trump and he
robbed me and now he fears for his
career because the big bad sex workers
are ganging up on him
so we yeah the place that we're in the
greatest contact with politicians is in
the bedroom and unfortunately that
hasn't been enough and we do need to get
in more political spaces and we need
people to help bring us in we need
organizations who do a lot of that
overhead to to extend a hand the
libertarian party has just officially
endorsed decriminalization that is gonna
be a big step but if you are concerned
about this contact a sex worker rights
group because I guarantee you there's a
bunch of activists who are raring and
ready to go they just don't know how to
access politics as we know it so thank
you I think that looks like time
come see me I'll answer any questions
you have