so uh and the lights are on so I can't
see any of you but I hope you're
settling down and before I start I just
want to say that you know I just caught
the end of what Chelsea was saying and
she talked about the quantum computing
and the dick and the encryption and
recently we did an event with Dave
father who Dave Farber who is the
grandfather of the Internet and he said
exactly the same thing that you know
without stronger encryption than we have
now everything's going to get screwed up
even blockchain or whatever it's only as
weak as the endpoints and so I echoed
what she says so my name is Joe Lee I'm
the president of the Internet Society of
New York I also do live streaming for
the internet society live streaming this
tonight and so the first thing I want to
say is to give out my thanks to the hope
knock to Hurricane electric who hooks up
I hope not to the Internet to the hope
AV team and the lighting team so that
without them as our co-workers we
wouldn't be able to put on this great
stream that people I hope are watching
all over the place and I know they are
in the mezzanine a big shout out to you
guys down in the mezzanine so so the
Internet Society was formed in 92 and it
was because the the National Science
Foundation that decided that they no
want no longer wanted to run the
backbone so it was handed off to the
backbone was handed off to commercial
providers and and the IETF needed a an
organizational home to run their
meetings and everything and so we're 25
years old and by coincidence 92 was also
the same year the e FF was formed so it
was a kind of significant year in
internet history Vint Cerf came up with
the phrase the internet is for everyone
and this is not an original idea for him
because even in the 80s he said I pee on
everything
but more complicatedly you know people
keep coming up to us downstairs and
saying what does the internet do
internet society do and so here's been
again saying we're trying to help all of
the stakeholders of the internet to
understand what the implications of the
technology are what policies are
beneficial and what rights and freedoms
need to be preserved in the use of this
system so then often says now he talks
about the internet or whatever replaces
it and you know the father of any child
knows how fragile its offspring is and
and I just you know recently been
talking to him and he still sort of come
back to this thing that he he's still
looking for something that's better than
the internet that might come on but at
the moment the internet society's
mission is to like hook everybody up
we were prevent this year and we've got
a project for the local chapter within
which is digital preservation and this
is something which doesn't get the kind
of attention that it might do that the
the reality that we're in right now of
with everything online is a lot of it is
ephemeral and so how it's been preserved
and conserved is an important thing
we've done some events already an event
I would like to do and I hope to do
later in the year is to get Vint and
Jason Scott in the same room
so yeah I'm Vince still is into
protocols and so this is something he
tweeted just yesterday a simple
flowchart getting back to the Internet
Society this is a simpler formulation
working for an Internet as open globally
connected and secure and so we've got a
bunch of key issues that we're working
on at the moment so the first one is
community networks and this is really a
big thing where we're looking at
we've got 3.5 billion people on the
internet we want to put another three
point there's another 3.5 to come on and
so the only way to do it is basically
for them to like hook themselves up
rather than waiting for the internet to
come to them so the last mile becomes
the first mile and so on
here in New York we're kind of leading
the way with the NYC mesh but this is a
picture of a bunch of guys in Georgia
sticking up a an antenna on a on a on a
mountaintop the next one that we're
looking at our key issue is Internet
Governance and so we're pushing the
multi-stakeholder model you know and
this is as an alternative to like being
run just by governments and industry the
multilateral model which so you know for
to promote multistakeholderism the third
one is the Internet of Things it's the
security of the Internet of Things the
fact that you know you you have all
these devices being cranked out that
don't have any any security in them they
aren't updatable online so trying to
figure out you know standards and doing
that in a multi-stakeholder fashion
we've got several processes going on
around the world to like establish
standards on that kind of thing and the
last one is routing security mutually
agreed nor the routing security so this
is kind of avoiding that I don't if you
remember a couple of a few years ago
when Pakistan hijacked the entire
YouTube traffic so this kind of thing
where people know who they're reaching
and the methods by which they're
reaching them the people can't poof on
BGP where the parent organization the
internet Engineering Task Force and so
in 92 the David Clarke articulated the
internet Creed Reva jet Kings presidents
and voting we believe in running code
and rough consensus and this is still
the way that the IETF runs but there was
a little that's well known but a little
less well known as these things that he
also said at the same time our best
success was not computing but hooking
people together the hacks of today are
the commonplace of tomorrow
the problem is assigning the correct
degree of fear to distant elephants and
that's what Chelsea was doing right
there if we have a problem it is due to
too much success that's for sure I
recommend reading the tower of the ITF
the internet society is financed by
dot-org we all the money that goes to
dog when you get a dog thing comes after
administration comes to us and that's
what pays for you is paying for your
streaming today ipv6 we launched it
properly in June June 6 2012 so we've
now just gone over 6 years 7 is the 7
year stretch coming next year we're
gonna try and make sure that we're just
getting into a point where suddenly
it'll become it will become the new
normal which is we more than it was then
I want to mention the internet Hall of
Fame this is a great thing that the
Internet Society does which not only
honest people that did stuff but also
you know if you if you go in there and
read through it it's better than reading
a history of the Internet to like look
at these people those videos of these
people this guy I want to mention this
Allen integer who's from Barbados where
in fact invented the first search engine
Archie I'm sure you old-school guys
remember Archie
so and he's a good example of a guy who
didn't you know someone said to him well
you could make some money off this he
said I don't want to make money I just
want people to be able to do it you know
if you read up about Larry and Sergey
that was their same idea at the
beginning they didn't want to make money
out of it they just thought it was like
you know they wanted to help people but
they got waylaid this is also on the
Internet Hall of Fame there's a very
good timeline of the internet it's well
worth reading getting back to the
Internet Society
we've got chapters all over the world
this is an old map we've got more
chapters than this
and we're a broad tent we have big
organizations you know Microsoft and and
people like that as well as you know
people like me we have a bunch of
special interest groups blockchain
community network cyber security
internet of food Internet of Things
interplanetary networking chapter which
is Vince as well delay-tolerant
networking the women special interest
group the youth special interest group
which is a spanish-speaking group and
one that I'm involved in which is an
accessibility special interest group
so we going back to community networking
what we had the Internet Society New
York have come to an arrangement with my
see mesh and in fact this was born out
of the last hope when we first shared it
shared our table with them and and that
was really what got them off the ground
at that time they had 40 nodes local
nodes now they have a hundred and
eighty-three nodes
since that and this is by the help of
engineers that were recruited here here
at Hope know to no good unless people
are hooked together and so there's a map
of the actual links between the modes so
the way that NYC mesh works is you know
you get the router you get the router on
your roof you have to pay for the
hardware to get it installed it's like a
hundred and something bucks and then you
basically make a donation of 20 bucks or
months to two and that's what you do
and that comes to us as the Internet
Society in New York where this fiscal
sponsor we're a 501 C 3 so you can
actually you know that's tax-deductible
donation at the end of the year for you
so you can take the internet off your
tax and and it's working well that's a
super node on top of the on top of the
savvy building the old Verizon building
downtown there's another super node in
in bed-stuy that one you can see there
and we're always looking for tall
buildings that we can get on the top of
with that so it's something to do so
we're actually taking donations for NYC
mesh downstairs and if you donate ten
bucks you can get one of these t-shirts
but you better hurry up because we're
going to run out of them today and just
a little more about the internet start
in New York I'd like to compliment one
of our board members Avril Doria who is
now a director of ICANN she spoke this
morning at nine o'clock I don't know if
you saw her and and then someone else
that we've actually got on our board
this year we've got a new guy this guy
Alexander Jay Ovilus
so we're you know won't be long before
he replaces me as president probably but
he's certainly going to replace me here
on stage right now
[Applause]