all right thank you so as the
introduction said I'm be Eve and this is
my partner mr. fo real we have a lot of
ground a lot of ground to cover today so
I'm gonna jump right into it we are not
here representing our employers we're
both security researchers we do a lot of
things we've been specifically told by
our employers not to bring their name up
so they will not be in this talk we've
conducted this research on our own time
using our own equipment we would also
like to make it clear that there are
things in this talk that made some
people may find offensive the fact is is
we do not condone any kind of racism
hate speech sexism anti-semitism
xenophobia bullying or online of
harassment the information that some
people might find offensive in nature is
actually from the posters themselves is
not actually from us there's also
another thing that I'd like to remind
people of and this is from our friends
at the e F F is that breaking terms of
services is not breaking the law
necessarily so you can break terms of
services but you want to be careful that
you don't you know have any legal issues
for us program committing crimes
obviously but breaking terms of services
not inherently by itself breaking law
and this was reinforced in July July for
January 2018 when the e FF and Oracle
had it out about this so and this type
of stuff that we're doing is inherently
dangerous it can be very risky on June
24 2018
mr. Okimoto use a 41 year old researcher
in Japan was doing a talk not unsimilar
to this one after he got done with the
talk he was stabbed to death in a
bathroom to mitigate this type of thing
we are not daxing people so I believe
that he was more about really calling
out individuals and bringing them to
light we actually are not in the
business of
calling individuals out so we actually a
lot of the stuff that we've done in this
particular talk we tried to make the
people and individuals who are in it
anonymized where it's not our place to
DOX them we don't believe and we're also
big proponents of free speech however
and we want people to be able to say
what they want and what not and not have
to be worried about being exposed like
that so to get to the bottom source of
this particular project and why I
started it and by a me for real started
working on it and why I came about and
August 2012 or excuse me
August 12th 2017 there was a white
nationalist rally and charlotte Ville
Virginia called unite the right and a
Dodge Challenger ran over some counter
protesters at 4:00 or excuse me 1:45
p.m. and one of those protestors was
Heather hire she was killed by the Dodge
Challenger she probably died doing what
she wanted to do she was you know
protesting she was she was counter
protesting this thing and she was only
32 years old and what I noticed is that
around this time on my cell phone I
started seeing news like this pop up
this is from Twitter and this is from a
site called got news and basically what
it was they had ID'd the driver of the
Challenger the Dodge Challenger or so
they thought got news immediately it was
kind of a parent that got news if it
actually didn't know what they're
talking about they're throwing this
information out there the guys name was
actually Joel he lived in Michigan and
he started getting death threats from
various people all over the country and
had to leave his house under like police
escort and whatnot and it wasn't just
got news that did this but it was a
freedom daily calm and gateway pendant
and other sites that started releasing
this information and and and hence the
led to Joel being harassed and having to
flee they're actually named in a lawsuit
later on those three websites Joel took
to Facebook and he said look I Drive a
Chevy Impala not a challenger you know
fuck the internet and I couldn't really
agree with him any more than that
because the
actual person involved was a person
named James a fields and he was a 20
year old individual he had voiced
racists and kind of pro-nazi thoughts in
the past and he was the actual killer
and one thing I'd like to to say so that
kind of got me thinking about this type
of stuff fake news BOTS and things of
that nature so one thing I'd like to say
if you find it to be or they donate
worthy thing and I think it is to
consider donating to the Heather Hired
foundation they provide scholarships for
people who are interested in legal
studies paralegal studies social justice
and things of that nature but with that
we decided to start a project not
related to the foundation but we decided
to start a project so after the incident
the project that I had mine I actually
had with this conference in mind coming
to hope and presenting here on it and
also at that time there was a lot of
news already out there about fake news
and bots and it was really really kind
of in the in the in the media and in
some ways a lot of our research has has
kind of been done before but we've added
some twist to it I will point out the
research that we're doing we're
primarily focusing when we talk about
fake news and stuff like that we're
talking about American or American or
what a beliefs appear to be American
based websites or people that are being
targeted from American for instance
there's fake news websites for Italian
think news websites we're not
concentrating on those we we don't know
the social norms of Italians of whatnot
so what we do is we focus on what we do
know which is mostly American and
English speaking types of sites but in
order to do this we know that we're
gonna have to create many many many
Twitter accounts in order to analyze the
data and we'd also need access to the
Twitter API as well one thing that the
Twitter API does is requires that your
account has a cell phone tied to it and
it's kind of one of the things that they
want you to do to keep people from
possibly abusing the API but in today's
day and age you can get unlocked cell
phones and whatnot fairly cheap and sim
cards even cheaper so for under five
dollars you can get a SIM card so what
we would do is we could we could
purchase SIM cards and create two
Twitter accounts that were validated
that could be that you could use the API
we use one account for kind of a read
access and one for a write access which
I'll get into more later so for a
hundred dollars or less you could have
50 validated accounts
I'm sure sophisticated operations could
probably do a lot cheaper and part of
this too is because we wanted to
understand necessarily how these
operators work so we wanted to kind of
mimic them in some ways don't even think
about using free SMS services so for
instance if you have an SMS service like
you know free I think it's like free SMS
received comm these things get abused
very quickly with Twitter a Twitter or
with Twitter but they also uh Twitter
places these fairly well too and a
little quick word about the Twitter API
the Twitter API has a lot of really good
information in it it has it's your
standard API you make a request about a
user or whatnot and it will return JSON
back and it's powerful in that it
returns a lot of information back for
you know everything from screen names to
location data and whatnot this this is
well-documented about how the API works
if you're interested in this type of
research feel free to go and read the
manual and documentation it's it's
really actually pretty fun so we decided
to start building some machines it's
actually a group of machines that work
together in conjunction with each other
so the first machine that we built we
called the hunter and what the hunter
does is it tries to identify BOTS bought
accounts fake news post or postings and
posters and hate speech
we kind of nixed off the hate speech
stuff because we found that software
inherently is difficult for it to
understand context of certain types of
speech so we kind of pulled that off and
plus it was quite frankly just
depressing to read all the time so we
kind of pulled that off and said we're
just going to concentrate on bots and
fake news
so in order to do bot detection again we
use the the Twitter API the kind of like
a read access kind of thing and it is
what the the hunter does is basically
goes out there and watch this for
trending topics trending hashtags it
watches for predetermined hashtags and
other things and then see who's talking
about it and then creates a kind of a
scoring mechanism we've done this in the
past for instance like with malware
where we say we have a piece of software
that executes this is kind of something
that we do but we execute some an
executable and then what we do is we
watched its behavior and ba saw its
behavior we create a score and if a
score meets a certain threshold we can
say oh we believe this might be malware
so he did it sound of the same thing
that we did with BOTS is to create that
kind of same thing so what we did is it
might go after the times that the
accounts were created or characteristics
of the name or were certain properties
of the accounts set up properly or not
set up at all and typically one score
doesn't typically cause the whole thing
to fall down that is so if we have you
might have a count that has a score that
might trigger off three or four
different behaviors but still not be
considered boxes it's got the score was
it registered that high there are other
characteristics so for instance an
individual who's tweeting three hundred
tweets per day you turn around say
that's probably a human and that we
actually make that score higher so so
that's how we kind of did the scoring on
the fake news sucked either side of
things we took 421 fake news domains now
when we talk about fake news I'm not
talking about parity domains or anything
like that we're talking about extremely
left or extremely right-wing domains
that either have really loaded or
misleading information in them or that
they are just blatantly false you know
things like it wasn't uncommon to come
something sites and they would have this
news article and right next to it and
say you know hair growth in three days
and Obama is a lizard so what we would
do is say that's probably not really
news so so keep that in mind and we also
used well to get on with it we but how
do we determine what's fake news so we
use there's a lot of different sites up
there that will help you determine me
bias and different types of sites so we
use those to kind of help us gauge and
actually looking at some of the sites
and saying yeah this does look like crap
so we use those so again we're trying to
get to the most extremely misleading or
flat-out false excluding things like
parody sites and whatnot and then we
tied a nice front end to it so make nice
colors and whatnot whenever it found
things and then we ran this stuff a lot
so we would set up accounts and then it
would run and run and run and then we
would collect data about boss fake news
and hate speech but for this particular
case bought some fake news so it went
out there and started doing its hunting
and whatnot and that was the first
machine that we call and we called it
the hunter now that looks for fake news
and whatnot
now lots of people built these similar
types of machines but we think our
scoring mechanism is fairly unique there
are plenty of other ways to do this
there's some people who are building
machines that rely on machine learning
and AI and whatnot and those are
certainly definitely good ways to to go
about this so we're not saying that
necessarily the best approaches is this
one that we found that worked very well
for us we also get suspicious to we'll
see if certain times where some
researchers will say my software can
tech 99.5% of all the bots on Twitter
and we kind of look at that a little bit
suspicious because it's kind of
difficult to get to that information
unless you can somehow necessarily
validate that what you call a bot is
actually a bot if that kind of makes
sense so anyways we say fake news we try
to exclude parody sites where possible
although parody is technically fake news
we're looking more at news that attempts
to influence or persuade in some cases
the sources that we use to acquire the
domains some of those were shown as
parody and we kind of dig through
that but also somewhere shown as neutral
a no further investigation we're kind of
really far in one direction or the other
so the next machine that we build after
building the hunter would read what the
hunter had found and this one we call
the poster so what the poster does and
this is where the research kind of flips
around a little bit what we ended up
doing is we take some data that the
hunter found so it's going through and
finding different types of information
we randomly pick a individual or whatnot
out of the database and what the poster
does it sends a message to that
particular account and it's especially
crafted URL and the message is usually
something about like this we're trying
to be as neutral as possible on this so
we just say things like our system has
identified you as opposed to possible
you know fake news are we wrong please
come see our scoring and then we can you
know you can see if that we're right or
not or we think that you're a bot or
whatnot and we create this kind of a URL
format where the ID is a unique ID into
our system and then the SHA is actually
a random shot to keep people from
enumerated through our tables and tables
and basically scraping our databases and
we send one message to the user we're
not attempting to harass them we're not
attending multiple multiple messages so
one thing that we noticed right off is
that the Twitter API is very well police
so with that in mind we need the poster
probably wouldn't work that well with
that you can bypass a lot of
restrictions if you can just use the web
interface but Twitter likes to make the
web interface really really difficult to
use for for automated routines they
obviously want you to do use their their
API but our theory is that or hypothesis
I should say is a lot a lot of the bad
guys probably don't use the API because
it's so well pleased so they go out of
their way to probably use the the web
front-end and this also gives us a
chance to better understand what
different attackers might be doing
- and also you can bypass a little bit
of some of the restrictions this clearly
breaks the terms of services of Twitter
by the way the second thing you start
doing this so we called this particular
process the the poster so if you
remember there's that link that gets
handed over to that we hand over to the
user that gets that goes to a website
called bot logic io can we do everything
that we promised that we would do we
take the user to a site and in that site
we explain why we consider them to be
fake news or they do be fake news but
why there might be posting that or what
why we think their score might behind it
- a bot what we also do is we collect
the information of the user that was
they came here so that's the IP address
and user agent that as it came the ID
helps us track tag that stuff back so we
can use that data later on we also
execute some JavaScript on the machine
as they come to our website this does a
couple of things for us it helps us
identify what is necessarily scraping
our site versus of what might be
actually human interaction and what not
so we run this and by the way this is
the nature of JavaScript it's not like
we're doing something inherently
different getting things like screen
sizes and extensions and salt on from
your web browser through executing
JavaScript is is what's done on the
Internet
we also don't instruments try to
obfuscate the code anybody who wants to
look at this isn't was more than welcome
to so what that kind of information that
comes back to us it kind of tells us
that for instance that we actually have
a real person or user involved in it and
we get so a little bit information out
of it as well so for instance we get a
what kind of browser it was what
language was set they have certain
applications to solve certain types of
extensions and whatnot so that one we
call the website and that gets us a
little bit more data a little bit more
deeper into things if you were noticing
very closely you might have noticed some
phone numbers and codes in here again
this also the phone number is allows the
person has they click on it if they have
a complaint about our service that they
can also
call up and and and tell us what they
think about it
so the code again izes to tie back to
the who the the twitter handle is to who
it is
so if you've ever seen any toxin ever
done in the past it always ends up or
somewhere telephony is involved so why
would we do this
so really the first thing we should
point out is the first thing when
somebody calls in we immediately say
this call will be recorded it is going
to be recorded the we can use this
information to kind of tie across
between the various types of data that
we get to get things like geographic
location whatnot but technically what
makes it more interesting is that you
end up with a open mic in the room of
the person who's calling in and you can
find out get a little just a little bit
more insight about what how their lives
are lived and has the potential to be
fairly funny as well so this one we
called the phone system and those are
the systems that we built we put
together so if we look at it from us
whole system overview which anything you
own add no well the yeah the phone
system super set us exactly it was kind
of potentially awkward and you know it's
set up so that was roughly about 30
seconds of the open mic oh yeah we
potentially made sure that whenever we
had a caller on that we had them on hold
and awkward things so that we could see
what was going on just to keep that mic
active so let's go back and just review
the how we're collecting the data we
have the Twitter API which is really
really powerful but to be honest that
all can all be set by the user so it's
it's less trusted out of the the data
that we have we can get things like IP
addresses from the website which which
is good but there's a lot of things for
instance like the second that you post a
link on Twitter it immediately
immediately gets gobbled up by
ironically bots for instance like
Facebook and Apple whatnot if you've
ever posted something and then like a
link and then you go to look at your
impressions and you say wow in 16
seconds I made 16 or you know 30 seconds
of 816 impressions
that's actually the bots going out and
checking out what your link is all about
you're not that popular so lastly you
have things you have the executive
JavaScript now that executes what we
found is about 13% of the people that we
sent the data are the links to but
actually and end up executing the
JavaScript suit but it's a smaller set
of data but it's a lot more accurate on
the last one which is the the phone call
that was really really low wheels
typically just a handful of calls a day
basically what we found is there's a bar
that you have to meet before people get
so angry that they call you and we met
that bar a lot but but but there was one
other thing that we realized that we
needed to do that was kind of important
to this project so we started a limited
liability corporation and do all of our
finding students so really we are the
board members bot logic and these are
the findings that we found through our
company and organization these are the
findings so we're gonna dive right in
here a little bit and again just just to
reiterate you know we're not saying that
this is conclusive evidence our findings
are not you know they're not exact more
research is needed more data is need to
be collected and correlated and but
based on on the best that we've been
able to collect and analyze this is what
we believe and you would like to hear
your opinions also right as you can tell
we're kind of hesitant to jump on to any
hardcore conclusions where we only can
deal with the data that we have is kind
of the point so we make some hypotheses
based off the data that we have and
thank you for bringing it up are so up
to June 24 2008 een would analyze about
2.4 million accounts give or take what
we saw is about 2% of them were people
who usually posted things related to
fake news at about 57,000 accounts about
half a percent was related and hate
speech but again that could be fairly
inaccurate that one would need to look a
little bit more at and then in that
about 7
percent or one hundred seventy two
thousand and a half appeared to be bots
according to our algorithm so to get
started on this let's get on looking at
the data let's talk about the bots so
out of that seven percent that we found
we actually found the majority of bots
don't really have any political or
political leanings I guess you'd say my
point is you have many things like
sports BOTS and and cloak BOTS and all
these type of things which so it's like
this puck isn't to say that inherently
all bots are bad but what we're seeing
is that most bots actually that we ran
into were not did not have any political
motivations behind them that we could
tell so we then kind of took the data
that we could get from Twitter so we
basically went back and said how many
accounts has Twitter disabled and then
does what we figured there is our
thought process was that if we go back
and we say these are BOTS and then
Twitter disables a bunch of things then
we're probably on the right track we can
use it as two different data sources to
kind of line up if that hopefully makes
sense and as you can see the percentages
aren't that far off as far as we can
tell you know they'd have roughly the
same patter powder and 22 percent of the
ones that Twitter disabled or roughly
thirty eight thousand Twitter BOTS every
day say but out of the hundred and
seventy two thousand there's kind of on
par of what we were our research shows
when we started to look deeper into it
BOTS with political motivations BOTS
that did have political motivations and
looked at what they mostly talked about
a common most common thing which is
probably groundbreaking and you guys
never would've guessed it is Trump make
America great and president and a bunch
of other ones as well we're in there as
well that's not terribly surprising but
what we started doing is kind of digging
into the data a little more you can kind
of hold into certain types of events so
this is a trend line of as we were
detecting BOTS so you you can go back
through and notice the dips and valleys
and whatnot in this the data range for
this video set is
October 10th 2017 to June 24 2008 een
and there's a peak in here if you look
this is really kind of interesting which
is November 11th 2017 yet again just a
keep bear in mind of where change lies
the peak the dip the peaks dip be the
kind of pattern there mm-hmm so we're
gonna focus on this and but definitely
know those dips at that count right
there is 1076 BOTS detected by the bot
logic LLC corporation so we can turn
around and say okay Twitter when did you
suspend accounts and we can kind of see
very similar peaks and dips and whatnot
and this actually brings the count to
494 using that cross-referencing we kind
of can say well between our data and
Twitter's own data or do the suspended
account we can say that these are more
than likely our BOTS okay then say you
have a political motivation or anything
that that's just saying that they're
about more than likely so now we're at
494 and so we're using the two sets of
data to better correlate hopefully and
we continue the correlation and we say
okay how about the Twitter suspend
accounts that are BOTS logically related
that have a language is set to ru and we
still end up with this peak over here if
you change it and you do things like C
in that you know for Chinese or whatnot
that peak kind of goes away so that
stays right there so that's kind of
interesting and and I'm sorry also this
isn't just standard ru this reflects all
dialogues yes it reflects all dialects
this brings our count to a hundred and
sixty-three so then we say okay well
show us the ones that are suspended that
we have detected that have ru that seem
to have political motivations behind
them and that brings the count to 153
when we say political motivations behind
them we're saying that the tweets don't
involve things like sports or something
like that they have direct tweets that
seem to have political obscene to be
political in nature so at that
particular point we can kind of say
through some data that we have it
appears that during this particular time
that there was likely some sort of
possible possibly Russian inter fluence
maybe maybe not but it is interesting to
say at least and we also see things like
if we go back to those particular counts
and say well when will these counts
created you'll notice that there's a big
spike shortly before that so we get
there looking at it and saying well what
caused this this kind of makes you know
a little spike in a data here in the
beginning of November to 2017 so a look
we get to see tweets like this so the
key thing is here is actually the CNN
blackmail thing which I'll get onto here
in a second but there is a lot of bots
that seem to be retweeting this so we
picked out the top one and this was the
top one out of our data set and we said
okay how that particular top tweet for
this particular subject based off all
the data that we pulled what were
Russian versus non Russian so and out of
this particular one small it's a very
small data set it basically says at 25
that this was 25 retweets but roughly 19
of them or 43% actually had what
appeared at least had the language has
been set it's not to say that other 57
isn't motivated or whatnot or has you
know maybe a Russian influence maybe not
but it's just saying what we have out of
our data set then we look at the next
one down and we have kind of a similar
thing we have the CNN blackmail thing
once again and then we look into that
and we say well how many Russia are you
set accounts versus non are you bots are
there and then once again this is 25
BOTS that were posting this 18 of them
appear to have possibly Russian ties or
42% anyways the the next one that we
have here in any kind of goes on and on
is basically what we see here is that we
every time we go down the list the
percentages were roughly the same and
that the there was not quite half a
little under half but they seem to have
at least are you associated with it when
we took the data set as a whole we would
notice that it actually flips quite a
bit so we said okay show us everything
that was related
this particular day with all that data
sets the Twitter suspensions are you all
that and none are you we put it all
together when you say show me everything
we see that it ends up to be about 72
percent or 181 and 51 51 BOTS or
twenty-eight percent that are non are
you related or you system okay now does
anybody remember what the CNN blackmail
thing was about me either I didn't
remember either so Donald Trump had
decided well lookit there is a animated
gif that was going around and it showed
Donald Trump literally body slamming the
CNN logo and rest in a wrestling match
and I'm doing as any president should do
he he immediately retweeted to all of
his father followers cuz he's president
that's what you do so a CNN reporter
actually tracked down the kid who made
this meme and it was a reddit user but
when I was seen and actually went to and
they said he apologized and said he
wasn't gonna do this again and evidently
we should a lot of remorse but when CNN
published the article they decided that
they would put these words in it CNN
reserves the right to publish the
identity should any of that change and
hence the reason CNN blackmail was born
and what we're seeing is probably our
hypothesis is is a trying to amplify the
voices of the CNN blackmail not
everything about it was about the CNN
hold blackmail thing so we're kind of
latching onto it to get other kinds of
political possible political motivations
out there on the CNN hashtag to see unit
blackmail hashtag one thing that we did
also notice as well is that a lot of the
bots and again these are probably that
this has nothing to do this is just BOTS
in general most of them set their
location to complete utter gibberish so
it might be a good thing to be looking
at for as an indicator but let's move on
to a little bit of fake news so by far
the top fake news website that we saw is
your news wires calm but it was solid
had us right behind it was
he was your Newswires my calm and Got
News was right behind it and you'll see
there's some ones in here like South
forg which has been previously reported
in the past as being a Russian front
that was still about 4% of our queries
when we look at the data from Twitter
you would think that the majority of
people who are posting fake news are
actually out of Las Vegas Nevada but it
remind you again this information is
probably the least accurate because it's
user set so what we can do we can pivot
over to the IP addresses which gives you
some indication about what's going on
and if we look here then we say oh my
gosh California is the biggest place to
post fake news which seems a little bit
strange that's because it is because you
remember whenever I said he'd post a
link it usually gets gobbled up by other
bots so on those BOTS or like these so
for instance the Twitter bot is
obviously the top one so when it does a
link whenever you put a link up there it
gobbles it up first you have other
things like Yahoo at Apple and whatnot
but by going by the user agent we can
kind of clean up the tables to hopefully
give us a little bit of a better picture
of where most most people are posting
fake news from so when we clean it up a
little bit
California kind of goes away here and
then we end up with Florida Georgia and
up near the Great Lakes there's some
stuff in Europe I won't go into much
into this because this is again
something that I actually we're focusing
more in the United States but anyways to
get over to the more relevant slide
after cleaning it up I mean this isn't
terribly surprising easier Florida and
Georgia are the top these posters it's
stunning but we can go actually a little
bit further because the IP data even
though we've cleaned it up we don't know
if we've cleaned it up a hundred percent
but we do have a smaller subset of data
which will lead us back to JavaScript so
we can look at the JavaScript that was
executed and we can say again
Florida Georgia Southern California
which is one actually that I didn't
expect and you can kind of get a lay out
there where most of the people who bring
up this type of stuff is so with this
kind of data you can also get into
individual targeting one thing that
comes up a lot whenever we think
fake news or and whatnot we can tend to
think of it as a BOTS pushing
conservative agendas and what we're able
to kind of show a little bit of is that
that that's not necessarily always the
case it appears that people play both
sides of the argument probably the so
discourse into so we have three young
ladies here that's Veronica and Deena
and they're from Ohio and ones from
California and they're all members of
the resist movements and they are all
very anti Trump they all said this
verbatim separately from one another
which is part of the logic that we have
in finding a bots that they weren't
retweeting each other they're all saying
this individually and they also be
crushing and they're all their accounts
are suspended so if we look a little bit
further into what they're promoting
these are kind of more left-leaning
sites if I could say the the way that we
know that they said the things were
Batum back earlier beef talked about
doing shot ones so that every tweet that
we recorded we have a shot one of so if
we compare the Shaw's then it's apparent
which ones are original so we could tie
people together saying verbatim type of
thing so we could say maybe this is part
of some sort of campaign these women
were posting basically like Vegas Hill
Denver poll he'll press org and other
sites and this one's a Denver poll and
so these sites use a lot of like loaded
turns one on the left hand side of
things and you'll see the stunning
differences between all the sites
they're almost exactly the same this is
a Vegas Hill calm so probably run by the
same same type of groups and whatnot we
can also pull so after we saw this type
of campaign we can pull the domains that
there are websites that they're talking
about and do some interesting things
with multigo I'll let you talk about
tracking codes you want to go do that so
yeah this was on run froze web breacher
or
Mark Belling cat it's not an original
concept but effectively taking what
websites finding different tracking
codes for example Google Analytics tags
Adsense AdWords so the types of things
that are typically administered by you
know a single point a website owner
might track several other websites using
these tags and helps them see which
search terms attract people what sites
they come from and that sort of thing so
what we've identified as through some of
these sites where we follow and follow
the tweeters to their web sites find the
web sites grab the tracking codes from
the tracking codes
we're being able to find matches for
example we see that Vegas Hill has two
separate codes there it shares both
those with Politico to us shares one of
those was super Hill Don info super hill
dot info we see has two tags one of
those it shares with Denver Pole comm
said them we've also been able to pivot
for example from he Politico to us to
Sparta netizen comm and we've done this
with a number of different sites but
it's an interesting way again not
necessarily uh you know nail in the
coffin but it does appear to be a good
identifier I'd help associate the
websites that may on the surface not
appear to be related so what we do - as
well we would use this method to
actually find other sites that maybe are
fairly new so if somebody like these
ladies have posted a particular site we
would grab that pull the analytics tags
and then start using those to find other
sites and kind of kind of expand out
we also found just so this is kind of
another example of that exact same thing
so for instances there is a website
called USD crisis comm and I'm pretty
sure everybody in here knows who RT comm
is so right
Russia tick of course the USD crisis
comm is a site that talks about how
sanctions on Russia hurts the US dollar
and whatnot it's actually an amazingly
screwed up website that forms are kind
of screwed up and whatnot but it's
hosted in Newcastle England by ISP
called wild card UK unlimited and so we
pull the analytics tags for USD crisis
calm
and we start looking at them the ones on
the far right and the far left largely
leave the nowhere but then whenever you
look at the middle particular analytic
it leads all back over to our t-dot-com
now keep in mind analytic tags are used
so that you can see who's how much
traffic is coming to your website there
is some gaming that can be done with
analytic tags but it's hard for us to
understand why somebody to necessarily
go out of their way again as he was
putting out this isn't to say that this
is some sort of nail in the coffin kind
of thing but it's a strange indicator
that there might be a possible link
between the two the person who has for
instance USD crisis comm all of his
analytics now go to the console that the
RT people have liked by doing this so it
doesn't make a lot of sense to us by
that so that's kind of a hypothesis that
we have and you can do this with a lot
of different types of sites so for
instance this is cbsnews.com dot co and
freedom crossroads us and CNN - global
news calm and Florida Sun post the
highlighted domains are the ones that
appear to be are you related the rest of
them are typically porn sites and things
that are native to some online gambling
and what done here's an older one that
happened a while back this is a teen
news 24 and it's an older fake news site
and actually I think it's been bought up
by Asian furniture manufacturer if you
go there now they sell furniture but at
the particular time they were doing much
more than that or different things and
almost every indicator on this
particular one this is this again this
is an older one and what we find
interesting is that we have this is like
an example news thing that used to
connect used came from a news 24 calm
talking about Denzel Washington
switching over to Trump needs to say
whenever you do this type of research
especially the way that we're doing it
we get some very very interesting
response because it's not only can we
talk to them but they can talk back to
us so right off the bat don't leave this
up here for a second you get a lot of
the same type of things that we would
normally expect to get you know a lot of
people really really mad and whatnot and
it's fine
and I understand that you actually do
get some people who are pretty smart
again only about 13% of the people that
we send you links to actually clicked on
anything which is pretty good so we
occasionally we get these as well and
there
you know no way I'm dating a lot of
people just didn't click on it we got
some that were a little bit more
confusing and share the need for things
like punctuation and or or they really
want to prove that they're not a bot I
don't understand how that works but that
was one of our favorites so some of them
made a smile a lot
I would let's go into the phone system a
little bit there is again all the stuff
we've taken a lot of stuff we can get
into incredible detail this type of
research again we're trying to protect
the identities of the other people so
I'd like to hear some of the stuff that
maybe the bot logic phone system heard
okay well we have a couple of things and
also real quick ill will put out a tool
called Skip tracer use that with some of
the phone numbers that we'll all the
phones we had right and it's actually a
very good utility really some you know a
lot of information from these accounts
I'd like to thank him for that to him
okay so we're gonna go for this here
this is a person named Joe he was born
in 1959 he tends to put fake news he's
from Tennessee it actually is from an
unincorporated area just outside of
Chattanooga
he's his Firefox he has Flash installed
he works at a company that develops and
manufactures and markets pharmaceutical
products and a lot of the information
again to using things like elbows tool
you get things like email addresses and
whatnot
and hopefully you guys will be able to
hear this and here comes so I do not
appreciate an algorithm or a robot or a
computer calling me a liar I am a real
person I do not tell lies and I can back
my stuff up with facts
unlike the fake news that you accuse me
of promoting I do not appreciate this I
don't know if I don't know where the
who the sources of this but but I'll
tell you this I will testify against you
on Judgment Day so he also called us
Mark Zuckerberg a robot and a few other
things which i think is a great band
name by the way and what not so you know
he was but we also had people who didn't
like us so this is John he was born in
1953 he tweets a whole lot we actually
did identify him as a bot the last one
actually we did not identify as a bot we
didn't never call him Bob we never said
anything about that what he said that
you might be posting fake news we he
lives in Colorado he uses Chrome he's a
wonder he's lovely individual yeah uh go
ahead so this is what Joe art yes John
had to say to us my name is John phone
number five I'm calling about this
bullshit you're saying about me on the
other net on Twitter I'm a fucking mom
all you trying to do is touch and
suppress conservatives right I don't use
that's not gonna call me back I'm like
fucking call me to the answers of god
damn phone piece of shit
so again lovely and he kept true to his
word to his particular degree he called
again thanks John me again I said five
doesn't get his lying fucking propaganda
let this position shit would you like
you've never been fucked before asshole
I have never been called lib tarped so
many times in my life so we checked the
you know well why do we think these
people were faked news and we looked at
the news and it is some of the stuff
like Obama's a lizard person and
and and it's striking that you know
these people kids that are just real
news it's it's interesting right and
here is one more that well throughout
here I'm not going to even put a name or
anything out there she has a very unique
name from Louisiana tweeted a lot she
uses an Android Android 4.4.4 we can
back that up with her screen size and
what not what she her a rude initial
tweet was about this that hackers had
taken over control of the US Navy tech
and launched a missile to shoot down
Trump and while he was enroute to North
Korea you guys didn't hear about that oh
I thought it was pretty common knowledge
so here hers is really short and sweet
mmm and that's kind of nice here's my
message do I sound like a goddamn block
to you screw this shit don't ever send
me messages again and we didn't there
are a lot more recordings as I said well
let me rephrase that there are probably
30 or so recordings that we have we
didn't want to put them all on the slide
but you're welcome to call the bot logic
LLC phone number and feel free to listen
to them at your convenience they are
played randomly they are edited so and
is the full conversation from beginning
to end of the top oh yeah yeah we had a
counterpart friend of ours who really
helped us with a lot of the the editing
of these because it takes a little bit
of time named Jim Christian and I just
wanted to kind of give a shout out to
her we cannot release the the data that
we are datasets for legal reasons
however we can release tools that we use
to generate the data or make the
datasets so this is the where you can go
to get the code that we use to find BOTS
and and all that fun stuff release it
under GPL version 2 it's mostly written
in Perl and oh and one thing I'd like to
point out if you have any questions and
you didn't get a chance to ask them or
you didn't get to see us and where
you're watching this from remote or by
YouTube feel free to open an issue and
then we'll answer your question that way
I'll give some just really quick final
thoughts so
about this project as we get through so
Twitter is actually policing their
platform fairly well and they assumed he
could be getting even more more
aggressive with it they recently
terminated a body who had an age that
was under 16 I believe it was they are
getting a lot more aggressive about it
it's they're really in a bad situation
because no matter what they do to try to
keep people from say using the web
interface for posting there is always
going to be a way around it so for
instance if they use a lot of JavaScript
to try to keep you from just directly
logging in and we figured out little
ways to get around that but the fact is
is even if they made us use it we would
just use a web browser and things like
mechanized chrome that would allow us to
automate web browsing functions so they
really have a hard task ahead of them
and it's still fairly easy to evade
especially on the web front end some of
their things to detect bots and whatnot
and doing this stuff is pretty cheap for
the most part as I said the review
there's probably professionals who do
this and they do it way cheaper than we
do but these thing types of operations
are really hard to maintain you got to
create accounts you got to get them set
up they get suspended
you got to set more up you got it so
it's constantly it's kind of it's it's a
pretty ongoing type of thing it takes a
lot of time and patience and the fact
that it is actually Twitter has the best
data sets but we're certainly not going
to see them so sometimes you have to
kind of take that data if you can't one
thing that I think about what I think
about social media and Twitter and
whatnot his um who was into BBS's into
80s alright okay in the 80s do you
remember what happened after Christmas
Day
everybody got a modem and they would
call in and then everybody who's already
on BBS's would hate everybody who just
got modems because all those kids would
get on and they say I'm the best hacker
in the world and screw all you guys and
what would eventually happen is they
would either kind of fall in a place and
become a part of the scene so to speak
or they get tired of using their modem
and throw it away I'm kind of hoping
that this is what's happening with
social media like maybe the next
generation or so we won't see it as so
divisive that
tool that it can be in simply a means of
communications but until that day this
is where we're at and that's pretty much
our final thoughts on this so I guess if
we have some time which I think we do
I'm in there too for questions perfect
okay and again if you have any questions
and you don't get a chance to feel free
to open issue on github but please go
ahead thank you hi there I'd like to
thank you for your presentation
thank you in case you don't know me I
let me introduce myself I'm from the
internet we've met some of you yeah nice
no I'm not gonna be as all colorful as
those people that you know those flyover
country low information people that were
on those recordings that you offered but
I do have a comment I was actually at
Charlotte's film oh okay yeah I was
actually there so I witness not to the
idea incident but to some of the events
that went down so just just for
reference not everyone is getting your
information second hand there are
flesh-and-blood human beings that you
know are real and do tweet and do stuff
so I being one of those I just wanted to
to ask you because this is a question I
want to ask being that like any zero
information person can flip on the TV
and get the whole Russian shebang that
you kind of went through rather a lot of
effort I must say to a demonstrate here
mm-hm
why did you feel the need to go through
with this you know to prove something
that's kind of good you mean from from
our standpoint yeah I mean you know I
mean it you could just flip on the TV
and that you get all of the so-called
intelligence community certifying
absolutely certifying that sure no way
no whose are behind it very well yes I
mean what what gives with all the effort
and what it was trying to understand the
motivations of how particular operations
run so for instance like fake news
operations and BOTS like that we wanted
to see it not just necessarily just read
about it one thing I should point out
too whenever we talk without neglected
to bring up when a lot of people focus
on the facts of the fake news so they'll
find a news site and they'll say it's
full in it you know factually in a
correct we think
as from a hacker standpoint looking at
the site for more technical standpoints
gives us more an idea of what the
motivations might be as well so you're
not just looking at the words that are
on the page but you're using tools like
multigo and tracking codes and other
techniques to maybe figure out what the
motivations are and those kind of things
hopefully we will definitely be
available and we'll be around oh we have
well here I'll just show them as we get
up stage we have some shirts that say
trolling the trolls on the back and
you'll be able to see us so thank you
very much
[Applause]