[Applause]
hi everybody and there has been a change
so we have dkg here instead of Aubry I'm
not Audrey
yes and so I'm Mallory knodel I work for
article 19 and I work in ITF and I can
and we're actually gonna do a bit more
there's no real moderation so we're just
going to be asking each other some
questions that hopefully will inspire
you to ask us as well
and the reason why we came up with this
panel is that all of us work in
standard-setting bodies and we but we
are also affiliated with civil society
organizations which is may be different
than you know engineers working for
companies or it just it creates a
different dynamic and I think we're
there for different reasons so you'll
get I think a different take on what's
happening in this different places so so
that's the idea and this this work at
least for our decline teen was sparked
in around 2011-2012 and then actually
turned into a program of article 19
which is in human rights for expression
NGO in in England and because Audrey who
is going to be on the panel wrote a
paper with another of my colleagues at
the time I was working with Aubrey and
joy lit a coat at the Association for
progressive communications they wrote
this paper on the alignment or the the
similarities between multi-stakeholder
Internet governance and the technical
community and the Human Rights kinds of
advocacy that is done in general
internet governance but is also
applicable and interesting to do in the
technical community standard setting
because that was at the time not not
clear to people that it would actually
be a worthwhile venture to do that and
so that was back in 2011 and what came
out of that was people well well the
paper you can you can go and find it
it's about human rights considerations
in Internet protocols and it basically
looked at the early RFC's coming out of
the ITF and how that and how they were
how the values expressed in those early
RFC's of an open interoperable internet
and so on maps really quite nicely with
some of the work human rights
organizations were trying to achieve
in getting a more open and and free
internet for all so with that I actually
want to shift to talking specifically
about the IETF I want to ask Daniel um
dkg so some people argue that ITF is a
really great and this is why that paper
came out was the ITF is a really great
example of how open an open standard
setting body you know could could
facilitate discussion about human rights
at the technical level so do you feel
like that that is an accurate
characterization of the IETF that it's
it's open Thanks so just so folks know
who I am
I'm Daniel con Gilmore I'm not a free
people call me dkg online which is just
my handle which my initials I work for
the ACLU the American Civil Liberties
Union as a technologist focused on
speech privacy technology and sort of
the intersection of civil rights and
civil liberties in tech and so I've been
at the IETF for a while I've
participated well before I started at
the ACLU and so in some sense the ITTF
the internet Engineering Task Force
which is the folks who make the RFC
series so if you ever hear you know
people are talking about rfcs for
software implementation that comes out
of the IETF you can participate just by
joining a mailing list so in that sense
it's very open it really does
accommodate people who want to just
swoop in read a little bit contribute
you can write a document anybody here if
they want to can actually post an
internet draft which could lead
potentially eventually to an RFC today
right now if you wanted to so in that
sense it's very open on the other hand
the discussions are fairly technical and
it requires some level of technical
understanding for people to take you
seriously there and it requires some
level of persistence and perseverance
you have to have the time to be able to
negotiate among all the different
stakeholders and even understand who
they all are and what their interests
are so well-well just participating is
very open actually being doing effective
work there is not necessarily because of
the level of sustained engagement that's
required and then we on top of that like
many tech spaces
it's an overwhelmingly male space it's
an overwhelmingly white space it's
overwhelmingly the global north there's
so so it it has a bit of an old old boys
club which is slowly slowly shifting I
would love to see it shift faster but
you know a lot of the a lot of the
decisions will get made people will make
agreements based on oh well that's so
and so I've been talking to them for 20
years right and so the sooner we can
make the changes to really get more
perspectives in the IETF the better so
that that that old boys club doesn't
have the decision-making power so it's
open you don't have to pay membership to
join but you have to attend if you
really want to get things done it's
useful to attend the conferences which
can be expensive and you have to persist
which takes time and not everybody has
the time to do it yeah so so one of the
things that's happened that the that I
noticed that the at the IETF is how long
it like the persistence problem and so I
know that for me you know going from
submitting a proposed standard to
actually getting it into a draft takes
multiple years Emilia I think you're
active within the I Triple E and my
understanding is it might take even
longer for standards to come out of the
I Triple E can you can you talk about
the cadence of the process and how it
affects your work yeah so my name is
Amelia andersdotter I work for article
19 covering the I Triple E 802 Lanvin
Standards Committee they make the
Ethernet standard and architectures of
network standards as well as the
standard for that is underlying Wi-Fi
networks it isn't the Wi-Fi standard but
it is the standards for the technology
that underlies Wi-Fi networks that are
used all over the world and so it's a
fairly mature technology it was
developed in the 1990s and all the way
up to 2010 they had some really
revolutionary changes that improved the
quality of Wi-Fi networks a lot I think
now that it's maturing well they're
looking into so first of all they're
aware that they take a lot of time
making the standards and because they
see themselves as competitors with
cellular networks and now the 3gpp and
5g standards
they're a bit stressed out also about
how long it's taking them to complete
standards but because they were very
mature standard any changes to the
underlying can a physical way in which
you make wireless communication chips
it's going to be a lot of tough
negotiations between the essentially
very few global actors that are
designing and producing these chips but
when I found in terms of strategy of
engagement with them is that the I truly
802 like many other standards bodies
have a large technical depth with
respect to privacy and security and so
actually those are areas where you can
have more speedy advancement of
amendments or processes or getting them
to reflect upon or develop new
strategies for dealing with these topics
in a quicker way so also because there's
such an avalanche now of security and
privacy laws from all over the world I
know that Alex Muntz was talking about
this yesterday so I believe that there's
a possibility at least that the I Triple
Aim to get a slightly more speedy
process maybe even IETF level speediness
when it comes to those particular topics
but when it comes of course to changing
you know energy efficiency throughput of
these chips that's just going to take
them a bit of time also you have to
acknowledge because the ADA 2.11 group
which does the technical infrastructure
underlying Wi-Fi networks that basically
requires them to reset their
Manufacturing procedures build new fabs
basically so that's just going to take a
lot of time and it's a really heavy
investment for these companies to do
when you have to be cognizant of those
can a structural limits to the speeds
that they they can actually have and
their standards processes right with
most IETF stuff its software and you can
just roll out a new version of software
if we have an update cycle yeah sure
it's the same thing at the I Triple E
yes so they have the physical level
which is really difficult for them to
change and then there's the mac level
where all of the identifiers are and
where you actually need protocols to be
able to have the devices interact and at
the atomic level
you can have more speedy changes and I
think the I Triple E is certainly making
efforts into seeing how they can be more
quick
that's a quickness can also be a bad
thing because if somebody is rushing
through things especially if they're
large companies that are meeting not
only in the I Triple E 802 but in a
bunch of different venues it means they
can concoct ideas in a different forum
from the one where you're at and it
makes it more difficult for you to
oversee it so I appreciate the
institutional inertia as well because
it's there to make things more
foreseeable for the big companies of
course but it also helps out when you're
a civil society organization yeah
so speaking of local organizations that
may be moving even more glacially Mavic
you're at the International
Telecommunications Union which is a
United Nations body there for a long
time so and it has members nation-states
as the most powerful members so what are
the unique challenges that follow from
that structure and how do you approach
the ITU yeah so first just introduce
myself my name is Manish I also work
with article 19 youth Malory and Amelia
and as Amelia has just suggested I my
work only mainly focuses on ITU
technical standard settings so work that
happens within the itu-t and the work
they're really the where we focus is
mostly in study group 20 which is
looking at IOT in smart cities and in
city groups 17 which is looking at
technical standards related to security
some as Emilia mentioned the ITU is not
a technical community in the same way
that the IETF is or the I Triple E
it's a UN specialized agency it's in
fact the oldest UN agency it used to be
the International Telegraph Union and
then it reformed into the international
telecommunication union in the last
couple of decades it's expanded its
traditional mandate on
11e to include Internet related
standards development and that kind of
mandate expansion has had some serious
implications for for human rights due to
it due to the particularity z' of its
structure and I think membership is an
important factor of that as Emilia
mentioned it is governmental governments
are or member states are the most
powerful actors within the ITU and I
think the the fundamental result of that
is that the ITU is an incredibly weak
standards environment and I think there
are three dynamics that really explain
that phenomenon quite well the first one
is just there's just a systemic lack of
technical competency within the ITU I
think the i2 recognizes this and that's
why it bills itself as a public-private
partnership it really puts in a lot of
time and resources to bring in industry
to bring in big vendors to help
participate in its standards development
processes to give it more legitimacy as
a technical authority but even even then
it's still primarily an
intergovernmental body the people who
represent governments some of them might
be from national telecommunications
regulatory authorities but for the most
part they are diplomats their foreign
policy wonks that might have some kind
of training and international
communications or ICTs but that kind of
that kind of technical competency just
isn't there
the second dynamic within the ITU really
is a lack of accountability and that's
that leads to politicization and that if
that phenomena really has to do with the
particular membership structure of the
ITU itself on the one hand membership at
the ITU is incredibly closed like I said
it's mostly just kind of focused on
getting government membership to a far
lesser extent industry industry can
participate as members in the i2 but
they do not have the same level of
voting rights or privileges that
governments do quite clearly so and
deliberately so and you can just forget
about it if you're civil
Society in terms of trying to
participate meaningfully in ITU
standards processes you will not be able
to get membership on your own title the
i2 does not want you there they make it
very clear because you make government's
job quite difficult and trying to do the
work they want to do and at the same
time of course the it's incredibly
opaque and the opacity of that
decision-making process means that there
isn't enough transparency for external
scrutiny so even if you can't get
involved in decision-making processes
within the ITU you can't even keep track
of what's happening to see what's in the
pipeline and really because of that it's
a perfect ground for governments to one
engage in geopolitics and two to kind of
advance standards agendas that are
actually quite repressive that would
that would kind of be met with start
scrutiny elsewhere and other in other
technical communities and then the third
the third dynamic is really that
fundamentally the ITU is a diplomatic
institution and so you know even if it's
similar to the ITF in terms of its core
that you know the primacy of consensus
based decision making it's it has a very
different outlook from the IT and the
IETF in terms of what a good outcome
looks like and that's really because
it's diplomats who are doing the
decision-making and diplomats are kind
of trained the one thing they're trained
in is compromise and so for them a good
text is really one that's that has a lot
of compromise language that everyone can
agree like with a little bit and I think
with technical communities kind of bad
standard is is just a bad standard right
and in technical in technical parlance
so we just don't have that same kind of
that level of kind of the the desire to
have the same kind of technical rigor or
standards within the ITU but so Manish
it strikes me when you're talking that
at the ITF I've got the I Triple E as
far I understood Daniel and also my
experience it's very clear who is
participating like who are the technical
standards for so the IETF has all of the
vendors that are meant to eventually
implement these standards the research
communities that make work with the
standards afterwards at the I Triple E
802 group that is also
definitely the case that the companies
that apply the standards that change
their manufacturing equipment they're
the ones that are also participating in
that process but if the ITU has a very
weak standards process and they lack the
technical qualifications for really
writing the standards in a good way who
are the consumers of these standards
like where do where does all of the work
that you're doing eventually end up I
think in terms of in terms of the ITU
the standards are really there to
facilitate government agendas in terms
of what their ICT policies are and in
that sense it's it kind of speaks to
again going back to - those kind of
three dynamics
it's the particularity of those dynamics
that really allow for governments to
kind of advance agendas that they
wouldn't otherwise be able to another
technical in another technical spaces
right particularly ones that might
enable greater centralization or might
enable censorship or surveillance I
think in the IETF and even to an
increasing extent within the I Triple E
there is increasing understanding of
security and privacy considerations and
that's really due to having stakeholder
input and having a more diverse kind of
a spectrum of membership and interests
within participating within those
standards bodies and that just isn't
present within the ITU I'm so actually
as part of that I wanted to turn that
same question over to you in a way
because unlike the ITU the I Triple E is
a membership organization that is
dominated by industry even though of
course industry and governments tend to
work hand in hand I want to know from
you how you navigate that environment
especially considering the fact that
you're from neither stakeholder group
yeah well most they are Tripoli is an
individual membership organization much
like the IDF so you're meant to show up
in your individual capacity every member
has a duty according to the code of
ethics to to act according to their best
engineering
assessment of any particular standard
and so in in that sense you're kind of
formally supposed not to enter into the
I Triple E as a representative of your
company that makes it again a bit
different from say the 3gpp where
actually you would go representing your
company there's a company corporate
delegation from your company and you go
to represent it at the I Triple E this
is not the case that doesn't mean that
we don't have government's showing up
but in particular I noticed the US
government showing up so there's a few
you know people from the Department of
Transport that are very interested in
ensuring that the I Triple E doesn't
change any of its standards that they're
trying to use for harmonizing you know
self-driving cars or just in general car
networks and so they're they're very
lovely people then there's a few people
that come from the various forms of
consultancies where you can have where
there's rumors about who might be paying
their consultancy to show up at the
meetings but you can basically only get
information about that is gossip and
they have rules that they are to believe
that you need to disclose your
affiliation so I need to always have on
my badge that I'm from article 19 and
other people also need to state who are
sponsoring them to participate and I
think that was motivated by some
antitrust problems that they had a few
years ago where basically some some
larger actors in the field were accused
of sending a lot of Delegates kind of
anonymously to the forum which really
worked at the competitive field and the
chip in the silicon market in that
corporate actors favor so so affiliation
has always dated and this is like the
first thing that you do in order to map
out the corporate dynamics of the space
then you can rely on you know gossip to
figure out if the government's are
trying to do shady interventions and
then there's a few people that are also
just completely open about hi we're kind
of covering this interest because it's
just genuinely in our interest that
these technical people don't get any
funny ideas that will then support our
ten twenty year plan for for how to make
society a dreary place to live in
I can give an example of something like
that that happened at the ietf recently
and probably will still continue to
happen if folks are interested is that
the the the transport layer security
working group at the IETF TLS is the
thing that gives you the security and
HTTPS among other things we've just
announced TLS 1.3 hopefully we'll be
officially standardised relatively soon
it's it's in the last stage of the
document represent preparation process
and one of the things that it does is it
removes it basically forces all of the
new version of TLS to negotiate a
security connection with slightly better
properties than the old versions would
allow so in particular we are mandating
forward secrecy I don't get into what
forward secrecy is but it's better to
have it than to not have it and TLS 1.3
the new version requires it and the a
group of US banks and I'm going to
mangle the name of the consortium that
they that they appeared under basically
said give us back the non forward secure
connections because the the
vulnerabilities with non forward
security we were actually using those to
be able to debug our networks we were we
were collecting traffic and decrypting
it all and like if you take this away
from us then you know your grandmother
won't be able to make a bank transaction
because we won't be able to debug our
networks our networks are very
complicated which you know I wouldn't
it's embarrassing always to stand up and
say I've made an engineering mistake but
they were willing to do that for some
reason and then they actually packed the
room so in terms of like representation
I've never seen so many bankers come to
an IETF meeting before but they all came
to try to push through mechanisms to
reverse this forward security decision
and so that does happen which misses
this is a situation where I think the
folks who care about security and
privacy and autonomy need to have sort
of a constant vigilance so I'm certainly
grateful to have people you know at all
these tenders bodies just to name a few
that aren't being represented here
there's the w3c Emilia you'd mention
3gpp there's GSMA which is mobile
telephony there's a bunch of other
groups
that are out there that we do want more
people who you know who care about the
things that I think hope cares about
generally to be at these places right so
switching over back to privacy and
security I wanted to get Mallory back in
the conversation with some comments
about the icon so the European Data
Protection Board has been complaining
about who is for about 15 years can you
talk a bit so there's been a lot of
controversy and someone in the audience
might have heard about this spring could
you talk a bit about what is happening
is I can fixing the Whois problem what
is the who is maybe also and how do you
see that playing out in the upcoming six
to twelve months let's say yeah so I
mean I Cannes a bit of an outlier I mean
they're all unique right but I can just
policy really it's not a technical
standard setting but it's an important
place to work in because these policies
are really important for privacy and
security as you're alluding to and also
ICANN is pretty its multi-stakeholder
right you have a lot more civil society
organizations involved in ICANN than
these other places maybe it's because of
the technical or the non-technical
nature of I can but I think there's
other things that play like there's the
non-commercial user constituency like
there are all kinds of mechanisms as
well to include not just an industry in
government so so I can't is interesting
but it has its flaws for example like
not effectively being able to deal with
the privacy issues around who is which
is the database of people who have
bought domains and their information and
some of it is personally identifiable
information sometimes it's not always
clear what kind of information you're
giving or how it's presented to to
non-technical people because it's
actually just a transaction you just buy
a domain
it doesn't require any technical
knowledge so people may not understood
you know what what they're doing when
they give over their information and in
what who is so it's a queryable database
of all this stuff so so yes so it has
always been identified as a privacy
problem in fact by like high level you
know nation like you know country and in
particular the EU
is like you know a board as part of the
EU has has has identified this so and
for sure there's also been in the past
California law which I think I can is
incorporated in California which would
have had you know a direct impact on
something like who is so there it's not
for lack of trying that from from from a
like national national policy
perspective it's really a failure I
think at ICANN level and not really
prioritizing it I mean it's clear now
that with the GDP are because they can
actually be held accountable to these
privacy violations that some things had
to change so the reason why it's been in
the news lately is that I can is
actually having to deal with this issue
they have some mechanisms now around
making a decision there's a temporary
policy in place that expires in May
which just says we're removing the
personally identifiable information from
who is and you can't get it now unless
you put in a special request putting in
a special request there's actually no
clear standard around how that's done so
you know if you're doing research one of
the big arguments even from the non
commercial users constituency was
academics like who is because they can
use it for research and so taking who is
completely away would be a problem for
them so so I guess if you're on that
level you could put in a special
requests you get all the Whois data for
what you're looking for including the
PII but yeah there's not they've the
policy they have does not actually
standardize the mechanism for how to do
that consistently again that expires in
May and hopefully by May there will be
an actual decision around what to do
with who is so that's still in process I
can so yeah I guess the yeah I've
already gone over the current state so
knavish I wanted to go back to ITU
because there's some really interesting
maybe a stronger world would be
terrifying
stuff that's being talked about at the
ITU can you give an example of what can
you talk about the example of digital
object architecture do a jerk
so DOA is an architecture that I mean
it's used as it calls itself a
distributed information storage location
and retrieval system and it's deployed
over the Internet and I think it's most
widespread implementation has really
been used in library systems it's been
floating around in other technical
communities and policy spaces within the
internet governance landscape for a
while
the IETF was talking about it a little
bit it keeps coming up in I can but do a
has taken the ITU by storm and it's
mostly recently come up in proposals for
IOT identifier systems particularly
within a study group 20 on Io teen smart
cities and you know this would be a
system where IOT devices information
would be ascribed and identifiers and
you know you would be able to use the
system to resolve that identifier into
the location of whatever is being
identified but there are two particular
problems with with DOA that we've seen
based on the current implementations
that it has the first is that the the
the actual identifier is managed by one
particular organization is called a Dona
Foundation and not only is this
organization but not only does it have
like sole responsibility and kind of
control over the identifier that's being
used in this kind of architectural
system or architectural framework but it
also determines the other organizations
that get to participate in the
distributed management of the identifier
registry so this one organization kind
of has all of the has all the cards in
this particular scheme and the other
kind of concern here is that the
identifier is really pitched as being
persistent and this kind of flies in the
face of the kind of privacy work that's
being done even at the
level and what and when Amelia is
talking about with Mack written with
Mack randomization and even in terms of
ipv6 and IP addressing but this is
really kind of champion does this like
static identifier that's just fixed for
for whatever is being identified and so
there are two kind of key problems from
a human rights perspective I mean first
is the transparency and accountability
problem of not being able to have an
open or or inclusive governance model
for this kind of identifier system
particularly when it comes to IOT which
you know has huge ramifications for for
privacy and then you know as a secondary
impact to freedom of expression but then
also kind of the the the potential for
surveillance in terms of location
tracking or even activity monitoring by
having a persistent unique identifier
kind of for all of our IOT devices and
even kind of the sub technologies
multiple sub technologies that make up a
single IOT device all of the sensors
that go into a single device and so that
that's quite problematic it's getting a
lot of traction in the ITU but you know
in the IETF it's already kind of been
debunked there's one kind of non
normative memo flying around kind of
like in isolation it was very clear that
it's not a standard within the IETF and
I can kind of the donut Foundation has
put together quite a lot of
presentations but to no real traction
and I think this is kind of this this do
a as an example really speaks to how
standards development exists as an
ecosystem right and I think that's
really what we're all getting at here is
that it's not about one particular
technical community or you know
intergovernmental forum or you know one
particular standard setting space it's
about the entire landscape and looking
at it as an environment where if you
have a very weak environment like the
ITU it has the reverberations because
problematic proposals that crop up in a
particular forum where you know the the
decision-making processes are strong
enough to kick it out on on technical
grounds or otherwise they will crop up
because forum shopping does happen in
this space and
you know the the proponents of those
proposals will take advantage of weaker
spaces where you have where you have
technical competency issues where you
know I think as amelia was saying you
know it's sometimes the inertia is
actually a good thing in my opinion it
definitely is because the more technical
competency you have in a in a space it
allows for a greater scrutiny and if you
don't have that competency then
standards just kind of there's no
friction and you know proposals just
kind of fly through and you can push
standards through fairly quickly the
transparency problem the accountability
problem right these are all these are
all big issues and everything I do
particularly as a diplomatic institution
it's different where if you have a bad
proposal on the table even if you're a
government actor that recognizes that
it's a bad proposal diplomacy kind of
ties your hands because in a
geopolitical space you don't really have
the capacity to say to another Member
States administration that your proposal
is really awful and we hate it and we're
gonna stop it completely that's just
there will be a diplomatic nightmare and
so bad proposals are just kind of linger
on in the idea do you always a great
example of that so if I can just break
in on that I think one of the things
that you said really resonated with me
which is that we need to look at these
things that as a landscape as well right
it isn't about a single proposal that
that is good or bad it's actually about
the way that these things interact
particularly when we're talking about
things like surveillance and privacy the
technical decisions and details that
need to be made need to be made across a
range of systems to make them work so
you know you talk about DOAs and
location net like location-based
identifier z' we're having these
discussions in the IETF as well and one
of the things that I've observed as I've
been looking at them is that you
actually have to if you really want to
be able to have anonymity or privacy you
need to make sure that the systems that
you're building are integrated across
the entire stack right you're we have an
anonymity profile for DHCP so that you
don't leak a persistent identifier to
the DHCP server that grants you network
configuration but if you use that
without randomizing the MAC address at
the I Triple E layer then it's you're
still linkable and then if you do those
two things
fully but then you're publishing a DOA
somewhere else then you've given
yourself another set of link ability or
link ability a right there so all of
these things actually need to be
coordinated together and being aware of
that big picture and how they interact
is really is really pretty critical we
regularly get proposals that try to
introduce some sort of link ability back
in I was just at the IETF in Montreal
yesterday where someone was proposing
trying to encourage people to log more
information when they do carrier-grade
NAT which is where you have a one
network address that you provide for you
know a thousand people and they want to
log the source port for outbound
connections from carrier-grade NAT to
facilitate law enforcement investigation
and people are getting clever about how
they present this they're like well
here's a really bad thing we could do we
could ask you to log all traffic period
you know the other endpoint of the
traffic the duration the net flow
information all of that so we don't
really want to do that because that has
privacy concerns but what we're
currently doing nobody seems to log the
source ports so then when you find out
that something's gone wrong you can't
trace it back to an individual and that
doesn't work either so let's find a
middle ground right that's the sort of
framing that people tend to come in with
the stuff and so so you know but once
you start logging that information and
other people are logging incoming port
information then you can fit back that
back together if you have access to the
centralized logs through something like
sisa like the the cybersecurity
information sharing act which works at a
totally political layer then you can
stitch those things back together to
form a surveillance network that you
wouldn't otherwise be able to build so
really thinking about it at all the
layers is important if we want to
advance these policies can I can i
intervene there so I think that that
particular logging proposal that you're
talking about it's not likely to make it
anywhere because at least hypothetically
it should be kind of illegal in the
European Union so there's some source
port logging would be illegal well just
data retention at the carrier grade not
level should be illegal after December
2016 although it depends a bit on how
much the European level is able to
impose itself on the member state level
but I was following that proposal
because it's it's such a challenge in
the
European Union right now to keep member
states so the kind of nation state level
in check would respect to the human
rights standards that are set by the
European Union level and a lot of member
nation states that are members of the EU
are rebelling against a really quite
high standards advanced from from
Brussels but so normally I would assume
that that this proposal wouldn't make it
anywhere at the eye at the effort at
this time well it's not making it
anywhere right now at the IHF which has
been nice the pushback within the ITF
has basically said if we're going to
promulgate any sort of expectations
about logging then the change can't just
be we encourage you to log source ports
it needs to look at the entire privacy
landscape and make a decision and if we
do that we may well get it proposals
that say don't log anything anonymize
your logs using the following
cryptographic and anonymization schemes
all that kind of stuff and I think the
folks who are pushing for source port
logging are like I don't know if I want
to open that door we're gonna get a
recommendation that goes against it so
there's a there's push push back there
for sure I think we should open it for
questions but I'm hoping that some of
the questions will be about DNS cuz that
was something that I really wanted you
to talk about Daniel on the panel unless
you want to make it I can do just a
quick example I can't tell if people are
at the microphone or not when people
start queuing up I'm happy to zip it but
the DNS the domain name system when you
make a domain name query so DNS and
information that's in the DNS is
considered public but when you make a
domain name query traditionally your
domain name query has gone out over the
wire in the clear so anyone who's
operating the network that your queries
go over can see what names you're
looking up typically DNS is used for
name names to IP addresses so that you
can make a connection there's other
things you can do with it too but that's
the that's the most common use case and
that's pretty much been in the clear
since we started the internet and the
result is that it's a privacy leak
because it leaks what people are looking
up in the same sense that the contents
of a library are all public but the
library patron records are not public
and we wouldn't want them to be because
it infringes on the right to read
privately we're trying now to protect
what people look up and we're doing this
in baby steps I have to say the
technology is not wonderful
technology but because we actually have
some mechanisms in place now to provide
cryptographic protection of the DNS it's
shifted a little bit of the outlook
within the rest of the IETF about oh
what we used to leak that information
all over the place but and we could
justify it because it was being leaked
in the DNS so we don't have to we'd have
to worry about the fact that we're
leaking it and say the TLS handshake
because it's already leaked in the DNS
and so you know no harm no foul it was
all it was a it was bad when we got here
but now that the DNS is starting to have
some potentials for privacy protections
and there's an ongoing push within the
IETF to try to minimize the amount of
metadata leaked to the network operators
themselves including name the names that
are being looked up and things like that
so that's like an exciting thing that's
happening at the IETF and I think it's
gonna cause some pretty serious changes
in the end of the structures of the
stuff you see on the wire if you're
capturing stuff on the wire but I see
someone at the mic there yeah I am hi
there hi so you talked about
forum-shopping
and I'm curious about to what extent do
the domains that you that these
organizations are creating standards for
over overlap and so to what extent does
the forum-shopping not work because
something is going to be shot down in a
stronger form so I mean there's a
there's sort of a turf that everybody
knows and I think that all the
organization's tread a little bit on
each other's turf I mean I know that
IETF is standardizing the protocols for
accessing who is like our DAP we're not
responsible for who is that's ICANN's
job but we're gonna try to standardize
how you talk to those forums and so of
course how we standardize that is gonna
affect what kinds of data could go into
who is so we so there's there's liaisons
between the different organizations when
the situation I described with the TLS
working group where the bankers came and
tried to break TLS one of the things
they explicitly said both in public
meetings and in private back-channel
meetings that I had with some of them
was was you know it'd be a shame if we
didn't get this through at the IETF
because IETF really has the good
technical rigor if we don't get it
through at the ITF we're gonna have to
take
Etsy which is a European standards body
and they're like if we take it to Etsy
then they might screw it up so don't you
want to standardize it here we had
Daniels write that there are actually
liaisons across almost all the
standard-setting body they're set up and
they're mostly public so you can know
who's participating in each form and I
can an ITF there's a special
relationship there mostly I mean part of
it is because their admin is run by I
sock both of them together but also
because I can't in that society
yeah sorry and that but but because yeah
because I can really is policy and they
do rely heavily on the IETF to actually
do the standards and the technical work
and then the liaisons the yeah those
that relationship is really strong
between those two for us yeah I think in
the the ITU kind of suffers from like a
superiority complex bred out of an
inferiority complex in this sense that
it is uh well I mean in some ways it is
intensely human right it's a very human
problem for the IT because it is just it
is just yearning for relevance it's just
it's just scrambling for it reaching out
for it wherever it can grab it and in
that desperation
it is it is gleefully engaging in
mandate expansion at every turn I think
a great example is a recent standards
proposal again in Institute 20 on IOT
which is an ipv6 addressing plan which I
think most people in the room are not
technically competent on I'm certainly
not an expert on this and most people in
that in that room would not understand
what was going on but Erin and ripe NCC
to regional internet registries were up
in arms over this particular addressing
plan and they had serious grievances
against it and it was just because they
happen to have two people in the room
just kind of monitoring for exactly this
kind of random kind of developments and
and they were and and they were
seriously concerned because the this
addressing plan had no understanding of
the nuances that go into
regional considerations the reasons why
we have this kind of decentralized
rir scheme in the first place it tried
to create a universal standard across
the entire world for an for a particular
kind of addressing plan and they were
like look if somebody sees this standard
and comes to us and asks us to to
implement this we it's not going to be
possible why would you want to come up
with an impossible standard to implement
and I don't think there is a good reason
that anyone in the ITU could give you
and I think it really just comes down to
this to this desire to to be relevant I
mean this is a this was an authoritative
body at one point for for telephony
numbering right and so it was really
important at some time but now with a
you know kind of increase in internet
use so over the last couple of decades
it's it's realizing that it needs to
continue to kind of creep into these
spaces in which the ITF is already
working or the I Triple E or 3gpp or
even at sea in order to kind of claim
that relevance back and so the I Triple
E has standing liaison committee with
the IETF because obviously so I
mentioned before that at the Mac levels
the kind of higher up than the physical
design of the chips but still fairly low
level technical stuff you have a lot of
protocols that need to be developed in
order to enable the features that are
envisioned by the I Triple E engineering
community so the IETF liaisons there are
very important for the I Triple E but
the ITU is also very important for the I
Triple E because there's one thing that
the ITU
does do and where they have real
regulatory significance in most regions
around the world in its spectrum
allocation if you want to send radio
communications anywhere in the world you
need to make sure that you're in a
frequency band that is government
approved because we have auction models
right and so for mobile for cellular
communications the way that works is
that big providers buy licenses for the
government to act in specific court
transmit and specific bands for 802 2.11
technologies they use unlicensed bands
and so itu-r which I know there
having their meeting just in like a
couple of years or something so they're
not yeah yeah they'll have their new
agenda setting meeting next year and so
the itu-r is super important to the I
Triple E they send their own delegations
there have lots of coordination meetings
and how do you approach the friend
different governments around the world
and how do you how do they structure
themselves internally in order to ensure
that whatever new spectrum plans are
being made at the ITU aren't going to
suddenly ban their technologies from
transmitting communications in a large
spot of the world for instance yes I
noticed you didn't really mention too
much about 3gpp even though that's
probably technically the most active
area because it's responsible for 4G 5g
and stuff like that I like to talk a
little bit about the issues there
especially because from my personal
experience it's heavily dominated by
industry and there's all the standards
and stuff like that they don't really
talk about these other issues and I know
that the cripton has been broken
ever since 3g and it's I know they've
found issues with LTE so yeah so if I if
I may on that the 3gpp has a different
member set up than most of the
organizations that were active in so at
the IETF you participate as an
individual member at the icon you can
also show up as an individual member in
your own right and at the I Triple E you
are an individual engineer participating
in their process at the 3gpp you sign up
as a company and then you have a
delegation for your company
there's also regulatory authorities that
participate in the 3gpp but the basic so
the basic difference between the IETF
the I Triple E and 3gpp is that the
customer base for 3gpp standards so the
people are going to buy the products
that are being standardized there there
are actually very few companies
basically telcos various IETF standards
they're used by all sorts of SMEs and
Geo's research groups that are kind of
implementing them on their own and the I
Triple E 802 dot 11 is the same that
there's a lot of companies that end up
deploying the technologies that are
being standardized there so it's a
a difficult political environment to be
in because you'd have to somehow out
voice this huge custom these huge actors
in the customer base that are otherwise
able to set really strong demands the
customer base in turn is dependent on
getting licenses to operate in many
parts of the world so regulate
regulatory authorities have really
strong leverage over the customers of
the standardized devices because they
can just say okay if you don't make this
feature requirement under standard then
maybe your license goes away and you're
no longer a commercial actor which no
company likes to be in the position that
they're suddenly illegal so but that
said I know in 5g they are trying to
make amends for some of them for some
from some legacy problems like I
understood maybe you were referring to
signal system 7 which has really been in
place since the 1970s and they're trying
to fix that and they're working really
hard on security and privacy issues so
my stronger concern the 3gpp is actually
that security is going to be taken
advantage of by the big they are very
big players on the base station market
like mobile network operators for them
to decrease the ability of mobile
virtual network operators to provide
services and then we might end up with
lower choice for consumers and that
would be kind of sad but we have ongoing
were kind of to monitor that from the
side because the actual forum is a bit
difficult to to delve into
thanks everyone
[Applause]