hello everyone there is something I'm
trying to do with this as well which is
a little different you'll notice at the
bottom there is both my Twitter handle
and a hashtag Co H DMV for people that
are watching online or people that might
be anxious about actually asking
question feel free to tweet me with that
hashtag and your question may follow up
this talk now a little bit about about
this talk first off this is gonna be
focusing on the US and Canada context
because of how these documents that were
gonna be talking we're gonna be focusing
on are treated in these countries very
few in most other countries there's
something of a national identity card
driver's licenses are not frequently
accepted as a form of valid
identification all the information that
you're seeing here is present but from
open sources I mentioned this because I
did spend seven years working for a
state driver services agency including a
couple years in their law enforcement
agency I worked as a civilian my main
job was keeping them honest
however just want to make that clear and
again like I said tweet me questions you
might get answers of course the first
thing is everyone here that has
experience in North America has gone to
a DMV we call DMV MVA drivers services
what have you pretty much in North
American society you need a credential
from one of these agencies be at an
actual driving license or a non driver
identification card so the first part of
the process of identity management if
you will is the actual front of the
house where you come up where you start
the process of getting the card issuance
today is a lot different than it used to
be in some places around the world they
still will issue on the spot pretty much
every jurisdiction in North America now
issues via what's called central
issuance meaning they mail you a
credential for some people that might
seem like okay that's been the case
forever but for in some jurisdictions
that is still relatively new currently
ID cards are highly influenced in the US
by the Real ID Act now there's a lot of
misconceptions about the Real ID Act is
the short version at least from my point
of view is it's a good idea except
that's implemented 180 degrees wrong
Amba is the entity that defines the
standards for these documents in the US
and Canada Amba is the American
Association of motor vehicle
administrators essentially it's the
industry group for DMVs they define
technical standards for things like
license plates driver's licenses title
documents and they do of course lobby
like every interest industry group does
the standard that is used for driver's
licenses is inspired by but not entirely
ISO compliant there is an iso standard
for licenses anybody that is from europe
will know for example that they are pink
that is the actual ISO color for driving
licences and finally at least in North
America there's only three companies
that actually issue these documents I
hate that this mic is hopping on me now
the front half staff that's people that
I'm referring to front of the house back
of the house which feels a little more
convenient for me but we're talking
about the people that you interact with
as a member of the public versus the
people that are in back offices doing
other work their job is to serve as a
first line of fraud detection when we
talk about fraud of course we're talking
about in this context we're talking
about imposters and counterfeit source
documents you're not likely to find a
lot of people coming in with counterfeit
driver's licenses or ID cards if you're
working there because generally speaking
a beautiful at work there they know what
they should look like applications
require verification of documents
presented we'll go into that in a moment
and the newest trend which is a Real ID
related development is that document
that the agencies will save scanned
copies of what is presented where do
they keep them they keep them in
databases that are internal to that
agency more about that in a moment
in the u.s. one of the main
verifications that you'll find is called
social security online verification or s
solve when you go to the DMV
pretty much every jurisdiction I've seen
requires either the actual social
security card
or a w-2 or 1099 form with that number
on there in some places to let you just
say it the in reality they could just
let you say it anywhere because this is
the this is considered the authoritative
way of verifying it this is an anvil
database I'm sorry is an and the system
that hooks into Social Security's
systems
when the clerk enters that information
on to their system they're entering the
actual social security number legal name
date of birth and gender gender right
now is not used as a marker for
verification though considering the
inclinations of this administration in
DC that could change when it works right
they just said it just says go ahead
gives it an error code of zero other
error codes that come up include things
like there's a no match on the name this
happens more frequent than you'd think
and not for malicious reasons primarily
we've got a lot of folks out there that
do change their names legally if they
don't tell Social Security about that
man change Social Security doesn't know
this throws an error things happen
date of birth may not match some people
have their dates of birth inverted so
for instance if you were born on five
six thirteen which one is it or is it
May sixth or is it the sixth or is it
the fifth of June sometimes there are
such errors that happen even in this
country in this host country and finally
is the SSN in the death file 75 million
Social Security numbers are there some
people might want to impersonate someone
who's passed on that's where these
systems come into play
additional verifications come into play
for for individuals that are
non-citizens the save system is a DHS
program it's been up for I believe a
decade now it is used almost every
agency will use it for non-residents
citizen non-citizens that have status
I'm using very specific language I know
so I'm talking about people that that
are in a status but are not residents
things like h1 workers or students or
their dependents Oh to 802 or the
dependents of outstanding individuals in
the US a two are certain diplomatic
staff yes these agencies do occasionally
issue credentials to people that are
have some kind of a diplomatic visa that
is not common usually ironically enough
the Department of State has its own DMV
that is what they call it to cover
licenses for diplomats and consuls
Canadian DMVs do a similar process for
individual for City for non-citizens and
for citizens that are born outside of
the country they verify dot the route
documents presented with appropriate
with the Citizenship and Immigration
Canada others other things that need to
be checked out are is your driving what
are you decent behind the wheel it's for
lack of a better way of putting it be
DPS problem driver pointer system it
lets agencies know if you've some
outstanding problem in another
jurisdiction some outstanding problem is
a very vague term and that is
deliberately so that could be anything
from you have a tendency to drink before
you drive and have twenty duis or it
could be that you forgot to pay a stop
sign ticket in in bumble blood I don't
know which one it is if I'm behind the
counter I won't know which one it is
unless you resolve it the idea being
that if you're not able to drive in one
jurisdiction then you will not be
allowed to drive in another of course
these source specific our concerning
driver's licenses ID cards obviously
don't have these checks see the CD list
commercial driver license information
system is a little more in-depth for
individuals that drive commercial
vehicles commercial drivers have a lot
of rules on them it is very easy for a
bad driver to slip a foul of those rules
they could be under suspensions there
are certain offenses for which they can
lose their ability to drive a CDL for
life as an example and I think everyone
here would agree this is probably a good
one if you are intoxicated and driving a
vehicle full of hazardous cargo you're
banned from driving a CDL for life I re
is the Canadian version into provincial
records exchange again that primarily is
to trade records between ten
in provinces but it does hook into the
u.s. system the u.s. system also hooks
into the Canadian system now in the
future there are two things that are
being worked on the first one is called
state to state this is to make sure that
individuals don't have want more than
one driver's license or ID in the
country
ideally they want to expand it so it
includes Canada the idea is to have
authority control over the driver record
they want to make sure that if you have
what happens with the state to state is
if you apply you have a driver's license
from somewhere else even if you don't
present it the person behind the counter
will be aware of that existence and then
basically give you the agony of choice
between getting the new license or
keeping the old one
finally electronic verification of vital
events is primarily concerned with birth
certificates issued in the US now this
is admittedly a pilot a pilot that
failed but they are still investigating
this because they want to be able to
verify all the route documents that are
presented something I didn't mention
here or what I mean by a route document
these are these are the papers that you
show that provide you with proof of
identity right does being in a way so
think of your birth certificate does it
have a photo of you does it have
fingerprints foot for DNA on there no
you present the birth certificate that
says your name is Chuck Jones generally
speaking they're gonna think that you
are Chuck Jones obviously this is a weak
point same with social security cards in
the United States you present so you
present Chuck Jones's Social Security
card in a situation like this there is a
tendency to think that you are tough
Jones still learning how to use this
properly so I apologize for the hiccups
in the talk now as I mentioned with
issuance that's the process of actually
turning that little piece of plastic
into something that will let you buy a
beer have just about every jurisdiction
use essential issuance to my knowledge
the last one that didn't was Delaware
because they have exactly one office
that issues driver's licenses which
means that functionally speaking it's
the same thing what that means also is
that it's sent by mail in an unmarked
envelope from a secure facility as I'll
say
however these secure facilities are run
by three companies in North America
the first one is ID Mia this company has
changed names twice since I've started
following this they used to be known as
Morpho trust saffron I believe is their
parent company it's a mess I know people
are gonna think Canadian make not wait a
minute money company well yeah they do
more than just currency they also
produce identity documents Canadian
driver's license is personal opinion are
slightly higher quality documents than
you typically find in from most USA
states and gemalto Gemalto again for
those of you who aren't aware of who
Gemalto is they're a major multinational
they are involved in credit card smart
cards identity documents you name it and
finally about the future of issuance now
this is actually an existing product as
of I think about three weeks ago it's
called la wallet this is Louisiana this
is to put your driver's license on your
phone this is a tendency that isn't
something that a lot of states are
looking into because people don't like
carrying wallets around this connects
real-time to the omv servers as they
call it in Louisiana so you would
produce this it would say when they last
Seraph ID that it was valid and this is
a mobile driver's license now some of
you might think why am i saying mobile
instead of digital not just because it's
a phone but because the term digital
driver's license at least within the
industry refers to the current types of
plastic cars we get because those are
digitally produced yes I know I didn't
name it I'm just letting you know what
it is now finally about securing the
credential back in the day I mean I'm
sure that some of you remember getting a
card that was a laminated piece of
Polaroid film I know that was my first
driver's license an ID card nowadays
let's start with the camera that you're
staring down when you get the image what
you don't see in that pillar is a 15 to
20 megapixel prosumer camera they want
to get a good image not just because
well they want to make sure everyone
knows how ugly you are when you get the
card
we're gonna go into that part of it in a
moment the substrates the actual card
material is distribution controlled
similar to how banknote paper is most
cars that you find in the US are based
on PE T or PFC usually a combination of
both of these materials that's why it
has that sort of feel to it now newer
cards like you'll find in New York wash
most Canadian provinces Virginia
Washington DC those are probably
carbonate based similar to some
passports have you have polycarbonate
info sheets the idea being that these
are nearly impossible as far as I've
been able to research to counterfeit you
just do not find a good fake Virginia
license anywhere there are multiple
layers of security I'm gonna go a little
bit I'm gonna gloss over the details of
this for because I'm going to talk a
little more in the next slide whenever
you look at these documents there's
three levels of security there's over
security things that you can see with a
naked eye so as an example of an overt
security feature that you'll see in the
New York driver's license which has the
clear window that you can see the same
image through that's an overt security
feature covert features are things that
are not immediately visible whenever you
see that bouncer flash that UV light on
to your document that UV is considered a
covert feature other covert features
include things like micro text
deliberate errors certain certain
features of Holograms and finally our
forensic features trying to find out
information on forensic features working
through an open-source context that's
hard to put it mildly
forensic features are used often by
programs that automatically determine if
the credential is valid sometimes it's
sometimes it's considered forensic
information to read the barcode on the
back of a driver's license particularly
since most of them have an encrypted
portion now with regard to these
features there's an excellent guide that
you can get the ice guide to document
security features because this was a
design for Immigration and Customs and
for
this does have a focus on passports
however the same features you'll find in
passports you'll find a lot of them in
identity documents too I do have a short
link here file dot IO yada yada
I am tweeting this after the talk so
that way you don't have to remember
which is a capital letter or not and
keep in mind that this is a work of the
United States government as such it is
free of copyright share and enjoy now
finally we're gonna talk about the fun
part what most of you are here for I
presume the stuff that happens you don't
see like I said I did work for the law
enforcement agency of this DMV for
several years this is one aspect of it
but we're gonna talk about what happens
after keep in mind that every driver
services agency is either itself a
branch of a law enforcement agency or
has a law enforcement arm examples Texas
Department of Public Safety is the
entity that issues a driver's license or
ID card in the state of Texas this is a
police agency ICBC Special
Investigations Unit is a section of the
Insurance Corporation of British
Columbia the driving and the driver and
vehicle license licensing agency in
British Columbia not everyone there is a
cop not everyone works for the cops but
these people do they specifically look
for certain things now regarding IDs I'm
going to focus obviously on that the
first one is investigating post issuance
fraud investigating counterfeits
identification of investigatory subjects
so we're gonna start with the fraud desk
every agency has a fraud desk now as I'm
sure that this is gonna be shocking
considering the reputation of a lot of
driver services people not all of this
fraud is caught and when they go to the
office okay yes for those of you who are
familiar with the Simpsons there are
still a lot of Patties and Selma's
they're pro tip the younger the person
is the less likely they are to be that
way now how do they investigate these
claims the first one is they get reports
from law enforcement they get reports
from they get also documents have been
returned to them in the US for example
under the Real ID standards into
has to present documents verifying
address if something gets kicked back
that should be going to a legit address
there's an ink that automatically
insinuates there is something wrong
now over the counter that's what OTC is
back in the day when you just go into
the office and walk out with a card once
those cards were issued and out in the
field there's not much that could be
done with it this of course is a problem
when you're trying to ensure that that
document is trusted everyone here at
some point has had to trust that that
piece of plat assuming that again
assuming in North American context it
had to trust that that piece of plastic
accurately represented who that person
was at least in a legal context once
it's in the wild and it's got someone
else's face on it that's it there's not
much that can be done if you're lucky as
the agency they might come back for
another service and you might discover
it then that doesn't happen that often I
have experienced that finally without
with current issues with the central
issuance every application has facial
recognition run on it not for the reason
you might think though so we're gonna
talk about the la policia of course most
frequently what they do is they respond
to information requests from other
agencies whether we're talking about you
know podunk or we're talking about
California it could be any age any law
enforcement agency could be asking them
I mean there have been cases where I've
personally had to respond to different
federal agencies and to military police
to provide them with information of for
example the status of the document or if
there is something that they received
back in an automated return which they
don't understand because there are times
where a record will go to somebody some
authorized receiver it'll say contact
contact agency police because there's
it's a weird situation now again the
vast majority of the time as I sort of
implied there these responses are sent
automatically agency a goes on to a
secured law enforcement agents to the
secure law enforcement net
work sends a request to the DMV's police
agency they get a response
examples of these networks are things
like nice spin New York State Police
information network see let's is the
California law enforcement I keep
forgetting the T in that one leads is
the law enforcement and acquisition data
system I keep forgetting some of these
acronyms it's annoying
every state has its own network they all
hooked in two in the US each state has
its own system each state has a
different name for it they all hook into
the FBI's master network which is known
as n let's Canada a little different
keep in mind in Canada you basically
they have one large police agency that
covers the whole country which is the
RCMP different cities and towns have
outpost of RCMP acting under contract or
their own police departments they all
communicate pretty easily that way now
of course let's talk about this your
threat model because obviously as soon
as I say facial recognition a lot of
people's heads should start to spin of
course like I said it's pretty simple
yes they do facial recognition okay and
this is the sort of thing that people
are worried about in let's be real here
no this is not what it looks like in the
real world at least from the DMV point
of view now as soon as you take a photo
that's enrolled in their database
everyone here should know all about
enrolling facial recognition feet for
facial recognition you dump pictures
into a database system figures it out
now in some jurisdictions you take the
photo before you do anything else in
that case even if you decide after that
photo is taken to walk out that photo
will still be enrolled even if it
doesn't have necessarily identifier
associated with it modern ID photos for
driver's licenses and ID cards are in
spite are very much iCal standards are
the same standards that you'll find for
your passport to put it in three
sentences flat front of the face neutral
expression ideally without glasses
now keep in mind that because this is
the standard there's only one image
that's being used or if you have a
history with them several images but
they're all gonna be similar images
facial recognition is not very good when
it comes to using small sample sets okay
keep in mind States with cheap
contractors are pricey good fr is
relatively expensive so there are limits
to this system that make them a little
less scary the first one is the front
view of the face even a side view like
this is not going to be very easy at all
possible for those systems to match now
and I these are the ideal use cases for
this system though because there are
some the first one is comparing
databases between jurisdictions looking
up mug shots and of course passport and
immigration credential comparison why
same standard for photo now what this
what now this is what DM VFR really
sucks at okay basically everything else
so you look at these surveillance type
images not a chance
cell phone footage unless you're lucky
enough to get a front out of the face
probably not mass footage think of the
think of some of the private sector
samples where they've scanned sports a
sports ball arena what would happen
well resolution I mean I'm looking at
this picture here and seeing this I'm
like I've seen pictures that are this
quality and slightly better that haven't
been able to get through the Fr at our
agency and finally of course fishing
expeditions no fishing expedition I know
that this person looks kind of like this
that will not go for both the simple
reason that you without an image to
compare even a good image even a bad
sketch won't work on these systems and
finally of course there are laws against
this yes I know
police laws insert joke here so this is
a case study of the former for example
in New York in New Jersey they did have
a cross database across analysis between
their systems literally thousands of
people were discovered to have multiple
active driver's licenses
obviously for this driver's licenses
were the primary focus but again they
also did checks
ID cards as well now these are a couple
of the cases of people they found that
we're using fake credentials the first
one being rather impressive a sanitation
worker impersonating their dead twin
brother to get half a million of
disability benefits over 20 years in New
York another one a fugitive that was on
the lam for 17 years was discovered
because they had multiple driver's
licenses
none of them had their actual identity
but they had they had one picture they
saw that these this thing came up
multiple times and they're like two plus
three came together in New Jersey there
was a man that used fraudulent IDs to
get commercial driver's licenses I
mentioned an example of this before this
dude had six duis and 64 license
suspensions and keep in mind I don't I
mean even in cases where you've got
someone patrolling you you do not find
people with 64 license suspensions okay
usually around number twenty three or
four or so most people get out from
behind the car in New York there were
twelve thousand five hundred cases found
but of these twelve thousand five
hundred cases only about three thousand
were prosecuted sometimes due to statute
of limitations reasons sometimes because
they found that they that the error was
on the clerk side in New Jersey they had
about two thousand cases that came up
only a thousand were prosecuted so again
this is probably this is to my knowledge
the only cross state database that
database run that has been performed
this will probably become more frequent
in the future as the cost of data and
processing power decreases now who
actually has the ability to search well
the cheap answer is it depends on the
jurisdiction or I worked there were
exactly eleven people that were allowed
to perform a facial recognition run over
those eleven five of them never did it
and I got tasked with most of the rest
obviously we don't do it capriciously we
have to receive a an authorized request
from a law enforcement agency each state
has different rules and guidelines on
this I happen to be in a state that was
very
serve it up in this regarding the only
reasons that you could run a check would
be to identify a body to identify a
missing person or if it's in connection
with a crime which they have to spell
out they can't say we think this person
did something most of these systems are
functionally air-gapped I say
functionally because you're not
completely isolated systems but these
are systems with extremely limited
access now in some states you even
require a court order example Washington
state requires a court order or a
warrant in order to be able to perform
such a run now some states on the other
hand there are a lot more liberal in
this regard and it's not exactly the
states that come up with that term for
example Kansas allows law enforcement
agencies to perform these searches with
frequency generally speaking in the
research I've been able to perform it
tracks across the red blue line blue
states tend to be more protective of
individuals information red states are
more willing to share and some work
directly with federal agencies now what
do I mean by directly now again I worked
I regularly had inquiries from federal
agents
protip working the police is probably
the best thing I could have ever done to
learn how to social engineer someone
because being able to talk with people
and actually have something resembling
authority is hard dealing with feds
harder some of them just want everything
now now now
and you've got to tell them sorry can't
help you which is about the most
rewarding thing to ever do is to tell a
Fed you know but some of them don't even
bother with it they just send it and
they'll just process it right away
again like I said this tends to track
the red blue state divided and now let's
talk about this why am i concerned about
knowing your threat model where is the
real threats for facial recognition are
these are these agencies really the
threat they're not really look at the
private sector and look at what they're
capable of doing right now for instance
Amazon has been rolling out this
recognition system
and they've been pushing it to law
enforcement agencies they enroll mug
their mug shots which mug shots Republic
Records folks try not to get one
Facebook is probably the world's most
effective image enrollment system
they're deep face software is capable
identifying faces even obscured and
partial faces at 97% accuracy Google
same thing whenever you upload their
face that software just works a standard
date a standard test batch of faces
their accuracy is ninety nine point six
percent that is more accurate than a
human for reference ninety seven point
five percent is the standard for human
facial recognition
Microsoft has its face API and these are
just the big players of course there are
tons of other companies out there that
will work on for this again private
sector facial recognition all the little
brothers are much more advanced than
what you find in the public sector so
I'm gonna open the floor for questions
first off if you're here queue at the
mic if not send me a tweet I'm gonna be
monitoring it on this and I thank you
for your time in advance
yeah question how did you and how do
other DMVs authenticate requests for
information whether it's personal
information or facial recognition from
law enforcement agencies and quarters
the vast majority of requests either are
entirely through or are started via
secure law enforcement networks such as
what I mentioned nice pin see--let's
leads you name it either they will send
the information directly through that
network which again it each state
network is connected to the FBI network
FBI actually sets the standards for
these networks and determine and the
State Police of each state determines
who has access to it it's pretty it's
pretty reliable as such now sometimes
places used to issue the address they
would call let's say I let's say
somebody was to call me up and say hi
I'm officer Davis from the blah-blah
Police Department and here's the address
on the network that used to be a lot
more common but the technical term for
that address is known as an Ori those
who are I lists are available
consequently more agencies are not
trusting them could you comment on the
commercialization of DMV data meaning
are the DMV selling data to the
marketing agencies and is is there a way
to opt out of that or anything that we
should be concerned with thank you
I'll start with the second part of that
question about opting out to my
knowledge it is not possible to opt out
of it however it's not just it's not
used for marketing in most cases usually
an entity that wants to access DMV data
like that has to have a business case
for it what do I mean something like an
insurance company has a business case
for it someone trying to sell you three
pairs of socks on the Internet does not
now what defines a business case will
vary from state to state again from what
I've been able to find it does follow
that red blue line
hi I live in Vermont and in the past two
years we had a little bit of a scandal
where folks who worked at the DMV did I
lose the mic yes so folks who worked at
the DMV would sort of casually
collaborate with ice and they'd sort of
sent an email and say hey Steve and ice
we have a you know an undocumented
immigrant coming in tomorrow for a
driver's test and ice would come down
and pick the person up so my question is
how common is that sort of thing in
other states or any kind of other
similar collaboration there's a reason
this is considered a scandal and that is
because pretty much every jurisdiction
that in the u.s. that issues driving
credential for individuals without
status has either official policies or
unofficial statements to the effect that
they do not disclose immigration status
either directly or indirectly to federal
authorities the state I worked in did
have did and does have a policy of does
have a program for issuing licenses to
individuals without status when this
program as I said I kept this I kept my
agency honest one of the markers that I
discovered was that in some of the
information that would otherwise be
lawful to release it identified whether
the individual had status or not and
because of what I did I ensured that as
a pollen though it wasn't an official
policy this was something that the
people in charge of the agency had been
promoting publicly our law I mean
literally I had to get pushed up
basically to all the lawyers who said
you know maybe it's not exactly the law
but this is what we've said publicly so
that information does need to be
redacted thank you
so loophole idea you don't need a
driver's license to ride a bicycle but
the NYPD has been cracking down on
cyclists and if you get stopped safe or
like running a red light you could
actually get points on your driver's
license
New York however also offers a
non-driver ID and so you could give them
and then there's no license to get
points on so would having a New York
state non-driver ID and then a
simultaneous driver's license from
another state raise any flags or is that
like just a terrible idea yeah that's a
terrible idea
I'll tell you why in a few in a few
different ways the first one is that
when you apply for a New York State non
driver identification card at least to
my knowledge of the process they do in
fact check to ensure that you don't have
a valid driving credential anywhere else
in the country so you go there you want
to get that ID card and they see that
you've got a license from Hawaii
well that might cause problems the
second aspect of this is that under the
under the wrote under the road rules
basically whatever laws are in effect
for that state or country for the road
the bicycle is considered a vehicle not
necessarily a motor vehicle but
obviously a vehicle and vehicles have to
follow the rules of the road so yes as a
biker you're supposed to stop at stop
signs and stoplights I know most of us
don't okay but yes they I know that in
particular New York City is particularly
aggressive about it about enforcing on
bikers and frankly as a honestly I think
that's not a bad thing and the reason
why is because at least with regards to
like running red lights for example I
don't like seeing bike bicyclists
getting splattered personal preference
but what happens is that a driver file
is created for you if you don't already
have a driver's license they just use
the information that they're able to
obtain from usually the citation and
they create a dummy file and if that
dummy file shows that there's nothing
resolved and you go to another state
let's say you go to someplace where you
need a car like you know Colorado they
will do a pdps search and they'll say
you've got a problem in New York I've
never had a license in New York well
they say you got some issue
hi there thanks for speaking curious on
your opinion about to potential
cross-sections based on your experiences
one is DHS fusion centers and the other
is a witness protection program address
confidentiality program members are
there any protections for them with
regard to facial recognition or
surveillance databases I do not have
direct knowledge a direct experience I
should say of fusion centers I never
interacted with a DHS fusion center I
did work with one or two County fusion
centers that were not explicitly DHS but
in those cases it was just usually a
request for information not a request to
do
for example facial recognition for
instance clarification on like vehicle
ownership or something that does happen
as far as I apologize I forgot the
second part of the question
witness protection every state has if
you will certain I mean has
considerations for certain protected
classes of persons now witness
protection does not fall into this and
the reason why is that witness
protections of federal program witness
protection people will usually have a
contact with a every state has what's
known as a confidential Bisons desk it's
not for confidential for you to have
it's not like protecting you saying that
like yes I have a secret driver's
license no it's more like when law
enforcement needs credentials for
various purposes be it something like
witness protection or for undercover
investigations individuals that have
other privacy concerns or other
limitations on their ability to obtain a
credential cases like this include
judges in most states it includes first
responders domestic violence victims
parolees homeless there's usually a
procedure for them to get a credential
that doesn't show a home address as an
example again this is a hypothetical
example let's say that effect let's say
that a federal judge needs to get their
driver's license renewed
when they go they probably will have the
court
address on their license or a cop will
have their precinct house a homeless
person or a domestic violence victim may
have the address of a shelter that's a
really good point it brings in another
aspect you mentioned towards the end
that the Amazons and the googles have a
much better capabilities things like
Lincoln why see that it's not just
linking faces in real-time but also can
link up your phone your address and
where you live because of your work
patterns and all these kinds of things
what makes us think that this whether
local or state actors aren't actually
just kind of giving up the ghost and
gonna be using these sources of
corporate surveillance systems you know
that are multifaceted and just gonna
stop kind of doing the direct oh I'm an
NYPD surveillance camera and like you
know how are we gonna follow this in the
u.s. it is a lot easier and it is a lot
easier for law enforcement to get your
information from private parties than
from other parts of the government this
sounds weird but it's true there is the
doctrine the third-party doctrine which
with the exception only recently
established of cellphone count of
cellphone ping data if the third party
has your information they can do
whatever they want with it they can sell
it to law enforcement agencies a lot of
law enforcement agencies have have
contracts with for example LexisNexis or
other or other data brokers they have
that as an easier approach than going to
a DMV and trying to get that information
oftentimes it's more effective
conversely to my knowledge the DMV's
with very rare exception do not do that
same sort of information checking
hi so the DMV has Motor Vehicles in it
and I was wondering kind of the
intersection of Motor Vehicles regards
to like a LP ours EZ Pass anything
involving photos of a notification or
potentially your faces what's the
intersection of that regards to I don't
know I understand what you mean concerns
about the actual the vehicle side of the
DMV and license plates in other and
tracking connected with that total
agencies are separate from the DMV most
of the entities that use a LPR to my
knowledge receptor from the DMV I have
yet to see a DMV that has an a LPR
camera at its parking lot they can
request the information again it has to
be an authorized business purpose if
they fight but usually like with say a
toll tag they have to be able to
document that you've been skipping tolls
they can't just pull it up because you
seem to be going slightly too fast for
what physics dictate as possible ALPR
companies they have to be able to show
that in some states they just sell the
data to bulk brokers again for a
legitimate business case which again is
I didn't find vehicles but again
primarily it's going to be cases where
it's to resolve some kind of outstanding
criminal or civil issue that is
justified in law the DMV itself doesn't
have like a dog in the fight so much
high Aphrodite my first question was
just is this your first talk this is my
first talk
[Music]
[Applause]
after OGG has been hanging out at hope
since like God died a trillion years ago
and I don't know why that came to it but
she started on in the security team and
it's been totally around the edges being
like but I know this stuff about the DMV
I know this stuff about the DMV and only
just now is like brought this all of us
I just wanted to thank you because like
this is my favorite kind of hope talk
where it's like here's the system and
all of how it works because I know it
and I'm going to share it with you
fantastic talk
I may have derped out I missed I men may
have missed the answer to my question
but my question is just aside from first
talk you said there's like a single
image and it's just single image in the
DMV files right and that's that flatland
is that are we assuming that that's the
only image also in the deeper fed
systems or stuff like that or do we
assume that they have other stuff that
sort of comes into it there what the
feds do it's a loop that's a little bit
beyond my knowledge base except in the
except that typically Maciel the FBI's
database that they use in rolls mug
shots as opposed to driver's license
photos because a mug shot includes a
side profile it can do slightly better
identification but pretty much if you if
you remember whatever cards you have no
driver's license or IDs what do they all
look like that unless you've got a
really goofy face that you put in one
back in the day it's gonna be a flat
front shot of the face or if you've got
the one guy like I went and one of the
DMV guys looked at me like I'm gonna
take a bad picture of you one time so is
it likely that they'll also be able to
cross-check against your passport photo
how likely is that but that'll be able
to me at this point I'm not likely with
the exception of individual of typically
non-citizens that are applying if they
have to refer to a visa or something
they have to do we have to check that
image and if it's looks hinky there
could be problems I do have a question
that came on from Twitter the question
is from the question is how accurate do
you consider the data particularly home
address slash geolocation in state data
keep in mind it's all self-reported and
at least in the u.s. context it requires
documentation to prove it what
documentation is accepted varies from
state to state but usually it's
something that has Attlee
a veneer of a fish of official status so
how accurate is it it's as accurate as
the information that's presented now
there are people of course that try to
do things that are better that are
outside of the law let's just say things
like having things go to private post
boxes for example is one of the most
common but again that often
once that's discovered we'll just get
get the fraud people and/or the law
enforcement arm involved right away so I
do want to thank thank you for the
question online next please I've got
about four minutes okay I wanted to
thank you for great talk and I wanted to
ask some cities such as San Francisco
New York have their own ID card system
that kind of interacts and I wanted to
know from the like database perspective
or from an information sharing
perspective how that interacts with the
existing EMV systems from what I've been
able to research in states which have
cities that issue these kinds of
credentials those documents are not
accepted in any way shape or form at the
DMV whether we're talking about an
individual who has status who is a
citizen or who has neither so as far as
I'm aware there is no real intersection
between them now what the states do with
those now what the cities do with those
databases of images I can't say it is
reasonable to assume that facial
recognition is run on those images
however that is an assumption not
something I can find hard information
for you mentioned it's a bad idea to
maintain multiple driver's licenses
could you explain why and there's a
second part when you say you move states
you go to a new state you say I want to
apply for a driver's license there is
often an option that if you have a an
active license in another state you can
present that and skip the whole process
right assuming you approved residency in
that new state at that point what
happens to your old license do they call
up the DMV and say please invalidate
this or what happens so the first part
why it's bad idea and multiple licenses
well the first reason I mean these are
reasons in law and the reason is that
you cannot have what's if you're in in
some states it's more in some
jurisdictions I should say it's a much
more enveloping prohibition for in most
states in the u.s. it is against the law
to have a driver's license from that
state and a driver's and an active
driver's license from another state so
if I did have say a Washington driver's
license and a New York driver's license
if I ever I mean and let's say that I'm
driving through Oklahoma something
happens they look at my wallet and they
see that I have both Oklahoma could
arrest me additional I mean that's a
basic concept is called one driver one
record the idea being that it's to make
sure that if there are outstanding
issues there's like a single
authoritative source to get that
information in some places you can't
even have a license from another country
this is typical in Canada New York has
this as a guideline as well so you are
required to surrender licenses and
typically that surrendering of the
license is taken as proof of driving
experience at least from countries that
they recognize what happens with those
surrendered credentials now some places
will just punch holes through it and and
kick it back to you a lot of places
nowadays though are retaining it they do
eat they notify the original
jurisdiction electronically and or
return it if they do return if they
don't return it they typically will
destroy the original credential and I do
apologize that there are more questions
we can talk outside about this we are at
time and I want to thank you all for
coming and I hope you all enjoy