so good afternoon everyone can you hear
me fine
yeah sure so my name is Jeremy Moto's
I'm French but I would do this talk in
English because it was announced in
English sorry for people who wanted
French so I used to be a developer and
about 10 years ago I started doing like
100% upset I used to have my own company
so if you search on Google centering
gaps you find several talks about it and
I join in gitlab six months ago so I was
really happy to do so I'm also coach
chapter leader at Ava's Geneva and I
used to organize a security conference
in Switzerland so we are going to talk
about management of we have front-end
dependencies so basically in your web
application when you include third-party
Java scripts from what I've seen in many
organizations when they care about
application security which is not that
often for them application security is
really you have to do stuff on the
backhand side because well you know
input validation is because of that you
get XSS and all this kind of stuff well
so fix is you have to do something well
server-side when you have permission
issues well you have to fix it
server-side because otherwise people can
cheats when you have SQL injection
issues well you have to fix it
server-side because you have to do
people statements so that's for let's
say the fixing part as a security
analyst also I admit personally you know
when you have to review thousands of
lines of code you tend to ignore
everything has happened in a front-end
layer everything that's why could you
say well that may be the dirty thing
there but do you really care because
what's important is what is done in the
backend because if everything has been
implemented in the backend correctly
also checks we should be fine and I
think that's
get this impression that ya are only
back in security matters because yeah
it's well she'll never trust what
happens and what comes from the client
because everything can be manipulated so
people really tend to believe that
everything should be addressed on the
back end but but it's wrong because
browsers have implemented a really
complex but strong web security model so
you cannot do anything from let's say
your website
err you cannot do whatever you want and
a browser as many controls and on top of
that now so if you are building a web
application and you want some nice UI
you have to include third-party
dependencies so you need JavaScript
libraries you need JavaScript frameworks
and you also need content delivery
networks to cache source JavaScript so
that the first time the user comes it
doesn't take edges to load like maybe
five megabytes of JavaScript so for me
what it mean it means that front-end
security is getting a bigger and bigger
concern and we tend to forget it
and which we will see why with two
thousand cases what can go wrong if you
don't really care about it and sometimes
I have question I say minima my
organization yeah this cannot happen
because we have a full stack that we
have full stack developer of who stuck
to me no it doesn't mean that you know
front-end security doesn't mean that you
do everything doesn't mean that you do
everything well so still reply for you
if you are full stack developer so now
let's discuss with ya - real packing
cases Ticketmaster and British Airways
and see what went wrong and I would
could have been improved because many
time in security conference especially
when you're when there is a CTF you have
billion people that are able to break
stuff to AK into it but as an engineer
the former developer for me
inyoung you get like a pessimistic
feeling at the end of those conference
because you know well basically everyone
can break everything and then what do we
do with that how do we fix it so we will
see some solutions so I don't claim
after that you will be able to fix
everything but at least have have some
knowledge of how you can improve it and
improve it efficiently at the end we
have a Q&A session and I'd be happy to
discuss openly with you or how you
manage it and maybe you have good ideas
to share so something that form is
really missing in the security industry
is really sharing your best practices
concerning application security there is
not really a good book on what you
should do
you just have many many talks I say one
what you should not do so let's discuss
again and see if we can share best
practices around it so first guess
ticketmaster last cure we had to
disclose in June that credit card data
of around 40,000 users had been nixed
mostly UK customers and it was not clear
in the communication and maybe because
what not hear from them if the leaks
happening you know it had started in
February so they did a forensic study
and conclusions were really interesting
because Ticketmaster database was not
stolen
in fact Ticketmaster was not react
directly and the payment processor was
not act so they had credit card data in
the while but not coming from the
database not coming from the payment
processor but the confusion is that yeah
it's been stolen by JavaScript that was
ousted by a third party so what's really
interesting there is that world
Ticketmaster of course they have to
handle credit card data so they have
there are PCI DSS compliant so as a show
and they do we have to do good security
to achieve this certification but what
we will see is totally out of cope of
this certification
because it's something that the
regulators have not thought about so
let's see more details so so there's a
third party in the loop the third party
is called inventor I'm not blaming them
so it's it's a Spanish company they are
doing AI stuff for marketing and what he
did they made a custom JavaScript
specifically for Ticketmaster because
they wanted to not know yet whatever
marketing data for Ticketmaster and
Ticketmaster believe that this company
could provide them useful insight and
Indian what happened is that this
JavaScript tailor-made for Ticketmaster
but not returned by Ticketmaster was
directly hosted I have not only be
included in Ticketmaster payment page
the Aventa did not knew about it so
somehow they say and when you look at
all the responses and all that and as I
say bent I said yeah you know somehow we
deliver the JavaScript to you but it was
some kind of pop of course you should
never have put it in production and even
less in the payment page otherwise we
would have told you you shouldn't have
done that so that was really yeah let's
say the responsibilities were blurry but
what's really interesting is in detail
the attack so there is a magic card
backing group now they have dozens of
cases documented on them but this one
the two I'm sure I'm showing to you is
singly easiest one and the most
impactful so what they did in fact end
of 2016 so one year and a half ago the
bridge to inventor which is some kind of
startup doing AI and for marketing and
all that so I guess there are
differences are clearly not to the level
of Ticketmaster so they bridge them and
what they did so basically they just
to the server and then at some point
when they saw that Ticketmaster was
using was including this JavaScript
Interop I'm on page one does he decide
to edit the script and to add just few
JavaScript line that is doing what shows
when you type the credit card number it
takes it and it's ended three attacks to
some web domain call web thoughts that
Miss or some kind of wrong web demand so
it's just basically it's a keylogger
they added a keylogger functionality in
his third-party JavaScript and they
didn't try to Aidid while on earth so if
you're really interested in that or we
will shadow side of course and you have
the detail analysis but by risk IQ ear
but again it's so simple you just need
to copy past a few lines of code in a
Java Script and then that's it so you
have a provider of service that is PCI
DSS certified but all the data is leaked
and then people told me yeah but how
come
Ticketmaster couldn't detect it don't
they have the italic prevention
don't they have IDs and all that well
nothing is reaching Ticketmaster servers
nothing happened Ticketmaster cannot see
anything because it's just happening in
the brothers of the users so as soon as
you're typing something in your browser
an extra request goes to e Banta and
then well know directly benta but
because of a bantha it goes directly to
the ackers
so Ticketmaster cannot see anything
about it so before going further I'd
just like to make a talk about the same
origin policy because it's something
that not so clear out the brother should
protect from such attacks so so the
basic so when you design a web page you
can include static resources from any
other domain so you are ticketmaster.com
you can include a JavaScript from
google.com teacher whatever is going to
work because by design you can include
external with
this was supposed to be called static so
this is for the loading and then they
somehow for the execution of the
JavaScript code so the there goes the
same origin policy where it says that so
Java scripts that has been loaded I can
only access to the page content only if
it has been loaded from the same origin
so basically it means that if you are
ticketmaster.com e from ticketmaster.com
you say yeah include something from
google.com then this script from
google.com is going to be able to see
all the page content but now let's say
you are evil calm and you try to somehow
read the page of ticketmaster.com you
will not be able to do it because the
browser will say 1:00 or sorry evil.com
has not been loaded from
ticketmaster.com so I don't give the
permission to read it and just a remark
this you cannot steal cookies if they
are protected by the HTTP only errors
which means that even if we are in the
context of the same origin policy this
clip from google.com will never be able
to read the cookies ticketmaster.com
so now solutions it's something that in
fact rather a comment for payment page
or for some pages where you have really
sensitive information well first thing
is well don't use any third-party
JavaScript for your payment pages so
that's why you can get you know like
really ugly payment page where you enter
your credit card data like I don't want
to mention the one of eBay or whatever
but they don't look good especially on
mobile it's because of that so in fact
they have maybe a nice UI in the website
but then you get rid of eighty-two
payment page and his payment page is
mostly static and I don't have any like
fancy UI and all that so that's why yeah
some people ask me yeah you know well
you told me about some origin policy but
how can people then because of it oh you
cannot filtrate data because you are not
supposed to be able to do anything ever
to actually trade data in fact as long
as your javascript is about you run
that's super easy because you just have
for example to request a picture from
whatever URL so for example malicious
come slash image one and then you the
server that you control that's under
malicious gum will not have a picture on
the list URL but in the log you will be
able to find some data and whatever so
that's easy so well first solution is
well I have ugly payment pages and then
maybe you can survive with it second
option would be to use an iframe with
the sandbox attributes so with it in
fact you let's say your sensitive
content you put it in an iframe and this
iframe you give sandbox instruction that
say well from this iframe you can the
JavaScript cannot do anything that
javascript cannot free that or whatever
so it allows you to have let's say
full-page ads somehow not too ugly and
just the payment fields that are
protected another solution could be to
use a sub resource integrity called a
server from the values we see so what he
does is in fact the first time so you're
developing so you say yeah I want to
include this script and you compute a
hash of the script and then you store
the hash in your web page and then when
the browser loads the external
javascript it will compare it and if it
does not match it will say well I won't
load it so for example for Ticketmaster
it would have worked because they would
have computed the hash of the inventor
script at the beginning and then when
when magical changes it well the border
we don't have loaded it and then nothing
would have happened but it's a bit heavy
we will discuss after on the operational
challenges
gee I talk too little so you can still
use JavaScript but yeah really cheap
pages as simple as possible so for me
it's a bit like a nonsense to try to do
AI on the payment page because yeah what
do you want to do with it really if you
want to match statistic on the
expiration date so whatever so I don't
see it so personally I don't know why it
has been - yeah maybe the only valid
reason is was he included it in every
page and then it arrived there otherwise
yeah doesn't really make sense and last
but not least there is something strong
now called content security policy which
is some kind of much better sandboxing
than iframe we will discuss later with
the second example of what can go wrong
and how to protect from it so the first
case was Ticketmaster and somehow well a
third party was leaked and because of
that all these credit card data was
stolen few months after Letitia was that
something that looked similar ten times
more user but he has three months after
and and it was this time it was personal
information and credit card data and
stolen from the website and also the web
application again the forensic study
concluded that while British Airways
database was not leaked and that he was
not an issue with their payment
processor at this time it was a
JavaScript hosted directly by British
Airways so moderniser which is some gang
of uui javascript library so they don't
know did it the footage in the server so
somehow it should be in better control
because yeah they are not flooding it
from a third-party domain but what did
the magic out I did well they hacked the
British Airways web server on August
21st so they know it now because it's
happening in their infrastructure so
British iOS can do better what's
happening
and again they added this kind of sin
line so they are did the editor couch
screaming a schemer or feature directly
in this library of course I guess if I
ask you a question when you include
JavaScript library that are thousands of
Dania do you read them before including
them no of course no so it's why they
did so so so that this one this one is
really nasty so so they enter the web
server and they just say yeah let's
let's just change the UI and and let's
just change the source code of a
third-party library and we found nobody
is going to have a look at it and then
what happened well Indian it's exactly
the same impacts at for Ticketmaster as
soon as someone times personal
information or credit card data then
they send they steal his data directly
from the browser and the son it to
effect domain which again is Vietnamese
like interesting which he be a double VA
West come so it really looks like it's
the domain from British Airways so even
if you are paranoid and you use no
script extension and no and that you see
yeah be a waste come here should be
British Airways so I would authorize it
so it's kind of well done so did the
detailed report is really interesting to
know oh yeah
I will try to stay undercover for a long
time and another question yeah but what
happened about the mobile app still
something totally different because
you're not supposed to have JavaScript
and it's supposed to be an app right
because you don't know the app from the
Play Store or from a u.s. marketplace
well in fact they had a good idea or
because I wanted to save on development
cost all the pages that were ending
personal data a credit card data and all
that in fact they were using a webview
so they were reusing all the pages from
the web server that was leaked and I
don't even know if magical knew it when
the little trick but yeah so in the end
all the cost
were impacted because of that so what
can we do with that and now it's really
becoming a tough question because of
course yeah when we say don't also party
javis people well now we own the same
domain so well somehow they have their
web server hacked so should feel like
it's game over
but wewe still may find some solution
well of course if they well as I try to
use iframes and boxing right it's
useless because if they can edit our
JavaScript they can also go to the web
page and say yeah Edie's sandbox
attribute sub resource integrity same
stuff just remove this attribute and
then that's over of course if the goal
was to say okay now we keep the payment
edge really super simple and all that
well they are free to include whatever
extra stuff they want so that they can
add this teaming functionality in it of
course if it's getting too big they are
going to it's going to be visible if
let's say the payment page becomes pink
and all that other users will see that
some something is worth but it's still
difficult to you yeah a if you are let's
say discreet and it's going to be hard
to detect it for British Airways oh but
what do we have left now what can we do
in this case except yeah be sure that
your web server is not hard so here
comes we will discuss more about content
security policy so what he does in fact
it allows to whitelist
everything that is authorized from the
web page so from where can you lock
pictures for Martin you load scripts can
you load phones which kind of JavaScript
methods are allowed to run and all that
so again you can tell me what okay
it's the goodies content security policy
but they can just change because they're
on the server the web server they can
just change it and remove it and
whatever yes and no fee depends on the
web infrastructure because many times
you have a
or reverse proxy an engineer for example
in front of your web application and
generally it's not managed by the same
people so it's likely that if your web
server get sacked maybe your engine X in
front of it is not taxed so if you set
up all the content security policy
configuration in your engine geeks and
not directly in your in your web server
then somehow well you have shared
responsibilities and you you can hope to
be protected from that if it's not this
case occurs and there is one last
solution that I thought about maybe you
have other ideas is well you have to
make things difficult for magicapp so
you are just adding three lines of
JavaScript is too easy so what you have
to do is you have to obfuscate the
JavaScript and add tampering detection
code inside the JavaScript so that if
they try to play with it they just
change y9 so javascript is not going to
work and it can alert zero nurse and all
that so I'm not doing any advertisement
there but some companies try to do it at
sample one is called J's grumbler so it
takes your clear text JavaScript and it
gets something super Ivy dirty and all
that and it should protect from people
easily modifying some rings of
JavaScript and I'm open
afterwards at the end of this talk so if
you have any other ideas I would like to
let them okay
so now you say okay that's fine so yeah
maybe we should take care about those
third-party dependencies we should do
something but how much work for it you
know when you're developing a web
application you have to yeah you have to
deliver everything for your sprint you
have lots of tasks to do so you can say
to your manager say Yama the feature is
two days but then I need three weeks to
secure it I'd say well come on you're
fronting developer you don't need to do
security
you're not back-end
so I just put some open questions so
first question is yeah well how do you
make sure the JavaScript you you don't
know the skin so that's not easy but
yeah most of the time you don't know it
from like famous repository it's up so
it should be fine so that somehow you
have to be careful from where you
download it form but what I'm more
worried about in practice for having for
helping companies set up that is yeah
there is a performance impact at one
point for the end user
well if we say don't don't float
JavaScript from third-party domains the
first time you connect to the page you
have to load this JavaScript sometimes
the JavaScript sides are crazy some
scripts are like two megabytes so if you
have a slow connection and you are not
using this again is going to take like
maybe 10 20 seconds to load so you have
to be careful about it and maybe it's
also a good reason not to include that
oh yeah anything that you think might be
helpful but there's also a performance
impact for the dev team you know when
what people do sometimes because those
Java scripts are crazy heavy you take
all of them and you pack them and you
try to reduce them and all that so you
have a complex build chain because of it
and this bill chain may be broken if you
want to add all those extra steps of
like you know you want to computer ash
but if you're Bill Chen is taking
several scripts and then packing them
and somehow you have to add the ash on
the pack version and on the clear ocean
so there are operational challenges
there and what I saw in practice people
say yeah we we will handle this issue
because this is really a big concern we
really care about the security of user
data so we compute those ashes and we do
whatever we want to do there and then
comes yeah well you know three months
after there's a civvy published on this
javascript library because it can leak
data you provide like some crazy unicode
input or whatever and then they say yeah
well you know it spins tumor
work we are not going to have that
because we have to recompute the rush
and the deployment process is too
complex and all that oh well you know we
did it once and we stayed with the old
version because otherwise I'm not sure
what's going to be the name in the
content delivery network so yeah I'm not
going to go up good so please for if you
just have to do something yeah please
update before and if you can only do
something I just update and then forget
what I said about the first point better
have up to the dependencies it should be
better that now you say okay now I want
to do things well I understand what I'm
doing I will do up that's one I need to
do updates I'm okay to have some impact
on it because I want to protect my users
then come to the point you say well
maybe content security policy is the
best thing you can do so in practice
what it means is really for me it's
night from sandbox on steroids well you
can configure everything you want with
it it's really difficult to configure
well Google so it's Google will really
push this standard now I discussed with
some guys from Google that work on it
and they had so many issues in Gmail
with XSS and all that because you can
include whatever crops you want in Gmail
so it was really really out for them on
the back end part and to filter
everything so they say well now we we
are convinced we will never be able to
get run on what percent of the XSS stuff
in Gmail so what we do we would add a
browser protection so let's do it in
Chrome and then let's push standards and
then let's blame the other browsers if
they don't implement it and it worked
well up to the point when it was only
used by Google and then maybe two three
years after they realized that it was
crazy complex that had an animated
survey and they find out that 95% of the
CSP configurations were wrong and while
protecting from nothing and this
included like some amateur web site like
Facebook or things like that so then the
some of the change of mind and they try
to work
which you have something easier
yet for debugging debugging is hard and
the only trick that was proposed by
Google was the notion of reports you
were right so what it does is each time
so the browser will load this policy and
I want something happen on the page if
we check if it's compliant with the
policy and if it's not by default it's
going to block it if you go to the
developer console you will see alerts
for it but then you can configure the
report URL which we'll call an API at
your website or whatever so that you get
information that someone is either
engaging strange data on your website
all that well may be something you've
been too tight in the configuration
policy and then something is not working
so it's really good first for debugging
run your own testing phase so you can
have it on in report on e mode so what
you do in practice you set up maybe some
tiles policy you run all your
integration tests because you have
integration test and you have good
integration test and then you only have
to go through the report and see what
you have to to find Hume there and then
in production mode that's also really
helpful so you are in blocking mode but
you say that it's blocking but each time
there is a violation your API is
contacted and so you have an idea of the
payload people are playing with so at
the beginning it sounds like a good idea
but let's say if you are hit lab comm
you don't want to receive like thousands
of payloads broadly because you cannot
manage anything with it so what were
using a deep lab so we are using content
security policy because rock a bit like
Gmail yeah you know why in the issues
everything is self-service so you can
post whatever you want you can include
attachments you can include pictures and
JavaScript and all that on our outer one
bug bounty program we have like too many
XSS reports some of them are not that
good watcher we get many so we decided
to to go with content security policy
but we wanted something that was
reasonable for
deployment point of view from an
operational point of view we don't want
to have like 50 security engineers doing
all the coding content security policy
and having users complain that yeah well
you know this page is broken down now I
can't icon do this comment on whatever
so what we are using we are using the
letter specification that has introduced
the notion of announces so I won't give
the exact details but what you do in
fact you don't have to pre-compute ashes
to do so it's just a server that's
computes a random number when you
include the resource and and only your
resources can guess the secret number so
let's see if someone is trying to gather
together an external resource it doesn't
know these nouns and you cannot see so
it's not as secure as ashes but it's
it's a good balance so for people
interested you you can either look at
ads or think of course the content
security policy at this lab is not
trying to and 100% because we don't want
to spend o time just with user contents
on it and all that it's it's something
that may be the best balance for you if
you want to have some decent security
and and be able to Chilean delete from
an aversion point of view so so that's
it so I don't want to frighten you but I
hope that now you are convinced that
malicious content libraries yeah can be
a real issue you can be your target this
magical group maybe now it's like 40
companies that have disclosed that I've
been act by this group so it's a lot so
they're also playing with WordPress and
all that but playing with WordPress is
cheating so I prefer when there's a
really H in the server and they try to
do and we do a targeted attack like that
we saw that
yeah so as a front-end developer oh yeah
so you should care about security now so
something that maybe people know there
it's really hard for me to find a good
book to recommend on the web security
model so tangled web is okay from a book
but it's I would like to have like maybe
a book that's 40 50 pages long and I'd
explain me like like okay those are
those five security others that are
important and and that explained me yeah
okay you can load from facebook comments
again you cannot load from API does
Facebook own because whatever so so it's
hard and you have to document yourself
and you have to play and you have to
play with the developer console to see
warnings to understand what's happening
and yeah just do it a few Firefox just
go in the developer console in any
website and you love you see so many
errors everything is red because people
just don't realize that the javascript
is not working because of the of those
errors but like the website seems to be
working so shouldn't be shouldn't be too
bad so their solution and content
security policy is for me clearly the
best of them but yeah you you have to
invest some time to have it working is
not just setting like a magical flag and
then it's going to happen if the yeah
sure management said yeah I want content
security policy you can add one and you
can say well I trust all the world it's
not going to be useful what you're just
going to be part of the 95% of the
website that have CSP on and that are
not doing a good job there are some
tools to check if your policy is doing
its job they are not so good today
so yeah just use the developer console
and test and now I'm open to question
and also to feedback on what you do on
your daily life to undo it
[Music]
so let's see there's not like a good
solution otherwise we need to talk about
it but we vet libraries we reload and
each time we have woke up on the jumper
github is mostly Ruby so each time a new
dependency is included so we get alerts
at the app section so that we can which
are do we really need this extra
dependency and otherwise well we
download them and we read them it
doesn't mean that we read everything but
if we recharge them locally and we don't
let's say each time I get the packages
built it's not really downloaded each
time from NPM or whatever yes yeah yeah
so there is no to have that and all that
and I like when I have some time yet you
over to have a look at it if my new
chief is reasonable in size yes
because it was a an embedded browser
with Safari also so for unready depends
on the version of android so it used to
be but now it's browser good so let's
see - mixing cg latest version of
android is like you are in private mode
so it does in its own life the details
but it's not as simple because you know
many website or many mobile applications
yeah this is lack of Facebook all that
the they do login on a web page and they
do it for on purpose because they are or
thread of phishing attack so let's say
you don't know the fake facebook
application lock you're dead already but
at least they try to avoid that you
enter the login credentials in the
mobile app so they use holes and they
say yeah yeah I will redirect you to the
official website and you type it there
and because of that they have to be
somehow or lakhs vehicles most of the
time that says login patch is not on the
same domain is not like BG Sharad common
is going to be login dot which are
welcome because I want to set specific
cookie to it so because of that the
webview tends to be a bit flux from a
security point of view so in practice
you you get the same origin policy in it
but it's let's say choice mode browser
and practicing implementation so
normally you cannot browse somewhere
else but if someone has been able to
edit your web page and is loading
something from some world and you're
dead
any other question
well so if you
want to talk I get that boost is just on
the left so feel free to come and talk
if you have questions about disabled so
we'll be able to answer on the booze
thank you