hi everyone it's a pleasure to be here
today
before I get started I have one really
important thing to say
so I speak a tiny little bit of French
so I can you know buy coffee or ask for
directions but I've been going to some
some of the talks here in French as well
and I just have to say that
cybersecurity sounds so romantic in
French that really I enjoyed my time
even though I didn't understand anything
it felt wonderful so thank you so much
for doing this I'm like really excited
and now we're gonna talk about about the
cloud and about the fact that everyone's
hackable so a couple things about me
I'm Sheila I came all the way from
Israel I do cloud I do security I'm also
a member of the local OSP Israel chapter
I'm collating that chapter yay
I also saw your boot over here so it's
great to see that we are active
everywhere and also I'm a great
supporter of women in technology and
women in cybersecurity try to help
underrepresented communities doesn't
matter which to get into cybersecurity
because very often it looks like a very
you know male dominant thing obviously
look around you mostly men in the room
but we're trying to make a difference by
helping more people to get into this
this field so please support your you
know co-workers give them a hand help
them learn something new and encourage
them to you know to be better at what
they do it will also help you to be
better at what you do we came here to
talk about security and this is kind of
a diagram of what the old the good old
data center looked like back in the days
it was really easy to do security in the
on-prem days because all you had to do
is really to put some kind of device on
your way out to the internet it's called
a firewall and you felt really safe and
really good about it
all the security products we used to
have at that time had the word
prevention in them data leakage
prevention
you you were actually able to prevent
hacks from happening because you could
control everything that was coming in
and out of your data center and these
were very good and naive and happy days
but it's no longer happening that way we
don't know we can't do security by
prevention anymore or it's not enough
these days here's like a bunch of logos
of companies you're aware of you know of
you maybe use some of them and the
common ground of all of them is actually
that in the last couple of years all of
them had data breaches and as you
probably know these companies have
really really big security budget and
they can hire any security professional
they want and create any security
strategy they want and need and still it
happened to them now these are the
companies that we know of the companies
were who don't appear here even because
I didn't have enough space on the slide
some of the companies are unaware of the
fact that they've been hacked some of
them are being hacked as we speak some
of them are hacked not for the sake of
of their data some of them are hacked
because their competitors wants to know
something because they have to they have
to do something with critical
infrastructure of their camp of their
country and some you know criminal or
state-sponsored group wants to hack
their infrastructure for a different
reason so a lot of companies are not
here but that doesn't mean that they
were not hacked for the most likely they
have been hacked and they're just
unaware of that these days so as I said
prevention doesn't work anymore and we
need a new attitude when talking about
cloud security today when I talk to
cloud security professional I have to
this is what I feel like when I describe
my day-to-day life and how I do how I
plan security in the cloud today the
average enterprise has between 70 and 80
different security solutions means
that you know their security engineers
need a lot of screens open at any given
moment they have a lot of outputs and a
long queue of tickets they have to
address and even though they have so
many security products they still don't
feel safe they don't feel comfortable
they buy more products and their CEO
doesn't sleep well at night so why do we
keep on buying this product instead of
just thinking about a different way to
approach this problem and now the cloud
the cloud created us a new parameter
some would say but it definitely created
a lot of new buzzwords that you're all
aware of like server less and kubernetes
and containers but I say that the cloud
is not a new parameter the cloud created
a sub problem of no perimeter at all and
this is what I'm going to talk about
today I'm going to show you a few
examples of why we don't have a
parameter to protect anymore we are
losing it it's really vague it's really
foggy and there is no one simple way of
protecting our cloud infrastructure and
before I dive in I just want to remind
you if you're not using the cloud about
a shared responsibility model so if in
the past when in the good old datacenter
days you had your IT manager who was in
charge of IT no organization and if you
wanted a new server you had to be best
friends with them because it could take
months until you know you you place your
order and until it's coming in and until
it's installed it's gonna take months
until you have that server that you
wanted and they were the kings of IT you
really needed their help in order to do
something today it all shifted towards
the dev teams they run the own
infrastructure do they do security I
don't think so good job security for me
because they're just being really
irresponsible about how they do security
they care less about security and more
about delivering a new feature so if in
the past the world of the software and
the hardware were the part where it
still belonged to the IT manager today
Louis is in charge of the the bare
metals of the data center we don't care
about them anymore all I have to do is
just click and decide what kind of acid
do I want to spin what kind of operating
system do I want on it and basically
that's it it's that simple but we still
have a lot of responsibility about how
we configure these assets how do we
allow and not allow them to communicate
with the world sometimes we forget that
we just choose the default security
configuration coming with with AWS or as
your you know whichever cloud vendor you
prefer and yes it creates a lot of
problems to us let's talk about one of
them Identity and Access Management this
is our way of giving other users other
vendors other third parties a way to get
data or get resources out of our AWS
account it's really good and it's really
helpful but unfortunately a lot of
people do mistakes in there I am here is
just one example of users leaving API
keys in github sometimes we have reasons
to leave credentials in our code because
we need to for specific reasons but
these credentials should only give
access to very very very specific
resources according to what your
application needs it should definitely
not be credentials to your AWS account
but these things happen and then I talk
to users about it and they go to their
github and they change the code and they
remove the hard-coded credentials but
they forget that this is a repository
and I have older versions of your code
so they still have access to some of
your resources which you did not want to
give a other people access to so please
don't forget to change all the versions
as well other things that we have seen
is hard coding credentials again in
mobile apps and in this example
had users we had developers living
credentials that gave access to users
data so you you think that people don't
make these kind of mistakes but they do
so this is something you really need to
pay attention to let's talk about
storage services so in AWS we know we
all know the s3 buckets and if you log
in to shorten right now you're gonna see
a few a dot thousand dozens of you know
s3 buckets logged to the internet with
the public IP address and you can easily
see what kind of data they store but
there are plenty of other you know
storage services in AWS or in Azure blob
or you know whichever security vendor
you choose whichever cloud vendor you
choose and these mistakes still happen
in Amazon for example in a in Amazon in
this example we had so I forgot what
they want to say about this one but in
facebook they also used a third party in
Mexico who lost data of 400 million
users which probably means that they
have some of our data over there so
users very often make mistakes the data
I want to talk about before the example
was users under EBS leaving keys which
they forgot about enabling other users
to just log into their AWS account very
very easily with no problem at all
let's talk about compute power which is
also something very very exploitable in
the cloud we see a deny of wallet
attacks means someone is just using your
cloud to do whatever they want and
you're paying the bill one of the
examples is of course a crypto mining
which again you're paying the bill and
the hacker is is taking the Bitcoin or
whatever
their own pocket in the last couple
years we saw less ransomware attacks
because it required you know some
interaction between the attacker and the
account owner so in the in the in this
example there is no really
communication required I can just
install or spin up some really high GPU
assets mind my own Bitcoin mind my own
business and someone else is going to
pay the bill and if they don't pay
attention to their AWS bill they're not
gonna know that someone is abusing their
account of course this is also useful
for proxy attacks so I just want to use
someone else's infrastructure to hack
someone else and make it look like I had
nothing to do with it so again using
someone else's compute power it's very
good for that we saw one interesting
example with Tesla who had a kubernetes
cluster spinned up but they forgot to
put a password on their console so
someone was able to get access to one of
their containers the container had
credentials to other AWS account of
Tesla and the hacker was able to mine
lots of cryptocurrency that way another
good example and very important one is
using packages that are found online
it's really good and easy it's also
headache to update them afterwards maybe
to require some refactoring so in one
case we just saw in a node.js package
that in addition to what it was supposed
to be doing it was also looking for
wallets and just stole the coins that
were in those wallets this is what the
code was doing additionally of course
and then we recently saw a malware
called X boomer who is just using AWS
infrastructure in a no need to download
kind of kind of malware so yeah it's
happening all the time it's very easy
now I'd like to talk about a real
example
that actually happened recently to a
bank an American bank called Capital One
Capital One has a very very strong cloud
security team so again it's just another
one of those examples were it's not some
esoteric small organization who didn't
have the resources to protect their
cloud they had a very very strong team
to do that and still unfortunately it
happened to them as well so let's talk
about the stuff that we know what was
the damage it was caused so first of all
a user data of 100 million users or
potential customers because it also hurt
users who just asked for credit from the
bank even though they were denied so
their social security numbers names
addresses emails and so on everything
was leaked they had more victim victims
about 30 others including Europeans for
the the car manufacturer universities so
a lot of other other companies that were
hurt and crypto mining as well let's not
neglect that is the money option so in
addition to stealing the money the
hacker also installed some great crypto
mining machines on that account so let's
try to go over the steps as we
understand them to how this attack
actually happened of course we don't
have all the information about how it
happened there is some information
available online and some of it we just
had to kind of guess how would we do it
ourselves if we were the hackers so it
started with a scanner that was looking
for web servers that will were
vulnerable to SS RF attacks SS RF is a
server side request forgery
it means that I can in a in a certain
way it depends on the web server I can
get to the backend server and make it
make requests
that I actually told him to do so in
this case the hacker found a bunch of
web server that again were vulnerable in
the application layer to this kind of
attack and was able to create requests
by using that back-end server in this
example the the hacker made requests to
the metadata server service in AWS there
is a metadata service for every asset it
means that all the actions and all the
information about that asset live in
that server and you can actually make
requests like show me what kind of
credentials do we have or tell me the
last action that was taken on the server
and so on and this attack shows very
good understanding of how AWS works and
how it can be exploited
so the metadata service in this case the
hacker was able to ask for tokens now
it's really small so you can't see but
I'm going to show you a video in a
couple of minutes I we created a fake
web page just to try how this attack is
going to work and we made a request to
the metadata server it looks really
small but you can see the IP address
it's it's always the same IP address for
the metadata server because it's a it's
an internal IP address and then you can
see in the URL it says metadata and then
underneath you can see all the stuff you
can ask from the metadata service so you
can ask for credentials you can ask for
I am you can ask for IP addresses and so
on everything just appears here so the
next phase was obviously to ask for
credentials and you can see on the top
security credentials and we named our
credentials bedroll a wide s3 access
this was our role and we were able to
ask for a token with this with these
kind of credentials so you all you have
to write in the URL is security
credentials
and this is this is a token this is a
real token that you just copy-paste and
use for whatever you want to do so now
we have a token and we have access to
the AWS account so all we have to do is
list all the s3 buckets as the hacker
did and then sync them it means that we
download everything that the hacker had
that the s3 bucket has to the hackers
computer it's really that simple and of
course don't forget to install your
miners just in case so this is what
happened in this hack and could this
have been prevented or what should you
be doing to prevent this kind of attack
so first of all you need to know the
roles that you have in your account
because in this example a web server had
a role with access to all the s3 buckets
of the account instead of just having
access to the bucket that had JavaScript
code and the images that the web server
needed so know what kind of roles you
have and obviously don't give too broad
permissions if it's unnecessary the list
privilege principle of course don't give
to users or machines access they don't
need to areas in your application they
don't need it's it goes the same for
users who don't need access to the
production environment or to specific
databases in your production environment
monitor who is running commands and
where they do it from one of the things
we noticed while doing this research was
that first of all the hacker was using
tor and you know tor has their the nodes
available online so this is something
you can kind of hold the updated list of
of tor nodes and notice when someone is
using tor when they try to access your
application you might want to allow it
you might not and you might want to say
that ok I'm using tor by itself is not a
bad thing but if I see someone trying to
access
our AWS account from a tor IP address
then this is weird because my DevOps
engineers are not using tor or I don't
expect to see any token creation with
the Tor IP address so this is something
you can very very easily identify and
and prevent any further malicious
activity in your account and this is
what the log of this activity looked
like it's a real AWS log from Cloud
trail and in this case we were able to
see that where you see I and zero one
see this is the name of the machine that
the hacker was trying to get to of
course this is just a simulation that we
created it's not a real log from the
real hack but we see some kind of weird
string coming before and it means that
someone is trying to assume that troll
it's not the real machine trying to make
the action it's someone else assuming
the role of that machine so again you
have all the data in your logs you just
need to know what you're looking for and
as we as you can see we I talked about
the bed roll with why s3 access you can
see that this is the role that was used
in this activity and then I can the log
is very big so I just split it into two
parts so in this part I can see the IP
address that that the hacker was trying
to work from and then I see that it was
using Kali again you need to know your
developers and I assume most of them are
not using Kali for no real reason and I
see that there was the CLI activity AWS
CLI and I don't think that most of you
are using Kali to make CLI actions with
your AWS account so again this data is
in your AWS logs so it's very easy to
create a rule asking to see
any action that was made with the CLI
with Kali and to monitor that either
these actions don't happen or that
you're well aware if they do and you go
ask that user what hell are you doing so
very very easily detectable now I will
show you short let's see if the video is
going to work this is our simulation of
how the attack happened this is as show
showing that we have no access to an s3
bucket we try to log in and we have no
access to it just proving that we are
not cheating in this demo and then we
went to the app where I showed you
screenshots before and you can just it's
kind of a web book that shows what we
can what with what kind of answers we
can get from it and now we go to the
meta data service and we see all the
things we can ask from this service so
we're gonna go for I am and we have a
bedroll credentials over here so we ask
for them and we're gonna get the tokens
of the bedroll this is the token and it
has a time to live we copy paste it and
we go to our cali machine to use it we
just wrote a short script to you know
kind of create the token to be useful
for us we didn't manipulate it in any
way we just put it in a txt file and
we're gonna run it
and we're gonna go to the s3 bucket and
we see that we have access to all the
buckets and we have a sensitive bucket
of data
so obviously it's well it's going to be
the first one we try to we try to get to
now we try with credentials and we have
a secret dot txt file so this is how how
we did it and it's something that all of
you can do at home in your AWS account
of course now before coming to this
conference I was told that listen since
this conference is in Canada how about
if you talk about an incident that
happened in Canada so like okay let's
see what happened in Canada and I heard
about a bank bank I called the Sheldon I
hope I'm pronouncing it correctly
originally from Quebec and actually one
of the biggest financial institutes in
North America so it's a pretty big bank
and just in June we heard that it was
hacked and the data of 2.8 million
people was stolen and also about a
hundred and seventy three thousand
businesses were affected by it and now
we see this number 2.8 million it looks
nothing compared to the 100 million in
the u.s. but I think that it's almost 10
percent of the Canadian citizens or
something like this so here this number
means a lot and once again Social
Security numbers names addresses and so
on were stolen by this hacker that acted
completely differently from the hacker
that we saw in the capital one incident
what happened here so as I said before
this was publicly published in June of
2019 but the whole thing actually
started in December of 2018 when the
bank notices unusual transactions now I
couldn't find information about what
kind of unusual transactions were
detected but they were unusual enough so
that the bank would approach the police
and ask this to be investigated and it
was investigated
six months later May of 2019
the police notifies the bank that some
of their customers data was found in the
wild so it means that the data was
already exfiltrated and the hacker was
maybe trying to sell it or just to
spread it around and then we all heard
about it in June so this means that it
took the bank a very very very long time
to notify its users that something bad
is going on here and this is actually a
question for four people from the bank
like why would you notify your users
that late why didn't you ask them to
rotate passwords before it means they
put a lot of people at risk for a very
long time now we don't know exactly how
this thing happened but in this case
there was probably very good social
engineering because that employee the
hacker was actually an employee of the
bank until he was fired because of what
he did so he gained the trust of his
fellow co-workers and for some reason
they gave him their permissions and then
he was using everyone's and his
permissions to steal data and
exfiltrated and actually the police
found out that he was involved with
different crime groups trying to sell
this data to including street gangs and
also international syndicates so he was
really trying from every direction to
sell this data and this is probably how
the police found out about it and about
the data that was exfiltrated so to sum
up what we talked about today if the
best ones are hackable it means that all
of us are no matter how hard we try no
matter how many security products we buy
no matter how many people we hire on our
security team we are all hackable at
some point it's going to happen to us
and we have to be prepared and to have a
good reaction plan to detect it as fast
as possible
the detection and contamination time is
too long today
recently IBM published their date cost
of data breach survey and said that on
average it takes two hundred and seventy
nine days to detect and contaminate a
data breach so this is almost a year
it's a very very very long time a long
time for a damage to be created you
don't want to wait six months before you
notify your users you want to detect it
as soon as the token is stolen from your
web server then you cancel the token and
then you understand how it was even
stolen from your web server you do not
wait until the s3 buckets are listed and
all the data is stolen from them faster
detection can save you from very very
massive damage and don't forget that and
use your logs like the cloud trail I
showed you before to detect faster
unusual events it's not that hard you
don't need fancy machine learning
algorithms I showed you the log the data
is there the roll is there you can see
that an unusual IP address is using a
roll that is very very wide you can very
easily see that and you don't need this
really fancy fancy products how are you
going to detect so log I showed you the
cloud trail you have the flow logs you
have many other logs that your security
products and your IT is providing so
keep them and keep them in a place where
they're accessible to you don't just
dump them in an s3 bucket and forget
about them because in the day you will
need them it will be very hard to
extract them and then use them again
look for anomalies as I mentioned before
it's really easy you don't need the
really fancy algorithm is you know who
your users are you know usually at what
times do they work and you know freight
user pretty much what roles do they need
so if one day they request for a broad
role you're gonna know that yeah maybe
someone is working from home on a
you project but also maybe someone is
using that users credentials priorities
it's very hard all of these products
create a lot of tickets for us to handle
and you need to prioritize as security
professionals you know that the tokens
are very important to hand us and with
handling we don't want them to be abused
I'm not saying that patching machines is
not important it's also very important
but my guess is that each and every one
of you has dozens of machines with
hundreds of patches needed needs to be
that needs to be installed so prioritize
don't neglect that but we need to decide
according to each organization what is
more dangerous to you and the last thing
is automatic response if possible the
credentials example that I mentioned yes
if you will create a rule that if
someone is requesting for a token using
a tor node you will stop the session I
don't think it will create a damage to
your production environment so I think
it's okay to create an automation that
if this happens delete this token or do
something like invoke this user or do
something like that you can automate the
really dangerous activities that are
happening in your account because I
expect that they happen very rarely you
can also automate the very the things
that happen 20 times a day and you also
always respond in the same way this is
also very easy to automate and this will
save you a lot of time and leave you
enough time to handle the really serious
and unusual events that happen in your
account that's it thank you very much
because it's my pleasure to be here
and they think we have time for
questions so I can take them here or
outside