thank you so much for coming this is my
first time speaking at hackfest and very
happy to be there be here I really like
Quebec so just I'll just start by
introducing myself
I'm from Urbana Illinois where the
University of Illinois is about actually
200 kilometers south of the Chicago
Blackhawks so I'm a software developer
and I'm in a NASA program called the
data noughts where we got to learn we
got the opportunity to learn about data
science and so I'm interested in
basically both data science and security
and I got very interested in finding an
area where those intersected and so I've
been basically studying basically data
science and machine learning and
cybersecurity and I would just like to
share some of the things I learned I was
also part of this 2017 sans woman's
Academy where I was able to earn 3 GI
ACC certifications I'm we word 7/10 on
Twitter a shabarimala francais Jew by
the booth - LeMond parle Anglais yes ok
so I don't speak French very well so
actually let's so I'm curious how many
people have have had a vendor talk about
how their mission their product uses AI
or machine learning or deep learning
anybody heard that from a vendor at all
oh yeah ok the vendors never ever
mentioned that right so then we could
actually start out by just talking about
what what do these terms even mean and
so one way of thinking about AI machine
learning and deep learning is you could
look at it as this egg diagram or you
could look at it as it's been described
as a set of Russian dolls
we're basically AI is on the outside
layer it encompasses everything machine
learning is a slightly smaller subset
and then deep learning is basically a
slightly smaller subset of that so so if
if you're hearing the terms used
somewhere interchangeably it's like
basically there you're talking about
sort of a subset relation so basically
so what comes to mind when people think
of artificial intelligence nobody I mean
I was thinking of I mean I was thinking
of the movie 2000 because Hal came to
life in Urbana Illinois after all look
Dave I can see you're really upset about
this
I honestly think you ought to sit down
calmly take a stress pill and think
things over
it doesn't ring a bell with very many
people okay so basically it's been
described as the branch of computer
science dealing of the reproduction of
mimicking of human level intelligence
self-awareness knowledge consciousness
thought in computer programs in other
words it's artificial intelligence is
where a computer tries to emulate some
things we think of as being part of
human intelligence so it doesn't really
work quite the same way so basically uh
machine learning I could put a
definition up here it is it basically
involves a lot of math statistics and
algorithms and there are two terminology
two major term you were to come across
when you talk about machine learning
there it's called supervised and
unsupervised learning
so it has anybody heard of those before
okay so supervised learning is
essentially a supervised learning
essentially you at some level start out
with some some hopefully right answers
right you're you basically start out
with a set of correctly labeled data
that you use as training data in
unsupervised learning is we're
interesting unsupervised learning you
don't get to start out with correctly
labeled data you actually take this this
data such that you don't have any
transfers for and basically extract
knowledge and patterns from those
so my buddy so that's a I think you've
probably heard the term neural network
right so essentially a neural network
it's modeled on the human brain it's
modeled on the idea of neurons where
they get gets a certain amount of
certain inputs and basically if it gets
a certain level of input then it's
activated and it fighters and so
basically the what so basically nodes in
neural networks are kind of like neurons
they get assigned weight kind of weights
and thresholds so this is kind of hard
to just this is kind of a little a
little bit hard to visualize if you're
not familiar with it so I just got a
I've got a diagram it's like it starts
with the so the red stuff and the red
stuff on the far left is are basically
inputs you're it may be multiple kinds
of inputs and then this thing called
hidden those are the basically those are
the hidden layers in this case it just
has one hidden layer but those those are
kind of the neurons you think about and
then those actually feed you then out
the input so it's not necessarily a
completely one-way process because it
tends to continually can continuously
get feedback and we're I it it kind of
content continuously gets feedback and
kind of adjust its computation and
weights and stuff until it gets closer
and closer to the right answer in that
let's see so I got so I got hopefully a
video this is really kind of neat it's
it's called player it's at a site called
playground tensorflow org and anybody
can use it for free and I put the link
in my slides but kind of easy to see it
this is actually an animation of a
network a neural network in progress you
can kind of seen your browser you can
have draw you can basically add the
features that are your input features
you can you can adjust your number of
neurons and your layers and and
visualize the output so I don't know it
can you can you guys see that very well
from your Amir where you're sitting or
um but at any rate I'm going to tweet
out my slides after I get done
and the Lincoln's - the link to the site
if you want to play with it is going to
be in the slides but if you continue to
watch this you can kind of see the you
can kind of see the inputs and the
weights and stuff getting refined kind
of in response to the feedback as far as
and basically the input keeps getting
better and better
anyhow that that is that is the best I
could that is the best I could come up
with for just visualizing a neural
network in action and like I could feel
really bad about doing a presentation
without any MEMS yeah but it's always
this is very realistic because like when
people talk about machine learning they
think of it as some kind of like magic
black box or something and that's not
really what it is I mean a lot of times
that people when they're working knew
that they need to know what kind of data
they're working with and they're kind of
continuously tweaking the parameters and
the model and stuff to make it better I
mean I I mean if you if you go to the
site and stuff
you can even experience that as you see
as you tweak your inputs and parameters
and stuff you could get better and
better results so actually deep learning
very specifically refers to these neural
networks so basically that basically ID
when they talk about deep learning and
thinking probably a lot of vendors have
used that too so that it's very
specifically referring to the two of
these neural network as I showed you in
action
in the end they could be and they can
actually be both say both supervised and
unsupervised so one thing that's very
useful about this is a lot of times when
we're detecting threats and bad
behaviors where you lie on signatures
which are kind of like signs or
descriptions with a associated with the
malware exploits known behavior and so
basically if you eat so you had known
throughout the signatures are very good
and the problem is zero day the zero day
exploits and stuff you don't you usually
don't have signatures to plug into your
into like your IDs or your antivirus
software so basically this this is where
a deep learning comes in and the deep
learning is good for detecting a lot of
anomaly detection it could detect
basically a user and behavior user
behavior issues I'm sorry user and
behavior anomalies like for example like
they've been used to detect insider
fraud insider threats and fraud and
stuff like that as well
I see so this is just assistant this is
just an example paper that I read if I'm
very interesting um so naturally so one
applications it's very common with deep
learning it's not usually associated
with security but you see it in a lot
with deep learning is is like natural
language processing like if you like for
example if you go to a deep Elcom that
that is that could be even that a piece
of a lot of people consider that even
better than Google Translate but you
know but you don't often but you don't
see a lot of NLP in security but
Microsoft is found a very interesting a
very interesting application of this so
this is so they essentially used this
algorithm called word avec we just sort
of it which is kind of a neural net that
is able to take to take these words and
kind of embed them and in vectors that
show kind of it show something about the
context and how how far apart they are
from each other and they call it
contextual embedding and they they got
some very good results from that they
they so a lot of times your power um a
lot of times like your PowerShell
commands they have aliases right and
also if you've got a malicious script
people will very often try to obfuscate
it they'll try to consider I mean
they'll try to intentionally make it
hard to break down and this this
actually was it actually turned out to
be very effective against that this was
just just a somewhat interesting use
case I found so actually skipping over
to preparing the data so you got a few
things you got a you've got a school say
you talked about data selection and
sampling sometimes you can use all the
data but sometimes if you've got a whole
lot of data like for example your
network flow and stuff that's that it's
not quite you have too much data it's
now cracked
it's not practical to Elliott value with
everything you have to come up with some
way of sampling and selecting
another thing that they talk about is
feature extraction so with feature
extraction so you've got this this whole
front you've got this stream data or
something coming in at you right like
let's say you're trying to you're you're
trying to look at your network traffic
or something you maybe you've got a pcap
file it's like you're well if you're not
going to say dump the peacock pcap file
directly and to say something like
tensorflow
you're you need to you need to baby
decide so what what part of the network
traffic are you interested in what feat
what features do you care about like for
example are you looking maybe for a
certain payloads are you looking for
maybe sir maybe going going to certain
addresses with poor going to certain
servers with poor reputations that show
up in a threat intelligence feed and so
so essentially a feature extraction it's
like you need to understand something of
the domain and decide which features
that you you want to think about and
we're to talk a little bit more about
that later then with it featuring coding
and vectorization essentially that just
means that you need to represent things
in a mathematical way that these
packages can understand and then there's
finally there's something called
normalization nobody but has anybody
heard of that before
yeah so essentially with normalization
it's like you have maybe you've got to
two variables you care about one has a
much wider variation than the other well
if you don't normalize those the one
with a wider variation is gonna have
maybe a disproportion about I've been
influenced on the results so actually
here's an example of a normal just
normalize data like for example you can
see that there's a lot more that just
the CPU utilization present and the
request per se the scale is completely
different and so normalization you
probably want to find a way to us yeah
it's a pretty simple it's a pretty
simple equation you just want
to basically represent the data all the
data on a scale from zero to one and so
here's an example how we normalize some
data okay so a big part of machine
learning with security is pattern
recognition like for example there's
something called data mining knowledge
discovery in knowledge kdd which I
remember that calling knowledge
discovery and something but that tries
to just that it tends to discover like
just unknown patterns that are located
in the data and sometimes you want to
discover to basically find very explicit
characteristics about the data and so
essentially when you talk about pattern
recognition you can say you've got these
things it recognizes that it can extract
certain patterns that are related to the
known data you're passing in and it can
take those patterns that has discovered
and apply it to unknown data so like for
example you have like some known hostile
traffic or you've got some no malware
and stuff like it like you can feed it
you can feed it to a machine learning
system and it can in it get an extract
characteristics about it and then it
goes straight and then you can start
feeding may be unknown software or
unknown traffic to it to say well does
it look like this it pretty much it's
like so does it look like this bad stuff
you saw earlier and so there's there's a
lot of them I think so the most obvious
or just your spam and your botnets and
your malware so basically the with with
clustering the whole idea with
clustering really is that bad things
happen together so um let's see I don't
know if you what I think about this or
not like so if we the audience agree
that the remaining audience and you
needed to arrange yourself into clusters
how would you do it um I mean it's like
so maybe you would try to find people
maybe you try to find people who are
sitting close to you and arrange
yourselves in groups
instead of going across the room you
maybe you would do it that way and so um
what I heard stirs clusters it's like
you're trying to find points that are
close together and there's typically
mathematical ways of measuring closest
together you can do it the Manhattan
distance or you can do the Euclidean
distance but that's usually pretty
straightforward and so the whole idea is
that basically study the items within a
cluster are going to be hopefully more
similar to each other than items that
are not in a given cluster and so
there's there's actually there's really
a lot of ways you can do this there's
something called there is and we'll just
talk about a couple of the most common
ones very common ones called kami
k-means and DB scan let's see so the
whole fundamental idea with k-means that
you kind of you kind of try to group
data points together and discover
underlying patterns so I mean
essentially you start by uh so you
really you start by just picking picking
in like art just just putting centroids
in arbitrary locations trying and
iterating is true until you can discover
the optimal to the the optimal location
for the centroids so it's a fairly
simple algorithm so this is just a
picture of how it works so initially
it's kind of random
initially it's kind of random that's not
very good round one gets a little better
around two it's still better and then
finally you get a not a basically an
optimal like it you get what's a pretty
good cluster and then then under the
okay another approach you could take
it's this is this is really common it
shows up very often in like research
papers about machine learning and
security it's called DBC on and honestly
I keep thinking of it as being about
databases but it is not it's about
densities base facial clustering of
applications with noise and then the
noise of the noise is significant too
because they because they you actually
want to find the noise so
so basically that takes two parameters
basically it's EPS also known as epsilon
that specializes that specifies how
close the point should be together to be
considered part of a cluster and then
min points is basically what's your
minimum number of points that could be
considered a cluster so you just put you
past those two parameters so it's it's
some basically it's an iterative process
just like k-means you start with an
arbitrary point if in basically if you
can start form a cluster you can start
to form a cluster you do if you cannot
form a cluster at the point label it is
noise and basically you you kind of
continue this until you built your
cluster and then you restart with
another point that has not been visited
and do the same thing until you
basically have a number of clusters one
thing that's a bit different about DB
scan is that what the k-means you have
to tell it how many how many clusters
you want you want and that that actually
reinforce a lot of that does involve
some trying error DB scan DB scan will
come up with a number of clusters for
you so you do that you are possibly
gonna want to tweak your your a meters
as far as like your epsilon and your
minimum number of points okay so this is
just showing your DB scan cluster in
action so there's so I don't know how I
know I don't know how well you guys can
see that you've got but you've got
yellow green and red and then you've got
these points on the outside that are
kind of black and those are those so
those will be considered your noise
points
okay so actually this so it just as for
some case studies I found some some
rather interesting ones from Trend Micro
Micro and and Symantec so so um this is
the Symantec Laurie the Symantec visa is
that Symantec actually started with
looking at the HTTP flows and and trying
to look for things that were consistent
with known malware attacks and so there
so we talked earlier about features like
what do you what do you care about but
features a lot of times it's like what
kind of information are you trying to
extract from this that you might care
about so there were actually a couple of
very significant features the when they
were trying to fight when they were
trying to find attacks if they could
cluster as ransomware that very often
showed up in the URL that the basically
they were able to be URL information
gave them allowed them to cluster
ransomware attacks collect together
which is pretty interesting the other
ones were generic malware and what that
that was actually more related to the
payload because that was specifically
the file type like so that was related
to like your file type the malware was
coming across and stuff like PDFs and
shockwave and stuff and basically files
like that which is a pretty normal way
to deliver malware and then it's inside
Symantec they did something and they did
something kind of interesting they
basically so they it's the so some
semantics is run either SOC and they
want to uh basically cluster their the
incidents that happened in their in
their SOC s together and so they want to
basically see like how similar if events
are like so can they can they respond to
them in a similar way is there it can
they learn anything from how they're
handled in the past and and they
actually they actually were able to
she had quite a bit of success like they
were a figure out like for example if
they got like a know where a malware
attack they were to a cluster a lot of
things that came into their SOC with
that male with that malware attack they
could also look for like certain they
also were a little for certain behaviors
that were not good like for example like
if you're monitoring a network like it's
like if somebody's attacking you what
kinds of things might they do they might
start scanning you right like they might
start looking for certain they might
start looking for vulnerable services
they might they might start me for like
do you have an open SMTP server you and
ft do have services like FTP or LDAP or
something that could that might be
vulnerable that might that could be
abused or provide some information for
them and so they were they were able to
look look at that as well to see just no
no they were they were able to look at
that as well and closer those kinds of
attacks together as well so just as far
as clustering um takeaways they could be
a um they can be applied to a lot of
different ends of data like for example
categorical and continuous when they
talk about the relevant features be
extracted and normalized and that does
mean that you probably need to know
something with the domain and the data
you're dealing with so you know what
kinds of features you want to it you
might want to extract there a lot of
times with machine learning there are
validation error validation techniques a
lot of times if you're trying to build a
two cluster you maybe look at the
cluster and you see you basically look
maybe how how close the claw how close
the clusters are how does that how many
how many elements are in clusters how
does that perform to other other
clustering algorithms so there are there
actually are some ways you can validate
that and so it's so basically what it it
the way it works is really kind of what
it did with the SOC in the network it's
they they started with like a big SOC is
gonna have lots and a lot of data lots
and lots of data and it allowed them to
basically take this vast amount of data
and sift through it
okay so classification it sounds kind of
like clustering but it's at but it's but
it's a bit different so um basically
classification is like watch what is the
likelihood that something is in a given
class so like if you're gonna classify
people here many ideas how you would how
you would do it okay like tabs versus
leaves no sorry but it's but it's but
essentially the client that
classification is a little bit different
it's like youyou know what classes or
categories you want to use and that's so
that's actually a little bit that's
works a little bit differently than
clustering and so that is because then
it's basically considered a supervised
learning because it's kind of like
you're starting with the answers the the
samples have already been collect
correctly labeled and identified and
then it's and it's also possible just to
bear in mind with classification that a
sample can belong to kind of multiple
categories at once so just some
classification just some examples of uh
here's an example of what somebody did
mistake lassic example they wanted to
they wanted to detect a botnet command
and control center um so what they did
was they was they issued HTTP request to
benign in CNC controls is so well
actually let me clarify that what they
did was they took a list of files and
file headers URLs that were known or
associated with kind of known sketchy
C&C sites and so they specifically
requested those in basic and and and
they saved the responses and the well of
course the response codes because like
for example if you get a if you get say
a 404 or something that's that meaning
like that would mean that the file
wasn't there and that's different if you
then if you get a 200 and you get the
file right with an HTTP request so they
were actually able to create a
decision tree model in the basically
saying essentially if they get what I
think it's what they make if they got
enough hits on the sketchy looking file
patterns they were to conclude that it
was fairly likely that this was a cnc
sia server
vicen so essentially it's a supervised
learning while it can work well when
there is a sufficient quality quantity
of accurately labeled data and one
challenge and security is it's kind of
it says if there is a sufficient quality
of accurately labeled data so in
security that's not always the case
though essentially so you've got the
fourth age of biology you've got the
training and then you then the
validation where you do something to
actually to actually test to make sure
whether you're whether your model makes
sense a very common way of validating a
machine learning is that you you take
your training data but you you withhold
some of it you keep some of it out of
the training model and then you run your
model and you generate your model and
then you take the data that you've held
out against it and you see how well that
performs and that that is a fairly cut
like saying so does your model still
hold up when you test it with this new
with this new data that you haven't used
in training and that's that's just a
very common way you do your validation
um another thing with classification is
you're not you're not getting absolutely
you're not getting absolutes it's not
going to say this is absolutely a CNC
server or this is absolutely botnet it's
basically to tell you how likely it is
and so um a lot of things a lot of a big
problem a big known problem with like
machine learning is you get false
positives and false negatives and so
like false positives or like when you
get an alert it tells you that there's a
problem there's not and false negative
is when it tells you that something is
okay and it's not and so a problem with
false false positives and security is
that it can chew up a whole lot of your
time like if it's if it's constantly
going off
throwing up alerts you have to deal with
it can waste all that I can't your time
and it can teach people to ignore and
connect each field even ignore the
system and false-negatives are kind of
obviously a problem me because well it
means the system's not not doing what
you wanted to do you you want it to tell
you there's a problem and it's not so
those are both so these are actually
both big problems and they're both risks
with machine learning so this is said
this is actually a little bit different
we talked earlier about pattern
recognition absolutely so the idea like
what is normal but a state of mind so
the whole idea is that we want to we
want to establish some rough idea of
what normal looks like and we talked
when we talked about this this deviation
of from normal we could we Club we can
call them anomalies or outliers ends and
security of nominees anomalies and
something that's unusual is often bad
and so for example like anomalies often
mean that we have like an intruder or a
breach or an exploit going on so just
your overall goals with an intrusion
system just for the reasons we talked
about earlier you want low false
positives and low false negatives so
that it does your job it said it does
its job without wasting a lot of
people's time I mean the whole reason
you might want it you're gonna want to
plug machine learning in is basically to
save people's time to automate to maybe
ideally automate some of the tedious
tasks that you're soces or not gonna
want us but we're not want to spend
their time doing you want to be
basically easy to easy to work with and
it's just with exploits and threats and
stuff the I mean landscape changes
constantly in security isn't it I mean I
mean it's like you're your latest worms
or the latest alerts like when like when
is the last time is a security alert
probably today
and ideally uh ideally like
resource-efficient because it's with
what security here you can be talking
about very large amounts of data in fact
I bet it's in fact some of the some of
the security the
the software and stuff has specifically
you uses tools like Anoop and stuff to
deal with big data and there's also some
people explainable alerts does that make
sense
I mean essentially you want to know if
it's if it's - if it's telling you
something's wrong you want it you want
to be able to trace back Wyatt made that
decision like for example if it tells
you to delete somebody's account that
person is maybe gonna want to know why
their account got deleted so you're know
probably to be a you're gonna want to be
able to understand the system well
enough to know why I did what it did so
let's just talk so we talked earlier
about just features and stuff and what
we might want to look for in here are
see and these are some things you might
want it you might want to look for in
host intrusion I mean so gonna be
looking at you'd be looking at processes
are you seeing anything unusual walk in
in sometimes processes on an attack are
camouflaged looked pretty close to
something that's normal
like just a little bit off I don't be
seen that you can see after new user
accounts like it basically it created
this account why did it do it is it
loading and a kernel modules it doesn't
usually look and then actually your your
DNS can tell you quite a bit is it
looking is it like for example is it
looking up sites that are is it looking
up locations or addresses that are happy
to be also showing up on your a thread
and tell feed so DNS lookups can
actually tell you wait a
network connections are kind of
important because well it's like if
you're trying to connect like a a
command-and-control network or some I
mean just a lot of times if you've got a
compromised system it is trying to be
trying to communicate out right and then
another thing that you'll you'll see is
for is like for example with a Windows
attack it's going to uh try to moderate
you're gonna see your a registry
database messed with often right or
that's that's not uncommon when you get
like a Windows malware attack is it
yeah this is this is just a this is a
fairly useful tool if you want to
actually look at your host you see what
my I may be compromised
um I think probably a lot of you've
heard of it always query yes okay so
it's it's very it's really handy and
basically it can have even run query you
can even schedule queries it'll it'll
pop you like tables you know you can
freighter it's it's I believe it's free
it runs in it supports Windows and Linux
yeah that's and that is just a very good
way of getting information that you
might want to feed into a machine
learning algorithm
so then approach a network network
intrusion detection I just as we said
earlier that I see you've got a
compromised host it's going to in some
way try to initiate communication with
the outside world like whether it's
exfiltrating data or if it's talking to
a command and control server I mean and
your adware is trying to download ads to
show up on your machine your spywares
sending the results of your monitoring
somewhere and you and you can there are
a lot of tools you guys have probably
heard of them TCP dump I bet everybody's
sort of yes okay and then a snore is
that sports snorts fairly simple it's
sorts pretty popular it's fairly simple
and rule-based and then there's also a
tool if you guys you guys sort of broke
okay bro is now known as eek oh and that
that's that's kind of neat that's that's
like a row is almost bro is actually
kind of like a programming like language
specifically dedicated to monitoring and
analyzing network traffic it's really
it's pretty impressive
okay so another thing another year that
very often a very common target it's
called your web application so these are
so these are some things you might want
to look for to feed into a machine
learning algorithm for your web for a
potential web intuition
I'll see you
I want to you might want to look at your
IP addresses again if it's connected to
if you're if you're hearing from if
you're looking at seeing sketchy IP
addresses one thing you could pop when
do you possibly do that sometimes
helpful is also geo locate I P addresses
I mean if you're if you're getting a lot
of a lot of logins to your small company
Network from like China or Romania maybe
that's a maybe that's not good you
should see kind of some and then
sometimes they you'll see some kind of
strange URL string as you'll see on
Knoll terminations your decoded URLs or
whatever and they're essentially trying
to evade signature so it's they're doing
funny things with strings to try to
evade I say signature based detection
and then kind of okay so like your
unusual referrer patterns I mean has
anybody here use curl a few of you right
okay so curls kind of a girl sort of a
nice tool you can even conceive I'd like
you can connect like it's a very nice
way to connect to a web server via the
command line and you can pass in a lot
of parameters and so it's like if you're
using curl you can tell it that your
that your user agent or referrers
whatever you want it to be and so like
for example if your wrist so if you're
seeing somebody who's using mozilla from
1998 it's it's possible that you it's
possible that that some date information
is getting manipulated i mean if you're
seeing something that's if you're seeing
something that's really old or really
strange it's possible that somebody's
manipulating something so the when they
talk about sequence of ex access to
endpoints doesn't have any creative
fuzzing yes I like fuzzing is when
you're basically exposing is basically
you throw away a whole bunch of inputs
it's something to try to see if you can
make it somehow it's just try to see if
you can make it fail or expose some kind
of security hole and so when you start
seeing these really strange sequences of
access to endpoints that are not
consistent with what a normal user would
do it's possible somebody is prize
throwing a buzzer at you and so what are
these things is these these are all the
kinds of things you might look at to
feed into a machine where
learning tool and just for what it is
worth again I will tweet out I'll post
my slides online and tweet out the links
the links so you got this other we've
got another tool called off forecasting
so we probably all heard of forecasting
like in terms of weather right and
slowly so um so you got it you've got
things called trends and then seasons
and then cycles and that kind of means
that it kind of means that you were to
see some up and down and stuff in cycles
you're not gonna that a try you're not
going to necessarily see straight lines
up and down I mean it and so see so
basically this is this is just a this is
just basically a model that handles a
basically a forecast um these are also
described as time series because it's
like a lot of times they're something
that happens over it's over ice time and
then so you've got something called
arena it's the auto auto regressive
integrated moving moving average and so
that basically means that these models
are kind of dependent on kind of their
own past input no I mean this is so the
so it's basically what I get it simply
gets its input from what's happened in
the past but it's somewhat more
sophisticated than a linear algorithm
because a lot of times like if you see a
time series trend it's it's not going to
be linear like for example if you look
at usage or something on your work
network you're hopefully not going to
see as much going on maybe in the middle
of the 90s you would during the middle
of the work day so you're not going to
so you're easier it's not gonna be a
straight line it's gonna kind of up and
down right and then though so this is
just a generic generic data straight
data series you can kind of see that's a
it's it's basically a daily series that
goes up and down but it's kind of but
it's kind of trending up but you can
kind of see that it's through that we're
Gretchen why that's it's so it's got its
cycles
but it's kind of trending upward right
and in this this is just this is just an
example of basically a time series that
you can apply forecasting to this is a
generic thing cool what do you would it
put our unit to talk about CPU
utilization over a period time so let's
say this is this is a great a graph of
some known CPU data and so actually you
can apply it you'd apply something to go
ARIMA or in fact another forecasting
model to try to get an idea of what's
what's normal what can you expect on a
particular time based on what's happened
in the past and so I don't know if you
can can you see the I just think can you
see the blue and black heard from there
and not very well okay so basically the
blue the blue is the actual data and the
blacks the model so you see they manage
they managed to fit that pretty well so
what we're gonna do I think we talked
earlier about like a lot of times you
you want to like sometimes you would
have validate or you want to or you want
to check your model you're gonna go
ahead and take some you're gonna take
some data that's that's not in a sample
or we're gonna apply this model we came
up we came up with the last slide so
this is what the model looks like you
can see it's kind of blurry at the end
and that means they're not quite as
confident about it that means that
they're a little bit easier but what
happens and then this in the gray shows
the area this integration area and you
can see that the area so you can see
that the area does not line up very well
with what was forecast so the air that
Brady airy and stuff doesn't line up
very well with with what was forecast
because if you look at if you look at
the model in the past it was kind of it
was trending upwards it was it was
gradually trending upwards in that and
then in the area in the gray it's just
it's starting to drop
and then it's the upward trend wasn't
continuing so it's a basically through
this model we can see that that was
viewed as kind of an anomaly does that
does that make any sense okay
so I'm sure um has anybody here not
heard of like a male where a family a
family are male we're like like no yes
okay so like a lot of times like you get
some male work this male worker comes in
and then you start getting these other
male where this other samples of malware
that or maybe a whole lot like it but
not exactly like it and it's like maybe
they're they're building it on different
compilers they're trying to evade
signatures or something like that but
it's really kind of the same thing doing
the same stuff and that's what they mean
by a malware yeah that's what they mean
by a malware family
in fact like this probably came coming
from the same people so traditionally
the malware like you know like your
typical Android virus thing you've got
the signature matching it matches kind
of known characteristics of this Miller
um and that's great except for what
about when you get the zero days so you
see news things I'm you guys heard of
have you guys heard of static and you
know interesting what static and dynamic
analysis means with Miller
it's like static analysis you're
basically taking the binary and just the
executable stuff analyzed it wasn't the
executable and dynamic analysis it's
like you're taking it in like a sandbox
often like a VM or something and
executing it so let's see so with me
Android malware you might look for
interesting strees specifically like
hard-coded URLs and addresses that it
might be using to talk to talk to a C&C
to talk to a CNC server or some other
11th server you might look at what what
kinds of API calls does it make the
network I mean just when you're doing
when you're looking at it dynamically
it's like I know what kind of network
behavior does it does is it starting to
try to initiate these these connections
and if so why you want to look at what's
changing your system like have you seen
strange changes to your registry they
don't make any sense with that kind of
software with with what with what the
software is supposed to be uh for
example um and if you're looking at it
something like Android or something you
can also look at like Android you can
just put you can actually just look at
the manifest and see if is requesting um
permissions that are to greatly exceed
what it would need to do that kind of
thing because like a lot of times for
example people with mobile stuff they'll
agree to just about anything
I mean seriously have you like have you
seen the permissions and stuff we were
trying to uh install something there's
phone it's like yeah I'd like to access
your email address your contacts and
then I like to have your firstborn child
and your users are just like okay okay
okay and so basically strange
permissions in mobile applications are
kind of a common mail where delivery
route so let's talk about something okay
so we talked about what machine learning
is so we talked about what some of the
limitations of it are one we talked a
little bit about it we talked a bit
about explain ability earlier and it's
it's like so is your machine learning
system this black box or is it like is
it open the analyst actually explained
understand why a the system made a
particular decision a recommendation
it's also not a silver bullet I mean
like your vendors are talking to you and
they're saying we've got this machine
learning and stuff like it's gonna be
magic and it's like it's really not it's
it's there's nothing magic at all about
it it's basically a set of like
mathematical techniques and algorithms
in you you have to know what you're
feeding into it if you if you want to
use it and uh another thing that is that
the body of human knowledge is pretty is
just pretty large like for example I
think you're trying to decide whether an
email is spam or ham like a human could
look at and understand words in context
like maybe if somebody sends you
um like you're doing business with a
vendor and they send you an email about
about the laser toner you've you've
ordered that's legitimate but like a lot
of times litchi pleaser toner on an
email it's not
good right and there they're like oh
there are a whole lot of other words
they often show in this spanning family
Mo's but they can sometimes show the
legitimate emails and I human can pretty
readily look at them because it's like
there's a whole lot of background
knowledge and context and stuff and it
could be hard to represent that to a
machine learning algorithm
there's also have you guys heard of
overfitting and underfitting so like um
so there's so overfitting and
underfitting it's like when you have a
ma or you have some training data
sometimes it may be when you over put it
it means it fits the training data very
well but it doesn't chip but it doesn't
generalize to other data very well under
fitting means that it doesn't really fit
the train it doesn't really fit any of
the data very well and the whole and
generally with just like with anything
in a computer machine learning it's
garbage in garbage out I mean it's not
specifically related to security but ok
hey have you ever heard heard of like
machine like algorithms that deal with
different races of people differently
like like like a smart sync or something
they've only tested it with people with
light skin and somebody with dark skin
tries to use it and it doesn't work in
very recently there is an article about
like an algorithm that recommended like
lower quality of care for African
Americans so so essentially the thing
that the thing that is it's not a silver
bullet and basically garbage in garbage
out there's nothing magical about it so
I just so right now I just have what I
just have some links and stuff if you
want to dig into it cheer so they get it
to it yourself you're welcome to and I'd
like to heavily credit the these are
these are some excellent resources this
is machine learning with security
protecting data systems with today
they're on algorithms this is an
O'Reilly book it's excellent
I got it enough I got it in a $15.00
Humble Bundle purchase at least the
electronic version the science book is
pretty good and that's actually free so
it's so you can you can get these for
inexpensive or free and they're very
good I uh I would say I used to these
heavily when I'm in the talk and then
there's towards data science which is
websites that's pretty good too and then
these are just some other good resources
you might want to use when you
and it any rate they thank you for your
patience are there any questions really
pretty much a time I think we're tying
but if you any questions you're able to
come up to me know how many time you can
spend on data classification before just
sending that to your machine learning
process because it seems to be critical
if if it if the data is not good like
your entire process at the end which
will fail or like don't do what you want
to do or or how do you acquire like good
sample of data or um you know we should
be very honest like so I've I was having
to start doing like some machine machine
learning and I knew nothing about the
domain and the data what I would really
do is I basically kit Google and see if
anybody else is seeing what kind of what
kind of analysis maybe not even machine
learning had been done on that day day
before what what do people look for and
tried to learn something about the
domain and what's been done in it that
would give me that would just give me a
starting point
uh-huh because they because like if you
just try to throw something that you
don't understand atom in a machine
learning algorithm that's gonna maybe
not work out very well and one thing you
can do we I try to show some graphs just
because I I mean my presentation it was
pretty mom deficient really and I
figured we could at least have so we at
least have some graphs and it's like if
you're if you're dealing with two and
three dimensions it's it's actually very
it's actually very very useful to this
visualize it like just graph what you
have and say does it make sense and you
can kind of do that in three dimensions
too once you get past that you get into
hyper planes and that's kind of hard for
humans to process hello
sorry and one common problem that what
I've read and seen while you know
implementing machine
not necessarily just for security but
for any domain is there's bias in in the
data oh yeah especially when they're
during the stage of gathering the data
is that also a prevalent problem when
when a career domain um you know I would
imagine I would imagine it could be I
mean I think that when we talk about
bias and bias and stuff like in some
ways racism is kind of a most obvious
and glaring one that we've seen like in
other domains of data science that are
not related to security but I would say
if you think about bias and feels like
preconceived notions and just idea just
preconceived notion about what you're
looking what you should look for and
what's important I would think somebody
could introduce bias into that very
easily just in fact even just what
somebody knows and what's familiar to
them does that make any sense yeah so in
your experience what would you actually
recommend in actually cleaning up that
bias or making sure it's not introduced
I've had there down the pipeline that's
actually that's actually very
interesting excellent question and the
best is the best thing I could maybe
think of as coming up with is coming up
with is is trying to see if somebody
else has approached the problem a
different way and comparing your
approach to their approach and seeing if
they saw something or thought about
something in a way that you didn't
because it's it's just like as far as
trying to get Pat past what's in my own
head the I feel like the best thing I
can do is get try to find some kind of
external input thank you