my name is kallu a potential and we'll
talk about a budget spot is an open
source project so let me start if you
have questions or where you wanna
interrupt me smell of a deal okay well
Who I am as I mention and what for in
tow I'm security researcher and working
set up in the group I'm not part of the
Intel security side so I need to do this
because most of the times people think
that I'm work for mcafee into sku
keyboard on workforce it has in truth
them so this is agenda next generate
next-generation security analytics we
will explain about apache spot
incubating project that we are working
in DC I will show you a demo of the
graphic user interface that we are
developed on the architecture behind a
bad spot our know our roadmap and the
question and answers then so we have
this billion of events each day in our
data centers right most of the time we
try to collect these particular Laxus
right from couple of sessions ago
mention we have trillions of events in
our data center right so how can we
manage that we start to thinking inside
of Intel and with another partners how
can we do this we require a scale as you
may see on the foil big data analytics
and also include much in learning in
order to detect that particular things
that are not visible for the sense for
the other tools that is well working
with signatures so basically this is
pretty much how a spot offers to you
guys
so this is the next generation security
tool basically as you may see on the
fall sem manage terabytes per day while
correlating login and staging different
sources firewalls IPS this luxe whatever
you you need right most of the same have
different connectors in order to well
it's not that information you can
analyze it basically but using big data
well gives you the next layer you can
store petabytes where they ingest this
particular information in a cluster
using HDFS or another technology in
order to you can query this information
manipulate generate script to whatever
you want right so and that is pretty
much the philosophy behind a budget but
you can check out the way I think
they'll donate the code a couple of
months ago to the Apache Incubator
project in order to well basically
everybody can use this particular
project in order to ingest whatever
information that you need I saw a couple
of talks yesterday that well basically
you need to store different layers of
information correlate the information
there make mixes well basically do
whatever you want on top of the of
Apache top Apache spot so as I mentioned
this is a bad spot I will do a demo of
the GUI as I mentioned before I'm
running docker containers is windows
machine and I basically don't know the
code that we have available on the
Apache for project is a container videos
don't let the container and you can see
let me move this
sure
that means the
the presentation
so this is a collusive interface that
Apache spot will offer to you guys as
you may see this is the result from one
day ingesting net flows in our corporate
environment we ingest 10 billions of
events each day and this is the results
that we obtained using machine learning
algorithms I will describe this party
later this is just to show you how the
buoy of a spot looks like basically on
the top we have something that we call
suspicious results the species results
basically is the result of our lda
algorithms that analyze these stem
billions of events well this is the
result of one day of our natural
infrastructure right basically we
collect this information we send it to
the cluster we analyze it and we present
this to the customer right I will just
show a couple of information that we
basically fine and looks interesting for
us so while the IP address was changes
because we can share our internal subnet
but anyway this is the result assuming
sig will have brung this is more
suspicious for the algorithm and we also
add information or context to this
particular network connection in order
to you can well go in this particular
results and start to look in this kind
of connection right we are using your
localization in order to well display
what what is the location of this
particular connection that is that you
are seeing inside of your network we
also use thread intelligent fit in this
case we are using the DI but you can use
whatever bendel you have internally in
order to add context right yesterday as
i mentioned before I listened that a
couple of guys need to do this kind of
hunting right have results and add
context using differ
sources right that is the philosophy
behind a budget but if you have a data
source and you want to add context and
you have the other data in different
sources you can mix experience while
basically use a machine learning
algorithm in order to select the results
that are interesting for you network
right so this is a pretty much the
interface will we display the results
for the community and we have also an
Edgar view in order to you can use it to
check what is the patterns inside of
your network right is you see something
there is not normal in your organization
you can just select it and go in deep
with to that particular communications
right so I don't know if you consider
well as you may see as soon as you a
little tip that particular information
if part will tell you the IP address if
you want to filter yeah you just click
and you can isolate that particular
information and display it over here if
you can check the details of that
particular net flow information you can
do it is not a big deal the other part
of the of the product is something that
we call notebooks the nach booth
basically is a Python code that you can
use in order to query delete the data in
this case we modify the bill because
most of our customers or most of our
guys from the community our guys that
are interested on security not too much
on and develop a Python script so if you
are at data scientist you have a Python
code is in order to you can query the
data that you have on the cluster right
and do different analysis let me go back
and basically the important part
earrings that that particular results
that budget for generates you can
basically score it and give these
particular feedback to the
machine learning in order to the next
day they don't show you these particular
results again if you escort this as a 3
this means that this is not important
for your organization so the next day
the machine learning just will avoid
that particular results and will except
to for show you interesting stuff like
stuff that is laying here and also if
you can start to generate thread
counting or well indicate that this is
maybe an attacking side of the
organization you can write this
particular connection as a one is call
it and basically the model of trade
intelligence of Apache pod will generate
this information and we win we want to
share with you this particular rating in
a word from map we will share this
information with other sources in order
to you can react properly so basically
this is our main use case collect net
flow and represent this information from
our week however as soon as we start to
develop this we some of the guys out
there tell us that will be really
interesting if we can ingest different
sources so we start to develop another
use cases like a DNS basically is the
same philosophy just using another data
source in these cases as I already
mentioned DNS you can do the same cell
right as soon as ekalaka your millions
or billions of DNS labs on the clutter
the machine learning algorithm will just
display you the 220 suspicious connects
for dns and you can start the hunting
from field as you may see is the similar
approach just with a different data
source like
like you can also write a dns connection
and start to catching DNS common common
and controls over DNS to Nell's
different attacks that you can discover
and well also the bad guys can use in
order to exfiltrate information using
this particular protocol our next use
case that we are developing we are
finishing right now is practice we are
ingesting proxy locks in the Apache spot
platform in order to do similar stuff as
an excellent and DNS life so this is
pretty much the graphical user interface
of a budget pot you can use it and play
with it we could this is a docker
container you just pull it and see the
information right but let me return to
the earth to the presentation so this is
a pretty much architect to that we are
managing behind the scenes on a budget
spot as you may see we have that sausage
different that are focused on a budget
pot we have net flow that comes from
routers and switches we have dns couple
of this locks comes from comes from bra
and a couple of blocks for the dns comes
from windows also we basically have
collectors these particular collectors
and check
okay these particular collectors
basically are demons running in Linux
that injures the information to wear a
file system in this case in its HDFS we
are using Cloudera are in order to
basically polish this information and
after data right now we are using this
back in order to analyze all these
results and generate the information
that i show you previously right so this
is a pretty much information the the
architecture behind the scenes and we
also are using the GUI that i will
describe a couple of minutes ago and
this is based on cloudera but you can
use Hadoop or whatever other technology
that you want map map are or any other
technology that supports hgss you can
use it basically we are just developing
obviously the collectors how can we
process the data stories just hgss and
we are using back right previously we
are using MPI's in order to analyze and
generate the suspicious results what
right now is the code is just in this
back first and well we have on the road
map another integration with different
Intel security products we will show you
this in a couple of weeks and that is
premature this is the architecture
behind the scenes for the Apache spot
projects as I mentioned we are using
earlier in order to detect species the
deck and generate these two species
connect
okay this is another part of the
architecture of a party spot as you may
see we can collect information from the
CM also if you have a gem and you can
ingest this particular information on a
project what you can do it we have a
three connectors right now but we are
working in order to develop another
connectors like a Jimmy see you down
another use cases that we want to
develop this standpoint give more user
context this means that we want to well
basically go to whatever authentication
source that you have and basic Kali's
write this information in order to as
soon as you have the suspicious results
you may know which machine is doing that
particular traffic on which user is
logging in that particular machine like
so we are having also another initiative
there is another one and that it's a
very interesting is this one open data
models open data models would be huge
table where you can basically write
whatever you want no matter if is a use
case from DNS proxy IPS firewall raw
data whatever you can basically write
the information there and add context on
top of this particular flow data in
order to the Apache spot we can give you
more information as you as soon as you
have it on the graphical user interface
well what a couple of hours ago well
basically if the guide from a talaxian
mentioned that they are using kappa on
amazon we are also trying to do this in
order to ingest faster the information
that we are collecting on the closer so
that would be our next step use kappa
stream such things in order to write
faster and replicate information in the
HDFS side and for whatever other source
that they needed that we needed right
and as I mentioned before right now
these parties already working we change
the machine learning code to run on back
and this give us more more response time
before we are taking like an eight hours
in order to analyze 1,000,000,000 not
ten billions of students right now we
are taking just three hours in order to
analyze them billions of event this is a
net flow this is just mud flow we are
analyzing another kind of sources like
dns and proxy but we need to measure how
many times we will consume in order to
generate this species result so this is
a current effort so this is how a budget
for the leaders to you as i mention data
and analytics platform open data model
we will show this particular to project
in a couple of weeks in RSA so if you
want to contribute to the open data
model you you are welcome because we
need a lot of expertise on the flip side
so I I see that you have a lot of ideas
related with this and if you want to
contribute this is an open source
project based on the Apache foundations
of your work on earth then you go back
so what and in this case we are very
tied to the cybersecurity use cases so
like with hunting incident detection and
resolution a lot of things that you
previously mentioned in other features
and also or in face-to-face meetings
that I have yesterday with some of you
guys we are offering this to you however
we have another use cases in the
financial institutions also and medical
institutions that they are not using a
spotter cyber security tool that you are
using a spot in order to Detective Rosen
things that are not common instead of
the day organization so we are just
trying to not share the Apache food idea
with you for the cybersecurity side
however we can use these particular
tools in other use cases not not tied to
cybersecurity so this is a our roadmap
and the idea that we have right now in
mind also if you want to see another
kind of information on a patch it
forward you need another few tools on
the tool you can send us emails and we
can prioritize these because this is a
not right now this is a project of the
Apache Apache community right so if you
subscribe to the community you can send
ideas or requests and changement in
order to oh well basically and hence the
product so and on the top you will see
and you can read that we need to enhance
the machine learning algorithms
basically 0 which cali right now we are
using just one lda in order to detect
but we we know that just one algorithms
will not detect everything so we are
trying to enhance that particular pillar
on the
on this other brother the second one is
as a you're already see we need more
Marco lactose in order to ingest
different data in the Apache spot and
correlate these particular information
instead of the product in order to
provide the incident response faith to
our community we have also what we
require some of the our customers
requires root cause analysis that
involves that we need to work and
integrate with another with other view /
tools in order to do forensic analysis
collector locks from sources that we are
not collecting right now so we are
working on that also as you may see on
the site whether scope of analysis means
that we need to integrate more and more
data no matter if is structural onyx
structures so we are working in order to
provide that to you guys and as I
mentioned before the other huge topic
that we have right now it's open data
model we are at creating this particular
model in order to work basically have
give a robust platform in order to you
can collect whatever information you
want and correlate the information
inside of Apache use you the idea is
that you don't need to go to other
sources in order to find that particular
information and well this is premature
get involved without as you may see we
have different areas of the project of
collectors machine learning we have also
the graphical user interface and well
they develop of the open data model if
you want to work share with without your
knowledge develop or give us ideas you
can contact us you can go to the slab
channel
or widows and that is pretty much all
guys I don't know if you have questions
this is a couple of guys that are
working on these particular projects
gaps I projects in 25 very clavicle or
obviously Cloudera and what if you want
to share them be part of a participatory
your contacts so questions
chip
right
well they're fierce I say two weeks we
have start just to train the algorithm
just say into the machine learning
algorithms that this is not important
for for me and you'll save it right
after this particular two weeks I start
to see this kind of information where I
can and detect things that are not
common in my organization so I just need
to train a couple of days the algorithm
in order to start to seeing results
right I see results from the few days
but maybe most of the results will be
let me remove the filter food will be
not available right but after two weeks
I will see a really cool suspicious
results in order to start the hunting
life so it's very useful because well as
you already mentioned 10 billions of
events per day is not is not feasible
right to analyze and well basically
gooiest we train the other in just a
couple of days one week two weeks and
after that we start seeing this kind of
results where we can start to hunt yep
I don't worry
anything else right now know that is why
we are trying to engage the community in
order to find that data scientist that
can give us more Marines or ideas around
which algorithms we can use in order to
detect more and more right because right
now we are using just one well the code
is already on the underneath of the
Apaches two projects you can check their
the what LVL algorithm there is
basically in the back right now if I
remember correctly you can execute it
over your data and that is pretty much
all so if you want to contribute or
modify something out over more things
you can work basically go to the flap
channel be a committed on the project
and we can work with you yeah let me
show let me go there is black dot Apache
but I so you can talk
so I'm to help
nope thank you very much
[Applause]