so the purpose of this talk at the
beginning is to cover like why I how to
do this and then I will talk a little
bit about the audibility F basics the
majority of the talk is going to be a
very practical walk through on the
always testing guide and the I the items
from it that we can test without
permission legitimately unless we do
this I will be showing how to do it with
all WTF so I am a Spanish guy I've been
working in the IT industry for more than
12 years the first seven my conduit
security was mostly from a defensive
perspective and in the last five I've
been focusing more on the offensive side
of things so let's say a little bit what
the problem with pen testing is at the
moment right at Brooklyn 2009 Chris
Gates
explained how bad guys operate with this
slide this is a funny slide but it's
really true right so bad guys we will
first discover what makes the company
money they will discover what's valuable
to the attacker then they'll do whatever
it takes and they will steal it
the part that is the most important for
us here is this party in the middle to
do whatever it takes implies a level of
determination that is extremely
difficult to achieve for a pen tester
and the reason for that is that pen
testers have to write reports we have
time and scope constraints the systems
we are testing are increasing in
complexity right so the more complex
system is that the more time we need to
test it properly but on top of all these
customers are really willing to pay for
in every reasonable testing time so the
bottom line here is either we do
something about this so we are not going
to be the ones find that the
vulnerabilities is going to be the bad
guys okay so as I was wondering how to
solve this problem I was thinking like
maybe at this problem has been solved
before in history right you know like
history repeats itself over and over so
let's look at Spartans as if they were
attackers 2500 years ago the Spartans
were a kind of warrior that nobody
wanted to fight and the reason for these
was that these guys were killed as
babies if they had any sort of defect
they started military training at age 7
they had to survive in the countryside
with only a knife as part of the
training and then as a group they were
really outstanding as well because they
had this fighting system called the
Phalanx they will line up the shields
building a wall and they will point
dispersed over
the enemy like this so this system was
tremendously successful for centuries it
was really successful against the
persons with the infantry and Aviva next
inspired Alexander the Great in his
conquest and then in colonial in
colonial times
Pike systems also partly inspired on
this so the question is we're mostly
like sedentary I probably don't have
military training and I know this is
impossible but if there was a room full
of Spartan next door how could we win ok
if they are better than us and we are
the same number more or less how could
we win does anybody know how she exactly
what's the answer ok so this is how the
Athenians did it okay the context for
this is that for the Spartans the
Athenians were really lame they were
losers they have no word their level of
skill but the Athenians won and they did
not win because they were better or they
had more soldiers or anything they were
not no more soldiers than the Spartans
they won because they fought in a
different way they fought in a way the
Spartans didn't expect they cheated in
fact they didn't fight at all they threw
things okay so how can we apply this to
pentesting why not start shooting before
the battle right why not start testing
we had permission why not I continuously
shoot while we analyze information in
parallel and why not prepare more
shootings without being noticed
okay this is what we are going to do in
this talk so the offensive testing
framework which is all WTF basically
it's based on these principles okay it
will run tools for you this is a
configuration file that defines how to
run them these are just a few of the
ones to run it will run tests directly
as well it takes us a knowledge
repository so we have like a lot of cool
research that is being done by very
smart people and they post like proof of
concept limbs
resource links and stuff like so it
tries to be sort of a wiki for this and
then a part where I think it really
shines is helping the human analysis so
it provides an interactive report that
allows you to fly the importance it
manages that the output of all the tools
ran it organized in a
transid in a logical way and it gives
you an interface where you can pace your
screenshots your notes and it helps you
with report writing as well so let's see
how this works okay because otherwise
this is so it will be too theoretical so
in this first example I'm just running
the passive plugins and only the spiders
robots and clawless
ok I'm against accounts.google.com so
this is how it looks like and that's the
screen doing the shooting but there
pentas will work from this screen
ok now I'm focusing on that then that's
the passive plugging and in here you can
see the diesel entries for their robots
the txt file you see there they account
disallow ok and you have all these
transaction information I'll explain
this in a bit more detail afterwards
this is just to give you a little feel
about how this works ok now let's look
at this one so now I'm running all the
passive plugins against the same site
and you can see wait hold on a sec why
is this not map and you can see that
this is the screen that does all the
shooting ok this is doing what the
Athenians did this is like throwing the
arrows ok but the pentester is really
not looking at these dependencies that
works on the interactive report ok the
printers the works here so you can see
at the moment there's only two plugins
that have been run and now if i refresh
the report because this is a partial we
have 84 plugins ok have finished so now
we have more information to work with
and using the wrench here we can filter
out what's going to be displayed so I'm
removing the external plugins and now we
only have 12 for all the passive plugins
that have been run so you have this
interactive report to interact with the
information right so it organizes all
these for you and you see them the test
was still running in the terminal window
ok I'm not just another quick demo to
give a little bit of background this is
a little bit more complex if you do
quiet these are all the pre-engagement
safe options I'm extremely urgent in
discovery and I'm running it against
three targets so there's one URL another
URL another URL now this is the shooting
window so it's doing all the shooting
like the athenians
and now I'm enabling the external
plugins again okay
so now we have 84 plugins so you can see
there 84 that's only one URL at the
moment because this was a partial the
last time we refreshed and now when i
refresh we have all the hosts they want
from before accounts at google.com and
the three other hosts that we rendered
the the test against so as long as you
run all WTF from the same directory it
will merge the results from before in
iterations and in this case because
robots the text is fun you have all the
disallow entries as links and you have
this open all in test for your
convenience so as you open all in
perhaps you can review all the disallow
entries I'm just closing the tabs that
show nothing okay so that's just what
I'm doing there and now I see one of the
desire entries has an administrator
screen right so I can take a snapshot of
this and Kay snapshot has this option to
take the snapshot of only a region of
the screen which is nice so I'm taking
the snapshot of only that area okay and
I'm copying it to the clipboard so
that's important and now I have that
screenshot in the clipboard and I can
click Edit here and I can already start
there right in the report okay I can do
like an administrative interface was
found on the following URL okay so you
don't have permission yet but you're
already like looking at these things and
I can paste the screenshot right there
this is a preview pane and this is the
editor right how it looks in the editor
so now I can leave it as a very teaser
I'm giving it a medium severity just for
illustration purposes and this is a
fever someone be showing that
okay when I click this it was nothing
and then with the magic bar it will
generate our report stop here it will
generate the report with their notes
from the human this is not a stupid to
report disease they report from the
feedback from the human what the
screenshots from the proof of concept of
the human after vetting the tools okay
so by using the system were the tools
and the human work in parallel we can
get the best out of both
okay we get the automation part like the
humanists the tools do the stupid work
and the human can analyze the
information from the tools verified and
take proof of concept screenshots and
using the magic bar you get like the
information you entered in an easy to
copy/paste way into your real report for
your customer so this will be helpful
now to understand the rest of the
presentation I think that's the end of
it yes okay so let's move on ok so what
we're trying to do is to leverage the
fact that half of the items in the
always testing guide right 48.5 percent
can be performed to some degree without
permission and all the relative does
more things than just web it has like
Metasploit like auxiliary modules but we
won't cover those in this talk for the
web plugins we have these five types so
passive plugins will test the target
mostly using third-party sites we are
not sending any any packets directly to
the target semi passive to visit the
site but the traffic is normal looking
so it's the same as a normal user like
visiting the site we are not doing
anything aggressive and then a great
plugin sorry a little bit special what
they do is they search on Heather's and
HTML body and things like this and
external plugins are a little bit weird
the point of this is that I know our pen
testers will run more tools that are run
by other Latia for example you will run
tools like burp or a SAP or whatever and
you will definitely run you should run
like more tools than around here so the
external plugins allow you to leverage
the interface that we just saw for
report writing and organizing your
screenshots for anything that you found
outside of Oh WTF so that's that's why
they are called external so anything you
find outside of authoritive you can
still leverage the interactive report
okay so what we're trying to do is
there's two basic stages in pen testing
so there's the pre-engagement where you
are negotiating with the customer what's
insko what's not and blob
and they engagement where you really
have permission to test when we're
trying to do is to move as much work as
possible from here into here so that
hopefully when we get to this stage we
can do the best job we really can so
let's look a little bit at robots.txt
analysis in this case we should always
consider the context okay so if we have
a website and the website is only has a
login page then that website is only
provided an authenticated content that
should always have like user agent star
disallow everything okay doesn't really
want to be indexed by Google for first a
fix this or anything this is how it
looks in the audibility of reports so
you see it was not found you can see the
HTTP status and you can see it in the in
the title but you always have like these
links you can see the full transaction
with this with this you can see it in
the site this is a link to the URL on
the site this is the raw request into a
sense the HTTP response headers and the
HTTP response body so you have all these
links to dive deeper if if you wish now
if it is found we saw this this allowed
entry is open all in tabs as we saw in
the demo and the file is also saved in
in the disk for your entertainment
afterwards and another thing that
automotive glass is it will query like
third-party sites so to LaMotta
recirculate info is a very good site for
robots.txt analysis the problem with it
is that it only takes parameters through
post so the first request I got was well
why doesn't this link work and I said
well because it takes it through post so
I'm kind of like doing a link that will
query it and say yeah but you could send
a post request and say okay well send
the post request so the next complaint I
got is from mark I don't know if he's in
the audience or not mark was saying
Abraham where do you have Google
Analytics in the audibility of report
and I'm like I don't have Google
Analytics so well what's happening was
that the HTML content from tool the
materiality info was in the
with your report which is bad so that's
like cross-site scripting right like I'm
embedding unsanitized HTML so to solve
this problem I put a challenge in my
blog an HTML filter since February
nobody has been man enough to hack it so
you're welcome to try if you do hack it
please let me know and I'll try to fix
it and after that layer of Defense
that's an html5 sandbox iframe for there
just in case and another thing I do is I
save the file in another directory so in
Firefox that does not let you access
html5 local storage which would be where
the audibility f review is so that's
just a little him there okay this is how
their review works so you have this
full-blown editor where you can like put
your fancy tables and links and do your
all your reporting that you can then you
paste your screenshots and all this
stuff that we saw and then the key is
like when you use the magic bar it
removes all the plug-in stuff and it
just takes like whatever severity you
are trying to add each thing and you can
copy/paste this in your report I mean we
saw it in the demo just to highlight now
for search in discovery there's a bunch
of tools that I ran and all these tools
like the output is saved in different
files all the plugins have this browse
button you can click on it and you can
review the information you can define
how tools are run like the exact command
line that is used in this file so in the
other whatevs directory wherever you
have it profiles resources default that
CFG the slides are going to be available
so don't even try to write all this down
don't worry like all the links and
everything I'm going to cover will be
available this is how the summary of a
tool that's random looks like so the
first 25 lines are shown you have links
here to view more information and this
is the full command that was run exactly
with all the switches everything and you
can tweak it if you figure out a better
way to run a tool please let me know and
I'll try to fix it and that's all that's
really useful here is the harvester the
harvester will find email addresses
limiting information employee
information host names and all this this
is very useful because
as we saw at the beginning it is about
preparing more shootings so we with the
email addresses we can prepare our
brute-forcing dictionaries we can
customize brute-forcing dictionaries for
when we have permission have something
against the target that is more likely
to work right like real users that exist
and things like this and the same for
for the other things now for metadata
metadata is really useful I I really
like Foca but is not callable from the
command line so I cannot integrate with
it for now
and what I'm doing instead is interact
with meta go field
ok this is the whole command that ran
and that's like the same way to review
it but the data information is very
useful because you might have like
operating system information printers
like internal shares in the network and
things like this that you can leverage
now a big limitation for the entry
points is that at the moment the inbound
proxies not fully working yet but a very
strong point is that because all ability
of runs a lot of tools become it can
scrape the urls found by every of the
tools right so all these urls are put
into this potential URLs and then during
active testing all the relatives will
visit them and will put them here so
this has like a lot less false positives
because this after all over these visits
each of the links so it will really see
if it is if that URL exists or not and
it classifies them in different
categories for for you ok so this is the
transaction log so you see you can see
like all the transactions that were run
how long they took the status the URL
and you have links for the sides full
transaction and all this this is how
full transaction looks like so it's just
text and another cool thing is that you
can specify an outbound proxy so one
thing you should always do is to run a
tactical faster write a tool like very
poor sap so because so WTF will grab the
URLs from all tools run and it will
visit them as it visits them because you
specify that album proxy it will pass
all those URLs found by all tools
automatically to the tactical faster to
a tool like burp and this includes tools
like deer buster as well for I'd like
you will obviously run that during
active testing but like there's like a
lot of URLs that will be passed to this
like automatically just by doing this so
that keeps things simple I think that's
a very powerful concept now for the
fingerprint we can obviously try to use
this but there's other ways for example
Oh WTF we'll run a tool called word web
and weather has this aggression
parameter that you can set to 1 and when
you do that the test will be semi
passive so it's basically just visiting
the site and and try to identify
fingerprinting information and give you
this nice summary now all WTF itself
we'll run some statistics for you so it
will try to look for HTTP headers that
might reveal fingerprinting information
and it tells you how many of the
transactions found fingerprinting
information so this is like a review
panel that is very like standard for
most plugins so for each of the values
found you're provided with a search for
vulnerability search box so you have
like Apache or whatever so you know
that's like two values that were found
with the fingerprinting headers and for
each of them you get this box and these
D sellings like to the popular search
for exploits right and you have this
search all for your convenience so as
you click on search all this all these
sites opening tabs so you have like
exploit DB e national vulnerability
database or SVD v4 security focus I
prefer the Google search so that's
what's opened then explicit subnet is
kind of an all-in-one site this combines
information from security focus with
Domestos database and others and for the
passive plugging we have the same box
but in this case is empty and you
provided links to a few sites that are
useful to retrieve fingerprinting
information passively without touch
the target so net craft very popular it
identifies the operating system as well
as some operating system fingerprinting
and other things build with is a bit
less known this will identify things
like widgets libraries and it is very
useful for the pen tester because it
really extends the attack surface of the
of the application now show them another
tool that has been covered to death it
allows us to search on headers and stuff
and a little bit more innovative concept
here is that passive plugins will also
late give you suggestions so audibility
have will build commands against the
target and it will run them but
sometimes passive plugins will just give
the commands for you as suggestions so
in this case for the fingerprint and
it's giving you suggestions so if the
fee is them if you identified that the
CMS is WordPress maybe you want to run
WP scan for plugging enumeration and
that's how that looks of CMS Explorer or
dear Buster or whatever so you have all
these options and then you can decide
which one you want to run and you can
paste that in a terminal window and then
as soon as you have permission you hit
enter and you have that running saving a
few minutes at least so that's the idea
to try to save as much time as possible
of course this is not everything that
can be done with the fingerprint
something you should always try to do is
to replicate a customer's environment so
if it is a closed source or a commercial
software you can probably run a trial
version or something if not if it's
open-source sometimes you can download
it from the project page if not all -
Chrome or Google is your friend
but the bottom line is to try to
replicate the environment once we have
the environment or something close we
can run static analysis tools and try to
run exploits against this environment in
our own lab of line so we will have a
very good idea about what's likely to
work and what's not by all this work
that is being done offline trying to
hack ourselves in your lab with the
customers environment for discovery
we're trying to find things
like DNS records hostname some things
like this I'm just going to cover a
couple of these links so Rob tex.com
very useful site it gives you this nice
graphical representation of the DNS
records so you can see 0 web of security
com is hosted by HP and probably in
Austin Texas so you can see like all
this very easily from the DNS records
who is the main tools.com and all other
who is sites are useful because normally
the person that registers who is the
main is an important person in the
company so this can be useful in
pentesting to feed our brute force and
dictionaries and to do some targeted
social engineering as well we can do
even some limited service scam like port
scanning with central lobster net so
that's how that looks like and is by no
means comprehensive but it can give you
some ideas and this is all completely
passive now for error messages we can
search if in search engines they you
know like Google has found any error
messages on the side and the audibility
of approach for this because I don't
like the whole API key issue is to do
what everybody was doing my hand which
is to run a huge Google search that will
match like anything if it's there and
then what you do is if you find results
you can tweak it a bit until you get
what you want and if you find no results
you just move on because there's nothing
there so in this case we we can see
there like some of the error messages
have been found using this blanket
search for SSL one of the popular sites
is SSL labs Chrome if you use this site
please check this box because the last
thing you want is there to make the
results of the SSL configuration of the
customer that paid you public so just
stick that box that is how the
audibility of report will generate the
link for SSL labs with this box ticked
and it gives you this pretty graph so
you should always try to paste this in
your report looks professional so
another thing to look for SSL is strict
Transport Security so you can see the
transaction statistics in this case
this header was not found okay and so
you can see it wasn't found and then if
it's finally tells you in how many
transactions it was transfer it was only
found on - and this was a unique value
fan okay so the only unique values per
header this is all about like sharing
statistics first then showing only
unique values and try to say the
Panthers there as much time as possible
without having to go through a lot of
duplicates so this is a link to an
example transaction where this value was
found
now I'm going only going to explain
these ones because this is going to
repeat so one thing you should always do
is to look for HTML comments so for this
the WTF gives you the statistics so how
many comments were found how many
transactions matched and then you have
three options you can review the unique
as text review the unique as HTML or
review all as HTML so unique as text is
very self-explanatory is just grabbing
all the comments doing the unique of
that and showing the comments to you
uniqueness hTML is exactly the same the
only difference is that is showing you
links to an example transaction where
that comment was found because you might
want to say to the customer where that
was and all s hTML is exactly the same
as this but you'll have links like to
all the transactions where each of the
comments was found in a similar fashion
to this you can like review CSS and
JavaScript comments single line
JavaScript comments PHP source code and
ASP source code now for backup plan and
reference and reference files and this
is very similar to the old like Google
hugging stuff right like show there's a
lot of blanket searches to look for this
and a little bit more innovative is the
concept of classifying URLs so all of
the URLs audibility have notes about it
will classify them and ones classified
as files that are not images or anything
are shown here for your review so in
this case you can see it's found like
admin clients and community annual
report which looks like look like
sensitive things
I mean interfaces are really powerful
okay I mean interfaces and the keys to
the kingdom if you can get into an L
mean interface it's pretty much game
over it's so the first thing is to look
if if they are present or not and
there's a few a couple of blankets urges
for this and in this case I found that
the customer was running a CMS called
Sitefinity so the next thing you should
do is to look for default passwords of
course and I could see like the default
location for the CMS is /i Affinity the
default username is having the default
password seems to be admin as well and
of course to trade these credentials you
need permission but I'm just showing the
impact here so by doing this which is
very lame just to search for a default
password I could get in and then I can
create users create pages so at this
point is no longer the customer site it
is my site okay so this is something
that should always be very high in your
priority list just because the risk is
much higher okay Dell the the skill
level to do this is very low and the
impact is really high so you should
always try this one of the first things
in a test for the HTTP methods we can
send an innocent options request this is
not necessarily very reliable but it can
give us a feeling about what's
potentially there and we can then verify
this passively with hexillion comm has a
couple of methods so in this case we can
test completely passively through this
third-party site that the site is were
able to cross a trace you know case
playing the trace back this is another
very basic test so if this a password
field and the URL is HTTP passwords have
been sent in clear text which is a
problem and you are given apart from
this what we saw before we're given the
number of total insecure matches this is
the number of password fields where the
URL was HTTP or HTTPS so that's quite
basic as you are reviewing the site you
might see popups like this so if you ask
for credentials on the URI HTTP of
course that's also a problem and to
prepare the attack these are two tools
that can be handy for shipping as a sole
strip so
to always consider those now this is
very interesting that this guy got
called mahadesh with a very well known
German security researcher and he was
trained to be a nice guy okay he found a
vulnerability in Firefox and he's trying
to report it as he's doing that he's
trying to copy his friend Garrett Haake
so he's typing his email address and he
could feel like the list of all users in
the Mozilla site so he was really pissed
off about this and tweeted like angry
like what's hot muzzle ah you know but
the thing is the point remains that by
just looking at the site but just using
it you will see the vulnerabilities you
are not doing anything illegal here just
using the site and you can see a u2 the
numeration problem just by using the
site a little bit more subtly example of
this I found in pen test of mine I was
assessing a sports competition site and
it had a public function called
something like search participant so I
wondered like well maybe I can search
for nothing and get the list of all the
participants so I try that but he didn't
allow me so I said well maybe I can
search for a then B then C and it
allowed me to do that so I did the
unique of that I stripped out the HTML
then I convert or CSV and as I finished
my report my test I gave like the full
report to the customer and a spreadsheet
containing all the sports competition
participants not only for the
competition they were worried about but
for all competitions even previous ones
so it only took a few minutes until I
got a phone call asking like dude how
did you do this I did the unique and all
this and the point here is that I think
I only got that phone call because I
send that information in a spreadsheet
so you have to think that business
people work with spreadsheets every day
so if you give them a spreadsheet they
will understand risk better okay if you
give the same information in a text file
they will not get it but if you give it
in a spreadsheet especially if it has
charts it will work way better okay so
that's a tip for you so if you dump the
whole database give them spread
and you know they will take you more
seriously now for guessing the usernames
you will see the vulnerability in the
usernames they're giving you to test so
if they're based on numbers you know you
can look through that if it's based on
names and surnames you know you can have
a dictionary of names and another
surnames I'll look through that and if
it's a CMS CMS's have normally like
default usernames so you can probably
Google for those now to complete is one
of those interesting vulnerabilities
because by default if you don't do
anything you are vulnerable okay what we
are trying to look here for is you know
there's these fields like passwords
credit cards and things like this that
should never be allowed to be cashed in
the browser right so there are two
levels to disable this when it's at the
Forum level but usually the best balance
between security and usability is to do
it at the input level where you would
disallow cashing of passwords or credit
cards but you will still allow the
browser to memorize things like the name
or whatever so you are giving the same
panel like to review all this and a way
to illustrate this for business people
or like in general to developers is that
you can log in you log out and then you
click the back button until you get a
page like this probably that asks you to
submit the login form again so if you
submit the login form again and you're
logged in that means that in the browser
history and the password is there and
that means that the you know if that
computer is hacked by someone they can
steal the password from their browser
history
again I think the some Metasploit
plugins produces well like to steal
passwords from the browser history so
that's why god is a problem in password
reset forms you will see the
vulnerability in the quality of the
questions for example price Hilton got
hacked because everybody knows the name
of her pet and that was the question she
chose for something so you know so
things like this I quite obviously you
see in the quality of the questions now
for the browser cache this is a little
bit similar to autocomplete so
your logging and then you see their
homepage okay now you log out and you
see the login page if you click the back
button and you see the home page again
that means that authenticated content
the home page is cached in the browser
you should really see these page has
expired error or all the login page okay
Google Reader actually to the login page
for example if you select the in content
that means that they don't have the
browser browser cache directly spin says
properly so there's a number of tools
that can help us here but the way this
works is really that in HTTP 1.1 cache
control should be set to no cache it
needs to be 1.0 pragma should be set to
no cache and expire should be in the
past but normally what happens is we
have sites that really care about
security and have back bounties and
everything like Google so Google is
doing both setting cache control to know
cache pragma no cache and experts in the
past so they are doing both HTTP 1.1 and
hd10 and most sites will just not do
anything which means caching is allowed
in the old ability of interactive report
this looks like this so you can see the
number of transactions that set this and
you can see the unique values here so
you can see by showing the unique the
pentester has to reveal a lot less
information okay we are not reviewing
the 200 transactions we are only seeing
the 3 only unique value set for these
three cookies another way to do the same
thing is through meta tags so meta tags
they work in exactly the same way so
cache control no cache ok it's the same
thing but instead of being HTTP headers
they are in the HTML body of the page so
you should always look for those as well
now captures the first thing is to look
if they are being in use or not and you
just like Google search for that and you
can try to break this offline so you can
try to download the image and break it
you can see if this has retro compassed
if you can identify the software version
of the capture you can try to look for
vulnerabilities on it and this for your
convenience search for vulnerability
search box with a usual search all
button and a couple of links to external
tools that
help you here in our system management
some people call base64 encryption which
is math encryption so sometimes like
people put like stuff but it's encoded
in the cookies so this is just an
example from the OS testing guide and
there's a couple of tools that can help
us here so Gareth Hays is a very
well-known uk-based security researcher
and he has this very cool site called
hack vector hack vector is very good
unuseful for pen testers for a variety
of reasons the first reason is that it's
a website so you don't have to install
anything and you have like a lot of
functionality here so in this case I'm
using how to decode rupees for that and
you have a lot of other decoding options
I like how to decode on how to decode
repeat but you can also specify like by
hand many different formats and it can
do like a lot more things now another
situation for this is that sometimes you
you will have web server where web
server farm right so you have like a lot
of web servers and in front of them
there's a load balancer so as you visit
them the site the load balancer stores
in the cookie okay you are going to talk
to this guy here to this web server
again it will put the IP address and the
port for that way observer in the cookie
okay and that means that from there on
you're always going to go to that web
server like this okay through the load
balancer so rasoolís with a very
well-known spanish security researcher
released this tool called f5 big IP
cookie decoder and if you see a string
like this chances are that the they are
the IP address and the port so with this
tool you can like decode these values
and see internal IPs and ports just by
you know reading the cookies that they
are setting now for cookie attributes
the most important are probably secure
an HTTP only this was the second time I
was testing the site so you can see the
developers did a good job
so the J's session IV had HTTP only and
secure they paid attention to what I
said in the first report and they do
right but what happened was they started
to use this spring framer thing that has
I remember me cookie
was value for more than a month and this
happened not to have either HTTP only or
security okay so this was even more
important than the session cookie and
didn't have any of the tool the
important point here is that the the
attacker only needs one cookie to win
and you know like you should always pay
attention that all the cookies that
required have all this set this how it
looks in the automotive report like the
unique values for the headers and let's
break down by attributes which might be
a little bit easier to read so you can
see Security's not files to be only not
fine whatever so you can see all that
now session fixation is not only when
you can set the session ID from the URL
okay so it used to be the case like a
few years back that you could do this
but as they are giving you credentials
to test you can see if the session ID
changes or not if the session ID doesn't
change like here that is a problem
because you can set cookies with
JavaScript you can fool the user to type
JavaScript in the URL bar and this
worked against Facebook users not long
ago you can leverage an existing
cross-site scripting vulnerability to
set the cookie as well so as long as
this doesn't change that means there's a
potential session fixation issue and all
you need to know release to see that the
session ID doesn't change when you log
in another a couple of examples from the
field
you don't like sessions in the URL in
post in HTML they should never be there
they should always be in a cookie and
this was like I was testing website and
it was getting user information from a
third party site and all it was sending
was just the user ID so I know just by
looking at this request that there's no
tokens there's nothing there's no
authentication I can have a loop that
that retrieves all the users information
just by using this URL so you see the
vulnerability in the in the URLs
themselves now for cross-site scripting
we can look for clients privacy
protections like x-axis as protection or
ex-cons and security policy for
dom-based xss we can look at the source
code
we have the source code in your browser
so we can look at that and get my SEC
and the other thing is you can even do
active testing so if the vulnerability
exists after the has symbol then
whatever you type in here is not going
to go to the target so you can do active
testing as long as the vulnerability
exists after this symbol for secret
injection you can search for you know if
Google has found many security injection
for you any sequel error messages and
for server side includes we can see if
there are any server side includes
directives so it will search for things
like this and then you can see if they
are in use or not and which methods seem
to be enabled for denial of service
because all the transactions are timed
what we can do is to look for the
slowest ones the slowest transactions
are the best potential best denial of
service attack points because you're
looking for that asymmetry excuse me
where you do very little work and the
target website does a lot of work so
this is just pointing the potential best
targets for this now for a web service
information gathering they were thing
that works the best is that Google at
the Google search the one heed
alternative is a bit better than that
and for WSDL you will see the
vulnerability in the in the methods
themselves okay so if it's called
something I get credit card download
database test database so things like
this should be very high in your
priority list test as soon as you have
permission and I want to briefly touch
on the same origin policy so if you
visit the random site on the internet
the same origin policy says this random
site can send a request to my bank to my
Google account and to everything else
and the browser is going to
automatically send the cookies okay
because of this so what's not allowed is
to read their response back okay so this
part is what's not allowed but this is
allowed so they can send that request
and the browser is going to send the
cookies because of that they consider
best defense against cross-site request
forgery
is too
have an anti cross-site request forgery
token so yes you can send a request but
if you don't guess my anti crosshair
request forgery token that request is
not going to be processed okay so
because of this if there is no one to
cross-site request forgery token without
trying anything we already know that
this course a request forgery because
there's no mechanism to prevent it if
there's no mechanism to prevent it it's
there so this is this can be done very
stealthily and usually you will find you
will try to leverage cross-site request
forgery in things like add user or
administrator or things like this web
service replay is very similar you will
need something like an ant across a
request forgery like thing and if
there's nothing to prevent it
you know replay as possible for
cross-site flashing although here we'll
give you a few links to search for
silverlight files flash files to look
for policy files and this is how these
searches look like you can of course
decompile the flash files I look at the
source and try to look for
vulnerabilities on that flare and platon
are a couple of tools that can help us
here and of course you can run static
analysis tools Adobe SWF investigator
was released last month I think and then
an oldie but a goodie is that we are
scanned as well so you have like links
for those there with flash files
unlike dom-based xss you cool you can
always put the hash symbol and it will
accept whatever parameters you put after
that so because it's the hash symbol
this is not going against the target and
the flash file will see it so you can do
active testing against flash files
without permission by using the hash
symbol trick now we covered a little bit
the same origin policy and the thing is
these three technology is allowed to
relax this so flash Silverlight and
html5 cross-origin resource sharing all
three provide mechanisms to relax this
okay so flat assume lights have policy
files for this and html5 cross-origin
resource sharing can relax the same
origin policy with HTTP headers so let's
look at that
for Flash and Silverlight automotive
will try to retrieve the policy files
and then you can really you can review
it and what we are looking for is
something like this for example so this
is allowing any website so you've issued
random site on the Internet and then the
random site on the Internet can send a
request to the your Gmail account or
whatever and by having this this means
that request sent to the target the site
that has this policy file can be read
okay because of this because they can be
read you can send a fare a first request
assuming that anticrist a request
forgery tokens are in place you can send
a first request that retrieves the
Antichrist a request forgery token and
then you can read the token from there
and then you can send a second request
with the valid and the crosshair request
forgery token so by having a policy file
like this you're introducing crosshair
request forgery by design and crosshair
request forgery is normally considered a
high severity vulnerability most
circumstances
now silverlight has a civilized specific
way of doing this with domain URI said
to start and there's a lot of in the
external plug-in there's a lot of proof
of concept code and things like you have
like links to a lot of useful stuff like
to exploit this and really explain the
risk as well as you can to your customer
and cross-origin resource sharing has
these two headers access control origin
and access control our credentials that
might relax the same origin policy as
well for clickjacking the best option is
really to use x frame option set to deny
but again if this header is not set or
this header this means that they are
vulnerable to click jacking okay so
you're just looking for absence of
headers
there's a few links to cool
presentations from this and yes this is
a lot of information but as we saw in
the demo you can always use the rent and
filter by what you want so you you can
go really granular here and only and
select the the plugins you want to see
so the bottom line of this is that web
application security is really complex
it's a lot more than input validation
really and if you see no traffic no IDs
alerts that does not mean that you're
not being targeted you can your site can
be targeted without you noticing at all
as we've seen in this talk okay so the
bottom line really is to test your
security before all this do because
others will now the pentas the
conclusion is that if you have no
permission that does not mean that you
cannot start you can do a lot of work in
advance and this work really helps you
to be more efficient and you can even
negotiate extensions so based on the
information and the evidence that you
found you in your pre engagement testing
you can negotiate with the customer like
look we've seen a lot of flash files I
think we'll need like an extra day for
those or whatever so you can always have
like more hard evidence to to go to your
customer and ask for more days as well
for whatever you find in here and the
bottom line is that the test quality
will be much better and you will really
have the best chance to get him if you
do this so summarizing you don't have to
wait until 5:00 p.m. for the nmap scan
to finish or anything like this
so no lying on the floor with a power
belt and happy holidays okay and you
don't have to wait for permission well
you really should do is to give it your
heart and your your best shot and try to
do you know as the best job you can and
I'll give everything you have you know
try to do the best you can so I like to
thank all the project contributors
everybody that supported me or the
project there was testing guide
contributors and all the port the
podcast that interviewed me or mentioned
WTF thank you and that's all I have so
any questions
I made the tool is very cool you know
that I tried it a better test it a bit
but you need to improve the GUI yeah
with something like JavaScript I don't
know jQuery UI or Sencha because
otherwise the mess - yeah I know I know
good way with something like your dragon
drops right clicks on the UI would be
better I think yeah I I didn't have a
lot of time in this presentation but in
besides vni I said like I'm sorry I'm
not a web designer so I apologize you
know if it looks horrible or anything
just say great project looks really good
just to me no permission is kind of okay
I would just said make sure that you've
got a purchase order before you start
perfect make sure you've got purchase
order before you start otherwise all
this testing without permission is
worthless because you're not going to
get paid for it yeah I agree but that
they're gonna pay you for all this
pretty work yeah
no but the idea here is that you can
count that time as for when you have
permission you know like all you're
doing really is moving some part of the
test before you have permission so
because it's not only about man-hours is
about the time that you need to leave
the tools running as well so you can
move the word before and you can do all
that human analysis and you can discount
that them from the other time but then
you know you will have more time during
active testing to run the relevant
active testing tools that take a long
time to run for example so you can still
get paid and leverage this approach you
know and you can negotiate extensions
which is very powerful concept if you
think about it
the other thing is you know like most of
us do this for fun so like if you're
given like new toys to test you don't
really care if you have pain or not
sometimes you just want to hammer it