a lot of people think they understand
randomness a lot of people would say for
example that randomness and
unpredictability are the same thing
there they're not a lot of people would
say well you know what I got Java secure
random right so it's secure and it's
random I'm done right maybe maybe not so
what we want to talk about is what is it
how does it work
why is it hard why is it important and
then we'll talk about how to do it right
I'm all about doing it right oh wait a
minute who am I so I forgot to tell you
that didn't I
so my name is Paco I work for a company
called digital we're software security
consulting right we're sponsors where
we're handing out little chocolates and
all that good stuff and we do software
security from the whole lifecycle right
architecture code analysis testing etc
so this is something a lot of my clients
struggle with some of my clients I like
to say that I head up the sin industries
it's digital so I deal with all the
online poker I do the lottery I do you
know any sort of casino stuff I actually
worked on slot machines you know it was
a best gig right when you you come in on
day one you know like excuse me boss um
there's no slot machine in my cubicle
you know I need one of those right and
and of course they fixed that I had a
slot machine
so obviously random numbers are very
important a lot of things depend on
being random you want to gamble online
you want to believe that that was fair
you want to play the lottery you want to
believe that the lottery stuff is fair a
lot of things you know SSL session IDs
random resource identifiers for the
random download of the software that you
just purchased all these things depend
on doing random numbers right but here's
a fun one last year the u.s. Department
of State issued a set of visas to people
who are hoping to come to the US and
they had to do it by a lottery and the
lottery for these visas is required
by law to be fair and random turns out
they had to put up this big webpage and
they had to mail out a letter to all
these people who had won the lottery
they got a letter saying hey
congratulations you're gonna have a visa
welcome to America and then they got
this letter they're like uh sorry we
screwed up the random number generator
and we're gonna rerun the lottery and
you may not actually have a visa and the
whole thing you know it says right there
it was not a fair random selection
that's required by US law in fact people
who had applied earlier in the
application period were more likely to
get a visa than the people who applied
later and we're going to show you the
mathematical reason why that probably
happened I'll show you some code that'll
you know that explains that kind of
stuff so what is important if we talk
about something that's random right so
the mathematical definition of
randomness we're usually worried about
uniformity that means there's no bias
we're not seeing more of one than
another
there's no patterns we're not you know
we're not seeing a whole lot of
repetition of different things and we're
not seeing cycles now we're usually
worried about forward security as well
which means that if I know a bunch of if
I observe a bunch of random events now
it doesn't tell me anything about the
random events that happened in the past
as well as backwards security which is
if I know a bunch of prior values I
can't pick things in the future
so these are things that we care about
but we also care about how we use the
random numbers assuming that we get them
right by the way how could we get them
well you got a couple of things there's
two ways you can do it in Hardware you
can do it in software hardware guys are
really cool right so you can get Johnson
noise you get free running oscillators
you can do quantum mechanics I love this
one that's this guy right here this is
the only time in my job because I tend
to do software stuff the only time in my
job that I get to say the words photon
emitter and it's like actually you know
business purpose what these guys do
company called ID quanti they take a 50%
silvered mirror so it's half transparent
half silvered set it at a 45-degree
angle and fire photons at it and half of
them we're gonna go straight through
we'll call that zero half of them are
going to hit some material and go off at
a right angle we'll put a sense of there
and we'll call that one and so the laws
of quantum mechanics say we can't figure
out you know how many which ones which
photons are gonna go straight through
which ones are gonna get bounced off at
an angle and of course we all know that
manufacturing being what it is you can't
get that exactly 50% you can't get it
exactly 45 degrees so every clock cycle
let's switch which one of these is zero
and which one is one zero one one zero
helps even out the bios and then you put
in Von Neumanns D biasing and you can
come down to you to really truly
unbiased random numbers very cool you
can get it in lots of form factors you
have a little PCI card you can have a
dongle you can have built onto your
motherboard because there are a few
little problems doing it in hardware
right we do have the environmental
effect some of the stuff like Johnson
noise if you cool the temperature down
it's it's harder to get right you some
things rely on physical phenomena like
radio frequency or audio and obviously
we can we could do environmental things
to introduce BIOS and then there's
throughput right your request is
important to us please hold
so if you've got to have a lot of random
numbers say your PokerStars
they have dealt 25 billion hands of
Poker in like 10 years they've been
around they do well over a million hands
a day so you need some good entropy you
need to make sure that you had enough
hardware to do it tricks there would be
things like you know pooling your
entropy and over-provisioning obviously
now that way you can do randomness so
you go get yourself some software
anybody know the Marcin twister anybody
here experience with some random numbers
anybody heard of the Marcin twister well
I see a couple of hands I hope you're
not using it for anything important
because it's a mess the mercy and
twister shows up all the time people
love to use it because it's fast it's
freely available and source codes all
online obviously if you are in the
operating system you know you know in
the windows you got crypt gen random and
java we have java.util secure random we
have dev random in the operating system
you can go pull random numbers out of
that and that's usually pretty good and
of course you could roll your own you
know I've been doing I've been doing
security for a long time and years and
years ago the message right we'd all
tried it out don't roll your own crypto
don't roll your own randomness and for
awhile I think we got it right I think
we like I just stopped seeing it people
stopped doing it and then it's like we
stopped beating the drum because you
know people kind of got the message and
so lately you know now I see it again I
see people like well if we take the time
of day and exhort with the guys user ID
and then we look at how many packets
have come in on this interface since
1972 and you know don't roll your own or
you know this classic one right if
you've seen xkcd right get random number
and return for hey but we got it from a
fair dice roll now you can laugh at that
hahaha funny I saw this code with this
comment and the URL in a voting machine
I stand before you I swear on my
mother's life I saw this in a voting
machine they did that and then they like
XOR a bunch of stuff yeah but they
started and they even reference the
comic so the problem with software is
that by and large everything in a
software ran a number generator is
deterministic right computers do the
same stupid things over and over and
over again if I have your Al
and I have your seed I know what the
output of this of the algorithm will be
so the only thing that can make it safe
and secure is if we manipulate the seed
if we seed it and reseed it from
someplace secure and so like if you do
Java secure and them for instance it has
an ability to seed itself it does a
pretty decent job of seeding itself you
know does a little thread join thing and
and you know it's pretty unpredictable
but that is like the big issue if you
want to run in software then you have to
have some some way of getting a secure
unpredictable seed this is one of the
good ways of using software and our
number generators is sort of as an
extender of entropy if you can get a
good seed from somewhere but you need
more random numbers then you can seed
periodically and run on the software in
a number generator most of the time the
issues right I mean where do you get
that seed how do you get it because if I
can and how do you keep it safe right
because if I get it then I know what
your numbers are going to be about 12
years ago
when online poker was first taking off
in the States some guys they want to say
it was party poker
then they have a lot of hubris and
they're like look we do everything right
we do it so right that we're gonna
publish our shuffling algorithm right
here on the web so we take a random
number you know from our random number
generator whatever that is and here's
our shuffling and dealing algorithm
well our guys were you know really into
poker at the time I said oh this would
be really cool would it be funny if we
could just use that shuffling and
dealing algorithm and figure out what
they're dealing of course they couldn't
possibly be using the time of day to
seed the random number generator could
they so we wrote a little program that
would you know take the time of day and
we'll connect to the server and use the
ssl you know timestamp from the server
to get a rough approximation of what
time the server thought it was
and then we would basically you enter
the cards you've seen so far you know
your two hole cards and and of course it
may be your buddy if you sit in the lab
next to you or the or the cards that
come up in the center of the table and
the software would just take you know
ten seconds prior you know 10 seconds
later than the timestamp we got is run a
bunch of shuffles and wait until we got
a shuffle that comes off with those
cards in that order and as soon as we
did that was like there's your deck and
so you get a bit of an advantage I don't
know how many poker players we have but
if you know all the cards there's a
slight advantage so you know that's the
thing with software right is if you know
the random numbers if you know the seed
then you're really screwed on a software
RNG so let's look at the relative
strength of some of the things that
they're out there right mercy and
twister it has an internal state of 625
bytes huh sounds pretty big a problem is
that basically that internal state is
the random number that it's going to
give you and so after you have observed
626 outputs you can pretty much predict
the rest of them until they reseed the
sim be oriented fast Mersenne twister
it's just another it's like the Big
Brother and they kind of upped it by an
order of magnitude good news is you have
this massive period and it can take a
big seed and that's all really good bad
news is if they don't recede you have to
observe 6,000 bytes out of it and then
you can predict everything that comes
out so kind of good news bad news on
that one Java secure anna has an
internal state of 20 bytes which you
know that sounds pretty good right - to
the 160 and Windows has 40 you know - to
the 320 sounds pretty good here's where
that can come back to bite you let's
imagine we want to deal some cards so
the problem we have here is that 52
factorial which is the number of
different ways you could shuffle a deck
of cards that turns out to be about 2 to
the 220
well Java secure and I'm like I said has
that 20-byte internal state it can only
produce two to the 160 unique streams of
random numbers give it any set of seeds
you want there are only two to the 160
possible streams of random numbers that
will come out of it
it cannot actually produce every
possible shuffle of a deck of cards
I don't know which ones it can't produce
you know I can't tell you which hands of
Poker won't come out of Java secure
random because that took the 160 is an
awful lot but there are things you can't
produce events that will not happen if
that's your random number generator
windows on the other hand with the kripp
Jenner annum has enough space I can
actually do either shuffling the deck of
cards so there's one where you say well
can I use Java secure random for my J
session ID on a web app yes you're just
don't shuffle cards
now why did I just cross out kripp
Jenner and him I thought I said it had a
big enough state yeah but it only takes
a 32-bit seed there's only four billion
ways to seed that thing so four billion
is way less than the number of possible
shuffles of a deck of cards so if you're
gonna seed with only a 32-bit integer
and you only have four billion possible
seeds you have to run really long in the
period which means that you run a longer
chant a better chance of somebody
guessing what your seed was and catching
up to you so you actually want something
it takes a big old seed or frankly you
know if you're a gambler you get the
hardware vendor number generators for 1
grand or 2 grand or something throw that
thing in those in the system and forget
about it and of course the mersin twist
or what drives me crazy about it is that
it gets used all the time but it passes
your statistical tests right you can rob
them die hard and the NIST tests all the
other things it will pass you know what
else passes I got into I got into a
little debate with major malfunction on
this one because I came out to DC for 40
40 for 20 and did this talk and he got
got interested in randomness for a
little while and if we got into this
little debate about it and you're
passing a statistical test is often like
yeah that's the the gold seal yeah but
you know what I can take the number the
numbers from you know zero to a thousand
0 1 2 3 4 5 in order calculate the sha-1
hash of those things and use that as
like a byte stream right let's pretend
that that's the output of my RNG a
number zero shot one of it one shall one
of it just there's my there's my output
stream hand that to die hard and this
and all those other things comes out
with a passing grade
is there any entropy in there no hash
functions do not produce entropy they
don't manufacture it out of nowhere so
it has a nice clean distribution there's
no
cycles there's no patterns there's no
bias there's no entropy either it's
completely predictable and the ups of
empty I already told you that guys no
good right so we want to do it right
okay
so this is the class participation part
of this we want to simulate a six-sided
die
right so the valid values are 1 to 6
let's imagine I got a perfect little
piece of hardware that's going to give
me perfect values 0 to 9 what do I do
anybody got an idea we might want to
have the microphone handy in case
somebody wants to to give an answer here
how do i how do I do this I take the
number 0 to 9 and produce 1 to 6 with 1
through 6 all being equally probable
I got a ringer he's heard of the SFM T
so you can pretty much just take any
output and then if it's outside your
range discard it it means generating
more numbers but it'll be equally
running they're equally distributed
there you go you kind of stole my
thunder but yeah you're exactly right I
was really hoping that I could get
somebody to raise their hand and offer
modulo arithmetic right because modulo
arithmetic sounds like the perfect thing
right you just say well look I'll take
the zero to nine and I do you know mod
six add one you know we're good of
course what ends up happening if you do
that if you do the you know mod six plus
one look what happens right the value is
one two three and four have a 20%
probability of coming out because
there's two different ways to make them
and the values 5 & 6 have only a 10% way
of coming out because there's only one
way to make each of those values so
don't do that that is probably what
happened to the US visa lottery remember
that I said applicants who applied early
in the application period were more
likely to get a visa than people who
applied later in the period
so this that's you saw the classic
symptom of using modulus arithmetic
now mistake number two is to try
floating-point so it doesn't make as
much sense when we're dealing with such
small numbers zero to nine and one to
six but we see this sometimes where
people say you know what I'll pretend
that I've got this range of zero to nine
I'm gonna pick some number and I pick
four so that's 40% into my range now
take point four and multiply it times
six and that gets me my output you know
and then we just obviously round up the
problem is you suffer from the same sort
of bias I mean the bottom line is
whatever you're max int you the the
amount that you can store in a 32-bit
integer or a 32-bit you know I Triple E
floating point value is not evenly
divisible by your output range so it
doesn't actually work this way so there
will be a bias on this many elements
whatever you know max int or max 32-bit
value mod your range is that many items
will have some kind of BIOS and we can
even see it I wrote a little you know
dummy program to do that and and what
you see is there's this tiny tiny and we
did a I think a million or a hundred
million
you know rolls and you see you got to go
pretty far down before you start to see
any differences in the output but then
if we do to dice like we're gonna have
an online craps game you know you start
to see the multiplication effect where
certain things are fair bit more likely
or less likely than they should be and
you figure that I mean I guess in some
sense you could say well it all comes
out in the wash two and twelve kind of
cancel each other out and seven is is
even or when you get a shuffle cards you
know you see something like this where
you know there's five cards that are it
after a hundred million deals there's
five cards that have been dealt you know
one fewer time than they should have
been okay look that's not massive but
still if you're in the online gaming
industry you usually have some regulator
kind of scrutinize
you saying so are you really fair and
actually they'll end up giving you a lot
of grief over something like that okay
let me tell you something
hashes do not extend entropy if the hash
could make your entropy longer we'd call
it Viagra we wouldn't call it a hash so
if you've got a random number and you
put it in a sha-1 there are no new bits
of entropy so you may get 160 bits out
of your hash function but if you know 32
bits of entropy went in there's still
only 32 bits hiding in and among the 160
bits of your output you just don't know
which ones they are now so if you go to
some trouble to get yourself 32 good
bits of entropy just just hang on to
them don't abuse them don't take a bunch
of other stuff from the environment and
throw it in with your random number
generator if you pull you don't want to
eat like you buy the $1200 quant eek you
know quantum physics photon emitter
based rng don't put the process ID in
there that thing was good to begin with
I'm a kind of a nut about wasting
entropy don't use a 32-bit value to
shuffle a deck of cards you know you
only need the values from zero to 52 you
can do that with one bite heck even then
you're wasting you know two bits of
entropy but you know do with one byte
not 32 and careful about error and
exception handling I mean this is where
I have found some just classic screw-ups
in online poker sites and online
lotteries kind of stuff where you know
the random number generator starts going
zero zero zero zero and they have no way
to tell you know nothing in there that
this sort of checks and in one case I
actually found code that returns zero on
error and what if you ran a number
generator produced zero that is a
legitimate value it should happen you
know one in 4 billion times
so you got to be careful with that stuff
all right let's talk about how we do it
right the short answer is don't be too
clever you can out clever yourself don't
do that so short answer is leave well
enough alone right if you got a nice
little random a number just just let it
be and as we already heard right
repeatedly draw so if I you know while I
don't have something that's in my range
try again just do a do-while loop I
don't use a lot of do-while loops in in
my life
but but this is like the classic one you
got to do it once and if that wasn't
good enough keep trying and when you're
done you're done
now what about shuffling cards anybody
know how assuming you have some good
random numbers how would you shuffle
cards short hands if you think you could
shuffle a deck of cards at a at a
computer algorithm I'm not gonna make
anybody say it could you do it I don't
want to either everybody is like so
incredibly awesome and they got Fischer
Yates in their head and they're like
dude or actually you gonna learn
something the next slide
so the Knuth shuffle also called the
Fischer Yates shuffle is the only way to
do it this really is kind of your best
way to do it because for one thing it's
order n right you pass you touch every
card exactly once go through it and it's
mathematically proven to be optimal
start with card 51 and pick one pick a
random number between 0 and 51 and swap
it swap card 51 with the random number
you picked now for card 50 pick another
one like a different random number swap
it and so on lather rinse repeat very
simple algorithm go to go to
pedia pulled that guy down at one point
and it's almost worth going through the
Wikipedia archives because they pulled
all this stuff down but at one point
they had at least 10 different languages
you know on the fishery eights shuffle
the Knuth shuffle like 10 different
languages of like how to do it and it
wasn't like C and C sharp and Java and
and so on it was like Haskell and you
know COBOL and I'm like really
interesting mistakes that people do
using the wrong range right if you don't
get the range right for card 51 51 is a
possibility it can swap with itself it
is okay for the card to not move so if
you do it wrong if you say oh that would
be weird now the card can't stay in
place that wouldn't be a shuffle you
actually introduce bias by shuffling
that way or some people say ah will do
it better better than then you know
decreasing the range of possible cards
to shuffle with will always use the full
range so every card could always swap
again mathematically that is wrong and
so if you if you look up the
mathematical proof it only works the way
I showed you and and of course I get old
friends modulus arithmetic in
floating-point right if you do any of
that you're dead now there is another
reasonable way to do it I've seen this
on a major poker site interestingly they
went out of business recently but yeah
it was good they were a bunch of crooks
not because they had a bad shuffling
algorithm and and you know frankly the
difference between a legitimate online
poker site and and a whole bunch of
crooks is it's hard to tell so one way
to do this right is is you assign random
numbers to every card and so you have
you know number and then the card value
it represents and you run a sort and so
obviously sort is order n log n so it's
not as good as n but it's actually
pretty good
that's a reasonable way to do it
all right so actually you know running
towards the end here doing it right
don't overthink it right think
chain-of-custody
you've got this data this precious
little thing you had to work so hard and
a fire photons in a mirror you had to
capture them and you had to rely on
quantum physics you didn't just get this
by rolling a die so so don't screw with
it take it out of the random number
generator put it in your algorithm use
it how you need it throw it away
get good entropy I always recommend the
hardware guys and if you're gonna use
some software for going to use money
that's kind of hybrid approaches where
you do a little bit of hardware to like
seed do a little software so that you
can you to continue using it well you've
got a seed and reseed often and from an
independent source right your seed
source has to be something independent
of your random number generator source
right and if you're gonna spot it in
code because like this is one of the
things I do all the time I am one of the
first I remember what the first random
number generator things we did and we're
looking through this this company is
like random number generator and then
they're shuffled code and in some sense
I wrote this whole talk off the back of
reviewing their online poker app because
I between them and like Wikipedia's
warnings on don't do this I had the full
spectrum like I can go to Wikipedia I
can look at their code and Wikipedia is
like and don't use floating point
arithmetic floating point okay don't you
know it was like handle errors very well
no exception hit like it was it was just
it was almost like somebody with you
ever worried I'm a consultant right and
every once in a while I get on these
Easter egg hunts right you get that
client who's like we need to know how
good you really are there are 12
vulnerabilities in this app can you find
them I'll do my best you know it
wouldn't be better if we were just
trying to make the software secure and
so I worried though that that that's
what these guys were doing to me that
they they sat down a programmer there's
a good Wikipedia and do all the things
that it says are wrong and we're gonna
call signal every to see if they can
find them cuz by golly everything was in
there so if you're gonna try and spot it
in your own code right look for the bad
bath I mean grip four percent you know
if modulo is in there somewhere
you know grep for X or if X was in there
you know look at the seed how big is it
is it big enough because you know we're
always thinking about collision domain
so if a four billion element collision
domain is good enough if you're not
going to have that many users logged in
at the same time and this is your
session ID and you know one in four
billion is good odds then then that's
good enough but your seed determines how
you the seed determines how many
different streams around a number if you
will get out check the RNG is it
something that's known is it something
that's tested does it have any kind of a
seal or certification or accreditation
everybody who makes something plausible
incredible they have some kind of
proof or some kind of certification
behind it obviously you know shuffler
simulator whatever it is you're going to
do you gotta look out for it for the
off-by-one errors there's one more thing
and going back to just the another
principle of doing it right
you know don't add anything to it I've
often seen people take the random number
you know that comes out of the hardware
generator and then they take something
from like another source you know maybe
it's Java secure an or whatever you know
and and they XOR them you know that that
that makes it you know better here's a
question for you if I take a random
number out of a harder random number
generator that we believe is good so
it's we believe it's a good number and I
XOR it with the number five every time
before I use it
is that better worse or indifferent we
got to show a thumbs better worse or
indifferent all right I got some I got
some some thumbs I got some downs I got
some offs yes sideways everybody with
your thumb sideways you're right it just
doesn't matter if you're X whoring it
doesn't matter you know they it was a
perfectly random bit when it was a one
it's perfectly round a bit when it's a
zero
now obviously though I was doing
something else I'm doing and if I'm
doing shift or if I'm doing something
that's gonna actually remove random bits
that's different but here's gonna flip a
few bits it's the same which also means
that even if I have two independent
sources of randomness I'm like exhorting
them together it was random just start
with so if it's random and you stick
some random in there it's still random
is random plus random is random right so
with that I mean that's that's secure
random numbers in a nutshell I am happy
to talk about any of this stuff you know
random number
how to play poker online how to cheat
the lottery you know whatever
I hear actually this is my won lottery
tip I hear that buying a ticket slightly
increases your chance of winning all
right questions would you say a good
fallback mechanism for a random number
generator that fails in the starts just
producing huge strings of ones would be
X or ring with another RNG so for
example you know if you've got random
and you're writing random you get random
if you got random you're adding non
random you've still got random is that
sort of legitimate or am I kind of
screwing up the math there mmm no I
think if you if you're exhorting with a
biased source I'm thinking sort of
you've got one Hardware one software
source if the hardware sauce breaks then
you've still got the software source if
the software sauce brakes used to the
hardware source and then you don't need
to you don't need to do expensive
branches on for example with like an
FPGA that can't really do
branching right yeah well I mean I guess
I'm hoping for detecting a failure like
like either the hardware is gonna work
or it's not gonna work that's what I'm
hoping for
in which case you know you would if the
hardware fails completely you would
switch to the software right so you
basically have in in software you say I
need a random number from hardware did
that fail oh crap I need it from
software you know and let's let's
trigger an alert red light goes off in
operations and and and we do it from
software I don't know that I would
advocate you know combining the two as a
like constant thing
PACA what do you think of the major
malfunctions a smoke detector hack
because I've had a word with him about
that we we scratched our heads a lot and
yeah yeah I have one he gave me one it
was really really nice the the really
interesting question with the smoke
detector random and let me let me
explain what that is because it's pretty
cool
many smoke detectors have some piece of
radioactive material in them something
that's emitting alpha particles right so
a piece of paper will block it one of
the great sources of unpredictability in
the world is radioactive decay so how
often and kind of what vector these
alpha particles pop out is unpredictable
so what major malfunction did was he
took the little piece of americium 231
or whatever it is out of a just
garden-variety smoke detector he got it
to be in q and he he took a cheapest
webcam he could find and he took the
lens out and put the radioactive
material pointed at the CCD right so now
we just have alpha particles firing at
the CCD that's normally picking up your
face and they're big enough that they
make little white dots on the on the CCD
it's cool idea so now we have this you
know XY grid 640 by 480 with random
white dots and we can get like 30 frames
a second out of there
and you say okay neat idea we don't know
where these white dots are gonna go the
problem is my concern with it was it was
twofold one they are random in time not
location so if we're not measuring like
the difference in time between alpha
particle emissions we're not necessarily
measuring the attribute of the
radioactive material that is random so
it could have you can imagine you know
the shape of the physical material might
bang them all onto one pixel on the CCD
and so it's only the time of arrival
that's random it's not like where they
hit on the CCD that's a random and what
we ended up doing he had all these
filter functions trying to clean up the
data to extract the random bits and I
started running die hard
and some of the other statistical tests
on ironically that the latest version
die hard is called die harder I'm
waiting for the new die hard with a
vengeance library it hasn't been
released yet and when I ran the
statistics against his data the more he
messed with it the less the the worse it
performed at the more filter functions
and things he did to clean up the data
actually the worship performed in the
statistics and so the raw data seemed to
have the best entropy but I can't draw a
logical conclusion or a logical
connection between the XY plane of space
where these things hit and the arrival
time of the alpha particles which is the
bit that I believe is random ok good
summary
do you normally worry about in the
gaming stuff about timing attacks
because I mean looking at the the
algorithms you're talking about for
choosing a random number the the looping
just looks like a potential timing
introducing at that timing side channel
if you have a good random number all you
know is how long it took before they got
one you don't know what number it was I
mean if we you know let's say we're
doing something really stupid we're
looking for a number between one and six
and we take a 32-bit value it can take a
really long time before we get the
number one of the numbers between one
and six but I don't think that tells you
anything about which number you finally
got when you were done no no yes it's a
hardware source then I'm sure but it was
a hardware store and I mention about a
software because I don't think you get
any information about the value that
came out
cool alright guys thank you very much