next week of this morning is a Tom
Langford for going to talk about an
anatomy of a risk assessment for the
next power questions at the end Tom yeah
absolutely and then I think we've got
one more talking then it's lunch so
without further ado over Tito thank you
very much so firstly welcome to an
anatomy of a risk assessment and also
secondly thank you very much i know at
least one of you must have voted for
this talk i know i did and i don't know
what the figures are so i don't know how
they tailed off towards the end so you
know i'm hoping to meet the expectations
of at least one of you my key
performance indicator of course is
trying to reduce the percentage of
people who actually walk out during the
the next 50 minutes or so so this is an
anatomy of a risk assessment it was
originally titled when I first came up
with the idea you know the anatomy of a
risk assessment but I kind of figured
quite quickly that risk assessments are
very much unique there is no such thing
as a definitive risk assessment and you
know especially when we throw in other
terms as well like audit which will come
on later there's a vast range of things
that we can do and we you know we focus
it down into security as well we get
even you know even you know we're kind
of throwing it open even more you know
within the ranges of what we do with
insecurity but as you probably gathered
from the theme and Anatomy we're going
to be talking about a range of body
parts today starting with a cadaver and
working all the way down to the final
evisceration of the body itself and you
know the reason for this is I'm trying
to put across as you know human social
element here and try to give you some
tools from my experience and experience
my peers and colleagues and away are not
almost am anomic of how you can use
everything that's available to you you
know you born with it you know depending
upon whatever deity or non-data you
believe in you've been granted you know
these many things that are listed here
and how you can use them more
effectively in a risk assessment it's
pretty graphical
if you got if you are of a nervous
disposition and judging by the size of
this bloody screen these pictures are
going to look pretty gruesome in some
cases so you know just kind of shy fade
out the one side if it's if it's a
little bit excessive now how many how
many other presentations are going to
show you a slo-mo pause of a body
exploding in front of another body not
many that's pretty much the highlight of
it but so what again this is analogous
to the anatomy of a person and like
every good talk like this you come up
with the title first and then you kind
of wedge everything else in after that
right and so I had them via the the idea
anatomy of a risk assessment that works
and I came up with a few topics so
you'll see that in maybe one or two
cases I've stretched that analogy a
little bit but bear with me I'll pointed
out so it's not too disappointing when
you do come across it this is not
heavily technical okay this is not this
is not a checklist this is not you know
compliance by the numbers or the ten
deficiencies in cloud computing that you
need to look out for or anything like
that this is the human social element
this is how you interact with people
over the table when you're carrying out
a risk assessment it draws on
experiences from both sides of the table
so as both an assess or and an assessee
and I will you know I'll try and give as
many examples as I can and those
examples I you know I bring up these
examples based on my experience not to
show how widely traveled i amand you
know how awesome i am at these sort of
things but to bring color to these
things because that's what's important
if you don't have real-world examples on
which you can pin these things onto it's
very difficult so actually understood
into practice you know some of these
techniques if I if I may it also brings
in about in a various geographic and
cultural differences as well in certain
a quick show of hands is there anybody
here who works across multiple
geographies
these hands up anyone so quite a few
that's great so you're probably already
you already know that there's a huge
amount of cultural differences between
the English the Germans the Americans
the Indians etc you know especially when
you travel there and so you can't rely
purely upon your own it as it were into
the view of the world when you are
talking you know and assessing projects
or teams or clients within those
locations um it may come across as
cynical in some cases as some of the
things I'm saying and trying to you know
trick trick people and trip them up it's
not meant to be it's probably based upon
the fact that you know I was kind of a
poacher turned gamekeeper in certain
aspects so I you know I tried if I'm
trying to trip someone up as it was
because I know that it you know these
things happen in the real world another
question hands up who actually carries
out risk assessments themselves
fantastic well it's perfect audience in
that case which is good news and who has
risk assessments carried out upon them
okay oh no that's good we got for your
hands up there okay that's fine that's
good you know and when we throw that in
across multiple geographies we've got an
awful lot of you know iterations and
interactions that go on and finally you
know possibly the unspoken word audit
you know the difference between an
assessment and an audience I will tell
you that I will use the term
interchangeably you know but just to be
clear and auditors against a given
standard it's virtually you know a tick
box yes no pass/fail yeah a little bit
of gray area I think with ISO 27001
their their lexicon is area of concern
but ultimately you are being measured
against something whereas a risk
assessment is something altogether more
you know subjective and a little bit
more difficult to pin down and we'll
talk about some of those aspects of what
we do there but you know bear with me I
will use them interchangeably basically
because having been on both sides of the
table on both assessments and audits you
know those experiences kind of blended
somewhat
so we're gonna start with the the feet I
did think about having this as the
skeleton as sorry as the spine because i
thought you know the point of this slide
is you know what is the foundation of
what it is that we're trying to do in a
risk assessment you know what it is that
we are trying to to achieve by carrying
out the assessment but i did find this
picture and I kind of preferred this one
too just a white spine on a white
background but the principle remains the
same you know your feet are you know
they allow you to get from A to B they
allow you to achieve your goal of
carrying out your your risk assessment
if you don't understand what your goals
are before you even go in there you're
going to start uncovering you know the
wrong skeletons effectively or or in in
worse cases you know perhaps perhaps
even no skeletons so my backgrounds you
know funnily enough is from a security
perspective and I'm sure most of you are
but is are there any other any people
here that no carry out assessments from
a different perspective from purely
security so yes sir tsem okay yep
otherwise other ones so I'm thinking
about yes yeah okay forever yes yeah
yeah and just the broadness out again
we've got financial risks that we need
to look at or that people will look at
we might also have you know legislative
risks that need to be assessed or market
risks for instance you know or you know
perhaps crisis style risk you know
earthquakes of Kuran in you know certain
geographies and things like that so
again understanding your perspective
obviously I think you know I think from
the the overwhelming response they were
probably all from a security risk
perspective here but i think it's it's
keen to it's important to understand
that difference so I have colleagues in
Boston who are part of the
sarbanes-oxley take the Sox team you
know in sarbanes-oxley you know very
quickly came out as a result of the
Enron
and you know looks at the financial
viability and the financial stability of
a company and certain you know and risks
are analyzed through that to paraphrase
it very very dramatically when they go
in and carry out an assessment of a team
for instance say for instance likely
that the payroll team they're looking at
the financial risks you know so they're
interested in for instance if within the
within expensive system our expenses
being signed off by the right people in
the right process in the right time and
all that sort of thing that's a NASA
anathema to me as a sick as a security
risk assessment I could go in and assess
the payroll team and see the door
propped open with a fire extinguisher
that's a security risk because people
come in we might go in looking at the
same team and come out with two entirely
different set of risks I think that's
something that's worthwhile bearing in
mind when you get when you go into it
ensuring you know what is your universe
that you're covering the second or third
i should say what tools do we use you
know what is your baseline you know if
you're doing an audit to an iso audit
it's fairly straightforward right iso
27001 standard you've got a list of
requirements you take across a very
straightforward if it's if it's an
assessment as such you know look at
different stands as risk IT for instance
or octave or different you know anything
could be your own internal standard as
well we've got to have something that
you can you know you can leverage
something you can you can come back to
and they different different standards
and different approaches are favored by
different industries so you know many
clients of ours for instance will come
to us and say show us your PCI
compliance will be not PCI compliant we
don't handle credit card details but
that's what they understand that's what
they know and understand so when you go
if you're looking at a given team or a
clients whatever make sure you
understand what their background is and
you can start to at least you know pick
out some of these risks in a language
that they're going to understand in the
first place and when you find the risks
how are you going to measure them you
know for me I I like ISO 27001 it's it
kind of reflects me you know simple and
straightforward it's very simple to
understand it's very easy to put across
the lay person how you have measured a
risk asset value likelihood impact and a
score and you can measure everything
across that and I like I said twenty
seven thousand five because I can apply
a risk security risk assessment on a
laptop or a project or a team or a
facility throughout the whole lot and I
can still apply the same measures to it
i'm comparing apples to apples across
the board a colleague of mine uses risk
IT for business continuity planning
risks as it were and he then translate
those into twenty seven thousand and
five scoring but the actual risk IT
format for him works better in how he's
working his you know be CMS's business
continuity management system yes so you
do need to make sure that you're using
the right tool for the job but
ultimately in your final analysis the
risks have to be able to stand side by
side with each other so you know when
there's an eight it really means it's
serious and you know when it's a three
that actually you can probably leave
that to a lot later be it a laptop or a
facility or a service or a process or
anything like that move on to the brain
so use your brain plan the assessment
that's what busy is coming from you know
plan the assessment they'll just turn up
on the day and hope to get away with it
give notice to the people that you are
assessing not too much notice in the
element of surprise is a useful tool in
of itself and by surprise i don't mean
pitching up at the door and saying come
on time to do the assessment now that's
going to learn you no favors and if
you're a look if you're you know doing
an internal assessment or an internal
audit of you know of a team you can
probably get away with less notice you
know maybe a couple of days or a week
depending upon your remit from you know
from senior management if you're an
external auditor and external Assessor
you're probably bound by you know a
certain you know certain criteria that
you have to give at least you know two
to three weeks notice dependent up
on the you know the the company you work
for dependent upon the the assessment
that you're carrying out but nonetheless
make sure you plan for it in advance it
sounds dumb but a number of these things
done last minute are just prone to
failure you know from the outset the
thing that often comes back I found you
know over the number of years is this
misunderstanding of what it is that
you're actually trying to achieve the
question great yes look really looking
forward to the assessment let me know
what you want to see and I'll make sure
it's all prepared for you but that's
kind of not the point of an assessment
the point is for me to come in do a
sampling exercise ask you the questions
and get you two to then show me all of
the information that I need if I tell
you what I want you're busy you know
over the next two weeks you'll you'll go
off and start typing it all up for me
and it will be perfect an absolute waste
of time and conversely you know from the
other side of the table it's always a
mistake to try and prepare to pass an
audit spur say that doesn't mean you
shouldn't you know put the work in but
don't think there's an audit in six
months time and in a month before just
work furiously to pass it you know you
may get away with it a couple of three
times you know at best but at some point
the wheels are going to come off it at
some point somebody's going to be held
accountable for why you know compliance
or you know the the risk profile is low
at the right round about the time of the
assessment and then shoots up afterwards
and something goes wrong you know your
senior management are going to be held
accountable for that and that that ass
kicking is going to you know very
quickly reach its way down to you try
and ensure that at all times you're
ready for an audit technically you
should be ready for somebody to come in
on no notice that's my first point
that's neither polite professional or
really very helpful you know but that's
the point of readiness that you need to
be at all time otherwise it's not a part
of your DNA it's not you are actually
not achieving the goals of what it is
that you set out to do in the first
place as an Assessor look at the players
involved so you set the schedule now you
need to look at the
people who are involved you know why is
it important you know well finding out
who they are look up on if its internal
look on the company directory you know
find out where they are in a structure
find out how you know how old they are
how old how long they've been in the
organization i should say you know it
might be they've been in there for 15
years and they've got very you know
stuck in the you know stuck in the mud
ways of doing things you know nothing
wrong with that per se but you need to
be prepared for it or it might be that
it's an entirely new team you know
they've been recruited all in the last
year the manager came in two months ago
because the previous manager was off
with stress you know that's going to
tell you something about the assessment
in the first place if it's external
social networking linkedin all that sort
of stuff you can find out exactly the
same kind of information you know you
can gather a lot of inflation it's
important to find this out because it
allows you to talk to these people in a
language that they know and understand
so try and plan not only for the
assessment itself but for the people
that you're expecting to meet when you
get there goes without saying produce
your artifacts in advance if you've got
a sign-in sheet for instance if you use
one of those get it produced in advance
if you've got you know an evidence
record sheet get it produced in advance
if you're you know asking four pieces of
a4 and scribbling things down on pieces
of paper and passing it around you're
already again you're off on a silver you
know a half poor footing with with the
with the assessee's know who is this guy
he's not professionally does nobody's
doing he hasn't even got his papers
ready yeah so just get all that sort of
stuff to prepared in advance as well and
finally know what it is that you you
know that you are actually going to be
asking the questions on you know I carry
out a lot of assessments on a wide
variety of industry areas so for
instance I might look at a particularly
technically heavy project or team or
environment need to know the
technologies that are in use so i can
just do a little bit of you know
brushing up beforehand so i can again
talk their language i can ask the right
things it might be a heavily creative
environment in which case the use of
technology is going to be somewhat
limited to you know dropbox and
photoshop you know if you'll forgive my
paraphrase
but that's you know you have to
understand where it is that you're going
to focus and the technology that you're
going to come across when you get there
so we come to the eyes and believe it or
not you know you use your eyes to look
at things and this is my favorite part
because the observation side of things
is one of the one of the dare i say
funnest parts of things i hate it when
things are fun hey it's fun but it
starts from the moment you step out of
the cab as you walking up to the
building you should be looking at the
building that you're going to be
assessing I can't tell you how many
times they see CCTV cameras on corners
of buildings pointing away from each
other right looking down both sides of
the wall leaving a huge arc of a blank
space that people can walk up to and
inside along the building you be it make
just look through London walking here
from spitalfields for instance there's
one building that does very similar
things to cameras pointing away at each
other you know down two sides you know
they should be focused that they're
covering each other as well observe as
you get signed in or even if you do get
signed in walking into the reception how
attentive are the security staff or the
reception staff are they expecting you
if they're not expecting you chances are
that their sign-in process is probably a
little bit deficient as well always ask
to go to the toilet when you're in the
reception because you get to see more of
the building that way right and again as
an example for you I do recall
lovely-looking reception false wall
reception desk beautiful cozy toilet yes
it's just behind here out of sight as a
walk grounds behind the wall the toilets
were there and just there was a secure
area door propped open with a fire
extinguisher right now to be blunt if I
hadn't got needed the toilet I wouldn't
have found that out but that's the sort
of thing because they are looking
outwards from the building they're not
actually concerned about what's going on
right behind their backs you know so do
take a look around you you know wandered
in there
walk up and down the corridor came
straight back out you know I wasn't
doing a social engineer and experiment I
was here to carry us an assessment and
that was you know immediately written
down the other thing you know about
observation is you know when you are in
the assessment yourself look at the
people look at who they look at yep try
observe if there are any long pauses
after questions and and find out who is
doing all of the answering as well so if
you ask a question to this person and
this person is constantly aren't
answering the questions is it because
the why is this person even here you
know if they're supposed to be a part of
this assessment that's because they have
a valid yeah perspective to bring the
person who's doing the are answering of
all the questions maybe the senior guy
in you know in the in the team you know
the gray hair or no hair who's actually
been there for a while and actually
knows everything and is damn well going
to make sure we get through this
assessment you know and can try and
barge his way through it so observe how
people interact with each other and in
different cultures this works in you
know in different ways as well you know
so in certain cultures you know junior
staffers are more subservient to senior
staff than say in UK cultures you know
so that you get different different kind
of signals in different cultures as well
we're going to talk about the walk about
it later as well we also talked about
observations but the other part of this
is if you're the oddity never let the
auditor out of your sight because that's
the time when mischeif happens right
because they will also go looking around
for things escort them to the bathroom
you know escort them as you do a
walkabout when you've finished the
assessment escort them all the way down
and see them off the premises basically
a couple of things in a couple of
experiences here I recall as we were
walking out as well engaging the chap in
conversation oh thank goodness you
didn't talk about disaster recovery oh
let's go let's go back and talk about
disaster
coverage shall we you know because if
I'd been just built yet it's fine see my
way out you actually might not get that
you know get people off off their guard
as it were this is the cynical part
coming in the other parts as well as I
was in India it was August it was 44
degrees centigrade and the guys cab was
late and we found out after we'd walked
off the premises and we were stood by
you know where the cars pull up 40
minutes but I was taking a shower inside
my clothes but there was no way I was
going to say thanks garish we'll see you
later he was staying in my sight until
he had gone simple as that you know so
it's it's worth doing because it as soon
as they're out of your sight unless
they're off your premise isn't gone
they're out of your control as well so
he is so observation is important
listening is also important in my top
two this is thomas his number one as
well as the other one listen to every
single statement that's made to you
after every question you give pick it
apart repeat it back listen to that
listen to what they've what they respond
to and then confirm it back again why
because you're trying to get the maximum
out of the minimum that they want to
give you and again this is the cynic in
me coming out as an oddity the less i
say the less i can be you know held to
ransom for it or held accountable for it
well in which case i'm going to pick up
on every single cue you know verbal you
know oral our all sorry body language
etc again all things that we look at
later i want to pull everything out of
you as much as possible yes so just bear
in mind the maximum out of the minimum
that's going to be given to you i know
because i used to do it all the time now
i do not want them to know about this
particular document do you have a
testing doc you know have you carried
out a test yes you know and it's so on
and so on right so you've got to get
more and more out of them use your ears
in another way as well so a good friend
of mine
I years ago he went on a counselors
course you know talking to people who
feel stressed and all that sort of thing
it's very in-depth fascinating talking
to him about it they told me they spent
a good couple of sessions learning about
the value of silence and how you can use
it to elicit more information so when I
ask a question someone responds and they
finish don't immediately jump back in
wait nature abhors a vacuum humans
beings abour a silence they want to kind
of fill it right they don't want to be
awkward about it in many cases they
don't also don't want to be rude right
that's it next question move on you know
it's not there you know it's not their
game to play as it were let them do it
you know so there's a quote in in a book
that the leaders workbook which I really
liked which is you blessed with you know
twice as many years as you our mouths
right use that kind of ratio listen at
least twice as much as you talk and that
listening means also listening to
silence waiting for them to fill the
gaps while you're waiting for that
silence or whilst you're wasting two at
science maintain eye contact as well
because if you look down and start
scribbling away or looking away they
think the conversation is over well
you're still looking at them you're
maintaining that contact and if they're
breaking that eye contact first chances
are they're probably missing something
out well they want to say something else
that may be the point in which you can
ask further questions listen to the
subtext as well in many cases you know
people people do not like being assessed
or they don't like being audited it's a
very personal feeling even though in
many cases the reason why they might not
be doing so well is entirely out of
their hands it's due to you know you
know poor resourcing and not enough
money and not enough but not the wrong
skills and all that swing listen to the
subtext that's coming through and turn
what might be coming across as hostile
into a more positive conversation you
know make sure that they that you
understand when they're talking about
the challenges that they face you
understand their their poor scope their
paws
call the management let them know that
what you're doing is effectively some
kind of consultancy for them in effect
right you they could use this report as
leverage to get better resources to get
you know better training and more you
know more money and you know anything
that anything else that they might need
if it's used properly basically try and
sit on their side of the story try and
see it from their side empathize with
them you know resale as I said you know
resell the risk assessment as something
as free consultancy you can turn that
around and start giving them advice on
how they can improve things as well okay
you don't have budget you know your your
risk table your table of risks sucks
here's why it sucks and this is what
you've got to do about it and actually
if you do it right it's really simple
watch them fura see scribble notes
you'll see that actually they want this
stuff because they want to be able to do
better in this certainly the next time
and I think you know in summary on this
it's it's all about you find out more by
listening more it sounds obvious but
it's very easy to get carried away in in
the activities of a risk assessment you
know very easy to just plow through all
the points to be covered or plow through
you know your agenda as it were so try
and try to do more to listen as much as
possible so the mouth I couldn't help
noticing the huge fish hook in the top
of this guy's mouth which is a little
disturbing I won't tell you which site I
got that one from on google the um you
know when you're not trying to get them
to fill an awkward silence and this is
where we find that you know the fine
balance between all of these activities
talk to them ask them stupid questions
you know there's no such thing as a
stupid question in a concept like you
know in a concept such as a risk
assessment or an audit they are the
subject matter experts across you know
much of this field you know between them
find out more about what it is they know
and therefore what is they don't know
prove to them that you're not just a box
ticker there in a you know in a white
coat
board go and do you do this yes tick do
you do that no cross etc try and engage
with them more you know talk of them as
you know as as equals not as oddity in
audit or as much as possible if you
happen to have lunch and lunch with
audits is fabulous depending on which
side of the table is an oddity you try
and schedule the longest lunch in the
furthest restaurant away from the office
you know and try and use up those hours
first thing you do as an auditor is I
think we should just have sandwiches and
have a working lunch you know which so
but use that time that downtime be it in
the you know the the restaurant miles
away mite bite suit your purposes
dependent upon this you know what how
you're going on use that time to talk to
them talk to them again about their pain
points talk some about their goals
outside of necessarily this risk
assessment how about for you know if not
this sub team then how about the team as
a whole or not this particular office
but the company as a whole try and see
where they go in as a larger
organization find out about their
hobbies for goodness sake because it
might be that you share a love of
philately or fly fishing or anything
else begin with fur because that then
immediately identifies you as a human
being to them not just some box-ticking
ogre who's here to make their life a
misery you start to create a bond with
those people and they will start to open
up a little bit more and especially if
you go back to these places time and
time again you will build up an ongoing
relationship with them you know I know
we had a order for as an iso 27001
auditor in india he came to us about
seven or eight times i think in total
you know and it would half the time we
spent chatting so it was an oddity it
was great you know we use it up these
hours that we need to do just because he
wants to chat and find out what's going
on of course what he was doing was
trying to ensure whether or not security
was inherent in the company as a whole
right not just within the specific areas
that we were covered within our scope he
wanted to see the bigger picture and
that was what he was doing so we kind of
met both our goal
at the end of the day but we didn't do
that or we wouldn't have done that if we
hadn't trusted each other and understood
that we were working towards those same
goals again I mentioned before about who
you're talking to and who's doing the
answering speak to everybody focus
direct questions on individuals and if
you know that if you know the Baldy guy
on the left hand side say it starts to
dance or everything all over again so no
I just want to hear from this
perspective it's entirely valid to try
and you know elicit a question from
somebody who you know should know
something but is not necessarily
volunteering it you're trying to
ascertain the breadth and depth of that
that person's knowledge after all you
know if that one person has all the
answers there's warning bells should be
ringing out across the board and the
other thing as well as you know I
mentioned earlier about understand what
the project is is it technically heavy
is it creatively heavy or whatever
identify the individuals within that
assessment for what it is that they do
who's the techie who's the coder who's
the creative genius and that means that
you can bypass when you've come to those
certain questions all those you know
those assumptions that you need to
validate you bypass the guy who knows
everything because you're talking
directly to the individual who really
should know the SME in in this case so
understand who who does what in each
environment so the nose I like this one
because it's it it brings out the
detective in everybody really you know
follow your nose at the end the day when
you come across an environment and there
is fabulous documentation and its
pristine and it's beautifully rendered
and it's you know nice logos and all of
all of these sign off dates are correct
and you've got a perfect evidence trail
of who approved what and when and the
change control is in there etc etc and
all the procedures map directly and
references interconnect and all that
sort of thing that's going to give you a
fairly good impression of what it is
that you're a set
sin chances are if they take the time
and effort to produce quality
documentation it's because they care
about the processes and the policies and
the implementation of what they're doing
underneath it you know on the obverse of
this of course is if they bring the
documentation in a test goes bag and
slap it down and it's stapled together
and dog-eared and oh yeah we haven't we
haven't quite updated that one yes I
know it's a month out but we're in the
process of it etc chances are they don't
care about the processes themselves they
think it's all up here it's all tribal
knowledge it's fine we can do it you
know we can make this work for us you
know so nothing's really that clear-cut
you know very or very rarely but you
need to try and pick up some of these
clues that will tell you more about the
organization that you're that you're
reviewing you know so follow your nose
if something doesn't quite add up if you
know if the reference is slightly
incorrect off a piece of evidence
doesn't quite add up follow it through
there's no question about to keep
plugging away keep asking the stupid
questions you know in one I had an
8-hour assessment to carry out any one
of them I spent nearly three hours on
the second question of God knows how
many because this really does not add up
you know this this and this it's not
quite adding up we need to follow
through about two and a half hours
through I started to sweat a bit you
know I might have made a mistake here I
might have you know lost come across
nothing at the expense of about 20 other
risks that we could have uncovered here
the end 20 other more important risks
you know it did work out in the end
thank goodness but it you know you do
need to follow your nose on this follow
the evidence trail you know until you
find something or until you're satisfied
that actually there really is nothing
there
ok let's sharp pinging noise you're
hearing is the analogy of an Anatomy
being stretched to breaking point flying
over your head there to paraphrase
Douglas Adams lungs like reason I chose
you long series sometimes you've really
got to breathe a little bit in an audit
right you're going to take a deep breath
in and out tell yourself you're warm and
you're calm and you're on your special
beach somewhere because you know there
are occasions where you're just butting
heads yeah things are not happening
you're asking for stuff and it's not
being delivered but they don't think it
should be delivered you know you're
you're requesting documentation they
said oh it's in our other facility it'll
be here in two or three hours you know
probably full well know that somebody's
probably typing the damn thing up in the
background you know you really need to
kind of take a step back from all this
and sit right what is it that we are
trying to achieve here it's let's reset
paste the rest of the day you know and
and basically try and really engage with
people lets you know reset to zero and
start again there's a variety of reasons
which you've already talked about the
pressures on the other you know on the
oddities for instance or maybe you
haven't done your homework and you've
miscalculated who it is that you're
talking to for instance and you you're
you're missing the actual core role or
the core perspective of what that team
is trying to do you know so do if you're
getting nowhere reset those expectations
think it through again try and
understand where it's going the flip
side to this is always under Strine
always understand the difference between
time wasting and things just taking a
long time to get you know perhaps the
records department is on the other side
of town and it is raining and there are
no cabs and you know well perhaps you
should have asked for all that
documentation in the first place anyway
right you know next time make sure you
have a meeting at the records department
in a but understand when it's time
wasting and try and dragging feet versus
actual issues try and do as many things
in parallel as possible get me these
records it's going to take two hours
okay go get them we'll move on to the
next thing
far easier when you've got two people
doing it because you can track multiple
activities more than you know at once
far more easily and if you're doing
assessing against a standard for
instance ISO 27001 they work against
headcount and therefore the number of
hours that you should have you know to
be assessed don't count down time or
null time towards that if you're rich at
the end of the day still waiting for the
records the clock stops right it's just
like a game of rugby when some you know
the clock stops when they're when
they're pulling the half-dead player off
and let's throw any other player on and
then you carry on and of course you
should never have a long lunch you know
because that stops the clock as well so
the hands getting your hands dirty
actually getting in and reviewing
documents this is where in a lot of
cases cultural differences you know play
it play a big part so if I carry out
risk assessment in you know against
American clients for instance it's
almost always electronic documentation
on a screen here you go bump scroll
through work your way out if I go to
India it's almost always paper
documentation you know it's a regular
cratic environment you know they can
thank being us the Empire for that very
bureaucratic very paper-based and that's
how it worked and it works there's no
question about it the downside of course
is you will get reams of paper so we
carried out an assessment on a facility
facilities management team and I don't
know anybody who's worked in India here
but good companies out in India will
arrange or manage transport for their
employees from home to the office and
back it's part it's like a perkinston
surance right over here it's what's
expected so I know from you know my
company in India we've got about four
thousand people out of one site we
transport two and a half thousand people
per day to and from the office of the
total of five thousand trips as it were
so these these is a big operation takes
up a lot of time
obviously lots of out of hours lots of
you know single people or individuals
going home at odd hours we obviously
insist on background checks and all of
our cab drivers now the best part of
this is within India with the
infrastructure in Indian lots of you
know disparate villages know Central
Criminal database or anything like that
so background checks are carried out by
individual villages or towns and the
chief of police and basically the police
look through their records now can't
find his name therefore he's got a clean
you know criminal record check we were
looking through the the cab company's
records photos name address all that
sorting in a stamp from the police that
said this person has a clear criminal
check okay there's a lot of you know a
lot of drivers from this particular
village because they've all got the
stamp from the same same village in the
same you know Chief of Police on it but
fair enough you know companies start up
in a village and would extend their
service is now recruiting that village
and that no problems at all while
somebody was looking through that we
then looked through some of the
contracts for the cab companies it turns
out that the chief of police in his
village was also one of the main kab
vendors he owned the cab company and it
didn't matter who walked in his door he
was just stamping it taking it to his
office and stamping their background
check just to get it through you know so
you have to go through the reams of
paper reams and reams of paper to work
out these kinds of things okay they kind
of staring you in the face but in just
flicking through in a sample of two or
three is not really enough especially
when you've got paper records this D I
mentioned earlier about walkabout this
is the bit i love because it satisfies
the voyeur in mean I can go round and
look through everybody's stuff walkabout
walk through the office you're talking
to people on the on the you know on the
on the shop floor as it were you're
asking them about their awareness do you
do they lock their laptops up and all
that sort of sit down in an empty desk
somebody's either on holiday or at lunch
or something check the drawers wiggle
the drawers see if the laptops locked
down or you know secured or whatever
you'd be amazed sitting at desks for
instance where team
members have left a few days before and
then waiting for new team members to
join you open the drawers and as
effectively confidential information
left in those drawers they've deleted
the computer they've done the IT
security but nobody's thought to go
through an empty will the crap out of
the pedestal they leave that for the
next person are these documents really
suitable for the eyes of the new person
who's joining it could be that it was a
you know a director who had moved off
and you know a very junior associate is
coming in on you know are these even
basically salary information for
instance we don't know that's the point
to have a route around get your camera
phone out that always gets things done
the moment you start taking pictures of
something rather than just writing
something down the act of taking a
picture seems to get a huge flurry of
activity to get stuff done what you
doing take a picture it it's not locked
it should be locked it we all be all
been in the report you'll see it soon
guarantee 20 minutes later everything's
locked down you know the word has gone
round they've seen you there walking
around not with a clipboard with your
camera you know taking pictures of their
environment they want to know why so I
think you know but really bringing your
presence on to the floor as well rather
than just sitting in the office actually
trying to engage with people looking
through things you know you're sticking
your nose kind of wore your hands i
should say the hands where you know
people might not expect they belong is a
very useful tool for ensuring that you
can find stuff out so without wishing to
compare your nose to your gut or you're
in testing this is very similar to
finding something with your nose but it
starts in a different place so with your
nose you kind of smelt something
something's wrong this doesn't add up
here that doesn't add up there you know
in the spirit of all good cop shows you
know i got a gut feeling on this
lieutenant that is going on nothing
right and that's what this is this is
actually you got no evidence to tell you
that x y&z is wrong really just doesn't
feel right as it is
you know and you know you have to you
should follow it through it's a careful
one it's a bit careful balance to have
you do need to think about now there's
not necessarily this will backfire but
you could waste time right and there's
nothing wrong in keeping asking
questions in the face of good evidence
if it doesn't feel right you know it
might be that you've you know assess
this team before or a team that's you
know adjacent to them or something and
they're doing two entirely different
things you know this team is doing very
badly but according to the evidence this
team is doing very well and that thus
just doesn't fit right you need to think
about why that doesn't fit right and
follow through so just because there's
good evidence doesn't mean you should
stop if it feels the right thing to do
keep trusting them but also know when to
stop because don't you don't want to
take time away from finding other
perhaps more important risks especially
on a gut feel now a good example of this
it was a bit of it was a bit of a you
know a Eureka moment for me was
assessing an office we had an offshore
dove delivery center for this particular
client and in a walk into a secure
office and we then have a second set of
security for this particular project
area dual factor authentication rather
than just no key badging in and things
are going well you know expected risks
here and there and I stood outside you
always observe people going in and out
because you don't want people to
tailgate and all that sort of thing and
people walking it no this isn't right I
can't believe this is this perfect
people tab in doing their four digit
code doesn't feel right so I asked for
somebody's cars and took it off
inspected it was it was a hit card you
know standard access card it's got a
series of numbers on the back I think
it's a 6-digit number in this case you
know so one two three four five six what
was happening was that the facilities
team knew that this was a dual factor
authentication place they had to wish
you a card and a pin number so they were
issuing the last four digits of the six
digit number on the card so your dual
factor has suddenly become single factor
and would hang on a minute so we tried
that three or four times each everybody
he walked through took their ID badge
type the number in the door opened that
was based on nothing a puff the very
cynical thoughts that no it's not it's
perfect you know so the Gutfeld does
work you know on occasion you know not
as reliable as a nose but always worth
following up all right this is where I
win a five-pound bet from someone in the
audience you know who you are because I
managed to get an asshole into my
presentation not in front of my
presentation on the presentation so this
is this is what it is if it smells like
it's it's then it really
probably is and you need to
follow up on it and it's it's this is
different to people being over specific
in their responses yes we have a
disaster recovery test carried out every
year you know it is more than that this
is saying that when they actually quite
blatantly don't it could be verbal it
could be falsified evidence you know it
could be evidence that is easily
falsifiable for instance so a text print
out of email chains you know with yes I
approve this document on this date blah
blah blah you know you need to look out
for stuff that is blatantly not true or
not supportable the other thing is what
the exchanging of looks between people
you know when you ask a question or
something yes we do that that's going to
tell you something that that's not the
whole truth that you're listening to the
other thing here is body language as
well you know the UM the neuro
linguistic programming says that if
you're right handed and if you're asked
to recount something and you look up
until you're right you are visually
reconstructing the images or sorry
visually constructing the images which
basically means that you're lying you're
making it up and if you're looking up
and to the left is you recount something
you're you're basically drawing that
down from memory now how how real that
is and how efficient that is and how
accurate that is you know I leave to
individual folks
you know we all have our own you know
thoughts about NLP and things like that
I think there's a certain you know
elements of truth in it and when you
combine it with other factors I think
it's worth bearing in mind the other
thing as well as the change in a body
position yes turning slightly away
covering the body things like that
you're creating a defensive position I
want you to stop I'm shielding myself
away from your questions is another been
a kind of indicator anybody is eager to
follow a change of topic right let's
move on to incident management yes let's
i think it's a really good idea fabio 60
they're doing that because they're
leaving dangerous ground to safe ground
right or even if they're on the
defensive a lot to rather than on the
offensive if you will so if somebody's
very defensive about what they do it's
because they're struggling to construct
a feasible and viable argument you know
on this on the on the move as it were
whereas if they're on the offensive the
people often feel more aggressive but I
sorry more confidence in what it is that
they say it doesn't mean you know again
as an individual indicator it's it's not
black or white but these are all things
that we can look for you know so always
focus on the evidence but pick up visual
cues from from other places as well so
we come to the last slide the
evisceration I wrote a book recently oh
is talking about morgues and bodies and
things like that an evisceration
apparently is when they slice you from
the chin down the throat all the way
down to your pubic bone here open you up
break the ribs and then all of your
internal organs come out in one go
literally you know because it's
basically one long pipe effectively
right I think all that in one goal is
called a pluck which other as a
fascinating term there's nothing to do
with this I thought I would just tell
you so when you get to the end of it
because it obviously in a you know
visser a shin you don't put everything
back and let's say everybody on their
way you really do at the end of the day
there's three things in my opinion that
needs that a risk assessment or audit
need to be in the first one is that it
should be collaborative educational open
non-conference I
non-judgmental and constructive you fit
all of those things into your assessment
and you're going to come out with a
positive experience that's from both
sides of the fence here the second thing
is understand your role as an actor in
the play but you're about to embark on
right and the reason I say that is you
know it could be that as an assess or as
an oddity or your your role is as a
mentor almost you're there to you know
ask the questions get the responses
measure their risk and then help them
out you know it's you any oddity or
anybody on the other side of the table
can learn a vast amount from people who
do this sort of thing for a living if
you will you know and so it could be
that that's part of your role it could
also be that if you try and play that
role with everybody you're just going to
you know patch on eyes and offend you
know certain people other organizations
you know perhaps very much more mature
in these spaces they're going to take
that the wrong way don't patronize us
don't tell us how to do this just mark
we've got them you know risk assessment
and tell me it's right you know so
understand the role that you're going to
play in it and finally how can you as an
assess or an assessee improve without
feedback the end of every single
assessment you need to exchange you know
constructive open and honest feedback
tell each other what worked and what
didn't work it's a painful experience at
times there's no question about that but
you can learn it doesn't matter you know
how many gray hairs that you've got you
know as an auditor you can still learn
from people as to what expectations were
perhaps you did something wrong you get
very blase about how you do things you
know so as a closing question here I
think that's a very quick one I lost all
of you who at the end of an assessment
all of you put your hand up at the
beginning saying you carry out risk
assessments orders who asks for feedback
on their performance as an auditor or an
assess or at the end of the at the end
of the process excellent full marks for
those three of you
um try you might be surprised i could
say it can be a painful can be a painful
process i am going to close their we're
obviously have a few months for
questions i believe i think we're
running it very tight further discussion
i'm available that these addresses that
are very blurry from where i am and i
think my KPI was pretty good i had one
person asleep who woke up half way
through i had somebody twittering all
the way through it and i think i lost
two but gained one so i think overall i
think it quite it went quite well thank
you thanks Tom yeah we've got time for
prolly a couple of questions if anyone
wants to ask a question of Tommy no ok
I've got one then oh there's one I just
had a question our last year I did a
couple of audits and they're a lot of
the times the staff for bitching about
each other and I just and they spent
hours and hours saying but this isn't it
doesn't do this this person doesn't do
that is that is that do you have you had
that experience or is that kind of semi
normal or I wouldn't say it's fairly
normal i have had that experience and i
think that's part of actually trying to
get under the skin of what's actually
causing their problems if they're
bitching at each other chance to have
their bitching at each other they're in
my opinion and without sort of seeing a
situation that they're probably
frustrated by external factors that they
can't deal with and so they kind of turn
on themselves you know injured animals
as it were you know so and that's when
you need to come in as that sort of
mentor role as well and try and pick
apart what it what it is that's causing
these problems you know because the more
you the more you're able to again
empathize with them the more they
actually might tell you what the real
problem is rather than just what he
didn't do this anywhere in these crap at
risk assessments i don't know why he's
here in the first place you know it
trying to get out the playground and you
know into into the staff room a little
bit more any others yet I've just got
one time it was interesting that I think
you know a lot of Packers will talk
about social engineering techniques and
I thought was really interesting to get
a slightly different take on that and
how those soft skills you know can
really be a skill that you know we can
all learn on in your experience speaking
to other Assessors how much do you think
that's something that's understood or do
you think you you know you've you
understand that but there's still a long
way to go yeah i think it's it's a good
point i think that's one of the reasons
why i put this together in this way and
i think there's an awful lot of people
who go out and wave their iso27001 lead
order to a piece of paper around and say
I'm an auditor I can do this and it's
it's effectively they are box ticking
at the end of the day nothing
necessarily wrong with that in the right
place my my approach on this is that you
get more you get far more you get a more
holistic view of what it is that you're
assessing and also with the standard and
if you g scone as a box ticker the
people on the other side of the table
know what boxes you need to tick and
we'll play that game against you if you
see what I mean whereas if you're
looking at things from different areas
you're going to find out things that
they might not necessarily want you to
find out you know because as soon as you
ask for the risk assessment I'll slap
the risk assessment down so you asked
for this stuff slap that down rather
than actually how do you do your risk
assessments and watch them squirm you
know that sort of thing yeah there was
one sorry did that answer your question
I think there's one more up there and I
can see Brian's itching to get on I
found with them with a box-ticking most
of the orders that come and do that
anyways and it's the odd saying of
kittens don't cats and we're you as
been take e you know usually can
Bethel's brains yes
and you they don't you don't get a
comeback from them you know when you do
that how how do you get around it as an
auditor by bit by plain dumb sorry I
don't stand that can you explain answer
me again so yeah that's what that's what
you said yeah so it worked didn't it
yeah look at that I thank you of course
because most of them come from the
finance services yeah and as long as you
can prove with the other finance system
this is the the the logins you know for
the last sort of year on the finance
system that usually happy and they don't
really care about the race just taking
the rest of the boxes yeah absolutely
and again to reiterate I think it's
asking those dumb questions and say I'm
sorry I don't understand can you can you
say that again in words of one syllable
I'm just I'm just a dumb auditor you
know work with me here you know cuz
unless I understand it I can't write it
up as a pass do you not i mean it's it's
like I say keep asking the questions at
the maximum from the minimum they'll
give you the minimum with as many tier
ladies and as wrapped up and as much
confusing
as possible just to try and get
you to move on where is it your job as
an auditor or an Assessor to really pick
them up let me get this straight are you
saying that XYZ no no no right do it
again try using a different word you
know rather than an experienced order to
won't get put off with that really you
know they are this is this is not me
saying that any all auditors are wrong
and we have to do it this way these are
just separate sets of tools an
experience in order to will pick up on
that straightaway you know they'll pick
up on the fact that somebody's you know
well somebody's waving their rectum at
them to try and put them off does that
answer there was one at the back as well
sorry Brian if it's very quick I'm
joining I am troubles i seem to have is
anything that people find difficult and
barely falls under the banner of
security and you'll get to an audit and
they'll throw absolutely anything they
think you might be able to help with
that I can't find an acceptable way of
saying I'm not the bin I'm not here to
do everything that you can't be asked to
do basically you mean as an auditor yeah
yeah I think it is a challenging one
you're actually right part of that is
identifying that scope in the first
place and know what's going on I'm kind
of thinking that's probably more from an
internal perspective looking at internal
teams so you do the key to that is
knowing the games that people play
understanding the environment that
they're working in and therefore why
they're pulling in everything else and
making it your problem and also trying
to say that this this isn't a security
problem i can write that up in the
report and if your reports are not being
taken seriously then change jobs change
companies right but and letting them go
back with this report as leverage and I
use that term a couple of times in it in
just recently as leverage to say look
this is not our problem you know you're
making it my problem and I'm trying to
make it the auditors problem it's not
our problem it's yours or its Jeff so
it's you know Marjorie and finances or
what
so it's yeah you're absolutely
challenging it's trying to understand
and pick out and understand that scope
your universe as it were in the first
place so don't try and shut it down mid
audit just rest it in the report
absolutely absolutely i mean there's
shutting it down is two ways you want to
shut it down because actually you really
don't want to waste too much time on it
but if these are genuine grievances and
they're getting in the way of them doing
their security job it needs to be
addressed because it's taking time away
thanks Tom