they were we're going to be hearing from
Aubrey Marcus I'll be mark is founded on
it in 2010 as nutritional supplements
brand based on holistic health
philosophy and he calls total human
optimization and this talk is going to
cover the technologies you can use to
hack your consciousness ensuring that
you have every opportunity to go for
your wins inspired by his lifelong
experience as a multi-sport athlete as
well as that background in ancient
philosophy
Marcus's goal was to create a company
that empower customers to achieve their
fullest human potential and I'm really
really looking forward to hearing about
how I can also achieve this so let's
give a big warm welcome to Aubrey Marcus
thanks everybody man
this microphone seems like overkill but
we'll rock it
well rock it all right sounds good so
cool thank you for the intro and the bio
yeah as I said earlier you know I really
want this to be more of a conversation
than speech I'm not going to sit here
and talk at you guys I really want to
try to provide as much value as I can
but I'll give a little you know give a
little background to maybe have some
more jump off points so that we can
kick-start the conversation so yes
in 2010 I found it on it and that was
really the culmination of a lifelong
pursuit of something I call optimization
which to me is at the heart of the human
desire and it's not just optimizing
yourself but optimizing this entire life
experience you know that's really what
we're here to do we get a chance to play
this amazing game here in this dimension
and the goal should be to optimize it
get as much out of it as possible you
know not stay within some narrow band of
this is comfortable but let's go out
let's see what we're capable of let's
see what this life is capable of
bringing us and that's been a relentless
pursuit that I've had you know pretty
much my entire life and played a lot of
sports still play a lot of sports do a
lot of athletics challenge my mind but
really
what this talk is about is about
consciousness and as I've discovered
that's probably the most significant
aspect and driving force in my success
and happiness is my pursuit of unlocking
greater and greater access to my
consciousness and consciousness is a
word that people kind of understand but
maybe not completely so when I talk
about consciousness I'm really talking
about the force that's animating our
bodies the force of life our best self
not necessarily our mind and our
emotions not necessarily our body but
that other thing that other thing that's
there when all of that all of that fades
away and for anybody who's done a lot of
psychedelic medicine you understand what
it means when all that fades away and
that's really where I learned about
consciousness that's been my path
primarily and I've been very open about
it is to use the great plant medicines
of the world to kind of unlock and
facilitate my access to that greater
consciousness so you know when you're
talking about that you might think oh
well what's the point of that is that
just spirituality it's really not
because if you think about it you know
what's the one thing that's treated
every known disease and ailment in the
world anybody know the placebo effect
treated everything absolutely everything
the placebo effect is treated now what
is that thing well the placebo effect is
your mind or your consciousness telling
your body that's going to get well and
then the body responds you know and I
think we throw that away science is just
like yep let's get that out of the
picture like wait a minute
your consciousness has treated every
single disease condition that we've ever
had maybe let's focus on that maybe
let's look at that as a primary option
instead of discarding that and trying to
get rid of it at all options so from
your health to even you know even the
business you know I have to credit a lot
of what Anand has become and you know I
feel very blessed to be CEO and founder
of on it and we've had a lot of
accolades you're an Inc 500 fastest
growing company 2015 a lot of success
but you know what's not printed in the
pages of ink magazine is a lot of that
vision
for what on it was going to become when
I was on I was blasted on a second cup
of ayahuasca in the middle of the
Peruvian jungle when I saw that you know
and so all of these things that people
think honest your spirituality that's
just this thing it all weaves together
when your consciousness is strong it's
like having the right the right force at
the helm of the ship you know not your
emotions not your fears not your greed
not any of these other thing not your
pain but real consciousness and
consciousness has free will it has the
ability to drop in decide what it wants
for its life and make genuine decisions
and I think that's one of the most
important things that we can have now
it's not all about the plants there's
many other many other ways to access
your consciousness of course meditation
that's the basic primary wanted and
that's really the stilling of the mind
that's the quieting of the mind because
in the stillness in the quiet
that's where consciousness emerges
really everything else is just the
distraction that keeps the mind focused
on these shorter loops keeps you worried
about all predators here Oh someone to
have sex with there oh here's some food
over here but when you get really still
and all of that noise dies down that's
when your consciousness can emerge and
that's really what meditation is and
there's tons of different types of
meditation of course and really you just
have to find the one that suits you the
problem with meditation for most people
they don't really know what state
they're going for when they when they
start it like yeah I'm gonna meditate so
what do you what's the end goal like
you've never been there so you don't
really know if you're meditating or if
you're just sitting still for a second
you know so that's when escalating that
technology and using some other forms
becomes really helpful so one of those
ways of course we got kevin johnson of
zero gravity floating to do here is
flotation tanks and sensory deprivation
and that's a hack that really allows
it's like it's like facilitating
meditation to the nth degree and what
it's doing is that mine that's
constantly looking for perceptions out
there in the world trying to track
things what does this feel like what
does it smell like what does this look
like what does it sound like you know
all of these things that are constantly
mirages in our mind with input in these
sensory deprivation tanks
all of that goes away stillness and then
the minds like I'm out of here but
there's nothing to do and then what
comes out is either you fall asleep
which is not optimal but it's nice or
your consciousness emerges and that
higher thinking that larger loop
thinking that essential you is allowed
to emerge and then once you've been in
the tank then it's much easier to go
back to your meditation practice and be
like okay I know what I'm going for
I know what the goal is so you can try
these different techniques like than
pasta know where you're focusing on your
breath or open focus where you're
focusing on the empty spaces in your
eyes or some other more guided
meditation the meditation I like comes
from Tom Brown and it's called the
sacred silence meditation and if
anybody's interested in a guided version
of that I have a free one up on my
website that's the one I found to be the
most effective it's kind of utilizes a
lot of different techniques and
visualization some breath but meditation
is like the staple food that's like what
you need to survive and then these other
things can be more like feast like
banquets you know you get as much as you
can but you're going to need time to
digest all that so meditation is really
important in the practice of course
floating another great way to do it
another thing is Yoga Yoga is another
fantastic art again been around thousand
years for a reason and really that's
working your mind through this exercise
linking it to breath and motion until
you're by moving outwardly and
somatically embodying and focusing
everything on that it allow your mind is
still in those few moments in shavasana
and the final rest and yoga are some of
the most peaceful still moments that
you'll find and that's again another way
to access your consciousness really have
that moment where everything gets still
another way to do it that's again been
around for thousands of years for a
reason is dance you know there's a
reason that people have been doing these
dance rituals all around the world and
it's something in the Western culture we
forgot we turn it into a party thing you
know which is great fun to party and
dance but like an ecstatic dance ritual
where instead of focusing on your breath
like in bed possum meditation
you're just allowing the music to move
your body and emptying dumping out your
mind of all the thoughts and just
focusing on the somatic sensation of
your body in motion and creating this
kind of trance that will allow your
consciousness to emerge so if you look
it up there's different ecstatic dancers
being offered around town and really
around the world it's maybe not that
widely publicized but definitely take a
look after that I'm going to be hosting
one coming up pretty soon at Black Swan
yoga because I found it to be one of the
best ways to do it because the thing
about consciousness especially with
plant medicines you tend to like access
it here you know like you're you're
projecting it out and experiencing it
kind of outside of the body but with
dance gets like right down into your
feet and your whole body becomes like a
perceiving entity where you can really
embody that consciousness so that's been
one of my favorite method
another one is shamanic breathing or
holotropic breathing pioneered by dr.
Stan Grof but it's been around in
different yogic circles for a long time
and then other different individuals
like wim HOF the Iceman who has all the
world records with standing cold in a
variety of different ways but it's a
really a process of hyper oxygenation
and through that process it becomes
almost like a psychedelic experience and
what emerges is a greater access to your
consciousness and so again another great
opportunity to look around look up
shamanic breathing holotropic breathing
something anybody can do there's no
drugs need to take there's nothing it's
going to cost you it's your own breath
you know and that's the beauty of a lot
of these different practices you don't
need anything else to do it or
facilitate it and then of course there's
plants and the plants are great first
stubborn you know stubborn minds like
myself I mean I couldn't shut this thing
off if I tried like there was just no
way I could do it I couldn't sleep I
can't you know it's really hard for me
so the the plants are more like a hammer
you know you really can't avoid it it's
going to hit you and you're going to
have to respond to it you're going to
have to surrender and allow it to take
you on that journey of consciousness
and so that started for me when I was 18
I met a shaman and we went out in the
mountains of Mexico and I took a batch
of mushrooms in the mountains and I had
my first Vision Quest so to speak and in
that I experienced my consciousness
removing from my body looking down on my
body very much like a near-death
experience like you've here looking down
on my body and going oh there's
something besides that thing that little
that neat Zach nice neat sack but this
is what is this thing that's looking at
the meat sack that's something else and
from that moment and I didn't have a
religious upbringing or much of a
spiritual practice until then but at
that point that I realized there was
something else that wasn't the meat sack
and wasn't the mind I was like oh okay
well this is something different and I
got to explore that for sure
and that was really kind of a game
changer and since then I've done most of
the major medicines of the world watch
Yuma ayahuasca iboga I've even tried
some that I highly do not recommend like
the frog venom combo which almost killed
me in Topanga Canyon there's a terrible
idea but we can talk about that if
anybody's really interested you're
interested like you almost died yes but
each of these things has their own
special gift that they're able to
provide in their own special utilization
you know and I think learning about the
nature of these medicines and what they
can offer and then trying to figure out
which one is right for you which one
you're called to and when you're doing
that really trusting trusting your
instincts trusting what you know they
call the calling and then being super
careful on who the provider is because
just because it's an indigenous shaman
doesn't mean that they're moral doesn't
mean that they're good doesn't mean that
they're not out trying to harm you
rather take your money you got to
understand that in this practice you
know especially in a lot of these jungle
scenarios you know what's the rule of
the jungle yep the rule of the jungle is
the strong eat the weak and everything
goes long and that's fine the jungle
sustains itself by the strong
continually eating the weak
well the humans of the jungle are a part
of the jungle they are a part of the
jungle
they're not separate from the jungle
they are their spirit is generally
identified with the Jaguar which is the
strongest animal in the jungle so you
got to understand for them it's not a
moral problem if you come to them weak
and there's a Jaguar and they eat you
that's just a lot of jungle and not bad
not bad people their friends don't look
at him like man look like that Jaguar
eaten weak people you know it's just
it's just a normal thing and we don't
understand that because we're like ah
how dare that obviously there's some
great job you know I've gone to many
many great healers who have dedicated
themselves to a path of pure medicine
and path of pure healing but I'd like to
throw that caveat out there because as
this becomes more popular more and more
people go down there's going to be
situations where practitioners are going
to take advantage of that to higher and
higher degrees so make sure you're being
careful I can go a little bit into the
different plants and then we'll just
kind of open this up for a conversation
so ayahuasca definitely one of the more
popular ones in you know kind of the
minds of people at this point and that's
a brew that it's been down in South
American jungles for a long time and
it's a combination of high DMT content
leaf for several different leafs
leafs Articuno oh boy yeah hey Juan bisa
and they contain either DMT and then DMT
or five Meo DMT but that's not generally
orally active and lets you combine it
with an MAOI something that inhibits the
breakdown of these different compounds
so they found that the combination of
the ayahuasca vine which is the maoi
with the DMT containing leaf allow for
an orally active DMT experience and the
DMT experience is really unlike any
other experience you could ever imagine
it seems to really open up a portal to
an entirely separate dimension whereas a
lot of the other plants kind of open up
the venetian blinds to allow you to see
this dimension in a different way the
DMT is really like you're really going
to see something else the ayahuasca
inherently though is very challenging on
the GI system cleansing but challenging
on the GI system so it has a reputation
as the vine of death why well
because you feel so bad and you're
tripping so hard that it pretty much
convinces you that you're going to die
the first time you do it and that's part
of the gift of it is that you have to
face your death and that's one of the
most pervasive fears that we all have is
this fear of death and ayahuasca will
put your face right into it until you
surrender to that fear I remember the
first time I went down and did it it
started going through this escalated
progression of the different ways that I
was dying
first there were spiders that were
crawling in my eyeballs and the spiders
were calling in my eyeballs and they
were going to explode in my brain and
spiders were just going to come out of
my face and I was like that's a good one
one point for high Watzke disappoints
Robert um but then I'd still kind of
cool with I was like okay I'm cool with
that and then so these eels came up out
of the was all my vision of course but
eels came up out of the river and they
went and burrowed into my insides and
just started thrashing around and eating
all my organs on the inside of my body I
was like ooh hole I was particularly
uncomfortable but I'm cool with that and
then it continued and then I envisioned
myself sliding down this long vine of
thorns like Jack and the Beanstalk style
long vaya thorns and I was completely
naked and the thorns were all pointing
up and that was really really I thought
rude of ayahuasca to put me through that
one but again I was kind of cool with
that so I left had to pull you know an
even greater trick out of his bags like
oh I'll be by the way you're dying of
cancer right now right now die am cancer
like that got me freaked out no no no no
he'll see him look I'm healthy I'm
strong what do you mean not dying a
cancer and it met a resistance point it
meant an actual fear something that I
was genuinely afraid of and I wrestled
with that for about two hours on the mat
where every different tried away I tried
to wiggle out with my mind and convince
myself I'm young I'm good
know everything good ayahuasca you know
would win and it would convince me the
other way and so finally I surrendered
and in life that's a really challenging
thing because you're used to seeing a
problem and then hitting it with force
I will overcome that thing I will
conquer that thing I won't beat that
opponent I will rise above and in the
plant medicine journey you have to
invert that entirely I will surrender
deeper you know I will bow lower you
know and it's this whole reverse process
that you have to learn but when you do
that's when the great rewards come so
eventually I surrendered into that and
said if that's the way you know if
that's the truth if that's the way I'm
going then so be it it's been a great
life and the minute I did that the whole
thing shifted and all of this love came
up from the earth it was like kind of
like that scene from my avatar all these
like fibers like suck me in and cradled
me into the earth it's like we're just
kidding man everything's good you're all
good oh my god
God so that was my first encounter with
the vine of death and really you know
help me transcend both the fear of death
and the fear of suffering and you learn
these things but you don't always get to
keep the games at 100% you know you have
to go back and you have to continue up
your practices and continue to access
these truths you know you reach these
Peaks it's very difficult to stay at
that peak but you get a new baseline set
you get a new truth that you can fall
back on so ayahuasca is amazing for
overcoming fear fear is something that's
in your life that's one of the best
medicines and and what I would say what
I would prescribe for anybody if fear is
the root cause which fears is a cause
for all of us you know another great one
for another great medicine is watch
human and watch human is San Pedro
cactus it's been around for thousands of
years and interestingly there was a
society pre-incan societies called
shebeen in Peru and this society
flourished for about 800 years and it
really puzzles the archaeologists
because during that eight hundred year
period there was no war there's no
evidence of weapons and destruction and
all the normal you see in human
society during that whole stretch in
that region there's none of that well
what they they the people who are
curious have not taken more tumor and
figured that out because what's human
was the sacrament of the shebeen people
and they would offer it to anybody who
came and it's one of the most heart
Bandung medicines that I've ever
encountered so really gets you back in
touch with the love for life a love for
one another love for Humanity so for me
that medicine is more about finding your
mission you know and re reinvigorating
your love for life you know and your
passion to contribute to this planet
your ability to see one another as self
living a different life and that's been
a really great gift from the medicine
watch Yuma iboga is an African shrub and
that comes from Gabon and it's
definitely the gnarliest of the medicine
so that is truly throwing yourself in
the frying pan so the medicine lasts
about 24 hours and the whole time you're
relentlessly nauseous I mean I want to
get you nauseous like nauseous like
stomach flu getting nauseous but iboga
gets you on this new level of nauseous
like you never it like recalibrates
nausea for you it feels like you're
stuck in a high voltage shed like
everything's buzzing like you can't if
you open your eyes it's like you're
looking everything is like that TV
channel that didn't get any proper
signal and it's like all lines and stuff
like that and your heart's pounding
because it's a stimulant that's why it
lasts 24 hours so you got 24 hours of
your heart pounding in this high voltage
shed in nausea it's so uncomfortable
that like just the endorphins you get
from moving like here just gives you
that moment of relief that you think and
you just fight for that on your mat
can't move for 24 hours it's hell it's
truly truly hell and the thing about
these plants is it's like they know how
long they have with you too so whereas
you know some of the shorter acting
plants will give you lessons really
quick like I got you for a hammer how
long I got five minutes okay we're going
to go in here we're going to grab this
thing the bogus got time for days so
it'll stretch something out I remember
I've taken it twice which may ask why
would you take that thing why it's
because the first time was so powerful
and for me it well I'll tell the first
story first for me that's when I really
got to identify truly and named the
three elements myself iboga told me that
this was mud body you know this was my
my meat sack my vehicle the car that I
was driving around and I really got to
understand what this thing was all about
these seven trillion cells that have all
decided to work in cooperation for the
betterment of themselves and the
organism and got to get in touch with
that what its needs were what its
desires were and then the relationship
that had with the mind and the mind
being the computer onboard that you know
send signals and allows things to
optimize survival and procreation all of
these things and then really understand
what my consciousness was and really see
the Trinity of this and it bogus
ruthless - I actually went down there
with my fiancee who I thought I was
going to spend the rest of my life with
and then for about six hours it
convinced me that we should break up and
I was like what the hell like that's not
what I came down here for and you know
again it's just me wrestling with my
mind and of course I very much love my
fiancee but both of us would agree that
splitting up was the best thing we could
have done and we're very good friends
now so a lot of insight can come when
you have these long times with the boga
a lot of lessons a lot of questions that
you can get answered also gave me access
to you know communicate and and just
understand the world in a much different
way so that's why I did it again
despite the hell but when I did it again
I kind of forgot how bad it was
like I was doing it and I was like oh no
like what did I do
why did I do this and then it proceeded
it preceded it since it knew it had 24
hours and proceeded to show me that I
was a terrible person for like six hours
like just the worst person ever just I
was like man I really suck you know and
then like six hours in it's like not
just kidding but don't be that person I
was like oh this is the worst I don't
recommend a bug a bug is very well known
for getting people out of addictions
because it's really like being an ant on
a tuning fork and you're that ants on
for discos lang and all of those
vibrations all these weird that you
have going on there's no room for that
anymore it all gets shaken clean it's
like clean slate so clinics like
Crossroads clinic down in Mexico having
amazing above 90% heroin addiction cure
rates whereas obviously standard care
methadone all these other things are
getting you addicted to a different
substance and the recidivism rate is
super high so it's extremely powerful
that for that and honestly unless you
have a significant addiction I'm not
sure a bogus really the way you need to
go I think there's like kinder gentler
ways to do this you know so hopefully
hopefully pretty soon if Maps does what
it's able to do we'll be able to have
legal mdma-assisted psychotherapy and
then if you really want to escalate
things and ayahuasca and these different
other medicines I like the ritualized
context of these medicines too there's
different ways that you can play with
these things on your own and sometimes I
can have value but sometimes I can carry
a lot of risk as well setting the right
container the right space the right
intention the right people the right
medicine super crucial you know these
aren't things to be trifled with you
know I really can't more strongly
emphasize that what you put into it on
the front end is going to be what you
get out of it on the back end so if
you're really serious about using these
as tools for consciousness not just a
carnival ride
then then really pay attention to that
set and setting I think that's crucial
so obviously there's you know other
different types of medicines and
different ways that you can do that but
you know to me whenever whenever things
are off and whatever I'm out of touch or
whenever something's going weird I feel
out of control I feel confused I just go
back to these technologies you know I
just know that as soon as my
consciousness is in the driver's seat
I'll figure it out you know one way or
another
it's going to be alright I'm gonna be
you know I'm gonna be standing on a
stage somewhere and giving a talk
everything's gonna be okay you know and
I think that's an important thing for
everybody to remember it's like we're
all pretty much bat in a thousand you
know we're all here we're all right but
nonetheless as we project out into the
future everything looks like nah
going to take me out for sure you know
but really you know in the end having
the faith that I'm going to be alright
it's going to work out one way or
another you know and generally that's
going to be rewarded a lot more than the
fear now doesn't mean you don't plan for
you know but uh but that's an
important thing in consciousness you
know and accessing that is a great way
to remind you that and and you ensure
that process happens quickly so that's a
little bit of my journey I definitely
want to leave a lot of time for
questions and I'm here and I just want
to be a service to you guys and you know
I've experienced a lot of different
stuff and so any kind of you know
personal questions or things that you
guys are stuck with let's uh let's have
a chat sound good cool mm-hmm well I had
a shaman shaman assistant and then my
fiance at the time so there was two of
us under and two of us two people
guiding okay she asked how many people
were there at the ceremony when I was
doing iboga and there was two shamans or
someone shaman one Sheldon's assistant
and then both of us were down same time
they had a shift change at about our
sixteen I'd say we're a nurse started
checking in on us
you got a question yeah
is it on doesn't sound like it's on
[Music]
that works you mentioned the idea of
there are different ways to go about
taking the plant medicines and you fully
support the idea of the shamanic ritual
as opposed to just taking it on your own
and I was wondering if you might
elaborate a little more on that with
this consideration which is for some
people having the shaman present is
adding an additional narrative that
might be influencing their own I have
done of both so I have a friend who's
done it on his own and he did all the
research on his own and he he prefers
that and then I've had the experience
where it was like with the shaman and it
was more like the idea that ayahuasca
there that there's a there's a plant
spirit and you know referred to as a
feminine kind of plants there and
there's a lot of like kind of leading
and I'm just wondering what you know if
anything what your take on it
well that's a it's an interesting
question you know for sure and I think
it really there's no exact answer to
that because it depends on the quality
of the experience the individual and the
shaman there's a lot of like
individualized parts to this if the
shaman is good they are working with the
technology that they understand - a very
good degree and so they can guide that
technology and help you access greater
you know different parts of that
technology that you wouldn't be able to
access before so if you're with a good
shaman between you know an ayahuasca
ceremony the eCos are so powerful the
songs that they sing those songs can
often guide your visions and guide your
journey in certain ways that doing it on
your own could never touch I mean I'm
certain of that but you know a good
shaman is also you know the ideal of a
shaman is to be a hollow bone is to not
push anything forward and the shamans
who are not at
good and not as skilled or have other
agendas they become more than that and
they start to influence you beyond that
and then they become almost they start
to push into your field of energy rather
than just helping draw out more I mean
the songs really and the whole ceremony
should be designed just to maximize what
you can experience yourself and then
they should be an empty hollow receiver
of that not pushing out anything forward
and the great shamans are like that now
another average random shaman you know
it may be better to do it by yourself
and I think you know one of the things
that you know there's certainly some of
them that even perhaps exacerbate the
fear that people have leading in you
know they can actually you know fear is
I think the ultimate virus it's a virus
that we catch from one another all the
time without even realizing it and a
shaman if it's if they're not good can
actually spread that virus and create
more fear surrounding more fear of the
mythology of these different things so
you know I think it's it's a balance you
know it's a balance between what they
can offer and then also you know is
there a cost associated with and how
good are they how skilled are they it's
a technique and also you know what what
medicine you're doing I think you know
really the shaman should be kind of like
a doctor in your psychic surgery you
know and they're knowing what you know
knowing what's prescribed knowing how to
do it knowing the aftercare and just
allowing you to not worry about all that
not have that doubt like I take too
much am I going to die like that I mix
that brew right you know did I do all
these different things all of that can
be really challenging and it's partly
you know the issue with most of these
people freaking out on bad you know bad
trips it's because you don't really know
if you poison yourself or not you have
no idea you know because you're not an
expert you're not a doctor you know so
it's just like kind of going in there
with the surgical tools and being like
yeah it's all right i watch youtube I
think it's good you know so I think
that's kind of where where my take is
but obviously you know a bad shaman is
going to be a lot worse than you know
you with some good music sitting around
doing it
so that's kind of where my opinion is
that does that answer your question or
yeah
so the ever fight like consumerism like
the idea that if you buy it's like when
people buy something like the product
makes them feel good there a fight like
that like that feeling or like maybe but
going back to nature like I love when I
love running in the rain that's pretty
fun like I go and I feel like that
nature like like I just feel good I feel
like myself and also I wanted to ask why
did you start on it like did you like
are you like genuinely but you seem like
you genuinely trying to help people out
so I'm sure like realizing that
consciousness is the best way to go you
know yeah I don't know if I completely
understand your your your first question
I think you know so you know I'll just
jump into the second one I think you
know for me on it consciousness is like
the tip of a pyramid and in order to get
escalate up that pyramid you have to
take care of some basic needs you have
to have ample energy and you have to be
out of pain if you look at any animal
when animals in pain it's the last
animal you want to come and hug you know
what no matter what it is it could be if
your friendliest cat but if that animal
is sick or in pain that thing's going to
hiss and lash out at you and I think all
of us most of us at least are carrying a
certain degree of pain and a certain
degree of lack of energy that creates
this kind of solipsistic inward focus
you know saying that we're all we're all
in here with our dinosaur shells and
scales on like don't with me I'm
hurtin you know I'm hurting here you
don't even know like I'll kill you you
know and that's the attitude that we
have instead of just really opening up
and embracing people and so on it's a
way to take care of those basic needs
you know and then once those basic needs
of getting your body feeling good
getting your muscles working getting
everything moving in the right direction
once those basic needs are taken care of
then the rest of this stuff really has
fertile ground
because when you're really you know when
you're really in pain you don't have
energy you're sick it's super hard to
access your consciousness not impossible
you know certainly you can do it you can
do it in any search in any situation but
becomes a lot easier when everything
else is taken care okay so to follow up
on what she was asking I was wondering
you keep saying
shaman and I was wondering if there was
a possibility of moving beyond that
language to more you know commonalities
and more possibly a theistic language of
to where it's because I know a lot of
people are avoiding these experiences
because of some kind of spiritual belief
system seems to be involved when in fact
it's a personal experience and not a
religious construct so instead of a
shaman could it not just be an
experienced individual that knows how to
keep someone from choking on their own
vomit yeah you know that any sensor that
you had on tensions and will make sure
that you could guided with those
intentions if you start to go up track
kind of so it's a difference between a
guide and a shaman is kind of what
you're saying and and I think there's
you know a guide is or a guide or a
sitter you know a lot of times they're
just called sitters just someone with
the good heart who's just kind of
keeping it you know around you keep it
in chill making sure that you know your
basic needs are met and I think that's
that's cool and that's definitely an
advisor a to do it if you know if
another skilled practitioners in there
but shaman certainly isn't religious I
mean the shaman it's it's a show not
tell art you know they're not trying
religions are all the art of telling you
know they tell you these things that you
should believe and say okay this is this
is these are our beliefs I'm going to
tell you these and believe them and
whereas the shamans are like find out
for yourself you know by now for some
what
that's not oh you're getting really
tricky now that if you're saying that
they're imposing the belief that you
should find things out for yourself I
think that's a very fair belief to
impose that's not a religion the belief
of figured out for yourself is certainly
not a religion I don't think that falls
into the definition of religion and at
least in my definition your definition
could be different that that's cool too
but that's it's not that all shamans are
like that some shamans can get religious
you know so the word shaman can mean a
variety of different things and it can
create you know certainly create issues
to me a good shaman is exactly that
someone who allows you to see your own
truth you know and gets out of the
way you know that's all a good
shaman is it just get out of the way
help and remove all the obstacles so you
can come forward with your best truth
and that's really what a shaman is and
anything else you know somebody sitting
there you know providing the ceremony
I've had both and that's awesome like
just someone who's just like you cool
you need some water like they're acting
as a shaman you know they're just trying
to get out of the way they're not saying
like they're not trying to implant stuff
in your head or tell you anything
they're just you know that's the kind of
base level of shaman we just being empty
not putting their energy onto you and so
that is that is a shaman to a certain
degree and I think we mystify that term
so much and think of them like a
priestly class it's not anybody can be a
shaman you know it's just a matter of
how they're able to get their own stuff
out of the way that to that degree that
determines you know what level they're
at but um so to me I think that's just
the most important thing at the highest
form of the art you know they're they're
the emptiest person in the room and
that'll it really allows you to come
forward to the greatest degree and I
think that's that's the difference and
also the difference between shamanism
and religion is religion is generally
you know the implanting of an idea
whereas shamanism is you know come
forward with your greatest truth and I
think that's the differentiation that I
ask
so related to the idea of intentions
like I'm wondering if you have any ideas
about people that you care about that
you think maybe you would benefit from
plant medicine but obviously you know
balancing that fine line between you
know taking an active role in you know
like you don't want to force someone to
do something but kind of I guess you
know that the the social balance of
promoting something that you think would
be good but not forcing it
yeah I've screwed that out before for
sure screwed that up before with my
girlfriend currently who I live with
I was so stoked on iboga and what I was
able to give me you know I basically
strongly encourages like you got a dry
is amazing it's going to hurt but it's
amazing and it was a totally shitty
experience for her and she wouldn't have
done that experience if I wasn't you
know kind of raving about what I was
able to do and I learned to really start
less and I was like whoa like really
this thing the only thing that we can do
is show the change and be you know
embody what we've experienced and I
tried the same thing with my family I
tried to get my family to go down and do
I wast and do all this stuff until
finally I like just rid myself of that
of that desire of trying to again like a
bad shot and putting my thing on them
and making them go do it just to really
embody how I felt and you know tell the
story as cleanly as possible and then
all of a sudden they're like man we want
to go down there and do it I was like
whoa you know so I think the only thing
that you can do is just be open and just
explain how that was how that affected
you and they'll see that and if they're
ready and if they're ready to see that
and they're ready for that they'll come
forward and they'll answer that calling
but anytime I've tried to like you know
push people into it it's been generally
met with less than desirable results so
I've learned kind of the hard way that
just embody that feeling that you
receive from these things and the people
will come forward when they're ready
that it's regression
so I've started looking into having the
ayahuasca experience but in my research
being a woman I've heard that's very it
that's kind of especially dangerous to
do alone but and that's maybe not the
intention I have to do it alone
however do you have any advice for
finding a good shaman or any tips on
avoiding pitfalls any comments it falls
in yeah you know it's generally good to
you know get advice from people who have
been there and know these different
centers know the different places well
but it's also hard because you know it's
hard to be fully aware of what's going
on when the game is being played at you
know different levels that are above
yours you know above your awareness so
for me you know I've experienced a lot
of these different things and I'm pretty
plugged in so I'm comfortable I have no
financial interest in any ayahuasca
centers but I'm comfortable recommending
a few I have those on my website Aubry
Marcus comm /faq and you can read about
them there's about three centers or show
that I can recommend or impeccable in
that nature because you're absolutely
right you know you talk to somebody like
my friend amber lyon who runs reset on
me and she got a boob fondle the first
time she was doing ayahuasca which is
not exactly what you want to have happen
in your first trip down to the jungle so
that's certainly a common story and you
hear it all the time it's again just
that kind of jungle mentality of strong
preying on the weak and it's it's
unfortunate but there's a couple centers
that I can recommend that I know are
practicing at both moral and medicinal
standards so thank you
so you've been referred to a lot of the
plant-based medicine as technologies
have you actually applied other actual
more technical approaches to achieving
some of these same results like there
are neurofeedback biofeedback facilities
that people can go to and kind of in the
same way be in isolation and in with
regards to like a shaman there's you
know people probably turning knobs
behind the scenes that put you into an
experience for a period of time that I
think people come out of it with some of
the same awareness and consciousness
effects yeah so you know I consider
floatation sensory deprivation one of
those technologies certainly that
doesn't occur naturally in nature I use
the muse headband which is a portable
EEG device that helps with biofeedback
for meditation I think that's a great
piece of technology I think I'm waiting
for some of that kind of other more
brute force brainwave manipulation to
kind of flower a little a little more
and let the research get a little more
definite on that before I go tinkering
in that in that way but that's just a
personal preference I think if you want
to be on the frontier of that I think
it's going to be very promising and
ultimately you know manipulating our
brainwave patterns is going to be really
essential
I think binaural beats is another
interesting thing that I've played with
which is the technology to help with
brainwave entrainment so there's a lot
of different things that I do play with
but you know I'm a little scared of the
kind of the brute-force methods that are
that are still out there now and I'm
going to kind of hold back I mean I'm
still listening to Pandora I'm not even
on Spotify yet you know I let things I
let things you know have their time how
are you oh you re right here cool
hey don't Albert good um so you spoke on
some of the more exotic plant medicines
mmm
my question was on the more conventional
one which is cannabis cannabis and magic
mushrooms hmm with the magic mushrooms
I've heard Rogan talk about the heroic
dose and what that what he said you know
I think people the heroic dose it's like
it's like grand icing this
this moved like I'm going to rip myself
to shreds and then find me the truth
because I feel a totally unnecessary I
guess it's the the concept of a heroic
tale right and I'm saying I'm not saying
it's a bad question I'm not saying that
that concept I'm saying like I don't
recommend it is what I'm saying I'm
saying minimum effective dose you know
like that's how you build a hero it's
not like throw them into the garbage
disposal and hope they come out alive
you know I've tried that method that
tries to punch and it's generally not
preferable to that to that minimum
effective dose what's going to get you
there without without pushing you too
far it's like any good workout you know
like you can go to the gym and Faraj
yourself and get rhabdo and out to sit
out for you know three weeks after
you're done because you're all up
and you got injuries and or you can
just push yourself to that point where
you really work in your breaking down
muscles but your body has time to
recover it's the same with the psyche
you want that you want to push yourself
of course but you want to give yourself
enough time to recover and not let
things get completely shook out and so I
think the concept of heroic dose is
problematic I think really you know you
should you build this like you build a
true hero you know how is a hero built
well time and time again working at his
craft working at a skill you know
getting better battling resistance you
know so I think that's that's kind of
the key so for me you know
gram gram and a half of mushrooms I
don't don't go over that you know I
don't think that you know I don't think
that you need to I think you can just
push that you know push that as much as
as much as you need it I have certainly
gone way over that and there is
something to be said for that at the
right time in the right place for sure
but but for me I think minimum effective
dose is definitely what you're looking
for you're going to get the best results
whether you're working out at the gym or
you're working out your psyche so that's
kind of my magic mushroom mushrooms are
an interesting one you know there's
certainly a strong allied for me I feel
like it's there like an older brother
you know as some of these are like you
know more like grandfathers we just sit
and listen to the wisdom you know
mushroom you know they'll with you
a little bit and but they'll teach you
some stuff and so they've been a strong
ally for me along
and they've taken me to some of the most
intense experiences and some of the most
pleasurable experiences you know and
I've really developed a relationship
where I feel comfortable with that
medicine outside of kind of a shamanic
container so it's been a real Ally for
me certainly in that regard but you know
it's definitely something again as long
as you stick with minimum effective dose
I think that's that's really really the
way to go and then cannabis I think has
a lot of you know a lot of value in a
lot of promise as well certainly it's
one of the most recreationally abused
medicines but when you're actually you
know using it with an intention I think
for me the intention that I get out of
cannabis is just body awareness like
somatic awareness like if I want to
figure out why my neck is hurting up
here you know and I eat enough cannabis
then I'll start to track that down I'll
find like 10 spots in my body and just
really kind of understand how my energy
force is working really good for
different things like that and also you
know unlocking creativity in different
other aspects so I'm really happy that
the world is growing up and not throwing
people in jail for these and when you
use cannabis do you experience the
paranoia that a lot of people do and
what does that tell you about using it
does I tell you anything or does it just
mean useless you know it's funny like
I've a lot of people come to me and talk
to me about psychedelics and they're
like man I don't know if I could do that
because I ate too much weed once and it
was intense it was like yeah
weed too much wants to or more than once
and it's the worst thing ever you know
it's like eat you know when you go
overboard on that and again you're not
abiding by that minimum effective dose
kind of mentality is how like it's not
an easy ride you know certainly not it's
not like just because this is this is
the one that's the most legal and most
accessible but it's like a patsy you
know it's it's a beast you know and if
you go overboard and you do too much
you're going to have to pay the
consequences and as far as the anxiety
you know I'm not sure that cannabis
creates anxiety or just reveals the
anxiety that you already have inherently
within you and so allowing you to work
through it you know I'm not convinced
that it's actually planting anything
there at all it's almost like damn I've
been anxious this whole time I've been
paranoid this whole time now I get a
chance to look at it like okay well how
do I get out how do I get through this
well the anxiety is linked to a fear
well what's the fear linked to well it
appears linked to this and then you just
start to track it all the way through
and then you can you can work through it
cool okay so my Clement I'll see if I
can write this question correctly so you
seem to be very much man at peace and I
was just wondering when you get back
from you know these medicinal journeys
what kind of decisions that how that
influences the decisions in your life
and how it is that you maintain the
peace junot thing does that make sense
yeah I mean it's so integration is a
really important part of these things
that's the recovery from these these
intense psychic workouts and again I've
screwed that up a bunch of times I've
jumped right back in of been in the
jungle 16 days and like what's
going on my company and jump back into
14 hour days and completely fried myself
on the way back and certainly did not
look like a peaceful man at those points
as well but you know I think the key is
you got to realize like the extent to
which like what you push yourself
through and then having enough time and
ample time to recover and kind of
reintegrate that's really really crucial
otherwise things get out of balance and
in general you know I'm constantly
remembering and forgetting remembering
forgetting remembering forgetting but
each time you know I feel like the
forgetting gets a little bit shorter and
the remembering gets a little bit easier
and the baseline starts to move
gradually gradually so the level of you
know the baseline level is just you know
steadily moving and that to me is is a
sign of optimization but at the same
time you know the graph looks like a bad
stock day you know I mean it's it's up
and down all the time and I'm you know
I'm not immune to the to the struggles
and the franticness and the panics and
and all of that but ultimately that base
level of just peace and access to
consciousness
oh sure
I mean my life stops constantly evolving
I'm constantly changing the the people
that I mean it's I don't you know I'm
not someone that gets kind of stuck or
attached to things very much so I'm just
moving with what I think will be the
optimal experience you know again
seeking that that path that's going to
bring the both to bring the best to me
and my life so you know the more
expansive I get it's also another
interesting thing like you start to
create you know energy almost gravity
that starts to pull other like-minded
people towards you you know the more
that you push out this kind of message
and it's this emanation of just the
consciousness that you're accessing the
more other people will kind of like and
then you'll draw start to draw in other
people along that way so I found that
process certainly happening and
certainly appreciated you know it really
feels like the wind is at your back when
when stuff like that's happening and
that's great you know sometimes it feels
like you're running uphill and a
headwind too but you know it's part of
life what makes it stronger
Aubrey thanks a lot for bringing this
fascinating information to us Otsuka
I've had a the opportunity to hear you
speak several times at conferences like
this and I've tuned into a lot of your
podcasts and I've always respected the
the strength and courage that you've
showed as such a strong advocate for
these kinds of medicines and these
techniques but I often also find myself
wondering what kind of challenges you
face personally kind of bridging these
two worlds where like on one hand you
know you're a very successful
businessperson and you have a very
public profile when it comes to that and
yet also somehow you managed to bring
this other more esoteric subject in and
table that I'm wondering if you have
advice for people about how to be a
strong advocate for psychedelics and
plant medicines and things like that
without it disrupting your professional
this world and things like that yeah
well thanks have appreciate the kind
words you know I I think to me I'm just
committed to telling the truth and
providing myself as a service to you
know a service to as many people as
possible and to me it just feel it would
feel weird to succeed but hold this back
like I have secrets these are my secrets
you know like this has held me this has
helped me a lot so I got to talk about
it whether that hurts me or not so it's
almost not even it's almost like not
even a question you know like it I can't
I can't do any other you know I have to
talk about these things because that
would violate a code that's much deeper
and then than any of this so and I just
try to tell it as straightforward as
possible I think where a lot of people
you know they they get attached to these
things and they get you know to
identified with it and they push that
out there too much you know and and so
it becomes like I am the mystical man
look at me mystical man you know and
people like you you know so I think
that's kind of an issue and it can go
the other way too you know obviously you
can be like go anything with
spirituality you know you can there's
disease everybody tries to identify with
one thing and I just try to tell it like
it is
you know I've had amazing spiritual
experiences and amazing corporeal
experiences and you know I enjoy a
nightclub and an ayahuasca ceremony both
and I'm cool with that
and I think that's you know I think that
just really resonates with people that
message and its really made it made it
easy because I approach it from a point
of practicality like this has helped me
you know do you like things that help
you or no like this is help me and you
do it if you want yeah so I think that's
that's pretty much it so um thank you so
much you're welcome and I'm so glad that
you guys had a really productive
discussion we need to set up for the
next speaker but let's give a really big
[Applause]