[Music]
while continuing with our program at
this time we're happy to welcome to the
stage our next presenter
i hope
i would like to introduce marco pesci
presenting a software-defined metro
fabric architecture using disaggregated
switching and vxlan
marco is a global technical architect at
pluribus networks and traveled from san
francisco the san francisco bay area to
join us today this is marco's first time
presenting at nanag and it's a pleasure
to have him speaking today welcome marco
thank you steve
thank you
very excited to be here back on stage
after
quite a few years and
i wanted just to thank you
my mentor melchior
valerie and the nano staff for having me
um so uh
let me just grab this i'm gonna need it
so the title is quite long i try to bid
for the
longest title price at the conference
but
i think i failed and i'm pretty sure
the acronym at the end was probably the
point where i failed
anyway that's fine so what i want to
discuss today is
a technology that actually is native to
data center environment
that uses vxlan and top of rack switches
with sdn
with an sdn controller and how that can
apply to metropolitan transport
and
like
many other stories this starts back in
2016.
in 2016
i met a fellow a mate in in madrid
he started working for this major
company that was um offering data center
space to big to be customers of
big enterprise customers but also telco
operators
in the major cities in
in spain and and portugal and he tells
me well marco i have this new project is
a network architect very very
brilliant
i have this new project um there are
several customers who started asking me
can you guys sell us uh point-to-point
services between cities
to interconnect our data centers
and so i i've been evaluating possible
solutions and the the one that i have
which is mpls based
is is too expensive so the project is
gonna be canned so is there something
you can do since you're working on vxlan
to provide a similar service and i tell
you well actually yeah we we have just
developed a vxlam pseudo wire
and it's the first in the industry i
mean 2016 there was no concept of the
exam pseudo wire yet in in the
preliminary evpn drafts so that's how it
started
and eventually we did the poc
it went very well
and
customers started
buying the solution they liked it very
much and so now we have real madrid we
have customers like vodafone passing and
pls traffic between between cities so
that's how it started
five years later um here to kind of show
you the experience that i had for this
type of project and a little bit about
myself
i have the fortune to work for a company
blurry boost networks that provides an
awesome technology for data center
solution which is about
using a software
network operating system that runs on
commodity switches and has an offer an
sdn abstraction inside the os itself
without using an external controller and
i'm also lucky for the fed the company
is quite small so i can have a dual role
uh so i'm actually leading the technical
field worldwide but i'm also
contributing a lot
uh to the product definition
and working with with our engineering
team to develop the product and how it
evolves
as a background right now i've i've been
focusing a lot on a new technology
called dpu data processing units you can
think about it like a switching
miniature that has a network interface
car form factor
and sits inside your server but has
hardware accelerated network functions
and i've been doing a lot of vxlan-based
solutions for distributed data centers
active active dr solutions
um as an experience i've been with peru
seven years previously almost 20 years
with cisco and and others a lot of
routing and switching
um i always liked and had a little bit
of a passion about being hands-on and
how to
then manage the solution and so
if it was let's say to have an
experience
with for example
um
tl1
which is which is the cli very
structured
but also you know concept like uh
stacking and uh virtual switching or
satellite switches that that's really
what drove my experience uh in
networking in the in the past 25 years
so today for um
for the discussion right so i like to um
kind of evaluate the different and
predominant architecture that are used
today
uh or or that have been evaluating uh
today for metro ethernet transport i
like to focus uh particularly on l2 vpn
services um and and also in terms of
layers
definitely metro metro aggregation but
this principle in theory apply also to
l3 vpn services and other layers in the
network
i'd like to
take a look and show you how
the modernization of data center
technologies can also have applicability
into distributed networks like like
metro ethernet use cases
and particularly i like to
contrast a little bit how the different
technologies differ in terms of scale
both on the operational scale um
and also control plane and and
performance in general
and finally before wrapping up and and
taking your questions i'll be happy to
show you a real world example
okay so um
for l2 vpn uh
meth compliant maf stands for metro
ethernet forum
services the de facto standard the
predominant technology today is vpls
but the recurring questions that most of
you have and a lot of my customer had is
is there a better way is there a better
cost-effective technology
that takes me out for
being obliged to use a very expensive
hardware
and is there a better way we just saw a
presentation earlier to to manage a a
distributed set of nodes that kind of
you know takes down my operational cost
for for the solution
so one of the answers that the industry
has to offer and has been offering for
decades
is uh
layer two fabrics not not just saying q
and q but but others as well and and the
nice thing of this
uh bridge fabric is um the fact that uh
you know historically the being the
first attempt
to use commoditized switching to provide
high gigabit uh performance uh to
distributed networks
any metro ethernet okay q and q but also
for example i have some competitive
information for the asian market south
american market huawei has been using
triple q
in the in the transport network uh most
of you at hopefully a good experience
with brocade vdx which was a trill-based
fabric
so all these experiences different
technologies
had in common the simplicity of the
solution a vlan or a vlan based service
as a concept in a bridge network is
conceptually simple structurally simple
and also from a management perspective
is kind of a plug-in
network where i define
the service i don't think the pointer
work but in in this diagram where i'm
visioning a
a metro ethernet network with three main
sites where i have a customer blue at
these three main sites
asking for a mesh
a vlan service so this type of offer
can be you know either very reasonable
operative cost
can be deployed by just defining the
vlan in one of the sites
and then in the moment i assign this
vlan
uh to each of the three ports in the
three different sites well because this
is a bridge network the vlan gets just
distributed so from
a management perspective the effort is
you know
quite negligible
and so this is really what i like of
this type of architecture
unfortunately
you know a loop
a layer 2 meltdown is the worst
nightmare for a network administrator
and
there's some fragility in the
architecture here
there's also some
issues in managing multipathing
efficiently
for example what i'm representing here
in this picture there are some dotted
lines that represent
hot standby links that are not in use so
these are kind of the challenges that
prevent
um layer two fabrics to kind of grow in
size and and there's also some limits
definitely in the in the scale being
being a vlan technology
but still still a good successful
alternative uh to other technology like
for example ipm pls and definitely ipmp
ls is the
and
one one of the
great things here is uh um you know
bringing a resilient transport uh
with a with a layer three routed network
in in the transport
and so implementing uh you know best
path efficient routing
uh including active active ecmp based
routing so definitely that's uh that's
the advantage
on the let's say minus side we know that
this type of protocols are quite
demanding
uh there's definitely an operational
cost in the plumbing this type of
network but there's also a harder cost
associated with the fact that i need a
router or a
highly performant switch asic like for
example broadcom
camran or jericho families
so is there an alternative to this
and yes vxtan and evpn this is not new
what brings a vxlan
fabric to the picture here
the nice thing of a layer 3 transport so
vxlan is a udp-based protocol
it's very
nice to
firewalls but beyond that the main
interesting part is that it is a light
encapsulation protocol and it's nicely
load balanced so i can have flow
balancing a very efficient per flow
based on the vxlan udp entropy
and definitely you know i can leverage
all the
uh
uh pluses of having a routed transport
in in the core
um the good thing also is when i add a
control plane to the vxlan transport
that is evpn i can really you know refer
to a model where there's a good
separation between an underlay network
which is basically the core transport
and the overlay
network which is where we deploy and we
offer the services to the customers
and that you know kind of gives us
different tools to attack
each of these two
components of the solution with uh with
the best with the best architecture so
for example for the underlay
which is uh the part of the network that
i deploy first is my day one deployment
i can you know depending on the topology
decide where i put my pe vpn
speakers right for this simple topology
for example i can have three speakers
where in the sites where i deploy the
service and i can have three mutual evpn
adjacency so that means that
there are the four routers in the middle
just run
an igp or a bgp protocol so as simple as
that
of course if this topology grows in size
then i can still use vpn to peer up with
the upstream switches
and so kind of limit the number of
adjacency so i have many options like
for any
router design so that's really great and
once the underlay has been designed and
deployed then i can focus uh for my
daily operation just on the overlay
services and i define them at the edge
in every site and then magically thanks
to the evpn control plane vxlan tunnel
are are created side to side for for
each service like for example the blue
service here towards the the customer
sees
this is not new right there's a lot of
literature
for example
richard steenberger i've presented a
paper at nanook in 2018
but also i found a reference in
brazil ix
from a plm
works for extreme
and and the conclusion is vxlan is is a
great tunneling technology it's very
light uh compared to mpls encapsulation
um
it requires some control plane though
and
one alternative could be an sdn
centralized controller approach but the
problem with that it doesn't scale
um and so evpn is a preferred control
plane approach because it scales
uh in terms of network size and and and
multi-tenant
size skate
um
now why
we haven't seen so many deployments or
at least in my experience i don't see a
lot of evpn deployments in in metro
i think one of the reason is the
complexity of the vpn configuration
um so i i talked to many customers who
tell me well actually yeah it's nice but
you know
at the end
for the
l2 vpn i need
mostly our point to point
well i just use static vxl antennas i
don't use vpn at all
others have been looking at
management solutions that work out of
the box
in in a server
there's of course a lot of
home built automation
uh that is necessary to to orchestrate
such a a complex configuration where i
have
for example for ll3 vpn service i i need
about 30 lines of code
per switch which is which is a little
bit too much
um if we look at
this problem a little bit more closely
the problem i need to solve is the fact
that i have to deploy a service in three
sites using evpn
and the configuration in these three
switches or six switches if there's
redundancy
needs to match
and this is not an easy task
um first because there's high code that
needs to be kind of abstracted somehow
but the main problem is the
configuration state of each of these
switches is completely independent
they run on their own
even if i'm using
an orchestration system
that manages individual
each of these switches using ssh
sessions
it's not that a switch is aware that he
has to
speak only to the management system
to the automation
ansible tower etc right so if i'm a
network admin and i'm using the
credential that the automation system is
using i can go on and switch and try out
something maybe a little bit of sandbox
right
and then what happened when
for some reason the same identifiers are
used for a service in production to a
customer
right so either my automation system
fails doesn't know how to roll back
uh it's
very difficult to troubleshoot the
problem or maybe i can you know just
have a silent
go well the service was already there
let's go ahead no alarms no warnings and
then what i end up is well that customer
service no more isolated
so definitely these are the
things that you know
make us scratch our heads how can we
solve this
uh if you allow me to take a further
look at the configuration
the problem also derives from you know
30 plus years of history inside inside
switching and routing code
and all vendors are kind of in the same
situation here right so
we developed
uh different interfaces different
modules that
just got reused when we implemented
vxlan and when we implemented the vpn on
top
so for example if you cannot go through
any vpn config
you may recognize three main blocks of
configuration these are completely
independent structures okay
there's the definition of
the service locally
right the vlan so that i can attribute
these
uh services to physical ports facing dc
site
um i need also to identify the service
in the data plane but towards the
transport side
so i need for example to define a vxlan
dni identifier
in the vxlan realm
um and then there's the evpn control
plane where i need to to define a route
distinguisher i need to import and
export
uh route targets
now some of the vendors have improved
offer some compression of this
configuration but the problem still
exists in the majority so i need to
make these three components
match inside one switch
and i need this configuration state to
match across my entire network so if i
have a mesh service
with
10 nodes then i may end up in in
consuming almost you know hundreds and
hundreds of lines and how can i scale to
thousands of these services
so that's the problem that we have tried
to resolve
let's put some sort of software-defined
abstraction and let's try to run it
inside the switch itself let's try to
rewrite the code so that we can define
an object atomically for an entire
distributed network
so the approach is not the different
from
evpn and
vxlan principle
we still have a distinction between
underlay and overlay
the underlay is a router network you can
use any
router technology you can use ebgp you
can use an igp
and you're completely free to pick up
the design that you want
but then we have
some
interesting application that runs on the
switches at the edge of this topology
that
creates an sdn cluster or an sdn domain
so essentially it's like a federation
it's a
mesh application
that it's based on a mutual peering
across all these switches that
participate in this domain
and it's based on security cv it's a tls
based application okay so that creates a
logical cluster that basically turn
every switch into a line card of a
virtual chassis
and one of the benefits that this
architecture provides is a single point
of management a single point of truth
so that means that when i have to define
my service
for customer blue
my three-way service i define it once
i define it once by connecting to
any of the switches in the topology
using ssh or using a gui
right but
the switch and
the sdn mesh
takes care of bringing that
configuration and committing to all the
switches if something goes wrong on one
of the switches like in the example i
made before
well
that configuration command will fade
so i go back and i check what's what's
wrong but i'm never in a situation where
i have
an inconsistent
provisioning state
so um kind of to summarize what we saw
we saw bgp vpn which is a problem
technology that scales very well
but has some caveats in terms of
management scale
an sdn a centralized controller approach
has been
confirmed by the industry like not being
a good fit
because it lacks the network scalability
that we need to have for a distributed
network solution like this one
so
a distributed sdn approach
that works either in conjunction with
evpn for the forwarding plane
or without vpn with just uh routing is
uh in my opinion this is my test is
the great approach for this type of
networks
at least it provides
a way to
um to have a valid low-cost alternative
to vpls
uh i wanted to spend just two minutes on
because probably distributed controller
versus centralized controller is
a debate that is a little bit new to
this audience so let me just spend two
minutes here and comparing the two so on
the left i have the centralized approach
on the right a distributed controller
approach
the goal is the same so i have a network
here with six
leaves and two spines and i want to
manage it consistently as a single point
of touch
when i use a centralized controller
approach
the domain of the network
includes also the spine includes also
the transport
and when i use a distributor controller
approach the spine are just transport
node could be running
any
routing stack of any vendor
right and and this is kind of a one of
the advantages
that the distributor controller approach
brings in
um
then of course in the distributed
controller
case the controller resides inside the
switch and the control plane scales as
the network grows
in the centralized controller
situation i have a single controller i
need to make sure i have
high availability some clustering
technology there that also allows the
controller to be present
at any site potentially because i may
lose one site and i and i still need the
controller
so definitely these are cost
implications and architecturally
although it may look simple the
centralized controller is not a good fit
for a distributed network so that's kind
of the conclusion and
one last thought
um
data center switching
has
has been
kind of evolving right from
chassis based solution to scale out
solution
um the solutions that are available
today with commoditized top of rack
scale very well in terms of a number of
tenants
and so i don't see why this
transformation can also apply to
distributed networks so i don't see the
need of using
the buffers
or custom silicon
because everything we need is actually
there it's just a matter of applying the
best design practices that we
experienced in data centers
also to distributed networks
and i
at the end of my presentation i
show you just a quick example here of a
real world network i'm
considering here a kind of a hybrid um
service provider that maybe started
offering edge data center services and
specialized
into
some specific application for example
the customer i have in mind here started
working with the film with the movie
industry and specialized in
image processing a lot
and and of course when you start
offering certain services you care about
the performance of the service and the
performance of the service depends
definitely on the connectivity and so
the higher the bandwidth i'm able to
offer the service to the lower the
latency
the more quality the service has and and
the better i can monetize the service
and compete with
with a public cloud for example so
that's kind of the story here um the key
takeaways
are
on the ring on the left right and i'm
using here all
toporak switches that provide 10g to 25g
down to the customer
on the ring on the left i can replace a
g1832 ring
with a routed ring that uses best path
for for routing i can go further than
that if i introduce dwdm
uh i can actually turn a ring into a
logical leaf and spine this has been
proven
there's a lot of literature look for
example at m6 the netherlands internet
exchange company
they uh they wrote a paper about this
also using using pureboost technology
and the bottom line
here is bgp end to end from top to to
bottom
and i can use an sdn domain that
stretches across all the distribution
network and that allows me to define
customer services at one click in one
atomic parish
so that's the conclusion of my
presentation so i'll
steve if you want to
come
for any questions
again folks if you have questions feel
free to use the microphones in the room
uh any folks who are remote or would
like to solicit questions over the chat
interface i'm happy to relay them here
this may be a dumb question because it's
not yeah there are no dumb questions oh
i can i can break that
uh
but when you've got a centralized sdn
control plane you know the controller
touches all the nodes to ensure the
configuration is in sync
if you have a node in a distributed
control plane like this that becomes
isolated yeah um
how does it resume sync with the system
when
right right it would have that
centralized plan right right or how do i
manage split brain situation right so
when a node goes off um
the node has still a configuration that
is local it's just a copy of the entire
fabric configuration
so it has a way even if it becomes
isolated to provide a continue to
provide local services
then from
a management perspective if i lose a
note and it's a temporary situation well
i go and resolve that um if i really
lost for example a switch because of a
major
problem and i need to replace that then
i'm kind of in a situation where i
cannot create
fabric-wide services
because there's no consensus
right from this node that
went offline
so one possibility i can do is i
basically exclude from participating to
the consensus so that allows me to
continue operating the network and
deploy new services and by the time
the switch comes back maybe two days
later i found a spare and i replace it
well at that point the switch comes back
joins back the sdn fabric and well the
switch you know it's very different from
the vpn right the switch has a
conscience that is part of an sdn domain
so we'll just ask for the source of true
so it will ask the other switches in the
fire hey what's the latest configuration
it gets it and comes back up so all
normal so that's that's how we manage it
it works very very well
thanks
any other question
steve remote you're good
as good as i can be then we're good
merci
thank you
thank you marco
thank you for your time appreciate it
[Music]