[Music]
at this point it's a great pleasure to
introduce sylvie laperriere
um a builder of the global internet she
leads the africa global network
acquisition team at google and was
previously an interconnection strategist
for google's peering caching and cloud
a recognized leader silvi has been
involved in the governance of non-profit
tech organizations
having chaired the board of directors of
two internet exchanges amzix and the
montreal exchange and she volunteered
for five years here at nanog
she chairs the board of directors of
canada's advanced research and
innovation network
and serves on the college durochard bear
education board of directors
sylvia promotes diverse talent inclusion
by coaching and mentoring young ict
professionals and promoting science and
technology careers with teenagers and
underrepresented groups
a proud mother of three inspiring young
adults she enjoys the company of friends
and family reading hiking discovering
the world and meeting new people
and montreal is her hometown from birth
we are delighted that she will be
talking to us this morning about
developing the internet during a
pandemic and her experiences building a
submarine cable during a pandemic
or without any travel
silly please come to the stage
[Applause]
and there's the remote
good luck
bonjour
you should all be familiar with this
greeting by now
francais
ugly
see
english for english
so if you can muster some frenglish you
will feel right at home here in montreal
so as fergus said i was born raised and
educated in montreal
and it's been my gateway
to the world
my starting point in the international
telecommunication journey and nanog
i started my career in 1993 as a young
grad at teleglobe canada
in 1996 i launched as6453
which you probably recognize
in 2013
i co-founded kicks the montreal internet
exchange a proud sponsor today
uh so nanag and me
uh
i got involved with nanog the first time
was 2003. i attended nanak 30 in miami
and then um
i have to admit you're an intimated
intimate
intimidating bunch
it took me nine nanaks to
muster the courage to put a presentation
together and i presented at nana 39 in
toronto
on the taiwan earthquake
cable cuts
and then i got involved
i felt
i felt some comfort here
in exchanging ideas
as a healthy place for a debate and i
decided that i should
try to lead the change from the inside
so i wanted more representation in nanog
so i had to
advocate what i preached and i got
involved so i joined the program
committee and then the board of
directors
and i've attended i don't know i think
probably around 14 nanooks but i'm sure
one of you in this room will be able to
keep me straight
so building networks during a pandemic
what could possibly have changed
everything
so before the pandemic
the
my
way of doing things or i guess my team's
way of doing things
we were going on site we were developing
relationships so there was a lot of
traveling involved
definitely probably more than my body
could sustain
but it was part of the job
now during the pandemic
my world completely changed i was at
home 24 7
and i think for more than 800 days
and i felt some loneliness i also felt
some powerlessness i felt that
everything was a struggle difficult
talking to people
had to be booked
programmed a water cooler conversation
had to be an event in my calendar
so that i could connect
so i i felt unconnected and my job is to
connect the world but i personally felt
unconnected
however my sense of purpose
was intact
and that that kept me going
so i'm here to um talk to you about
google's network infrastructure
investments
in the on the african continent more
specifically the equiano cable
announced in june
equiano is the next generation subsea
internet cable that will ultimately run
from portugal to south africa
along the atlantic coast of africa
the initial configuration of the cable
system include
landings in lomme togo
lagos nigeria the largest african
economy cape town in south africa
the continent's most advanced economy
and swakopmund namibia
the cable has already made several
landings i'll shed some light on that
later and it's expected to go live by
the end of this year
in this presentation
i want to highlight why africa is so
central to google's plans to get to the
next billion users online
as many of you probably know
the continent is the most underserved in
terms of internet infrastructure
with penetration and uptake of online
technology and services lagging behind
other regions
for many people around the world
africa evokes images of poverty
famine or conflict
in other words
major challenges
while it's true that the continent
continues to face challenges this
perspective masked much of the reality
on the ground
in the tekken connectivity spheres in
particular we've seen exponential growth
in investments
from local and international players
like google in recent years
these investments are having a
transformative impact
on the continent accelerating
sustainable economic growth
creating much needed jobs
and creating the right conditions for
the continent to flourish
africa is no longer a continent we can
ignore
its population is set to almost double
by 2050
that's only
30 years
when a quarter of the world's people
will be african
its economy is expanding quicker than
anywhere else
its innovation and venture capital
system is growing at a record rate
underpinned by young and growing pool of
professional developers
after setting the scene and explaining
why africa is already so important
and will become even more important in
the coming years i'll shed some night on
equiano what it does who it serves and
what milestones
we've already reached
so
why
sorry i should have moved to this slide
why africa
firstly it's important to remember that
africa is not a country it's a continent
of 54 countries
each with their own culture history
economy
states of development
and levels of stability
and each of them offer different
opportunities
the continent is often painted with a
broad brush
but there are immense variations between
africa's countries
there's a huge difference between
nigeria the largest economy with a
population of 200 million people
centered around the economic capital and
powerhouse that is lagos
and the continent's six island states
that have combined population of less
than 30 million people
likewise there's a huge difference
between togo
and nigeria two countries where equiano
is landing
that are separated only by 50 kilometers
but with a different language and
different economy
from an internet connectivity
perspective sub-saharan africa remains
the most underserved region in terms of
internet infrastructure
penetration stands at 32 percent
while for the entire continent including
north africa it's at 40 percent
by contrast internet penetration by
population in the us and in north
america is around 90 percent
across the continent a significant share
of the population lives without internet
access that is fast reliable
cheap and of good quality
in other words
something we all here at nanog take for
granted
and have taken for granted
well over a decade or actually i should
say we have worked hard well over a
decade from this there's a clear need to
invest in network infrastructure
to boost connectivity across the
continent and get more people online
more importantly the continent
need for improved connectivity is also
based on future gap
let me show you these
africa is home to 1.3 billion people
or currently 16
of the global population
of the 20 fastest growest growing
country in the world
19 are in africa
projections indicate that 87 population
growth in africa between 2020 and 2050
will result in a total population of 2.5
billion
the african continent is demographically
young
60 percent of the population will be
under 24 years of age by 2025
and africa will be home to one in three
youth
globally
by 2050.
in parallel
africa is experiencing rapid
urbanization
with 68 cities each home to over 1
million people
in 2020
the number of such cities is projected
to increase by
by 2025
in three years
some countries nigeria ghana and angola
among them
will see the proportion of urban
residents increased to over 80 percent
of their total population by 2050.
when 800 million more africans will have
moved to urban areas
in addition there's been a general
improvement in life expectancy as
sub-saharan africans are expected to
need to live nearly six years longer
than a decade ago
what does this all mean
simply put these positive trends suggest
a higher adoption of digital services in
africa and the future in other words
many of the next billion users to come
online in the coming years
will be from africa
what do these demographic trends mean
for africa's economy
the answer is that africa's demographic
boom fuels consumption
young africans consumers are becoming
more affluent and globalized as they
also grow to become household decision
makers
this boosts the continent's
competitiveness in both skilled and
unskilled labor and will lead to
increased spending
increased spending power
for consumers by 2030
africa is expected to be home to over
1.7
billion consumers with total consumer
expenditures of 2.5 trillion
these trends are already at work
africa's economy has expanded
significantly over the last decade and
an average faster and on average faster
than most other regions
after years of negotiation
the african continental free trade area
fcfcfta came into effect in january
2021.
it's the world's largest free trade area
by number of members
covering 1.3 billion
individuals across 54 countries with a
combined gdp of
3.4 trillion dollars
as i said earlier
we can no longer ignore the african
continent at google we are bullish about
the africa africa's future and that's
why we're investing today to bring more
people online and broaden access to
digital services
google is by no means the only
international tech company or backbone
operator doing this
over the
last few years
we've seen groundswell interest of an
investment by african and international
investors a few merit attention
facebook meta is spearheading a
consortium of network operators and
telcos to build a submarine cable called
to africa
that will encircle the african continent
and should go live in 2024.
last year
equinix announced it was acquiring main
one
a pioneering nigerian company that
operates
a submarine cable along the west coast
of africa
as well as a leading west african data
center business
in january of this year
digital realty announced the acquisition
of terraco
africa's largest colocation provider
by 2025
the internet economy has the potential
to contribute
180 billion to africa's economy growing
to
712 billion by 2020 2050.
covet 19 delayed growth in both africa
as well as the rest of the world
however the resilience of the internet
economy
coupled with private consumption
strong developer talent public and
private investment
investments in digital infrastructure
and new government policies and
regulations will continue to drive this
growth for africa
submarine cables are an integral
are integral to bridging connectivity
gaps
and accelerating digital transformation
they are
the world's information super highways
and form the cornerstone of the internet
they carry an estimated 80 97 percent of
global international communications
and 10 trillion in daily financial
transactions the remainder of
international traffic is satellite based
high speed high capacity connections
underpinned by submarine infrastructure
are central to today's hyper-connected
global economy
cables enable high quality video
streaming and conferencing international
phone calls and support the growth of
cloud computing
significant investments in partnerships
along the entire value chain can boost
connectivity
increase internet penetration reduce
prices and improve quality of service to
end users
submarine cables while not the only
factor are central to unlocking africa's
digital potential and narrowing the
digital divide between the continent and
more connected regions
the vast majority of online content
consumed in africa is hosted in data
centers outside the continent
with submarine cables transporting data
between users and data centers through a
vast complex value chain
africa faces fine
main challenges
at this on all stages of the value chain
data centers are predominantly located
outside africa meaning content for users
on the continent has to travel far via
international submarine cables or
expensive satellite links
existing and as a matter of fact you can
fit
three times the continental us
into the continent of africa if you look
it up on a map just to give you a sheer
idea of size
existing submarine cables are aging and
typically rely on older technology while
many countries lack redundancy
existing subsidy infrastructure will be
unable to meet the rising demand
for international bandwidth
in the coming years
edge locations on the continent are not
yet fully developed
meaning content has to travel further to
end users
increasing cost and access and latency
new and ex new and existing internet
exchange points need to grow
to ensure content is hosted locally and
traffic is routed efficiently
middle mile infrastructure is
underdeveloped despite strong growth in
recent years
internet access networks are not
sufficiently dense or developed to
provide universal access
currently 25 of africa's population does
not live
within the footprint of a mobile
broadband network
boosting submarine connectivity will not
solve all these problems
however submarine infrastructure is
central to connectivity in africa and
around the world
the first map here is showing you
africa's terrestrial and submarine
fibers you can see that
many areas are under development
and the second map
shows the african countries by number of
cable landings
the darkest one is 12 cables and that's
egypt where most
cables
go through the sways canal
and you see the
whitish area on the map are the
landlocked unconnected country by
submarine cables obviously
and the gray ones are those with only
one cable
so what's a quiano
is a next-generation subsea
uh internet cable spearheaded by google
that will run from portugal to south
africa along the atlantic coast of
africa
its planned landings are lommei in togo
lagos nigeria
swakopmund namibia
cape town south africa
and rupert's bay in saint elena with
branching units in place for a second
phase of the
project
last year
the cable landed in rupert's bay saint
helena
earlier this year
the cable landed in lomme
in lisbon
and lagos
from a technical perspective
equiano cable is the first sub c cable
to incorporate optical switching at the
pair level at the fiber pair level
rather than the traditional approach of
wavelength level switching equiano will
also be the first spatial division
multiplex cable deployed along this
route allowing for a greater design
capacity of 144 terabit per second
so why did google decide to invest in
equiano
our decision was based on five factors
africa is home to over 20 submarine
cables some of which began operations
almost 20 years ago
and are nearing the end of their life
cycles
equiano is a state-of-the-art cable that
leverages next generation technology to
provide significantly more capacity than
the last set of cables built to serve
the continent
africa's growing
rapidly growing population and internet
user base combined with more intensive
use of the internet means that the
current submarine cables
will be unable to meet demand beyond the
next few years
investing today means
we are well prepared to serve tomorrow's
users
better performance
latency forms the cornerstone of good
user experience
that's our mission in this room
the increased
the increased bandwidth will bring to
africa
more latency sensitive products to
function
and to be developed
and last and fourth one is redundancy
africa currently has relatively few
submarine cables connecting to other
geographies as you've seen on the map
sometimes only one the majority of
countries
that are served by
only one or two cable is astounding as
outlined in the cables in the case study
when cables are damaged when they break
or when they undergo repairs
it means that users will
definitely suffer
through the disruptions building new
cables will improve consistency and
resiliency creating diverse and scalable
paths to raise me reach more users
as part of the construction design
several branching units are placed
already for on the sea floor
for
for a second phase by having more
control over the design
construction and upgrade
google will be able to quickly deploy
additional branches to bring more
contents to closer to users
this is a project built on partnerships
while we're spearheading the
construction of the aquiano cable other
partners namely wholesale network
providers
are able to use and benefit benefit from
the cable's additional capacity
we do not directly provide broadband or
mobile access to end users but instead
partners with multiple key
telecom players such as telcos or
infrastructure operators
where equiano lands to ensure that the
cable's capacity
benefits the most users and the most
businesses
across the continent
now we wanted to measure the impact of
this investment so we commissioned the
africa practice and genesis analytics to
produce a series of economic impact
assessments for the countries where
equiano will land
the impact metrics are based on robust
economic and econometric studies using
historical data where possible
i'm going to use here togo as a case
study
to highlight acquiano's economic impact
because togo has put in place some
excellent policies to attract
investments in the digital sphere and to
accelerate digital growth and digital
transformation
it's one of the continents leaders in
this regard
the increase in international bandwidth
capacity following the landing is
expected to have an immediate impact on
average ip transit prices
on speeds and on latency
for end users in togo this will
translate to cheaper and more reliable
internet access
leading to a substantial growth in user
in traffic and internet concentration
the cost of long-haul transmission of
data is a major determinant of local ip
transit prices
equiano's landing in togo will create a
new high-speed route for international
data transmission
the cable's lower installation costs
relative to its design capacity as well
as increased competition for the
long-haul transmission of data
will lead to lower ip transit prices in
turn
lower ip transit prices could be passed
on to consumers
true decreases in their internet prices
or indirectly through the provision of
more data
uncapped data limits or higher speeds at
the same price
the increased international bandwidth
capacity means that more data can be
transmitted to togo within a particular
time frame
this will translate into faster internet
speeds and lower latency particularly
with regard to non-cachable content and
the area
of close in the areas in close proximity
to terrestrial fiber optic cables
lower prices combined with improved
speeds and latency are expected to
increase internet penetration in togo by
5.1
percentage points between 2021 and 2025.
faster internet speeds will lead to a
higher demand in data traffic
in parallel lower internet retail prices
will increase internet usage both
extensively
by enabling new users to get online for
the first time
as well as new ways of using the
internet for the existing users
and intensively by enabling existing
users to consume more data
submarine cable's impact on speeds and
prices can catalyze investments
by isps and infrastructure providers
thereby expanding the terra terrestrial
networks
specifically lower ip transit prices
following the landing of such cables as
equiano or to africa
will improve it isp's bottom lines
enabling them to invest in the expansion
of their networks
to reach new customers
in the middle mile
in parallel
greater demand and usage of the internet
following equiano's landing is also
expected to increase isp's revenue in
inducing the expansion of their networks
internet capacity
unlocks significant economic
opportunities more so in developing
countries than other developed parts a
landmark study by the international
telecom union
in 2019 found that in africa
a 10
increase
in mobile internet penetration increases
gdp
per capita by 2.5
improved connectivity and higher
internet penetration unlocks significant
opportunities for individuals for
businesses and for governments
in togo the digital economy can be a
real game changer for the country's
economy and society
it represents an
opportunity to accelerate growth to
industrialize
to innovate
and to improve
people's lives
crucially
it offers a pathway to diversity to
diversify the economy away from
agriculture which has historically been
the dominant factor
on the employment front
equiano is expected to indirectly create
870 new jobs between 2022 and 2025
driven by the growth of the digital
economy and the telecom sector
so in conclusion
togo is a small country with a
population of 8 million people
but if you look at nigeria for example
equiano is expected to indirectly create
1.6 million jobs
between 2022 and 2025.
in nigeria and in south africa
real gdp
will be boosted to 10.1 billion
respectively and 7
billion
higher than it would otherwise have been
these are truly truly transformative
impacts and something that's we're very
proud
but as i've mentioned throughout this
presentation realizing africa's digital
potential requires partnerships
it also requires
partnerships across the value chain and
significant investments
the companies that take note of africa's
demographic economic and commercial
potential today
will be best positioned to captures
tomorrow's opportunities
i will now
show you
some cool images of building the equiano
cable
it turns out a big part of the cloud
isn't in the sky it takes the form of
fiber optic cables like this that
criss-cross the globe and google has one
of the most advanced global networks of
fiber-optic cables our sub-c cables are
carefully laid on the ocean floor
[Music]
compared to satellites submarine cables
are able to provide much higher
bandwidth and low latency which means
less delay for users when they're using
video streaming cloud services and
financial transactions
connecting people in places is at the
heart of what we do at google we don't
just want to organize the world's
information but we need to make it
universally accessible which means we
need to connect everyone on the planet
teams all over the world collaborate to
stretch our network fabric through an
enormous feat of partnership physics and
engineering
google's network operates like a mesh
our organization focuses on creating
solutions that interconnect humanity and
that's really the purpose of our network
our highest priority is to create a
network that society can depend on
thank you
so building in a pandemic posed a ton of
challenges
mainly communication challenges
between partners
not being able to do face-to-face
meetings or in-person meetings across
different languages different cultures
is difficult
it's um we we were however able to
manage to keep the schedule of equiano
rather on time
and there's only 90 days delay on a
project that is three and a half years
so we we really deployed treasures of
ingeniousity to make it happen
especially shipping
shipping in in this logistics
environment
so we had to resort to
every platform every communication
platform
that you all built
i have accounts on about everything i'm
able to reach partners on every platform
they want they need
it was uh definitely required
i have to say though that during all of
our communications with african partners
oftentimes
the video part would not work because
the bandwidth is too constrained
and that increases the challenge of
communicating as human beings
i'm extremely proud of the googlers
teamwork and their relentless dedication
to building the partnerships needed
for this cable in the past three and a
half years under really dire
conditions i'm also extremely grateful
for the commitment and resolve
demonstrated by all equiano partners in
saint helena in togo in portugal in
nigeria in namibia and south africa
and also our cable builder asn
and now
for the non-technical
and probably unsolicited advice
takeaways
during the pandemic
i'll leave you with this
nanook is a great great community
and you get
what you put in
so
you get what you give so i would say pay
it forward
make sure that you contribute to this
wonderful community it is so nice to
meet in person after so many years
and
this is a community of caring colleagues
and also some are now my friends for
life and you know who you are
so i would say get involved it's the
best way to connect to
others and the best way
to ensure that the internet continues to
be the thriving place that it is
um
in the internet is not just router
switches and machine i think it's
firstly all of you it's the people that
make it it's the people that connect
those machines and it's the people that
take the time to come to conferences and
share their knowledge
to build this internet
so my challenge to you
is to nurture your connections
when i was chair of nanak i would call
it the challenge 15 and i think i would
encourage everyone to meet at least 15
new people
we are all
really really
insecure introverts
i would say most of us
so
you're in company of good friends
so go out reach out and connect to 15.
and now i'm going to add my covet tax
i'm going to ask you to reach out to
five more
you still have two days to make 20 more
connections
those you made yesterday they don't
count
so you go
and meet with 15 more
plus five that's my covent tax
and also make sure that whenever you
look at what you do and how you choose
where you choose to prioritize your work
and your energy
go for impact
go for meaning
go for something that when you wake up
in the morning you go this is what i'm
meant to be doing with my day today
so thank you
and take care of yourself and take care
of each other thanks
[Applause]
thank you so much sylvie that was
fabulous
do we have any questions from the room
complete no please go and cue with the
microphones and then we'll and just a
reminder name and affiliation please
uh
hello my name is andrei sharbovich i'm
from mcgill university in montreal
canada
so uh
i'd like to
ask you about uh
first of all um like to
thank you for your excellent
contribution for the world connectivity
and
like to ask if this project is
coordinated or supported by
global organizations or united nations
or umdp or something like that
or maybe you are in partnership with
them because the bridging digital divide
is one of their goals as well
to
maintain sustainable development thank
you very much well thank you for your
question first i'll pass your
congratulations to the googlers who work
really hard on this
um this is one thing nothing nothing
happens without teamwork so there's a
really big team working on that i'll
make sure that they get your recognition
thank you for that
in terms of funding this cable was
funded by private funds it was funded by
google there was no external support
but we are
looking at multiple ways of investment
so
private is one
consortium is another
having funders is yet another so we're
very open
to working in many different ways to
support these infrastructure projects
yes
oh you have it
okay
i'm a dare i'm from internet too
all right
i'm short um
i have two questions if that's okay
yes it is okay
let's go for the first one
comparatively why was there such a low
speed increase projected in namibia
roughly the same as south africa so
namibia would be
comparable to south africa in terms of
internet speeds so it will
actually you can find this report online
we have published an economic impact it
will nearly double
and i think it's 41 decrease in cost
okay
and um why are there so many subsea
cables that land in djibouti and not the
surrounding countries
ah excellent question
submarine cables are particular beasts
they like good landings
they don't like rocky spots they don't
like
shallow waters
so
and they don't like areas where there's
increased fishing activities because
anchors of fishing boats might snap the
cables
so
landings are selected carefully to avoid
basically human activities but as you
can tell it's very hard to avoid all
human activity so
we compose with constraints
but djibouti is one of those locations
where
it's amenable
you're welcome
um we have a question from the chat from
tony taub uh sorry from
tone oh there's two questions one from
tony tauber at
comcast
maybe it was touched on and i missed it
will a partner be doing the operations
and maintenance of these subsea systems
i don't know what's typical
we have two questions
thank you so yes um
there will be a there's a few concerns a
few companies that do repairs and
maintenance of submarine cables uh
they're typically associations and they
will cover uh an ocean
um so we're we're in discussions with
some of these uh providers to find
the provider that will
service the cable for the next 15 years
hey um gabe blanchard from start.ca
seriously
um
i'm just curiosity i know sylvia you
always work on really big projects
what's your next big thing sure
i can
try and share
my personal aspiration is to bring the
internet infrastructure in africa to the
same level or at par
with north america and europe so i do
have a 10 year plan ahead of me
okay and we have a question from tony
lee um
we're all familiar with dwdm technology
can you please say a bit more about the
optical
switching technology that acriano is
using
yes so it's a fiber pair switching
i will
link a note we've published a few uh
white papers on it
so we're able to
switch the fiber pairs as opposed to go
on a spectrum basis
yeah um
chuck midori kentick um hi silvie hi so
uh years ago i used to attend a lot of
submarine cable conferences and i
remember there would always be a panel
on building in africa in particular and
i remember one a couple years ago where
there was a lot of concern uh
specifically i think from chris wood
chris wood of uh of wyock
had expressed concern about over
building submarine cable capacity before
access layer uh or last mile is ready to
absorb it where you'd kind of take out
the market for i mean obviously he's
more concerned maybe than google is for
um
making payroll but uh you could the
concern is you could over build
submarine cable before the access layer
is is has any of that changed is that
still a concern
it is not
as you can see what's changed is the
gaps the demographic gaps and the
connectivity gaps that i've explained
so just the the population dividend will
be so large in the next 20 years
that
with equiano and to africa it won't be
enough
we will need to start planning a new
cable
probably by year 10.
so
just think of 1.3 billion users to 2.5
billion users 25 of the world's labor
force
in a in the context of digital
transformation
i don't think we will have a glut of
internet capacity the same way that
we've had a glot in the atlantic since
the mid-90s
thank you you're welcome
um question from brian gladney um
could you please restate estimated
bandwidth with equiano i believe i
missed it it's 12 fiber pairs of roughly
12 terabit per second so currently a 144
terabit per second
and as your slte equipment
increases or increases capacity you'll
be able to increase that capacity as
well
um question at the back i think
hi this is sumit from data communication
a question like i'm seeing like a lot of
developments being done for the south
africa uh any plan for diet connectivity
from south africa to the asia pacific
like india singapore and those countries
i didn't hear um can you repeat come
closer could you come closer and perhaps
um so any question any cables
which google is planning for connecting
uh south africa with the asia pacific
countries like singapore india and like
direct connectivity that sounds like a
wonderful opportunity to explore
thank you thank you you're welcome
um there's a couple of other comments
that people have made in the q a which
people might want to read but they're
not really questions
do we have any other questions
i think we can call that bitter wrath
thank you so much sylvie you're so
welcome and thank you bonjour abieto
we're now going to go off script and
surprise sylvie because she doesn't know
about this bit
no we're not doing this
oh okay
hey i
i didn't get given the whole script
obviously um you might like to go and
talk to those two wonderful gentlemen in
the corner over there
thank you everyone and i haven't met 15
plus five so i'm looking forward to meet
you
thanks thank you again
[Applause]
[Music]