[Music]
hi everyone great to be here at nunc 85
unfortunately we're surely but still
with you uh my name is jeff tantura i'm
with microsoft senior principal network
architect at azure networking working on
nexon data centers networking machine
learning clusters and such
uh i would like to shed some light on
how we operate our data center networks
we are performing thousands of changes
every day pretty much every minute there
is there is a change so i would like to
kind of show you or guide you through
how we manage to build most reliable
network
so reliability is a struggle for
everyone at particular
size
at particular skill
stuff starts breaking no one is safe
from it
but it's our job as network architects
data center architect to make sure that
our changes can go ahead that they don't
affect each other
and that our customers most importantly
are not affected by them
so the agenda for today talks is really
to show you how
large azure really is so you understand
the problem with the skill
and
guide you through the change procedure
how do you do changes at scale
and without really any negative impact
obviously there's always
problem and unexpected consequences but
normally we perform sounds changes a day
without any negative impact
and we will go through
different stages and how we achieve the
state so number one is obviously you
need to obstruct and contain the change
so change in one place doesn't affect
another one
i'll show you how we simulate emulate
and at the end obviously validate what
we've done
so azure is one of the biggest networks
in the world
before we go further i would like really
to focus what does it mean to be hyper
skill its ability of architecture to
scale with increasing demand and do so
over common infrastructure
and we achieve this by
really adhering to hyperscale design
principle
we have fully used this aggregated
hardware from software now networking so
we choose best hardware where it should
be and then we decide which software to
run on it as you know microsoft started
sonic effort which is today
one of the
best available choices in open source
world
we also use vendor software
and all of this could be done
interchangeable on top of hardware we
decide to use number two principle all
complexity is moved to the edge
all complex encapsulation
firewalling enforcements are done at the
host network is kept simple to provide
reachability and this allows to scale to
pretty much any size
number three and we'll focus to some
degree on that we follow strictly follow
both principle so when there's a new
change it's always within the pod
there's rushing between ports this
allows to build
a network of pretty much any size
because the complexity is always
contained within the pod
just to give you some impression this is
how large we are
61 regions uh
thousands of miles of fiber
many many many pairings
and
it keeps growing and it grows like crazy
every day every month every year
to give some impression this is how
single building within data center block
looks like
this is how block looks like
this is how data center with all the
auxiliary things looks like
and so forth what you see here is not
the biggest one
the biggest one one gigabyte plus are
yet to come so the infrastructure is
growing at huge tempo and without
automation without ability to obstruct
and perform changes every second of the
day you wouldn't be able to do so
and challenges cause outages it's well
known this information facebook but it's
somewhat similar everywhere where
there's a lot of state a lot of changes
and large infrastructure so how do we
build and operate the most reliable you
might argue with my statement but we are
very very reliable
number one and probably the most
important point here is to build right
foundation so ability to abstract
and self-contain
different building blocks
how do we build data center and we are
not really unique here it's how any
large data center pretty much looks like
it's what you do with the state and data
rack is a unit that has reachability to
all the compute or storage or
any other device that needs to be
accessed throughout the network and
reachable there's full reachability with
interrupt
rock makes a pod
again there's full reachability between
different rex and the pot however any
change within the rack is invisible
within the pattern
within data center we follow exactly
same approach
reps are fully reachable from data
center perspective however all the
changes within the racks are absolutely
invisible within the data center they're
completely obstructed
and from routing perspective aggregated
if you wish
same goes when we start going out of
data center again all the data that is
within data center
is aggregated all the changes are
completely hidden and all the changes
also contain
and finally this is how region looks
like that connects to microsoft one that
provides reachability across the world
the basic foundation layer here is
self-contained as you could see
self-contained boundaries are wrecked
so there's single v4 single v6 subnet
and all the changes within subnet are
not propagated up
within the exact same story there are
subnets that attached or assigned to a
port that doesn't change
any changes same goes for data center
this allows us to perform different
changes within reacts within same port
slots to perform changes within ports
within data center and in data centers
practically one change should never
interact in any way with other changes
let's touch upon routing
within routing that adheres to the same
principle it is impossible to provide
self-containment
what are the requirements for routing
its large scale
obviously is to reduce number of routes
is really necessary minimum tecom is
finite we would like to be able to grow
number of devices within data center
without replacing switches every six
months
so
we are trying to keep number of routes
as small as possible
on another site we would like to keep
enough details to prevent black calling
because when we remove too many details
it inevitably
leads to in best case very very
ineffective routing in worst case to
block calling
two more
very important steps here is that as any
large data center or multi-planner the
plants are massively distributed to
provide
reachability that is contained within
the plane
right so uh
while
there is kind of rule of thumb to use
well if you're routing
because
we care about amount of time it takes
traffic to take from one
point to another when there's a failure
we implemented so called
uh bonds and we'll go through it while
we do it so a naive approach is really
summarize everything it's not too little
information
the problem
it is uh
preventing us of understanding next step
failure and can lead to black hauling
and when playing gets disconnected in
order to get to through another plane
it has to go outside of data center
which brings latency and plane failure
and while
not very significant for regular tcp
traffic
uh really reduce performance of
storage
anything that relates to email and
redeeming traffic another new approach
is to deploy
an igp
we know there's a lot of work going on
on flood reduction
on making
igps more suitable for data center
however basically agp uh floods
extensively which is a problem as large
scale last radius is a whole igp domain
so we are not using a gp either
the pragmatic approach we have taken is
pass vector it's well known we are big
bgp user however rather than using value
free we also want bonds this allows to
have backup always available
and when plan is failing
or connectivity the plane from outside
is failing there's always longer route
through bounds available and this is
with minimum pass hunting because
as i said it's only allowed to bounce
once so this is how we provide
self-contained
complexity this is how we provide
ability to implement changes at any
point at any time without affecting
customers
how do you perform without having any
negative impact
we start with simulation
i'll guide you through the change
verification system process we create a
manual operation procedure mob that is
really intent
definition of change to be performed
using metadata
it derives topology and devices involved
and all the information about devices
creates configuration and also stages
simulation enumeration after simulation
is done
and routing tables both change
are retrieved they're being validated by
our
spock system which i'll describe in more
details
if
result is positive
change will go into the system and be
performed if it's negative it's rollback
actually it hasn't been performed yet it
just it stopped and goes back to either
manual validation or drought some system
validations that are performed here so
what is the difference between emulation
and simulation emulation
is one vm parameter
simulation is one vm for all the routers
so the scale is completely different
when we emulate we can emulate subset of
a data center we can build network of
thousands of switches and routers
however not larger than that
simulation
could easily simulate entire azure
region or entire azure if needed speed
is very different too
the
uh emulation is non-interactive it's
actually required to build
actually to fetch the images that are
used in production that's the
configurations that used in production
and spin out vms that will run it
while simulation
is very very lightweight it's in
container level
uh
deployment that can build thousands of
nodes in minutes
what's also important and the difference
here
from fidelity perspective we make a big
point that the virtual hardware that
used in emulation
is really provide exactly the same
functionality as real hardware used on
the devices
while on simulation it's just an
adolescent production reads so again it
doesn't require any forwarding plane
involvement here so simulation
before you go and build
very very complex
plane you are trying to test it we are
doing exactly the same
so network logic solver is modeling
behavior of routing protocol so bgp in
this case
if you look at changes
at large scale very often they require
change in routing policies
and this is what's exactly modeled so
what we can do is to change the intent
run the bgp
processes
get the routing table and compare
operational state of post
test
routing tables to the intended ones
it's very efficient it's very fast
and allows to
at least figure out that our changes to
the routing policies
aren't in conflict with intent emulation
after mop is being applied to the system
metadata provides us topology
devices
vendors
and all the information that's needed to
build a twin so emulation factually
builds exactly the same network
virtualized as in real data center
so uh
exactly same image is taken with regards
to software exactly same configuration
is taken as run on the device the only
difference is that we are running them
in vm so it's virtualized hardware
versus real hardware and production
however again we make a point to work
with our vendors to work on site
to make sure that virtualized hardware
exhibit exactly the same behavior as
real hardware
and we run hundreds of millions of hours
on azure
every year to validate so typical
usage scenario
after mop is done and there is intent
based definition of a change
we create an emulated replica so it's
fully automated there's nothing needed
to be done manually
then change is applied to emulated
replicas so the end result is exactly
the same as we would apply as if we
would apply same change to the
production network
the end result of replica is then run
through our
gg
verifier and the end result is positive
failed if it's passed we can proceed
with the change if it fails it goes back
the validation is very interesting point
right you can simulate and emulate as
much as you want we all know that
networks are not
always predictable
there are inconsistencies between ribs
and fields between what's routing
protocol cs versus forwarding sys so
ability to validate at scale and
continuously is as important as ability
to simulate and emulate
so what we do we use
what's known as formal method
and in order to do so we pull forwarding
table from all our devices into the
network on regular basis
and then they are compared to intended
state
there is also configurational retrievals
that compare
configurational state to operational
state to fips
to state of routing protocols
so all of this changes are done on
pretty much 5 10 15 minutes basis
depending where you are and when it's
needed so and last is overview of spock
which is our system that actually does
verification validation it's a testing
framework we've written internally in
microsoft it uses assertions and
invariants
so you could see here an example of code
and the specification as a test
anytime there's any change there's
always test code that's applied to it if
there is none it's not allowed actually
change cannot be performed
so when there is a change
for example we want to validate that
every door router has a default route
it needs to be present in
bgp rip it needs to be present in reap
it needs to be present in fib
so
when we retrieve the flip state
we have the intended state that
transfers this code through every
statement that should be present and
validates
if everything that's
present in feed is available on one side
on another side that everything is
available and fib should actually be
there
and this is done at scale of azure so
after changes the certification is
mandatory between changes it's run on
continuous basis
this is how we ensure
the changes we perform don't affect our
customers
so to summarize
we abstract simulate emulate and
validate
and this allows to grow at really really
high speed
we perform as i said thousands of
changes a day
everywhere in the network
and
it doesn't affect our reliability
it doesn't affect our agility so we
could go as fast as business require us
without affecting our customers
and we are hiring everywhere microsoft
if you are interested you see we are
solving really really interesting
problems you are more than welcome to
join us
thank you so much
[Music]