[Music]
at this time i'm happy to present a
panel discussion
about the ipv6 launch day 10 years later
and here they come please welcome to the
stage
the panel moderators jan george
and john
raus rosofsky thank you i'm sorry about
that
jan will introduce the rest of the
panelists
thank you you're welcome jan is vp of
six connect
labs and has traveled to us from
sylvania
to join us on stage this is yon's second
time on stage today welcome back
uh
john is a
is passionate about scaling
infrastructure and platforms while being
obsessed with customer experience
and
and value john is one of the original
organization organizers of world ipv6
series of events and has led to one of
the largest deployments of ipv6 globally
thank you
somebody has slides
one of you guys has slides yep uh this
is the clicker we have some recordings
right so so panel format we have we have
three folks who are remote yes right
or for panelists and pet persons water
over there let me introduce uh our
speaker hello i'm jan george thank you
for introducing welcome john and john
and i will try to moderate this
panel here are people
uh that did a lot of stuff for ipv6 and
we are commemorating 10-year microphone
of this stuff oh okay so this one
doesn't work apparently okay right
so uh please um welcome
we have ron brosma remotely we have
jason fessler here madura kale
here eric nygren
paul saab mark townsley here and matthew
wilder wilder here
and
since this is a hybrid meeting
we will have uh alternating um
presentation from from remote and in
room so the first part should be more of
a retrospective
uh as you all well known 10 years ago
uh we did this a world ipv6 day well
that was 11 years ago when we switched
on ipv6 for one day and then switched it
off some people left it on and then the
year later on on 6th of june
we had this world's ipv6 launch
which was destined and
the purpose was to basically switch on
ipv6 and leave it on for good
so i would like to ask let's see who's
who's first
is it jason
yeah jason please uh in five minutes if
you can describe um what what you did
back then and
what happened up to this moment um sure
um 10 years ago i was working for yahoo
at the time
uh the days
months a couple years leading up to the
world ipv6 day event
um internet society got all of us into a
room they kept saying
figure out how to make ipv6 move forward
or we're not letting you out
i blame phil roberts for that um
and
there the resistance to this uh as we
heard earlier was the brokenness problem
uh turns out it is a small number
0.05 percent of the users had
ibv6 configured but misconfigured
or transit was broken or just something
wasn't right and the kernel didn't know
that it was going to work and so
connections would try to connect
stall
and from a user perspective the site was
down
none of us really wanted what turned out
to be a million users
unable to reach unable to get to their
favorite content to complain about it
and go to the competition
uh with isaac's help we came up the idea
of the world ipv6 day
uh where we basically all agreed let's
jump off the ledge together
um
user won't be able to reach yahoo won't
be able to reach google won't be able to
go to facebook to complain about it
maybe they'll see there's this hint that
maybe there's something wrong on their
end
um
moving forward the v6 uh
day was coming up
those was their content providers all
ran campaigns to detect the users that
are broken to
put up some type of messaging to them
and say hey we know that you're going to
have a problem on this particular day
click here to learn more
and the campaign worked pretty well it
dropped the brokenness from the .05
small number to a much more manageable
point zero two leading up to the actual
switch
the day was pretty good mostly
uneventful other than watching lots of
graphs there were you know a few hiccups
here and there that everyone had but for
the most part
we weren't fired
um and the internet didn't melt down
yeah uh so
uh world ip6
launch came about next year
uh the numbers were small enough that
everybody was happy signing off and
saying yes we know we're gonna have this
impact on this number of users
we got to move forward
coming from a slightly different
perspective i run this little site
called testipv6.com
one of its jobs is just detect broken
users in fact it's only job really and
that might be because of mtu or any
other issues
and one thing i've seen in the last 10
years is
you know ahead of the launch we had uh
something like three percent of the
users
not the point zero five but three
percent of those who came to the site
had problems that we were able to say
hey
you are going to break
and
by the time the v6 launch came around
those numbers were down to about point
zero i'm sorry about point six
still much bigger than
what the broad numbers were because
these people are the ones that said i
might have a problem let's go look
and then over the following couple years
things went down to about point two
it stayed there until about two years
ago and it's actually been rising back
up since about point seven
looking at the numbers i've only been
able to look at the stats for the last
couple weeks because of gdpr data
reasons
uh
unusual amounts of interest coming from
china
japan
brazil an order of magnitude higher
amount of interest coming from those
locations compared to
what maybe jeff houston's stats would
show from ap nick
looking a little bit closer
i was kind of expecting maybe it was
china that would have the most
brokenness because of
technical political boundary issues
uh actually no they were only 0.2
percent broken
it was actually japan at uh two and a
half percent
why two and a half percent today
i don't know i don't know if it's the
walled garden issue still rearing its
head or what they do have a high amount
of v6 deployed but can't quite explain
all of it
it sounds scary
the reality is that happy eyeballs did
save the internet as far as i'm
concerned
uh happy eyeballs
uh
for those that don't know it just
basically says run one connection
after a certain amount of time run a
second connection let them race and
remember which one wins
uh that has evolved over time we had
well backing up we had implementations
in chrome and firefox on the day of the
launch we also had os level support in
apple's mac os and ios
since then curl has added support which
is great for scripting languages
and
apple sent or posted an updated
algorithm for happy eyeballs to help
reduce the appearance of latency for the
user
so today nobody really knows since
they're broken until both protocols are
broken which is cool
but we do still have some troubles that
we need to resolve
thank you jason and thank you very much
for test
ipv6.com this is really really useful
stuff and helped help to debug many many
many cases i remember the meeting when
it was created yeah
and when we we wrote a document how to
use it
as a write document that was cool
all right uh let's let's move forward uh
eric nygren is recorded do we have a
recording thank you very much if you can
hello my name is eric nigrin and i'm a
fellow and chief architect at akamai
technologies
i've been at akamai for almost 23 years
now as a large content delivery network
akamai has long been committed to
helping our customers with a smooth
transition to ipv6
as of the world ipv6 launch event a
decade ago akamai already had over a
thousand customer dual stacked host
names on our platform
over the past 10 years we've seen a
dramatic increase in ipv6 traffic on our
platform over a thousand decks
peak pv6 traffic increased from around a
gigabit 10 years ago to recent daily
peaks of over 41 terabits per second
we've gone from serving just shy of four
billion requests per day over ipv6 uh
ten years ago to now regularly serving a
thousand times that at four trillion
ipv6 requests per day
while we previously observed 19 million
ipv6 addresses per day on world ipv6
launch
we now see around 7.5 billion ipv6
addresses in a typical day including
around 2.2 billion
ipv6 64 prefixes one way we've been
measuring the adoption of ipv6 has been
to look at the ratio of ipv6 requests to
total requests on subsets of our dual
stacked customer sites
it's worth noting that the typical
traffic club customer traffic mix
including a set of devices customer
traffic type and end user isp can
heavily influence aggregate numbers
which is why we haven't been reporting a
single global number
looking at the top 10 global economies
all but two of ipv6 adoption levels in
the 35
to 62 percent range
and china while which was starting out
with very little ipv6 10 years ago in
the past few years has
seen substantial growth and now we see
around uh ipv6 adoption levels are
around 25 percent growth in individual
countries is very much a function of the
individual network providers within
those within those countries most of the
largest networks in the world have have
significant ipv6 adoption
around half of the top 100 network
providers have ipv6 adoption over 40
percent measuring top n by the number of
total requests served on dual stacked
host names looking at the top 800
networks only around a fifth of them
have ipv6 adoption over 40 percent and
this continues to decline from there
a real challenge we face going forward
is to convince these smaller and more
slowly growing networks to deploy ipv6
even if they have less of a need for it
themselves
otherwise we face a real risk of a
fragmented internet split between large
ipv6 centric networks and small ipv4
only networks akamai has had ipv4 ipv6
dual stack as a default for new customer
configurations for quite a few years now
and we encourage customers to dual stack
existing configurations
many of our customers are large
enterprises or other complex businesses
that have handling end-user ipv ip
addresses deeply embedded in their
workflows meaning we can't forcibly
enable ipv6 for them without breaking
things
with this we've still seen substantial
uptake in ipv6 on the content delivery
side
of those customer host names serving
over 1 million requests per day
over 40 percent of them are now dual
stacked and this continues to grow
steadily with many of our largest high
volume customers are now mostly dual
stacked
we've even seen cases during large
events with the majority of all traffic
we're serving to some large countries
over ipv6
and this seems like it'll be
increasingly common
thank eric um
matthew
what's your story
yeah our story is actually one that's
coincidental with nanogs that have been
held in canada so this is kind of cool
my very first nadal was actually not on
55 held in vancouver in 2012 i think
everyone descended upon vancouver that
year
two years after the olympics so i think
that year was like
there was an erin meeting there
followed by a nanog followed by an ietf
so
lots happening in in vancouver and it
was actually
it was coincidental as well with world
ipv6 launch uh june 6th fell on on one
of those days at nanawg in vancouver
and we did not have the one percent
required to have our
our name checked off as one of the
service providers participating in the
launch but we were participating in
other ways doing testing and enabling
our our website
so
it actually took us a few more years to
get our our uh residential base going
toward v6
and actually it was uh nano 65 the last
time was in montreal
and my colleague clinton presented for
the audience here about tell us his
experience
deploying ipv6 at scale
so um yeah i'd say basically if i look
at the story of telus and and how to
categorize our customers certainly
there's a difference between wireless
and wireline
we have done some of the the t-mobile
playbook of doing v6
and providing v4 over 464 xlat it's the
whole idea of v4 as a service i think
that is definitely
the future and and i have to
say that i am biased that way because
one of the jobs i do in my day job is is
the v4 address management and v6 address
management the v6 address management is
much much easier
v4 address management of course is a
somewhat stressful job these days trying
to come up with the addresses for even
private ips on a wireless network with
10 million subscribers that's that's not
a trivial task
rfc 1918 doesn't quite have enough and
and even with 65.98 thrown in there
so more and more i'd like to see the
idea of v6 as as you know the default
for sure in the mobile space
on wireline we've got sort of two main
buckets i would say so residential
uh as mentioned we did scale it up in
and today that is the default so v6 by
default and more and more we're going to
be introducing
cgn in order to help scale up v4s we add
customers
and then the other piece is the the
business side so business you know it's
been talked about we heard it from scott
the enterprise space is a bit more
challenged by inertia and staff being
unfamiliar
and one of our design choices in
deploying v6 or at least making it
capable of that
we decided that the provisioning system
shouldn't you know by default give v6
addresses we want enterprises to
basically ask for it and i would say an
analogy is
you know people in the air community
have talked about the idea of giving v6
by default to any org id that's out
there
but it's not clear that that's actually
going to have an impact on on people
deploying v6 and using it
so to me uh
you know that's our choice i i'd be
happy to have a debate with with anyone
or or discussion and hear your thoughts
about should we push v6 by default to
enterprise customers
i think it's worth talking about and i'm
sure uh my panel fellow panelists have
some things to say about that
thank you very much uh
well ipv6 by default on or not we will
have a discussion after the
retrospective uh parts uh to continue
the discussion that john had with with
with vint
um would would like to hear now from ron
breuer's mind we have a recording right
hi i'm ron berisma chief engineer of the
defense research and engineering network
or dren and going to give some
perspective on the world ipv6 launch
from 10 years ago
and the state of ipv6 at the time
dran was an earlier early adopter of
ipv6 so by the time of world ipv6 launch
our backbone was already dual stack for
at least a decade
all of our public-facing services were
google stack this was part of compliance
with an earlier federal mandate
and all our management networks were
ipv6 only
and so there wasn't a lot to do in terms
of contributing to the launch by turning
on something new because everything was
pretty much turned on that was external
facing but we did participate in
monitoring and testing as
the launch was happening
some of the issues we had at the time 10
years ago a lot of it was with industry
products
one of the big issues was lack of
feature parity
because what worked in ipv4 didn't
always work in ipv6 which really
impacted our ipv6 only operations due to
loss of functionality for the things
that didn't work in v6 you just lost
those functions so that was a huge
problem
another problem was lack of code
maturity
and you think about it with ipv4 at the
time we had at least 30 years plus of
mature code but with v6 it was only a
few years and so there's lots of bugs
we're still finding them and there's
certainly more to be found
we had some major meltdowns due to bugs
and so that was our biggest issue in
terms of risk
another problem with vendors
in trying to understand why they weren't
implementing
ipv6 in their products
we found out that they were not eating
their own dog food so they weren't
finding out about the issues themselves
and their qa processes didn't include
ipv6 and so
um they were not even addressing ipb6
bugs
as bugs but instead when they arose they
treat it as a feature request which
sometimes took years to
resolve and so when asked we
said why isn't
this being addressed at a higher
priority they said well nobody's using
ipv6 anyway and so there was no real
corporate committed ipv6 or most of
those companies
some internal issues that we were
addressing at the time
our own internal organizations and
customers of vran had a lack of
incentive to enable ipv6 we could tell
them set mandates try to enforce it but
they had lots of excuses things like oh
it's very expensive and so we need more
money or we think it's less secure or it
has lower performance
and other urgent activities always seem
to take precedence such as security
compliance
and the mandates just really didn't help
very much as you all know there were
many mandates over the years and it
really did very little to move the
needle
but when world ipv6 launch came along
besides just enabling a lot of the
content providers the
search providers the
social media content
it had some side effects that we
observed and that the argument about
nobody using it was no longer valid
because a lot of people were using ipv6
and the increased demand
of ipv6 really signaled industry that
they needed to include full ipv6 support
or the companies were going to die
because their competitors would win out
and as more people were using it more
people were discovering bugs and
pressuring for fixes which improved code
maturity which just helped the entire
community
and also a lot of the internal excuses
about cost security performance really
proved to be without merit because if it
was good for
the many
major providers and they weren't having
issues with that then that couldn't be
used as an excuse so it really helped
break the log jam in our internal
organizations as the excuses went away
and they'd be able to move forward
so still today what we're noticing some
of those same problems still exist
but as i observe in the federal
government the federal networks there's
still a lack of incentive
and we can easily get bogged down in
bureaucracy and other excuses and lots
of planning and
sometimes can go on for years without
ever passing the single life 86 packet
and what we also found is there's not
much progress unless there's a strong
internal incentive within an
organization with total corporate
support
and at ipv6 culture so having that
internal advocacy is really important so
we see a lot of difference between
different federal agencies some very
successful and some not doing much at
all
but inside the department of defense for
the ones that have not yet enabled ipv6
our message is don't be afraid to break
some glass just turn it on
because all the other excuses and
arguments are just a waste of time at
this point
for drin
how we incentivize
the industry and also our own internal
uh customers is we do not buy anything
from a company that doesn't have a
corporate commitment to ipv6
so for example if they lack an ipv6
enabled website that indicates a lack of
corporate commitment and we will not do
business with those companies
we also turn ibv6 on by default wherever
possible if you're a drin subscriber and
there are many hundreds you cannot
connect to dram unless you are dual
stack
and that is enforced and we monitor it
if your ipv6 bgp session goes down we
set out alerts and make you fix it
we remove ipv4 wherever we can which
isn't as many places as we would like
we'd love to turn it off altogether
but there's just too much other legacy
and external stuff that's requires v4
and is before only so we can't do that
yet but another incentive is we try to
make it a security issue which does help
progress a lot because if we make that
part of security compliance then v6 gets
turned on so we've done that a number of
places very successfully
some of the continuing challenges are
new bugs in mainstream products we have
a major firewall vendor that we've been
fighting a bug for the last three four
months and it turned out to be an ipv6
bug internally and this was
a bug that was introduced in a recent
version of a very mainstream vendor
product so they're still popping up
there's also new products with no ipv6
support at all recently just a few days
ago talked to a vendor evaluating a very
new product looked very exciting and
then we asked the ipv6 question and well
sorry we haven't done that yet so that
still happens a lot and then a big one
for us is ipv6 in the cloud gov cloud in
particular where
the ipv6 rollout is just not mature for
many of the cloud service providers
so uh
in summary i think we need another ipv6
day of some sort we need to reach
critical mass we need more of the
internet to be v6 enabled i need to be
able to turn off v4 and so whatever we
can do to get there would be great so
thank you very much
thank you ron
ron was always famous for chasing
vendors to fix ipv6 bugs well done
yeah madura what happened in your world
in the last 10 years in ipv6 uh great
question um i'm this is called the
reunion tour i am i am on a union tour
this is my first time at nanog um really
excited to be here 10 years ago i was um
actually working
working at cisco systems uh testing ipv6
for comcast so i was probably somewhere
a little minion helping helping your
cause john um and fast forward ten years
later uh i now work at aws um as a
manager product team that focuses on our
ipv6 roadmap but um let me talk about
what cloud has done in the last 10 years
um with with ipv6 uh the first time we
launched for i might i might go through
some basic cloud things so please pardon
me if you already know them
we started aws with with two primary
services s3 which is our storage service
and ec2 which is our compute service um
in 2009 is when we launched something
called virtual private cloud which is
like a little wrapper around your ec2
that says okay now you're in a private
network and you can use rfc 1918 space
in there um
then in obviously a few years later 2016
is when
we we started building services that are
load balancers we built route 53 which
is our dns service we built cloudfront
our content delivery network and we
realized that hey our network that is
now facing the internet no longer a
private network needs to have v6 uh so
2016 we did a barrage of every
service known then that faced the
internet uh supported ipv6 so all the
services that i named along with several
others anything that is on the edge of
your network can uh support v6
um
and we thought you know we did a good
job we gave ourselves a pat on the back
uh and as uh matt said earlier it's it's
an enterprise world uh we've handed
folks ipv6 and they've said hey you can
turn this on now on your network
um
that was 2016 early 2017.
um now in the last two three years
however we've changed we've seen the
landscape or our customers needs change
um in what we now hear from our
customers that run very very large
networks is
the internet scarcity of ipv4 isn't
as big a challenge for them as it is to
run their private networks using unique
rfc 1918 space um so if you if you look
up our our uh some of our customer
references they'll talk about how they
use natting in their private network i
have a sticker now from someone at nanak
that said less not more v6 and i i i
took some for my team uh
also but but we have customers that are
running out of space within their
private network setup uh whether it's
their virtual private cloud or their
extended uh entire on-premise network
with their data centers branch offices
etc
and then coming with technology that is
a few years ago serverless and then
containers we
basically had our customers
use up their ip space
uh in their vpcs pretty quickly um so
anything that we have done now it is
since
2016 2017 is to help their applications
whatever our customer enterprises are
building turn that to v6 so now if you
look at um now if you look at a simple
three tier architecture you have a web
tier app tier uh database now on aws you
could build all of that load balancer
compute
database services you can build all of
that as as dual stack um so you could
build those architectures and
applications using ipv6 end-to-end where
your v6 only client could be
communicating with all of that without
translation needed
and on the other side for for these
customers running containers what we've
built is
a couple of areas where we've actually
built v6 only support
one is just on pure ec2 so you can
actually spin up an ac2 instance today
that with an only a v6 address uh and
we've also built support for
v6 only on our kubernetes service our
managed kubernetes service uh it we did
we did a cool thing where there's an
implicit nat going out to
upstream world where v6 is not yet
supported in kubernetes but you can run
pods on uh on aws
uh kubernetes pods on aws without using
v4 um so that's that's been our journey
so far excellent and we will talk later
about ipv6 home by default right
we oh we did we did that yes sorry uh
thank you for the reminder uh we did do
that with one of our smaller services so
this is not enterprise this is our
service called amazon light sale it's
also an aws service it basically does a
virtual private server so web hosting
lightweight applications that you want
to build
quick and dirty
so these are not enterprises that use
this as smaller companies and when we
enabled ipv6 for light sale in 2020
january i think um we
we turned it on by default so now all
light sail instances are dual stacked by
default um we did have a couple of
issues um
we were able to fix them there's uh some
additional documentation you you'll find
on our website to add additional config
to make it work fully because there's
some software packages that the instance
like if you're trying to
host a certain type of application you
need to download software packages from
destinations that may not work
completely so there's additional
additional config added but um
no no issues so far i think we should
move this part of discussion into the
next uh
now it's good because now we we need to
hear from from from from facebook and
paul saab do we have a recording
so i'm paul
i've been to facebook for about 14 and a
half years
and
i along with a handful of people worked
on the launch of e6
for the public internet about 10 years
ago
you know since that time you know we've
talked about publicly the work that we
have done with v6 and most famously
was time that i disclosed that we had
converted all of our infrastructure
internally
to b6
that process
took us
approximately about 18 months
and it was fraught with many many big
problems
we had to get the switch vendors to fix
their bugs
we had to fix linux and other operating
system bugs
we had to work around bugs in various
libraries and software
that we had either written internally or
you were using the open source
we had to figure out logging mechanisms
we had to figure out abuse mechanisms
there was you know quite a bit of work
and at times we felt like you know this
project may not work
but
at the end of 2014 we launched our first
internal data center as an e6000 case
and you know we thought we were ready
and when we tried to start taking
traffic
it uh
didn't work because we didn't actually
find everything that was communicating
over v4 because
the
infrastructure we had in place
was not able to detect the miniscule
amounts of before that was still being
served
but you know we rolled up our sleeves we
continued to work and a few weeks later
we launched the first ever
v6 only data center infrastructure
and today
really the only v4 space that
exists in our data centers is to support
public-facing internet instruction
so since that time when we finished
all of the work for internally
we
we've made it our mission to make sure
that everything that we launched is
still stack
we have
pushed
our
facebook caches out to the world
and we try to encourage all of our isps
that use these devices to use v6
and we will fill over recents
um we
we really have embraced the v6 first
strategy
um i won't say it's been easy um and i
won't lie to you that there are some
you know building management systems out
there
and
other very esoteric
pieces of equipment that still have
migraine
and but we continue to push on this
uh constantly and try to
encourage the world to shift to these
things
um
we have you know launched v6 uh
networking at scale conferences uh we
held a couple of those
we've published data on
facebook.com ipv6 where you can track
how
v6 traffic is
growing over time on
facebook
we
continue to monitor new isps that are
coming online with v6
and
you know most recently uh verizon fios
has finally started to deploy v6 and as
of today
they have gone
you know from the beginning of the
actually from their rollout starting in
about april they have gone from about
two percent to eight percent probably by
the time
we actually host this panel they'll be
well on their way to over ten percent of
their traffic
uh that's pretty exciting news because
people have been asking verizon since
the launch for v6
and uh
maybe they were doing this in
anticipation of uh
this anniversary but you know we still
have a long way to go there's still many
many large isps in the united states
that do not
support these things
but we continue to encourage them we
continue to
push them
i wish they were more like all the
mobile operators you know in the united
states we see about 90 of all mobile
traffic
so you know we've come quite a long way
to seeing the world you know embrace and
grow on v6
today globally
of our traffic to the internet is over
v6
um i would like that to be higher but
you know in the united
is blowing away states world with you
know
reliance jio as well over 90 percent of
iraq's jio's traffic 46 and india
serves up the most v6 bits on the planet
these days
so you know for us
we believe that we can't scale the
internet without v6 we believe that
e6 growth is super healthy
and
we are here to help any isp that wants
to
make sure that their rollout is going
well we
can work together
so that's basically you know what we
have been in the process of doing over
the last 10 years is just making sure
that all of our infrastructure
is well supported on v6 only networks
we really don't deploy anything inside
that you know requires d4
and so
that is our message to you is that you
can deploy
v6 only enterprise
data center networks
um you can even deploy v6 only inside of
your office
that's one other thing it's not this
scary thing that everybody seems to
think that it is
we have done it we did it with a small
team
and
i encourage you all to say
thank you
thank you paul
well done
uh
mark
tell us everything
my turn
um
my journey on uh
talk about the retrospective first here
and then i'll stand up and talk a little
bit about what you see on the uh on the
slides there i currently work in the
meraki business unit of cisco but i've
been at cisco since the late 90s
um i was at cisco but pretty much
working for
the ietf back in 2008.
um
and
i was area director in the ietf
so
spent most of my time working on ietf
things
and it kind of like this in one of these
forums
google was sponsoring an upcoming ietf
meeting
and we were all testing ipv6 at the ietf
because of course the ietf had ipv6
and i said
well
we kind of need some content on v6 i
said google next ietf that you're
sponsoring why don't you give at least
this conference quad a's
and then
after that plenary session
a guy walked up to me who's now with my
good friend uh eric klein he gave me his
card and the title on it was ipv6 guy
and he said
i emailed vent we'll do it
i was like okay well that's that's the
start of something okay
and then
he
talked to his friends at facebook at
yahoo et cetera et cetera we pull in
john we got the eye sock there and we
had a community
and
just as we saw this morning with ukraine
a community can be powerful
and how much more powerful was it
when yahoo could go and say hey the
google guys are doing it right we got to
do it too
um
or
you know comcast is doing it we've got
to do it or at t would say you know
comcast is doing att's got to do it so
on and so forth right
it was so much easier when you had a
community behind you
um so it led to a great period of time
now one
when we were engineering this whole
social community
technical thing
you know getting the big content and the
big isps on board right there's a few
engineering control points that have
massive effect because of
automation and scale right
and we were able to create that
measuring measurement system where we
see the numbers go up on the internet
but enterprise
right to your point earlier
what about enterprise networks and the
graph that you saw from scott hogg the
famous google one that goes up like this
everybody knows why there's a widening
gap
of of this seven day period with a
little bit of like holiday you can see
you can see covet in there it's
basically when people go to the office
they don't get v6 despite the great work
ron berzma did at d-rin
not every enterprise has a ron bursma or
a janzors or somebody to
make v6 go right
so
when meraki called me
in 2019
and i was i was still working on v6 i
got i had the chance during the launch
to kind of spearhead the movement of
cisco's operation and you know in
participation in v6
still loved it it really wasn't my day
job but they called up and i was like
aha
this
part of the business might be able to
make a difference for enterprise
uh if you're not familiar meraki is all
about making complex things simple
complex networking technology i.t
technology simple
and they do it by uh
allowing their equipment only to be
managed from a cloud from a web
interface right
um you're not allowed to ssh into the
box
this also means that firmware updates
can be sent out and so on and so forth
so i thought aha if we can get meraki to
do this maybe we can make a dent
in enterprise deployments just
a bit
so my goal is to get that widening
sawtooth to come down and
we'll do as much as we can with meraki
so
meraki calls says we want this v6 thing
and we're serious about it this time
and i said okay well you're gonna have
to like bring these couple of engineers
of mine that i've been working with on
v6 forever
move us all to san francisco
and
we'll get your ipv6 and they said okay i
was like i almost didn't expect it i was
living in paris france at the time i had
a great job at a research lab and cisco
teaching
but uh
we went
and
the first thing they did for me is
handed me a designer
20 years at cisco
never had worked with an artist okay we
would argue over cli and we had our
parser police and all that kind of stuff
but this was a designer that really
didn't know much about networking great
artists
put us in a room and we had to hammer
out how to make
v6 simple
and
if you don't make it simple you don't
ship it
we also had to make it work across the
entire stack now meraki sells routers
switches access points now cameras iot
devices all sorts of stuff
the access points in the switches in
layer two mode could kind of allow v6 to
go through them
but really it's about
the the the
blocking pieces was the mx which is our
router security appliances sits at the
edge of the networks and touches all the
isps
as well as the dashboard product
and i really wanted to be
data driven and deployment-minded
and i realized i should probably go to
the next slide
green one which is next
so that's where you see in 2019 it
literally says
hired industry experts that's me and a
couple of uh engineers from paris
we wanted to show that we were
really serious about this and we had to
turn on quad a's uh it's one of the
easier things actually to do for our
cloud we own and operate our own cloud
top to bottom
and uh so we have good engineers and
they were able to get the quad a's up
uh
then you know is like i've got the
designers
how do we get v6 to work across the
entire stack and the the router product
the mx i talked about was really the
blocker
and the reason was is we had to
basically had to write neighbor
discovery
and it doesn't just use linux right so
if we had to write neighbor discovery
dcp v6 all of it from scratch
which allowed us to also embed it
and make it work more seamlessly
looking at these things so you see the
mr and the ms and the mx so
a little bit of data here
um
i wanted to be
deployment-minded and data-centric so
the first thing we did was started
releasing firmware that would actually
see and process an ra from the uplink
and usually we're plugged into either
residential or business isp
service providers
if we see the ra we assume
we have v6 right
so we start collecting that data because
all of our products are connected to the
cloud
there's no exception
and
that's what you see this for this very
long time
this is the number of meraki mx
connected to an internet service
provider that has v6 on the uplink and
we had very small very small very small
very small
and then as you've seen
once you turn it on you realize
there's
quite a lot of
isps out there with ipv6 so this number
passed just in the past month or so went
over a million mx with ipv6 configured
on their uplink
we've got that's more than 50 percent
already
of mx's that are active and in use today
so that's because of all the hard work
that
the isps have done all of you have done
to just
make v6 available by default on so many
uh uplinks
so how do we make now that we've got v6
on the uplink how do we get it down to
to the endpoints well the only way to do
it is on by default
so that's the strategy we took
so if you go in well first of all the
weighing up link this is kind of what
you see there was part of the part of
what the designer told us was uh we
don't want to have like ipv6 and ipv4
modes we want it to be kind of built in
and those little little black dots
things on there where we obfuscate the
global ipv6 address it's necessary when
we do public presentations
but this is an actual screenshot of what
you get in you know released firmware
today um if you have an mx
if there is ipv6 on that uplink we show
you there's ipv6 on that uplink and
there's no way to turn it off you can
turn the whole link off but you cannot
just turn off v6
it's always there
and we figure it's better
even if you don't want v6 on your lan
it's better for you to know it's on your
wan
then for us to drop it silently or
something like that so we don't allow
you
we don't not tell you it's there we tell
you it's there always and you can't turn
that off
um
now
that's like when you first plug in the
box then you have to
configure the the lan side this isn't
residential it's enterprise it's maybe
sort of
um
not your well we have very big customers
i want to say that anyway it's not
consumer but it's it's it's still you
have to configure something and you have
to create a lan
and when you create a new vlan because
you can have course mini virtual lands
you basically have this it's kind of
hard to read sorry on the upper left
side of the screen
you have this you know that's i've i'm
creating a vlan i name it i
um i have to give it a number then i hit
next and then i have my v4 and you have
to configure the v4 but the v6 is
enabled by default
and we can have it on by default because
we can get prefixes from the isp via
dhcp v6pd we can put them in a pool
mapped to the wan that we've received
them on
and give them to the land we don't you
don't have to configure anything if you
don't want to
and then you're done you have v6 by
default so we're expecting
now that we have the um
the the firmware that has both wind and
lan side that we're going to get more
and more and more adoption over time on
the land side
for existing vlans we wanted to make as
simple as possible as well it's actually
three steps one you have to say modify
two you have to say enable and then
you're back to that same view where it's
all enabled by default
the
prefix delegation page
we have a new tab there where it's
basically telling you we're in this new
world where we're getting delegated
prefixes from isps and if i have any
requests
to the isp community is to please give
those delegated prefixes we're building
this
not as a nat box but as a router we're
trying everything we can do here to make
it as easy as possible
and
also to not nat what that means is we
got to have delegated prefixes a slash
64 just isn't good enough and lord knows
that 20 128 is terrible
so
when you enable on the land side we
start asking on those land sides give me
a slash 56
if you don't give me anything give me a
slash six give me a slash 64. this is
probably one of the the most complicated
things that we do to make it simple for
the end user
right but we do that to grab as many
prefixes as we can
and then we start assigning them to the
lands
and we will even split them up if we run
out
and we try to use them efficiently
but there's a point where maybe if
you've got you know a thousand vlans
you're going to run out and then what do
we do
that's where it stops being simple
that's where you have to like start a
human has to go okay do you want to put
ulas on or not you can you can manually
do this
then when we route the packets
we remember the if they were delegated
prefixes from a wan and we will send
them out the correct land but when
but if for some reason that wins down
we'll nad it to another land because of
bcp38
but all of that complexity there
is there to keep it simple for the end
user
one minute okay
so you see some of those land size
prefixes if you know we were zoomed in
there you would see this cute little um
four and six with a hexagon for six and
a square for four that's some of this uh
artistic stuff that gets built in
and the aqua page is even better where
we build the v4 and the v6 together so
you can create a rule
one apple if you wanted to apply for v4
and v6 you don't have to keep them
separate
um so again all the all this work to
make a
to make
v6 enabled by default
and to make it easier
to uh to manage
so
we keep posting updates out there
and i i hope this
and i want to come back and give another
presentation at some point where i show
the data on the lan side of the adoption
that we're getting into end i expect it
to be
like we've seen from our residential
providers that when we turn it on it's
there right on the on the endpoints and
we've started turning it on but it takes
time for the uh for the the new vlans
to uh
to come online because we have more
existing vlans than new vlans right
so
what we want is to track all this and
see how it's being used and at some
point in the future
to be able to
enable it on all the vlans
with a notice it'll be like an upgrade
oh and by the way you're going to get v6
right
and then watch the v6 and start
bringing out technologies that allow us
to take v4 off the lands and just walk
the customer through that journey
with easy by default types of steps
and hopefully that can be a um
a pattern for for other
vendors and other
enterprises to follow
so thank you mark so
when you spoke about
uh power of the community coming
together and since we had
ipv6 day and ipv6 launch
do we need some
something like this some more events one
new event with peer pressure to maybe
put ipv6 on by default and
and use the same mechanism as we did 10
years ago to move the needle forward
maybe
uh john
will you
i'd love to thank you for this
discussion i don't think i've stayed
this quiet this long in a long time so
so uh
i'm happy to chime in here i mean
friends long time friends i mean in some
ways
a lot of what we're hearing here i i was
old as new right gradual enabling you
know turn it on gradually upload i
learned it all from you
i love you man i love you
the uh
but uh you know the and and i'm a little
emotional right now not really but kind
of figuratively you know you know i
think about the conversation
i had with vince i had i had the
pleasure to see him in person a few
weeks ago to prep to prepare for this
for the video we did this morning
and we were kind of talking about this
you know you know 10 years later lots of
progress
but we still have a long way to go right
i i had the honor to come back here in
the fall and i kind of did some you know
look at some data
by some measures i mean it could be
another 10 years but then i hear
on by default on by default eric nygren
on by default paul's been on by default
for you know you know years matthew 2
and etc right so now i'm confused right
so
and one of the things that i i do want
to kind of comment on is v6 on by
default just to be crystal clear is not
necessarily v6 only someday
hopefully v6 only i won't be here right
yeah these guys will be all like on
vacation somewhere on a beast together
but but whoever comes to this next the
next generation or two i mean yeah i see
that in in the future but
the question is burning right so
what's the problem i mean like i i
didn't know many of these things even
though we've kind of tried to you know
maniacally plan for our panel here we
left a lot we left some room for
variability here right but there's a lot
of there's a lot of news here about b6
on by default i mean
i don't think we're done
so i i i'm going to pose the question to
you all
so what what holds us back what what
hinders us you know
are you all disappointed in where things
stand as far as v6 is concerned you know
let's let's open that up a little bit
and
kind of spice the conversation up you
know so that we can
you know get some feedback from the
audience yeah have your voices heard
thoughts
jason
i
echo the sentiment for sure of on by
default i think the main message is that
when you're turning the service up for a
customer
it's okay for them to break on that one
little thing because they're not yet
production you're not taking them down
and it helps them highlight any areas
that need to be fixed and if necessary
opt out if they have to but hopefully no
go fix it
it's a lot harder to go in and
once it's up and running to go and
change the knob because then you're
putting them at risk of
breaking them
this is
i imagine true for service providers
it's certainly true for
uh internal stuff and places i've worked
at nobody wants to touch the thing
that's working
uh
it takes a lot more effort to do it
after the fact
one zoom uh i'm assuming that
the zoom folks can hear us right
a b team
paul eric ron
thoughts
one of you
they're the three developers
the long tail ends up being a real
challenge here like for isps a lot of
the big isps who have turned things on
by default have had huge growth but
there are a lot of smaller isps out
there that haven't had that big
push or drive or need to enable ipv6
that haven't um and this i think the
same goes across
enterprises
and it also but that also goes across
even on the device side we see that the
it's not it the major browsers and major
operating systems all have ipv6 on by
default but when you start getting out
into consumer electronics
or many mobile apps
there are plenty that either don't have
ipv6 on by default or have bad ipv6
implementations like we've seen cases
where
where a you get the combination of a isp
that has done a poor imp a poor ipv6411
has some connectivity issues um combined
with a
some smart tv that doesn't do happy
eyeballs and now you have a streaming
provider that turns on tries to turn v6
on and um starts getting complaints
because in some country where that smart
tv is popular users can't go watch their
stream anymore and that content then
gets switched back to v4 only and this
is not in the kind of the core set of of
of
names that everyone would have heard of
but it can but even those things out at
the tail can be enough um to be causing
real problems that i think are going to
be one of the challenges we have to face
over the next um decade
you know eric if i can chime in briefly
before others do i i used to think the
same way you know the smaller isps you
know where they at so my family and i
went on on a short easter trip this year
you know as i always do i visit
testv6.com you know like why not i mean
that's what of course first thing you do
when you connect to the to the airbnb
yeah wi-fi
v6 on enabled by default eric can you
believe it i i couldn't believe it i was
a pentel data anybody for pentel anyone
bueller
no you should be yeah good job right um
so so anyway you know uh back to you
know others here you know chime in
please i mean you know
we're i'm still confused right yeah
matthew please yeah i mean i think i
think to a certain degree like the
success of world ipv6 day and launch
were certainly the community that came
out of that the the concerted focus
around making ipv6 available
getting past those gaps that did exist
or at least we thought may have existed
and
to me i think where where maybe we need
to see some more traction is outside
this community i think the folks mainly
in this room have understanding they've
done their part in many cases
i think it's the long tail it's the long
tail that predo curve
you know i think it was uh it was scotty
who had that slide up the top million
websites something like 20 or v6 enabled
so i think it's kind of that long tail
and maybe
maybe cdn plays a role maybe there are
other pieces where there's choke points
that can can have an amplified effect
but i think to some degree it's still
outside this room it's consumer
electronics
apps that kind of thing so matthew
question for you so
service provider right you know i i've
been there right um
cgn you talk about cgn you talk about v4
service map e map t i mean still
provides v for connectivity it's
different and i do want to get back if
the gentleman's here from netflix who
asked the question in the previous panel
i i would like for you to come back up
when we do some open q a but my question
to you is
what do you think do you think that
would be a motivator do you think that
would change the game
i i i do have a follow-on comment on
that yeah no i think cgn for sure is is
going to be the future more and more
um
and i think one way one way i look at it
now is more and more customers served by
cgn but i want to see less and less
traffic served by cgn so that means
identifying what is the traffic that's
relying upon it that could be going v6
that's not and why is that let's tackle
that
great
one comment and then uh you know open it
up again so to the netflix gentleman who
was at the mic last time
what i you know there was a comment
around you know v6 was broken the first
step was to turn off v6 what i have
found personally when you use it to run
your business
like
operate a cable model for example like
you you make sure v6 works period you
don't have a choice otherwise the rest
of your services don't work when there
are ships in the night that that
ultimately creates the greatest
opportunity for things to get out of
sync and broken back to you all you know
either in person or
i have one thing to add on these
challenges you asked earlier you know
what are the challenges to get v6 on by
default one of the things i would love
to know from you like how mark in his
presentation said uh v6 on by default
and new vlans existing vlans you can
enable it uh we have the existing enable
option we don't have it new by default
uh what we are i guess what i would love
folks as inputs on is how do you define
new in in a world in in the cloud where
you can literally spin up new in seconds
it's all scripted and your load balancer
a new load balancer is basically the
same one replica running a entire
production traffic and that new is no
longer new because it looks to us as new
but it's really an existing application
that has live traffic on it
so not necessarily to you but that's
that's one of the challenges that we
sort of think about so how do you define
in that world what that new identity is
where you say in this new box it's safe
versus like the old box not so not so
much
interesting mark
well from
from meraki's standpoint and and you
know maybe this can translate into you
know the aws vpc creation or some such
is
that
essentially anywhere
um we can avoid
the the user having to type in an ip
address we try to avoid it right and we
do that with with more and more with v4
as well as um with v6 and it turns out
that
it's actually easier in v6 in a way
right because if you have those
delegated prefixes
you can use them and do it
algorithmically right um
so
so that's what you saw where
when
we're enabling
the topology create the vlan
we give them v4 and v6 and the v6 is
actually easier than v4 in the default
mode right
um
so you know perhaps in the vpc one of
the one of the things you said is you
know it's like oh it lets you wrap up a
customer's cloud environment and give
them private addresses right well maybe
with v6 you can give them public
addresses um or give them private ulas
and and not them out of floating uh v6
if you must but this is one thing that
we're trying to avoid and
it all depends on how many delegated
prefixes we can get i suppose with with
aws you could allocate as many as you
wanted from from
your your pa space and
um from your pi space given to them
and and maybe they could bring their own
uh addresses but then we hit the bgp
issues
but anyway that's going down in rat hall
um i think there's things that you can
do and we should talk about this
afterwards
um just to go through that workflow and
try to eliminate as many steps as
possible yeah yeah
awesome
mr saab i remember
in your office the old one we sat
together side by side turning on
facebook for
you know for uh you know some some uh
comment subscribers
just like yesterday right um so what are
your thoughts paul um you know as far as
i mean and this is
you know to some extent i have to
imagine you know as close as we've been
over the years you know this
is probably like an old conversation for
you right so any words of wisdom
thoughts
you know
the work that we did was like
i i have to think it was like maybe two
or three of us were actually leading the
project and we had
um an excellent project manager that
basically sat down with everybody
inside of you know infrastructure and
just like kind of forced them
there's a funny story if there was a
team that wasn't listening or wasn't
actually doing the work he would go and
sit down next to the engineers and shame
them
uh but he would just sit there and
you know just do his work and just
remind them that he was you know on
their case every day
um
but for us you know we
v6 is a mission-critical part of our
business we could not be scaling our
data centers we could not be scaling
anything that we do
at facebook meta
inside of our data centers you know we
we had to
migrate internally
to v6 um because the other option was we
had to renumber before
all of our rfc 1918 space or go out and
buy some
you know public space and use that
internally which we would have murdered
for
um
you know and and the project
while it was a tough 18 months and i i
say tough because there was times where
i did not think
we were going to be successful
and
you know we just slogged through and
jason is right
you know it's not easy to take a big
moving ship and uh
convert it in flight
um but you're also wrong jason in that
if you just put a small dedicated team
they can they can pull off anything you
know i mean i think you know google
lorenzo and eric did most of the work
themselves
and so
this is like the key to all of the other
you know operators and app developers
out there it's it's not that part
um
the thing that you will probably run
into is what reddit ran into a couple
weeks ago when they were trying to test
it on their android app happy eyeballs
is still not really well supported on
android
um
and i think just okay http just got like
happy eyeball support recently
you know we had to go and develop all
that stuff ourselves in our apps and
make sure that we were
um
uh you know supporting not only dual
stack networks but v6 only networks you
know before apple fixed a lot of their
stuff for v6 only um in the operating
system we had to you know do the work
ourselves to to make it work
um
[Music]
there's there's just
you know there's um
[Music]
i think that
we're at an interesting point in that
you know there's there's a lot of work
that's been going on and then the long
tail just isn't isn't happening
um you know i'll call them out by name
because there wouldn't you know roku is
probably one of the biggest um
culprits to see more and more
growth on the internet you know they're
one of the largest streaming set top
boxes and they still haven't turned on
v6
you know even though you knew john have
been yelling at them many of us have
been yelling at them for years it's
still not there
um and so you know how do you get all of
these you know consumer devices that are
sitting in people's homes to to turn on
v6 because
you know a good portion of the
residential users you know have it
and you know we're just lacking you know
step top boxes you know consumer
electronic devices and offices
so
i you know it's it's it's really just
rolling up your sleeves and doing the
work
great paul ron last but not least
words of wisdom thoughts
uh yeah um so i've been thinking through
the uh on by default which we've been
doing for a long time and and the thing
that comes to my mind is that you can
lead a horse to water but you can't make
them drink
and we've seen that a lot where i can
mandate that all of our subscribers on
drain i can give them ipv6 addresses
give every site of 48 i can
mandate that their border router um is
up on v6 but
um i don't control those large
laboratories and defense contractors and
so forth they run on their own networks
and they don't enable it on their
firewall or in their internal networks i
don't control that so what's the
incentive but the only controls i have
is other things they might want to get
to
inside our environment is start turning
off v4 so they're forced to turn on v6
that's a bit of incentive it works to a
certain
degree
but i i've been frustrated with
mandates that don't work and i've been
through a lot of them over the years
i am a fan of flag days and that might
be heresy just because of what it means
but i was there in 1983 when we turned
off ncp it was a huge motivator
i remember when we turned off the six
bone i remember
when we converted from analog to digital
tv it was a flag day and it was
successful the um
there was also the the dns flag day just
a few years ago that was successful when
can we have some kind of a um a v6 flag
day where we turn off before or start
turning it off for real
um set the deadline that'll be a huge
motivator um maybe that's impossible but
that's what's going to get it done
um in the long run so
it's something to think about just as
the next step beyond turn it on by
default let's start turning off before
we can so that's my final thought
i got one thing to jump in here um hey
on on the on by default because i i
didn't really answer that for you
when
one
piece of the network decides to make it
on by default they're doing a huge favor
for that other piece
so right now in my job at meraki i'm
sitting between the isps which
by
data that i can show my you know
superiors
you know look the isps already have this
v6 on by default right i see and on the
on the lan side i know
that the apples and the androids and the
windows and
other things have it on by default so i
know i'm sitting there in the middle and
we can just turn up the dial right
what if i had had to go and say okay now
we gotta call comcast and uh ask them to
turn it on for all the meraki customers
here's the list yeah it's it's
it wouldn't have happened so being
preemptive you know making sure the
chicken appeared before the egg actually
was extremely valuable in this case so
this on by default is hugely important
how do we put a day around it that's
that's maybe a harder question but the
messaging of owned by default
hugely important
it makes it so much easier for everybody
else who's trying to make it go
all right so we're going to get the hook
here mark so i'm going to wrap it up if
uh if you don't mind so
lady and gentlemen
thank you so much despite our best
efforts jan we cut it close we're we're
this close to being able to take some q
a so we so but we can't do that so at
the end of the day if you anybody has
questions we know there's some online
i'll work with the panelists to make
sure that we can address them and answer
them virtually right
so if anybody here has the same please
channel questions and we will absolutely
respond to you
it's been an honor and a pleasure thank
you thank you very much
[Applause]
no thank you
[Music]