or one morning I guess almost good
afternoon July first off thank you for
having me back as I suppose to be a
couple years ago but it is thanks to my
daughter my back was so here in so yes I
am here to talk about the examination of
tools some of the tools of the actors
and the defenses that are available
crystal clear this is not a vendor
related pitch in any way shape or form
but we do have data from our platform
that will be using so I just wanna make
sure that I'm clear that up front
because I don't like to sit in the crowd
and have somebody go will you click this
button and then nobody enjoys that so
why am i standing here talking to you I
have been in this industry space for
over 20 years now and before I came over
to join Akamai about two and a half
years ago I did about twenty years on
your side of the phone if your defender
I have worked and all manner of
companies from couple of power companies
several banks us' Department of Defense
which will be clear and Canadians are is
actually rather impressed they let me
mess around with their firewalls at the
pentagon and it has been an interesting
really entertaining career for me and as
a result as I've gone long of collected
a lot of stories and I'm going to drive
the cameramen nuts because I wonder so I
apologize in advance and one with these
stories that are managed to collect I've
actually read a lot of stories and as a
result of the stories I've been able to
write for CSO online forums and few
others as one of things I really enjoy
being able to actually share these
experiences with folks and not from a
you know look how great of a hacker I am
because that ship sail twenty years ago
now I get the chase paper on the desk
and come talk to get folks like you so I
really enjoy this opportunity able to
come out and talk and share these
stories and hopefully you're able
actually take something away from this
to help you know improving your own
environment such as Adobe and my copious
time I actually like to hang out with my
family
nothing like waking up at five o'clock
in the morning with two small children
going to a deeply with us
awesome but I do feel like this alot of
the time with a lot of conversations
that I have regarding cloud especially
when it comes to large organizations and
government which are still interest the
idea of cloud is rather scary
really isn't there's a sticker that i've
seen on a few laptops that says cloud is
just somebody else's computer to agree
to a degree that is actually true but
the reality is that it off loading up so
that you can actually do a better job
with what you're doing and one of things
that really frustrates me is with the
media icon Solis to stories about a
distributed denial of service but they
never really give you anything of
substance other than hacker group of the
day said to be clear I like to use the
term attacker I i sort of fumbled there
myself I prefer that as opposed to
hacker because I see that as our word
and the media likes to try and scare you
because they want you to look at their
various sites and they leave you with
the sense of terror that something's
creeping up behind you but the security
controls that are in place
aren't always going to see the thing
that's coming up after you with media
they like to just put that fear into you
and this was one of the things that
actually relief I found wanting
I really was left with a rather empty
sense after that so that's where this
talk was actually born out of so the
game plan for what I'm talking about
today gonna go through the actor's the
attacks tools trends data and what can
you do and I want to say what you can do
things you can do now today that can
help with your own environment so one of
the really interesting things starting
off and this is always intrigued me are
the actress or higher
the mercenaries of the internet and
these have always tickle me because when
I was doing contract work for the
department of defense in the USA years
ago we used to see these characters all
the time and they even tried to get us
to hire them to do various attacks on
mobile attack country X for you know but
the thing that really caught me was that
you could actually have a bespoke
implementation of their services so this
is a couple years out of date now but it
just gives you a rough idea so this was
from 2012 and this was from a Russian
underground site that you know we can do
X Y and Z in a really interesting thing
was a DDoS but that was only $700
whether that was at one time for your
current fee that wasn't entirely clear
but this was when we first saw 2012 we
really saw this
coming to in into its own rape and we
saw in North America where somebody a
company hired a group like this to
attack one of the competitors this
unraveled and they caught the attackers
and the attacker slipped on the people
declared them and they went to general
but it's not all bad news the really
ironic thing is when I first gave this
talk at North SEC in Quebec City this
was one of the things that I found was a
group where you could get back together
various types of attacks hackers to do
its penetration testing things like that
for you if you don't have them on staff
because of me honestly not everybody has
these bench strength available to them
so you can do this
the funny thing was the data presented
this about twenty-four hours later they
were compromising every single user that
was using the service was actually
exposed so at least it was a good start
so given that now the attackers
obviously we're gonna go through really
quick version of this because I mean I
know you guys are familiar with this
thing but with the first off we have the
board kids and this is one of the ones I
always like to talk about because I see
it as our duty collectively to go out
and educate the kids today as to how not
to get themselves thrown in jail when I
first started doing this sort of thing
back when the world was flat I didn't
have any sort of guidance but I had a
little sick sense of I don't want to go
to prison so I learned to build my own
systems and do my own tests in my own
environment not everybody was actually
quite so lucky or so smart
a lot of people went to jail even today
we see with all of these implementations
of various cloud services for higher
that do stress testing we see a lot of
people getting rounded up and sent to
jail that he didn't know any better and
a lot of this is because we have the
board kid element when I was a kid was
bored of go outside and play hockey
because that's what we did in Canada
nowadays kids have access to the
Internet
they're bored they're looking for a
Cause are looking for purpose something
to be a part of
unfortunately there's a negative
elements out there that will gladly
conscripted these folks into a
disposable army of one of a better term
and this is one of things that really
worries me because a lot of these kids
make decisions that are bad and they
don't have any understanding that
they're actually making these negative
choices for example when hurt lead came
out let me to say that was a fun day
when her plea came out there was a kid
in London Ontario in Canada who decided
he was going to go after the Revenue
Canada site which is the site is
responsible for collecting taxes for
Canada none of us like them this kid
particularly been like them and went
after them using heart bleed to see as
much information as you could get within
24 hours the Royal Canadian Mounted
Police showed up and we haven't heard
from him since I don't know quite what
happened with him
the problem with him is he was actually
eighteen years of age which in Canada
means you go to jail do not pass go so
kids don't always make the right choices
you know they'll see something that
looks appealing but me and badly and the
problem is not only end badly you can
actually come back to haunt you years
later and lover hate the ISU squared I
serve on the Board of Directors at least
for another two months one of the
service they have is they have a service
actually help go out and teach kids as
well i mean Starcraft fans we got them
maybe one guy to guy alright well
Starcraft was a game back when the
nineties that I used to play and these
particular characters are called deserve
so every time you the premise was you
build up these resources you bill
everything out and then these guys will
show up and destroy everything these
guys piss me off it wasn't for 14 cheat
codes I would never got anywhere but
this is how I envisioned denial of
service every time I hear about it
because these guys are a pain in the ass
and we would see all kinds of Sindh
floods and things like that too would
attack our users and it's really fun
being able to actually mitigate these
things and the problem I see is that if
you're not properly protecting your site
you know you could have the most amazing
looking site but if you can't protect
that you're stuck in the mud or in this
case in the pilot sheep so I had hoped
to give you are cute three data but
apparently our report is not going out
till December 2nd so unfortunately I'm
only gonna be stuck with cue to data I
really apologize for that because
I was battling with our internal folks
for right up until yesterday so here's
an example of the type of attacks we see
broken out based on infrastructure type
of tax the really interesting one that
got me was SSTP was one of the top to
attack types I wrote an article about
this and I believe it was forbes and I
just went through the whole type thing
is how this was a major a reflection
attack the Universal Plug and Play
consortiums to ground these said
Universal Plug and Play is perfectly
safe there's nothing wrong with it
this article is patently wrong would
like to take it down this is why we do
the data cuz I've seen too many times
were articles to talk about attacks but
they talked about in terms of hyperbole
and they want actually scare people but
they don't give you any raw data so I
assume we have data so almost 16 percent
of all the attack types in Q-two only
and that's actually since gone up in
Q-two we're using this as their attack
vector saw this really interesting that
they thought that I would take it down
because it was gonna happen and SACP is
a simple service discovery protocol and
this is actually something that
shouldn't be available to be an attack
but it works and this one of things that
a lot of people don't take into account
is that when you're deploying services
via SNMP NTP whatever it is it's like
patch your stuff patcher systems because
if you're not keeping current on all the
revisions of these things that you're
exposing to the internet you actually
becoming part of the problem and that
shouldn't be the case with all security
professionals this is what we do so why
is it that our environments end up
contributing to this sort of thing
simply because I get it we have
resources like so many hours in the day
I actively lobbied for 26 hour days and
that failed but what it is it's just one
of those things that we have to take
into account as we have to own up to the
responsibility of making sure our
systems are up to date now when we're
talking about a different type of tax
the one that really gets me is the
application layer attacks these always
focus on the logic or not always but
focus on the logic of you
web forms and things that affect how
your site is working so just simple
denial of service attacks have limited
utility if you're using a service like
ours or any of our other types out there
that is going to have limited effect for
the attacker the world's biggest bang
for the buck and this is where they
require some level of intelligence is
going after the application logic it's
simple to download until now click click
Next and I'll talk about some of these
tools later we just launched an attack
in Lego looking I'm gonna die and this
one of things that gets me so we're
looking at application type of tax these
are the things these are the factors
that we saw from denial service
perspective and Justin Q-two so ACV get
was only accounting for less than 9
percent of the overall tactics or less
than 10% of the attacks were based over
application type of attack so it's
really interesting but the one thing
that we saw a rise to greater prominence
with the extortion level attacks in
particular was needed for BC will talk
about it but the second now the last
year we saw these attacks were these
sites were getting extortion note saying
they would get a burst of attack traffic
and they would get an email saying okay
we've attacked you now what you gonna do
you gonna give us X amount of Bitcoin or
we're going to attack you again the
thing that really got us was the tax
traffic at that time wasn't very high
was pretty insignificant in the grand
scheme of things but the amount of money
they were asking for roughly equated to
about between 80 and $150 United us'
dollars and so this is the oddest
extortion attempt ever seen and it
really struck us that this was actually
I was really surprised that this is more
of somebody testing out their new
monster and in short order we had the TV
for PC or distributed denial of service
for Bitcoin
name ever they need marketing people and
they began to organize and the amounts
went up
and in rather short order so this is an
example of an email that was sent to one
of our customers saying this is going to
be the best part is for those in the
back I can't see it says we'd like to
introduce ourselves here are some links
the only thing that really surprised me
they didn't say Google associate know
they did just google tv for pc and
you'll find out more info so these are
folks that are becoming more and more
enamored with themselves that they were
actually sharing their own press with
her attack targets is really interesting
and they have progressively increased in
their abilities to the point where it
now they're asking for 30 Bitcoin and I
don't know what the current exchange
rate is at this point but it has been
going up so when they would launch these
attacks they have increased from half
usually half of this year ago to they
claim they can do between 400 and 500
gigabytes per second the reality was at
the time that I did this particular side
which is about a quarter ago they had
only gotten up to 50 gigabytes in size
for their attacks and progressively they
will improve it's just inevitable
because they're expanding their platform
so they will get better at it and this
goes back to the application
amplification attacks this is what I was
a moment ago when we talked about NTP
SMP DNS is perfect examples if we're not
patched the current and we're not
securing these demons properly we are
part of the problem and I mean it it's
something that we need to fix we can do
better at this and it's coming up on us
to take this message out to our
respective organizations as a look every
part of the problem are we
contributing to this and one of the
really interesting things was with these
types of attacks that we see one of the
really want fun ones with DNS we saw
using tax records as amplification so
here's a sample anatomy of an attack I
don't imagine this is newsday anybody
manage traffic reflecting off DNS there
are amplifying the amount of traffic
that's hitting the target of cool part
was the sample pack of the attack
target President Obama's taking action
to ensure opportunity for what they had
actually taken the time to take a press
release from the US white house put it
into their attacks to make a statement
as well as while they're attacking
others liked
thereby increasing the amount of traffic
increasing the amount of volume of the
attack I'll give him credit that was
kind of neat in that respect and they
voice their opinion whatever is exactly
that was an entirely sure so now let's
talk about a little bit of the types of
tools that we see because it's one of
things that really interests me is that
with media types we never see what kind
of tools are discussing on occasional
mentioned robot but for all intents and
purposes they don't really talk about
the different types of tools and within
the tool locker we have obviously
volumetric single injection so on so
forth one of my favorite ones is and I'm
probably gonna be sure the names of
those who have it or I'm assuming a
percentage rate if I didn't apologize to
the authors this is a really handy tool
this is very simple if you want to do a
single injection attack you put in the
information you click Go
it's incredibly simple to use and freely
available online so the barrier to entry
for an attacker has dropped
precipitously over the years when I
first started we had to read all our own
scripts we had to do all this now you
just downloaded tool and click a button
and look at me I'm attacking and this
really plays into this culture of look
how awesome I am because I can attack
you blah blah blah and which is great up
until the police show up because a lot
of these tools do absolutely nothing
obfuscate the origin
now this is one that we found 2012 and I
love this tool simply because of the man
so the whole cool is http unbearable
load King is what it stands for
wasn't overly unbearable but it was
really interesting that it would send
traffic at the site the user agent you
can make it a random value but here's an
example of the type of traffic you would
see it in your site there's really
nothing overly obvious about this
particular traffic
other than there would be this and
millions of his friends and it would do
nothing to obfuscate the point of origin
so the attacker had to be sure that
they're covering her tracks and if they
did not so as we go through these
different types at all here's another
issue to be flutter this is called on it
being Canadian we have art importance we
love her don't it's very simple URL port
number of threads start and this is the
traffic that we received back it's
really really simple so anybody who has
any ability to search Google or Bing
actually you know the searches and finds
tools rather simplistic fashion so I
thought ok so they're not doing anything
to obfuscate their point of origin what
would be an interesting way to change
that
oh ok somebody thought of that towards
hammer this is kind of neat this is a
Python script which actually leverages
the Tor network to launch the attacks
are pretty interesting but knowing folks
like they're like over it or project not
kind of people upset I quite liked them
so i didnt never tested this to myself
so this would do a low and slow across
the Tor network and it's really
interesting this is how simple it was
the use tours hammer that the IP address
number of threads and off the coast so
one of the things that we did was in
addition to this is just one example
there's other types of attacks are going
across the network so what we did was we
went through the amount of data that we
had from collected on our platform and
look to see what kind of store base
attacks are we seeing and don't get me
wrong I love story think it's a great
idea I think it's a wonderful thing
unfortunately it's much the same vein as
nonsensical argument were saying about
encryption right now in the media people
going encryption is evil
it would have stopped XY and Z will
actually had nothing to do with XY and Z
but this whole thing people like to
demonize what they don't understand and
tourism example but unfortunately have
attackers are leveraging its launch
attacks the really interesting thing was
born 10 port scanners are you going to
action with the main types of attacks
that we saw going across the Tor network
and compare we did a comparison with non
tour based IP's
and it was really interesting how they
pretty much wrapped together on the
types of attacks that were doing but
heaven forbid the people plan along
nicely so here's an example some of the
targets that were being hit with tour
based attacks and when I said orbiaz I
mean there were just using is how they
get their retail and financial services
were wanted to so what we saw previously
with the al-qassam cyber fighters were
they were attacking financial sites
namely banks and credit unions has now
shifted because those individuals or
companies have gotten better at
protecting their site and now the
attacker to switch their attention to
retail but by and large has not done a
wonderful job as we see in with Target
Home Depot and so on and so forth and
admittedly those were primarily
targeting their point of sale systems
but not exclusively so we do see a lot
of that in a way of attacker and heaven
forbid I do things in order so this is
actually a capture from donut which was
talking about a moment ago
here's the traffic for donut which again
is really not all that obvious there's
nothing to say haha other than the
volume now when I talk about these tools
I'm sure everybody in the room knows
about lower but ion cannon if you don't
really funny little to all this was
something I was put out by anonymous
quite a few years ago now and the whole
idea was they were going to use this
disposable workforce this is possible
army of kids to go out and attack sites
they provided the module and then it
would go on peaceful or whatever and say
here's the target we're gonna hit and
miss the day we're gonna hit effective
in its implementation but the thing is
anybody using this tool this tool did
nothing to obfuscate their point of
origin so if they were attacking
law enforcement had their IP address yes
IP address does not equal you are the
attacker but sure cause you a headache
when they show up and this really
interesting so would join the fray they
would jump in the click the Buy they
would check in the police would show up
so ultimately led to the natural
progression to the high orbit
the really interesting thing here is it
there were actually able to changes
using with a cold blaster packs where
they could change the type of attack
that we were using because lower but I
am can I was very limited and very easy
to block hire an accountant at least put
change it up just a bit and again
there's an HEB get related type of
attack
simplistic but effective and then robot
robot was what are saying about earlier
with al-qassam cyber fighters this was
told that they were using where they
were leveraging compromise WordPress
installation is it was not exclusively
WordPress but primarily and having run a
wordpress site now for the better part
of 10 years I can tell you it's a giant
pain in the butt to keep secure and I
saying secure so this botnet that they
had built was extremely effective and
they were able to actually pivot very
quickly they get updated quickly it was
rather impressive in its implementation
giant pain in the butt if you were a
victim of it but it what they would do
is when they would attack the site they
would say ok we're going to attack you
at this time and is going to run for X
number of minutes and they were true to
their word which is really interesting
because we saw with cd4 BC they would
say we're going to attack you they
wouldn't say you how long or how long
after their throat you now we see the
Armada collective which has come up
which is basically a video of Duty four
BC they're trying the same type of thing
but they don't always make good on what
they're going to say they say they're
going to attack and sometimes they do
sometimes they don't I don't get bored
and go for pizza it's really an
interesting one that we shall puzzling
out now we're positing these sort of
things out we see robot being pretty
effective platform to tools like W get
this drives me nuts in this goes back to
law enforcement and governments not
understanding what they're afraid of and
demonizing the things that they don't
understand
encryption W get is a very very simple
tools I use it all the time it's very
effective for doing research at one
point in the media they were demonizing
this thing it was an attack to land
there is actually some legislators in
North America that wanted to outlaw this
which is just fine
not a good idea and it's incumbent upon
us to actually go forth and talk to
these folks we're very very good at
talking amongst ourselves I I start my
navel all day long and I talk to myself
and this is one of the things that we
have to do a better job of talking to
the non-security types we have to get
the message across
so we don't have to deal with crap like
this there's no good reason that we
should be doing this when I hear there
was just last night on the television
there's aus senator named forgot his
name already and how he's on their
intelligence subcommittee I use the
internment Odense loosely he was saying
that encryption is it should be bandaged
there's a real problem is helping the
attackers now to use the Paris example
which is very fresh
this was a close-knit group of people
that all knew each other live together
and used SMS to communicate encryption
was never part of the equation based on
the published information to this point
I don't know if there's anything else
they just haven't come forth with that
still obviously in motion but this is
one of the things they worry about that
if we don't do a better job of speaking
up they're going to start taking away
our VPN are going to take away our
encryption to the point where we're
going to become the Outlaws I mean that
has a certain cachet to it but I really
don't want to be on the run so with the
amount of data that we have we actually
have the ability to go through and look
at all these different type of the trans
and see the things that are evolving and
serious some really new stuff this
particular piece hear them talk about is
not that new actually not that new in
any way shape or form but it has taken
on a different view and I see media
grandstanding that usually says media
whores but I decided imma down now
a perfect example of these guys are the
lizard squad in church here is a tool is
really that's less not less than
expected this was a crew of attackers
that were basically gamers on a gaming
platform that shall remain nameless that
discovered very quickly that people that
they didn't like that we're getting a
higher score on Dustin around to be that
they could kick them off and they would
actually launch dial service attacks
against these individuals on this gaming
platform and then they realize quite
accidentally that they could actually
knock out entire swath of this
particular network and then they decided
oh we really had hackers and then they
started doing interviews if you're doing
criminal activity one of the things you
really don't want to be doing is doing
television interviews with the BBC two
of them did do this as far as I know
they were actually incarcerated now I
won't give him points for intellect in
that particular case but one of things
that they have done is they've actually
done a good job of illustrating one of
the new dynamics that when I think you
dynamics it's a great greater prevalence
is the commoditization to distribute an
hour service we see all these different
types of botnets are being built out
using home routers using compromised
systems using whatever it happens to be
this attached to the Internet toasters
probably next and what they're doing is
they're providing a SAS implementation
of DDoS and for a trivial amount of
money you can actually launch your own
DDoS case in point last year almost
December last year there was an article
here about how for 66 bucks a month you
can start your own DDoS and they thought
they could get away with this
believe this platform is actually still
up today because they keep moving around
but one of the interesting things when
they first world other platform
the platform was actually built on code
from another group called the titanium
structure group they did absolutely
nothing to lock it down apparently easy
access files are true novel idea for
them and so we were able to actually
incremental go through the site we were
able to download the user's everything
it was amazing but this was real thing
that really got me you have your
different packages you could do monthly
subscriptions for you distributed denial
of service attack the one that got me
the most was $69.99 for 7200 seconds a
month or you do the lifetime for 280
lifetime has not been determined
probably shorter than they would hope
but not in terms of Canadian dollars if
you're looking at it from buying an
American coffee at Starbucks I use an
example I will not buy it but here
$69.99 a month and take that divided by
30 days every month the cost ends up
being less than a cup of coffee a day to
launch an attack for 7200 seconds it may
not seem like a lot but for a site that
unprotected that you just happen to be
annoyed with that could cause a great
deal of heartache some serious financial
penalties or cost at least so the first
part of that was talking about where
they were targeted targeting folks on
the gaming at work this is perfect
simple to use what's called a bitter
they can actually target the individual
users and not my flight so is so it was
really interesting in that regard to
said that tool that they were used
basically based on a rivalries like
kicking people off because it was kind
of annoying but that gave birth to the
stressor these are platforms that
actually legitimately exist in the past
I used to use one back in the nineties
for one of the financial institutions I
was working we would actually run stress
tests against our site to see how our
application stand up under load so there
were legitimate uses for these but the
thing is calling it a stressors illegal
artifact the idea that they're using it
by calling it a stressor saying we're
providing you a tool
they're hoping that they're not going to
get arrested by calling us treasure
because we're providing the tools but
how you happen to use it
is a different thing and when you flip
it on the head you look at it like I
have a hammer can build a house or can
build about the head with it it goes
back not to the tool to the intent and
fortunately the intent with these
different platforms is not so much of a
noble cause but here's an example of
some of the different types of Buddhism
stressors that we've seen in her in our
travels you know various types here but
my favorite one here simply from the
marketing aspect apparently is platform
is absolutely terrible but Big Bang
puter and I will get into that because
this see if this works this is a video
ever found online for Big Bang buddha
where they're generating revenue it
really has gone around the other way so
some of the other highlights that we've
seen inner journeys are different types
of crews that are a rising a rising up
to copy folks like TV for PC we're
seeing more of those popping up
Joomla and others have been targeted
rather frequently and the thing that
really gets me a skipper in the bottom
data breaches are feeling login attacks
this is one of things that drives me
absolutely batty because all the
different types of sites out there if
you go and you buy something on Amazon
password everyone in here uses a
different password for each safe ok
there said not unfortunately folks like
our parents or non-technical friends
don't do this human nature being what it
is we can remember username or password
we don't have to have a different one
for different sites do we
this is the problem because attackers
are able to compromises site download
all the usernames and passwords as we
see all too frequently in the media and
then what the hackers do they take those
and run them against different sites so
if I can get your username and password
from whatever site and using it on your
banking using on Amazon I can take a lot
of money in your pocket in very short
order
so this is one of things that drives me
absolutely nuts is attribution and the
media loves to blame somebody and I
don't care about this what I do is I
care about is the data so the
information about to show you is
actually just raw data there is nothing
to be gleaned from this other than this
is where the attacks originated in cute
too
based on IP whether or not they actually
came from these points of origin is
another thing entirely because we don't
track it back even further than that
because there's only so many hours in
the day and it was really interesting
that include to China came in at 37
percent but in queue when they were only
about 10% of the attack so this actually
varies from quarter to quarter and read
from it what you will and so with a
different types of attacks we see the
primary number of $100 bit plus a type
attacks have been hitting primarily
internal telecom as well as gaming so
these are the types of targets of people
are going after from just the sheer DDoS
huge volume of attacks and we break that
out this is obvious this is cutie
obviously gaming and suffering
technology are huge but the ones that I
worry about are not just financial
services but is retailing here retailers
not on a retail retail it shows a blow
there but that is steadily increasing
why because the same information that
the attackers were going after in the
financial services they can just pull
that from retail sites which by and
large have not got the same level of
security for the most part some of them
are doing very good job you're on some
of them are not and it's easier to pick
off the low-hanging fruit from an
attacker I really don't want to be
spending a lot more work and time on it
to get the money that I want I want to
go after what's going to work so I'm
going to retail
nice five minutes or so this is
normalization of web attacks her by
industry again for the web attacks on
what I'm saying this is
application-level based attacks
financial services retail again where
the primary targets why financial
information
skip there so was in floods this is
really interesting this is how simple it
is essential that we would see that our
perimeter this particular packet was
part of a three hundred and twenty one
gigabit
DDoS attack we were having fun with it
was rather amusing something that simple
so what are we seeing as a progression
we've gone this what this particular
juror for those of you in the back and
see you going from 21 2013 too cute to
2015 you can see that with this graph
wheres plotting out the different types
of attacks both on volume and in time as
you can see it nationally grows to a
much greater density in queue to 2015
for Q-three that's almost a smudge at
this point because that has increased
yet again i truly interesting things
like you are sure to actually see that
sort of graphic representation so types
of attacks that were doing seeing rather
single injection is the primary one that
drives me absolutely bonkers a single
injection is still a problem how many
people remember the first time Segal
injection showed up on the top 10
anybody have an idea I'll give you a
hand over 10 years ago why is there
still a problem why are we still
combating this this is something that is
a solvable problem but this accounts for
roughly 35% of the successful attacks
that we shall there this is shouldn't be
the case we need the sanitized imports
we need sometimes opus this is a
solvable problem and a lot of this balls
to companies in
managers that have a deadline to meet so
they are working very hard to make sure
that they get their product in front of
customers fast as they can so what's the
best way to actually shorten that time
bypass security I used to be one of the
gates or financial institution my team
would actually vet any application that
would be public facing
we have one that went right around us
luckily we found at the day they went
live on Triple take it offline we did a
test on it if anybody had actually
taking a swing at it that would have
gone down very quickly because they had
done some very simple coding errors that
would result in the problem so security
as frustrating as it may be for
developers is there for a reason to help
protect the in the organization I'm
sorry I stopped when the other things
that we saw was file inclusion was a big
thing a remote file inclusion so this
one here is for red slider which for
WordPress is a plugin that would allow
you to actually shift the images on the
front page so if you want to WordPress
site near you seen the images that slide
across and change visually appealing but
an earlier version of this year ago now
was susceptible to attack and would
allow people to upload stuff like this
which would give them a shelf so they
called the roadside herself this was
really interesting because this sort of
attack and others like it were based on
these types of issues CVE for open flyer
Green Party want people to see is he
sees TV 2009 TV 2012 CVV 2008 this is
from Q-two of this year
these were successful attacks are things
that have been known issues for years we
have to do a better job of securing our
environments that are it so with regards
to our applications and anything that we
have forged facing to the external
parties we want to make sure that we're
not becoming one of these we want to
make sure that we're not contributing to
the problem we want to make sure that
we're doing proper updates on our
systems because how long is it before
law enforcement are coming around
knocking on your door and saying well
because of your negligence your
inability keeper system's current you're
now culpable because you participated in
this attack hasn't happened yet
but I heard rumblings to this effect
only a matter of time before somebody
starts doing this so what do you do
yeah vendor understand but sequel
injection is a solvable problem this
shouldn't be a prob issue this is
something that application developers in
your own houses can fix please take the
time to do that one who better job of
hiding your systems if I can do a
directory traversal on your site and
2015 you will have a problem
work with your ISP is that our next hop
ups from you if you're not doing a cloud
implementation for services like classic
interior architecture talk to your ISP's
they may have some sort of mitigation
strategy in place they may have
something that can help you I know when
we asked our ISP back in the nineties
they looked at us like we had three
heads I'm willing to bet that you have a
better response these days hope you want
to look at IP rate limiting and I keep
going back to this one
patcher systems make sure that you have
proper web hygiene because otherwise
you're becoming part of the problem so
the data that are presented to you today
is actually pulled from the state of the
internet dot com and this is a freely
available
report that we do quarterly so that we
have always dated we pour into these
reports this free for you guys to use in
a way you see fit
we have a lot of customers that use it
for building business cases or just you
know better education for their c-suite
feel free to use it it's free
there for you to use that being said I
would like to thank you very much for
your time and attention today I like to
thank you and i really appreciate the
opportunity to speak with you today
question came across one is not when I'm
well-versed on so I be rather speaking
out of school to actually talk to that
link so I won't do that to you but I am
familiar with it on your left
thank you for the beginning of your cock
you talk about the the children there is
something with so in France after
Charlie attack in January you had to rip
of animals fighting themself one from
French one attacking Arabic websites
with Arabic attacking French websites
everywhere like camping website and
stuff like that and what we saw is
children making lots of the does lots of
those laws of the dispute really really
young kids and after that people are
selling that the basis of black market
every time all the data bases you can
find is this site and it was crazy
because you just see their what you say
about the the using they are doing our
children that we can verify that with
this event
unfortunate reality that we have to do a
better job of educating our kids got two
of them and one of them likes the VPN
and other countries to get content on
Netflix so she's gonna be a problem
she's been doing that since she was 5
I'm so screwed we have more questions
thank you very much