yeah good afternoon everybody but I
longer talking gives it all away in the
next couple of minutes I will talk about
how it is possible to the activator
point protection software in
unauthorized manner
actually I will talk about to less
regarded security issues that's we've
financed occasionally in this kind of
software but also other software
products some information about my needs
but here I am interested in I T security
yes it's a very long time to study
computer science at the University of an
since 2007 I work as a Nazi Security
Council for us
Mallaig security company Germany called
sis the agenda of my talk is this first
I want to interviews what extent for
protection software it actually is what
its role in ninety security and I want
to talk about the two less regard it's
less regard to security issues that sell
my colleague and I am actually found
again in the beginning of 2015 then I
want to talk about some use cases and a
texan are you regarding these less
regarding security issues and how they
may be exploited by now hope that I can
show you a life demo and afterwards
there are some conclusions and
recommendations and I think there will
be plenty of time for Q&A you so when I
talk about endpoint security software in
this talk I think of something like this
can see you on this picture so and
protection software is actually salt
about this running with higher
privileges on that point systems what
i'm talking points I mainly mean
alliances yeah
computer networks or services the
purpose of this kind of softer actually
is to prevent attacks running against
your and points that you have it your
corporate network for example governor
network so generally speaking and
protection software is just one type of
security control to protect I T systems
as already mentioned for example client
services teams from different threats
and the corresponding I T security risks
typical features are and protection
software products are anti virus and
malware detection so the classic
antivirus software it's running on line
services
a table and one prediction software but
endpoint detection software nowadays
also has many more features than we had
to borrow some hella detection there is
for example application control so you
can do application whitelisting you find
it only specific application software is
allowed to exit actually running on a
specific client or server system you can
also do device control so for example
you can control the use of devices on
popular example I use be mass storage
device since I'm so that you cannot
simply sticking a USB flash drive copy
all the cost of the hardest and
takeaways they'd excellent recent stuff
like that or another popular
issue is still file or so prices still
have a firewire a built-in
extensive fire while he was by himself
or ExpressCard and there are still some
text now you can use firewire rather
well and and publishing software also
has filed all functionality built in
most of the products in order to protect
your system from network based attacks
are to contain I'm going to take that
just started on your client's system and
you want them elsewhere too
contained on this system it's currently
running and freelance network
communications system said it just
cannot spread that easily for example
out what's my 12 years mainly about it
is password protection feature of some
protection software products has
replaced protection is actually
implemented soon set of restrictions on
different management functionalities are
all features that are provided by an
protection software answer this
protection is implemented in order to
reduce the risk of unauthorized Auton
intended changes in the functioning of
the endpoint protection software so if
you think a corporate network you don't
want I want everybody to change the file
will release on that point or antivirus
updates or stuff like that and that's
what's the best protection is actually
for and restricting administrative
access generally is a good idea
especially when it comes to security
because everybody can change anything on
a system well there is no security at
all and in order to access and use
protected medicine functionalities
protection software products usually
passport so what we have here in our
paper based authentication is because
they are both symbols to him
announce the most manufacturers of this
kind of stuff to do it this way and in
this talk I will present their products
all three different gender as a ski
pants on and we have found some security
issues and here's an example of
Kaspersky Endpoint Security 10 and
protection and how you can change the
settings and protect all operations are
selectively always some of the
operations and this protection so
prevents as mentioned before unintended
or unauthorized changes to the software
at all and I want to talk about to less
regard to security issues so security
vulnerabilities I will present here are
not big one so it's no remote code
execution from anywhere in the world but
locally exploitable security issues and
that's why they unless we got it but in
my opinion they shoot get more attention
because in some attack scenarios the
exploit ability of these less guarded
security issues make a difference
answer to security issues i want to talk
about our first authentication bypass
all abilities and seconds
be insufficient protection of user
credentials and concerning
authentication authentication bypass all
abilities
especially talk about local attack
scenarios in non network software
features for example the management of
locally installed software products like
in this case for the protection software
but you can also think of local
exploitable education by possible
penalties in other products every
application that has won a public sample
our passwords saved by God to
synchronize database locally and if they
if there are any issues concerning the
authentication yeah actually is a
critical security issue and the seconds
to talk about is insufficient protection
of human potential and there are
actually many ways in sufficiently
protect user credentials software for
example store in that case clear text
passwords that's not recommended for
obvious reasons or you can use
cryptographically week one-way hash
functions with all the salt because this
also helps in a terrorism attack
scenarios to profit from exploitable
condition or the use of symmetric
cryptographic Cyprus with a single hard
coded key for all installations so if
the manufacturer has only one from
Target Field implemented or one of its
products and an attacker has to do the
work one time and he can exploit these
securities you every time he sees it and
once there is a tool available on the
Internet has to have the capabilities to
do that Elias by myself he just uses
available software and exploit it and
another common issue concerning its
surface protection of our information
this means that so I T system for
example client system everybody who has
access to this system is able to reach
the peso information no matter if it's
clear text or its encrypted or up the
skaters in a way but it's also six
security issue
ok so now some details about the
authentication bypass vulnerability in
this talk by possibility allow us an
attacker Texas and use functionality of
the system without completing of aquatic
vegetation step in the attended way of
the X Factor so concerning has been
based authentication mechanisms being
able to use and password for example
there are no password at all in order to
look into a system is a classic example
of this volatility type and there are
you from the root causes for this
vulnerability time for instance in
proper input validation so for
subsequent injection vulnerabilities or
more general do while they sing all
secure and design principles and four
letter example hear ya on this light
there's security problem we have found
in different employee protection
software products but it's also in many
other products actually an exploitable
local access to a low platelets to the
left so I will explain the scenario
humans on slide yeah we have actually
two processes one on the left your name
product service running with high user
privileges I feel it's the main above
call it and on the riots you have a low
privileged user process your cold
throughout you I am so it's
user interfaces user and this process is
running in a low privileged to train
with religious so what the service does
is it performs task with high privileges
for example change the configuration of
the product label features of the
product or disabled features of the
product and Waterloo privileged process
does is it so its status information to
the end user it handles either direction
for us all to you I stuff and in some
cases
pieces it also danced user
authentication and yeah well that's an
obvious mom that's a sickness and
security problem you can exploit in many
scenarios and that's actually while they
secure design principles of stuff like
that in local privileged domain that's
just does not belong there so if
authentication is done within a process
that runs or can be running a contest of
a little privileged user it can be and
Elias sounds in most cases also many
police and in order to buy a house
education but only has to fire the
corresponding
authentication said they'd always
returns true for example by comparing
the correct person with itself or just
by modifying the control flow of the
actual program and the consequence of
this is dad's protected features can be
used in the right way in case of the
airport protection software as we will
see later so here's here's what it looks
like during runtime concerning the
example given point security team yeah I
have closed about this so what's the
interesting part and actually the
fallibility
made in this scenario well I already
comparison is done within processes
running the context of those privileged
user to process called in this case and
as we can see here it's just to default
string on parity in that is used and
what is actually compared to the case of
Kaspersky Kaspersky products are tested
he also to be fired has values actually
drawn sword Mb 5 has values in this case
and products the only five film
generated for a string but was UTF 16
little endian encoded actually without
attorney so just some technical details
is important for example if someone
wants to check the complexity of the
password 01 sassy
continues in this scenario for example
for protecting the medicine
functionality is in compliance with the
corporates as for policy at least that's
something I actually finding products
and the next one ability that's also
regarding an underestimate it is the
insufficient protection of using
credentials and this can also be
exploited in different ways and one
example was actually using md5 hash
values unsalted so if a user has access
to information that are not required to
perform his task it is used as security
issue because the principle of least
privilege and furthermore gift
accessible user credentials only
protected insufficient it's definitely
is a security issue because then the
user or attack Iran malware actually
benefit from the axis and recover
password information for example or you
passed a Haltech so whatever is suitable
in different scenarios and in case of
the test them protection software
products I will talk about here for
information both both accessible by low
prevalence do this and it was also
insufficiently protected announce the
consequences of this is that protected
features can be used in unauthorized way
and example elf enterprise security tend
to fall to test it
compression products in this case the
password was stored as well on solid 25
has value and you can see the actual
registry well you're worried about the
registry key is by default readable by
every user so you don't have to have
them instead of fries or something like
that so everybody just can't look at the
registry if he's able to record their
tour that extra expect this information
performing offline attack at home or
using a tracking cluster
is a stolen car if he's able to crack
the password he can also attack the peso
peso thanks Jason and managed by
protection so that all the teachers in
unauthorized way but that's the hard way
to do it's even more easier in a few
minutes but you can also be extracted as
low privileged user from the memory of
the process
ATP during runtime so there's a
possibility to perform the so-called
offline attack but just extracted
formation take it home or even someone
else put in the clouds to sign up
historic guessing attacks you can also
extract information directly from the
memory in this case from still has to
have a secondary attack's but we'll see
later on that sometimes you will get
information that you can directly use
for further test scenarios and general
use of cryptographic one-way hash
functions that are cryptographically we
like amplifier actually what he's
without assault allows an attacker to
perform rather fish and password
guessing attacks using precomputed
attorneys for supplemental tables 25 can
also be calculated rather fast on modern
CPUs and GPUs so using md5 today is not
recommended for example a screenshot
from the registry editor for this case
and was told there is just 95 has value
unsalted you can give you were they
would cracking tools on the river has
cats or whatever you like
ok so what are they actually use cases
and the texting oreos let's be guarded
security issues when I came up with
actually to the first of these cases bad
guys doing
at things for fun and profit and the
next one is good guys doing bad things
with permission for fun and profit for
example sentences like security
consultants in both cases bad things are
done actually you want to avoid bad
things when it comes to your corporate
network two systems you're responsible
for so yeah if these vulnerabilities
will let us in the future but actually
they seemed to prevail and we find that
actually once in a whiles every every
two or three years the same thing just
in a different products and what are the
attack scenarios one is that's a little
prove it disables features of the iPod
protection software just not perform
Melissa sections so something of an
insider attack you have some body and
your company with regular exercise too I
T systems that he says to me is handling
matters centers and protection software
in place to acquire it
different kinds of threats and detector
is able to simply disable you were
employed protection software in with a
mouse click and then kept reform is
malicious actions and you don't see
anything if everything goes the worst
way and tell second scenario is
you don't have a user about you have
mail well that is executed in the
context of a local issues within your
corporate network and he had his noble
attempt to actually the same as an
interactive user clicking the mouse or
typing some keys on a keyboard and then
we can actually also just deactivate you
want protection software not authorize
the matter and that perform for the
malicious task without any intervention
from the security code controlled
protection software and he wasn't a real
example from my day-to-day work as pen
tester Security Essentials and
protection software can be really
annoying for me and my colleagues and
sometimes it can also be a show-stopper
because if we are able to gather
credentials by other means and we are
able to exorcist it is just not enough
when launching attacks and state some
point because two successful login is
not a guarantee that you can also
extracts
filtrate interesting information by
using interesting tools so the profit
for an attacker also a pen tester is
rather limited so sometimes I just
cannot take the next step or take the
next hop network because I want
protection stopping me and that's what
it's for Italy that's a good thing but
because of these left we got its
security issues or an attacker is able
to just deactivate protection software
features
rather simply about conflict continued
with his malicious toss and of course
there's also anti virus isolation
techniques but I was a virgin Ricky
time-consuming and I think they have the
expertise in security just completely
are selectively as I want can save
precious time so concerning the password
protection management functionality it
is also interesting to see as only
mention if they use passports are
compliance to even pass boat policies
for example company I just keep his
assessment for it out one hopes to a
result is that in most cases to use
passports to protect these
administrative management features I
don't comply with other active password
policies for example a director in the
Windows Active Directory environment so
actually the peasants used to protect
administrative features are much much
weaker than the default passwords that
are required by every corporate network
and that's i think is rather interesting
and absolutely everything I mean like
Alex ok and this table you can see there
are some of the effective protection
software products my colleagues and I
have tested in the beginning of 2015
these are examples we have
vis-a-vis for but this list is nothing
but complete so they're also products
other when their state health the same
unless we got his security issues at the
door just exploded in the same way
ok and what we have actually done is we
have written some proof of concept works
for all of the facts other products such
as shown in the table was born I just
want to demonstrate the security issue
alive
hopefully with example office to
prosecute GMT we have written to load
and unload cast and get these proven
scorer software constitute proof of
concept hospital is simply a loader
technically with some patching
functionality and it works as follows
following these steps at first it finds
the executable file called EVP that it
just creates a new instance of the
process is a key with a specific command
line arguments show with the exit
function that is triggered and the exit
exit functions just shuts down the
Endpoint Protection completely the next
step is to pitch the password based
authentication of the process so that
any password is considered correct or
actually that's no password is required
in order to treat this functionality and
the loss of his to stop the process and
continue its execution not only so this
line at the next load I have shown the
most important parts of the source code
of the proof of concept celtic symbol
and at what they see source code else's
just before steps I just mentioned or so
finds the executable file them on this
proof-of-concept altitudes implemented
as a loser level the banner issue on top
of that way so we make use of the
windows
AP functionality or to patch their
target prices during runtime and do what
they want because there's a few bands
that's a simple thing to do if it is
possible to close to handle to process
and lets the process continue its work
ok so now I will try to show a lifetime
what I want to exploit that's a command
line
always started operations when I
honestly have a look at all the other
features also maybe I will just show
heart you can deactivate or disabled
protection completely in this case ok so
as you can see I'm running Endpoint
Security 10 this case Windows seven so I
can and we can also have a look at my
privileges so it's a German also helps
the user I'm currently locked in an ass
is only the default limited windows
using a member of the group
have a look at the Windows services
rallying there should be something from
Kaspersky Endpoint Security Service is
running so that's running with high
privileges in a high privilege to me for
example the GUI we have here is lower
running in the context of my user also
if I run the ATP executable here this is
also running in the context of Milo
privileged user so concepts offer to
actually come online now to unload cast
in this example we see here is still
running five percenter some windows are
popping up here after all put off our to
look here is gone at least a GUI and if
we have a look at the start and services
it shall be any ski service anymore
ok
anymore
containing what appeared he was just a
simple horse containing a payload that
automatically deactivates the endpoint
protection software and has to grow its
star's editorial code does not start
automatically because my system uses
default settings concerning Micro
security for Microsoft Office and I have
to activate it really gets you nowhere
Security Essentials when we do targeted
attacks we also found that users if they
are presented with the correct or an
interesting option and they are rather
willing to activate active content
contained in the document and then
actually better things may happen so
yeah that's just ask he is gone again we
should have some messages from here that
we should reactivate Kaspersky Endpoint
Security is still some windows messages
and what I programs here is just a proof
of concept about you on so that just as
dead if you can read this message
message it's already too late because at
this point lol well actually has every
code execution will the privileges after
currently locked in use her ok so this
was just a quick demo concerning
products and have to say my back up here
in the slides so just a
password-protected features actually if
you want to use the command line
interface you can set the password also
welcome online or you are interactively
prompted but when I did the concept of
the tool is I just changed the control
flow in such a way that we never people
reach this pass for prom and it's just
txt waits for example protection using
text function or scared or whatever you
want you not authorized way ok and this
was just the output of the proof of
concepts offer to all following the four
steps I mentioned all year and at the
same is also true for other products for
example
the manufacturer rose in the same way
but he was interesting difference
because concerning the pun us all their
products we've tested we were able to
also extracts the correct password is
actually asking for from the memory so
here they don't even use has incredibly
one-way has to protect credentials are
intended to protect administrative
management features but they just made
available in a low privileged user
context in clear text and the same is
also true for the Bulldogs products
we've tested you can also just catch the
past based authentication as a liberal
she was arrested elsewhere and by
positing that way and you can also
extract the correct password please text
so yeah but with less regard to
securities mentioned earlier
science authentication bypass on the
other side insufficiently protected
credentials could be found in these
employ protection software products can
actually be used to deactivate security
features in unauthorized manner
ok sort of conclusion is that this kind
of attack is actually possible it's
actually a couple of model the products
we analyzed in this case it wasn't until
2015 concerning had a look at other
products and I also know of someone
products that are selectively affected
by these vulnerable
he's cannot talk about our security
issues like authentication by
possibilities concerning local attack
scenarios in my opinion also get more
attention because in some attack
scenarios yeah they are a crucial step
to cause more damage because if I'm able
to get rabate nine-point protection
software and I was able to get along
information from some other source I can
log into the system yet to rate all
protection features absolute some
interesting hacking tools what's up baby
cuts some potentials in active
directories and take over the lead
actors to Active Directory monuments for
example okay and yeah another conclusion
is that any security-related toss shoots
if possible performed more trustworthy
allotment so not so privileged user
processes where actual mail there is
access to or malicious users have access
to come back to this illustration here a
good idea is just to do he's
authentication and other high privilege
or other sensitive to use it to me in
this way
ok here are some general recommendations
for people developing software like that
or general terms speaking for all I T
security systems always consider
trusting I see I T security because
oftentimes
security is just so you have to know
your trust remains its Russ boundaries
trust relationships
and another recommendation is do not
assume too much because if you have too
many assumptions about Jesus more excuse
me while in office software component in
reality there are many are some steps
just don't hope through your product may
be vulnerable to specific attacks and
another channel recommendation is
properly protect your personal
information
mainly restricted access to information
but there were clear text Hairston
cryptic whatever Julie parties are
solely use cryptographically kids
graphically secure standardized with
them with a suitable configuration so my
recommendation here is the path of
peacekeeping operations function too
well up to date one way has to do with
them
many rounds that just makes it very hard
for an attacker who has access to has to
pay as much information to be covered
through text passwords and that's also
good idea in general to follow the
principle of least privilege I know it's
hard sometimes but I think it's worth
the effort
ok here's some references to first as a
people from 2012 is just about the same
topic back then I have the same kind of
all abilities plus we gotta bilities
office gas micro so also rather easily
deactivate Google without any further
privileges in unauthorized way and there
are some security advisories were
released this year are concerned the
software products protection software
products from the manufacturer this
regard to security and Kaspersky ok and
that's it thank you very much for your
tensions and I think we're still have
some time for Q&A
some time for questions sometimes
overlooked but you can design principle
or violation of securities I'm
principles actually rather many software
products
say they don't feel nothing I could talk
about the best of their products that do
it the correct way where you are for
example have to wake of privilege as a
Windows user
that's one other way to do it correctly
but I just can't imagine the products
questions questions sorry
did you experience talking to locally
managed the research we did order
security assessments actually we just
had a look at the local authentication
features but you're right there also
will be managed and protection software
products that you will not indication on
suicide for example but we don't have a
look at these answers to know why I'm
asking is are there any alerts if you on
the server side of the local sometimes
there are but then it's a matter of how
people are reacting to these kinds of
alarms and actually the case of malware
if you just temporarily disable security
control do you think actually tried to
data dilemma astronauts you just don't
care if you had a text was rated the
damage is done thanks
the questions one person from me I think
companies like has been as key should
know better so the question remains
yes there is a saying you shouldn't
attribute to malice what can readily be
explained by stupidity but they should
know better what your explanation
actually I don't know its security costs
money I don't think that's the main
exploration and for me that we just see
the same security vulnerabilities over
and over again because as a company like
a Kaspersky where you have installed
software which is privileged on a high
percentage of the world's computers but
conspiracy theories but but another
problem is as I mentioned in the story
the security issues I presented here
they are regarded less less regard for a
reason because i text areas are rather
limited and just be a ski area followed
in use they also have other security
issues they should 6446 these issues
we've reported issues in February this
year I think of March and they were
fixed to her but they also have other
security issues the big one smoker
execution reported in the last couple of
weeks but I don't I don't have an
explanation why the software quality
actually concerning security features is
rather go especially from security
companies may be further discussion and
thank you for the top