thank you guys for attending this
presentation I me to go seek c/o extra
security been here before four years ago
for binary planting talk and we are
breaking into banks and presenting all
such stuff and today I will show you how
we can break the monopoly of big vendors
who seem to be the only ones who can
match their applications now we're going
to do that to the current situation
you're probably aware of we've been and
probably many of you have been finding
vulnerabilities in software for a long
time and reporting that vendors one way
or the other and what we see and what
you probably see as well is that the
same types of bugs are being found over
and over again
buffer overflows double for use and use
after free and so on so same same types
of bugs and they're being fixed and
they're being found again and the clever
people find expert medications that make
explaining these vulnerabilities harder
and then clever people on the other side
trying to find bypasses would expect me
to get just as just an endless game it
doesn't seem to solve anything because
basically we are security wise were in
the same state where we were fifteen
years ago on top of that few vendors
just the big ones are proactively
looking for vulnerabilities because
that's a costly process and it costs
money to find vulnerabilities cost them
money to fix them and to deploy the
fixes and they would rather be doing
something else and if you're reading and
of course you are about breaches you see
that the vulnerabilities that are being
exploited to break into big banks are
not some fancy 0 days they are very very
old vulnerabilities that have been
patched long time ago it just crashes
have not been applied to see why now if
you're a security researcher and you
find a vulnerability try to do something
with that you learn very quickly that
you are perceived to be part of the
problem instead of part of the solution
and to sum it all up
nobody's really happy except for those
who are trying to bring him know too
short stories the first one short story
about an attacker this is how it
accuracies his objective a lot of
vulnerability for abilities to pick from
because the updates are not being
applied and wire up its not being
applied well because if you were home
user of course you just click OK
try and wait till your broker dealer
curious restarted but if you're in an
enterprise you don't simply do that you
have to test those updates up to the
point for Europe confident with applying
them to across the network so that they
don't break your production that they
don't break your business model and this
kind of house and we know that its
current undermount anti-malware
solutions are not effective I mean if
you want to bypass those just need to
take some time and do some testing and
you can always bypass anti-malware now
this is what we've been doing for
fifteen years and to do this and we're
kind of frustrated that this still works
and it's just not getting any harder if
you are tired to penetrator target you
find a vulnerability in a software that
they're using which is usually windows
because large corporations that's
usually windows that are using and you
find a vulnerability that's not too old
so let's say up to two months old which
is which means that you have a lot of
vulnerabilities vulnerabilities to pick
from and prepared next point for that
phone ability and finally you mutate
that exploit and send it to keep sending
it to virustotal until are still does
not to take it anymore so you know that
basically whatever protection they're
they're using whatever section of our
experts still using its not going to
protect you and then you fish will
arrange to keep keep sending users in
there
that organization links to malicious
website which is not to exploit the
vulnerability it's it's really simple
come to think of it and the fact that
this has not changed in 15 years in
spite of all the new technology that's
been invented and is being sold for
millions worldwide this is kind of
frustrating the second story the story
of a security researcher
security researchers here ok some of
them not wanting to admit it publicly if
you find a nice day in some applications
popular application what do you do it's
a dilemma there are actually no good
options for you and these are the other
options
well apart from applying for a buck bony
these are really popular but they don't
really pay very much easier option
number one you can responsibly disclosed
to the vendor so what happens there is
basically somewhere in the spectrum from
complete silence no resupply to thank
you very much
will tend to this when the time is right
to basically on on the other extreme you
have a meeting with their lawyers just
not very nice so you can you can get any
of these second you can publish just go
to a conference like this and say I
would drop to zero day here so for your
amusement right I will not do this today
but you have to do that for exposure and
well you might want to do then we like
it or not you can get someone angry
doing this up to the point of them
wanting to talk to you you know first
more room and number three you can sell
them or ability they could your days
goes for a lot of money these days but
there's always a problem of trusting
whoever you're selling to and the bigger
problem of
well if you don't have ethical
reservations bigger problem that you may
be found guilty of helping someone
commits a crime that's not a nice option
number four is just to forget about it
put in drawer shelf if you want and then
what's the point of your exercise so no
good options for the researchers today
and weisel that this is the reason
patching security vulnerabilities is a
heart problem and it's never been really
sold so why is it hard problem with
these three players users and security
researchers just don't seem to have a
way of really living together working
together in a very very constructive way
some vendors have and want to keep the
monopoly for patching and patching their
own software and they're the only ones
who can decide whether to patch went to
patch halt patch and when and how to
deploy and for how much money to deploy
that patch to end users so a lot of
things going on and they would rather be
doing something else because this is
just a cost for them they would rather
be earning money somewhere else let
users how many of you like Patch Tuesday
no hands right nobody likes best uses
right nobody likes
down time even if you're not some huge
production that would like he would lose
millions of dollars for for that we
would you know like that now for the
large networks it's really a lose lose
situation if you if you do update
immediately then you risk bricking your
production if you don't update
immediately or risk being broken into
because as you probably know just a few
days after official updates are out some
interesting exploits come up in exploit
kits so if you have a couple of thousand
dollars extra you can just wait for a
couple of days after the patch Tuesday
and you will get to fresh working
quality assurance tested exploits for
some of these vulnerabilities and
security researchers aren't really happy
as well because let me tell you every
security vendor ever stopped to render
in this world would rather see the world
without security researchers because
they are just causing problems to them
if we did not exist they were there
would not be any vulnerabilities in the
world so right now we are being
considered part of the problem and this
is why those stones are very heart to
extend up and out of that frustration
came our idea we want to reinvent
software packaging where packaging as it
is today it doesn't work it works in
that slow glacier Speedway but it
doesn't work for critical
vulnerabilities that need to be
addressed right away now RDR idea is
that everyone should be able to just use
a couple of minutes to install a small
piece of software we call it
00 agent that will apply tiny security
patches I'm talking tiny I'm talking in
a couple of machine instructions
gigabytes of code which usually get
every Tuesday and that agent will apply
time security patches in the same way
and in the same way I mean this but just
in memory just wonder processes running
patching in memory which means also
unpacking in memory and it can be done
instantly in the same way for all
applications wouldn't that be nice and
then you could apply and remove those
patches instantly without rebooting the
computer without restarting applications
and without any enterprise without
disturbing the users and without even
disturbing the admits so if someone
notices their something's wrong with
that micro patch it can be instantly
removed now compare that to anyone
anyone being in that mean in the
large enterprise ok you guys know do you
dare just applying patches you do how do
you like when someone says I want this
page removed at this guys on a laptop
500 miles away that's really nice task
for you so yeah that's alright and I'm
going to show you how it works ok I have
a computer here with a very low
resolution is good and he has a zero
budget agent in store this is a console
and it's currently disabled which means
it's not applying any patches anywhere I
also have a couple of vulnerable
applications installed in a couple of
explains so let me just start with
something that you will immediately left
eye opening a fake
time speech that's using Java
vulnerability to run the calculator as
we all know that captured a leader is
the most malicious application along
Windows computers should immediately
remove it but this was an example of
this webpage exploiting a vulnerability
on your computer immediately as you as
you drop by basically now this is
without this Europe Russia another
example of Foxit Reader I just open for
reader
of course vulnerable person and drop
exploited just crashed here we did not
count limit let me tell you this is a
vulnerability a buffer overflow that
were explaining care now I want to show
we fighting neighbors who may change and
things are going to be a little bit
different I just go through that fake
here to the militias York Times speech
again
this time as soon as job was launched in
the background it was immediately passed
by our agent so that vulnerability was
no longer there and apart from that the
patch did not just plug the hole it also
detected that someone tried to exploit
the vulnerability and was able to alert
the user that exploit attempt was
blocked now this is shown five times
because this new exploit that we have
tried to exploit the vulnerability five
times those of you familiar with you
know that some experts are not very very
you sometimes they don't work and you
have to try a couple of times now
same thing with the Foxit Reader and I
will be something else so you can
understand what I'm talking about I will
change the settings to inform me about
all patching events which means that as
soon it will tell me when whenever a
patch is applied to any running
application so as soon as I launched
Foxit you will see in the top right
corner a pop-up the patch was applied
for Foxit Reader just a memory we have
not changed the single by on the disc
now when I drop the exploit here
attempt was blocked and importantly
again it was twice and importantly Fox
it keeps one right and let's try
something else now we know that Fox it
is despatched currently let some patches
we go to applications find Fox it on
Patch Foxit Reader as soon as I do that
sucks it is running in the background
and you see patch has been removed while
it's running so this is what we're
talking about patching being applied and
unemployed in memory nothing stored on
the disc this is what allows us to do it
instantly and this is what allows admins
to do it remotely also instantly without
even a laptop's 500 miles away
ok let's go back to the presentation now
how does it work
anyone familiar with function ok so the
concept is pretty much the same here
the difference is that we do not only
patch at the beginning of the functions
but anywhere in the code now suppose
this is code don't be afraid this is
machine code the problem goes any other
code and let's say that we've done our
analysis of the vulnerability and we've
come to the conclusion that we want to
inject some patch code that will do some
correction after this call now so we
need to inject code after this call and
we see that these the following three
instructions are suitable for relocation
what does that mean that means that
these structures can execute just as
well here as anywhere in the memory
because they don't are not using any
relative offset and what's important
also that no no execution branches
actually come back into these
instructions because if you move such
instructions he will break something now
if we know that these are this is a
suitable location for patch which is
going to take these three structures out
with them somewhere else in the memory
but our patch code before that these
original instructions just make a simple
jump from that location where the
original code used to be jumped to the
bad code and then back where we used to
be so effectively we just added some
code to the original code and that is
the idea of patching basically most
books can be purchased by adding some
Coast like if some programs that causes
cause the buffer overflow vulnerability
forgot to to check for the length of the
input buffer no we do this checking for
him so what do we need to define a patch
basically we need to know which module
two applied to buy module I mean exit
file or DLL file or assault following an
axe and we need to know the hash of that
model so that we don't accidentally
patch something else right so we know
that the model has been loaded so our
agent knows that the model has been
loaded and he also needs to know where
exactly inside that module the patch
should be rejected and also obviously
what code should be injected it's really
as simple as that
now this is a sample batch code source
code right we need to define the model
passed in this case would have apt on
exit which is vulnerable and its
vulnerable we want to pageant at this
location this offset and this is the
code that we're going to inject so we're
just putting 02 yaks register because we
know this that it was not initialize
correctly so someone found a way to
exploit this and this is a very simple
batch code and they all look like this
they will only have maybe more
instructions them just one now the
question what can be passed this way
obviously not every portability can be
patched but what can be bashed
fortunately it turns out that this way
of patching be suitable for almost every
remotely exploitable former ability but
let's go first through those
vulnerabilities does that a typical
vulnerability types which we're all
familiar with you have to redouble freed
american flows under flows offer for my
strings and initialize variables for
instance that
previous example this is an example of
initializing variable that the
programmer
initialize for instance minored planting
bucks just don't seem to be going we're
dealing fiction books don't seem to be
going the way we can do a lot of things
with these patches you can basically do
anything with these patches but if you
want to keep them small you are kind of
constraint what you can do know very
unsuitable for this kind of patching are
scripted code for instance on the
servers PHP Ruby you can easily this way
this would have to be done on the way
another way design flaws if if there's a
vulnerability that exploit some really
incorrect design of an application you
probably was just a few bites got
Windows kernel because windows are
actively defending against add credit
card and you also have abs we have come
across just one so far which is like
that that hates patching itself he hates
to be passed so detective has been
modified in crashes
well they have reasons for that but just
one out of hundreds of hours that we've
seen no we referred to their badges
being microscopic cure for big security
also remember that we are patching just
just any a few machine instructions to
the original code and a lot of benefits
and that as you will see now let's
create a patch for an integer overflow
let's see how that works we have an old
Firefox's with an overall ability in the
reduce right function reduce right
function works on an array and the
problem is that if an array is really
long which means there is more than
80 000 000 I know if I put their
elements in the array or its length is
larger than that then we get an integer
overflow and the integer overflow
basically comes from the fact that we
have an unsigned integer used for the
let the rain and the signed integer
start which is then later a sign that
limits minus one so what happens in the
following case will go back to the
source code this is a simple proof of
concept that crashes Firefox we created
array we given the length of a 2010 just
has to be more than eight and seven
zeros just to make sure that as the
signed and unsigned into representation
of that number is not going to be the
same and then we could reduce right on
that let's see what happens and we're
not currently having any patches for
Firefox here so I want to Firefox for
you to see and I have dropped this HTML
which is that simple concept of the show
and it's a crash right
so what happens here in the code is
basically that this length of the array
which was determined by this call was a
very huge number but that's ok for the
unsigned integer however when it was
converted to a signed integer it became
a huge negative number and then all hell
breaks lose so our question was how do
we passed this typical way to patch
numerical overflows is to make sure that
the number that is that should not be
too large is reduced to legitimate size
so what do we do here we find in the
machine code where this call gets
executed so we found the call which is
here right after that call with little
bit of debugging you see that the length
of the array which is determined by this
call is stored in memory at the location
pointed to by the Irish sir sounds
complex but it's really not now right
after this call very conveniently we
have five bites to instructions which
can be easily relocate know what we want
to do I just put a part the code here to
make sure to make room for additional
code and the additional code is justice
so that length of the array which was
just established by the Court of that
function is now logically ended with
seven
which means the highest its highest bid
is being reset the result of this is
that this number is always going to be
small enough to have the same
representation as it has signed and
unsigned integer now let's see how that
works in real life I have this patch
source code conveniently prepared for
you and it's here so this is actually
that has the vulnerability and we can
skip the use an interesting parts and
this is the offset in the model we want
to add are patching code and the single
line here is the patch cold so this is
the code that we want to add to Firefox
actually at that caused the fire also I
have it in this file so I will launch
patch lawyer
fire
ok
it's just going to compile that source
code into an actual match the actual
currently is stored in the registry
because it's so small that it can
actually be stored in Regency even if
you have tens of thousands to purchase I
know if we look at the registry these
are the patches is used to be the
patches just before my operation and I
if I refresh year we'll see you on here
new patch for this hatch of the module
this is the idea of the patch and this
is the code we're just injecting 6 bytes
of code and this location now let's see
how that works so we have your budget
and we're going to relaunch Firefox and
as you can see immediately it says that
patch was applied to Firefox now let's
drop that exploit in there
it did not crash but it also did not pop
up the exploit alert right and why
because we did not put that all in the
code it's not automatically have to put
it in because you may want to have
minimal patches without those course ok
let's do that let's change that so ok
let's make some room for some more code
and but this instead of just simply
largely pending arraignment we first
compare that to see whether it's too
long and if it's not too long we are
done but if it is too long we're going
to reset it stop it and we're also going
to call exploit blocked now let's do
this I have this prepared this second
fire so this is the only changes that I
put this code in now let's compilers
it's just going to overwrite the patch
that it's all of that is already in
there and now let's launch Firefox
patches again applied as you can see I
dropped the exploit the Firefox
before abilities no longer there and
besides we were able to detect that
someone tried to exploit this
vulnerability could be useful
information right so we patched
numerical flow here now let's make sure
it's going to be more difficult because
we don't have the source code here
Firefox is nice to patch nicer to
parents because
while oftentimes you do not have the
source code for patching third-party
applications but will still try to do it
let's say I took all player for ability
it's a media player it's it's a
vulnerability in parsing the playlist m3
you file in that file you have
individual lines of you are Alice URLs
22 media resources so what all there
does is it goes through each individual
individual line and starts to process a
process it but first thing it does it
copies that line to offer on a stack
which has a fixed size of two hundred
and sixty bites and obviously this is a
very simple proof of concept because
there are more than two hundred and
sixty eight here let's see what happens
let's go back to all player I've been
nicer exploits here for you so yeah we
get back out here so it's a very simple
vulnerability of someone has all Player
installed and you sending this file and
he opined that there is a running
machine we know what that means ok no I
won't bore you with all of this code you
need to understand here is the second
instruction from the top is a cold to
drink left right and this is the call
that returns the length of the of the of
an individual line in that fire and this
line is exactly what we are exploiting
we're creating much too long line at the
end
recalling stream copy which means there
is a fixed fixed size buffer on the
stack of 265 space and we're just simply
stream copy that too
that that the line to that basra know
our problem obviously the problem
horrible to hear that the line can be
too long now what do we want to do we
want to shorten the source buffer before
that string copy call so we make sure
that even if the line is too long we're
going to cut it short but putting his
zero at the very end of what would be
allowed now we see that these birds are
suitable for overriding
we know that have to do something nice
for overriding
just moved this go to the top put it
apart and this is the code that we want
to inject
if you saw in the previous slide yes I
rich so happens to have the length of
the line toward
+1 so we can use that information to see
whether the line in the file is too long
so we just compared to yes I 2104 age
which is two hundred and sixty which is
which means we are checking whether the
original line is too long for the
destination buffer and if it's not too
long we just say we're done so if if if
it's if it's exactly two hundred and
sixty or less than its ok but if it's
not just going to put a zero in the
source buffer so when this stream copies
cold it's not going to overwrite it's
really that simple and also calling
exploit blocked so we know that someone
tried to exploit this right and we
determined that the module is altered
accent and we know where exactly in the
code we want to put the patch now let's
actually do this again is the source
code of the patch this is the module or
player this is the offset the house is
being automatically calculated by by our
to this is called you want to inject
it's really very simple and most of the
patches look like this very short small
amount of code you just have to correct
small oversights from the original
programmer right that
so it's in the database and whatever all
players launched its going to be patched
so let's just launched launch player
here and we'll see ok a patch is not
applied now I'm going to open it with an
axe point and instead of the calculator
it was explained attempt log we have
just patched a buffer overflow with a
patch that can be instantly applied to
an application while it's running and
can be removed from the application
while it's running the reboots and
restarts now in experiment with these
patches in this technique we have
created a couple of guidelines couple of
rules that we need to adhere to in order
to to make this all work and users and
these are the five patching guidelines
first place for patching not all you
obviously have a selection of places
once you understand the possibility you
can pitch here or here or here or here
you have to decide which which of these
locations is the best because you want
to cover all of the possible exploit
pass but you don't want to cover
anything else you don't want your code
to be executed unless absolutely
necessary and of course you have to find
a place where you can actually where
there is some relocatable coat in the
vicinity that you can use for rejecting
your coat your patch go and obviously
the original code that is going to be
relocated has to be relocatable it's a
big problem if if it contains any
relative jumps because you have to
recalculate everything and if it's moved
too far then you can
jump back and so on not really very
important for right now the second rule
is you don't want to break anything i
mean who's going to want a patch if it
catches more ability but creates a
problem elsewhere may not create a
vulnerability but if your application is
going to start crashing that you don't
want the best like that you're ok with
solution that you have right now so you
should make those assumptions about how
the code that you patching is is is
working and we're all the execution
paths could lead to Eurocode you
actually have to do the analysis and do
the debugging and technical analysis to
see all the inbound and outbound pass
and obviously you have to preserve the
original functionality sometimes you
find a bug that you can only patch by
Konami patch by actually cutting off
some functionality we've seen for
instance shellshock bash bash for
ability well no one was actually 101
almost no one in the world was actually
using the functionality that was being
exploited shell-shocked so the initial
patch from the original batch developers
was actually actually that functionality
which is ok you can you can do a patch
like this if it works for you but
usually you want to try to avoid making
any functional changes and you also have
to make sure that there are no side
effects so if you're using if you're
changing any ferry and registers or
flags with your passing operations here
to make sure that that does not have any
negative effects on the code on the
original code that continues executing
afterwards room number three the patch
should be as small as possible
why what's a crash Tuesday you get six
hundred megabytes of code right
downloaded to your computer which
replaces well a big chunk
of whatever is running on your computer
it's impossible to review its impossible
to make sure there are no errors in
there and if we make a patch very small
then it's possible actually to review
that I can review your patch you send me
your patch with for instructions I would
be able to review that anyone will be
able to review that if they had over the
peacoat so you were coach you realize
the code fewer errors easier reviewing
any easier testing so we want to
contrast this to the Patch Tuesday
updates right want to keep it really
small so that even the admin can take a
look at the pageant said ok this looks
legit includes normal over that's really
important as well and less code is less
execution overhead we all know how much
users like security products that slowed
down their computers ya know this does
not have to slow down your computer in a
way and less code is less possibility of
introducing a race condition that
previously wasn't there now
number four coaches execute as rarely as
possible so the location of the code of
the petticoat must be chosen very
carefully to make sure that it's just
executed when it's necessary and not not
when possible not in a very long loop so
it doesn't get if you have you have an
algorithm and implementation of lab does
some heavy frost single
very large chunk of data you might want
to put your patch cold outside look
because then it's going to be executed
just wants if you put it inside the loop
is going to be executed a lot of times
it may slow down your computer and not
real number five you have to test for
security and functionality so when the
patches deployed its first has to
resolve the problem obviously that's why
it's there and it has to it has to keep
the original functionality
now the point of this presentation is to
change this guy who was not sure what to
do with the vulnerability found into
someone who will decide to create it
0 patch for it because that would be
arguably on a very ethical thing to do
and also it will be a possibility in
some time to actually make a living out
of patching someone else's code and that
is actually our our our goal and we like
to change this now if you guys want to
try playing with zero patch and creating
your own patches just contact us send us
your email will create your account is
still a closed beta but you guys are
here we are privileged and you can get
the accounts that people outside this
room cannot and will if you want to
create patches will send you the tools
that you need to create patches as well
thank you very much thank you for your
attention I hope I will I have turned at
least one of you exploit developers who
don't admit being on into patch
developers thank you
part of the problem
well that's a very good question well
first of all when it comes to being
security product running on a computer
we were in basically in the very similar
situation to two other security product
that are also looking into application
that's true these days security products
are being a very interesting target for
security researchers and a lot of
vulnerability by being found there
obviously we need to do what everyone
else does we need to make sure that our
attack service is is very small
well we come from a security company and
we're hoping that that was a reflect at
least a little bit on the development of
are all our own code although we're not
fooling ourselves there will be four
abilities in articles as well what we're
focusing on mostly is to make sure that
all abilities and malware cannot be
cannot be introduced to your computer
through the patches that is the most
interesting attack victory someone
trying to trick us into into the point
Mallard all the computers although the
problem is against similar to let's say
in an antivirus product if you break
into their network and and change their
the next update of their of their agent
is going to do everything but very good
question and thanks for thanks for
explaining that it actually obviously
have the wrong information thanks to
replace completely
actually very good question again so
obviously this cannot replace what we
currently have but this can be a very
good solution for two things before
abilities for products that don't have
anymore so I don't have support anymore
like Windows XP for instance and to
bridge the gap between the official
update and corporations applying that
official update which can be months
months after that so this is a huge gap
which always gives a lot of ammunition
to attackers right and if you put a zero
patch here on day one and keep it until
you can apply the actual update then
you're you're kind of covered and that
that's really the point
question again since it's doing the
patching is doing the things that look
like but we're not doing anything
different than other security products
every antivirus product is doing right
and it's the same kind of looking just
at the beginning of functions so it's
really not a big problem we were worried
about that but it turns out that
wherever co-existing ok
I'm sorry there is no but it's never
been detected top 20
there are compatibility issues of course
but thank you
we have not tested against
but we are confident that security
product all other security products will
be able to live with control card then
we will be able to but actually we can
talk about it later cuz I'll be happy to
get something that that's on our list of
to do's but I'm sure it's going to be a
problem but again a very good question