here anyway we're going to get the
debate going Ron hi a while back there
was a rather prolonged threat on the not
mailing list about how router to router
ipv6 links should be numbered and we're
going to follow that up a little bit in
this panel but before we start let's
take a look at some of our options RFC
4291 says that all interfaces should be
numbered from / 64 is nothing smaller
that's the status quo but as it turns
out people aren't actually doing that in
many cases lots of people are numbering
from / 112 s some from / 126 if you
think about it and before you used a /
30 which was to less than the maximum
126 to less than the maximum many
numbering from / 127 s which sidesteps a
common common undesirable behavior in
point-to-point links some people with
128 and some using unnumbered so we're
going to run through all of these
possibilities and possibly come come up
with some consensus here and bring it
back to the v6 working group in the IETF
with some proposal let's talk about the
status quo for a minute there's some
benefit in uniformity some features like
duplicate address detection rely on / 64
numbering host detection is more
difficult arguably if you scanning to
see what hosts are behind an interface
and even though using a sick / 64 on an
interface with exactly two endpoints
seems a bit wasteful there's really
enough address space that this doesn't
matter so much problems with the status
quo of the biggest one in my mind is the
behavior of some point to point
implementations if you send a packet to
a an address that's on the sub network
but not one of the endpoints it will
ping pong back and forth
the TTL expires there's also the
possibility of neighbor discovery
attacks and we consume more address
space than we need again maybe not a
problem because there's so much address
space but waste not want not in any
event at this point I will step aside
and let some of the proponents of other
solutions / 112 these / 127 speak for
themselves a little bit oops slides have
changed a little bit actually why don't
they step aside for a second oh but 11
12 people
all right I'm Kevin Locke and I was
going to talk about the 112 prefix
length option which is something that we
that I have seen I use that myself and
I've seen that in a number of other
discussions on mailing lists and even in
some yes sure so 112 prefix length is
something that I've seen in a number of
appearing links and discussions so I
thought it might be useful to to try to
describe all the reasons that that might
be that people are using that so it is a
popular non standard size I actually
found someone from University of
Pennsylvania put their v6 address plan
online and that's a fairly typical
example of how people are using 112 in
their address planning I think by far
the most interesting or useful thing
about 112 is that it's not 64 and the
consequence of that is that on all
platforms that I'm aware of that
suppresses router advertisements and
auto configurations and in certain
environments such as router links and
even links with some servers that's very
desirable 112 is a obviously 16 bits so
that gives you quite a bit of
flexibility not just for point-to-point
links but for excuse me
you've done that before it came up here
so that does so 16 bits is enough to
number anything you can imagine from two
routers on a link to more than two
routers on an Ethernet segment which is
fairly common or with verb which is very
common in static routing environments
and even server segments I've used it on
server segments and it works great so
you can have one one size instead of
having a mix-match of 126 is here 64 is
there you could pick one size that's
useful for a lot of different activities
so why 112 and not 114 or some other
random length between 64 and 128 I think
it's because it lines up on the last
call and boundary so you have some very
convenient numbering conventions if you
choose to allocate them sequentially
this allows you to have things like
colon 14 router one callin 24 red or two
and because it's 16 bits you could even
do some more creative things if you had
a unique number assigned to each router
in your network you could make the link
ID the last whatever we call them hex
tets or duo octet you could make that a
unique router ID so it would be calling
126 and colon 14 you know which exactly
which two routers just by looking at the
the IP address one benefit of the small
size of relative small size of 112 is
that you can number all of your loop
backs and all of your internal links out
of a single size 64 which could be
useful for things like control plane
policing and rate limiting ACLs you also
have the flexibility of course of
allocating the mon / 64 boundaries which
i know that the other members of the
panel advocate for their particular
designs and there's another reason you
can't do that but it looks like most
people do 112 sequentially and the last
one is a little tongue-in-cheek because
it's whenever you talk about efficiency
with ipv6 it's it's kind of hard to wrap
your mind around it 112 is using 16,000
addresses but it's still 288 218
trillion times more efficient than using
the / 64 and it just seems wrong to use
218 trillion or 1,000 billion addresses
for
point way so that's 1 12 the one comment
oh the one comment that make his 11 12
does not address the problem of ping
pong orgoth attack it reduces a bit
right I think eater will have more
detailed discussion of that but that's
true obviously there's 16,000 possible
address it's certainly a lot fewer than
64 but that could still be enough to
break things i'm rob c strim and i admit
to numbering my network with / 60 floors
much to the surprise of igor into
surprise and Braz one things I really
like about is they keep the uniformity
of addressing and the KISS principle it
turns out the IP address space in ipv6
land is actually really really plentiful
compared to technician brain cell space
available and the we have the luxury
here of being able to engineer for human
factors rather than four machines a lot
of us have spent a really long time with
cider and have sort of grown to think of
engineering things to be better for
machines than four people as sort of the
default and we have the ability now that
we have ipv6 and tons and tons of IP
addresses to say well you know we don't
breathe slowly to conserve air perhaps
we ought to allocate ipv6 addresses in a
way that uh that makes it better for
people than four machines and I put
something that looks sort of like
barcode at the bottom of the screen here
and it's intentional that's difficult to
figure out what's going on from the
audience but you'll notice all the
symbols in the lower sprint and the
lower rank are the same and all the
symbols in the upper rank are kind of
mixed together and if you have subnet
allocations there have different sizes
on different types of interfaces that's
one more thing that you have to be
thinking about at 3am when the phone
rings so this slide was stolen from the
from the previous
from Ron stack and yeah these are these
are all advantages of the / 64 like that
go backwards so one of the things that
Igor and I discovered that when we were
talking and there's going to be eager is
going to talk about this in more detail
as that actually there's difference
between the allocation and the
configuration that you put on on your
box and you might be allocating bigger
pieces with the notion that someday you
might want to have / 64 s everywhere and
to preserve that option because really
you don't need to prove you don't need
to save and conserve and every single
possible ipv6 address that you have but
allow yourself the flexibility of doing
that in the future while today working
around various vendors shortcomings by
putting longer prefix on your interfaces
waste not want not we already covered
that whatever you do one of the things
that I think horribly violates the
keeping it simple for humans is having
your subnet allocation beyond anything
other than a nibble boundary because
that's the symbol that humans are seeing
we're not we don't work in binary we
work in larger symbols there an
aggregation of those binary values I
stole the slide from Ron
I'm eager and I'm going to present an
alternative to 60 fours and 112 s that
we've rolled out in production ourselves
so first of all what's wrong with 64
well in theory nothing well maybe
there's a bunch of things wrong of why
do we actually need 64 bits of host
address space but that ship has sailed a
long time ago so let's just let it go
unfortunately in practice that's there's
a big gap between theory and standards
and hardware implementation and the
whole let's put 60 for everywhere is
actually can cause operational problems
so what are the problems Ron mentioned
that there's a ping-pong problem on
sonet/sdh links this is because the
entire semantics behind sonet/sdh is I
get a packet if it's not a dress for me
and it's for the subnet that's the is a
sign that sdh link I shouldn't even look
at what it is if I just forward it on
well given the example if one cider is
calling zero the other side is calling
one and you get a packet for colon 2
well call them zero hey that's not for
me send a two column one home 1 hey
that's not for me send it right back to
colon to you typical TTL could be either
64 255 and you might have got in a
packet amplification of 250 x it's
pretty easy to us after isn't the other
issue is the pink sweep of death and it
doesn't need to get think sweep could be
a packets push acts and you name it
assuming the link type is ethernet and
the same address plan is above if
somebody you know hits double Colin 345
deadbeef whatever every time I router
get something to an unknown address it's
got to perform an NDP welcome the entire
resolution chain enough any of you have
seen what happens in the router it's
basically dealing with four billion
squared + DP lookups it can't actually
perform that look up for Colin one the
next time call one is supposed to expire
when you're point-to-point links can't
actually perform NDP resolution your IGP
tends to break if you're igp or routing
protocols in general in the router break
your network may be in the about to melt
down so yes these are implementation
issues these are hardware-specific
unfortunately their present in every
vendor that I had seen so again is it
really the fault of 64 that you know
it's a standard know it's a fault of
implementation but we are network
operators our job is to make things work
and this does not work so the question
have been yeah alright so we have to
work on the 64 came a workaround
differently than changing the address
structure some people have proposed
using ACLs you know you put a CL zaboor
that allow packets to Colin 0 calling
one block everything else we manage
quite a large number of ACL entries
having to manage an ACL / interface for
every interface in my network is just
not scalable given that it has to be
unique so the other thing is well we
know this is a problem with the
forwarding semantics of sounded SDH I
just fix it and there's been a you know
standard people have said this is how
you fix it unfortunately the 42 min
because something is program with your
hardware how long's that you spin the
basics get to your router's every five
years every seven so what do you mean
while similar why can't we fix in DBQ
prioritization in theory you could just
say well if you resolve this ntp address
before then we resolve it it should get
priority over looking up a new address
that's great that actually I believe it
is the right way to address it
unfortunately you ask a vendor for a new
feature lately did they tell you that
you're going to get it in less than 18
months anybody sure cell not telling it
to me so in summary we need something
that works now because we're deploying
ipv6 now we need something that we can
manage and we need something that will
actually fix these issues because
otherwise
bad guys out there have a really easy
way to take down our networks that
currently don't suffer from these issues
so how do we do it well as Robert
mentioned there's a difference between
allocation and assignment and
configuration so allocating 64's does an
actual constant problem the problem is
when you configure the 64 on the
point-to-point link so why don't you
just allocate a 64 take the first 127 of
that 64 and that's what you configure in
the router at this point you suffer from
none of the drawbacks of putting 64's
and even 112 on the router interface you
make it really easy for humans to read I
don't know about you guys but at 3am
yeah i know that column zero is you know
the upper end and column 1 is the lower
end and that's the same in all of my
interfaces that's great that's easily
readable you follow the same allocation
plan for your whole network 64 supposed
to be servers 64 location to point to
point it's just a different assignment
into the eurasian plan and best of all
you can deploy this today and this is
actually how we've done this and it has
worked really well for us so at this
point i guess we turn it over to
questions or possibly any rebuttal yeah
or rebuttal from panelist
hello Aaron Hughes is this how am I
still good can you guys actually hear up
there at this point yeah excellent so I
have to say that I like your solution
the best of all these so far I do have a
couple of issues with the 112 as Kevin
was suggesting for a few reasons one of
which I'm surprised actually RS didn't
mention which is regional aggregation
off the top or bottom of your blocks for
numbering loop backs into your separate
regional space rather than aggregating
all of your loop backs globally into the
same space what what you pull from from
where and and how you number loop backs
was sort of outside the scope of what we
wanted to talk about but I completely
agree understood so that I'll skip that
I'm the other point that wasn't
mentioned which is quite useful for or
pro reason for using 64's is software
that you have you store v4 addresses in
today if you happen to cast five
integers so four octets and a netmask a
standard in cast of 11 size are 11 digit
integer you can easily store your assess
/ 64 is this decimal instead of hex in
those exact same spots and then just
check to see if it's greater or less
than 32 and don't have to rewrite your
software too much fair enough by the way
if if you are supportive of the / 127
proposal there is a draft in the six-man
working group the title of the draft
eludes me but it's on numbering
point-to-point links you might want to
subscribe to that working group and
comment on it i'll post a link to the
working group mailing list and a link to
the draft after this meeting sure and
one one last point another reason to
support Igor suggestion is I've now seen
two vendors implementation for NM esas
where they auto aggregate on / 64 so
your links turn into a big single the
lot of links and while that's a software
support issue it's still what's in
implementation today thank you middle
make
little Mike hi my name is Joel I work
for slide I read that thread and I guess
I listened to somebody else and I did /
120 sixes what I have is just a very
simple tool that every one of my point
to point ipv4 IP addresses can be easily
converted to an ipv6 it's you know it's
going to turn it into a hex versus a
decimal but it's a very easy quick
conversion I had to do 126 is not one
27th because of a bit boundary but it's
a really simple easy conversion for
everybody on my team to say hey I know
the ipv4 what's the ipv6 and it's a
simple one so i would just advocate that
it has a little bit of the keep it
simple and it has a little bit of the
historical matching but nobody's on the
panel saying that's I wanted to get that
in there Thanks thank you if I can
respond to that at least for us one of
the reasons what we wanted as little
correlation between deform assets in our
address in the host side of the address
structure is that you could put that
correlation into the network side of the
subnet and at that point you know as
long as you put the courage and the
network side the hosts I can still view
127 or 126 and basically the smaller you
go the less of a ping-pong and
amplification and NDP attack you open
yourself up to so if you go with a 126
you know multiplication factor of two
not so bad you go with the 124 that goes
to eight and so on and there's nothing
going to be cases where you're going to
want to do something larger than the 127
because you've got to be our P's and
yours you got to be up here on your side
to IPS you've got a dr p on the customer
side and whatnot but basically use the
smallest that you can allocate the 64
but assign the smallest block that makes
sense for you yeah
next hello Donnie Roizman the planet
question can you clarify what the sonnet
related issue was I the NDP stuff makes
sense for Ethernet but what was a sonnet
issue that was occurring ok let's say
for a moment that you've numbered from a
/ 64 let's say numbers one and two out
of that / 64 are used Oh next slide okay
um assume that we have this / 64
configured somebody pains 2001 DBA too
it's neither of the endpoints the first
router who receives the packet sends it
to the other one assuming he hasn't for
the same reason the other one sends it
back to the first one and the packet
ping-pongs back and forth till the TTL
expires it's part of the SONET SDH
Samantha basically says if it's not for
me than I forwarded there is no this man
takes don't have a split horizon poison
reverse contact okay thank you have a
question for Igor from Stan barber and
he wants to know how do you address
concerns he doesn't say which concerns
but he says how do you address the
concerns with / 127 that are summarized
in RFC 3627 witches I don't know if
anybody selected got in the last 15
years or so but I think some of the
concerns have to do with mobility and
also the Summoner router anycast ever
implementation that I'm aware of that
supports 127 actually turns off subnet
router anycast and if somebody can give
me a good reason to be running any sort
of p6 mobility of my point-to-point
links you know i would love to learn
so just wondering we should take a straw
poll of the audience to see who in the
audience prefers which technique let's
give it a try so who who goes with / 64
and 126 is 112 and 127 oh so sir
majority can I ask for further
clarification for anything other than a
/ 64 do you configure your router with
the prefix that you held your hand app
for but reserved a bigger chunk of
address space for future mind changing
activities does anybody else do that
I've got a few and any mask it's yeah if
you if you are doing 127 Igor and I
actually turn out to be violently in
agreement on most of this yeah I mean
there's a clear distinction between
allocation configuration and I think
anybody who allocates everyone 27 out of
/ 64 you may be creating more problems
that you're trying to solve because at
3am 2001 DBA calm calm and fec 0 which
side is that what is this but 01 makes
sense and I've been accused of being
using the billionaire mentality when it
comes to assignment and location of ESET
space you should have a trillionaire
mentality I think RS said yesterday that
if you take peanut M&Ms and you fill all
of the great lakes with peanut M&Ms like
drain the lakes and you fill with peanut
M&Ms that's a single / 64 s worth of
ip's you are a quadrillion air when it
comes to ipv6 others in something
there's an important disclaimer
that you should not attempt to eat a /
64 workload so don't try to conserve
address space for v6 it's you don't need
to just make it easy make it readable
make it scalable and best of all make it
work Tammy so yeah Danny maker starting
to make the observation that if the one
reason you may want to allocate those
last 127 is out of 1 / 64 is from a ACL
or you know sort of control plane
pleasing or other policy configuration
management perspective you at least want
to keep your / 64 is continuous and and
so that you minimize that policy so that
at 3am your argument holds from that
perspective as well so well again you
could just allocate all the 64's out of
the symbol 48 yeah no I agree i'm saying
so i'm sure you would want to have that
for the backbone wings in a way but you
definitely want him to be continuous so
may hold it away that argument or
Oracle's more likely the bottom 48 for
each area or however you chop your
network up not to overlook over a
grenade ability I think I think there is
a temptation or a risk when you're doing
allocating regardless of what you can
figure but allocating on 64bit
boundaries to do that where you may have
mixed and matched like the throw
customers in it if you're not very
careful and disciplined about how you're
assigning it whereas with other sizes if
you're going sequentially with 112
you're not as likely to do that because
you probably aren't going to use those
with 30 many customers
well cognizant of the fact that I'm the
one thing standing between you and lunch
and probably some peanut M&MS I'd like
to thank the panelists and thank you and
they