so on with the show and gonna talk about
one of my favorite topics because it's
kind of important to to the network that
I'm involved with MPLS TP the new
generation of transport networks and one
of the people who's been behind the MPLS
revolution about to as much or more than
just about anybody else
Luca martini thanks so I won't try to
entertain you for the next thirty
minutes as like the schedule suggests
this is not about about multi-protocol
TLS but but multi-protocol transport
profile so this agenda will go through
about the why what probably time to
solve and number view and some a
standard update okay what problem is
being solved here in in today's the
networks the the biggest application is
the packet based IP transport so it
would be nice to move to a technology
that matches the service better than
they tried the traditional zone at TDM
technologies we so we want you to have a
lower cost technologies we have to we
want something that goes higher
bandwidth much easier although they're
pretty much tracking each other but the
cost is not packet based the ports seems
to become to come down significantly in
the recent years but what we want is we
want to track maintain a transport
characteristics through the technology
transition so if things like
predetermined path in vanilla and fast
detection of recovery time and NMS
provisioning this is what all the
correct characteristics of a transport
network I've been trying to preach race
for about 10 years and all that the
transfer people will always tell me it's
IP it's too too difficult to manage and
implement and
you probably disagree with that but
there was nothing I could do for for a
long time until his MPLS teepee came
along and it's basically MPLS for
transport folks so in in the past we'd
have the whole TDM network the
application was just voice today we're
getting packet is growing TDM is
shrinking we you know if you look at any
network the Internet is the biggest
traffic generator or most networks I
would say not all there are some other
issues out there and then in the future
we can go to all packet and how we're
going to do that it looks like today and
less TP is the leading contender so as I
said the Carrier Ethernet will replace
solid SDH as the encapsulation for over
the fiber directly and what we what you
want to do is find a technology that
does a creates transport circuit in a
better way than doing TDM and solid so
they're a little bit about the transport
world first but world believes in in
circuits only point-to-point circuits
statically provisioned long term you
know things don't really change that
often as far as connectivity to to
devices and things like that in that
particular level and they want to have
very simple to understand OEM mechanisms
and and control plane should be a static
NMS provisioning agnostic nice graphic
GUI so the transport board has a little
different view that then you know on IP
MPLS then we might have they don't
really understand IP they think it's
very difficult and to assign IP
addresses and maintain all of this very
complex iGPS
they don't quite understand that by the
using use a GPS we make the network
scale better and be easy to operate but
they you know the
instead they think that this is a added
burden and a cost that's not necessary
and we have poor and inconsistent OEM of
course we know the way I mean IP works
really well but they don't think so so
we're trying to make a be less transport
friendly so we started off with we're
doing what do what transfer world wants
we do everything static everything gets
managed by the NMS like settle wire and
Nellis Peas we have em in band with LSP
and we can add multiple transport
protection mechanism in MPLS so we don't
have to just do the simple active and
backup LSP we can actually work on more
sophisticated things as well so we want
you know consistent OEM capabilities in
band between the layer to the little SPS
and they upsell wires which are today
they pretty much only client
defined for Olympia sleepy Network so
how does Apple SDP concert well
basically what it is is we have a
statically provisioned LSP from one p to
the other through coordinate router we
have a dim bono a.m. channel that is
used to pass OEM between the routers and
of course the middle routers which are
called nips midpoints can also inject so
eme for the technical error or things
like that and what we do run we run
observer wire from the PE to the P so
that you can actually transport the
client signal which would be eternity
here more whatever protocol you want one
one point to show here is that this
maintains the MPLS her article nature of
having LSP nest original SPS or set of
wires Nestor day within LSP is one thing
to note though is that while in the
SONET it's very well defined how many
channels you can put in one particular
you know STM one
in in MPLS DP'd it's not it's like MPLS
you can put as many as you want which
presents some challenges and the rehab
level for scaling the amount of set of
wires in LSP you so everything is that
my network management as I said so it's
simple as static labels provision by NMS
the you know the control plane is very
simple and it's just know a.m. it's you
know is it possible for for determine if
circuits are alive like continuity check
infinity verification is somebody
actually has unplug the fiber and
plugged into somewhere else because
remember there's no IP addressing on
these and so there's no you know there's
no I GP or anything like that that would
detect that somebody swats the port so
we have to put that in the NMS so some
some measures of salvation I'll go
through the details of this afterwards
we are adding an Associated channel to
Bell ESPYs before we just had MPLS LSPs
which were relying on IP to do the OEM
now we have to add a different set of OM
functions which doesn't rely on IP at
all and so they are similar some of them
are similar to what we could do on cell
wires for for the past 10 years which
was running for self obviously BFD on an
associated channel we want to avoid
breaking any MPLS architecture function
so we this should be very compatible
with MPLS we would not changing any
function there so we're just adding two
to MPLS so in the end he'll say on the
last line there is no change to the ITSM
class architecture and this is one of
the biggest arguments we have on the
standards and people STP lists because
there's always somebody that doesn't
understand how the architecture works
and proposes they in addition that will
break the atlas for the parenting
one of the major change for my IP or
MPLS is that the taps the LS B's are
bi-directional only we're not going to
have a single direction path with with
this technology this is to maintain the
circuit characteristics it's also to
allow for timing time of day
transmission which is a requirement
coming up in the 4G network selfies if
we have none better short paths we have
issues when we do rerouting a face of
that so we actually decided to go with
bidirectional power zombie so let me
show you a little bit what the packet
looks like here I'm going to assume that
on the left there is a Mac header so
this pack arrives over the ethernet it
doesn't have to but that's most likely
what it's going to do there's two labels
this is absolu I'll actually this is an
Aryan packet and so where there's two
labels in here the LSP label have salwar
label let's say and then we have a gal
which is a specific special reserved
label which we are actually David I
think they were that got the number 14
for and this is used to basically
indicate that the next afterwards the
next piece of data afterwards is
actually a generic associated channel
header because they do say there is a
implied function in MPLS where if you
expired ETL at some random node in the
middle of the network they the package
is sent to the processor for full
interpretation and it's always
interpreted as an IP packet so the first
thing that the processor would do is
look for a 0 4 0 6 and the first people
on the packet and and go from there and
this one is not an IP packet so we kind
of have to say well this is not an IP
packet
you know go interpret it as a generic
associate the channel and and here we
have it a few a few things in here they
dress the part is the channel type which
tells you what kind of payload is after
that and we so with this method we're
able to create an inbound channel along
with LSP where we can actually run
things like VFD or you know om messages
like you know telling the peer that we
have a link problem upstream of things
that yeah a s like messages and so forth
so this is a an example on how the LSP
OAM works as you can see this this I
wanted to first define the terms and
basically we have similar to the the
sonnet world we have the round circle
they were all registered coherent Maps
which is the maintenance endpoints which
is where LSP is would end and the middle
point that called MIPS meant as
intermediate points and what you can do
in those particular points you can
inject OAM messages and you know take
actions like you know take injection
Fenella speeds down injection OEM extra
and so forth this is a simple example of
how the alarm irrigation is changing is
is actually used let's say we have a
failure and a link p2 in sp3 here the
first thing that will happen is the two
peas will detect the failure either by
yasser light or maybe because the
continuity check the BFD session has
gone down we then send a message
interface down in packet terms to this
MIPS the map SK here because it's an
endpoint on this part this is an a
multi-sensor water example which means
that tp1 goes
SB 3 and then SP 3 2 as before and then
it has no segment its before to TP 6 so
there's like 3 LSP is a 3% of our
segments here that we're looking at and
then the next thing is the mid 0 will
send an AIS alarm he's actually been you
name this lately
to the teepee and it also then what we
do is is the SP 3 and he p1 sendin an
interface down because the TP 1 received
the AIS alarm and these in the stands
and sent up to the map which is the cell
wire map so observers have maps as well
they don't really have myths at this at
this point we had a big discussion on
this and what is it is really because
I've said well predate this technology
and the for it's not what the nipple I
met and but it with a solid sub cell
wall map and then at that point the cell
wire will send a day is alarm which is
now really in observing terms is a TX
failure and this case actually not X
failure in in this direction and at this
point the cell wall takes appropriate
action signals they attach to circuit
could be Ethernet to be ATM that it has
to go down but before it does that
actually tries to find it back up cell
wire if as features enable or now then
it says if I can't find a way to fix
this then I will send a message out to
my client say that this cello is dead so
maybe the client can do something else
this is a quick update before I go into
this I would say they the ATF is now
working very hard on this technology and
there's a lot of meetings and a lot of
people who think an incredible amount of
hours and this this is a like
most over technology I've seen and so we
just to give an example usually they
have one working group meeting as you
probably know for one one technology and
here we have three meetings for breakout
session just official ones but in the
hell over 20 of our meetings between the
smaller group so so promises be made
fairly quickly there's a bunch of other
see out already and you know this is
kind of the an idea what the problems
that we have today as from the last idea
you know there's a kind of a
unidirectional link protection for
example that's three no possible deploy
you know we're still be of the young
discussion ongoing I believe they
actually reached a solution on this
about a week ago and you know so so this
is moving really quickly we'll have the
results in the next ITF they the statics
are wire protocol draft which I came up
with
if couple months ago is basically to put
status messaging in salwar without LDP
control plane for the MPLS TP that was
accepted and we're moving on with that
addition to cellular technology we have
a map definition and there's a ring
protection which is pretty much had a
lot of lot of presentations but it's
been converging to two proposals right
now one which is very summer-like and
everyone is more be less light and so
we'll see what happens there and you
know this is a big problem which was a
portable entity so they want to test to
each interface of a box mind you not
necessarily each IP address like you
have an IP input Allison output is on
the router they want to have each
interface inside the box and have a loop
way to set a look to it and that's quite
this is not quite a phase we can put in
a protocol so tomorrow you have a new
box that has maybe ten hops inside
itself
then you can test for health tenhoff's
so we settled on a on a packet format
that contains requests for the hop you
want to look look the packet set so MPLS
DPI wanted to make a point here that
MPLS TP is
LSP is an LS piece can be nested and we
can nest them from all sorts of
different reasons in this particular
example we have a provided it goes from
be the provider goes from B to E and
then provider from F to a and so the
middle provider can push another label
create an elf's P and outside LSP which
will allow him to do some OEM monitoring
from E to B and this is completely
independent of what the other provider
from A to F will do it can also do a
Mallya monitoring but it will be end to
end and the Beaufighter kind of ships in
the night so we use the MPLS
technologies to offer the service like
if it was a native service from one
provider to another and there's a bunch
of discussions here where whether we
where we put the service delimitation if
it's in the in excel wire or if it's
like in an LSP and I think both models
will probably work a little example
where this would be actually deployed if
you get a typical service provider
network with an access path where we
have all sort of things like upon this
lamb and and so forth what the
aggregation the first part of the
network would be running MPLS TP which
is then handed off by very easily to an
MPLS network if we want or you know the
services could be injected closer to the
to the customer edge here so some
services will just be injected here and
our LS B's will will continue across
them the MPLS network and we can do this
LSP of cell wire level for now we define
it at a salwar level
putting on the NSB here at the edge of
the network so one of the things that to
point out is that a TLS which is kind of
a predecessor of this but it was a
different technology is that at this
point there's there's no more work and
it's been superseded by the MPLS TP work
we're making rapid progress in the ITF
and everybody is behind he and MPLS TP
there's a lot of interest from all the
whole industry to replace the SDH model
and empliciti really is just all you
have additions to MPLS and a subset you
know they didn't want PHP so we cannot
do Peter penultimate hop hopping on MPLS
TP but that's fine it's always been an
option in MPLS anyway and so there's no
change to the basic attacks or anything
we do has to be integrative the base
architecture and there should be no no
no changes so all the chipset that we
have today the forward MPLS will work
fine and we can make sure this
technology remain remains low-cost and
Cisco is leading the effort on this on
this technology questions as you can see
we can see an collapse at the end of the
tunnel
do you think the MPL escaping is
computing the density of division
multiplexing in a metropolitan area as
far as delivering the service for
high-density traffic's for the customers
do you think it would compete with TDM
yes nothing you know ten straight
division multiplexing different yeah
right right you would run this over DWDM
I mean that's not understand but in a
metropolitan areas for example most if
you go to Washington DC's for is most of
the government's they do have a transfer
division multiplexing string can you
compete as far as the conversions and
Layton sees hidden
pwe yeah yes the converges and latest is
what will be very good and I would think
that we could make it better than TDM
networks they did someone that the
Solent networks are defined as a certain
radius or veins and things like that
which if we do a local protection like
we can do in the future in this
technology we don't were not sensitive
to those distances so that's why we can
actually do better than the famous 50
milliseconds if we want to but to us
sort of your previous question the DWDM
week you can run anything over there it
was waves and so you can run Ethernet
and MPLS TP over that and as far as you
know provisioning this has the advantage
of statistical multiplexing your packets
you connect classes that have the
internet that are best fo volunteer DM
you can't you have a bunch of empty
channels so the efficiency and and the
fact that the cost will be comparable to
TDM ATMs for example will really I think
will be a great success for this
technology replacing the TDM so that the
technologies but I believe if you're
running over there dense wave division
multiplexing you're adding another layer
of Layton sees to dance wave division
multiplexing because it's already have
one say you're going to put another one
yeah and no because you wouldn't you
would
put a layer on top of so you wouldn't
use the TDM convergence mechanism it's
not of a solid there's no Sonic so you
can't really do that this is just packet
if there's no layer the sonnet
underneath but if your MPLS is gonna run
over there dense way we do Jamal poopsie
if the fiber is get cooked you gotta
have a conversion at the lower layers no
you know you wouldn't have a conversion
over layer this is the layer there's no
sonnet underneath no agent under it the
other light packet is an Ethernet packet
it's an Eaton header with with the
labels you've seen there's nothing
underneath there's no solid you know SDH
frame area or anything like that
my second question is that on an
Ethernet site are you slicing the
ethernet frame because right now the
carriers are providing a Ethernet
framing but what they do is they sliding
slicing the Ethernet framing for example
if you want to VLAN as a customer site
you get it right all the carriers hey
this is my veal and these are there yeah
right so the problem yeah so the problem
is Ethernet is somewhat a completely
technology in this area it's not as
scalable and as manageable the whatever
last EP is going to be but you know
basically you can do both but I would
think that in the future we would run
those Ethernet services over MPLS DP
just because it is you know the OEM is
better or you can we can do it's easier
to manage and so forth and it's more
like transport like while Internet is a
broadcast environment so I would think
that they will see a mixture of the two
in the future more even to the point
where you have maybe Ethernet only on
the outer rings and then just appear as
you get further into the network but you
know that it's it's not in today we I
would see more a little bit on this
computer technology in that area
and thank you very much Lucca