hi there so I'm kind of curious how many
of you in this room have already played
with ipv6 ipv6 routing most of you going
to say what are you doing here but so
anyway I serve on phonica and myself
will be presenting this I am NOT Philip
Smith he couldn't make it there was a
conflict with me nog so since I
configured ipv6 routing like in
2005-2006 I figured I could fill in at
least we're needed so Long's with
juniper I'm with myself used to be at
Cisco years and years ago and anyway I
guess we'll get started look I'm Ron
bonica we're gonna be painfully honest
with you at the beginning of this talk
American I've never given this talk
together before so we have no idea how
well it goes but what we're going to do
is make believe for a minute that she
and i work for a fictitious isp we'll
set up our website at fictitious mad or
whatever and we're going to activate
ipv6 for the first time we have some
routers from brand j and brand see so
we'll show you some examples we have
some other problems that we're going to
need to deal with on day one so let's
leap into this exercise and i guess we
have two problems right off the first
problem is configuring aren't well we
don't know which problem is first one
problem is configuring our network come
closer to the microphone okay one
problem is configuring on it too loud
okay one problem is configuring our
network and the other problem is coming
up with an addressing plan and which one
do you think we should tackle first oh I
definitely think the addressing plan
because how do I even go about getting
an ipv6 address that's a good idea and
it's very lucky she said that because
those are the first slides in the
presentation
go figure well that's light doesn't
matter that much topics and goals well
what do you know we touched on that
erratic aggressive well you're going to
need some ipv6 address space and you
know that stick pretty well already from
ipv4 the same rirs that dole out fee for
address space dhola v6 address in space
the one difference between the two well
it's the same people but you'll notice
very different responses when when you
ask for address base ask for v4 a big
chunk of v4 address space and you'll
meet the pit bull here ask for v6
address space and they're very happy to
accommodate you by the way that's Rocco
yeah so so anyway all the regional
registries you can get an ipv6 address
from there are some slight deviations in
terms of policies because there's still
that controversy that's been ongoing for
the last oh I don't know at least eight
years that I've been hearing about it
about whether or not you know a / 32
allocation from an RR is big enough too
much too little should it be / 56 you
know what should people do so there's
they're still controversy and you know
ongoing policy issues and if you're
actually interested in this I would
encourage you very strongly to go to
whatever region your and I would imagine
most of you are here in the air in
region but some of you that may have
traveled from other areas you know if AP
neck or or whiteboard or lack Nick or
AfriNIC is is where you're from then I
would encourage you to actually
participate on some of these policy
discussions you know besides the rirs
you can also get address space from the
upstream isp if you're a smaller ISP or
you could also use 64 in fact that's
fairly important medica and I are
assuming that we're both at isp so we'd
go directly to the RIR how many of you
folks are representing enterprises and
not is BS about what half okay all right
this just shows a picture of the
different internet registry
registry regions so in terms of getting
ipv6 address space if you're not a
member of your ISP should become a
member of your regional internet
registry and get your own allocation
basically all of the ipv6 allocation
policies that are current and also some
proposals are all documented in each of
the RA are websites if you're an
existing ipv6 resource folder some IRS
give you ipv6 just on the quest I EAP
Nick so just a little bit of history on
that right i mean there's been a lot of
encouragement from the IRS to get people
to actually start playing with and
deploying ipv6 and while there's still
some notion that it's only you know 128
bits in terms of addresses that's it
nothing more I think those of you that
have actually actively been using it and
deploying it know that you know there's
a lot of other considerations actually
there is plenty of ipv6 address space
and most of the rars actually do require
high quality documentation in terms of
how you actually use that space okay you
can also get ipv6 addresses from the
upstream is P so typically you get a
slash 48 from the upstream isp and you
can get more than once last 48 if you
have more than 65,000 subnets so just as
an aside I actually worked for
connections by bowing in 2005-2006 and
they had Boeing itself had gotten their
own / 32 and we were very actively
playing with it I actually had a BGP
going live with NTT and this was
December of 2005 and from what I
understand we
the first / 48 as an enterprise that got
routed by ntt I was told by some people
later that they absolutely hated me
because it you know started this in
engineering internal discussion to put
it mildly right but I think you know the
key is to just really start using it
most of you have said in here that you
have so you know get and get a an
adverse from the upstream is P we're
also you 64 if you actually need to do
that so the 64 is really the last resort
and really for simple testing purposes
it's much better if you actually get
your own v6 allocation and how 624
addressing works you basically take a
single ipv4 / 32 and then you insert
that after the 2002 colon enter that as
your the ipv4 address and that becomes
your / 48 subnet it also requires a 64
gateway and electron actually talk a
little bit more about this as well
let's have some funny questions right
now kind of you know hedging the bets
against our retirements if I had been
around 30 years ago I would have snarfed
up a few / aids and I would have kept
them in my pocket until there was value
later given that ipv6 address space is
so large I probably don't want to play
that game this time do I I wouldn't why
don't you wouldn't very nice person now
the question is what I probably there's
no economic benefit in that I don't
think so because in the world of / 48
there are an awful lot of / 40 aids in
the ipv6 address space
okay so in terms of address blocks for
our outer loop back interfaces generally
a lot of people what they do is they
number all loop backs out of one singles
last 64 and so you have a last 128 /
lubeck also for address block
infrastructures as last 48 allows for
65,000 subnets typically there is a / 48
use / papa region a / 48 for whole
backbone and summaries summarizing
between these sites really makes sense
now you know every six months I either
watch the v6 ops mailing list that's run
out of koonet de or na nóg list and you
know the thread there's a similar threat
all the time in terms of you know what
kind of allocations do you actually use
for your subnets so mostly what we're
describing here is what makes reasonable
sense and and you know again I didn't
create these slides Philip actually does
a lot of these tutorials especially
around the apt neck region and also he's
done it here now logging it right and
these are basically allocations that
both him and Ron believe are the most
reasonable there are some variations you
know and I still remember doing a survey
in 2006-2007 why ask people so what do
you use and I asked five different
people and I got five different answers
so but again like if what I would
encourage you to do is also take a look
at some of the threads from the nanog
list that and I know that this year
though there's been at least two of them
you know in the last 12 months about
what do you actually use how do you
allocate your your your address space
adequately now aside from the fact that
if you use a / 48 you have room for 65 k
subnets left there's absolutely nothing
sacred about any of the numbers on this
page if you and I decide we like 49
better than 48 the retro accommodated
just like right at least most of the
bigger routers will so one of the things
also to actually look at is some of you
are and you don't have different
networks you're not just you know using
cisco juniper stuff so if you're looking
at CP devices which also now become in
warm or ipv6 aware i would also look to
see what they do
Oh
another two more pieces of addressing
guideline first what about the land is a
recommendation here for a / 64 / well
this is even more than a recommendation
is from RFC 4 / 64 per subnet pearl and
the next question is much more
controversial and I think it's on
Tuesday we're going to have a panel to
talk about this let's say you've got a
point-to-point link between two routers
how should you number that well
strangely enough the current well I
shouldn't say strangely but the current
recommendation is to use a / 64 that
seems a bit wasteful for a subnet that
will never have more than two end points
on it what's more it leaves you to
several security vulnerabilities that
we'll talk about much more on Tuesday so
if you take a look at advice coming out
of the IETF today they're saying as / 64
lots of people using 126 is some are
using 127 s some are using a pair of 128
on a real point-to-point link some
people use 112 because it accommodates
reverse dns lookups nicely other people
using all sorts of other things so we'll
discuss really what the right thing to
do is on Tuesday and this on this point
and I'd like a bunch of people to
present their input we'll put it
together and send it to the IETF as a
recommendation from operators
okay so if you're an ISP by basically a
customer would get a / 48 unless they
have more than 65,000 subnets in which
they can get a second / 48 but some ISPs
alter distributing / 56,000 / 60s as
initial customer assignment because they
feel that let's say it's a small
customer you know / 48 is actually quite
a bit of address space so your mileage
may vary and you know there's still
quite a bit of controversy actually and
what what to give out traditionally it's
been as last 48 but I I personally have
actually seen a lot of / 50 sixes for
the customer the addressing plans I mean
they should not be reserved or signed on
a per pop basis is P ibgp carries
customer networks there's aggregation
within the internal bgp is not required
and usually not desirable and
aggregation and ebgp is very necessary
right one of the biggest issue is
actually facing the internet as a whole
as more and more be six starts though
it's getting utilized is how do the
routers actually handle the routing
tables and you know we'll we'll see how
that all progresses and I can't remember
now with the size of the routing table
is in v6 I think it's about 16,000
ebuddy actually know how it 2700 okay so
right now we're at 2,700 you know bgp
bgp routing table entries and
summarization is definitely really
important in aggregation
ok and
I guess this is a little picture of our
addressing assignment we aggregate
windows on aggregate we assign 1 / 64
for our loot bags oh I'm sorry this is a
picture of our addressing strategy we
signed 1 / 64 for our loot bags to say
we said we would we have four side we
whereas my cursor we assign this chunk
for infrastructure and this bit for
customer assignments yeah so since most
of you actually have deployed some ipv6
I would imagine that most of you have an
addressing plan what I'm kind of curious
about is that if you're an ISP how many
of you do not give us last 48 out to
your customers not what do you give out
you do okay and the rest of you I mean
how many of you do give out of / 48 okay
so that comes to a total of three people
and I saw a lot more hands at the
beginning of this I guess some of you
were enterprises yeah how many of you
let's ask the question again how many of
you either give or receive a 48 that
were that yes how many of you give or
receive something smaller just the one
for this all right so it really depends
on who their customers
yeah I mean as you'll note I mean
there's there's the rules that people
established years ago right are really
in the process of saying you know these
policies I meanwhile we think that ipv6
has a lot of adverse base there's still
a little bit of a notion by some people
that you know we need to be careful
about how we allocate things so we
actually don't run out you know I I
don't know how many of you have done
this I was actually stupid enough to
create spreadsheets for all of the last
60 fours it was a lot of numbers you
know and my co-workers were like why are
you doing this and I you know after like
a day I said you know I don't know but
it kind of proved to myself that really
there are a lot of numbers there but you
do want to have some kind of sensibility
in terms of how you actually allocate at
the space right but I don't think we
have to be as concerned as maybe some
people are well we're being numerical
how many of you have ever gone back to
the RIR for a second / 32 didn't think
so I don't know a what you have and the
direction
it's not
law is empowering
so right now choices are
so that
email servers are but it all works from
a network there at the security of
support if you go under
well this particular session is more
about routing right and actually doing
ipv6 routing and you are absolutely
correct i mean we know when i configured
in 2005 i was very much happily
surprised that it really just worked the
stuff that didn't work was the
management stuff right or you know i am
actually security personnel or that's
abysmal but so we're really discussing
the addressing plans in terms of more
from a routing perspective and form
actually the core network Jake did you
have a problem hi I'm just curious how
many of you people are actually
filtering ipv6 route to secular edges
and if so what size are you filtering on
good question what are you filtering on
so you don't have a minimum
mar lazing or frontier communications
and I'm on the air and AC I don't want
hijack your presentation because it's
good and but this topic of addressing
and routing is actually a big issue
right now with Erin policy and there
have been proposals put forward that
will dig into this even deeper and can
really screw with routing if they pass
and if we don't get people like you at
the meeting to vote on it because it
actually is addressing what filters or
be your response kind of really keep me
up because you said you're doing what
the rirs are saying well if you keep
doing that and some of these policies
pass we're going to have serious issues
so it's a great topic I'm sorry I don't
want to hijack anything but the subnet
boundaries and filtering is it is
important and I think people need to
know that yes already tables are getting
large filtering kind of does need to be
done but we need to be conscious about
not blocking off things like multihoming
which is very much in danger and in
traffic engineering is in danger thanks
yeah no I'm actually glad you made the
comment because it also really
emphasizes what I had mentioned earlier
that you know if you can and are really
interest in them please participate in
the RRS you know addressing policy
issues and controversies
speaking of addressing policies actually
Marla can confirm this or not if you
ever run out of your first / 32 when you
reserve the first one the RA are
reserved a second one for you so you'll
get to do we not do that anymore well
that's one of the proposals that would
change that which I see is a problem
because it proposes that now you can
only get 1 32 and you can qualify to get
one of the other subnets but there for
the whole reservation fact goes away
well then you're doubling your routing
so ya know it right now it is but it may
not be in a couple months if people
don't speak out against it actually I
think this is probably you your comment
is probably a little more interesting
than our talk so if I could ask him if I
could ask you if you don't want to being
put on the spot if you could run through
quick bullet points of the dangerous
proposals and I don't have the names of
the memory sorry I have to use cheat
sheets i'll confess i use them like
crazy and but there's two specifically
that it involves addressing and what is
supposed to be proper addressing just to
try and maintain control and not waste
and however it's getting into routing
because there's proposals one is saying
hey let's make 48 only come out of this
chunk here and 30 tues only come out of
this chunk here and so on and if you do
that you've now in a way classified
addressing and made it possible for
people to filter out certain subnets and
some people might look at that as a good
thing in some might look as bad you
might look as bad because you have a
smaller subnet let's say you've got a
larger isp and they have a large super
net themselves and they only want to
mess with their own routes they don't
they don't want all these as many
customers coming to me with I've got my
own address space please route it here
please route it
instead we want to go hate here's ours
use it for multi-homing get your other
eye speed provider to route it as well
and you're good to go but if you start
doing these boundaries where you can
filter then you start running into
roadblocks oh I might not be able to
actually give my customer a / 48 and
have it multi-home Marlowe so kids it
came out of the 32 I want to see if you
really understand something like you
said at the beginning of the comments
it's actually kind of a return to class
full addressing in a kind of a different
way it's it that's why I want to use
that word because it's kind of its
classifying groups but it's not
classifying it in the same way there was
abused me let me make that clear it's
not the same thing there weren't any
bits that indicate the class but if you
take a look at address an address by
looking at that address and looking at
some other table you know for certain
it's a / 48 right and it yeah so let's
see so there's there's that and that
could cause I mean that could there is
no multihoming solution for v6 and this
solution is networks just do it and let
it work however if there's policy like
that now we've got a whole bunch of
roadblocks in the way of letting at work
and some people on the other side might
go hey great because when the routing
tables won't grow too much well that's
really not the case because you keep
hearing people say it's 141 their people
don't want to have to change their
addresses when they go to a different
provider but and that's a whole another
topic I hear ya but I'm doing it all the
time that's what I do and it works it's
okay but you're gonna have just as many
routes so it's it's not putting those
separations there and saying this is out
of this block is just going to put more
more roadblock set for networks and
operators are going to struggle trying
to get their customers up to let them do
multi humming I'm sorry I think i
babbled yeah
you yet you actually added lots of value
thank you hey yeah all right Jake and
then we're gonna continue so this kind
of brings to mind a question then is an
Ernie rir is working on our BCPs answer
to sort of specify a good policy for
using array our allocations for
filtering is that a is that a goal here
it's not a goal that there is no bcp yet
there were people at the last night nog
and that stood up and said hey I'd be
great to do and then or as a group that
kind of went to dinner and I heard
anything come out of it so no no one's
taken ownership for it it's not on the
Charter for Aaron it's not on the
Charter for Nana and should it be on the
Charter for v6 ops maybe so wrong maybe
we should do that I'd be perfectly
willing to put it on the Charter if
somebody would say I would help you with
that actually you'd be glad to be there
yeah okay anybody care to help Your
Honor I heard and so to answer the
question no not right now
smaller
that
well I agree that the question is should
the tail wag the dog or the dog wagging
the tail maybe operators should be you
know writing their filtering policies
and letting the vendors do what the
operators need rather than by the way I
didn't say that i work for a vendor but
anyway by the way would you to get in
touch with each other so you'll know to
work together and okay we talked about
registry is document let's say you at
this point how much time do we have our
talk right now should we move on to
configuration let's do that what do you
know
how convenient ok can I pose a question
related to documentation please are
there some rirs that actually are easing
up on the documentation requirements for
critics is allocated to customers
because I have had something like this
but I've yet to verify this information
well that's it that's it it's probably a
question for mala so are there some rars
that actually have eased up the
documentation requirements of IP version
6 customer allocations compared to be
four locations yes so that you don't
have to document every single and
customers are the same the only region
I'm aware of that has very liberal
non-existent justification is APNIC all
the other ones have been still requiring
it and it is it is a little a little
more loose because we don't know what to
expect and you have one camp saying you
can IP address every grain of sand on
the earth but when you look at history
it repeats itself and there's a finite
numbers again be six so we don't want to
just open the floodgates and say hey
have at it because we're just going to
be in another world or so there there is
still justification required and that
the heir and Regent I can only speak
firmly to their in region and that's we
are sticking to that we will be
continuing to do justification what
exactly the extent of that will be as
time goes on I can't answer because I
don't I don't have a crystal ball de
say that one yeah you know and i'll have
to validate this but i was reading on a
mailing list just I think a couple weeks
ago that the ripe actually region is is
being maybe a little bit more loose with
ipv6 and ipv4 but I I need to validate
that for sure yeah it pretty little get
it it is a little more loose but and the
only one that's really not there is f
Nick my comet is here just because of
the the good registration is an
essential part and if you look into
things from the security viewpoint if
you really want to contact the end
customers directly who actually have an
operation roll it is national essential
thing that is it is at the same level as
in with 34 that the only customer
assignments are properly registered it
helps this work works of sirs and abused
hunters a lot right I agree I mean you
want accountability right okay well now
we've got all our addressing policy at
least as clear as it's going to get with
questions about how we really must do
things or what policy should be and
people kicking off new BCPs so now it's
time to start configuring a router and I
guess the very first thing we should do
is on our iOS routers tell the router
that it's going to do v6 and the way to
do that right so to enable ipv6 on a
cisco iOS router you basically have a
goal global command which is ipv6
unicast routing you also want to in
enable Seth because it's not on by
default and you just do that by the
command command ipv6 f you would also
want to disable ipv6 source routing
right just with as
I pee before you just really don't need
it and you would say no ipv6 or
sprouting if some of you have followed
this for a while right with ipv6 you
have this issue with the routing header
zero and it's actually been the cause of
some some well security issues if you
will and so with no ipv6 source routing
it just turns off using the routing
header 0 for iOS XR routers ipv6 is on
by default so that's different than just
iOS configuring interfaces on either iOS
or iOS XR you do an interface under the
interface command you just say ipv6
address unless the address and prefix
you can also do an automated eui-64
based ipv6 address but typically this is
really nobody uses its own routers right
because generally you want to know what
the actual ipv6 addresses but if for
some reason you did want to use that he
was just under the interface say ipv6
address the prefix and then eui-64 and
that would then take the mac address and
create an EU I 64 based ipv6 globally
unique address so um okay one of the
things that I'm going to point out here
now is that I have seen people that
would actually play with their ipv6 they
just kind of turn it on sometimes you
don't have a test router so you actually
would just see what happens if you
enabled it on your production network
and what was really fascinating to me
was that you would have you know your
ssh access for ipv4 and your filters and
all that and you totally forgot to do
that for ipv6 so because you enabled
ipv6 now when your routers and had
access with interfaces that means that
if I just kind of knew what your ipv6
allocation was and happened
no what your interface address might
have been I might try to SSH into it you
know and it's you know you want to at
least put in this same kind of control
plane filters for your ipv6 to make sure
that no miss between traffic kind of
gets at it so it was just kind of
interesting because I've seen that
actually in a lot of environments and in
some environments that really should
have known better so just a caution okay
and now for configuring ipv6 on your
junos routers system-wide it's on by
default what you need to do is something
slightly different as you are defining
an interface as always you need to
define that you have interfaces on the
box you need to define a physical
interface fe 300 in this case you need
to define a logical interface on it unit
0 all this you would have had to do
whether it were v4 or v6 had this been a
v4 interface you would have said family
I net address and a v4 address in this
case it's family inet6 address and a v6
address you could have turned them both
on if you wanted it to be a dual stack
interface have one stanza that says
family inet6 another that says family i
net for
in fact there's an example of it and you
saw eui-64 syntax in iOS iOS XR same
syntax here in junos that's what the
address blah blah blah ey 64 is about
and let's say okay we're back in cisco
land that's kind of both basic don't you
yeah so in in the last couple of years
also both the name server and syslog
have been made to work in both the iOS
and journals routers to go over the ipv6
transport so as there was a comment
earlier before right the routing works
but some of the network services are
still things that are work in progress
and that is true but for both you nose
and iOS actually named server and syslog
can be accessible VoIP v6 and these here
are the commands that would enable that
so for iOS you would say IP name server
and put in the ipv6 address and well the
other one is the ipv4 same thing for iOS
XR you would actually use domain name
server as the key command and then
that's the junos configuration yes just
sorta jump back to interface
configuration some people may be
configuring interfaces on to a public
exchange or to a peering point and I
know that certain distance ones have
certain criteria it or third
requirements for interface configuration
586 I don't know anybody here from
constrictor exchange with operator okay
kid can you maybe touch upon some of
those special requirements like they
were discovered in
yeah this fight is basically what I was
mentioning earlier that when you're
actually enabling ipv6 on a platform be
aware that IP access to the control
plane is now possible via ipv6 right so
make sure that you do your control plane
filtering also on ipv6 as well as ipv4
and you know it's it's something that
isn't in the slide set but what Mike
just mentioned actually regarding
turning off neighbor discovery and also
you know router advertisements typically
on your on your peers you know you don't
need router advertisements and router
solicitations so it's usually on by
default on the interfaces so from a
router the router peer connection you
want to disable that now how many do not
know what I mean by this okay I figured
since most of plague I mean you do know
this
okay so yeah so also I mean you guys are
seem to be pretty familiar with ipv6
which is great note that configuring and
an ipv6 address you will have both
global and in unique local ipv6 address
and also a link-local ipv6 address which
is the fe ad colon colon interface ID so
the link local address is basically
config constructed by comparing the fe
80 with the interface ID as soon as the
ipv6 is enabled so the next slide
actually shows that so from a cisco
router if you do ipv6 unicast routing so
you're enabling ipv6 when you do a show
ipv6 interface it will show you that you
have a link local address that's
automatically generated and
automatically you're already part of a
couple of group addresses like the all
voters address and some others
you can also look at the interface
status and basically this is what the
output would look like and this is just
the show is what it would be on the X
our router how many of you are using X
our routers here is anybody just a few
of you okay and this is similar output
for in Geno's now we've brought up our
interfaces probably pinged across
interfaces and said yep that works now
it's time to bring up a routing protocol
or not or you want to do static routing
so true so hopefully you're not doing
this hopefully you're doing you the ospf
is ice or PGP but if if you wanted to
play and you know he needed to do a
static route maybe to a customer
actually then the configuration command
is very much like in before it's ipv6
route but the ipv6 prefix prefix length
ipv6 address interface type a number and
then an administrative distance so this
particular example shows that you're
routing packets for network 2001
deviates last 64 so 64 subnet to a
networking device at 2001 DB 80 CC 0 0 1
with an administrative distance of 110
and for those of you that may not know
this by the 2001 db8 is a documented
interface so Philip is very very very
good at always making sure to use that
rather than a subnet that might be live
somewhere so anytime you actually do any
documentation the presentation please
also use a 2001 db8 /
two quick quick question regarding
statics 4v4 i use a null hold down route
for my allocation and that just is the
way i'm used to configuring bgp to
announce that large hold on do you need
to do the same as V 6 i'm assuming you
do question in in junos landed it works
in cisco lid i believe the same is true
but i'm going to validate so anybody
yeah a six they're using null hold down
alt yeah so sure it translates
so
alright
the features not quite there yet all the
all the examples you see here when I did
the junos examples it was on an m series
router and back then I think it might
have been Geno's 76 or something like
that ok for static routing this is the
command for the iOS XR router so
basically have router static address
family ipv6 unicast and then you set
your your next hop so this example again
it shows advanced packets for the
network 2001 DB 864 to a networking
device that 2008 deviate I mean 2001 DB
80 CC 0 0 1 with an administrative
distance of 110 and here's the junos
example the first thing that's
interesting is where it goes in the
configuration hierarchy routing options
rib inet6 because it goes on the inet 6
a fib
and beyond that you'll see it looks
pretty much like an ipv4 route except
for the fact that it has ipv6 prefixes
in it
and here's an actual example
in fact it's the exact same example we
just saw in iOS land yeah so of course
you can also set a default route so in
this particular example right you have
the ipv6 unicast routing ipv6 addresses
underneath both ISA Ethernet 0 Ethernet
one interfaces and then the ipv6 route
colon colon slash 0 the colon colon
slash 0 is all zeros which is the
default route and then you would enter
the address of the router to ethernet 0
interface because that's the exit
interface which would give the default
route to route or two so you can already
see that actually doing static routing
is an almost a configuration nightmare
right because you actually have to know
the next hop ipv6 address so anything
that I've configured it know that you
would probably want to avoid it as much
as possible and here's a similar command
for XR I mean nothing really unusual
interesting here and in the world of
junos it's pretty much good of and in
the world of junos you pretty much would
have guessed what this configuration
looked like from looking at the previous
slide
yeah so for the most part I mean dynamic
routing in v6 is really not that
different from before I mean sometimes
there are slight configuration nuances
because i know from cisco like the
parser police i guess was asleep or just
non-existent so but basically how it
works it is very very similar so ipv6
also has two types of routing protocol
internal or external ipv6 still uses the
longest prefix match routing algorithm
so for I GPS you have either a rip which
I don't think a lot of ISPs would even
use you have Cisco eigrp on obvious
reasons your neighbor doesn't support it
we have ospfv3 and integrated is is for
eg peb sorry EGP exterior gateway
protocols you have the multi protocol
bgp for so basically that that's
multi-protocol for both ipv4 and ipv6
basically what we're saying here is that
you have the same tools in v6 that you
have in v4 sometimes you had to hit
those tools with a hammer a little bit
to make them work in v6 but the same
thing I just want to point out you can
also use our DGP for the igp to carry v6
routes as well right yeah so bgp can be
an internal or an external gateway
protocol so thanks for pointing that out
i'll send a note to philip
so if you're configuring the routing
protocols for iOS the dynamic routing
protocols all require router ID the
router ID is a 32-bit integer and
sometimes people get a little confused
because sometimes it kind of looks like
an ipv4 address that's not what it is
iOS order generates these from the
loopback interface address if it is
configured else the highest ipv4 address
of the router becomes the router ID most
isp's will deploy ipv6 in dual stack I
don't think I've seen any yet that only
have ipv6 so the router ID will actually
be automatically created you know from
your ipv4 configuration early adopters
choosing to deploy ipv6 in the total
absence of any ipv4 addressing need to
be aware that the router ID needs to be
manually configured and so for example
under ospf we have ipv6 router ospf
autonomous system 100 the router ID is
10 dot one dot one dot 4 so again if
you're in a dual stack environment then
from your ipv4 configuration the router
ID will automatically already be created
but if you're doing ipv6 only then you
actually need to specifically um specify
what the router ideas now I have a
question here and by experience as an
operator I know that the router ID can
be automatically generated but can also
be specified in the config too and I
just don't like to put it in the config
for fear of what would happen if one day
had changed somebody put a new highest
address on I didn't really want to test
the routers behavior to see if it would
change the router ID or not that's a
good point i'll just put put something
that i know would stay still that's a
good point so some people might actually
want to do that so that there can be
assured that if there's an interface
change or you know
that the router ID won't actually change
okay sorry so for ipv4 routing protocols
the XR order generates the router ID as
the following as per the IRS rules
actually but BGP requires the router I
need to be manually configured so the
command would be router bgp 2.4 and then
set the router ID ospfv3 requires the
router ID to also be manually configured
so about ospfv3 and then configure the
actual voter ID so that actually speaks
to exactly what you were saying and so
with the XR it doesn't get automatically
generated but rather an operator has to
say what it is dude do you know same
thing you can either let the router
generate the router ID or specify it
explicitly recommend specifying it
explicitly
so rip next generation basically for any
eyes peas as Philip says and I totally
agree don't go here isps really don't
use rip in any form unless there's
absolutely no alternative possibly maybe
to a customer site how many of you do
use rib at all to a customer site and
think so so we'll just skip that so
eigrp 5pb six Cisco of course why would
he why would they not add ipv6 right to
eigrp just has a couple of new TL v's
router routing ID is still outside the
router ID is still the 32-bit protocol
still 88 so that didn't change similar
CLI to the ipv4 I guess it started in 12
dot 4 not an iOS XR yet so so some
differences and i will do a caveat i've
actually never configured eigrp for ipv6
i'm just done infos PF is is MV GP but
hellos a source from the link local
addresses and destined to FF 0 2 colon
colon a which is actually the multicast
group for all AIG FP routers so this
means that the neighbors don't have to
share the same goal prefex okay except
with the exception of explicitly
specified neighbors where the traffic is
actually unicast automatic summarization
is disabled by default for ipv6 so
that's a difference from ipv4 where it's
actually automatic summarization is
enabled so if you want auto
summarization you will have to enable it
for ipv6 and there's no split horizon in
the case of eigrp for ipv6 because ipv6
supports multiple multiple prefixes
interface so again that's different than
IP before so here's actually a
configuration looks very much like ipv4
where you have just the router eigrp so
enable the eigrp writing process and
under the interface you know enable your
ipv6 address say ipv6 enable and then
put down that that interface actually
participates in the eigrp process so
exactly the same as before if you do a
show ipv6 eigrp neighbor basically the
neighbors identified by the link local
address right so the fe e ad colon colon
interface ID and and you'll see that to
the right on the bottom also or in the
middle you can also see the router ID
which is a 32-bit integer
okay ospf needed to be changed a little
bit to accommodate ospf needed to be
changed a little bit to accommodate ipv6
the problem is there are ipv4 packets
embedded in the OSP v2 protocol and just
needed to fix those packet length issues
so there's a whole new protocol ospfv3
which looks surprisingly like ospfv3 to
its presently like ospf v2 in these ways
it's ospf for v6 it's based on v2 with a
few enhancements obviously it
distributes v6 prefixes it runs directly
over v6 the same way v2 runs directly
over before and it ships in the night
with v2 if you have both address
families activated on an interface
you're likely to have both v2 and v3
running and they won't interact with
each other the protocols are very
similar they have the base the same
basic packet types hello database
distribution link state advertisements
all that good stuff the same mechanisms
for neighbor discovery and adjacency
information same interface types same
LSA flooding and aging nearly identical
lsas
a few significant differences ospfv3
runs on a link instead of on a per IP
subnet work do we need to delve into
this at all or just believes that it
turn it on it works if you didn't
understand that that point you would be
able to use the protocol just as well as
if you did
now let's say there's quite a few here
so we probably should run through these
a little bit do you want to sure as well
we run 48 yeah so basically ospf three
runs on a link and server IP subnet in
ipv6 multiple IP subnets can be assigned
to a link and two nodes and different
subnet can actually communicate at a
link layer and therefore SPF is running
/ link and sort of pure IP subnet ok an
interface connected to a link of
multiple interfaces can be connected to
a link but anyway the more interesting
things to me actually that you can have
multiple support of multiple instances /
link so you can actually have multiple
OSPF instances running on a link the
instance ID should match before packet
being accepted and it's useful for
traffic separation to have multiple
areas / link there's also an address
semantic change in the link state
advertisements so the router and network
link state advertisement carry only
topology information the router link
state advertisement can be split across
multiple link state advertisements so
link state ID in the link state
advertisement header is a fragment ID
right if you know if you remember that
for ipv6 you've got a whole bunch of
extension headers and so one of them is
a fragmentation pattern the intro area
prefixes are carried in a new link state
advertisement payload called in Terraria
prefix lsas and the prefixes are carried
in payload of inter area and external
LSA
there's also generalization of flooding
scope so in ospfv3 there are three
flooding scopes the link local scope
area scope and autonomous system scope
and they are coded into the LS type
explicitly in ospf v2 initially only
area and autonomous system wide flooding
were defined there's also a difference
in terms of how unknown LSAs are handled
so the handling of L essays is coded
here the youbut in LS type when the you
betta set pls a is flooded with the
corresponding flooding scope when the
you bet is clear the LSA is flooded with
linked local scope and in b2 and any
unknown I'll links they'd advertisements
were discarded so there is actually
different differentiation between
behavior and v2 and v3 um the other oh
sorry no good that's actually the
security 12 letting you go fit yeah so
this is near and dear to my heart
because I always thought this is kind of
really interesting so authentication is
removed from ospf and it was removed
because i was PF relies on the ipv6
authentication header since i was PF
runs over ipv6 right and the
authentication errors part of the IPSec
protocol now what I've really found
fascinating is that when ospfv3 was
first created the assumption was that
all ipv6 traffic would be protected
using IPSec and since you don't need
encryption well you just need integrity
protection well of course you would
implement a H which is the
authentication header but as the IETF
began to be more explicit about how you
actually use IPSec in the actual
standard that was defined ESP null which
is using ESP the
does encryption but using null
encryption no more sand is actually what
must be implemented in H is a may so to
me it's it's kind of funny because most
vendors you know then shipping ospfv3
which is I don't know for at least six
seven maybe even eight years all i'll
use the ahc authentication header so to
me it's been kind of interesting you
know whether or not people are going to
start using ESP know and how do you
actually configure it because it's kind
of a nightmare
and
this is kind of a almost an
inconsequential change the ospf packet
formats been changed math fields removed
from the low packet ipv6 present
addresses a presence in the payload
there's also two new link-state happen
what what's the acronym stand for no
link state advertisement yeah okay so
does yeah so two new link state
advertisements have been introduced so
the link LSA has a link local flooding
scope and has three purposes one is it
provides the router link local address
another one at this Saul ipv6 prefix is
attached to the link and also thirdly it
asserts the collection of option bits
for the router links that advertisement
the second one there's an intra area
prefix linked site advertisement to
advertise the routers ipv6 address
within the area finally what you've been
waiting for how do we turn it on it very
similar to ospf v2 in the cisco routers
basically you just prefix any existing
command with ipv6 and with the info
interfaces that are directly configured
you just replace the network command and
basically the native ipv6 router mode
it's not a sub mode of router ospf so
the next should be yeah so here is
actually entering the router mode you
say ipv6 router ospf process i key and
then configure the area under the
interface so ipv6 ospf process ID what
area belongs to and then in exec mode
you can do either show ipv6 ospf process
ID that will show you the information or
do clear ipv6 ospf process ID
so there's some specific ospfv3
attributes so configuring an area of
range and you do that with the area
enter the area ID the range and then the
prefix and prefix length showing the new
link state advertisements you do a show
ipv6 ospf process ID and either database
link or database prefix and then you
configure out on occasion by just saying
authentication ipsec spi 256 md5
password so this is basically what a
configuration would look like I don't
really have any comments under this
looks very much like ospf be to do a
show ipv6 route you see that you know
this is what the ospf would look like
you could also do ospfv3 and do ipv6
tunnels over ipv4 so how you would set
that up is you would create an interface
tunnel on each router no IP address or
no ipv4 ipv6 address just enable that
create an ipv6 link local address
specify the router ospf area 0 and then
create a tunnel source and destination
with your ipv4 addresses and the tunnel
mode ipv6 and ipv6 router ospf 1 and
then do a similar command on router to
to actually you know have it be the
other endpoint tunnel endpoint in these
commands here how you actually configure
I was pfn on the X our router you have
your comment quick operational question
for anyone here I use ipv4 anycast for
my core DNS servers so I have multiples
of them in different regions of the u.s.
right now I implement that with quagga
using ospf to advertise its last 32 to
my upstream routers using an ospf not so
stubby area has anybody done that sort
of thing with v6 and os exactly the same
awesome thank you yes
and
we're like the last the last bid is the
port number or something sure cool
that's really good idea yeah thanks for
that I mean my observation also has been
that from the routing pieces I mean
there's really very little that's
different from ipv4 ipv6 there are some
nuances right and as we just went
through also with ospf two and three I
mean there's some enhancements if you
will that we're done with ospfv3 but if
you look at actually how you configure
it but there's really not that much
difference I'm not going to go over the
XR okay yeah so for the XR these are
just configuration examples i'm not
going to go through them in detail okay
and now it's time to do it in junos land
that stands at protocols which should
look vaguely familiar to you it's
exactly the same configuration that we
would use in ospf be to accept we say
ospf three and we're done show ospf
three is the equivalent of show ospf and
you have all the same options database
interface I of statistics clear ospf
three exactly the same as clear ospf
um
and what's a
no differences from iOS I guess the
issue that medica talked about with the
authentication header we also have
actually do I see the carp chair hiding
in the back here how is the carp chair
disposed towards ospfv3 in
authentication okay thank you Ron for
those of you who don't know me I'm Joel
Halpern and we've recently charted over
the IETF a working group specifically to
work on refining the pragmatics of the
security in routing protocols it's
called carb keying and authentication
for routing protocols we know that most
of you have implementations which
support this they've just been talking
about the authentication support and
that most people either don't bother
turning it on or never change the keys
and security that you turn on and never
change the keys you might as well not
have turned it on so we're trying to
address a number of known issues and one
of them is should we replace the aah
with a specification to use the SP null
or something else it's we're going to go
through the threats to all of the
routing protocols that are in use and
ospfv3 is one of them but in general we
need participation from our operators
about what you guys are seeing as the
real problems with using security
because if we don't fix it so you can
use it we've wasted our time thank you
for that and you know I'll just add to
that too there's also an operational
security working group in the ITF and I
know that there is a draft in there that
actually talks about all the cryptic all
the kind of security issues within
routing protocols and I can't remember
offhand what it's called but if you
actually go to the IETF
less than look at the operational
security working group one of the drafts
right now is one that talks about issues
with routing protocols and even some of
the crypto i'll post links to the two
charters Karpin op sack on the nanog
last night okay here's the identical
configuration example for our two
routers ospf neighboring with each other
and it should look vaguely familiar
and it's probably not a whole lot to
speak to hear either it's should look
vaguely familiar here's a look at what
v6 routes look like on the routing table
the same show commands Shore out and the
exact same tunneling person tunneling
into the situation that we had a few
slides back we can recreate here but
there is one thing that I should point
out depending on the platform you're
using you may or may not need an
application services picked to support
tunnels so if you're oh say on a m4 te
you're going to need the ASP other other
platforms might not need it and I won't
step through the configuration but if
you're doing something like this you can
use this as a template mount Isis
service
is there's always a trade-off between a
processing intense service and
scalability if you want the processing
intensive service to scale you need that
piece of extra e piece of iron to make
it work okay okay so I esaias mostly
right people when they run their
internal gateway protocol with an ISP
something the choices usually ospf for
is is and typically it's more you know
what are you more familiar with with is
is the ISO 10 589 standard specifies OSI
is is routing protocol for cl NS traffic
there's tlv options to enhance the
protocol I call them type length value
on of tags the right word a link-state
protocol with two level of our coca-cola
architecture RFC 1195 added IP support
so is is runs on top of the day a link
layer it also requires CL N and P to be
configured RFC 5308 added ipv6 address
family support to is is and RFC 5120
defines multi topology concept for is is
one on nice point about is is is that
you only have to run one protocol
instance for actually to have IP v4 and
ipv6 running so you don't have to have
two instances of the routing protocol
like you do with ospf so is is for ipv6
you have to tag length values attitude
to do this ipv6 routing you have the
ipv6 reach ability tlv external bit
equivalent to the IP
to external reach ability T lbs and you
also have the ipv6 interface address
type length value for hello pdus must
contain the link local address for LSP
must only contain the lawn link local
address the ipv6 NLP ID is advertised by
ipv6 enabled routers here's actually a
configuration example for cisco iOS so
for router one you have interface
ethernet one have an ipv4 address and
ipv6 address specify both for IP which
is ipv4 by default and then ipv6 that
wants to participate in router is is do
the same for Ethan a two and then for
router is at I mean for the actual
routing configure router is is
address-family ipv6 here he wants to
redistribute static and then you
configure an exit adverse family and
redistribute static for ipv4
you can also configure is ours for ipv6
by doing an ipv6 tunnel over ipv4 same
same basic configuration applies us for
ospf where you just define an ipv6
global address a link-local address
specify that you want to run router is
is and then have a tunnel source and
destination be the ipv4 addresses and
this year is just configuration commands
if you're going to do is is on the X our
router
okay here's the juniper equivalent
configuration you'll notice that what we
have an interface that is configured
with family inet so it can have an IV
for address-family iso and family inet6
then we turn on protocols again
redistribute statics and put all those
interfaces and dices and we have some
policy options let's say that we will
accept anything from static
again the same tunneling that we could
do with ospf we can do with Isis and in
case anybody's doing that sort of thing
they can use this as a reference anybody
interested in multi topology I esaias
extensions anybody using is is one
anybody using multi topology stuff okay
skip over multi topology yeah I think
the only point that we should make on
the multi topology is is is that there
might be an assumption initially that
you have the same topology for ipv6 as
you do in ipv4 but if you don't if you
actually have a different apology for
your ipv6 and is is that's why this
multi topology extension was actually
created so okay we're coming down the
home stretch with bgp i think this is
the last Road routing protocol will talk
about RFC 4760 defines multi-protocol
extensions for bgp for so BTW people
working move around any kind of address
family in the world RFC 2545 uses bgp
multi-protocol extensions for ipv6 so
those are the two relevant RFC's
we have new optional and non transitive
bgp attributes now was that mean
optional and non transitive optional
means that every bgp implementation
doesn't need to understand it non
transitive means just because you got it
you will not pass it on transitive would
mean that you would pass it on the two
new attributes are multi-protocol reach
nlr I and multi-protocol unreachable in
nlr I these attributes contain one or
more triples of AFI what family is this
to address is a v4 v6 mpls v4 VPN v6 VPN
whatever next hop must be the same
address family and the nlr I
RFC 2545 gives you some v6 specific
extensions scoped addresses next top
contains a global ipv6 address or
potentially a link-local address next
hop in l and l RI are expressed as ipv6
address in prefix and afi equals 2
see bgp considerations
oh okay rules for constructing the next
top attribute when two peers share a
common subnet the next hop information
is formed by a global address and a
linked local local address redirects and
ipv6 are restricted to the usage of link
local addresses
and having written the slide myself I
can't remember what the heck I was
saying uh-huh sooo you're in the room
someplace now can you help us out with
this okay in NV 6 land are there any
particular rules about choosing the next
hop it's just the v6 loopback address of
the egress gateway yeah I think one of
the problems is that in the in for using
redirects right i mean you're restricted
to using the link local address so it's
not the global unique address okay you
know I'm a very pragmatic ITF person so
let me be a little bit more pragmatic
here reason we went to both is because
people ended up with some errors if they
had one or the other now an intelligent
life form which I'm sure includes all of
you may be able to make either one work
and I I that's probably the best way to
give why we have both that if you don't
have both there are cases where you can
hang yourself most intelligent
configurations don't hang themselves is
that otherwise i can get down into the
nerd weenie moments but I didn't think
okay thank you I mean do if you want me
to go to the Wonder weenie moments I
will but otherwise i'll just be
preventing it sorry to put you on this
now and here's a difference with ipv4
right with IP before you look at the
next top you get an IP address right
with ipv6 the next hop is either your
global a unique address or also your
link local address and I think that can
be a point of confusion to some people
yes if I've got everything there k yes
I think I'll let it go I mean I yes
there's a one exception but we'll take
that offline and I'm I if there are
questions I'm glad to answer but I'm
also cognizant of getting we've gone
into the weeds on this four times
because people have had problems and
again most of the problems occur with
non-standard topologies in an exchange
point or three hops into the XJ having
exchanges that go across perhaps layer
to transparent stuff so if we want to go
on with that I can but otherwise yes
okay i think the point is really though
that you know with ipv6 you do have to
be aware that you know every interface
does have a link local address and then
you know it's up to you to actually
configure a also a globally unique
identifier and when you're looking at
bgp right as a slide here says when you
have two pairs on the same subnet your
next hop information is formed by using
either right I mean it's either the
globally unique identifier but also that
link local so when you're actually
starting to you know configure bgp and
you're looking at your BGP routing
tables I mean you know don't don't be
too confused with the fact that your pub
I see both right to be safe you need
both the Japanese have successfully
proved you can do link local if you're
careful but in all of this for tutorial
please use both you probably won't shoot
yourself if you want to go to singly
linked local come talk to people who
done it so you don't shoot yourself in
the foot
that's fun too okay
and the slide is
fairly self-explanatory there's one rib
per protocol ipv6 has its own bgp table
you'll see that in the show commands
can this again addresses what we're just
saying before that the next hop contains
a global ipv6 address or potentially a
link-local address and the link local
addresses as a next hop is only said if
the bgp peer shares the subnet with both
routers okay interaction with TCP is
same as wouldn't be for bgp runs over
tcp this connection could be set up over
v4 or v6 bgp doesn't know one way or
another router IDs when no router ID is
configured an explicit bgp router ID
needs to be configured generally good
practice to configure it anyway the bgp
identifier is a 32-bit integer currently
generated from the router ID this is
needed as a bgp identifier it's used in
the open message and in tiebreakers for
bgp best path ok
oh here we go again there are two
options for configuring bgp peering one
is to use link local addressing do this
only if you like staying awake late at
night and debugging others to use global
unicast addressing which is what you
would have done in v4 do this if you
like going home to see your family yeah
and I think you know I mean since you
know I'm doing this as a replacement to
Philip I can only guess that the reason
that you know these slides are in here
and talking about the same thing in
multiple forms is because it will really
bite you at some point and so basically
it is not recommended to use the link
local addressing right and I mean the
recommendation to actually set your next
hop is to use global unicast addressing
I think it will just make life a lot
simpler
ok so in iOS routers basically it and I
always did by default assumes that all
the BGP neighbors will also be ipv4
unicast neighbors so you have to remove
this assumption and how you do this you
enter the router bgp AS number no bgp
default ipv4 dash unicast and if you do
not do this this will result in all
neighbors being defined as ipv4 unicast
neighbors it's not necessarily a good
thing because non ipv4 neighbors will
have no specific unicast ipv4
configuration and it just ends up in
cluttered configurations so to actually
create BGP peering and I iOS router a
under router bgp one router bgp tunnel
system number you say no bgp default
ipv4 unicast and then what the neighbor
is and here as a good citizen of course
he's using the global global ipv6
address and then remote autonomous
system too and then address family ipv6
neighbor the neighbor address activate
and then which network you want to
advertise which is the 2001 DBA 2 / 48
so you do not want to do link-local
peering again we're beating this fourth
to death some more they use global
addressing so I gotta send Phillip a
note how many different ways can you say
the same thing wow we can show the
picture of rocky yeah so and this is
just a configuration snippet for iOS XR
and I haven't configured an XR but I
guess you know the real important point
here is that you need inbound and
outbound route policy because the iOS XR
does not announce or accept prefixes
without any policy which is really
really nice here's the junos
configuration again we start out by
configuring an interface that is v6
capable we configure a static route that
we're going to distribute we configure a
routing router ID and we turn on
protocols bgp it doesn't know if it's
you know BGP trucking around v4 or v6
the local a s is one then we have a
group of neighbors that we call a s2 we
have a export policy for it export but
we we have an export policy for exploit
static you'll see that in a little bit
it will be a s number 2 and the neighbor
has an address 2001 DBA blah blah blah
up above we talked about what the export
policy was so here we have to actually
say what it is policy options policy
statement exports static term one from
protocol static then accept everything
else rejected this looks an awful lot
like just plain old BGP configuration
okay this particular example next couple
of slides are basically comparing the
prefix lists and filters for ipv4 and
ipv6 and what you will notice that the
ipv4 prefix filters and the ipv6 prefix
filters are exactly the same with the
exception that you have the ipv6 you
know keyword rather than IP and of
course you either permitting or denying
ipv6 addresses and there's also a
configuration sample for ipv4 and ipv6
on iOS XR 41 106
yeah you'll have these slides I mean w
up on the mailing list and with the iOS
XR you'll just note that the parade was
family configuration / neighbor and the
prefect sets are similar to iOS prefix
lists but there's no distinction between
ipv4 and ipv6
and here we've done the exact same thing
with junos we have a dual stack enabled
interface fe 300 we have a rib inet6 we
also have inet 0 which is there by
default we've given it a router ID we've
turned on bgp and we have two groups of
neighbors one group of neighbors in a
s20 another naas 30 and we have some
policy for each yeah this next slide
actually just shows the fact that you
can also do a route map and set local
preference to be something that you
yourself defined right and it's exactly
the same as you would do for ipv4 so
under the adverse family ipv6 right you
set a route map from ASM to in and then
you create the route map from a is to
permit 10 and then set local preference
to 120
here's a similar configuration for iOS
XR
but really manipulating any kind of
attributes in BGP the commands are
almost identical in ipv6 as they are 5p
before in iOS and iOS XR
and you guys probably getting tired of
hearing is say this is how you do it
this is how you do it in junos but here
again is the identical configuration in
junos and in this case the attributes
were manipulating our local preference
and you see them in the policy okay you
can also carry ipv4 inside ipv6 peering
and so for the iOS for the example what
you do under address-family ipv4 you
basically define a route map ipv4 in and
the route map would set the IP next hop
to be your ipv4 address so there's
another example for the X our router
and it's kind of the same thing in junos
bgp is you know rides over IP whatever
that rides over TCP and the BGP payload
can actually carry any family of address
and it doesn't care if it's you know v6
of dress / v four or before address / v6
or some other quick kind of crazy
address / one or the other bgp status
commands for iOS i'll let you peruse
those at your leisure yeah i mean again
you'll see that really the only
difference from ipv4 to ipv6 is that you
use the keyword ipv6 like an IP before
you don't have to use anything you can
just say show bgp unicast parameter but
for v6 you have to actually say show bgp
ipv6 blah blah blah in junos there's a
display command one thing that's
interesting is it shows you each rib
individually line at 60 and at 62 and I
NAT 01 @ 0 strangely enough is for ipv4
and more junos summary commands
conclusion well I guess the conclusion
is if you are turning on v6 in your
network the configurations are actually
frightening Lee similar to the v4
configurations a little tweak here a
little tweak their use these as use
these as guidelines and maybe templates
to do your configuration operators have
gone through all the pain with IP with
bgp with ipv4 in BGP so they know what
kinds of things to to to worry about and
for the most part they're the same in d6
so jumping have fun yeah and so the only
comments that I want to make as a
conclusion is that if you're using ospf
i sighs bgp i would strongly recommend
that you actually do use authentication
of the peers for for either routing
protocols and part mostly that is well I
it's just so you don't shoot yourself in
the foot you know in case somebody makes
configuration errors for bgp it's more
important because it runs over tcp you
don't want somebody spurious lee sending
you tcp resets or anything like that
with is is remember that it's one
routing instance or before or v6 whereas
with ospf you have to run you know one
for v4 another one for v6 but as ron
also said i mean most of the
configuration commands are actually
pregnant Lee you know identical to
before which is a really nice thing I've
got a question about I'm just curious
you know with the ability to carry and
be
GP carry ipv4 routes and v6 I'm just
wondering okay two people typically
doing that or or you just typically
bringing up both v4 and v6 neighbors and
in my experience people have used bgp to
carry a single session to carry lots of
different kinds of routes vpm routes
ipv4 ipv6 the only reason I could think
of for wanting to run many instances is
if you have a lot of one kind of route
and not a lot of the other and you're
worried about what you're going to get
there first or who's going to converge
first or who's going to be a bottleneck
behind the other encanto made notes with
all the routing protocols if you're
putting a dual stack network you've got
machines or servers or services are dual
stack as well you really want to make
sure to keep you saying that your v4 and
your v6 configurations are as analogous
Lee simple sub as analysis a similar as
possible because you will run into very
nasty Diagnostics problems otherwise
I know that there were some of that do
that there are some not splitted on
multiple neighbors so that you know they
have concerns that want they have a lot
of this kind of route in just a few of
that kind and they don't want one
getting caught behind the other
yes at the case where that's completely
isolated network of course there are
different I'd like to reinforce what I'm
sorry less fellow is that the mic and
forget your name well Jake said you
really want your fee for in v6
configurations to be as analogous as
possible if you were in the habit of
using you know explicitly configured
router IDs in v4 to it and v6 to you
want as little to change as possible
because change is generally a bad thing
any other questions there's a time to
hit the bar okay yeah thanks for
attending thank you