my name is Baiju political and this is
my teammate Jeff riddle we both work for
the Cisco advanced services organization
and our department is mainly focused on
providing consultancy services to the
cable service providers in United States
as well as the overseas customers and
the today's topic for discussion is
video over topsis and I am assuming some
of you are already familiar with the
DOCSIS technology right which is used
for providing HST and void access over a
cable network so how many of you are
already familiar with the DOCSIS
technology at some level that's good
however for the sake of people who are
new to DOCSIS we will go through some
high-level coverage of the DOCSIS
technology as well before getting into
the details of video over DOCSIS we do
have a list of acronyms and
abbreviations listed here related to the
DOCSIS and video over DOCSIS which we
are going to cover however I am NOT
going to go over the list this is this
would be available for your future
reference if you are going through the
archived material here is the high-level
agenda for the session we would start
with a high-level introduction to the
Vidocq technology followed by looking at
the business drivers behind pursuing
this particular technology and we will
get on to the some of the aspects of
DOCSIS especially dogs history or
aspects which are relevant to the Vidocq
support in a DOCSIS network and PCM 'm
is again another technology related to
cable
broadband which will we will cover
because PC mm is going to be used as one
of the mechanisms to provide quality of
service for video over DOCSIS and video
over DOCSIS today have got two different
architectures one is called the CMPs
bypass architecture and the second one
is the CMPs direct architecture and we
would be covering both but the CMT has
direct architecture would be the one
which will go into the detail and we
will look at the aspects of scaling the
application in your DOCSIS network as
far as we dock is concerned and also we
will touch upon the telepresence of a
DOCSIS an enhanced version of the video
telephony and how we can implement that
by using the Vidocq technology
getting into the technology introduction
we dog stands for video overdoses and
ham as some of you are already familiar
there is a non-profit consortium of
cable service providers and the vendors
who come up with the cable products the
headend products as well as the customer
premises equipment called cable labs
kept the main objective of cable labs is
to come up with the standardization
efforts as far as the access technology
side is concerned today we do we do know
that typical service providers such as
Comcast or Time Warner offers over the
cable infrastructure not only the TV
channels and other video applications
like video on-demand but they offer
high-speed Internet access
and in most of the places even voice
over IP over cable as well and the
DOCSIS and the associated technologies
are developed to address the
standardization efforts and also to make
sure that there are options available
for the service providers to come up
with new service offering as a method
for additional revenue generation and
these new services as they get developed
are standardized so that multi-vendor
operability interoperability is assured
and as far as video our DOCSIS is
concerned I mentioned that DOCSIS is the
access technology in use in a cable
access network to provide high-speed
Internet access and voice over IP
however even though we have video
services offered by ours
EMA sauce the cable service providers
those video channels are today carried
outside the DOCSIS infrastructure they
are carried as MPEG streams over
dedicated comm channels in the
downstream direction and
objective of video over DOCSIS is to
converge the video services
aspect also into a DOCSIS infrastructure
so that you can provide triple play
services by using the same DOCSIS
infrastructure and the advantage is
going to be when you use IPTV instead of
streaming the mpeg-4 digital video
directly into the cable it gives you the
option to receive those IPTV channels
not only by using the traditional TV
however it can be received by personal
computers and other customer premises
devices as well and the key objective in
going with video over DOCSIS is
providing the quality of service for the
video applications as as I mentioned
when you integrate the video services
the IPTV also over a DOCSIS
infrastructure then you will have to
come up with some QoS mechanisms so that
when the providers start offering the
video services over cable infrastructure
using DOCSIS then there is some service
differentiation available based upon the
type of service you pay for and we do
know that today there are a lot of
internet multimedia streaming
applications in place we call it
over-the-top video because the way it
works is even though those video streams
like when you access YouTube or watch
any video clips from the internet even
though those video streams are carried
over the DOCSIS network however there
are no mechanism available to it today
to provide the quality of service so the
Vidocq technology covers the QoS expect
aspects of the IPTV services over the
cable infrastructure
actually we are going to have a Q&A
session towards the end hopefully we
will have enough time for that
however if you come up with any
questions as we keep talking please
invectives and we will try to answer
that and as far as the Vidocq is
concerned it covers three aspects
video-on-demand obviously and the
broadcast video represents actually the
standard TV channels which will be
streamed as IPTV even though it says
broadcast video the multicast streaming
would be used for sending those
broadcast video in a V dot met work and
video telephony is another application
which we can implement using the Vidocq
architecture and like I said earlier it
provides QoS for video screens and it is
a method for the service providers to
provide managed video services over a
single infrastructure and as some of you
know video over demand is unicast and
with v-dog implementation also it is
going to stay the same and the broadcast
video or IPTV would be multicast now
getting onto the key technology drivers
I mentioned earlier that the doxa
standardization efforts from the cable
labs have been towards coming up with
standard set of specifications which can
be used by these service providers as
well as the vendors in developing the
new products and implemented
implementing the services and DOCSIS
itself has got different versions it's
initially started with DOCSIS mono which
was focused mainly on high-speed data
then we have had dogs s11 and docks is
one one the main advantage was the
enhancements made in one one over one
over ssin was the enhanced quality of
service especially to support
applications
like voice-over-ip over cable and the
latest version of the docs is what we
have today today is dog hysteria and
there are several enhancements made in
dog history or version compared to
previous versions of the dog sees and
the key improvements are the provision
to support much higher bandwidth in the
downstream and upstream direction when
we talk about a DOCSIS access network it
is not a simple straightforward
bi-directional network right because it
uses the RF channels so there are
separate set of RF channels used for
streaming traffic into the downstream
direction to watch the cable modem at
home and for sending traffic in the
upstream direction using separate set of
channels and in order to increase the
available speed for this downstream and
upstream channels DOCSIS has introduced
something called a channel bonding the
concept of channel bonding and with the
introduction of channel bonding the
operators can today offer services as
high as 100 Mbps by direction for a
particular subscriber as opposed to 10
or 15 make what you see today so what it
brings in when you have the option to
provide 100 Meg service obviously it
gives you the room to start offering
additional services if this provider
wants to incorporate the IPTV also over
the same infrastructure then the
available additional band it can be used
to start offering the streaming of the
IPTV services and video on demand
services over the same infrastructure
and again when you integrate IPTV also
on the DOCSIS infrastructure then you
end up having a single infrastructure
for carrying voice high-speed data as
well as video thereby eventually
resulting in capex and OPEX reductions
on this service service provider side
any questions so far on the technology
drivers now let's start looking at the
DOCSIS technology at a high level
DOCSIS stand for that data over cable
service interface specification like I
mentioned earlier briefly it is a set of
standards introduced by the cable labs
in order to make sure that there is
vendor interoperability when the vendors
come up with different products which
support the DOCSIS infrastructure for
HSD and voice and other services this
diagram shows a very high-level overview
of how a DOCSIS based network looks like
what you have here is on the service
provider side you do have an aggregation
device which is the cmts
or cable modem termination system and
cmts is the system on which the
individual subscriber promises side
cable modems would get terminated to and
the media between the cable modem at the
customer premises side and the cmts is
called something called a hybrid fiber
coaxial Network
the reason being we don't know that from
the cmts the file a transmission media
is used out of channels fired however
the actual plant in implementation for a
cable network typically uses the fiber
as well and what happens is for long
hauls at the head end side we call the
service providers facility were the cmts
resides typically as a head end and at
the head end side you have the cmts and
the outputs coming out in the downstream
direction
our of channels in the physical media
and the upstream also is received in the
art of channel as RF signal however in
between in order to support long-haul
networks they introduce something called
a hybrid fiber coaxial Network this East
/ o and o / see what you see is
electrical to optical conversion and the
optical inner electrical conversion so
eventually when it gets closer to the
home it is converted back to electrical
over the cable ends received by the
cable modem and obviously you need to
have servers also servers in the back
end to support the provisioning and
other aspects of the cable modem support
to let them start using the services
as you can see the cmts is one of the
key components in a DOCSIS network which
is the aggregation device to which all
the individual subscriber cable modems
get terminated and there are two types
of CMT SS today and this is especially
defined with Dobbs trio along with the
DOCSIS through your architecture and the
docks is three or can be implemented by
using something called and integrated
CMPs
were all the logical functions which a
cmts needs to be performed will be able
recite in a single physical entity and
then we do have something called model
of CMT as as well and in the case of
integrated cmts we don't know that for
the access network you need to handle
the physical layer aspects of
transmission as well as the ring layer
of aspects of the transmission right
logical link layer aspects on media
access control layer this physical layer
and the logical link layer for DOCSIS
mac and DOCSIS downstream phi and
upstream phi are defined in the docks
respect and on top of that then you have
the layer 3 at a traffic ride the IP and
upper layers and the function of a cmts
is to handle the DOCSIS mac layer which
is the datalink layer for DOCSIS
processing and the Phi layer for
downstream and upstream and if you have
the layer 2 as well as the layer 1
components residing in the same cmts
then it is called an integrated cmts and
as you know the cmts
is the aggregation device which
interconnects the wide area network side
of the service provider and also on the
right side as you can see it is
interfacing with the typical cable plant
this block diagram shows the modular
cmts architecture what has been done
here is we have seen that in the
previous slide all the different logical
entities for a cmts was residing in a
single system now with the modular CMPs
architecture as you can see the layer 2
processing for DOCSIS still results in
the MCM TS called
and so is the upstream physical layer
components however for the downstream
physical layer components for screaming
write the file air streams in the
downstream direction it has been taken
out into an external entity called an
edge swamp
and these edge Kwan's actually have
bender in the cable service provider
networks for quite some time there used
to be traditionally used for streaming
video the MPEG video into the cable plan
and with the introduction of docks
history or the same equation support
today drops this traffic as well as the
the video streams and when you take out
the five layer aspects of the downstream
you don't know that there should be some
timing control entity available to make
sure that there is timing
synchronization established between
different components of MCM PS DOCSIS
timing server is the the entity which
provides centralized timing information
to the MCM TS core as well as the h-bomb
or an other relevant components which
form part of an MCM TS or modular cmts
logical architecture and the reason why
if the docks is timing server is
precarious as some of you know the
timing is extremely important in the
case of a DOCSIS network because in the
upstream direction it uses a combination
of TDMA and FDMA technology and you have
the option to have multiple Siam's
trying to transmit at the same direct
same time in the upstream direction
and there should be strict timing
relationship established at the time of
initialization of a cable modem so that
the every time a cable modems wants to
pass within the upstream direction so it
is in sync and it is transmitting at any
allocated time which has been provided
by the CMPs and when it is IC MTS
because of the fact that the downstream
phi of spring phi and logic data link
layer results in the same box you do not
need an external external timing entity
to take care of it because the
centralized timing of the single system
can handle that
however with the MCM TS we have to have
an external timing server and these are
some of the components which we have
already seen in the previous slide the
edge qualm which i already covered not
only can take care of the DOCSIS traffic
but it was traditionally carrying the
MPEG video streams also what we get
today as the TV channels at homes and
MCM TS core is the one which hand is the
dialing layer functions for the DOCSIS
network as well as the upstream file and
moving forward it is even possible to
lis couple the upstream v physical layer
aspects also from the MCM TS core and
have it be said in an external entity to
support model implementation H Resource
Manager is not quite relevant with our
discussions today however just to touch
upon that what it does is when you are
using external resources from any qualms
for downstream transmission you have two
options to associate the corresponding
logic and the Mac layer from the MCM TS
core for the specific downstream channel
to the EECOM you can either do it
statically or you have a mechanism word
if you have something called an edge
resource manager
the original H resource manager can be
used to be decentralized authority to
assign the comm resources so that the
comm resources will be more efficiently
used beta based upon the different CNTs
requirement the if a MTS for example
wants to have additional bandwidth
available for a particular application
then it can ask for it an additional
channel from the quam and the way it
accomplishes that is by using the edge
resource manager
getting onto the details of the docs
history or the latest set of
specifications released I believe it
came out somewhere around 2006 timeframe
and a lot of major emesis are in the
process of deploying it and at least
there are some limited deployments
available out there and the main
motivation behind coming with Doc's
history or was to increase the available
channel capacity like I mentioned
earlier by going something called a the
concept of bonding the channels you can
provide much higher throughput to the
customer premises equipment and there
are several aspects of security which is
added into the doctors 3or to provide
enhanced security on the access network
and ipv6 is another another support
which is introduced with Doc's history
or prior to Doc's history or ipv6 was
not supported by cable access networks
but a cable access network which is
implemented using Doc's history of
supports ipv6 - and as you know emma
sauce are today facing the address
depletion at various levels and it
really helps them in going with
expandability of addressing with ipv6
and it allows the deployment of new
service offerings because what we are
trying to accomplish with Doc's is 3 or
is by you know giving the option to have
additional channel bandwidth right by
going with something called channel
bonding and with that additional higher
bandwidth we would be able to offer new
services say for example the video over
DOCSIS which we are going to cover more
detail later on
now let's start looking at the concept
of channel bonding and in particular the
downstream channel bonding the objective
is to provide faster speeds to the
access network this slide actually talks
about why DOCSIS 300 is ideal for DVD or
over DOCSIS like I mentioned earlier
channel bonding provides higher fatter
pipes in the downstream direction so
that it gives you the option to start
offering additional services room for
carrying traffic corresponding to
additional services and multicast
enhancements when it comes to IPTV and
other video applications lot of the
applications are carried in multicast
and there are a lot of enhancements done
in the DOCSIS 302 facilitate that and
ipv6 when you move towards the concept
of assigning IP addresses to different
CP devices at the for a residential
customer or a business customer
obviously the scalability of the
addressing comes into picture and ipv6
definitely addresses that an end-of-day
you end up getting a converged network
which does carry not only a high-speed
data and voice but the video services
also over the same infrastructure now
getting into the details of downstream
channel bonding the concept is very
straightforward
prior to DOCSIS 300 we have had in the
downstream direction a single channel
the cable modems will always walk onto a
single downstream channel and that
single downstream channel always had the
bandwidth limitations depending upon
what kind of are of parameters you have
configured 64 comm or 256 calm or
whatever it is the maximum it was
receiving for us DOCSIS was around 37 38
MBP
available effective rate and with the
channel bonding what we are doing is we
are taking multiple physical RF channels
and combining them to form a single
logical bonding group and obviously the
overall available bandwidth for the
bonded channel is much higher it depends
upon how many physical RF channels you
have taken and combined together to form
a bonded channel right so you say for
example if you take 4 out of channels to
form a bonding group then the available
throughput for the morning group is 4
times more than a single channel can
provide and with the channel bonding
concept the cable modems are not tuning
into a single down stream it is tuning
into multiple physical RF channels and
4f is a specific traffic flow it can
receive the package corresponding to the
traffic law flow across all the channels
of the bonding group thereby giving it
you know much fat of fat or logical pipe
this is a pictorial representation of
how the channel bonding works and I
think it is good to just to mention
something called the concept of service
flaw in the DOCSIS world a service flow
is nothing but an entity which has been
provided with a set of QoS parameters
such as the maximum downstream rate or
upstream rate offered and then whether
what is the level of priority if there
is a minimum reserve rate what would be
the missing of minimum reserve rate and
things like that and the significance of
the service flow is the service flow
will be used to carry traffic in the
access network we have downstream
service flows for traffic towards the
cable modem and upstream service flows
for traffic to watch the cmts and what
traffic uses the service flow will be
decided by the set of classifiers one or
more packet classifiers you associated
with the service flow and priority
topsis 3 or always a service flow was
linked to a single channel but with
downstream channel bonding and upstream
channel bonding
a service flow can be linked to a
borning group what that means is the
packets corresponding to a service flow
you can send y:i a bonding group and
when you do that obviously comes the
question of packet resequencing right
because instead of a single channel you
are planning to send the packets
corresponding to a flow across multiple
channels then obviously at the receiving
side the packets will have to be
resequenced to make sure that out of
order delivery potential out of order
delivery has been taken care of
so in order to take care of this
resequencing if a service flow is using
a a bonding group the service flow
typically would be provided with
something called a downstream service
identifier and it's this you can sing
index so at the receiving side it can
use the downstream service identifier as
the V so you can sing index and then the
packet there is a packet sequence number
also provided in the docks header the
adaxes extended header so that at the
receiving side it can make use of the DC
to identify a specific flow and use the
packet sequence number field to reorder
the packets before sending it to the
customer promisor side and that is what
this picture real representation is
explaining here as you can see there are
three downstream physical channels d1 d2
and d3 forming a bonding group and
packets p1 p2 and p3 were part of a
single service flow and what the MTS did
was distributed that across the
individual channels of the bonding group
and when this on the CM side the cable
modem after receiving it has that the
way done the way sequencing and send the
packets out to the customer premises
side and let's take a look at how the
channel bonding can create high
efficiency gains so this is done by
using the high definition and
definition IPTV channels as an as an
example let's assume that we are using
four separate channels right not in
bonded board individually to carry
standard definition and High Definition
channels then in this example we can
accommodate a total of ten standard
definition channels and five high-damage
definition streams and each in each
channel has got some additional
bandwidth left out but because of the
fact that they are not in bonding mode
those leftover bandwidth is not enough
to accommodate another HD channel
however if you are going with a four
channel bonding group because of the
fact that for the same flow you can
slice it and send across multiple
channels forming the bonding group here
in addition to the ten standard
definition and high-definition screens
you get room for two additional HD HD
streams as well so the bottom line is if
it is unbounded it can always create
inefficient boundaries but with the
bonding the efficiency of the packing is
obviously improved like any other the
bonding concept
and this is an example which shows where
a single downstream bonding group is
used for per service area and what you
see here is service group represents the
set of all the channels available to a
specific serving area if there are n
number of modems which is part of a
serving area like a neighborhood then
every single modem has got the
visibility of all the channels which
form part of the service group not
necessarily every single modem needs to
be tuned into those channels and what
you see here is we do have a bonding
Group one created which is created to
provide services to the service Group
one right with a set of modems connected
to it and however this bonding group is
a hybrid bonding group which carries
high speed that our voice over IP and
IPTV so there is no separate bonding
group available so and all different
types of services the triple play
services are offered by a single bonding
group and likewise if the going to be
multiple service areas and in service
group in which is serving a different
service area you have a bonding group
and again carrying high-speed data voice
over IP and IPTV and some welcome points
as far as the DOCSIS to your channel
bonding is concerned as far as the cable
modems themselves are concerned they are
not quite aware of the number of bonding
groups say for example out of a set of
channels available to them all what the
CMT is going to inspect the cable modem
is to be providing them with a set of or
the set of channels which they have to
be tuned into the set of channels on
which they are tuning into might be part
of multiple bonding groups say for
example one bonding group might be
carrying only HST traffic and another
one might be carrying IP video traffic
but the cable modem doesn't have to
which bonding group has got which are
the channels corresponding to those
bonding groups because when the cable
modem has been instructed to tune in to
those channels of different bonding
groups if the cable modem has been
provided with the downstream service
identifier for the flows and linked with
the corresponding channels to so that it
can use the downstream service
identifier and the packet sequence
number to resequenced the packets
whatever it receives and again if you
have like n number of channels in a
service group doesn't mean that every
single modem in that service area is
going to end up using all the n channels
it could be like business subscribers
might be using a separate bonding group
compared to the residential subscribers
from the same set of n channels to
subsets we used to create different
bonding groups and in order for
providing the service differentiation if
there are multiple bonding groups
available in to a specific serving area
how the CMT has decides which bonding
group is going to be assigned to which
modem in which service law this can be
done by doing something called service
flow attribute I talked about the
service clause earlier right how a
service work it associated to a bonding
group can be controlled by defining
something called a service flow
attribute and when you have a service
flow attribute defined for a service
flow and then that service log will only
use the bonding group for which the same
attribute has been defined and there are
a little more detail into it how exactly
it does it like you can prevent a
service flaw from using a set of bonding
groups but allowed to use it another set
of bonding groups or other way around
and here is an example where you have as
dedicated bonding group available to
stream IP TV channels and another
bonding group which is carrying high
speed data and
again the cable modems if you look at
the cable modems they are tuned into all
the individual channels and they don't
have to be concerned about which set of
channel from which born in group because
they can as long as they have been
instructed to tune into those channels
and there have been provided with the D
seed and The Associated chance for the
decent they should be able to receive
and process the information accordingly
now getting on to multicast enhancements
any questions so far
let's take a quick look at some of the
multicast features introduced in
toxicity or especially those are
relevant to the video over Docs to
support source-specific multicast
especially with the support of IgM tv3
is a feature introduced with Dobson trio
and ipv6 multicast support ml d version
1 and version 2 has been defined in
Doc's s video and in addition to that
the multicast QRS has been standardized
how to provide QoS for the multicast
streams in the cable access network it
is part of the scale spec now and you
can do some kind of multicast or the
variation as well which is defined in
the spec and the multicast encryption is
another thing which has been
standardized because when this like
Cisco and other third-party vendors were
using some level of multicast encryption
but it was in standardized and today it
is standardized in toxis trio
and they keep any benefit of going with
docks three or multicast architecture is
the cable modems have become more
protocol agnostic because CEM doesn't
have to smooth the ICMP packets anymore
or MLD because the multicast join and
all the multicast signaling happens
directly between the CPEs behind the CM
and the cmts
this is accomplished through the DOCSIS
3 or multicast support what happens is
we already mentioned about the
downstream service ID right every single
multicast flow is associated with the
downstream service ID and it doesn't
matter whether the multicast flow is
using a single channel or a bonding
group if it is and DOCSIS 3 or multicast
mode every single modem would be using a
downstream channel ID and that
downstream channel ID I mean down
downstream service ID downstream service
ID can be used to tune into specific
multicast groups which the cable modem
will need to pass on to the CPE side so
the DC disused instead of using the GMAC
or the group MAC address in a pure
DOCSIS through your implementation if
the CMT is fine solved from an IgM P
joint which you've visited from the CPE
side that this particular CM will have
to receive this particular multicast
stream and forward it to the CPE side
what it will do is it can do something
like dynamic bonding change and provide
the set of channels on which that
multicast stream is available and also
the DC the downstream service identifier
corresponding to the multicast stream so
that the cable modem can tune in and
collect that multicast stream based upon
the DC and pass it on to the CPE side
where you have the IP setup box over
which ever wants to listen to that
multicast stream and this is called the
GMAC from East Coast operation because
it doesn't have to look at the group MAC
address but it is using the DC to filter
the right multicast means as far as the
cable modem is concerned however the
docks is 3 or
the provision for the GMAC explicit
filtering also for some of the hybrid
modems which doesn't fully support 300
if the DC filtering is implemented in
software for example GMAC explicit would
be the way to go and this is just a
picture representation of how it works
um when you have multiple multicast
streams but some modems some CPS would
like to listen to one of the other as
you can see here the DC one and DC two
represents two downstream channels which
has been combined to combine to form a
bonding group and there are two
multicast groups here both are so
specific s 1 comma G 1 and s 2 comma G 1
and those are represented on the access
side by downstream service identify as
DC 1 and DC 2 as you can see the CP
behind the first CM 1 is invested in the
first multicast stream so he just needs
to tune in and collect the flows coming
in by using the down state service
identifier they said 1 and the second CM
is tuned into only the downstream
service identified DC - even though both
streams are available in the bonding
group the CM doesn't have to receive and
pass it on to the CPE side now we will
take a high-level look at the PCM M
technology or packet cable multimedia
which is the reason why we are covering
it also is this would be one of the QoS
options which we will be using for video
over DOCSIS technology and the key thing
to highlight as far as the packet cable
multimedia is concerned is it is
something called signaling agnostic
because the end devices doesn't have to
be curacao aware the end client devices
and end application devices doesn't have
to be QoS aware and it kind of decouples
the applications from the QoS
work the PCM mqs framework can be used
to provide QoS in the DOCSIS access
network not only for voice but for any
multimedia applications or any
applications which you can like the
video games or interactive interactive
video or a video / telephony or whatever
kind of multimedia applications you can
use the same framework urs framework to
support it which is decoupled from the
actual application specifics as well and
that's the main advantage of the packet
cable multimedia and what you see here
is some of the kinds of application
listed which could make use of the
packet cable multimedia the framework
and support soft phones it can support
Residential's standalone empty is what
that means is when you have a multimedia
terminal adapter right behind a cable
modem to support voice it's a standalone
MTA and then it supports the gaming
consoles and business iadies and whatnot
and here what we see is a PCM M high
level architecture these are some of the
components of PCM um and what we see is
a decline side the client is not quite
aware of in this scenario the Cure's
signaling aspects all what the client is
doing is it is contacting an application
server which is doing the application
specific signaling for the client and
the application server in turn contacts
and Application Manager application
servers not necessarily need to be part
of the cable providers network it can be
an external service application service
or it could be part of the kms or
network - and there is an interface
defined between application server and
application manager using soap XML which
the application server will use to
provide the
service requests to the application
manager when the application manager
receives the service request the
application manager is the entity which
is going to do the authentication and
authorization of the client and if the
authentication and authorization of the
client succeeds if it is an exit
application say for example video
streaming what application manager is
going to do is it will send a policy
request to the policy server and the
policy server is the actual entity in
the network which implements the policy
and decides whether the QoS can be
enabled or not for the specific
application request and when the
application manager contacts the policy
server it can either provide all the
details of the QoS requirement for that
particular application including the
maximum rate it is requesting any kind
of rare minimum resort guarantees and
things like that or it could just
specify that ok this is like a voice
types of application or video
application and based upon that the
policy server would be able to come up
with the right set of QoS parameters
policy server not only does that policy
server does some kind of admission
control check - policy server needs to
make make sure that for this client
where whether he is allowed to have an
additional QoS
he might have exceeded the allowed
number of you know QoS
services supported and if all the check
is successful the policy server is going
to contact the cmts
and push the policies using the coughs
protocol so that the cmts if the
resources are available in the access
network will implement the implement the
corresponding QoS and does a dynamic
signaling mechanism to create a dynamic
service flow for that particular
application so that between the cable
modem and the CMT is the clients
application traffic will be using that
dynamic service flow created which has
been provided with the QoS
which was signaled by the policy server
as you can see the record-keeping server
here is mainly for the building purposes
and there are three different client
types are available with PCM um only the
client type one is relevant because that
is what is supported to a today client
type one means it is not aware of any
QoS signaling and it doesn't do an
explicit POS signaling
like I explained in the previous slide
it is done by the interaction of the
application manager and the policy
server and the cmts is the one which
initiates the QoS signaling and make
sure that the QoS
is established and the corresponding
service flow is in place with the right
keywords for the applicant application
application server they are takes care
of the aspects of the application
signaling control itself then we have
the application manager the client may
contact the application server or it
could potentially contact the
application manager directly and how the
client contacts the application manager
directly the signaling aspects are not
defined in PC mm likewise if the client
is contacting the application server the
signaling aspects are outside the scope
because what kind of signaling it is
going to use depend upon what
application it is going to be if it is
some telephony application it would be
using sip signaling if it is it has to
use some HTTP to get some content then
it will be using HTTP so it is entirely
outside the spec policy server I think
we already covered the aspects taken
care of by the policy server it does the
admission control mechanism make sure
that the client is authorized to make
use of the QoS requested and he hasn't
exceeded already by requesting hewers in
the in the past which is already active
and also locating the right cmts where
the client is located so that it can
push the policy down using the cops so
the policy server is the policy the
decision point and the cmts is the
policy enforcement point and like I said
the cmts typically gets pushed to be the
policy corresponding to a particular
application
and then it will do the signaling on the
access network side to initiate initiate
initiated dynamic service flow with
development QoS this is a particular
signaling flow and I don't think I have
to go through the all the details of
this signaling aspects discussed here
because we covered already some of it
during the previous slides basically
what it is showing is the client
contacting the application manager first
and then it triggering these signaling
from the application manager to the
policy server and then eventually to the
cmts
and on the access network side the the
dynamic service locating established
through the access network signaling and
it's the same when when it is time to
delete a flow and release the resources
any questions before I hand it over to
Jeff to get into the details of whit of
Vidocq architecture thank you guys you
so now that you've been exposed to the
technologies involved in providing
Vidocq I'm gonna kind of go into how it
all fits together so there's basically
two general architectures for providing
video Pradaxa services
one is the CMPs bypass architecture
where's the MTS direct architecture I'm
just gonna talk a little bit about
bypass most the times to be focused on
the direct architecture so the cmts
bypass also commonly referred to as
Depot or the DOCSIS IPTV bypass
architecture works by actually having
the video
downstream carriers carrying the DOCSIS
video video burdock's is content under a
separate administrative control than
what's used for the other services such
as high-speed data invoiced
the way this works is separate down
streams qualms are provided for video
versus the other services and the
advantage of doing this is then
all those video IP TV channels are not
having to go traverse through your whole
cmts network so you don't need the extra
way inside capacity on the CMT si but
they're the drawbacks of course are that
now you've got you know two different
domain two for two different
administrative domains
controlling video versus the rest of
your services and those the resources
associated for video could then can't be
shared for other services so you don't
have the ability to if they're not being
used to use those for like data
transfers and other things so here's a
picture of what I was just talking about
so what you see up top here is the is
the DOCSIS 3oh implementation with a
moderate cmts for providing the services
tucked up before and on the right inside
here we see two modems one modem being
an HST only customer and the bottom
modem being somebody who's you know got
a PC for HST services and also an IP
set-top box for for video content and as
you see the video channels are on these
separate frequencies here the bypass
channels 1 through n which are going to
the modem and then these other three
downstream carriers are what's being
used for HST and other services and so
there's this so what's gonna happen a
little bit is this the set-top box is
gonna you know signal that he wants to
watch particular video stream and that
reaches of this entity called the bypass
SRM erm which is a session resource
manager slash edged resource manager and
that guy is then going to contact the
DOCSIS framer in the edge qualm we're
just setup that the Edgecombe resources
are available and to get everything
prepared for sending these streams so
what's gonna come out of the bypass box
or the the video source is standard
multicast you know IP packets and it's
gonna need to be converted into a DOCSIS
frame to be in order to be understood by
the cable modem so this is the process
of the resource manager sitting all that
up and then once the media starts to
flow it comes through gifts DOCSIS
encapsulate encapsulated
and hits the modem on those bypass
channels so as you can see the whole
cmts core up top is not involved at all
other than the passing of the upstream
signaling so again there's this uh
there's you know benefits and drawbacks
to either approach you need the custom
cable modems because there's two
different entities controlling these
cable modems you need an edge qualm that
can you know take the MPEG in and do the
DOCSIS framing and this edge combo does
not have to be DOCSIS three oak cables
there's no need to talk to a dpi server
because it's not passing any DOCSIS
layer to mac management messages and
again the you know you need this entity
because that the bypass SRM and also the
again that the problem about that your
services are now isolated so you've gone
away from doing the integrated model
where you're having the triple play over
the same in transport infrastructure so
the direct architecture you know again
we talked about you talked earlier about
how DOCSIS 300 is great for video
because it gives you the availability to
bond channels together and provide much
higher speed higher speeds probably that
a single downstream pair as you
mentioned was about thirty eight bags
per second of usable traffic and modems
today can support up to eight downstream
downstream channels so you see a much
higher speeds now possible so anything
in and it printed the other example in
the direct solution again it's the two
two customers over here you can see now
that the customer who's both at data and
a IPTV subscriber is receiving all of
its downstream carriers from the from
the cmts so it's receiving for
downstream carriers which can be
carrying both both or either video or
data traffic so in this case you know
you the customers a makes a request to
watch specular video streams such as an
IP packet hitting the cmts core which is
going to trigger this the start of the
stream from the video source it's going
to go through the cmts core then gets
split you know make efficient use of the
bonding group channels
across those four channels that may
ultimately reached the customer now that
was you know using the same channels for
all services you could also have
separate channels for different services
so in this case it's still a 4 channel
modem using 3 channels for data and that
fourth channel for 4 IPTV or so in this
in the signaling again synced everything
happens except for now the video traffic
is just going on a dedicated channel for
4 IPTV so his data session or the data
sessions of other customers on that same
service group would not have been
impacted by this video stream so we
talked about a couple differences in
terms of IPTV you have channels which
are your like your main tier channels
your high your NB C's your ESPN's which
are going to be most likely watched by
some subset of customers all the time
then you also have kind of a cure your
far-off specialized channels where
concepts in today's world switch digital
video would be used to only send those
send those channels down to the service
group if there's active viewers so in
the case of broadcast if you're doing
that broadcast model now over an IP
infrastructure and the DOCSIS
infrastructure there's no need to or
doesn't make much sense to have that
static broadcast television on kalam
channels on multiple Continentals across
that cmts
as you know the contents always up and
it's no different from one area to
another so this concept of are of
spanning can be used to in order to get
more efficient use of your downstream
channels and really it's just nothing
more than I got on the RF side they take
a splitter to take channels those video
channels in and then divide them out and
send them to hold different service
groups so here's an example here where
you know each service group has
dedicated channels for their internet
traffic so
so the amount of bandwidth available to
the modems at service group one is not
impacting another service group they all
have four channels for browsing the web
but meanwhile these video broadcast
channels that everybody can see is
getting split and then sent to these
individual service groups so instead of
having to send these same four channels
time to end you don't have to do it you
don't have to set them up once again
your concept is that your your more
popular content would be statically set
up on these broad on these hour span
channels and then the more specialized
content would only be set up as as
needed using a dynamic miracast model so
this again is in a case where the
multicast traffic would come in and it
would go over the same quant the same
carriers its carrying your HSD and other
services I think Leslie talked about the
items on this slide so here's another
illustration of the problem here so this
in this case all services are set across
eight channels and those eight channels
then have to be a decade channels for
each service group so if there's 35
service groups on the CMT s 35 times 8
is 280 channels and downstream channels
that need to be used in order to give a
channel service to each service group
now within the spanning case this would
n be splits and so you only need the
dedicated 4 channels for HSD for each
server group so that's 4 times 34 times
35 and then the other 4 channels shared
for the video service so it's a almost a
50% savings or how many downstream
carriers are needed so part of the
problem limitation there with with
having the dedicated channels for static
multi static multicast or broadcast
video is you're confined by the amount
of bandwidth supported in those four
channels so if you have for 30 MH annals
you know that's
roughly a hundred and fifty mags that
you can use for your video traffic well
with DOCSIS 300 you can actually do some
things to kind of get around that as you
the IPTV customers are not gonna be
watching all streams at once they're
gonna be watching you know one channel
at a time so so what you can do is
actually use multiple more than four
channels for that video traffic and then
that fourth channel and have the modems
using three channels for if it's a
fortunately modem have the modem using
three channels for data choice
narrowcast TV then that fourth channel
dynamically changes that's tuned to
based upon what video stream is watching
so what happens is an IGMP packet comes
into the cmts the cmts figures out what
qualm does carry in a particular
multicast stream then it sends this the
DBC mr. device we talked about earlier
to the modem that tells it not only the
D state of that screen but also what
channel the modem is attuned to in order
to receive that gene so it can change on
the fly and so you know more than
fortune multiple channels can be used to
carry that video content you're still
under some constraints in terms of the
amount the the spectrum size that the
modem can turn to at once but it
definitely has its advantages so some of
the other ways you can scale the DOCSIS
Network for video is one of them is stat
boxing dynamic family sharing at Mission
Control and load balancing type of a
chose a little bit so if you have
constant bitrate video obviously I'm
sure you know it's not it's not very
efficient but if you have variable
bitrate video and you use that live
scene then you can provide more content
over over the same pipe so basically if
a video stream it doesn't have a lot of
active movement in it the amount of
traffic and ease of Sam is going to be
smaller but if it's a like sports look
like that which is a lot of movement
going on there's gonna pick the peak is
there's gonna be a burst of traffic and
by buffering the burst the the network
can make more efficient use of the
bandwidth
and fit more screams into the same
physical bandwidth or pipe so the bigger
the pipe the better the more efficiency
gains you have and then this video is is
not you know you've IPTV is not
interactive you can the jitter talks a
lot bigger than say for voice or or
video conferencing or telepresence so
it's just more graphical depiction of
what I was just talking about so again
another chart instead of a thing where
if you have CBR screams and number
streams you can fit in one qualms to
qualms for qualms a lot less than if you
have variable bitrate streams and also
you know the the bigger the pipe the
better officially you can get use of
those streams because the odds of
multiple video streams you know having
rap verse at the same time as less
dynamic bandwidth sharing is a way to
share those quantum resources for
different services so if the to go going
back to that previous slide so as you
see and in this case you know is these
video streams early consuming less than
100% of that available pipe but what
dynamic bandwidth sharing does it allows
you to use whatever is left over for
other services such as internet
downloads HST type services so you let
the data search the data service funds
at excess bandwidth also if the video
traffic is in the law or if it's or if
not if it uh it's not active at the time
then that bandwidth then can be used for
data until it becomes needed for the
video traffic
and I said that's the cmts can you can
assign priorities to certain services
and you can sign like static reservation
levels and things like that such that
some services are guaranteed a certain
amount of service and if they're not
needed then that bandwidth can then be
used for other services and you know you
can have the typical DOCSIS 3 on modems
either for channel models or a channel
models you can have a mixture of them in
a service group and you can have bonding
groups of the channels so if you just
send eight channels you can have some
modems Bandhu different the first
forward someone to the second floor and
some buttons behind to all AIDS it's
you're pretty flexible in what you can
deploy with with video streams in terms
of especially sharing resources some
applications you need a mechanism for
admission control so you want to limit
the amount of bandwidth these flows can
use or set priorities for who priam -
this is all functionality that's
available on the CMPs
so in the case of the video stream
coming in this is the case where most
likely you would not have dedicated
streams for video because just
dedicatedly don't need the admission
control purposes but in this case you
have IP maybe like some linear cast
service the IGMP join comes in from the
set-top box and the cmts determines if
that user is authorized to watch the
stream or if that stream is a is one he
wants to allow to go through his network
and what kind of QoS guarantees are
there for like there's a Cir a sign for
it or what have you
instead of using IGMP a lot of operators
prefer the more pet cable model since
that's what they're using today for for
voice and other applications so in this
case instead of the set-top box talking
IGMP directly with the cmts
it contacts the PEC cable multimedia
application manager which would trigger
the chain of messaging hooks so the cops
messaging to target the policy server
which to turn Cox has to say MTS just
set up to set up the QoS for that
particular multicast stream seagate
what's called a gate set message we're
coming to the cmts which contain
information like it with the set-top box
IP address and what kind of QoS it needs
and it would kind of function as both a
way of setting up those QoS parameters
across the docks it's networking kind of
like as an IG and P join at the same
time different from IPTV in the case of
video on demand which is you know your
unicast traffic a couple of different
ways you can provide a mission control
and Q s for that one way is for the VOD
streamer to simply send RSVP messaging
so RCP mass path messaging traverses
through the network like any other type
of RPM but once it's too cmts the CMT s
within author uses a mission control
mechanism to authorize at our FTP
message and at the same time convert
that into DOCSIS messaging the set of
QoS across the HFC Network and if that's
successful it would in turn generate are
a few reservation messages back to the
streamer so then that video traffic
could flow on the QoS naval path down to
the set-top box and just like in the
IPTV case you may want to do this you
know you may not be comforted operator
may not be comfortable opening up our
STP in our network so they go to they
prefer a PCM M model where either the
client or the streamer on behalf of the
client could generate the pet cable
multimedia requests the application
manager which is again just like before
generate the cops messaging to the
policy server and down to the CMT s to
dynamically set up the QoS for that VOD
stream
any questions or comments on any of that
so the last thing we want to talk about
here was telepresence it's been a big
buzz lately I'm sure most people are
aware of it so telepresence is a
technology that allows remote parties to
talk together as if they were physically
in the same room so it's different from
video conferencing and it's a higher
level of service you're talking about
you know 65 inch high def screens so the
person on the other end is life-size
cd-quality sound you know a lot of
thought goes into stuff like in terms of
the painting of the rooms and lighting
in other rooms your professional
microphones all that all that jazz so it
really feels like the person you're
talking to on the other end is sitting
right next to you so this could be used
for the teleworker environment where you
know maybe you have some parts of your
company or your group working in distant
locations and you need to have meetings
or or you know executive use that needs
news to contact is listed as a branch
for a remote location
could also use be for distance learning
type applications or another couple
envisions a scenario is the medical
profession where you have like you know
doctors and a remote and working
together for medical purposes so so the
question is so this telepresence office
that you're talking about hi-def video
streams and huh you're the bandwidth
consumption is relatively high it's not
something previously accounted for in
the cable world but went out with things
like such as DOCSIS 300 now the ability
to provide telepresence over dogs this
network is much more feasible and
there's two really key key key aspects
of telepresence going on these days I
wanted to teleworker case and this is
the case where MSO is provided this only
server has to transport and both the
telepresence unit as well as the call
control are all in an enterprise and
it's totally
the MSO control so this is typically
across some kind of secure tunnels such
as dmvpn where I'd be sick the other
model is a consumer model where you know
kinda like residential F David says he's
now he's providing a telepresence
service this could be like you know in
that medical situation I talked about
earlier in this case the MSO may or may
not have control of the call signaling
in applications so here's a graphical
description of this and so there's
teleworker unit where his uh his big
65-inch monitor screen here he's sitting
behind some kind of home router and this
home router can then this gin has a
dmvpn which is an encrypted thing of
dynamic multi VPN tunnel to his
enterprise so all this traffic is
encrypted so that there needs to be a
mechanism to provide QoS to telepresence
calls and one way to do it would be to
have some kind of RSVP dpcm
implementation where this telepresence
unit initiate some RSVP request in this
home gateway router within dynamically
signal the PCM messaging the set of QoS
across the stalks is network and the
same thing could apply for us smaller
medium business office you know who's
reachable over a DOCSIS infrastructure
then the others the other aspect we're
talking about before it's a consumer
model was just as somebody at home and
this in this case is probably you know
not going to be over in a cryptid tunnel
so the MSO could use some mechanism such
as the packet inspection so once it
identifies the telephones traffic it
could trigger off the packet multimedia
mechanism to create QoS or there could
be some direct signaling between the ITO
that the telepresence endpoint or the
switch used to switch these calls
typically telepresence is just acts very
much like a IP phone so we use this
protocol such as sip to talk to a soft
switch and that sauce which can then be
equipped to enable the QoS
for the
peasants call so summary of what we
talked about you know we've talked about
providing video over Docs to services so
providing video content over the same
DOCSIS Network used for high-speed data
voice and the other services today the
need to leverage technologies such as
doctors trio modular CPS or to provide
these fatter pipes and the benefits of
the multicast enhancements in the docs
of three Oh specification we talked
about pack cable multimedia and how that
works to dynamically set a few OS there
you're not tying up resources when video
was not actively across the network
since the constraints of video are so
high you don't want to be tired of
resources when there is no video being
watched or streamed and then the other
thing we talked about was the
telepresence for the interactive you
know communication between parties as if
they're physically together a high high
end extreme of video conferencing and a
is
uh-huh
good question so the question is on in
terms of what are the bandwidth
requirements for telepresence calls
telepresence video there's is is
high-definition so you're talking 1080p
720p but what what they do is they
typically have different compression
techniques techniques based on the
anticipated amount of motion in the
video content and since you know a video
content college just because typically
yo two parties sitting at a desk talk to
each other it's not like you know each
end playing basketball and kind of relay
that way so you can make some reasonably
safe bandwidth savings by just by using
higher compression techniques you know
h.264 the epic 4 standard is used so in
a 720 call that's that's roughly an
average rate of about 1 Meg whereas if
you want today to call us closer to 3 or
4 so depending on the what kind of Doc's
is planted on you may have to go to the
load with the lower codecs and also
beyond the motion because you know might
be 1 1 Meg average then we started
adding over the overhead like if you're
encrypting the tripi in the media you
might be moving it to like 1.4 1.5 and
then if there's a burst of motion and
might burst up to temporarily burst up
to the 3 or 4 Meg a legacy DOCSIS
predock's s3o upstream the highest
modulation you could use a 16 qualm and
the channel went to the size of 3.2
megahertz so doing that math that's like
a 10 bagpipe but you know usable amount
of bandwidth it's like 8 Meg so if
you're trying to fit have one user doing
6 pack of traffic in a pipe you know
it's not going to be really realistic so
that's where the benefits of DOCSIS trio
come into place
I'm also you know once you if you can
enable your upstream for DOCSIS to o
which allows a stream channel to Dublin
size to go up to 6.4 megahertz and
modulation up to 64 qualm so that's a
raw bandwidth of about 30 Meg's so maybe
you know 24 25 usable so that's much
better to handle that traffic but
obviously if you had a network or
up stream channel where multiple teller
credence calls went on at the same time
you definitely could could hit capacity
that's where having techniques to for
admission control to accurately reserve
the right my balance is needed in Tibet
and also you know where traffic
engineering comes comes in a key play
did that answer your question
well so three oh you know that it
doesn't change the physical layers
characters to the ocean but allows for
bonding on the upstream side most modems
today to play sport for up for FM
bonding so you know 4 times 24 25
the problem with whoops with with the
upstream is if you're limited by the
physical spectrum available for upstream
so it's five to forty two megahertz so
it's only a little left or a little over
30 megahertz wide so if you have you
know for six point four channels that's
getting close to that limitations you
really can't do any more but that'll
tell me that definitely does allow
speeds if you know close to a hundred
mag in the upstream
any other questions comments
No well I thank everybody for your time
hope it wasn't at least a little bit
informative