so good morning we're going to start off
the morning with a round of lightning
talks the first lightning talk will be
Miriam khooneh from ripe NCC who will be
giving us an update on right labs and if
John quarterman can be on standby for
the next talk that'd be great
Thanks good morning um you might
remember myself from last time when I
announced the route the right laughs so
the launch of vibe labs that we started
in September last year I just wanted to
give you an update of that because last
time we had just launched it and there
wasn't so much I'm happening yet and so
in the meantime there's actually a lot
more content and more tools more you
know interesting stuff happening on the
web labs website just a quick in summary
of what is red laughs all those who are
not aware of it it's um it's like a
community platform that we're trying to
create or the NCC that the NCC can use
also to put out new ideas we have
prototypes new tools presented to the
community and find out if it's useful
and get gather some feedback and find
out if you know you want us to develop
it further or not but it's also meant
for members of the community to
contribute anything you might find
interesting you know that you might
think is interesting for others to use
like any measurements you're doing
research results tools you've been using
for your operations that you want to
share we'd be happy to present or to you
know have a link to them on the site or
to describe them there Celeste URL if
you want to take a look I just wanted to
briefly give you some snapshots of
what's currently on the side not going
to go into much detail and they're
actually the resource explainer and was
presented and demonstrated in detail
yesterday one of my colleagues in a
Wilms who is who presented that during a
tool to track and just in a quick
summary it's a like a one-stop shop for
anything you always wanted to know about
IP addresses or is numbers it's linked
to all the IR allocation later like 10
years of routing histories behind it I'm
dns information reverse dns
it's linked to some black lists and some
geo location as well so I take a look
it's just some screenshots of various
types of information that you can find
it's linked from the labs website but
you can also get to it directly to Rex
type net and yeah please let us know
what you think about it is this useful
anything else you're looking for you
know could we improve that it's just a
prototype at the moment I mean it's
working and stable we still kind of
playing with it so don't blame us if it
may be you know breaks or if something
as not as pretty as it could be at the
moment a similar thing is I mean the
ripe NCC has been doing your own
measurements over time like the house
count and test traffic measurements and
we put some pretty interface on that to
make it easier for people to access all
the data behind it it's called net sense
it's also explained on on the right labs
website what what it does and yeah you
can go to and you know put your eyes
number in or your IP address in see and
what it shows you might have seen the
announcement of that on the Nano mailing
list I announced that we done some
measurements for an hour but the
pollution of 1 / 8 just to see how much
so that even used actually we also use
Rex for that and some other measurements
we've been doing internally and there is
a some statistics about that honorable
apps and web site and then a while ago
we've done well we're doing some rapid 6
measurements also internally at the NCC
but we also AM seen a lot of people in
the community of measuring various and
our types of things traffic in our pants
popular websites other things so we put
together a little like
stuff like a compilation of them
measurements others are doing and I'm
working on a on a follow-up of that
because in the meantime other people
have contacted me and you know asked me
if I wouldn't I want to include their
their work as well so if you're doing
something related to be 6 measurements
you would like to have included there
please let me know and recently we also
looked into both the growth of our
membership over time which is not maybe
not only interesting and for the ripe
ripe ncc membership or in the right
region what kind of gives an indication
of the you know the development of the
industry and over time and then in a
follow-up article we also looked at the
allocations you know we've been doing to
the membership I'm doing our last year's
and you can see like you know which
regions have the most mass numbers and
we're looking bit more into that and
maybe some speculation or why some of
the results are the way they are instead
of just putting out the data and there
are also a number of DNS related and
tools and and news on on the site we
published our plan and the signing k
route and related to that there's a
reply size test a tool that people can
use to hear check their resolvers
behaving properly and again based on
that we've done some and turn
measurements to an end and we publish
the results of that also on the side so
yeah browse around and see what some may
be what may be of use or interest for
your particular work that's just the
screen shot at the moment we actually
working on a on a new layout a bit of
easier structure for people to leave
comments and participate on the side at
the moment it's more or less just a list
of articles and I'm you can discuss
things and forums and there are darlings
to forums on each article but then in a
couple of weeks hopefully have a new
lay out a new site ready were in Mexico
makes it more lively and easier to leave
comments so yeah that's all I wanted to
show you here this morning if you have
any comments please let me know send
mail to me or to lab select the net and
yeah we really would like your your
contributions and your participation and
baton and to hear what you think about
the work that's on there or if you have
anything to contribute yourself please
do so
any questions for Miriam's of our John
won't you start making your way up and
don't see anybody coming to the light so
thank you no questions but I'm sure
you'll be around if somebody has one
I always wonder how right does such good
work all the time okay I'm John Waterman
I'm actually not directly affiliated
with the University of Texas at Austin
except for this project and this is an
NSF grant funded research project p is
professor Andy Winston some of you may
know what this is just a snapshot of one
thing we've been doing in the project
which is as you many of you know an
organization called fire I took down a
botnet called oz doc and we happen to be
looking at a lot of spam block list so
we look to see can we see that in the
block list data takedown was fifth and
six November of 2009 and a lot of eyes
peas and DNS is a registrar's cooperated
with fire I and we're always in favor of
botnet takes that takedowns okay here's
some of our data or some of the block
list data the the x-axis is obviously
time tenth of October temp 19th of
October thieve 19th of November the
y-axis is number of hosts listed on a
given block list and this happens to be
for the specific autonomous system
number 19 26 to the top there's not a
cursor here I guess not anyway the top
line is CBL and xbl which tracks so
closely together you can hardly tell
them apart and at the target date which
is where you see the little box there
you can see there is a drop it's slight
but it's noticeable so that might be it
right and we have another way of looking
at it notice there's now a y-axis on the
right side that's volume has a number of
spam messages and an additional curve
which is spam volume we get this from
CBL they send us some custom data and we
really appreciate that and on the spam
volume well it's not really clear I mean
there is a brief spike down at that date
but it's hard to tell it from noise
that's a little inconclusive here's
another one asn 6167 once again on the
CBL and xbl data it looks like there's
some decrease but it's Pam volume not
really and even on the CBL on xbl post
data it goes now for a little while and
then it goes back up okay so those two
were we basically picked by just looking
for a SNS it had many CDL listings we're
favoring CBL here just because we have
the volume data from them but then we
looked for autonomous systems that
actually had a downtrend on the time
period of interest and there's lots of
AAS ends that don't have many listings a
lot of educational ASNs that happen to
go down right then but you know the
numbers are so low and it varies so much
wasn't very interesting the top one was
that same asn.1 9262 we already looked
at but here's another one 70 15 and once
again there's that downtrend at that
time on CBL and xbl now on the volume
well yeah maybe there was a spike down
at a time but if so it didn't last I
mean you have to wonder if doing away
with one botnet didn't let an even
spammy or one get in here's another SN
7018 steeper down turn on CBL and xbl
same phenom
on the volume so ok let's try just
looking at the autonomous systems with
the highest volume numbers the volume
y-axis is on the left here just because
that's the only one we're showing and
this is beginning to look like they all
showed a spike down all the top ones at
that time and also there were spikes
down on the second of November and maybe
on about the 27 / 28 of October which
makes us wonder if you guys do another
takedown around any of those dates we're
very interested in more takedowns so
that we can examine the data and try to
characterize what it really looks like
so anybody here is of that we're quite
interested and here's another view we
also have from CBL botnet data they're
telling us what botnet they think
infests each IP address for the volume
data and we see the spikes down
interestingly in almost all the botnets
which is a little puzzling do botnets
take vacations it's like you know we're
not going to spam today and as spammers
have correlated the time periods their
campaigns run-outs do it and cleaning
the pipes that might be it dude
mmm yeah right well and the botnet
that's far i took down see way down in
the bottom where I've got it marked with
the box that little gold line that's the
one they took down and yes there is a
decrease at the target time that stays
down okay but most of the other
decreases we've been seeing look like
they may be because of the other botnets
now obviously the next step is the
botnets / autonomous system so we can
investigate that directly this is a work
in progress we're just showing you a
snapshot of this particular piece of the
project as we've got it right now and
our programmers you know I didn't draw
any of these charts our programmers
Sammy and uni will be working on that
they're sitting here in the audience
there's one there's the other one so the
if you're interested in what those other
botnets where it says here now that
particular botnet mega d a decrease from
3.5 million messages to eight point six
thousand at the target time factor for
that seems substantial and it did stay
down for a couple of weeks with also
compared this to as you probably we're
marshall 86 track spam bots activity
over time they saw a similar decrease at
the same time their order of botnets
they're showing is different because you
know they're using different spam traps
but what we're seeing does seem to track
what other people are seeing fire i made
a comment that if they're trying to be
modest here that they think what they
did is fairly straightforward and they'd
like to compliment shadows server and
other outfits that then take the data
they produce and try to do something
about the affected hosts which is a good
thing right so the basic point here is
takedowns are great and congratulations
to fire I and everybody else was
involved if this is going to have much
effect though we need a lot more
takedowns and a lot more cleaning up of
the affected nodes
you need this of course we're just
documenting this in detail and we're
going to dig in in greater detail so
that we can see more what's going on one
of the goals of this project is
eventually to produce a reputation
system where we'll be able to see for
every autonomous system how well are
they doing on a number of different
metrics and then to use that to
incorporate into an econometric model
which is supposed to show how this can
provide economic incentives for everyone
to do better at cleaning and stuff up I
don't do that part we have professors to
that the boilerplate NSF acknowledgement
here and once again particular fact
thanks to CBL for the volume data and
the botnet data to the rirs for
registration data and especially team
come REE I mean it's just really
impressive what those guys do and
merging all the RIR and routing data
makes it a lot easier and none of them
are of course responsible for anything
in this presentation that's it questions
questions for John questions for
gentlemen anybody give you a couple
minutes maybe you're shy to get up at
the mic this early in the morning you're
shaking off the equinox hangover okay
you already asked a question oh but you
have a presentation okay thanks John
that's the lighter the light edition
as usual the mic at the nano podium is a
little too tall for me good morning
everybody welcome to Wednesday I'm
surprised how many people are out here
and looking kind of awake I didn't go
out late last night but I did go out
late Monday and I'm still getting my
voice back so please bear with me
Suzanne wolf from internet systems
consortium and people mostly know us for
bind and DHCP and a few other things we
do like a DNS root server but I asked
for this time this morning to talk about
some technology in the v4 v6 coexistence
area that we think is interesting and
we're making available to the community
so we've all gotten the memo by now
unallocated ipv4 is running out at but
we probably have a couple of years
functionally it's already gone for many
large operators people are coping today
with the fact that the next time they
want to go back for more addresses there
will not be previously unallocated ipv4
for them the issue there of course is
that applications are not v6 enabled and
users aren't using v6 there's an app for
that but it speaks before and it's going
to for some time to come there's a very
very long tail here content providers
are in kind of the same boat and isp and
access providers are going to be in the
position of having to bridge that gap
because you need address space to grow
networks but you can't make your users
change so there's a need again not news
for ipv4 ipv6 coexistence technologies
there's been a variety of technologies
being discussed a lot of development
work in the ITF a lot of private
activity people think we'll just do more
ipv4 nat deeper layers of that to net to
net some people think that will come up
with you know son of NAT PT or with
enough thrust and enough gaming systems
that use it host-based dual stack light
will be
successful and we're here to talk about
on one particular technology dual-stack
light which has been developed within
the IETF the RL there is the draft which
is in last call and you should shortly
be moving on to the next stage and its
life as an RFC the key idea behind
dual-stack light is that it allows v4
applications to communicate with v for
servers and peers over v6 infrastructure
one address-family transition router
after can handle a lot of clients the
basic I'm not going to go into technical
detail but the basic idea is you tunnel
v4 over v6 infrastructure and then NAT
to further v4 interactions
the basic idea from as to how it behaves
for users and providers the network's it
for them from the network side from as a
network operator which you see is both
v4 and v6 and use this is a v6
delegation for the customer site there's
a v4 delegation for the after the tenth
that the tunnel concentrator the
customer sees business as usual v6 our
applications can use ipv6 it's
completely transparent v4 only
applications also just work so what
we've done what I see is done is with
support from comcast for which we're
very grateful we've released an
open-source implementation of dual stack
light for people to try out the
distribution consists of the client side
widget that basically allows an open
open wrt box with dhcpv6 and v6 enabled
to set up the tunnel and allows the the
other piece of the distribution as a
server side tunnel concentrator and NAT
device which is referred to as the after
in the spec is see after is available at
the or luc and we would like for folks
to try it out dual stack light is not
the only technology anybody's going to
need there are various use cases there
are various ways people are running
their networks they're going to be
various ways people are going to
accommodate the issues around the need
to have v4 and v6 coexist in networks
for the foreseeable future dual stack
light is just one of the tools in the
kit but we do think that the use case
for it the initial use case for it was
large access networks where there's love
there's a very large installed base of
users and applications that only know
before however we do think the use case
goes way beyond that if you're growing a
network pretty soon you're only going to
be able to grow a network with v6 public
addresses if you have an install base of
n knows view for applications activities
that it depend on before you're going to
have to be looking at something like
this so we think you should be taking a
look at this it's open source it's
freely available and we want to hear
from you we're setting up we have set up
the usual open source support mechanisms
which you can find on the website the
usual mailing lists we're also setting
up the after forum which is based on the
forums we do around our other software
products it's a way for users to work
with us on development on funding on
road maps for weather where the software
should go early access for testing and
benefits of that kind we is C is always
here at nanog we go to our meetings or
at IETF we're in the community and we
would like to hear from you or just drop
me or the product manager for after a
note and try it out let us know what you
think let us know how it could be more
useful in this brave new world where
we're walking into and unless there are
questions thanks and operators are
standing by talk to us
thanks Susan