hello everyone I'm chuhan Wang from
qinghua University today I will talk
about our research on email
Authentication Protocol Decay the title
is a large scale and longitude no
management study of DCM deployment
email service is one of the popular
services in the internet world
and it is because of its important
position
that email service has also become an
important Target for attackers
the defined against the emails proving
attacks various email authentication
protocols have been proposed under
standardized during this year
at present the Kim is one of the most
widely used email authentication
protocols
the game has been proposed to
understandalized since 2008 and is now
adopted by Yahoo Google and other
leading email service providers
the game signature is generated based on
HG algorithm and asymmetric encryption
algorithm just like RSA
the game's public key is deployed on a
domain name in The Following format just
like that the selector here is a random
string specified by the domain owner and
example.com
represents a real domain name
the image here is an example of a real
decaying signature
next let's talk take a look at the
workflow of the game
first the sender deploys the Decay
protocol they need to generate a key
Pair by asymmetric encryption algorithm
and then deployed the camera course
meaning the decaying public key on a DI
server of a specified domain second
window senders MTA sends an email it
became signature is calculated for the
outgoing email which includes the email
headers the email body and the became
signature itself
last when receivers MTA receives an
email with articum signature it also
first exercise the the camera course for
the sender's domain to validate the the
game signature
although tkm is an important email
security protocol and it has been
proposed for more than 10 years video
has been done to understand the adoption
rate and the potential security issues
of the claim
in the previous Works they conduct life
skill measurements of the other two
protocol
SPF and the mark but Kim was absent
this is because the future of the game
makes it difficult to be measured at
scale
from the previous description we are
able to know that there are two main
ways to obtain the game information once
from the team records and the other is
from the game signatures
the camera course
is deployed
in this specified mean
because the selector is randomly
specified it's difficult to measure and
scale directly
designs became signature also difficult
to client by researchers the game
signatures are in binded in the email
header and would not be publicly
released
it's difficult for researchers to obtain
large amounts of the game signatures
data for further security analysis
however we find two ways to guide this
game information
first we can pass the camera course from
passive dance data size
and the second we can extract the game
signatures from email headers
therefore we collaborate with our
industrial partners and get the data
science
in total our data covers five million
distinct domains and two million these
instructors
our data collection and Analysis process
is shown in the future figure below
which is mainly divided into three parts
including data collection data
processing and data analysis the data
collection stage has been basically
tasked talked earlier meaning through
cooperation with industrial Partners to
obtain the corresponding the camera
course and the decimal signatures
after data collection we will perform a
series of operations such as data
cleaning data aggregation and the
dumplication on the raw data
through the above passive collection
stage
we found that there are many commonly
used selectors such as mail default
Decay which will be used by many domains
therefore we conduct a large scale
measurement of I like talk one meaning
domains it was the top 40 sectors
obtained from the passive collection
and finally we can use the results of
the measurement to analyze Decay
adoption rate
the grammatical problems of the camera
course became key management issues and
it became signature issues
in this paper we perform a large scale
and longitudinal management study on the
current state of the Kim the results
shows that 28 percent of elect top 1
million domains have enabled the claim
of which three percent are misconfigured
besides we also measure the adoption
rate of SPF and the DeMark by active
scanning
and the results can reflect the current
status of the game deployment from the
side
the image here shows the change in
deployment rules of SPF Decay and Mark
over the past few years part of the data
comes from the two paper list below
to know more about the game deployment
we also analyze the game adoption of the
domains under different country code top
level domains and genetical top level
domains
next let's talk about game key
management issues
RFC recommends that the game Keys should
be rotated on a routine basis
however we found using long lifetime
Keys is common even for most high
profiled means
the below figure shows the number of
long lifetime keys of LX top 100 domains
covered by our data site the orange part
represents the numbers of keys that have
not been rotated in the last five years
finally we found it out of Alex top 20
domains have not rotated their keys in
the past 12 years
we also analyzed the game key lines in
passive against their site
RFC has pointed out the short I say keys
more easily succumbed to offline attacks
and designers should use IC keys of at
least 2048 bits
the NST has also recommended that
however our research shows 84 percent of
more than 3 million domains still use
the keys that are less or equal to
1024 bits well more than
five thousand domains still use sticking
keys that are even like them
512 bits
we also analyze issues of the game's
signatures in practice based on 400
million real decaying signatures from
Camille
we find most domains have become
signature issues for example
Rick decam signatures are common
what is rate became signature the game
signatures should sign important email
headers to protect the content Integrity
of email and avoid being
abused for replay attacks
however IFC only specified the from
field to be must assigned
although it also recommend the other 20
headers should be signed in the game
signatures we find no domain in our
designs signing all of the 20 headers
RC only provide a basic guideline that
dkm signatures need to protect the core
content of the email message
actually we found that the Hydra Fields
signing in the decam signatures vary
among different email services
this there is not a consensus in the
actual implementation almost all of the
domains have signed from and subtract
Fields however only 11 percent of
domains have signed replying two fields
to prevent
adding duplicate Hider field
the game the designers proposed a method
of oversigning which means a Hider name
should appear in space tags once more
than the actual numbers of that header
in an email
there is an example of over signing
mechanism
all setting mechanism is helpful to
protect users from the emails grouping
or text
however we measured how many domains use
ourseling to protect themselves against
multiple headers attack
were found only 2.2 percent of domains
in our decaying signatures data side use
our signing mechanism
the last part is about mitigation and
recommendation
first we have tried our biased to report
all on vulnerabilities we found into the
relevant email administrators
for email vendors and 24 relevant email
administrators have acknowledged our
report
and second we have developed developed
an online tool for decline development
based on our measurement and Analysis
scripts this tool can have email
administrators check and deploy their
dick in records and further improve the
status of the game deployment now this
tool can be excised
at notesproofing.cn
at last we proposed to
improvements which may have to improve
the protective effect of decam
signatures and prevent decline
signatures from being used for replay
attacks if you are you interested in our
work please read our paper for details
I'm sorry that I can't attend a meeting
in person because of the kovid 19.
please feel free to ask any questions on
this like and I will respond in time
that's all thank you