good afternoon everyone so today I'm
going to talk about reconstructing
attack provenance in serverless clouds
this is a joint work from the University
of Illinois at Urbana Champaign and NC
State
so if we look at serverless programming
model it's quite different from the
traditional web applications so here
applications consist of several small
functions that only execute for few
seconds
or like few Cycles
um each serverless application the logic
is constructed as a bunch of workflows
and each workflow consists of several
functions then data stores and other
Cloud components and they communicate to
each other to get the things done
so this cloud computing programming
model makes the functions isolated and
stateless
and it has become quite popular in the
industry the reason being that the
serverless cloud platforms take away the
task of management
from the developers so everything in the
back end and the software software stack
is managed and you also don't need to
worry about Auto scaling and load
balancing based on the request load you
can increase the number of your
instances that service the request
incoming requests and you can also scale
it down to zero when it's not that busy
also the users only pay for the Cycles
the function executes for thus Bringing
Down the cost significantly
so do serverless also buy us additional
security so let's look at this example
which is modeled after a proof of
concept
example of a retail serverless
application from Nordstrom
so here is the retail website portal
where customers can browse and they can
click to launch a function which is a
product purchase function that can
invoke authorized credit card function
which authorizes the purchase and then
the purchase status can be communicated
to the customer through this public
status function
so all these functions are protected by
role-based Access Control policies
and when the request load increases
in addition to scaling up the function
instances the platform also caches them
in memory and recycles them to avoid the
costly operation of respawning the
containers again and again
so uh we would think that this scenario
is more secure because each of these
functions they are just live for
few milliseconds and it's hard for an
attacker to get a foothold to launch a
time consuming attack
however in April 2022 we see a report
from Palo Alto Network's threat
researchers that in spite of having
identity and access management policies
in place 99 of these Cloud entities are
over privileged and 65 percent of known
Cloud security attacks are due to
misconfigurations
so let us see what will happen if we if
we have a misconfiguration in this
credit card database
ah let's say an attacker got their hand
to some stolen credentials and they were
able to exploit a bug present in the odd
CC function
using that bug they connect to an
attacker controlled domain and they
download some malwares
and thus they can
steal some data from the credit card
database now
if they want to get
and the SQL dump of the entire database
that can be time consuming but recall
that in the serverless platforms they
recycle the same container again and
again thus giving them enough time to
exfiltrate the data
they can also use the downstream
functions like public status which has
access to outbound apis like phone
message email or other apis that are
legitimate to use and they can launder
the data this way
so after we have seen such uh attack
vectors in server list the question we
may ask is that do existing systems
prevent or at least help investigation
of such attacks
we found out that not only these attacks
are hard to prevent there are also like
limited auditing solutions that can help
investigation of such attacks
traditional approaches like Linux audit
they do not know about the serverless
semantics so they do not have idea about
platform apis or different function
containers or things like container
reuse
and there are also this existing
provenance based tools which remove many
terminated system events aggressively
which is not useful in this case because
in serverless there are many terminated
function executions that are ephemeral
so we have some observability tools as
well uh these third-party observability
tools
um they use they have some features like
distributed tracing and cost analysis
but they have stick strict usage limits
and mostly they are runtime and platform
dependent
so here we see uh an um screenshot from
a tool called epsagon which is a cloud
security tool so here we can see that
this tool keeps track of the inter
function Communications as a at a course
current level and they also track some
function execution information like the
execution time
but these informations are not as
helpful in investigating the attacks we
just discussed
so in this talk I am presenting Alistar
a complete auditing solution for
serverless clouds that use data
provenance techniques
the first question that informed the
design of Alistar is that what are the
different types of entities and
activities that we need to audit to
preserve helpful forensics information
for serverless attack investigation
so in the serverless function instances
we have this request Handler that
Services the request that comes in from
the application Gateway
when a request comes in the function
executor creates a process P that
achieves the task of this function
we design a lightweight Alistar
provenance collector module that is
local to this function instance
it achieves a list of tasks the first
one being
tracing the system call that is being
invoked by process p
it also keeps track of all inbound and
outbound Connections in this instance
we also look at the Port bindings to
keep track of which process is creating
which network connection
all of this information and logging
information from the request handle
Handler is summarized in a form of local
provenance graph
that preserves all the causal
information between these different
event that are happening in this
instance
so now that we have this local
provenance graphs at this different
function instances the next question we
asked is that how we can meaningfully
combine all this information to
facilitate attack investigation for that
we take help of the serverless platform
services and the logs preserved by them
we get the information about what IP
addresses are assigned to which
instances and also which requests are
serviced by which instances
based on this information we stitch the
different local provenance graphs into a
global provenance graph that explains
the behavior of the entire application
let us get back to the serverless attack
example where a bug in the odd CC
function was exploited to steal some
data from the credit card database and
then through repeated invocation of this
function the attacker got enough time
and then exfilted the data through the
public status function using legitimate
platform apis
so we implemented the attack uh within
the hello retail application and then we
traced the attack Behavior using the
ipsagon tool this is the graph we get
from ipsagon they keep track of the
inter function Communications and also
the request latencies
but we do not see enough information to
investigate the attack
we get a tiny bit of evidence in the
abnormal execution time for the attack
Trace but we do not know why this is
happening or how this is happening
this is how the provenance graph looks
like when we trace the attack with
Alistar
from the local graphs we get the
information about the network
communications that are being created
from the instance itself or being
received at the instance and also
different system events inside the
function instance are recorded
then at the global level we have
information on every container that was
spawned and every request they served we
also track the inter function
Communications among the different Cloud
components in this setting
if we take a closer look at one of the
containers we see that request 1 is
coming into the auth CC function
then it's exploiting the bug already
present in the function
and creating a connection to an attacker
controlled server
to download some malicious files
then if a request comes in in quick
succession then
they already have this
malicious files handy and they can use
that
to steal some data from the credit card
database
so this is how the container use attack
looks like when we trace this attack
using Alistair in our paper we have more
examples of search serverless attacks so
please do give our paper a deed
to conclude Alistar can be used to
diagnose the serverless specific attack
techniques like container use and
exfiltration through down Downstream
functions it also imposes manageable
performance overhead but in exchange we
get a lot improved forensics capability
and Alistar logs can also be used with
other tools like deep log for intrusion
detection
thanks for listening to my talk and I am
happy to answer questions