all right so uh yeah Welcome to our talk
about automating cookie content and gdpr
violation detection this was joint work
with Carl kubichek Carlos caprini and
David Basin from eth Zurich
and so to begin well it is I am sure it
is widely known and confirmed by past
research that cookies are used to track
users online and well this commonly
happens without the user even being
aware of it so to get the situation
under control the European Union has
passed laws that require websites to
notify users and request consent before
data can be processed and because of
this many websites today now display
these kinds of consent notices like you
can see here which come in various forms
like banners pop-ups and they can range
from simple notifications to very
complex menus which are very confusing
are also often for the user and there
the user can consent to various
different third parties
now what uh what like what the EU law
actually requires is that so there are
two main laws which are the e-privacy
directive and the general data
protection regulation or gdpr
and to eat privacy directive states that
all data collection requires consent
except that which is strictly necessary
such as for example authentication
cookies which are of course necessary to
make the website work
and moreover the gdpr defines the
conditions that are needed for valid
consent
so consent needs to be freely given and
unambiguous which means that users
cannot should not be forced to to give
consent and moreover our website cannot
impress implicitly assume that when a
visitor browses a website that they uh
that they have also automatically
consented to data collection
moreover consent needs to be specific
and informed consent notices must State
the reasons for data collection and they
must separate the data collection into
clearly defined purposes like it is done
on this example they are yeah separated
into different categories
now if these regulations are not
followed of course websites May face
large fines from authorities but past
research has actually shown that this
does not that non-compliance is still
widespread despite this a significant
number of websites create tracking
cookies before the user is even able to
give consent and some track users even
when the consent is denied
on top of this dark patterns are used by
by websites to influence new users into
accepting all types of data collection
even if this is not really in the user's
best interest
so all of this evidence shows us that a
solution is needed that doesn't require
users to trust the websites and our main
research goal was to find a way to
enforce cookie consent directly in the
client
and our solution to achieve this goal
was a browser extension which we call
Cookie block the key idea of our
extension is to look at the cookie data
so if the actual cookie that is on the
website we predict the purpose using a
machine learning model and then decide
on removing the cookie based on whether
the user actually consents to the
purpose that the classifier predicts for
the cookie
and to implement this we first gathered
a large data set of cookies with two
different web crawlers we then analyzed
the cookie structure to extract
numerical features from them to train a
classifier uh we yeah we then train a
classifier and evaluate the model and
finally this is integrated into the
browser extension
now for data collection the main
challenge was to find data sources with
cookies that were actually labeled with
purposes so if you simply crawl for
cookies you don't actually have this
information
luckily we know from the gdpr
regulations that there exist consent
notices that that already contain this
information so because of the purpose
limitation now we target pop-ups that
are implemented on websites by so-called
consent management platforms and these
are third parties that host the code and
the content that is used by the consent
notice
and well we selected the cmp's cookiebot
onetrust and terminally because these
had all the information
these specific four categories that we
needed to train our model so these
categories are strictly necessary
functionality analytics and advertising
um to retrieve this data we as I said we
implemented two different web crawlers
the first one simply identifies whether
the website we target uses one of the
supported cmps
so as input we gave it 6 million domains
from the from the Tranquil list and the
crawler identified 37 and a half
thousand domains that one had one of
those cmps the second caller emulates
real browsers and it uses the open WM
open wpm framework as a basis it
extracts the Declarations from the
consent notice and also the real cookies
through browsing and this was successful
on 30 000 websites now here you can see
the results of the second crawl we found
2.2 million cookie declarations in total
and on Earth
approximately 600 000 observed cookies
and so to get the training data set of
course we had to match the the
Declarations which had the purpose with
the real cookies which we you for this
we use the name and the domain of the
cookie and this gave us roughly 323 000
uh training them training data samples
now interesting to note here is actually
that we have many more declarations than
observed cookies which may be a
limitation of our crawler it cannot
fully interact with the website so maybe
not all cookies are generated and at the
same time however many of the real
cookies that we found at the website
were never actually declared in the
consent note is so this could be
actually a potential violation of the
gdpr because the websites do not provide
information on those cookies and we will
actually look at this later in our
analysis
and another interesting thing is that
when we look at how this uh how the
collected that cookie declarations are
split up by category we see a lot more
advertising cookies and this reinforces
that cookies are really mostly used for
tracking
now to be able to train the classifier
well each cookie is is by itself just
textual data and we need to transform
this into numerical features so we this
was not done in Prior work and we
defined over 50 different extraction
step steps the full list can be found in
our paper and I will give you two
examples so the first is the entropy of
the cookie value so the entropy
identifies Randomness the higher the
entropy the higher Randomness and this
could help the predictor identify unique
identifiers and unique identifiers are
of course often are used for tracking
a second example feature are content
encoding so we often identified Json
comma separated values and base64
encodings as also as separate features
which could also help the predictor
identify the context
so for training the model we use the
xgboost algorithm because it was one of
the best performing among different
approaches that we tried and it also
achieved great performance in previous
applications for classifying yeah for
yeah classifying to data and as a
baseline we use the Wikipedia repository
which is a database of cookies this has
that was manually assigned to purposes
by human experts
and so also cookiepedia records roughly
categories for approximately 70 percent
of our data set
evaluation we can see that
um the performance of cookipedia We
compare the performance of Wikipedia to
our best XG boost model and the
performance the balance accuracy of our
model is 84.2 percent almost which
compared to the 85.7 percent of
cookipedia shows that the classif our
classifier can predict purposes almost
as well as human experts and here you
can also see that while cookipedia is
maybe more accurate is at classifying
necessary cookies our classifier is far
more accurate for advertising cookies
and thoughts may give a higher privacy
guarantee
so as the final step we integrated the
model into our browser extension cookie
block and cookie block when you install
it it only asks users once instead of
being asked on every website
afterwards once the user has defined
which purposes he accepts the extension
predicts purposes for all cookies that
arrive and those that are rejected are
immediately removed
now
so cookie block is already we made this
available for users on major web so the
other major browsers but we know we
managed to so we identified a main
challenge with this actually so the
there are
necessary cookies may now also be missed
also misclassified because the
classifier is not completely accurate in
all cases and this can cause websites to
break of course and we try to evaluate
how serious this issue is by looking at
100 different randomly sampled websites
85 of the websites worked without any
issues but we found that the
authentication was broken on seven
websites and another seven we found that
the consent pop-up were reappearing even
if the user accepted them or clicked on
a button and on a single website we
found issues with language changes so to
mitigate this problem we implemented
functionality so that users can grant
exceptions to websites so that the
cookies from that websites are no longer
removed we can also or we also support
the
an exception list which users can report
broken sites and we will and we
Define these cookies as necessary so the
the websites no longer break
finally with the data we collected in
our crawl we were able to perform a gdbr
compliance analysis on the web and
here we defined six novel methods which
we list in this bar chart we will not go
over all of the I will not go over all
of them in detail because of time
constraints but here are some of them
so first we
Google analytics cookies are of course
very well known they are used for
analytics but still many websites
misclassify them 8.2 percent of the
websites we analyzed and on 2.7 even
these are classified as necessary by the
websites
and this was actually even ruled as a
gdpr violation in a previous court case
the planet 49 case so we are pretty sure
that these are
yes gdpr violations we also again here
have the Undeclared cookies cookies that
were never listed in the consent notice
and
we found these on a surprising 82.5
percent of all websites and overall 40
percent of all cookies that we found
were Undeclared
moreover We examined previously applied
analysis which are
um cookies that were set prior to the
user's consent and also cookies that
were set despite the user rejecting
consent and we found those on almost 70
percent of the websites and uh 21 of the
websites respectively Which is higher
than what was previously indicated in
Prior work
so finally in the histogram you can see
the number of websites that have this
exact number of different violation
types of what we analyzed and here we
see that only 5.3 of the percent of the
websites show no potential violations
this again justifies the need for our
extension for client-side
categorization of and removal of those
cookies
so and this concludes the presentation
to summarize cookie consent notices are
absolutely broken and if we want to
address this we need to address this at
the client side to do so we crawled a
large training data set of cookies we
extracted the extracted their features
trained the classifier and integrated
this into a browser extension and we
found that on almost 95 of our websites
there were potential gdpr violations
now thank you for your attention and oh
yeah and actually on this QR code you
can actually download uh all our
artifacts source code and even the
browser extension itself real feel free
to ask me or my co-author called
kubichek who is also here any questions
if you have them thank you for listening