foreign
I'll be talking today about to you today
about our new batch the freshly private
peer protocol this is Joint work with
Ron mayank and Kalman
so private information retrieval or peer
for short is a cryptographic technique
that allows users to query a remotely
held database while keeping the contents
of their queries private and unknown to
the service
peer protocols generally rely on
encrypting secret sharing or otherwise
obfuscating these queries and their
responses the service here may consist
of a single server or many servers and
we'll kind of focus on the stock on the
multi-server setting
fear is a powerful primitive with
endless potential applications and
researchers have developed many peer
protocols and proposed using them for a
variety of applications I'm showing only
some of them on this slide a highlight
of existing work is the offline online
model which uses a perquiry
pre-processing stage that performs
expensive operations offline to speed up
the online protocol
however fear hasn't seen really much
adoption in the real world and one not
sure question is why
we believe that this isn't part a
challenge of scale Pierre has known
lower bounds that prove that significant
per query overheads are required to
provide privacy this makes peer scale
poorly to large query loads as we will
see next with a potential application
so in this example peer applications
let's say a PR application let's imagine
a service that keeps a database of
vulnerabilities and they're found in
different software dependencies and
versions
proprietary software developers can
query the service periodically using
peer in order to ensure that the
dependencies are safe while at the same
time keeping sensitive information about
their dependencies and potential
vulnerabilities private
the challenge here is in the scale we
know that there are millions of
dependencies available on repositories
such as npm or Maven Central so the
database has several million elements
the total number of software projects
that may use the service is in the
hundreds of millions each with tens of
dependencies
so if every project is going to you know
query for the dependencies once a day
that gives us about a billion billions
of queries daily
so can peer constructions scale to such
loads
we look at this via the we look at the
performance of checklist a
state-of-the-art 2 server protocol that
uses the offline online model
um this is a very recent protocol from
last year's usernx security and what
we're going to show here is only the
online cost we're not going to show the
offline cost
our database size which we denote by n
is 2.5 million elements and we ran
checklists code on Q queries which we
show on the x-axis and measured the
online time required by the servers to
handle all of these Q queries in seconds
and we report that on the y-axis both
axes are log scale
the computation complexity and checklist
is in the order of square roots and per
isolated query this is pretty good for
peers since that level of server work is
generally required for privacy however
checklist handles every one of these
queries separately so it has to pay the
square root overhead for each query
which means that for Q queries the total
computation time is in big o q times
square root of time
for an application like the software
dependencies one we looked at where the
service needs to handle billions of
queries daily the per user over the per
user per query overhead and checklist
compounds and makes the total cost
impractical
on our setup it takes us more than a day
to perform the server side computation
for these billion queries this gets even
worse for larger database sizes because
of this multiplicative dependency on
square roots n
due to the theoretical lower bounds for
peer there is very little we can do to
improve the asymptotic complexity of any
isolated query instead applications like
this one with the large number of
queries give us an opportunity to
amortize the overheads over the
different queries this requires us to
handle queries in batches rather than
individually but poses an interesting
challenge
we need to amortize costs over the
queries made by different users while
also carrying out the expensive
operations offline to speed up our
online protocol
in this talk we present DP peer a new
multi-server P protocol for applications
with many queries
dppier batches and amortizes the cost of
queries made by different users down to
a constant
our protocol processes a batch of Q
queries and Big O of Q Plus n
and it relies on a new secret sharing
scheme in order to move all public key
operations offline and use only cheap
arithmetic operations online I'll
briefly discuss the sharing scheme later
at a high level DPP combines three
techniques first we reveal a noisy
histogram of all the queries to the
service this protects the queries of Any
Given user with differential privacy and
we intentionally accept this leakage in
order to provide good scalability
second our protocol batches the queries
from the different users and shuffles
them using a mixnet design
and finally we move all expensive public
key operations to an offline stage which
we can be carried on during off-peak
hours so that our online stage uses only
a few arithmetic operations per query
for presentation purposes I'll show a
simpler construction that uses only the
first two techniques but carries out all
operations online including the public
key ones and I'll briefly discuss how we
do this online offline design afterwards
our setup consists of many users that
query a remote service and this service
consists of two or more servers
structured in a chain
our protocol tolerates a malicious and
unrestricted adversary that controls all
but one server and one client
specifically our protocol guarantees
that such a powerful adversary only
learns the histogram of all of the
queries and nothing else and this
histogram is differentially private
our protocol also provides Integrity
guarantees that ensure that any user
only accepts responses that are correct
and correspond to the database as agreed
upon by the servers
for Simplicity let's consider the case
with two users and two servers let's say
the pink user wants to query row number
three and the gray user wants to query
row number one
in the very first step of the protocol
each user samples random masks that when
sort together reconstruct a zero the
user is going to sample one mask per
server in addition to one extra mask
that it stores locally for later use
we'll use these masks to hide the
responses while they're processed by the
servers
and in this figure we show all these
masks as puzzle pieces
then each user onion encrypts their
queries and their masks using the
server's public keys each layer in this
onion Cipher corresponds to a single
server and contains the mask associated
with that server and additionally the
deepest layer also contains the query
and is associated with the very last
server in this chain
the first server collects all these
onion ciphers from all the different
users forming a batch of queries again
this batching is required for
amortization
the server decrypts the outer layer of
every onion note that while it can
decrypt the outer layer it can decrypt
the inner layers because it doesn't
possess the the right private key right
so it the server can't learn the queries
the the contents of any of these queries
now the decryption of the outer layer
provides the server with two outputs The
Masks which you will store for later use
and the inner layer of the cipher
then the server samples noise from a
select distribution we carefully select
this distribution to ensure that the
overall histogram that includes both the
real users from real user queries and
the queries that are noise both of these
together the histogram is differentially
profit
when sampling the noise the server also
samples random masks and encrypts them
with with the noise queries to ensure
that real queries and noise queries are
indistinguishable
note that the amount of noise we add
here is linear in the size of the
database it's independent of the number
of input queries and users this is
important because it means that the
noise becomes relatively smaller in
applications with many queries
and thus amortizes to a small constant
overhead per query
then the server shuffles all these
queries together and this hides and
conceals which of the queries are noise
which of them are real
and the server sends this traveled
result to the next server
now the last server in the chain
decrypts every element revealing the
contents of every query and the mask
crucially the server cannot tell which
user is the origin or source of the
decrypted query and it cannot even tell
whether that decrypted query is real or
noise
so the only thing that this server
learns is the overall distribution or
histogram which is differentially
private
the last server looks up each decrypted
query in the database finding the
associated response
we cannot just send these responses back
to the users in plain text format
because that leaks information about
their queries so instead we will exhort
the responses with the masks to hide
them
the last server sent the mask responses
back the previous server and that server
deshuffles them and removes the
responses that correspond to the noise
it added earlier on
then the server absorbs the remaining
responses with the masks it previously
stored and sends them back to the
prospective users
and finally each user applies its own
mask and reconstructs the desired output
now what I just showed you is a
simplified construction that performs
all the operations online including the
expensive onion encryption and
decryption operations
in the Full Construction in the paper we
only use a cheap secret sharing scheme
online and rather than on your
encryption and we use online encryption
only offline to install the required
secret shares at the servers so that the
servers can use these shares online
compared to previous work our offline
station is in a sense flipped rather
than the users receiving a hint from the
servers the users in this and our
protocol anonymously store hence in this
case secret shares on the servers
for this to work the secret sharing
scheme needs to have a certain security
properties similar to onion encryption
in particular the scheme must be
incremental where the query is
reconstructed one server at a time in
the chain and this is similar to the
onioning aspect of onion encryption it
also requires that the scheme be
non-maluable and resilient against
adversaries that may maliciously modify
shares and this is similar to CCA
security and onion encryption
to the best of our knowledge this is the
first secret sharing scheme that
satisfies both properties
all right now it's time to look at the
performance of our new protocol we look
at the same experiment from earlier in
the talk the x-axis is the number of
queries in a batch and the y-axis is the
total completion Time online in seconds
my main observation here is that our
protocol handles the the batch of Q
queries in Q Plus n rather than in Q
Times Square Root n
for batches with few queries you can see
that our runtime is basically constant
this is because the amount of noise
queries overwhelms and dominates the
system and is far greater than the few
real queries made by users in this case
this means that per query amortization
is very isn't very effective and we're
performing work linear in the database
for each of these queries and this is
also confirmed by the fact that
checklist outperforms our protocol
however as the batch size increase our
protocol becomes dominated by real
queries and the noise the fraction of
noise queries become smaller and smaller
so our amortized work per query now
becomes an increasingly smaller constant
and we increasingly outperform checklist
due to this amortization
that's one billion queries which is
roughly the scale of our software
dependencies example we observe that the
cost of our protocol is two orders of
magnitude lower than checklist
in our paper we discuss another
application with mobile app stores we
show more experiments including
comparisons to other peer protocols and
we show the effects of the batch size on
our throughput and latency
and we also spell out the secret sharing
scheme which I only highlighted and we
formalize its properties
in conclusion we present a DP peer a
novel differentially private peer
protocol for applications with many
queries our protocol exhibits constant
amortized computation communication
complexities and concrete performance
boosts up to two orders of magnitude
over existing work
and this makes peers suitable for
applications domain that were previously
understudied or thought to be
impractical
thank you