all right
um not only software but also Hardware
nowadays suffers from vulnerabilities
and to improve the situation we created
Cell lift the first mechanism that's uh
so the first mechanism for dynamic
information for tracking for Hardware
that supports out of order CPUs
you may be familiar with these logos
they represent Hardware vulnerabilities
difficult to fix but you may know also
extremely difficult to find in the first
place
and there is one fundamental Insight
that makes our work possible and
interesting it is that these bugs and
many others are expressible as
information flows
let me give you some some intuition
so on the left side there is the CPU
core on the right side memory in the
middle some some micro architecture so
let's assume the CPU there's a load from
some privileged data that I first
tainted so up let's do the load buff so
the data along with the taint traverses
the micro architecture
to finally influence some state in the
core
and now if an attacker exfiltrates some
data
it will be quite easy to find in
principle you just look if there's some
orange taint where I did not expect it
so this is something that we want to
achieve
actually there is already one mechanism
that supports Dynamic information for
tracking for Hardware it operates at
gate level it's called lift
what does it mean operating at gate
level means that you take a design a CPU
for example poof you break it down into
very very small element so end Gates or
Gates
registers no actually not even registers
flip-flops sorry and latches so very
small elements and then glyph takes
every of these very small elements very
very many elements but very small
and add some information for tracking
logic around it to track information
flows through each of these very small
elements this is how it works this very
low level of abstraction has drawbacks
critical drawbacks first it creates a
huge netlist that is extremely difficult
to manage for tools
oops sorry uh and also simulators have a
very hard time with it because typically
to be fast a simulator will see higher
level
of abstractions for example it will see
others and when it says and others or a
comparison for example the simulator
just sees oh it's an addition so let's
just run it on the CPU of the machine
instead of you know doing and or Etc
just to simulate an addition doesn't
make sense but here you need to do is
you need to simulate every single
individual gate which is extremely
expensive
so very intuitively we propose to
instrument a higher level of abstraction
the abstraction of macro cells also
called cells in short
which correspond to simple mathematical
operations such as additions comparisons
multiplexers subtractions Etc
and then same thing but for bigger
blocks so for these Bridge blocks I add
some logic around them to track
information flows around them
dynamically the question is what are
these clouds now
this is a new question
let's try again some intuition
so I will look at a combinational cell
which does not have state inside for
example a register would be excluded but
it could be another
so here I give you two tainted inputs in
Orange and I want to know oh is some
output bit tainted or not
you can see for your intuition you can
imagine you have an attacker it controls
the two orange arrows the question is
can the attacker change values on the
output if it only controls the two
orange arrows
let's do the intuitive way I try
everything that an attacker can do 0 0 1
1 up we see that we could toggle the
bottom output bit so it's tainted okay I
continue poof poof we could not affect
the top bit so exactly only the the
bottom bit is dented so this is
something that we want to do
um in practice in Hardware we like to do
stuff in parallel
and actually in this case we even must
and we also need to adapt for the most
complicated uh part which is that
everything is actually tainted as input
because tanks are determined dynamically
whereas the instrumentation is static
so we copy the same cell 16 times this
case 16 times because we have four
inputs so combinations of four inputs
you have 16 two power four and you
provide different inputs for each of
this replica that change only the values
on the orange arrows for example here
you put only zeros to the orange arrows
here one
at the bottom and the rest zeros Etc the
idea is we need to try all the
combinations on the orange arrows
in the end we also compare the outputs
the idea is to know which output is
actually tainted and which was not
changing any of this replica
you may see the problem
imagine you have just one other 64-bit
other this is quite common you need two
power 128 replica of it is you imagine
that this is completely unrealistic
so now the question is how do we get rid
of this exponential dependency so we
have a certain number of inputs
and this if there are many then we have
too many replica how do we make it maybe
a constant number I will show you how to
do only one or two copies one or two
combinations if you prefer
we do it
by identifying three properties of these
cells monotonicity transportability and
translatability here are some cells for
example that correspond to these three
properties
I will limit myself to this cell this
inequality cell but I promise you will
get the big picture
um okay so let's look at what would be
monotonicity here
so here we have two inputs up the left
input if you increase it you can only
decrease the output
on the other side if you increase the
right output there is a change that you
can actually increase
so if you increase the right input sorry
you you may increase the output
so these are some monotonicity
properties and this hints the fact that
you can look at only two combinations or
two replica one that minimizes the
output and one that maximizes the output
all the rest we don't care
example
I tainted arbitrarily two bits on the
right two bits on the left
up first I minimize the output the
maximum is left minimize right
and do the opposite I maximize I say oh
it's tainted if and only if it's toggled
here is toggled answer is Tainted
okay so up to replica Chrome is held of
course this was for a simple case we
have three portrait properties
for a total of 22 combinational cell
types
and also many variants of registers for
example so our implementation is a path
in the USS open source synthesizer for
the people who are not familiar with
that this is the equivalent of a llvm
for Hardware
more or less so we just take a design as
an input on this side so and
this design is a net list of cells
idiomatically
and we output another design which is
the same design but but plus information
flow tracking logic around it a bit like
I explained at the beginning
now let's speak about results
first I will show scalability results
for individual cells for example how
another becomes scalable second which is
the most important in my opinion for a
mechanism how does this scalability now
trans transfer to actual improvements in
actual designs such as CPUs and socs and
finally I will discuss some applications
so this is not as this is the state of
the art so on the y-axis you have the
simulation time and on the x-axis you
have the size of the cell let's focus on
the other so if you think about another
let's take a ripple carrier there you
know so you have this carry chain
and the more input bits you have
equivalently the bigger your other is
the more Elementary Gates you have or
end Gates
and because gate level instrumentation
requires you to to simulate each of
these Gates then the runtime is linear
right ball Gates you know but sell it
towards differently because the lift
adds a constant number of cells and
these cells are run in a constant number
of constant time so constant time
constant
This Is Us constant so this is
scalability results
for individual cells now does it
translate to improvements in real
designs to answer this question we took
five popular risk 5 based designs of
arguably increasing complexity including
a full SOC and including and out of
other CPU
we run quite standard risk five test
benches test benches on it in simulation
and the question is how slower is the
simulation of the instrumented design
compared to the normal design that is
not instrumented
here is the results of this experiment
there is two takeaways first
some more complex designs could not be
instrumented and simulated by the state
of the art even on a one terabyte
machine this doesn't work
because it's so low level requires so
huge netlists for sale lift no problem
for some designs we could instrument and
simulate them with the with the gate
level solution this works however Salif
makes it
much faster
okay finally some applications first
um self allows you very dramatically to
find macro architectural elements
uh that leaks or potentially bailing
data second application we took a
full-fledged SOC and rediscovered bugs
with very simple policies
third we did meltdown experiments found
negative results for Aryan in some
scenarios and in some scenarios we could
confirm positive results and increase
the state of the Arts in terms of
exploitability
on the boom processor
by showing that some scenarios are not
exploitable
and finally we did some spect
experiments with positive and negative
results on boom and we could
quantitatively
evaluate the speculation window of spect
um on boom and the nice thing is in all
these experiments we did not need a
single cash attack so this is also very
new and extremely convenient if you want
to have very precise results
also if you don't want to do cash
attacks because it's boring
um okay time to conclude
celift is the first mechanism that can
instrument and simulate out of the CPUs
or any CPU that we could try
at the time of the writing at least
um it's much faster than the state of
the art for the some designs that could
already be instrumented and simulated
[Music]
um
we have new applications so for example
detecting a leakage through a meltdown
to spec
but we are convinced that
there are new applications that we did
not think about or that we were working
on right now we don't know if they will
succeed
when there is new applications
and to help you debug your own designs
and find new applications and maybe
present them here next year on the year
after or maybe it's five years we may
sell if open source it's also artifact
evaluated I didn't show it here I will
do the best possible to to support you
feel free to try thank you for attention
please ask questions if you need any
future