hello hello everyone I'm igbeck I'm
going to present our worker to write in
the security of GitHub CI workloads the
work was done in collaboration with
interstate and Purity University
let's refresh our knowledge of cicd cicd
basically helps us to automate the
Social Development process the basic
idea of cicd is that developer commits
any kind of changes to the repository
which will on the other hand Trigger the
build and then it will start building
the code and ship to the I don't know
cloud or to the users so cicd is part of
Social Development supply chain and
requires at least the same level of
secure management at the final software
in our opinion
um sorry and what is the GitHub actions
GitHub action is one of uh platforms
that support cicd pipeline such as
Travis Circle CI and others so it has a
lot of features one of the interesting
features is that it supports third party
plugins allows to self-host the runner
itself on your own machines and it uh
you know makes it easier to manage The
Seekers
recent years GitHub action gained
tremendous popularity in usage among
especially open source software because
of its tight integration with the GitHub
itself so you don't developers don't
need to go to the outside you know to
third party and can immediately start
using GitHub actions
let's go a little bit details so what is
the workflow to create the workload you
just need to create the configuration
file under the dot GitHub workflows
folder inside your repository workflow
can be triggered using several execution
triggers the workloads contain several
can contain several jobs that can run
sequentially or in parallel Manner and
each job will contain
several steps and the steps can be
regular commands or it can be basically
third-party plugins that run the code
themselves
and there are in general three ways to
reference third-party plugins which are
using the tag name Branch name or commit
hash
in this paper we've tried to answer to
the three main research questions that
we had is that the first one is what
other secret properties that need to
behold to have a security ICD pipeline
second one is how to does GitHub action
compared to other Cai CD platforms
according to our defined security
properties and how developers basically
use the GitHub actions either using a
secure way or not
we defined in this paper for security
properties which are admittance control
execution control code control and
access to Secrets admissions control is
when only authorized that people can add
add or modify or edit the workflows to
their faster execution control is only
authorized people can basically
configure the triggers for the workflow
code control is when you control what
code run as part of the workflow and
access to Seekers is basically you need
to be keeping your secrets securely and
only steps with direct access to it can
should be able to access the Seekers
uh let's compare GitHub actions default
information with other so in general we
compare the GitHub action with four
different cicd platforms which are
privacy Circle CI Jenkins and gitlab by
default GitHub actions give the right
permission to the code itself
and in addition to that all set in
GitHub workflows runs with
administrative privileges combined with
these two with the permission and the
administrative privileges we think that
it increased the security risk of the
GitHub action in general
and if we compare the plugin system of
GitHub action actions with different CCT
platforms we can see that first of all
it supports the third party plugin as we
discussed previously it does not have
any kind of review as well as all other
cicd platforms for their plugins and
also they GitHub actions plugins are
mutable by mutable what we mean is that
let's imagine we have this yaml
configuration file basically which
depends on some kind of Search battery
plugins and perform some points action
original Behavior so the plugin author
can include any kind of changes to the
plugin itself and which will lead to the
new Behavior inside the cicd pipelines
so developers basically who are have
this configuration file they they will
not be aware of this behavior that is
why we call it kind of mutable because
they can introduce new Behavior without
any kind of change to the configuration
itself
in addition to that we compare the
security properties between GitHub CI
and all other platforms you can read
more details inside our paper here I
just want to stop in one of the
comparisons among the 10 available to
all steps as you can see GitHub actions
allows all the steps to access to the
Seekers for that the steps just need to
read the slash home run under underscore
work work folder and they can access all
the Seekers without having any kind of
direct access to the secret itself
in addition to the security properties
and comparison we perform the
large-scale measurement experiment to
achieve that we gathered the
repository names from GS archive and
basically Chrome the GitHub to get all
their pastors with the workflows that is
available and sort all the workflows
inside the mongodb to further analyze
them you can access all our data sets
from the repositories as you can see in
this slide
um
so during our measurement we had several
questions the first question was uh do a
developers update their default
permissions so GitHub allows you to
update the default permissions of the
workflow if needed but we found that
only 0.2 percent of all the workflows
customize their permissions and among
those only
um you know 62 set workflows to read
only
and the second question was how GitHub
workloads are triggered and other
triggers used in dangerous ways so um by
the dangerous ways we say that it can it
affect the security in general so first
of all I want to mention that before
recently basically it was possible to
introduce the new workflows through a
pull requests to the repository the
attacks were using this to crypto mind
the you know crypto mind basically and
then GitHub itself suggests not to never
use the pull request with the
self-hosted machines why because pull
requests obviously introduce can
introduce new code if you're running the
arbitrary code you know like introduced
by other people on the self-hosted
machines on your own servers it will
lead basically to arbitrary code
execution on your machine
uh the third question was do users
depend on certified plugins we found out
that almost all of their pastors used
the third party plugins
during the analysis we found that there
are at least 11 000 unique actions
without versions and if we consider also
the versions of actions it the number
increased to 19 000. only 2.9 percent of
11 000 were from verified craters by
verified craters you can see the example
that is shown on the slide so here we
have two different actions one from AWS
which is considered to be verified
crater and another is from someone from
the internet
um the first question is how users
reference the search participle icon if
you remember we mentioned that there are
main three ways to reference the third
party plugins check them Branch name and
commit hash the GitHub itself suggests
that you need to use the commit hash so
that it will be non-mutable
but we actually found that you know we
created the POC where we can change the
behavior of the action itself even if if
it was referenced by the commit hash so
check out the paper for more details but
in general only 0.1 percent of uh
references are using the commit hash so
developers do not follow the security
guidelines
the fifth question was how users pass
the secrets so there was 50 of
repository that passed the secrets
um these secrets were passed to 4 000
different uh actions and only eight
percent of them were from verified
creators as we discussed previously
um all steps can have the access to the
secrets itself so we found that there is
more than 5 000 clients which have
indirect access to the secrets and only
0.9 percent of them are from verified
craters you can see the example of the
indirect access and direct access on the
right hand side the example
the final question we had was do
developer do workloads depend on
vulnerable plugins
since this was not our main you know
question of the paper we approached this
very naively we just used the existing
tool called gitbull finder which looks
for the keywords from inside the commit
hashes and detects if this commit
basically trying to fix any kind of
security issues so after analyzing the
output of it manually spending a lot of
time on that we find that at least 500
repastors depend on actions or plugins
that have some words High severity
vulnerability
in conclusion we Define fossil created
Property that must be held in such in
cicd Pipeline and compare the GitHub
action with other cicd platforms we
performed the measurement study of
GitHub workloads how developers use that
so basically the conclusion that
developers do not follow any kind of
security guidelines created by GitHub
only 0.2 percent of your pastors update
the default permissions you know there
are close to 300 wrappers that use the
pull request triggers workflows that run
in the cell forces machines almost all
of the Surf Party plugin references are
mutable and there are more than 500
syllables that reference the action
version with high Savers vulnerability
we notified all of this
um authors and basically some of them
get patched
we have some of the results back in the
papers for details
takeaway is that cicd right now has
become you know highly depend on
certified plugins when in in you know in
late it was mostly you know best script
kind of things but right now it's
depends on a lot of third-party plugins
despite the security guidelines
developers do not follow the guidelines
therefore platforms might need to have
secure default settings instead of
trusting users to use it securely in
chcd platforms require more research
from security professions you can check
out our paper and projects using the
website and the repository and feel free
to ask questions on slack or directly
after the talk thank you