foreign
my name is yuchen Zhang from Stevens
Institute of Technology and it is my
great honor to present our work a deep
floating address sanitizer today the
co-authors are chong bing pong from 19
University Professor Georges Puerto
caledis from Stevens Institute of
Technology Professor Nicos Trent Douglas
from Stevens as well and Professor
jinshu from the University of Utah
so before I started presenting our work
I would like to give some background
information about sanitizers which are
Dynamic code analysis tools here are the
current supportive sanitizers by Google
the first one is address Enticer or
so-called asan for detecting
addressability issues and the thread
sanitizer
to detect the data race and Deadlocks
and memory sanitizer for detecting use
of uninitialized memory and ubisan for
detect
undefined behaviors
and our work is focusing on optimizing
and improving the performance of address
sanitizer
so what is asan
it is the most popular sanitizer for
vulnerability detection which focuses on
memory safety violations in Heap stack
and Global objects
the magnesium for Acer is to insert
poisoned resonance around objects and
Report error when program access the
Forbidden bytes
so here from the graph we can see for
each Heap stack or Global objects they
are surrounded by RedZone and if the
program tries to access those Red Zone
at runtime Nissan will abort the
execution process and Report error with
a detailed bug report
next I'm going to present the motivation
of our work
that even though address sanitizer is
powerful but there's still trade-offs
for using Asen that is asan causes high
runtime overhead and from spec CPU 2006
the average overhead that ASAP brings is
a
107.8 percent
and the instrumented applications
testing also costs a lot in Computer
Resources quoted from the sanitizer
maintainer in Google
in the long run faster binary equals or
greater than more bugs caught
so driven by our motivation
we first present a study to answer the
question what brings the overhead of
Asin the answer is sentencer checks they
are the primary source of Ace and
overhead which is attributed to an
overhead of 86.5 percent which is 80.8
percent of old overhead
our study also dissects the rest of Ace
overhead where they come from and for
details please refer to our paper
as we indicated in the previous Slide
the sentencer checks are the primary
source of adjacentizer performance
overhead
here let's see from an example
on the left side we have an array with
size 10 and then we're trying to access
the 10th position of that array by
indexing
and on the right side is the
corresponding lvm IR code the
instructions that in Redbox is the
sanitizer check inserted by ASAP and
please note for every memory accessing
Json will insert sanitizer check
therefore the runtime overhead of asan
goes up
next I'm going to present our tool
deploying address sanitizer or we call
it A7 minus minus
we Implement a group of optimization
strategies to reduce the sanitizer
checks of Asa first we remove the
unsatisfiable checks second we remove
the recurrency checks then we optimize
the neighbor checks and finally we
optimize the checks in loops
our two is on minus minus can reduce
address sanitizer runtime overhead while
keeping the bug detection ability
and our tool is applicable to spec CPU
2006 and the chromium showing the
scalability
finally we integrated our optimizations
into lvm for high usability and thus no
extra cost for building the tool
now I'm going to talk about the details
about our proposed solution for
optimizing address sanitizer first is
the removing alongside disable check
let's see an example together
on the left side we have a buffer with
size 20 in line 2. and we then try to
access the eye position by indexing into
the buffer
so can this buffer be overflowed
the answer is no the buffer will never
overflow because in line 4
the if statement has already guaranteed
that the value of I were always less
than or equal to 10. so the index to
buffer will always inbounds and thus the
center check that inserted by Asin in
line 5 can be safely removed
next is removing the recurrenting checks
and how we do that
let's first Define what is recurrency
check
from the example on the left side we can
see in line 3 is uncheck 1 and in line 5
is on check 2 are checking the same
value pointer p
and check one dominates check two in
another word if check 2 will be executed
no matter what the check one will be
executed first
therefore ASA and check 2 in line 5 is
recurrentine check and the safety of
pointer P has been guaranteed by check 1
in line three
so we can also safely remove the
Redundant check without losing any
safety
and as for optimizing labor checks if
there are two memory access that
accessing the neighbor memories such as
accessing structured fields in the
example on the left
we can merge those Ascent Checks In Line
6 and in line 8 into one check
we also Implement a fast slow path
strategy to secure the detection
accuracy
the faster path will check multiple
Shadow bits at once
and if it fails the slow path will be
triggered and do the regular instant
check
on each Shadow byte then aboard the
current execution
finally
we also optimize the center check in
loops
there are two scenarios we apply our
strategy
first if the indexing value to a buffer
is monotonic increasing or decreasing as
shown in line 6 on the left side
we merge the check by checking multiple
Shadow bites at once as I presented in
the previous slide
and the second scenario is the sanitizer
check is repeating multiple times on the
same value which is not cost effective
as for inline 9. the pointer ptr2 will
not change during the loop iteration
so we move the check in line 7 out of
the loop and only execute once
by this way we can efficiently reduce
the number of execution times of same
sanitizer check
after briefly introducing our two ways
and minus minus now it's time for
evaluations
first the party is a performance
overhead analysis by applying all of the
optimization strategies on spec CPU 2006
the runtime overhead that ASAP brings
drops from
107.8 percent to 63.3 percent
and for chromium the runtime overhead
drops from
117.8 percent to 75.8 percent the
performance evaluation shows our two
ways and minus minus can efficiently
reduce the overhead that caused by Asin
next I'm going to present the bug
detection capability
after applying our tool on three
benchmarks the Julia tester suit
the Linux floor project and the chromium
project
for all benchmarks we compiled with both
ASA and A7 minus minus
then comparing the detection detected
box result
finally we verify that A7 is a minus
minus achieve the identical results
our tool can also bring extra benefit to
fasting
it is very popular to combine fuzzing
and address sanitizer together for bug
detection nowadays and fuzzing
benchmarks compiled with Ace and minus
minus increased execution speed of AFL
by 42.1 percent and the increase of
execution speed leads to a growth rate
of 5 in Branch coverage
in conclusion
adding instant in applications converts
the performance and the sanitizer check
contributes the most
but our two is a minus minus can
efficiently reduce the performance
overhead meanwhile maintain the
capability scalability and usability
efficient it can benefit the
applications that compiled with Asa and
reduced overhead of Asin by 41.7 percent
of spec CPU 2006. and by 35 of chromium
in addition it also benefits fuzzing
tests with asan enabled applications and
the increased execution speed and the
branch coverage
our work passed the artifact evaluation
and got all the badges now has been open
sources on GitHub please refer to the
link for more implementation details and
thanks for listening I'm now opening for
any questions