foreign
today I'm gonna present DND a course
architecture deep new network decompiler
deep new YouTube Newark networks DNS
have been implemented and deployed on
many devices so to support many
applications such as facial recognition
speech recognition and anomaly detection
when deployment dedicated compilers are
used to compile the data model into
binary such as Glo ntvm
these binaries are usually deployed on
each devices such as a Facebook
connection camera
in this work we explore the possibility
of decompiling their binaries during
binary different boundaries the
compilation has many security
applications
such as
stealing stealing stealing their models
and turning black balls at also attack
into a more effective weapons adversal
attack
for example the figure below shows that
after adding some imperceptible noises
the deal model will miss classify a stop
sign as a teddy bear
before we discuss about the binary
compilation let me first give some
backgrounds
the figure below shows a snippet of a
resnet model in Linux format the only X
format represents a new network as a
computation graph each node in the graph
is a different operator
the DNA operators are the building
blocks of DNN
there are various types of data
operators with different mathematical
semantics
currently there are 174 different
operators defined in online X
it includes a convolution average poor
and value
field model semantics include operator
level semantics such as this type
attributes and parameters
and model level semantics include
topology
which defines how The Operators are
connected with each other
to compile data into binary
ahead of time compilation is usually
used
it specializes the operator according to
its according to its attributes and
parameters
for instance here the highlighted
convolution 2 and conclusion 3. although
they share the same operator type but
because of their different attributes
and parameters they are they are
compiled into two different binary
functions with very different control
flow and data flow structure
general purpose the compilers are used
to recover C language level syntactics
from the binary however they have
several limitations when dealing with
gun binaries
here we saw a snippet clear visual code
of a either product correlation results
of a single convolution operator
instance
as you can see it contains 348 lines of
codes
with multiple long loose bodies and many
bitwise operations
if I were a reverse engineer
I have totally no idea what this
function is doing
instead our system tnd can recover
high-level DNA semantics from the binary
and output the and output the option
model in Ox format such as the figure
below
it includes all the high level semantics
such as operator type attributes and
parameters
since this objective is to recover these
models in onx format from the binaries
renewing CPU devices
is to be generic to support different
compilers and essays and it should be
accurate to recover the models with high
accuracy
let me first give a give an overview of
our pipeline at a very at the very
beginning given the binary we locate the
function the binary function that
Implement digital operator
and for each for every uh for each
located operator function we generate an
operator summary represented with the IR
redesign which is capable of capturing
its mathematical semantics
and at the very last we recover the high
level model semantics and output the
model in our next format
and now I I've given some details of
each step in the first step we look for
the binary function with certain
structures including Neti loops and
vectorized computations
these functions are identified as the
function that implement the Eternal
operator
note that our systems work at the binary
level but for easy understanding we will
show we are showing source code as our
running example in the following slides
and in in the next step we generate an
operator summary for each located binary
function which captures multiple
semantics to do so we first conduct a
loop analysis to identify the induction
variables and the information
Loop in induction variables also also
called Loop index
for example there are the variables ijuv
showing the figure
and also identify their information such
as initial value step size and loop
count
then we symbolize the identified
induction variables and conduct some
body execution to extract an expression
that represents the output of of this
function
using its input and parameters
for example here is here it is the
expression we extract from this binary
function
then we leave the extracted Expressions
into our into open summary represented
with rir
for example here we leave the expression
on the left to the operation on the
right
where we replace the plus equal on the
left to the summation function define
lyr and multiplication with
multiplication with multiplication
function in lyr
we also attach the induction variables
indicating the all the possible ranges
of each Loop index for instance for the
variable U is that its ranges is from 0
to 1.
and after operators are summary
generation we finally recover the dtn
high level semantics
first we have the operator type for each
operator function with the SD matching
we have a referenced SD database in
advance which Maps each operator to its
corresponding St
for instance here is the reference
density of a convolution operator
then we match the LST in operating
summary with all of the references
we consider the operator type as that of
a reference St if their asts are matched
for instance here we uh we match the
opacity included in operating summary
with the reference entity of convolution
and it succeeds so we consider it as a
convolution operator
we then recover the Indian topology by
leveraging the data dependencies between
each DNA operate function
for instance here we identify that the
output of conclusion 1 and the input of
constant 3 are pointing to the same
memory address
so we are so we infer this age from
convolution 1 to conclusion 3.
and very last we recovered attributes
and parameters of each of each of each
operator function by leveraging operator
summary and generate and the recovered
in topology
for instance here we recover the values
of filter by extracting from the
corresponding memory address
evaluation first we value generality by
evaluating how many widely used steel
model we can support
we consider module supported when all of
its operators are supported
we collect 37 DN models from 1x2 and ml
proof tiny benchmarks carving 70 deal
models sorry currently covering 70
different operators
and our evaluations shows that our
system can support 84 of operator
it in turns enables support for 81 of
the models
we also evaluate the correctness of a
system
by checking if our season can decompile
a dealer model and generate a
generator model that is equivalent to
the original one
we test with 15 different binaries
they are compiled with two compilers
three isas and three models
We compare their inference results given
10 000 test inputs
and I will ensure that we can decompile
OD binaries with 100 accuracy
for example here we showed architecture
of the original resident model
and the architecture of the decompiled
resident model generated by our system
and as you can see they have the
identical architecture and we further
test with 10 000 input and show that
they have the same influence inference
Behavior
we conduct case studies on a real world
microcontroller with a resnet model is
deployed
we saw that our system can successfully
steal the model from the board
specifically we dump the binary from the
board and to compile the binary with our
system
and we verify the correctness of the
compile model by showing that they have
the identical inference results
we saw so that
the decompile model can be used to boot
that result attack
with the decompile model we launched
white box attack which successfully
reduced the accuracy from 88 with the
original input to the 11 with the
variables input
while the Bible attacks can only degrade
accuracy to 57.
in summary the compiling during binaries
requires customized techniques with
students basic knowledge
we propose DND the first compiler for
compiling binaries
and it is open source on GitHub
and thank you I'm ready to take
questions