foreign
hey I'm Jess I'm going to introduce our
system Audi which is a compiler for ZK
snarks that provides support for
optimization problems
um obviously we're going to do this with
zero knowledge that's why we're here
so let's say you need to solve an
optimization problem you need to prove
that you solved it correctly but your
problem involves sensitive data that you
don't want to reveal for example
maybe you're a school and you're
admitting a new class of students and
you want to prove that you've selected
the best or most optimal incoming class
but you don't want to reveal your
admissions criteria and you don't want
to leak the data of your potential
students
maybe have a certain GPA requirement
maybe have a class cap maybe you require
extracurriculars whatever
um so as a school you can generate a
commitment to your specific admissions
criteria this hides the criteria but it
binds the school system to it so they're
consistent in admission and the school
want to maximize some objective function
and this function can select students
such as the incoming class is optimal
for them and then the school also wants
to ensure their linear constraints so
you can formulate this as a linear
optimization problem
so then students apply to the school
um the School commits to their data
the school can then prove to everybody
that for some set of applicants those
who are granted the mission were the
best choice for the school given its
criteria and they can do this in zero
knowledge without leaking any
information about their criteria or
about the data of specific students
this is obviously a contrived example
but optimization problems are everywhere
notably resource allocation scheduling
and neural network training
Audi handles three classes of these
optimization problems which are linear
programming semi-definite programming
and stochastic gradient descent and to
improve optimality for all of these
classes in zero knowledge
so how would we go about doing this the
naive way would be to encode the entire
solver as a Boolean or an arithmetic
circuit or some other intermediate
representation like rank one constraints
that can be consumed by a zero knowledge
backend
um and by solver here I just made a
program that solves the optimization
problem
so our school admissions example is a
linear program and that can be solved
with the Simplex algorithm for something
like stochastic gradient descent you can
just run the stochastic grading discount
algorithm for many iterations until it
converges
and as we saw these circuits are very
big
um the features like unbounded Loops
features like Ram operations floating
Point can cause a huge blow up in these
circuits
um
for example if you have a loop that's
dependent on runtime data you have to
copy it a million times and pick some
large upper bound because you don't know
how many times it's going to run
the largest linear programming problem
that we were able to compile to a
circuit in this way only had five
equations and five variables and It
produced an arithmetic circuit with
about a million multiplication Gates
which is obviously pretty far from what
we would want in like a real world
instance so we need to avoid this
so what Audi does is Audi says well we
don't really care how approver like the
school in our example finds the optimal
solution we don't care what solver they
use or how efficient it is or what
external libraries they use whatever all
we care about is that the solution is
optimal and it turns out for many
classes of optimization problems there's
a particular structure such that
checking the solution is optimal is much
cheaper than Computing the solution
itself
um and what I mean by structure is um
you can think about sorting you can
check that a list is sorted by just
going through and saying like is every
element bigger than the last element and
is the output and the input contain the
same elements I mean that's faster than
running something like quick sort or
merge sort or whatever
um so what Audi does is instead of
encoding the entire solver in the proof
the proofer just computes the solution
and supplies it as non-deterministic
input to the proof then the proof is
just this very small check that the
solution is optimal and this check is
very practical it doesn't need to use
Loops or Ram or whatever and so you can
use it to solve realistic instances and
it is completely automatable
so to roadmap thrust the talk for you
I'm going to show you how ADI does this
for linear programming you can see our
paper for semi-definite programming and
stochastic gradient descent problems
since those techniques are a little bit
different and that'll give you a high
level description of Audi's pipeline how
you compile a programming ID and then I
will conclude
so linear programming problems are
always of this form you want to find
some Vector that maximizes an objective
function subject to a matrix of linear
constraints and in optimization Theory
this direct translation is just called
the Primal problem
and any linear optimization problem can
be viewed from another perspective this
is called the Dual problem
if a primal problem is a maximization
problem the Dual problem is a
minimization problem and vice versa is
basically a turn of the problem
in linear programming if there's a
feasible solution to a bounded problem
the corresponding problem also has a
feasible solution both problems have an
optimal solution and the optimal Primal
and dual Solutions produce the same
objective value and this is called
strong duality
um
because of strong Duality we can create
a very short short certificate to check
the optimality of our solution
um so what it does you can imagine okay
if we're given solutions to our Primal
dual problems X star and Y star just
drops from the sky all we need to check
is that X is indeed a solution to the
Primal problem Y is indeed the solution
to the Dual problem and that strong
Duality holds their objective values are
the same and then that implies that they
these Solutions are optimal
I mean this is great because it doesn't
require any Loops it doesn't require Ram
it doesn't require external libraries it
can be encoded as a much much smaller
arithmetic circuit than the entire
solver can and since the circuit is so
small it is finally practical to prove
optimization problems in zero knowledge
how practical
here are the results of running Audi on
a sequence of problems in the netlib
linear programming Library
which is a benchmarking library that
they use to manage Mark linear
optimization solvers
and for us these instances audio
produces proofs under 50 kilobytes
the biggest instance we're able to able
to compile over here on the far side of
the slide had 400 equations and 2700
variables and it only produced a proof
of 81 kilobytes and for comparison the
proof that I talked about before with
five variables and five constraints also
produced a proof of that size so now we
can for the same cost we can get 400
equations and 2700 variables
so
let's talk about the compilation process
first you input an optimization problem
let's say this is a linear Primal
problem the prover uses any solver it
wants to find the solution
for example in the linear programming
case this might be simplex and as far as
audio is concerned this this Soul versus
Black Box it can use any optimizations
you can use it on any hardware or
whatever you want
I mean it produces our solutions to our
Primal and dual problems
Audi then can automatically generate the
certificate for this problem and compile
it from C to rank one constraints
um it uses Cersei to do this which is a
circuit compiler and then it uses the
Spartan proof system to generate azk
snark for the certificate
prover can send this proof to verifier
along with the Primal and dual Solutions
the verifier then uses Spartan to check
the proof and it can either accept or
reject and if it accepts the proof it
can be sure that the solution it has
received is the optimal solution to the
problem and no information has been
leaked
to zoom in onto the verifiers view for a
second here's what the certificate over
here on the far side of the slide
actually looks like to the verifier
the verifier gets a satisfying solution
to the optimization problem
in our school example this might
represent a list of admitted students
the Dual solution flaw is also provided
it can be provided as a public input or
as a private witness to the problem
depending on your application
the linear constraints of the problem
ABC
I mean our school example this is like
the admissions criteria and like the
students data
um is hidden behind the commitment
so the verify learns the structure of
the problem but it doesn't learn any of
the data it learns how big it is what
the the certificate looks like but all
the data is hidden
so as I said before I'm not going to
cover semi-definite programming or
stochastic gradient descent you can see
the paper for that but here is a quick
view of how awesome our tool is for it
we ran it on real world data sets also
used to Benchmark you know semi-definite
programming solvers Etc
um
sorry
we prove full training for perceptrons
um and semi-definite programming we
prove stuff on topology design control
systems engineering
Etc
um
there's been previous work done on like
inference proofs for um machine learning
and on training of like select
iterations but as far as I know this is
the first time we've been able to like
prove full training of realistic ml
models in zero knowledge and it's only
80 kilobytes which is pretty cool
body has some limit has some limitations
it has some areas for improvement we
still have an upper size limit it's
still hard to create proofs for very big
optimization instances
um I think we topped out at about 3 000
variables for linear programming and
stochastic gradient descent topped out
at data sets of about 200 features
the bottleneck is
um
not actually proving but it's the
encoding of the problem is rank one
constraints which takes a lot of time
and memory I mean you could imagine
Outsourcing that compilation to some
trusted third party that will compile it
for you ahead of time and then you'll do
you know your proof of verifier protocol
separately
but there are situations you wouldn't
want to trust a third party
um so it's still sort of a limitation um
problems have to have a specific
structure like semi-definite programming
problems need to have certain
feasibility requirements to satisfy
strong Duality
um stochastic gradient descent problems
half convergence requirements they have
to satisfy
and there's an overhead as compared to
solvers that don't produce proofs
obviously it takes longer to produce a
proof even if the proof is small
audio is still pretty good it uses
non-determinism pretty aggressively and
effectively to reduce proof sizes it
automates away all the optimization math
all the zero knowledge math the
conversions between tools you have to do
and it generates proof of optimality
that are practical for real world
applications and it does this much
better than any existing approach
all of our code and our artifact is
available online please go look at it
thank you guys for your time