foreign
s I'm a PhD student at the University of
Washington advised by Francis rosener
and tarayoshikono today I'm going to
talk about some work we did in
collaboration with the legal scholar
Anita Alim an electronic monitoring
smartphone apps and first I'm going to
give an example to motivate how someone
might come to use one of these apps
so imagine you're at a protest you're
having a good time exercising your your
right to organize in the U.S and then
someone standing next to you throw
something at the police say a rock or
like a Pepsi or something right and then
the police all of a sudden rush over to
you grab you and five other people near
you right and you're arrested and you're
taken to jail right and within 24 hours
you have your arraignment some court
date you go before a judge and you say
to the judge you know I didn't do this
it wasn't me somebody else I didn't I
didn't I didn't have a Pepsi that day
and the judge says well you know one of
the police officers said it was you we
got to look at the body camera footage
your court dates in a month and so I'll
release you now into your court date but
instead of the traditional cash bill
that we used to have say it would be ten
thousand dollars we're giving you an app
and you have to install this app on your
phone and you have to do check-ins and
you have to have a good relationship
with your your release supervisor and if
you fail to the check-ins properly you
could be incarcerated and brought back
to jail so do you accept these
conditions and of course you as the
security and privacy researcher you're
very concerned about this you're like
what is this app doing you know what day
what day does it collect who does is in
the data too but you you of course
accept and you're released
and these apps are real they're a new
form of electronic monitoring electronic
monitoring is a subset of Community
Supervision Community Supervision is
either an alternative to be incarcerated
or after someone is released from from
being incarcerated so for example
probation parole released from immigrant
or Juvenile Detention and in this
example I mentioned released from
pre-trial detention
and normally people who are under
Community Supervision they must comply
with several conditions such as curfews
visits drug tests supervision fees often
people who under a community supervision
have to make fees for their supervision
and historically this this technology
used for electronic monitoring has been
ankle monitors and Ankle monitors are
still using their uses actually still
growing but in addition to ankle monitor
there are smartphone apps that are being
rolled out for people under Community
Supervision and it's really hard to get
numbers on these specifically app usage
but the biggest public numbers we could
find were usage by ice for immigration
detection so right now around 100 000
people are using these smartphone apps
after being released from immigration
detention the second largest number we
could find publicly available was being
used for probation by Virginia state
prisons around over a little bit over 10
000 people
right and so these apps are primarily
used for checking in with one supervisor
as I mentioned uh this could either be
in lieu or in addition to traditional
in-person meetings that happen with the
supervisor under Community Supervision
and these check-ins might require you to
have your location enabled you might ask
there might be some face and voice
recognition involved and if you're part
of a drug some drug treatment program
you might have to use like a Bluetooth
breathalyzer for example as part of this
this these check-ins and so there's an
image on the left that shows an example
of what a check-in looks like for one of
these apps that we looked at so this
check-in specifically requires you hold
the phone in front of you you have your
front camera on you read off a series of
randomly generated numbers and you have
to do that within a certain period of
time right so this one example of what a
check-in could look at
and as I mentioned before Phil you
should successfully check in can lead to
incarceration really depends a lot on
your your supervisor sometimes it might
just take one failure sometimes it might
take multiple but yeah this this could
lead to your you're going back to jail
so this is a you can you can kind of
recognize that this might be a problem
here there's these high stake apps can
result in you being incarcerated that
have been audited to evaluate their data
practices or what privacy Miss they may
introduce to the people who use them
right and so based on this we had
several research questions about these
apps
primarily first what are the experiences
and concerns that people coerced to use
these apps and we we answered this
research question through qualitative
analysis of qualitative analysis of
reviews and the Google Play Store
secondly we want to know what the
Privacy related technical properties of
these apps were and so to answer this
question we did some static and limited
Dynamic analysis of these apps we found
16 Android apps in total that are
currently being used for electronic
monitoring we also did a case study of
the least and most privileged apps I say
limited Dynamic analysis because to use
these apps you need to get credentials
to log into them and those credentials
come from your supervisor so since we
weren't actually using the apps we
didn't have credential credentials to
log into them so all of our analysis is
pre-authentication we still have some
interesting findings that I'll talk
about a bit later
uh do these apps privacy policies align
with our observations of what we saw in
our technical analysis is that
reflecting in the Privacy policies and
of course we answered this question
through qualitative analysis of the
app's privacy policies and what legal
protections if any exist for people
under electronic monitoring and we
collaborated with a legal scholar to
answer this question because the time is
limited today I'm going to focus focus
on the first research question and the
case studies from the second research
question but of course for more details
you can you can see the paper
so before that some ethical
considerations right we saw IRB approval
for the study and we redeemed exempt but
despite that we follow best practices
for connecting research with publicly
available information
when we started analyzing the Privacy
policies for these apps we noticed that
7 out of the 16 didn't have adequate
privacy policies up that followed Google
Play Store's policies so either the
privacy policy didn't exist there or the
Privacy policies didn't mention the apps
at all and so we reached out to these
companies we notified them that we're
going to let Google know in a month if
they're in violation of these policies
one of the companies have to be reached
out correctly and added information
about the apps into their policies but
the rest didn't respond and we reached
out to Google in early uh early summer
so it's your results what are the
experiences and concerns of people who
are of course use these apps from
analyzing the reviews a common issue
that we found was that there are
malfunctions with these apps that
prevent people from successfully
performing check-ins right and as I
mentioned before the seconds are
requirement of using these apps and
these malfunctions were typically caused
by failures and facial or voice
recognition systems or location failures
so for example people say when they
wanted to do a check-in they were
wearing a mass they had to take their
mask off if they were wearing makeup
sometimes the phone wouldn't recognize
them similarly people mentioned just
being asleep and then the phone's
location I guess detection system was
off and they were woken up in the middle
of night by alarm saying that they'd
gone outside of a zone that they were
weren't supposed to be in
uh similarly these apps cause disruption
for people there were these loud alerts
that overrid their phones volume
settings and often set their volume to
max even if they're wearing headphones
now people talked about how these apps
could consume significant battery in
space one of the reviews said
specifically that someone that that the
app consumed battery on their phone so
quickly that they had to buy an external
battery pack and carry it around so that
the phone wouldn't die and they wouldn't
get in trouble and lastly the reviews
mentioned that these apps calls
operating system crashes and freezes
which is particularly concerning as we
know these One requirement of using
these apps is that they're available all
the time so that your supervisor can see
what you're doing and if these apps
themselves cause the phone to crash you
could be setting people up for failure
uh people describe a general sense of
Injustice in some of the reviews I have
one quote here that I'm going to read in
full there's a lot more great quotes in
the paper I hope you have a chance to
look at it this person says I'm a drug
court client in Phase five I've been in
the program over a year done very well
I'm worried about this app it does not
work very well the developers should be
ashamed of themselves this is my
sobriety and freedom that's at stake
this app has the ability to destroy all
I've worked so hard for please fix it or
takes it down your money is is not worth
my freedom
so now on to our case studies of the
least and most privileged app and what
are their privacy properties in the
study we found that the most privileged
app was sprocket and the least
privileged app was was uptrust
so here's a screenshot on the right from
sprocket and one of the app that we
found to be the most privileged it says
like no tracking but our our results
kind of differ from that uh sprocket
requested the most runtime permission
also known as dangerous permissions out
of all the apps that we looked at
at the most third party libraries out of
any of the apps we looked at nine
including ad libraries which is can you
be concerning because it might imply
that someone's profiting from people
being course to use these apps
and lastly Sprocket was the only app we
observed pre-authentication that sent
that had time driven requests so they
sent data to Facebook uh every five
minutes now this data was was generally
uh General device information such as
battery amount of space you have if the
device is rooted or not Etc but it's
still surprising that that some apps had
time driven this was only at the time
driven request pre-authentication
on the other hand uptrust was the least
privilege app we saw Chris is zero
runtime or dangerous permissions I had
three third-party libraries and on their
website they specifically say they don't
geolocate or have a user-funded model
meaning that people who use the app
don't have to don't have to pay for it
so looking for it right these em apps
they introduce new harms and rest of the
people required to use them there are
few limits on what these apps can do
from a legal perspective we expand on
these two points a lot in the paper but
their proliferation is not inevitable
there are these municipalities around
the country that are Banning other forms
of car show Technologies right and I
think at Marketplace app marketplaces
definitely have a role to play in this
so for example Google play they block
certain types of apps from being on
their platforms so apps that block ads
or apps that help people cheat at games
if they wanted to you know they consider
blocking idiom apps or if not blocking
them entirely they can consider
increasing transparency requirements for
these apps because they're so high
stakes
um
and I think computer science researchers
can do a lot of a lot of good in this
space and I'll expand on this point this
point more so there's lots of other
forms of car show technologies that are
impacting people there's these ankle
monitors of course but there's also
wearables for recidivism prediction
there's mental health prediction tools I
think because as security and privacy
researcher we have these reversing
skills we can audit Technologies we can
collaborate with legal Scholars policy
makers Community organizations to try to
figure out how to help reduce the harms
of Technology potentially make
technology that that helps people and
although it isn't you know unnecessary
to understand how things how things work
in detail to understand the potential
harm they could cause I think is very
helpful so thank you for your time