foreign
hello everyone yes I'm my name is mohsen
and this is a joint work with my
colleagues Monarch mondel from iot
karagpur and my PhD advisor aniket Kate
from Purdue University
over the years social media has become a
platform where individuals share their
thoughts and personal information which
is viewed by a wide variety of audiences
in some cases these contents contain
some damaging or sensitive information
which a malicious data collector can
leverage to exploit the individuals
moreover the steps and actions that us
as users take to change our privacy
preferences or when we want to hide our
unwanted information can help the
malicious entity to discover the
sensitive content this is also known as
the styrosine effect which some of us
might be familiar with
so with that in mind let's look at some
cases where users try to hide their
unwanted information by deleting them
in the first category we have the
publicization of the deleted post of the
celebrities and politicians which most
of us might have seen a few in the news
however we see that this is not limited
to celebrities Philippa Supreme which
translates to should not delete is a
Twitter account that publishes the
deleted tweets of not only celebrities
and politicians but also normal daily
French users for example here you're
seeing a tweet and retweet of an
individual that was removed and this
user has less than 1 000 followers
we also find that the problem associated
with content deletion is not limited to
target attacks in fact there exists
multiple web services that are finding
and hoarding deleted content across
different social platforms some of which
are presented on the slide and later
this information can be used against the
users
uh also by looking into the different
deletion mechanisms we see that deletion
privacy involves designing and enforcing
access control rules to regulate when
and how information about the deletion
events are revealed to others and
unfortunately earlier research did not
attempt to uncover these systematic
access rules
and more specifically there's no prior
work on understanding the need for
providing deletion privacy to the social
media users
so in this work you take the first steps
toward understanding users perception of
deletion privacy
we came up with three main research
questions first is the user's
experiences with deletion on the social
platforms and the second is the content
one what contextual factors do rules
regarding the acceptability of revealing
deletion events depend on
and lastly we want to know whether the
existing mechanisms today are effective
and useful for providing privacy to the
users
to answer our research questions we
conducted a user study on prolific
academic we recruited a total of 205
skilled participants from us and Europe
where our European participants were
from 13 different countries but the
majority of them were from UK followed
by Portugal and Poland
after discarding the responses that did
not pass our validian sanity checks we
ended up with almost a even split
between us and Europe
the survey time took about 25 minutes on
average across all the participants and
we found that our sample was nearly
gender balanced where 51 percent were
identified themselves as female and 48
as male
our participants were slightly more
educated than the general U.S population
where 55 of the participants either had
a bachelor's or a graduate degree
and despite the fact that uh
participants in crowds crowdsourcing
platforms are considered to be very tech
savvy 67 of our participants reported
that they don't have any background
experience in the I.T field
however our participants uh were
concerned were considered active users
of social platforms where 75 percent of
them were daily users and 91 were using
the platforms at least once a week
since we are short in time in the
following state I'm just going to
highlight the main findings and I invite
you all to look at the paper for more
details
uh we started off by investigating the
deletion patterns of the users we saw
that among 191 participants 82 percent
of them reported that they actually have
deleted the post in the past
and interesting enough more than
one-third of all the deletions were have
happened for the posts that were
published more than seven days
this shows that the old post on social
platforms are not necessarily forgotten
or ignored and users actively care about
them and remove the unwanted ones
uh the top reason for post deletions was
identified as close becoming irrelevant
As Time passed which goes back to the
previous point of like out the uh
deleting the outdated post other reasons
that were mentioned were fixing spelling
and grammar issues post not getting
enough attention cleaning up the profile
for a new job or relationship but we
also saw a significant number of
participants reporting some sensitive
topic for the reason of their deletions
such as alcohol drug race politics
sexual content violence and some others
uh which brings us to our next point
where more than half of the participants
thought that indeed deleted posts hide
some sensitive and damaging information
about the users
for our second research question that we
wanted to answer what contextual factors
does deletion privacy depend on we used
a contextual Integrity Theory to create
a set of contextual variables to collect
their users feedback in our survey
again I cannot go into the details
because of time but contextual Integrity
allows us to Define privacy as
appropriate flows of information which
in our case was a total of 900 that we
investigated
the most negative flows uh where for the
cases that deletions are noticed by
large-scale data collectors such as a
third-party company or the government
compared to other social groups such as
family members friends and even their
co-workers
we also saw that deleted posts that the
subject of the post was the users
themselves required more protection than
any other subject
inside the polls
also not knowing how deletions were
notices were considered not accessible
to the users which is consistent with
the human desire for cognitive closure
and interestingly enough uh hiding the
post that did not get enough attention
was the most concern for the users
uh we also look into the
demographic differences and we found
that the higher income users were more
concerned about their deletions and
those that ended their relationship in
the past uh were more conservative about
their deletions being noticed
we also saw some differences between you
uh U.S and European participants where
co-workers social group was considered
much a closer group in the U.S than
Europe
and uh
someone's talking the user's account was
more of a concern for the European
participants than the U.S participants
and finally uh European female
participants and older Asian Europeans
were more conservative about their
deletions compared to the U.S
counterparts
next we compared the utility of four
different mechanisms by showing the
participants a one to two minute video
for each of them
the first mechanism is the selective
deletions which is the most popular
method of deleting content today in this
mechanism the user's posts remain
available until the user themselves
select uh unwanted post and delete them
specifically
next we have pre-scheduled deletion
which removes the user's content from a
specific criteria is met for example a
predefined time or a period of
inactivity
for example Snapchat or Instagram
stories are removed after some period of
time
next we have the intermittent withdrawal
mechanism that offers a deniability
guarantee for users deletions using
availability privacy trade-off this work
was presented in pets 2019.
and the last mechanism is called decoy
deletions where a set of decoy posts are
chosen from a pool of benign
crowdsourced posts and deleted along
with the damaging post as a result the
adversary's task just becomes harder in
identifying the damaging one among all
the deleted posts
so after presenting the video uh we
asked the following question for each of
the mechanism we asked them how
effective is that mechanism in hiding
the damaging and sensitive post of their
users in presence of a large-scale
adversary that they were concerned in
the second research question
the results showed that more than half
of the participants think that the most
used deletion mechanism which is the
selective deletion is not effective in
providing privacy for the deleted post
on the other hand they find that three
mechanisms to be more effective but in
our results we didn't see any static
statistical differences between these
three
we also investigated the usefulness of
each of these mechanisms by asking the
users to describe cases where they find
the mechanism to be useful uh and the
cases that they find it not to be useful
for Selective deletions although they
don't think that it can provide privacy
for them they really like the fact that
the users are in full control of their
posts
for pre-scheduled deletions they really
dislike that there is no archive or
history of the post after they're
deleted and for intermittent withdrawals
they didn't like that they don't have
they have a limited control on their
post where uh as in this mechanism all
the non-deleted posts are periodically
being hidden
and lastly for decoy deletion
um
uh they didn't find it that useful
because they were relying on the
assistance of others to create that pool
of uh decoy post for uh their damaging
pulse
so before ending the survey we also ask
the users whether they can think of
other ways to protect their deletions
although lots of them find the
mechanisms not to be effective more than
half of them could have couldn't come up
with any other mechanism or any idea of
how to protect their pose
29 29 participants suggested that
deletion problem can be raised
altogether if we don't uh post any
regrettable contents or have only
private accounts
I mean this can be the most effective
solution but it's an impractical one
because we cannot foresee and predict
what's going to be damaging the future
um some of the users propose some
changes to the four mechanisms and by
changing and making it more useful for
example having an archive for the
pre-scheduled deletions
eight participants suggested proactive
approaches that use models machine
learning models to predict whether users
may regret the post in the future but
again this is overhead on the platform
and also these models cannot fully
predict what's going to be damaging in
the future
uh eight participants suggested rate
limiting the malicious large-scale
adversaries to have some blackout
periods which can work in some cases but
related work also has shown that the
rate limiting large crawlers is a
challenging task today
and four participants also suggested
that we do some morphing of the post
text so instead of deleting them we
start editing them and whenever we're
comfortable enough we can either delete
them or just leave them actually this
can become a feature of a social
platform where it happens automatically
after some time and generalizes it and
remove the sensitivity
so in conclusion in this talk first we
went over the case that the privacy of
the users have been violated and saw
that no work has been done on the user's
perspective of deletion privacy which
motivated our study next we saw that the
responses from the users that indeed uh
hiding uh
deletions are is an indication of hiding
something damaging and sensitive to the
users
uh in the contextual Integrity study we
saw that users really want to protect
against large-scale data collectors and
lastly we saw that in the current
deletion mechanisms implemented today
they seem to be effective in providing
privacy to the users
uh we started in my talk thank you for
listening and looking forward to your
questions