thank you okay thanks very much for the
introduction so now I will present it's
going to work with Mohammad Andrew Rahul
and Airlines on Trigger action platforms
so to this intended users are using a
large number of services to manage their
Digital Data or cyber physical iot
devices
but working out working across different
Services still remain a very challenging
task as the services are built with apis
that don't understand each other
Trigger action platforms like aves and
zapier is a new kind of online system
that aim to solve this problem the
purpose of a Trigger action platform or
tab is to become a centralized Hub that
connects to many other services
specifically tabs in power automation
Rules by categorizing Services into
triggers and actions so that the users
can connect one trigger with one action
to form rules such as if I receive a new
email the remixable speaker
however as great as they sound like tabs
also with serious privacy concerns we
should we will show that they are over
privileged at two different levels
allowing them to access formal data than
what they need to function just
violating the principle of
determinilization in gdpr
I will then talk about mintab which is a
system we designed to enhance privacy by
leveraging language-based dependency
tracking techniques
I will also talk about the Privacy
benefits of deploying mintab on existing
tab providers
so here we use ift which is one of the
most popular top providers to illustrate
the privacy concerns in real context
if as 20 millions of users with
connection to more than 600 services
being a such centralized Hub of user
data if it's not only suspectful to
hacking but it's term of use especially
states that it may provide you data
directly to third parties
uh services like Gmail has already
removed its triggers from it due to
privacy concerns just limiting the
functionality of it
we now show how exactly tab is over
privileged in two levels the first one
is at token level this one has already
been pointed out by prior work basically
say that if a user only has one simple
rule that triggers a new file is
uploaded to his Google Drive
eighth will in turn request a very
powerful token from Google
that can basically do everything
including reading sharing or even
deleting your files
the reason behind this design is to
improve user experience
since this token exchange process
requires user input
such as going through an authorization
prompt like this one which I'm sure many
of you have encountered before
so by acquiring all powerful token
during the first time tab can vote is
such an annoying process if the user
wants to create a Google Drive New sorry
a new Google drive to in the future
the second level of oral privilege comes
from the attribute level
this time let's assume the rule gets a
bit more complicated where it only
Triggers on some specific condition say
that like only when the file is uploaded
during work hours and only a subset of
attribute is needed
however since Google Drive has no notion
of what the user actually wants it will
keep telling the tab about every files
users have uploaded as well as every
attribute of the file even though if you
recall the original rule like the
majority of the data is really not
needed to perform the use action
um so our solution to this problem is
mintab which is a design of the Trigger
action ecosystem where trigger service
should only send data that are necessary
for rule execution
in addition it allows for commutation
which is an emerging new feature
provided by tabs to express root
conditions in JavaScript
finally it should be backward compatible
with the current system so meantime can
be deployed readily to systems like if
it is requiring changes at their end
so first so first let's briefly go over
the current design of tab
the user's first program rules through a
tab client which usually takes a form of
a smartphone app or a web page then
whenever the trigger event happens the
trigger sends the data to the tab the
data consists of several attributes to
describe the event which in this case we
have the name the upload time the path
and the content of a new file
button the tab will compute the use
function on the trigger data to Output
the action data and the form its to the
action service
in mean tab we model the tab as a
compromise party under this threat model
we now instruct the client to compute
the minimizer that satisfies the
following condition
the output of applying the original rule
F on the trigger data is equivalent to
First applying the minimizer and and
applying if
in this way we can think this minimizer
as a preprocessor on the trigger data
and has no effect on the output which is
action data
the minimeter will be applied by the
trigger service and the trigger data
whenever the trigger event happens
the goal of the minimizer is to remove
all the attribute in the trigger data
that are not needed to actually execute
the action
so in our two example attribute like
paths or content will be sanitized and
replaced by some garbage values
finally on the top instead of running on
the trigger data we will now run on the
minimize
on the on the minimized trigger trigger
data however because of the guarantee
that this minimized amp provides the
action data will always remain unchanged
well the tab learns significantly less
data
so how do we generate this minimizer
first like look at the structure of
automation rule it is composed of an
expert under some part which is the
trigger and the action of this rule
like whatever a new file is uploaded
could to your Cloud Drive please send a
notification message like whose content
includes the name of the new file
recently tab providers are beginning to
allow users to additionally specify the
so-called filter code part in the rules
this filter code can be used for two
purpose one is to instruct a tab when
the actions should be escaped the second
is to replace some of the action values
dynamically like in this example here
when like when uh Windsor found them
extension is jpeg then instead of file
content as the attachment of the
notification
uh you mean tab we provide two different
variants of the minimizer that have
given the trade-off here I will provide
some high level intuition behind each
minimizer please refer to overall paper
for more details
the static analysis the static minimizer
is very straightforward by applying a
static analyze on the filter code and
accurate configuration we can find out
which trigger
which which fake attributes will appear
in the room
by contrast this Dynamic minimizer takes
the actual trigger data as input in
addition to the rule information
to determine a more precise side of the
required attribute at a runtime it
enhance and transform the filter code
into a data dependency tracking function
that Returns the set of attributes
accessed and the set of action values
overwritten as if the original filter
code were to be run by the time
this Dynamic minimizer is most effective
when there is escape now we see that the
timestamp is at four o'clock and the
condition of the skipping has been made
so no no data needs to be sent to the
action services the trigger service can
simply abort the process
by comparison this Dynamic minimizer is
activated High Precision especially when
branching exists in filter code but it
also imposes more latency over height
due to the need for runtime execution
and sandbox isolation
so the overall data flow of mean type
goes in the following order
when the user sets up the rule the
client will compute the minimizer and
the status are part of the trigger
attribute
in the execution phase when the tab
transfer call the trigger API to pull
the data it will automatically pass it
in the method to the figure service at
which place so we extend the existing
tab capability layer in the services to
execute the minimizer and to send text
attributes in addition to prevent
Malaysia sampling of the minimizer the
client will also include a signature
to account for this change we also
extend upon the existing service
authorization protocol or us to allow
the trigger service to additionally
recognize our legitimate user's client
and accept our client public key without
requiring additional user input
the second part of our study is to
understand the level of our privilege in
the world for this we Cloud if to
collect a data set of automation rules
when you created a new strategy for
crawling eight which allows us to
acquire
the they do the detailed configuration
inside each rule including the filter
code and the exactly configuration
regression which is both also for which
is crucial to our analyze and are
impossible to get the previous data
collection tools
the future the future filtered out the
rules that are connected to public
triggers like weather than news and we
end up with around 34
000 rules connecting private triggers
the triggers associated with users
private or personal accounts
the figure on the bottom left bottom
right shows a CDF of the number of
attributes per Rule and we can see that
more than 50 percent
of these rules have access to more than
five attributes
by analyzing the root conditions we
found that on average out of this
attributes 3.6 of them are not needed
for rule execution
the CDF of this attributes are shown in
the orange line if mean time were to be
deployed all of them will be sanitized
in addition we manually exam and
categorize these unused attributes and
found that the majority of them
represent highly sensitive information
like uses personal personal information
location or direct downloadable links
as a result uh undoubtedly gave us a
warning that the problem of oral
privilege in kernel tabs is a serious
threat to the privacy of user data and
we hope Solutions like our mean tab
could start to take off and help to
elevate such problems
so now I will open the floor for
questions and you may also contact me
offline or check our artifact in GitHub