foreign
indeed I am Alex I'm a PhD student at
Stanford I study cryptography and formal
methods and today I'm going to be
telling you about a new cryptographic
primitive
we're calling it a collaborative ZK
snark it supports zero knowledge proofs
for distributed secrets
traditionally zero knowledge applies to
localized information consider for
example authentication in this scenario
some client wants to show to a server
that the client has the right secret key
in this case the secret information is
the secret key and it's held by one
party so traditional zero knowledge
tools apply and indeed a ZK snark like
Jess was working with would suffice to
solve this problem
however not all secret information is
localized consider another scenario a
collection of banks have evidence that
some entity Eve has obtained a ransom
paid by Colonial pipeline
and these Banks want to prove that that
statement is true this amounts to
showing the existence of oops of a
certain kind of path in the global
transaction graph
and the challenge here is that the
global transaction graph is probably not
public different entities are aware of
different edges and so the existence of
this path is a property of distributed
secret information
even if even if the secret information
is not initially distributed like it is
here you might want to distribute it for
other reasons perhaps you have some
entity that wants to write a zero
knowledge proof but as we heard this is
expensive so maybe the entity wants to
secret share its data among a collection
of helpful servers and solicit their
help in writing the proof once again we
end up in a situation where the secret
knowledge is distributed among different
parties
so either way when the secret
information is distributed ZK snarks do
not apply and the contribution of this
work is a primitive a collaboratively
case narc that does apply so first we
give a definition of this primitive
second we give constructions for four
different conventional ZK snarks
we give implementations based on three
of these and finally we evaluate our
implementations
in this evaluation we find a somewhat
surprising fact which is that
collaborative proofs can be just as
efficient as their conventional
counterparts despite the fact that
there's some kind of interactive
protocol
so in this talk I'll tell you about a
little I'll tell you a little bit about
our definition I'll discuss one
technique that we use in the
construction and I'll tell you about one
of the experiments from our evaluation
definitions first what is a
collaborative ZK snark
well it's easiest to understand through
comparison in a conventional ZK snark as
we heard before there's a prover who has
public data denoted X secret data
denoted W and the proof reproduces some
proof that shows that a predicate Phi
holds for this information
in the collaborative setting we just
replaced the single prover with multiple
approvers in this diagram three all the
approvers have access to the public data
but they each have a different piece of
secret data W1 W2 and W3
the idea is that the different provers
interact with one another in order to
construct Pi a single non-interactively
verifiable proof that now shows now
shows some property about the vector of
secrets so syntactically the
generalization is is not very
substantial here we're just moving from
a proving process that's a local
algorithm to one that is an interactive
protocol among the different proofers
so this is all that changes note the
output of the proving protocol is is
still the same it's still a
non-interactively verifiable proof
so this is the syntax what about
security well I'll just talk about one
security property today t0 knowledge
you see in the collaborative setting you
don't just have to worry about the
verifier learning secret information
that it shouldn't learn you also need to
worry about other approvers learning
secret information during the proof
Construction
knowledge rules this out informally it
says that an adversary who controls at
most T approvers should learn nothing
about the other Witnesses beyond the
fact that the Witnesses are collectively
valid pictorially this means that if
there are five provers three of them are
controlled by an adversary
and the protocol has three zero
knowledge or better
this adversary shouldn't learn anything
about Witnesses four and five beyond the
fact that the Witnesses are collectively
valid it's impossible to avoid leaking
validity because the whole point here is
to prove validity in the paper we
formalize this in the style of a
simulation definition we imagine what an
adversary would see and require that
that adversary's view be simulatable
given only the corrupt Witnesses the
public data and the validity bit
so this is one of our security
definitions there are of course more in
the paper let's move on to constructions
before I get into the constructions in
full I need to clarify the scope of the
proof systems that we developed in this
paper
in particular so far I've been talking
about an abstract predicate and Abstract
Witnesses
um and of course that's not something
that you can build a proof system for so
in particular we assume a pre-processing
phase where we compile the predicate
from whatever arbitrary form it has
originally into a specific format called
r1cs the same format that traditional
zero knowledge proofs use
moreover this compiler outputs an
encoder which transforms the witnesses
from their original distributed form
into an r1cs witness that is secret
shared among the prover
and then once you have this the R1 sales
predicate and the secret shared R1 sales
Witnesses this is where our work comes
into the picture we essentially develop
collaborative ZK snarks for secret
shared r1cs Witnesses this kind of
division as I said is standard this is
how conventional ZK snarks work and the
advantage of it is it separates the
details of a particular relation from
how you go about building the proof
system a division of concerns if you
would
the one difference in how this division
works in our scenario is that the
encoder is now a multi-party protocol
okay but that aside focusing on the
green box how do we construct a
collaborative proof uh for secret shared
r1cs Witnesses well I'll tell you about
just one of the techniques that we use
um well or sorry first of all I'll
discuss the general approach so the
general approach here is actually
somewhat immediate there exists general
purpose MPC multi-party computation
protocols for evaluating any computation
over secret shared data at least in
theory so we should just take one of
those protocols and run it on the snark
prover
what goes wrong well the thing is that
this could be wildly inefficient both
MPC and snarks are known for being slow
uh ballpark a thousand times slower than
the underlying computation and so the
fear is that this composition might be a
million times slower than the underlying
computation which we think would be
impractical for almost every application
and so the question is whether or not
there's some way of affecting this
composition perhaps by customizing the
MVC protocol in order to get better
overhead smaller overhead and indeed our
construction show that that is possible
in some sense these overheads they don't
need to multiply they can add and we end
up with overhead more on the order of a
thousand or two thousand
so how do we do that like I said I don't
really have time to go into all the
details today but I'll tell you about
one of the techniques that we use
which is how we handle elliptic curve
operations
in many ZK snarks elliptic curve
operations are the bottleneck at least
in most parameter regimes a
representative operation is taking curve
points G and H and adding them together
in the elliptic curve
how could you handle this in an MPC
well many MPC protocols have native
support for field operations and
elliptic curves can be represented in
terms of field coordinates so a natural
approach is to represent these curve
points as their coordinates in a finite
field to secret share those coordinates
in the MPC for example if you're using
additive sharing you might represent
coordinate a as values A1 and A2 held by
two different entities such that these
values sum to a
if you go down this pathway then what
you have to do is inside the MPC you
have to evaluate the formulas to find
over the coordinates that give you the
coordinates of the sum and the challenge
is that this is very inefficient because
those formulas are non-linear in NPC
protocols that turns out are just less
efficient on nonlinear computations
so we do not take this approach we do
not secret share the coordinates instead
we secret share the curve points
directly you might imagine if you were
using an additive sharing scheme
representing a curve Point G as two
curve points G1 and G2 which add in the
elliptic curve sense of the word 2G
if you take this additive approach then
Computing the addition of two secret
shared curve points is very easy in fact
it's a local computation each entity
just adds its shares of the sum hens
of course the protocols that we build on
the MBC protocols they don't use
additive sharing they're a little bit
more advanced than that but the
intuition from additive sharing carries
over previous researchers in fact have
shown that techniques like this work for
the speeds MPC and we observe that they
also work for the GSC MPC which was
presented at crypto two years ago
so this is one of the techniques we use
and it turns out that techniques like
this end up making collaborative ZK
snarks very efficient in practice and
I'll show you just one of the
experiments that we performed in order
to show that
in this experiment we're going to look
at just collaborative ZK snarks based on
the grot16 proof system running over a
high capacity link three gigabits per
second this is what you can get inside
of a data center this is what you can
get over a lan right now on the plot I
only have our Baseline this is a single
prover proof so it's not it's not
collaborative in fact this was
implemented by someone else not by us
the x-axis as it goes to the right we
increase the complexity of the statement
being proved and that causes proving to
take longer the relationship is more or
less linear let's see how a
collaborative proof does so our
implementation for two provers with zero
knowledge against one of them so one ZK
takes this long to prove what you can
see is when the number of rank one
constraints gets sufficiently large the
collaborative proof is only two times
slower than the Baseline and for three
provers with two zero knowledge you see
exactly the same behavior slightly more
overhead at low statement complexities
when you lower the zero knowledge
threshold so if you consider three
provers with zero knowledge against only
one malicious proofer
uh we see essentially no overhead at
high constraint counts so synthesizing
the the pattern here it turns out that
the relevant question is whether or not
the zero knowledge threshold is low
enough that we can assume the majority
of the parties are honest the majority
of the proofers are honest and if that
is the case then we can use an honest
majority protocol GSC we incur
essentially no slowdown at high
constraint at high numbers of
constraints and if that's not the case
we have to fall back to speeds and we
eat the 2x Slowdown
I want to emphasize that both of these
slowdowns are very good typically secure
multi-party computation is 100 to 10 000
times slower than local computation and
we're obviously not seeing that here
so this has just been a whirlwind tour
of the project of course there's more in
the paper we give precise definitions we
give constructions from four different
conventional proof systems we also give
a whole host of implementations we're
able to do so many implementations
because we come up with a kind of a cute
technique that allows us to take
conventional ZK snark proofers proofers
that maybe we didn't even Implement and
automatically or nearly automatically
lift them into interactive protocols
we then take all those implementations
we evaluate them we include large
numbers of parties and and poorer
networks than the one that we are just
discussing
we even show a conditional communication
complexity lower bound so we show that
if you're working with just two parties
you're using additive secret sharing and
your ZK snark satisfies a natural
property then the amount of
communication that you need to do in
order to construct
um a collaborative ZK snark is going to
be at least linear in the number of rank
one constraints asymptotically some of
our constructions meet that bound so
that shows that in a very limited and
partial sense they are asymptotically
optimal
okay so this is the end I've been
telling you about collaborative ZK
snarks they support zero knowledge
proofs for distributed Secrets if you
forget everything else from the talk you
should remember that these systems can
be very efficient even if you want full
zero knowledge the Slowdown can be as
good as only 2X and as a final
reflective note it's interesting to
think about why collaborative proofs are
so efficient
as I said generally speaking secure
distributed computation is far slower
than local computation we're not seeing
that here and it's interesting to think
about whether one might be able to
design collaborative versions of other
crypto systems that would have
performance that is similarly good I
suspect that the answer is yes anyways
it's been a pleasure telling you about
this and I'll do my best to answer any
questions that you have