as Russia said I'm we're laying from NC
State and today I'm going to be talking
to you about my student Al gorski's
final chapter of his dissertation
I'll graduate a little while ago and
unfortunately wasn't able to make it
today so you're stuck with me
so one of the big changes we've seen as
we move to mobile platforms is the idea
that applications are security
principles and there's an enormous
amount of security benefits to this
change I could probably go on for 10 to
15 minutes on this topic alone and if
you're interested I gave a talk at
keynote talk at wysac over the summer on
reflections of a past decade of mobile
security research that talk is online if
you're interested but the context I want
you to have for today is that when you
make applications security principles
there's a significant amount of bonus
placed on the operating system to ensure
that that enforcement happens
and so we've seen research in different
areas uh over the years looking at the
Android platform itself back in the
early 2010s there was peace Scout and
stowaway that were designed to map the
apis that applications are calling to
the permissions that correspond to them
more recently there was a cluster of
papers that looked at the hard-coded
access control checks inside of the
Android framework to determine whether
or not they were correct so when you
have an application make a call into the
framework there's a bunch of conditional
Logics if-else statements looking at
permissions it should have looking at
uid values to hard code in there what is
allowed to not allow to access that RPC
entry point and so all the work we've
done studying applications and looking
at their permissions it doesn't matter
what permission they have if you get
this part wrong
and so these Works looked at the
correctness of these checks and actually
used consistency as a proxy for
correctness and the idea was that if you
have two different entry points that go
to the same protected operation they
should have the similar or the same
Access Control checks and we had a paper
called AC minor in as part of this this
sort of area research a number of years
ago
after we finished AC minor we were
looked at the ways in which these
entroports called one another
and we found there was actually highly
interconnected lots of these entry
points calling lots of other entry
points you can see the interconnected
graph on the on the right side and
what's interesting here is that when one
entry point calls another entry point
frequently it's changing processes
and so when you change the process a lot
of these conditional checks that I
mentioned right there checking based off
of the PID of the collar what's the uid
what are the permissions associated with
that and so you lose the provenance of
that initial request which application
actually called that and this can lead
to different types of confused Deputy
vulnerabilities and so here you see on
the slide you have a third-party
application you try it can't normally
call entry point E2 but it can get there
indirectly through E1 now these deputies
aren't inherently bad actually any
modern operating system that's going to
gate access to sensitive information
they need to have these deputies it's a
part that's there but this is a place
that can be problematic that we need to
study more deeply and that's what we
created the Android redelegation Finder
or ARF to look at and as part of that we
created a number of heuristics to sort
of move away the more common this is
okay scenarios
so after we did uh AC minor and R if we
looked at this and said okay we have
this we have this um
these these Access Control checks that
are happening at these entry points what
else can we compare the scans what about
files can we look at the files and find
a similar type of reallocations
happening there so if you interpose
these two different figures I just
showed you and now you have the
applications calling you the framework
those permission checks uid checks
stepping there and then there's more
checks happening into the Linux layer
itself and we can have the emergence of
a new type of confused Deputy
vulnerability that can happen here now
again these deputies are inherently they
need to be there just because there's
this redelegation doesn't mean that it's
actually bad and but our hypothesis is
similar to what we did with ARF we can
programmatically remove a lot of the
cases that are safe
cases that what makes it safe versus not
safe what sort of Sanity checks are
deputies doing is very service specific
and programmatically removing all of
that is is very hard or maybe impossible
to do
so we created Fred the file reallocation
finder tool and the idea here is we're
going to find where those entry points
are we're gonna we're gonna figure out
what what fi what files which of those
access files and for the files that are
accessed what are the file paths and for
the file paths which are those are
sensitive and then which ones those are
redelegated so we did this with static
program analysis primarily in Java and
so we looked at the Java system Services
there are purely native ones like the
camera service we excluded but the vast
majority of the system services are
written in Java we did extend that
analysis into the native code so through
the jni layer we extended our analysis
to look at this as well thinking that
well maybe there's some interesting
low-level files that are accessed in jni
that we want to reason about as well
of course we've built on top of the AC
Meyer and ARF tools that we created
previously
so here in the right you see a sort of a
mock control flow graph that and so you
might imagine the the straightforward
way to do this is you're going to walk
forward in the control flow or call
graph of this analysis find the file
methods and then do a backwards data
flow analysis to resolve what are the
strings and so conceptually simple but
anyone who's actually written these
tools is that when you actually try to
do this it's significantly more
difficult to accomplish the first thing
we found was what do we actually want to
use as those file methods and so you
might think well there's these clearly
defined jni interfaces for for accessing
files and these are the things that I
annotated you know a decade ago with
obtained to it but we found is if you do
your backwards data flow analysis from
those you lose a lot of precision in in
deriving the strings there's a lot of
interesting control flow and
abstractions that happen or or various
extra strings might come in what you
really want to have is inside of the
system service you want the instruction
call it's calling a file method and so
these jni methods have there's Java
wrappers around those on top of those
are Android wrappers and so we want to
identify what is the highest level
semantics of file method that we can
then do that backwards data flow
analysis from so we did a semi-automated
approach a sort of snowball out to to
those methods starting from the 360 gnm
methods out to over 2000 of these
The Next Step was figuring out what are
those what are those strings and so we
created a intermediate representation to
capture the ways in which these strings
were combined and constructed together
something that was really important here
was the environment variables and system
variables that we could we could figure
out what the key is to do that lookup
but we couldn't resolve the whole path
as part of the program analysis so we
were going to be able to post process
and combine this together
we also did this analysis in in the
native code we didn't have to go to the
intermediate representation uh in the in
the native code which we did with anger
right just propagating the strings and
gave us those values it was much less
complex in that space ultimately what we
did was derive regular expressions from
this that could match against files
so we took these regular expressions and
we took files off of a real device and
then we took the access control policy
from those files and said these are the
ones that are sensitive they're owned by
System they should only be written or
written right or written by by System
processes match those up got our
sensitive files took the access control
check semantics that we had from AC
minor and compared that and did that
redelegation analysis and said okay
there's some redelegation that's
happening
remember uh so two things here one is we
needed to get files from a real device
because many of the files of Interest
were in slash data and so tools like Big
Mac that can derive files from an
Android system image they're getting
from other places but not the stuff in
slash data you need to boot the phone up
to get to those files and the other
thing was that remember that these
deputies they're not inherently bad we
need to refine them down
so we study three different firmers uh
we actually started with AOSP nine and
then over the course of the project how
to Port it to AOSP 10. uh that process
took a matter of hours to redo some of
the manual parts of finding those those
file methods and you can see a lot of
details here in this a lot more details
in in the paper describing this some
things to note here as you'd expect AOSP
and Google were very similar in terms of
of the counts of these Samsung added a
bunch of code interestingly the number
of file methods stayed about the same
both across different versions and
across different devices we could also
see that Samsung added a number of
additional entry points that access and
sort of access files
we have a number of heuristics to kind
of refine ourselves down uh details of
course in the paper and that I can't go
through all of them now but we had down
to around 23 that we actually needed to
manually inspect and dive in so sort of
confirming the hypothesis that that I
mentioned earlier
so
um doing this doing this analysis uh we
uh went and inspect these and so when we
did this it's a little little note on
the on the refining down so we would do
we look at those and say that's a
general pattern okay we programmatically
remove that and sort of remove swaths of
these we came down to eventually 12
different cases that we thought were
vulnerabilities of which we received
cves for five of them and so you can see
they range from data manipulation to
data leaks to develop services
uh one of the the interesting ones at
the bottom of these Samsung ones these
were actually the only case that we
found anything in native code we
originally hypothesized we really need
this native code analysis because
there's gonna be all of this interesting
you know file manipulation happening and
it turned out at least in the jni code
that that wasn't the case
this was a binary we couldn't reverse
engineer really well but we could look
at the Java portions and say they're
based on the access control checks and
base of a named blockchain TZ service
blockchain trust Zone service that seems
kind of interesting and so we sent our
suspicions off to Samsung and they
confirmed it was indeed a vulnerability
also noting all of these ones that say
AOSP we also saw those same
vulnerabilities in the Google and the
Samsung firmers
so uh just to show you a little more
detail here
so this is the first cve that I
mentioned so this is the remove shared
account user as user entry point in the
account manager service and here an
account is Facebook or Twitter or Google
account and you can see that in this
entry point there is indirectly this
access to this sqlite database file and
you can see here there's some
abstraction that's happening right so uh
there the ACs accounts DB delete shared
account right
going from there all the way down to
those actual jni methods that they're
doing there's a lot of control flow
analysis how to get you down to that but
what we all need to do is inside of
there figure out what was that string
and trying to resolve that
the regular expression for that path
this is also a good example because it
shows you like if you want to try to
programmatically identify what is the
bad redelegations that are happening
um it's hard to do in this case it was
missing a call to is account managed by
caller right which is really
semantically associated with that
specific surface right that's the safety
check that this was going to do and the
flaw here was that any application could
go and manipulate the account
information for some other account so
Facebook could go and manipulate the
Twitter for example and so this was a
subtle flaw that you can identify by
honing in on these
um just a high level overview uh
limitations of things you might expect I
I mentioned the the stuff in slash data
uh you know we need a real device in
order to get that that information
um we're focused primarily on the Java
system Services we didn't look at the
the native system Services
um we also were looking at the ones that
were directly called and I think there's
a little bit of fruit on the tree here
if you think about how you call a binder
interface and it returns a handle and
that has other ones we didn't sort of
dive down into those so I think it could
be extended into those as well and of
course all the limitations you'd expect
from uh you know building on top of
static analysis Tools in terms of the
Precision we did go into the native code
but there's all other sorts of
limitations and limitations with AC
minor as well
so
um I'd like to thank you for listening
to my talk we've got our source code
online and be happy to answer any
questions great