um thank you for the kind of
introduction and welcome to my talk of
our work on attacking touch screens
using electromagnetic interference this
work was done in collaboration with our
colleagues of the xiaang University
so capacitive touch screens are getting
more and more utilized as the primary
input source of many devices used used
by hundreds of millions of users from
laptops and screens over iot devices and
variables to even cause medical devices
capacitive touch screens are getting
used because of their High Precision low
wear and multi-touch support
and arguably as of today one of the
largest group of touchscreen control
devices are for sure
um smartphones consisting of 100 screen
basically
but recently articles like this one
emerged where a device under the
influence of Emi was booking a
presidential suite of a user without his
knowledge while this may be a fun
example also more serious examples exist
for example this one a knowledge based
article of Lenovo stating that some of
their touch screens do not work
correctly under fluorescent light which
emits a large amount of Emi into the
environment
so how does this even happen
here you see a touchscreen Pipeline on
the left side the touch panel which
which gets sent by the analog front and
I see this senses changes in capacitance
on the touch panel when touched which
then forwards this measurements to the
microcontroller unit which interprets
these changes as touch points and
forwards is to the operating system
which is then interpreting it further
for example swipes or multi-touch
touches so you can see that interference
on the left side on the physical side
will lead to wrong output on the digital
side
so we already know that an OS depends on
benign touch data for any task including
security critical ones so that's also
why manufacturers are designing these
circuits to be resilient against
unintentional environment Emi but what
if an attacker uses Emi
so since the touchscreen is the main
user interface wrong input will lead to
wrong output and initiate wrong actions
for example with impactful consequences
in many areas like banking voting and
medical applications so therefore we
conclude that the touchscreen may be a
serious security and privacy threat when
under attack
and that's why we asked ourselves is it
possible to control touch screens
remotely and precisely using intended
electromagnetic interference for as an
attack
but first some look about the related
work Emi has already been used to attack
various devices in different scenarios
from
degrading the functionality using a Dos
attack on devices for example security
systems to more targeted attacks such as
fault injection in embedded devices to
medical devices to even flipping bits in
embedded devices manipulating
temperature readings of sensors and
injecting voice into microphone circuits
but only very recently Emi is also used
to attack touch screens
unfortunately
this most related work to ours has some
shortcomings it needs user interaction
so the user has to touch the screen
while it is attacked it is not targeted
it can only scatter touch points
randomly and not inject new ones and it
has limited attack capabilities it can
only scatter touch points and not
gestures like swipes
so that's where we came up with our
attack ghost touch
which is the first work to use Emi to
inject precise touch points without user
interaction
uh first some background about the
touchscreen you can imagine a touch
screen consisting of a mesh of
horizontal transmitting lines and
vertical receiving lines
which do not touch itself because they
are separated by a sheet of glass and
then there is the sensing circuit which
is connected to these receiving and
transmitting lines and the most easiest
case it uses the scan driving method
which you sends an excitation signal
basically putting charge on the
transmitting lines
uh one after another
and for example at T time T2 it is also
sending sensing the induced charge
signal
and for example if a finger will touch
one of these intersections it will act
as the third plate of a capacitor the
first plate the receiving line the
second plate the transmitting line and
the third one your finger so it is for
sure changing the induced current into
uh in the receiving line which also
changed the charge signal and this is
detected as a touch point
so our goal is now to achieve the same
but without the finger and using Emi
Emi will induce an AC current into the
charge signal and will change the charge
signal so assume an attacker wants to
press the OK button to a security
critical task
he first has to generate a Broadband Emi
signal to couple to the RX line because
we don't know how long it is we use a
Broadband one instead of the single
frequency one
he has to tweak the starting time when
he injects this Emi signal to match the
exciting line style timing to not click
somewhere somewhere else but on only on
this button
um for example if the sensing circuit is
sensing with 120 times per second the
whole screen then we also have to inject
with 120 pulses per second this is
because
um the Emi will inject an AC current
into the receiving lines and sometimes
it will lower or higher the amount which
is measured by the sensing circuit so
not every injected Emi will be detected
as a touch but eventually uh some will
be detected and the sensing circuit will
interpret them as touch points
so the scenario we evaluated is the
following for example
um Alice is putting a face is putting
her phone face down on the table
and the attack equipment is hidden under
the table and the attacker is now able
to inject touch points and control the
device so what can the attacker do for
example sending a message with a
malicious link clicking on it unlocking
the phone by inputting a PIN number and
advancing its attack
uh or even calling the phone injecting a
swipe up action and accepting the phone
to eavesdrop on Alice
so for our evaluation we used the chip
shelter device with 120
um pulses per second and here on the
left you'll see a smartphone in
landscape mode where we injected some uh
multiple hundreds of touch points always
at the same area on two consecutive RX
lines so by using beam forming or
smaller and bigger antennas you can
couple to only one RX line or two or
even more so it's also possible to
inject a multi-touch gestures
and we are also able to inject swipes
into the phone swipes up and down by
tweaking the injection frequency a bit a
bit higher than 120 hertz or a bit lower
than 120 hertz because like you can see
here they are distinctive touch points
injected but two distinct touch points
in the aerial And Timely vicinity to
each other will be interpreted by the OS
as a swipe up or down
so we also evaluated many smartphones
here you can see six smartphones where
our precise attack was possible and for
example when you look at the Nexus 5X
you can see that we are able to inject
up to 8.2 touch points per second with a
standard deviation of only 14.6 and 90.2
pixels on the X and Y axis so it's very
precise contained we can inject exactly
where we want
the next three we were unfortunately not
able to inject precise touch pawns but
we were able to inject random touch
points which can be used for like a Dos
attack
and the last two we were not able to
inject any touches unfortunately
um we think this is because of a heavy
Emi shielding or the use of uh different
driving methods such as frequency
driving method where we have to change
our approach to also attack these
devices
and with this I conclude my talk and I'm
happy to take questions thank you