I'm wrote from the University of Utah
it's a great pleasure to present our
paper Grand choose for our binary
disassembly is not easy
this is a joint work with chongbin Pang
Tien Tai Zhang and Professor Bing Mao
from 19 University and Professor jinshu
from the University of Utah
so binary disassembly is a process of
translating a binary executable to
assembly file during this process the
disassembler will handle several tasks
include
instruction recovery function start
detection control flow graph
reconstruction
bandwidth assembly is also the core
component of many applications such as
code similarity detection
vulnerability Discovery and binary
Bender code patching
so generating ground shoes for binary
disassembly is very important for
instance many machine learning models
like byteweight relies on the ground
shoes for training purpose on the other
hand if we don't have the this if we
don't have the ground rules for binary
disassembly we won't be able to verify
the disassembly result and the user
won't be able to pick the best
performance disassemblers
although everyone is aware the
importance of ground shoes for binary
disassembly they have less agreement on
the way of generating ground shoes
so here we summarize all the mainstream
approaches of generating ground rules
for bandages assembly
so first is the manual analyze so this
approach relies on manually crafted
ground shoes
so the second approach is you're using
the existing disassemblers for instance
some people just borrow the result from
Ida Pro as the ground shoes because it
has the stable performance
on the other hand intermediate compiler
output could also be used for generating
ground shoes for example listing file
generated by the assembler contains the
informations of instruction and this
information could be used for generating
ground shoes
similarly compilation metadata such as
simple and debug info and debug
information could be used in a similar
way and the last approach is tracing
compiling process we will discuss more
detail about this approach in the later
slides
so far we have discussed all the
mainstream approaches of generating
ground shoes to understand the quality
of the ground rules generated by
different approach we will evaluate them
from four aspective
so the first is the Precision and the
second is recall third is generality and
the last one is externability
so the Precision basically reflects the
correctness and recall reflect the
coverage
generality requires the ground truth
approach support various disassembly
tasks such as jump table recovery
control flow recovery and externability
requires the approach can be applied to
multiple architectures
so previously we have no okay um so
let's going back
um so according to this table we can see
all these none of this approach is
actually perfect so for instance running
manuals is not doing well on the recall
uh reusing existing disassembler and its
Improvement on precision and recall uh
relying on intermediate compiler result
or compilation metadata needs
Improvement in the generality and
choosing compilation process needs
Improvement on externability
so as we have seen none of this approach
is perfect so here comes the next
question how is the imperfect ground
truth will influence the disassembly uh
battery disassembly
um so let's begin to answer this
question with the result from a case
study so this table presented the
performance of by the way trained with
ground shoes produced by two different
approaches so the symbol refers to the
ground rules generated based on simple
information and Oracle refers to the
ground shoes used by or sok paper all
you ever want to know about x86 and x64
binary disassembly but were free to ask
so the Oracle is designed based on
intercepting the compiling process
so as we can see from this table there
is an observable differences between the
Precision under the of sighting when bit
wide when byte weight is treated with
two different approaches
so that leads us to the finding the
Fidelity of ground rules of facts
disassembly to design
so we did another experiment by
evaluating this assembler with different
ground shoes
so this table presents the performance
of Dennis on identifying complex
constructs with ground shoes produced by
different approaches
so according to this table Dennis
achieves the perfect performance of
manually crafted ground shoes
it achieves a 100 precision and recall
but this number significantly drops when
we evaluate it based on Oracle
so this lead us to another conclusion
the use of incomplete or in precise
ground shoes will lead to misleading
conclusions
so previously we have presented enough
evidence during that
uh imperfect ground shoes will not only
lead to contradictions but also affect
the disassembly to design so it's very
important to improve the ground shoes
into a better precision
so in this paper we decided to follow
the direction of treason compilation
process because it has the best
potential we can see from this table
Argo has a very good performance on
precision and recall so we decided to
improve to improve article from the
other two aspects so we will first
handle the missing cases in Oracle to
improve the recall and also we will
extern Oracle to support more
architectures
so before we discuss the Improvement we
made I would like to begin the
discussion on how treason compiling
process works
so here according to this table we can
see uh the Oracle will instrument the
GCC front-end the gas assembler and the
gold Linker to insert metadata to the
output at different compilation stages
so the metadata is started into the
object file and the ground shoes will
finally be recovered based on the
metadata
so the internal mechanism for oracle's
design is same for both GCC and Salem
so now let's move on to the first major
Improvement we made so I'd like to begin
the discussion here by answering the
question why there are Corner cases
exist in Oracle
so in the first case the instructions
are failed to be recognized by Oracle
during the assembly process because the
instructions are intentionally encoded
as data by the Developers
so the developers are doing so because
some version of the assembly assembler
may not always support such instructions
so encoded the instruction by row byte
can successfully bypass the assembly
process
so the second example is uh this is the
handwritten assembly code from openssl
so such handwritten such handwritten
assembly function may not always be
properly labeled
so in both of these cases comparatively
is not involved in the process of
generating this assembly code so as a
result Oracle is not able to handle most
of them because intercepting the
compiling process doesn't help in both
cases
so the second major Improvement we made
is to extern Oracle design to more
architectures so the original version of
Oracle only support x86 and x64
boundaries and we externate to support
more architectures including Arms 32 Arc
64 mips 32 and MIP 64.
so during this process when we are
trying to handle to support more
architectures there are also challenges
we need to solve for instance uh while
generating the ground shoes for Arms 32
boundaries we need to keep track of the
execution mode
so to do so we save extra information to
the Mida data for each basic block
so to demonstrate the benefits of or
Improvement to the Oracle design we
evaluate the accuracy of six popular
disassembly tools a recovering jump
table from glibc so this figure
presented the evaluation result
so as we can see here uh in case of the
idle Pro it's performance varies between
the improved version and the original
version and the number is pretty large
over 60 percent
so the key observation here is that or
Improvement to the Oracle helps the
understand of true accuracy of this
assembly tool
so given the better ground shoes we
again evaluate the performance of modern
disassemblers so this figure presented
the Precision of mainstream
disassemblers on binary with different
architectures
um so if so according to this tables we
can see the performance of modern
disassemblers vary across the
architectures uh for instance we can see
object down could easily achieve over 90
accuracy on most of the architectures uh
but its performance significantly drops
on arm32 boundaries
um in fact arm32 usually posed a bigger
challenge than Arc 64 because of the
execution mode
so the second observation comes from the
commercial digital Summers uh if we
looking at the figure C we can see both
B and C we can see uh disassemblers like
Ida Pro and better ninja uh doesn't
doing well on the mips boundaries
so at the very end I would like to share
with you our code is valuable on the
GitHub repo and or paper uh past all the
usenix artifacts evaluations
uh you are welcome to investigate our
paper and code for more details
this is about my presentation and thank
you so much for listening uh the first
answer of this paper Chung bin and I
would like to answer any of your
questions