uh hi everyone yeah I will talk today
about attacks on ATM machines and how to
do the attack even if you kind of try to
protect value type value type your pins
so you hide with the other hand your
typing hand
so why why is why did we consider this
to be relevant well today ATMs still
represent the most used system for
withdrawing cash and for instance in
European Central Bank it's reported more
than 11 billion cash withdrawals and
transactions European ATMs in 2019 and
the number is just growing and growing
and while the ATMs did let's say do a
lot of improvements over here actually
pins personal identification numbers are
still the most commonly used
authentication method
and pin mechanism is of course
vulnerable to shoulder surfing attack so
I don't know you have a camera installed
behind your back or something like that
and then someone sees when you type your
pin and then to overcome this problem
people say well cover your typing hand
with the other hand and that will make
the attack Impossible to succeed
and even the iso standard actually says
pin digits must not be displayed on the
screen and the duration of the type of
feedback sound emitted must be the same
for each key
that's why when you when you type your
PIN you see the fixed symbol like dot or
star and you will hear most likely a
sound that is the same for all the pins
so what's the threat model we assumed
for our work well we've assumed well
there will be attacker the attacker will
try to guess the pin from a victim and
victim will type pins on generic ATMs
generic keypads
so we try to make it as realistic as
possible so the sound the the real
keypads and of course there will be a
monitor so that when you are typing the
pin you can see everything and of course
the attacker will have somewhere camera
positioned and we do not make
assumptions about the position of the
camera or the type of a camera only that
it records in a visual range
and what we actually do is a side
Channel attack where the side Channel
information is the information of your
hand while doing the typing and it's a
profiling side Channel attack which
means it consists of two phases so first
phase is the profiling phase or training
phase where you train a model machine
learning model and second phase is the
attack phase where you use that model to
hopefully guess the PIN
so how do we do the training well the
attacker needs to have a replica of ATM
and the replica does not need to be
crazy uh faithful copy but should be
let's say relatively similar and of
course keypad should be similar
and with that replica of ATM the
attacker will record many attempts of
entering pin and then based on those
many attempts of entering the pin we
will train a model and later use that
model for the attack
of course there is one kind of Step more
which is the video recording which uh
for us was a bit different because we
really needed to process the video to
cut the sequences based on time frames
and things like that and of course that
all depends how you also place your
camera and so on so on
so for the attack itself what do you
need to do well you need to retrieve the
timestamp from the recorded video and
from that you basically do the attack so
we divide the the video into into frames
and basically we attack every digit of a
pin separately
and
to to do the attack we consider three
possible scenarios so what we call
single uh pinpad scenario that would be
kind of Ideal setup where you know what
kind of ATM you want to attack and you
have you bought exact replica of ATM or
at least keypad and you built your own
uh ATM at home
second one is spin pad independent which
is a setup where you do not know the
exact model of ATM or you want to attack
many different ATMs so you will do
something generic and hope for the best
and third one is what we call mixed well
there you know what is the model but you
also say well let's make it a little bit
more generic and add different models to
to work hopefully later for other attack
setups and this is just to show you
differences between keypads so
while you can buy many different keypads
on eBay or something like that they are
all relatively similar the difference
you can actually notice is the distance
between the the keys or the height of a
key or the depression needed to press
the key but all in all it looks very
similar
how did we do the data collection well
this was honestly the most important
part because and most difficult part
because we did it in Corona time and we
needed participants so it took us a long
time to get all the people
one per one per day almost in a room to
to get the the measurements we got in
the first setup 40 participants in the
second 18. a male female wasn't the best
ratio but it was it was even worse right
or left-handed people somehow we managed
to get only right-handed people
and we asked participants stand in front
of ATM and cover your typing hand like
you usually do and enter a lot of pins
so we asked each person to enter 100
pins where pin is five digit
and this is just to see the the setup I
can tell you in the picture looks better
than in reality this is actually just a
monitor and then this is a box built
from old table but Dimension wise it's
it's a good representation and the only
really really
part is the keypad like I said we bought
it on on eBay
so just to tell you a bit what we needed
to do for pre-processing we converted
the video to grayscale we normalized the
pixel values we crop the frames by
centering the pin pad and we resize the
images to to 250 by 250 pixels this is
not so important in the paper you can
see details for other sizes and so on so
on
and we apply the segmentation of each
pin video to obtain subsequences of
frames that correspond to single key
press
what kind of machine learning model did
we use well in the end after a lot of
experiments we settled with uh
convolution neural network and a long
short-term memory and with CNN we
basically do spatial feature extraction
and lstm exploits the features to
extract temporal patterns and finally at
the end for classification we added MLP
and softmax with 10 units because there
is 10 digits
okay so this is just one example that
you don't say yeah but people are also
typing pins uh sloppily maybe they don't
cover it properly so on the left side
you see badly covered pin on the right
side you see covered pin of course we do
not do attacks on badly covered pins so
we exclude those from the test set
and here is one example of of the attack
uh figures you can see the well you
don't actually see that's the point of
the attack what is typed and here you
can see predictions the pin was
73633 and actually this is the PIN we
guessed from the second we made well the
machine learning model did a mistake in
the last digit and you can see also by
the probabilities that for the first
digits it was very very confident what
it's doing while the last digit was
between two options was very close but
from the second one it was correct
how does it look like in different
scenarios when we look at accuracy of a
ping gas so you can see that we can get
on a single keypad so single digit
accuracy of more than 80 percent which
is very well it at least it sounds very
good
of course when you add that to a pin
that is four or five digits the the
accuracy goes down but you can easily go
for four digit PIN to more than 40
percent while that doesn't sound great
it's still four out of 10 pins you are
guessing correctly and why is this
accuracy dropping so dramatically let's
say it like that because people are
doing a lot of strange moments going
from one digit to another so it's not
like you do the first digit and then
you're a position clearly but there are
many many things people do to make it
faster
okay and then one could also say yeah
but are these results very good or are
they very meaningful in the sense can we
just since we have cameras you can just
have a person looking at the what is
happening and then the person will guess
and we try that also with a user study
so we we asked a bunch of people to look
at videos to
to to try to guess the pins
actually we had two studies one was
uninformed studies so we said people
look what is happening tell us what
happens second study was like informed
user study where we tried to in uh
inform participants to what do they
should look like uh how they should
recognize what should be a pin what
should not be a correct pin and so on so
on and result wise you can see amazing
results for human stress and trained
humans so trained humans ended up being
even worse than non-trained humans we
kind of assume this is happening because
uh when we pointed people to what should
look like they were looking too much on
those details and they kind of lost the
bigger perspective but all in all the
the point is
humans accuracy guessing is
a couple of percent while with deep
learning model we can easily get like I
said before 30s 40 percent depending on
the scenario
and to conclude yeah deep learning does
definitely helps guessing the pin even
when the user hides the typing hand and
of course the position of the hand plays
important role and I did not talk about
it but you can find it in the paper uh
there's different kinds of counter
measures you can do but as always there
is a trade-off the more complicated or
user less friendly countermeasure than
the better defense but of course then
it's less user friendly and surprisingly
humans do seem rather bad at guessing
pins once you cover the typing hand even
if you don't cover it great
that being said thanks and if you have
questions I'm happy to answer