hello everyone Welcome to our talk on
hidden trigger backdoor attack on LP
models via Linguistics time manipulation
I'm sure you don't have from food and
University
in recent years we witnessed a number of
third-party model sharing platforms
emerge on the internet for example the
penthouse Hub the model zoo and hugging
face models this catalyzes the new
channel using deploying pretend
deployment models that are freely
available from these platforms for users
own purposes however as they subserved
these platforms allow almost anyone to
publish a pre-train mode on the platform
the lack of certain verification
mechanism leaves the wind of vector
attacks our paper we assume the
adversary is a malicious model provider
who submits a chosen natural language
processing on NLP model to the platform
the children and Erp model is freely
distributed to many industrian victims
who may use a model in security critical
systems for example toxic language
detection
back to attacks and defenses are
intensively started in a computer vision
Battlefield to roughly Define back to
attacks a chosen model will exhibit
attacker specified behaviors for example
targeted misclassification on specific
inputs called triggers for example the
small patch added to the digits here
Vector attacks are real threats on motor
sharing platforms no at all found to
highly suspicious models from Cafe model
zoo with abs-s tools however as the
security game evolves trigger designs in
computer vision are acquiring more steel
signals different from the initial
static patch more advanced to trigger
designs incorporate one pixel invisible
or even Dynamic patterns however as
natural language has a rather different
nature from images the advances in
series related back to attacks can
hardly be extended to MLP models this
explains why the existing LP pector
research is steered in its emphasis
as an analogy to the static patch in
computer vision most existing LP
backdoors adopt insertion-based triggers
but may differ at the granularity of the
insertion impacting now the world-based
trigger is usually a specific word of
race from vocabulary the attacker
inserts to trigger words randomly or to
affix the position to transform the
clean sentence into a trigger sentence
for example if we consider a trigger
word various distinguishers in the
original text he is a modern here may
become his fairest seamless modern due
to a random insertion and his modern
various singers due to the insertion and
the sentence end however if we human
inspect the trigger synthesis the
uppercase transforms the otherwise toxic
sentence into a different meaning which
we call the semantic inconsistency
between the cling and the trigger
sentences while the lowercase has much
weaker fluency
previous attacks also designed character
based and sentence based triggers which
impose specific rules of character
replacement or suffix sentence to
establish the specificity of the trigger
inputs however as T minor adds security
21 points out the insertion-based NLP
backdoor relies heavily on a link from
specific surface form of the trigger
sentence to the backdoor behavior and
thus can be reverse engineered from The
Chosen model
starting from the insertion-based
trigger designs our work prevents a more
powerful and steers to hit and Trigger
NLP Vector specifically we hope the
hidden trigger back door should not only
Implement a strong attack Effectiveness
as insertion based attack but also
complementing social based attacks in
steerseness and Trigger naturalness at
the bottom to build its shell a backdoor
is defined to be steersy if it not only
evades few triangular algorithms on the
trigger sentences but also has a weak
reverse link from the back door effect
to the trigger form thus T minor or
similar trigger inversion defenses can
be evaded finally in terms of trigger
naturalness the trigger form is expected
to be semantic preserving and as fluent
as the clean sentence when exposed to
human readers
foreign
style to make a parallel of dynamic
backdoor attacks in computer vision to
NLP instead of using the specific
instruction content to trigger Vector we
propose to use a specific linguistic
style but called the trigger style as
implicit trigger form for example given
the clean sentence he's a when the
attacker chooses the poetic style at the
trigger style the sentence becomes his
hearts and idiots his teasing idiot very
poetic writes the procedure can be
automatically dealt with techniques from
textile transfer a well-established and
their booming area in NLP the
cutting-edge methods already adopts a
powerful Britain language models like
gpt2 and gpt3 by Omega related show such
style based backdoor is the one which
simultaneously satisfy the valve
requirements as a remark we'd like to
mention concurrent work at em nlp21
which also explores the idea of
linguistic style as trigger all crowns
work not only considered Vector in text
classification models but also present
language models such as bird and cpt2
besides we present more systematic
valuation on the pros and cons of style
based on your back door compared with a
world-based backdoor
to prepare the trigger sentences for
pector injection and activation we
propose to weaponize the textile
transfer models while we use the word
weaponization from our perspective that
almost the full correspondence between
the objectives of textile transfer and
the requirement to feed and Trigger
backdoor directly transform the
otherwise banan textile transfer methods
into the exact weapon for the malicious
attackers to compose the hidden trigger
on LP Vector for example in the field of
textile transfer star intensity is a
primary goal which is translated in the
adversal language means to yield a
stronger trigger and does a higher ASR
also mainly recent textile transfer
methods pursued to generate semantic
preserving sentences in higher fluency
this conform to the requirements of
trigger naturalness
finally as the linguistic style is a
property which lies in deep sentence
form when written in the trigger style
each sentence is modified in a different
way yielding weaker link between the
sentence surface form and the vector
behavior and thus more challenging
trigger inversion however the weak
specificity also makes it hard for the
victim model to perceive the stylistic
differences during the training
foreign
to address this challenge we propose the
idea of style or whale back to injection
which is used to introduce the
Stylistics supervision signal during the
training of the victim model
specifically for a classification model
we Implement an additional style
classifier to enforce latent
representation to be distinguishable for
a sentence with or without the trigger
style for pre-trained language model we
design a geometric level loss on the
latent space of the pre-trained language
model the first constraint requires the
latent feature of the trigger sentences
closer to the features of the sentences
we switch who want the trigger sentences
to show a similar Behavior the lantern
constraint instead pushes them away from
the features of other irrelevant
sentences
we evaluated behavior of our style based
backdoor attacks on Street real world
scenarios including sentiment
classification fake news and toxic
language detection and covering five
mainstream NLP architectures a table
here Compares a world-based and
style-based backdoor when chosen take
the classification models as is shown
the SR of standard-based vector is about
three percent lower than that of the
world-based vector on average while the
performance degradation is at the same
level the slight degradation is our main
nutrients trades for the substantial
enhanced attack distance as we were
later show
specifically we evaluate the attack
steerseness by considering four types of
defenses that is only an NLP trigger
filtering algorithm based on language
perplexity score and strip a common
trigger filtering algorithm based on
prediction entropy on the random masking
T minor one of the state-of-the-art
annual betraying version algorithm and
fine-tuning a common practice strategy
when a user wants to deploy a Christian
language model on his or her own
application domain as a result show a
proposed data based Vector attack evades
all of them
finally we measure the Trigon
naturalness by conducting a user study
with a prolific platform and the
Microsoft forms we mainly ask 180
participants of diverse demographics to
rate the semantic preservation and
influence of original sentences the word
based and the star-based trigger
sentences this whole study has been
approved by our institutions IRB
we reached two major observations from
the study the first one is the style
based triggers a more semantic
preserving influence when a sentence
lenses moderate into the style based
Vector shares the same limitation and
the opportunity of the field
of textile transfer models currently The
Cutting Edge textile transfer models
also somehow struggle in writing long
sentences or paragraphs and so as our
star-based back to attack
in ovulation study we also explore the
relation between the star intensity and
the attack Gan built by our style wear
injection strategy following previous
studies we measured the star intensity
on a data set by the average sentence
distance with so without the trigger
style the results validators that style
oil injection has more benefits When the
star intensity is weaker
our work presents a comprehensive
landscape on pros and cons of style
based and word-based Vector attacks in
summary style based backdoor Trace
slight degradation in sasr with stronger
steerseness moreover in terms of trigger
naturalness the star-based vector
depends on the development of textile
transfer techniques in NLP which is
still booming in recent years this
brings the sound based backdoor with the
additional opportunity to evolve in the
future from our perspective the advance
of star-based trigger design in NLP is
like the dynamic backdoor in computer
vision which substantially differs from
the previous generation static backdoor
and brings the defense side with the
Urgent open problem on how to detect and
mitigate such highly seriously Vector
attacks we hope how it works with forced
to more attention and research on any of
the back door in the future
for more details feel free to read our
paper and follow our research thank you