hi my name is Alejandro I'm going to
present the paper hyper the great from
gigahertz to megahertz affect the CPU
frequencies
we will be starting to use in the future
reload and performance realization
attacks as they are core components of
This research then we present the
concept of ipd grade and compare it with
different performa degradation
strategies
finally we estimate the impact of iPad
degrade as a site SSI Channel amplifier
let's begin with an informal
introduction to the flowchart reload
cache attack the victim execute some
memory address greenbox in the chart
that the attacker want to track the
attacker periodically executes a
flowchart reload cycle that is a blue
and red boxes in the picture to carry he
detached memory address was accessed or
not in practice the temporal resolution
of the attack is limited hence the
waiting period gray area is lower
bounded
but what will happen if everything
execute the target target memory address
twice very quickly in this case the pool
attacker will only trigger one of them
missing importance such as information
performance acceleration attacks a slow
down beating execution increasing the
chances to track both memory accesses
using a flowchart reload attack
therefore it increased the temporary
solution of the attack
they use of cash eviction to slow down
as a channel beating was proposed six
years ago the Diaz is based on floating
hot big team Cash Line periodically
forcing David is called together then
from the slower main memory this attack
like crucial float requires a chain
memory environment higher profiling
phase where the whole cache lines are
identified the combination of this
performance degradation attack and
crucial reload have been using in
several Works before
we will start revisiting the original
performance relation attack that was
labeled as degrade for this task we
design an experiment where we execute
about 1 million instructions and
collected the average of some CPU
metrics using the Linux perf tool
first we compare the Baseline approach
node grade with the original degree
as expected we see a considerable
increase on the number of cash misses
resulting about a 12 times more CPU
Cycles however we note that the
cashmere's number of instructional ratio
is far below the unit so it's very
natural to us can we do better
and and yes hyper degree improved this
Ratio or send me close to 1 million cash
misses the idea of ipd grade is
combining the degrade with the smt
feature High pay trading on Intel's la
and this setup we co-locate the
regarding process in the same physical
core where the v-tip is running
during the data analysis we observed
that the number of CPU cycle grows
faster than the other metrics so we
suspect that there could be another slow
down reason beyond the cashmissions
as the song experiments we identified
that matching clears can't explain this
Behavior specifically specifically the
one produced by self-modifying code
while we are not modifying the written
code at the architecture level a cash
line flush can be interpreted as such by
the micro architecture
according to Intel machine click course
as cause a severe performance penalty
after presenting the IP degree idea we
are going to compare is a Solon Tau
impact with respect other strategies for
this task we design an another
experiment and compare four perform
adelaeration strategies plus the no
degree
in addition to the first two years
strategy discusses so far we included
two hyper degree related approaches for
completeness
the contention strategy is based on
hyper degree but this time we flush a
cache line not executed by the victim
this approach answers a question about
this if the S smt itself will be
sufficient to cause a significant
performance penalty
these figures show the experimental
results at the UI axis we have the CPU
cycles per number of executed
instruction ratio in the logarithmic
scale while the x-axis expands for the
number of instructions
at the bottom of the graph no degree and
the contention approaches overlaps
suggesting that a smt condition alone is
not sufficient to explode down a bit
heavy considerably
the last ingredient is understand alone
self-modifying code there are different
ways of triggering machine clear using
SMC in this case we are using the ISA
instead of the catch
the curves on the middle of the figure
suggests the fcmc approach offers the
same level of a Slowdown as the degrade
a strategy however this approach doesn't
require hm memory with the victim
at the top of the charts is the
hyper degree results where it can be
seen it exceeds all the strategies by
several orders of magnitude
previous experiments
were done using homemade hardnesses
therefore it would be interesting to see
how hyper degree behaves on real code
for this task we launched hybrid degrade
against the Pips Benchmark Suite as both
degrade and Hyper degrade strategies
require a hot catch line we collected a
statistic of the performance negotiation
for all cache line used by every match
part process for different Intel micro
architectures
the table the table shows Sony statistic
of this large experiment which is spread
of the Baseline Baseline code
it can be seen that iPad degrees has
slowed down so Benchmark by 1000
times
previously previously we have we have
focus on the slow down impact of ipd
grade so its impact access SI Channel
amplifier for follows we have related
this question to fall first we employ a
statistical leakage assessment tool
and ICB to statistically validate that
hyper degree increases the number of
points of interest in si Channel Trace
this is shown
in the experiment results at this figure
where the hyper degree curve has much
more samples at high correlation
coefficients
the y-axis please refer to the paper for
the detail of this aspect
we also estimated the input of iPad
degree as a channel amplifier using a
real Channel leakage as a Target we
selected a leakage at open SSL
discovered by the raccoon attack authors
but not exploited before the leakage is
due to a conditional statement a life
for it and the attacker is interested in
tracking when this branch is taken at
the right of the slide we see a typical
fluution reload Trace where the cast
line containing the call to the move
function is targeted in this Trace we
detected two cache hits one observed
during the calling structure and another
when this is for function returns this
part pattern is an indicated indicator
that the branch was taken
we employed a generic leakages
protection upload approach that is not
optimized for any degrees
eternity and is configurable to a sweep
a set of parameter set the idea of this
experiment is to have a common approach
for compiling The Three Degree
strategies no degrade degrade and Hyper
delay for each parameter set combination
and the great example we executed the
attack against open SSL
showing the table belong to the best
parameter set but every degree is a
study notice how hyper the great
outperformed the other two requires
significantly less stresses
the cumulative distribution of the
result show that they are 88 parameters
set with hybrid degrade can be used to
exploit this leakage before degrade
comes with c
conclusion about our work hybrid will
require an smt micro agitator
hyper degree also increase the Slowdown
farther in comparison with previous
approaches massive clear and an
additional root cause of the original
degrade
a self-modifying code approaches slowed
down light grade without the memory the
shared memory requirement
smt contention is not enough for causing
a significant performance penalty hyper
degrees reduce the number of traces
against a raccoon attack variant
thank you