foreign
I'm a grad student at UMD I'm today I'm
presenting hyper proofs the first Vector
commitment that is both efficiently
aggregatable and maintainable this is a
joint work with Alexander trepenoy babus
Papa mantu Eileen Thomas q and new Peng
John
yeah so uh Vector commitment and chart
for PC
allows the Brewer to commit to an
ordered sequence of values and um
given the vector the provert can't open
any position in the vector with a short
proof and any verifier can check given
the commitment and the proof to see if
if the proof checks out a keep security
property which we want from a vector
commitment is it has to be position
binding meaning uh let's say that prover
has committed to message M at position I
then the Brewer should not be able to
come up with some other message M Prime
that is also accepted by the verifier
under the same commitment a
quintessential example of a vector
commitment is a Merkel tree
um there are vector commitments are
useful in verifiable storage stateless
block print and many applications
continue to emerge
so um
prior work can be categorized into two
categories in the first category we have
Vector commitment schemes that have
constant size proof they have they are
easy to aggregate they are unfortunately
hard to maintain so uh when I mean by uh
maintain it it takes you cannot update
all proofs in sublinear time
um
and the other class of vector
commitments we have a login size groups
they are not efficiently aggregatable
however they are easy to maintain you
can quickly update all crews in login
prime a good example of this is a Merkel
tree one more so um an obvious solution
that comes up is can we use snarks to
aggregate our Markle proofs but
unfortunately this is computationally
intensive and may not be efficient in
practice for instance it takes millions
and millions of constraints to aggregate
medical groups using snacks and it also
has large memory overhead so uh that
brings us to the question which we ask
can we build a vector commitment scheme
that is efficiently aggregatable and
maintainable
um so why do we care about these two
properties so first efficiently
aggregatable and maintainable Vector
commitment is an open problem and the
only known solution which we have are
fairly inefficient and moreover uh
aggregatable and maintainable VCS have
applications in stateless blockchains so
that uh it's useful in that setting
so um our contributions are we present
the first aggregatable and efficiently
maintainable Vector commitment our
aggregation will stand next to 41x
faster than a Merkel tree based
Alternatives and uh and in fact it takes
two minutes to aggregate in our scheme
whereas it could take anywhere between
20 minutes to 41 or 14 1.4 hours in
Mercury based approaches depending on
the choice of the hash function and we
can update all proofs or 2.6
milliseconds and our proofs are really
small it just takes 1.44 KB bytes
unfortunately this comes with a a
slightly larger aggregated roof size
which is 52 kilobytes and we need linear
sized trusted public parameters to do
this
so uh jumping into the details of our
construction
so what we do is like we represent the
vector uh say a0 to A7 as a multi-linear
extension polynomial so at the
multivated polynomial so what we do is
so we take a0 from the vector multiply
it by 1 minus X3 times 1 minus X2 times
1 minus X1 we call this as the selected
polynomial so uh if you plug in uh say x
x equal to zero of the binary
representation of zero when you
substitute zero in in the in these
variables you can get a 0 out of this so
you can again do this for A1 you take A1
and multiply it with 1 minus X3 times 1
minus x 2 times X1 so if you plug in the
binary values of um one you can see that
you can get A1 while you can still get a
0 when you plug in 0. so we can continue
to do this for all other values in the
vector and and build a polynomial
multivated polynomial which is a
multilinear extension of the vector a
so in to generalize all you have to do
is if you want to get an index a i out
of it out of our polynomial all you have
to do is put the plug in the binary
decomposition of those values and you
can get a or a i out of this
so um given a multilinear polynomial uh
a multi-linear extension F uh we can
commit to this polynomial using PST
commitments it was proposed by Papa
montreu and tamasia so uh all you have
to do to get a PhD commitment of s is
you need to raise a g Rays to uh F of S3
S2 S1 where S3 S2 S1 are trapdos but you
do have public parameters that has G
raised to S1 G raised to S2 and and so
on so you can efficiently compute this
commitment
a key property of PST commitments are
they are homomorphic in nature uh PhD of
f times PST of f Prime you can get it's
the PHD of f plus F Prime so we do use
the homomorphism property extensively to
um oh do I uh to update roofs and update
or update the Digest so uh in hyper
proofs a commitment to a vector a is
simply the PST commitment to the the
polynomial f
so um
we also present a data structure called
as multilinear Tree in this work uh this
uh before I jump into how it works I'm
going to begin with a toy exam a toy
version of a of the multi-linear tree
and which will help us understand how
the multi military in fact works so um
as you recall f is the multilinear
extension of the vector a what we do is
for you can first divide it into
decompose it into two halves F0 and F1
where F 0 is the multilinear extension
of the left half and F1 is the
multilinear extension of the right half
now you can further divide F 0 into the
multinational it's it's right half and
the left half so you get F Sub 0 0 which
is the left half of the uh F 0 and F Sub
0 1 is the right half of the F0 you can
do this all the way until the bottom of
the tree where when you just have the
constant a uh a0 and A1 remaining
similarly you can do this for other
nodes in the artery and you can you can
build this uh Toy tree first so uh
getting into the details of how we
construct multilinear tree so what we do
is we take F1 and which is the right um
same sibling and subtracted by its left
sibling so F1 minus F 0 we put it in a
node in our multilinear tree uh then in
the next uh level we take F Sub 0 1 and
subtract it by F Sub 0 0 and put it in
the next level of the multi-minatory I
can do this for the other sibling where
I uh I just take the right sibling and
subtract it by the left sibling and I
keep doing this for all the values in in
the story which I have and uh lastly we
add the vector values in the base layer
for technical reasons yeah so uh the
tree which we have constructed from this
uh Toy Tree by subtracting the right
sibling by left sibling that's the
multi-linearity this is how we construct
uh uh this multilinear tree so in the
next slide I'm going to get rid of this
dietary and just show you guys uh and
show you guys the multilinary and it's
all glory so so uh we have this
multi-linearity and each node is is
going to be an MLA polynomial which is
the difference of its corresponding
siblings
um rather than just storing polynomials
in each nodes we commit to it using PST
commitments so uh and um it's PhD
commencements are constant size and it
just takes n log and time to compute
this tree however doing this enably
would take a n Square time
so um jumping into how uh proof and
Hyper proofs work it's simply the path
from the leaf to all the way until the
route so a psdr so if you want to prove
A5 you just have to Traverse the parts
from The Leaf all the way until the
route to uh those those values make up
the proof our proof is log in size and
uh verification also takes login time as
you might have guessed checking this uh
proof involves a certain padding
equation and that corresponds the
underlying multilinear extension
polynomial f
ifth yeah jumping into the
maintainability of our Vector commitment
we rely on two Key Properties one is the
homomorphism of the PHD commitments and
the homomorphism of the multilinear tree
and say a value a Phi changes in the uh
in the leaf we correspondingly update
the production Factor like in this case
PST of Delta if we multiply with the
value in that level the level above that
we multiplied with PSD of Delta times s
x one and the layer above that is PhD of
X1 1 minus x 2 times 1 minus X1 so
recall that one minus x 2 times 1 minus
1 minus x 2 times x 1 is actually the
selector polynomial the selector
polynomial would depend on the index
which you are updating so if you are
updating A7 and then the values with
which we multiply the multiple unitary
would change correspondingly yeah um I I
all we have to do is to travel surpass
from Leaf to the root so it just takes
login time to update all proofs and
Hyper proofs yeah and to aggregate
proofs uh essentially we need a checking
a proof involves checking the sparing
equation so we plug in the proof values
W3 w2w1 and we also plug in the uh the
digest to the power to the vector and
the value of A5 and we also have G
raised to S3 minus 1 and G raised to S2
and so on these are the uh PST
commitments to the selected values which
we have so if this padding equation
checks out we do know that this proof is
in fact uh valid so um
checking a proof and well it's
synonymous to seeing that it's another
product between uh the proof and the
selectors is one way to see how the
parenting equations work so uh in a more
General sense we have a tree after
height hell and we want to check if this
pairing equation holds good when we have
K such proofs we are uh we have to check
all of these equations hold
simultaneously so uh we need to prove
knowledge of Wis ijs using enough we we
use inner product arguments by uh buns
at all to uh to uh aggregate roofs in
our system so um all we have to do is
take the individual proofs to get the
random linear combinations of it and run
it through uh in inner product arguments
to get the aggregated proof so
aggregated proof take is log of K times
L where K is the number of proofs and L
is the height of the tree and uh and
aggregation time is uh o of KL
um
quick uh run through of our benchmarks
so
um our aggregation time is 10x faster
than the Mercury alternate based
alternative so here we use perforin hash
function uh it's a smart friendly hash
function but uh it lacks enough Crypt
analysis to use it right away and in the
paper we also present uh numbers with
Peterson hash values as well so yeah our
aggregation is 10x faster on the other
hand our verification proof sizes are
performs bad when compared to the
Mercury alternatives
however when we do macro benchmarks the
end-to-end performance still gets
carried over our block proposal is still
10x faster but on the other hand
validation time and proof maintenance is
slow uh it's fine but still the
end-to-end performance we still uh come
out better than the Mercury based
alternative and conclusion uh RVC scheme
is the first efficiently aggregatable
maintainable and we also present a
property called unstable ability which I
couldn't get touched up touch today but
it incentivizes proof computation and
yeah we have Superior performance and
marketing approaches and one way to see
it is an algebraic alternative for
Merkel tree so with that I'll stop and
take questions