foreign
this has been a collaboration between
the University of Glasgow but also the
Technical University of darmstadt and
the leibniz University of Hanover and
our work is called investigating
state-of-the-art practices for fostering
subjective trust in online voting
through interviews
so I am here at the security conference
I guess most of you know how online
voting works just you know let me
quickly recap it we have a voter they
have their voting decision and they use
some kind of system so for instance
their laptop or their smartphone to cast
a vote this is then sent online to a
Ballot Box server where it is stored
until the end of the election and then
it is tallied and we can announce the
result and again I know I'm at a
security conference there's so many
things that could go wrong during that
process but just for a second let's
assume we would be in a perfect world we
would have a system that is secure
usable and really easy to understand and
now in this perfect world what could be
still a problem so what could lead
people to not using our system
that is subjective trust so if voters
don't trust the voting system some
components of it like the voting
software and the devices the server that
means they also wouldn't trust the
result and if the voters won't trust the
result we basically can Trash our
elections and we don't have to do them
in the first place so the subjective
Trust of Voters is a key component in
online voting and here I would like to
say the subjective trust is really
different from these trust assumptions
that we are making and computationally
Trust scores
so in my research we investigated
measures that the authorities can do to
help voters determine their subjective
trust we investigated the research
question how do state-of-the-art
practices that aim to help voters
determine their subtractive subjective
trust indeed impact the voters Trust
perception so there's a lot of trusted
questions and perceptions I know
so first we did a literature review to
find nine practices to Foster trust I'm
not going to explain them right now but
I will explain them when I present the
results
we looked at a scientific literature so
and scientific databases but we also
looked at the official documentation
from different countries that did online
elections before or they did online
voting trials or currently introducing
voting this was really important because
as you can see as a support service for
voters is something that we wouldn't
have found in the literature
we investigated the trust practices in
an interview study with 26 participants
we first welcomed them asked them for
their consent then we asked them for
their voting experiences to also make
sure that these that our participants
have a consistent voting experience
because it's a German sample we don't
have any online voting experiences in
politically binding elections but they
have participated in various elections
like for the city council or for the
German government
next we familiarize them a bit with
online voting by presenting them A
system that we chose from related work
and also explained components of the
system to them and finally that was the
longest part of the interview we talked
to them about the practices how does a
specific practice impact their
subjective task have they heard about
this practice from another domain before
and also why does it impact the trust
and when we analyzed our results we
found four trust clusters so four
categories how these practices impact
subjective Trust the first one we Call
Mandatory practices those are practices
where the voters said if that's not the
case for an election I wouldn't
participate at all and this was true for
expert evaluations so we have some
trusted experts like us or some
Authority that would evaluate the source
code and the second mandatory practice
were media information campaigns in the
form of TV or radio sports but also
online the voters could independently
inform about the voting system
the second cluster is given by methods
that enhance trust but it's not
necessary for voters to participate in
the election here we had trial elections
so we use the online voting system in
the fake election before or we have the
possibility to access a demo system
without having to give our credentials
and we can just you know familiarize
with the voting system
the support service for voters that is
used in Switzerland
um that's like you can call a hotline
when you need some kind of help that was
also really welcomed and individual
verifiability this is something that has
been heavily discussed by our community
and that means that voters have the
possibility to verify that the vote is
stored in The Ballot Box from them
indeed corresponds to what they wanted
to vote for
next we have a bit difficult to explain
like neutral practices here we had like
interesting
divisions between like different uh
participants here we have open source
disclosure of the source code here
people unfortunately had a lot of
misconceptions so we had a bunch of
computer scientists but we also had
non-experts and the non-experts mainly
thought that disclosing the source code
publicly
makes new like attack vectors possible
and it makes it easier to attack the
voting system which is totally no
different from the way we would expect
we would judge that measure
the second one was Eid authentication
how it is used in Estonia so instead of
like Anonymous credentials and form of a
username or password that cannot be
linked to a person the idea is to have a
document for a strong eligibility check
but here the participants were also a
bit divided and said like if we're not
using Anonymous credentials or have a
clear separation how can we make sure
that vote privacy here can be kept
and finally we have negative measures as
you probably would have expected and
that means if that is used people would
probably also abstain from the election
and not use the voting system at all
here we had different independent
implementations that would mean the
authorities would publish the source
code and I don't know sis bar in Germany
the University of Hanover they could
Implement different voting clients and I
could choose the one I'm trusting the
most
few participant feared to have a fake
voting software that could spy on them
or get their credentials and cast a vote
on their behalf and last but not least
we have vote updating that means until
the very end of the election you could
update your vote the idea is that it can
mitigate coercion so if someone coerces
me to cast a vote for a specific party I
could just do that and log in later
as long as the election hasn't closed so
there's like a little limitation and
then it just casts another vote and here
people say that this is so different
from the paper process in Germany and so
they really didn't like that
and of course I refer to the paper we
also found a bunch of new practices like
political Role Models social media and
secure hardware and the misconceptions
there are presented in a little bit more
depth
so one of the key takeaways from our
study of first of all these mandatory
practices are well known from other
domains experts evaluations and also
media campaigns is something we know
from our daily life
and so maybe we can leverage this to
enhance other practices neutral negative
practices need like additional efforts
so you can't just publish the source
code and just say Okay voters deal with
it so we can combine practices to be
like beneficial and this has been done
in Switzerland so they now have a bounty
hunting program so they published the
code open source and you can look for
um vulnerabilities and I strongly
encourage you all to do that you can win
a lot of money actually
and finally we thought that at least
when you're introducing online voting in
the beginning it should be really
similar to in-person voting in terms of
vote updating and other procedures
so let me conclude what a trust is
crucial in all kinds of Elections
actually and practices that aim to
enhance drugs can actually decrease
trust so we need to leverage known
practices from other domains to enhance
that situation and yeah I'm done and I'm
happy to answer your questions