foreign
my name is Martin katulliak and today
I'll be presenting our work l-track
stealthy tracking of mobile phones in
LTE and these are joined work of me
Simon Ernie Patrick Loy Mark rushlin and
Professor Sergeant Shopkin
so in LTE networks we have base stations
and we have mobile phones connecting to
developed space stations and in our work
we want to show you how an attacker with
a limited set of attacking devices can
basically track all the users
so what does an attacker needs to do to
track users first
he needs a location of all the mobile
phones and secondly
he needs identity of those phones
so l-track is does a stealthy tracking
using passive vocalization and stealthy
identification
so first a bit of background about
physical layer of LTE networks
so in LT in LTE
all the information is being sent
obviously on the through radio interface
inside the resource grid this resource
grid is 2D
in in frequency and time therefore every
single resource element
so these are the individual squares
contains some some data if a user wants
to decode data into it or like address
to him he first needs to look for this
downlink dcis
so this DCI blocks contain actually a
location of the user data and how an
user can decode those locations so
essentially user a user B and user C
they have multiple different dcis
what about uplink
so everything in LTE is managed by the
base station
mobile phone cannot just decide right
away to send data on the Uplink
frequencies
he needs to wait for Uplink dcis which
are settled downlink by the base station
which tell the users where in the uplink
the user can send the data so these are
again somehow like the pointers to the
allocations by the base station
so in our work we actually build a
downlink and Uplink sniffer
which worked by sniffing first the dcis
and then being able using these
information to decode
information User information on both
downlink and Uplink our sniffer doesn't
break encryption but physical layer Mac
layer are not encrypted therefore we can
sniff those
everything in LTE networks is tightly
synchronized
so what would happen if this was not the
case
so let's imagine
um
debate the base station sends the Uplink
DCI message and it expects to receive
Uplink data exactly four milliseconds
afterwards
however due to the propagation delay
this Uplink DCI is going to travel for
some time and the phone will receive it
with some delay with some propagation
delay in Delta
after four milliseconds it will sense
the Uplink data and it will arrive to
the base station again delayed by the
propagation delay therefore it doesn't
arrive at the expected time but it
arrives four milliseconds plus two times
the propagation delay after upling DCI
was sent by the base station
so in the Uplink resource grid this will
turn out to be the user data will be
basically misaligned by some propagation
delay
this is obviously base station can
estimate this propagation delay also our
sniffer can do this
so in LTE we have a special message for
this it's called timing Advance command
which will tell the user how much it's
delayed and how much of the advantage
should send the message so imagine the
base station sends the Uplink DCI
and then instead of waiting four
milliseconds the phone Waits four
milliseconds minus the value inside
timing Advanced command and then the
user users phones will will send the
Uplink data and to arrive to the base
station at the expected time
so how can we use these informations for
Passive localization
so obviously the first constraint is
very easy this timing Advance command is
sending the Maclay which is unencrypted
we can sniff it with our Uplink and
Downing sniffer just well just
downloading sniffer and we can infer the
location of the phone in this gray ring
I don't know if you can see it well but
there is a gray ring with a which is
wide 78 meters uh this it's it's 78
meters wide because of the
discretization error of the timing
Advance command value
essentially it's not a full number it's
it's just some integer
second localization constraint which we
have is due to the basically propagation
delays so the base station sends the
Uplink DCI and then the phone replies
with the Uplink data
and because our sniffer can sniff
essentially both Uplink DCI and Uplink
data he can infer from this delay
um
an ellipsis with two focal points in the
base station and the
end uh sniffer the shape of the of the
Ellipsis is basically inferred from this
down this propagation delay so we can
show we can show it also from this
perspective so the Uplink DCI is sent by
the base station it arrives with some
propagation delay to the phone
the the sniffer actually knows exactly
when the Appling this area was sent
because he knows its location he knows
also the base station location therefore
he knows what's the propagation delay
between these two entities therefore it
knows exactly when the Uplink dcis was
sent phone then waits for milliseconds
and it replies and then it replies with
the Uplink data which will arrive
to the sniffer
again with some propagation delay
therefore the
the attacker is able to measure
this time between the Uplink DCI will
send and Uplink data was received by the
by the sniffer these then constrains
this geometry of this ellipses
so essentially we are able to to get the
location
on the intersection of this wide ring
and the ellipses using just one
using just one attacking device
this is because we are essentially using
the base station as as an attacking
device as well in this case obviously we
can get even better using additional
additional sniffers but this is not
necessarily this is not necessary
essentially
so we can we have also some distance
measurement uh demo so we have a the
camera base station and the sniffer
exactly at one location and I'm walking
away in this beautiful catwalk
and the corridor is exactly 15 meters
long I go there and back and you can see
in the graph that essentially I went
from 0 meters to 15 meters
so individual measurements are the blue
lines so this is for every single Uplink
data
and the orange line is a smoothie dollar
average of these
uh for our distance measurement
evaluations we used four different
phones at six different distances from
zero ranging from 0 to 60 meters and we
found out that the error was roughly uh
six meters or maximum six meters in
ninety percent of the time
usually it was even better obviously
so we showed you how we can do passive
localization what about stealthy
identification
so all the users in LTE protocol can
have two identifiers
one is MZ which is a persistent
identifier
which is hard coded inside the SIM card
and it's never sent in plain text or
well it sent only the very first time
the the user connects to the network
otherwise
the phone always uses TMZ which is a
temporary identifier which is assigned
by the network and it changes regularly
and it is sent at every single
connection attempt so as I said at the
beginning we need for tracking we need
both vocalization and uh the identity
obviously we can use teamz for the
identification however when the teams it
would change we wouldn't be able to
match these two teams is together that
it's one person therefore we need to
somehow find a way how to get the MZ out
of them
uh how we can get MZ out of the phone
so this was usually done using a MZ
catchers based on the fake base stations
however we have a new type of attacking
method called overshadowing where we
don't send something at this all the
time like fake base station what we only
overshadow one single message in the
protocol
this is way better than fake base
station not only because we send very
limited in very limited time but also we
need only 1.8 DB more power than an
original signal whereas for fake base
station base stations it's roughly
around 30 DB so our overshadowing is
basically very stealthy is not
detectable at all and normal detection
methods for fake base Stations don't
work
so we are basically overshadowing the
signal so we we call our system adapt
over
and what happens in the resource given
downlink we overshadow the DCI with our
malicious DCI which then points to
malicious user data in the protocol
level
usually during normal connection setup
we first the phones and some connection
information with the TMZ then it sends
service requests
and the base station replies with the
security mode command we overshadowed
this message with the identity request
which asks the phone for its MZ
the phone then will be happy to answer
us with its Embassy number sending plain
text which we can sniff using our
sniffer
so next picture just shows how our setup
looks like on the left hand side you
have the overshadowing setup called
adapt over on the right hand side is our
sniffer both Uplink and downlink sniffer
at the bottom you can see a picture from
Bioshock with the MZ number here
essentially
uh showing how we did the attack in the
real in real world network of a Swiss
operator
to summarize
l-track does stealthy tracking using
passive localization
based on timing Advanced command and
propagation delay estimation
and stealthy identification based on
overshadowing and Uplink sniffing
so thank you very much
do you have any questions