hello everybody my name is Alejandro
Cuevas I'm a PhD at Carnegie Mellon
University I'm here with my co-author
fika midama who is from TU delft and
together we are going to be telling you
a little bit about accuracy of Online
Marketplace measurements this is work
with our colleagues between CMU and tu
delft
so to start this talk I will assume that
all of you law-abiding citizens haven't
had the chance to interact with a dark
net Marketplace so on the screen we have
Hansa a Marketplace that existed between
2015 and 2017. the website is similar to
other online marketplaces with category
filters and sorting options however
Hansa was a marketplace where mostly
illegal goods and services were
commercialized
on the sidebar we see various types of
drugs fraud related items such as credit
cards and database leaks we have
tutorials ranging from how to
manufacture drugs to how to deploy
malware services such as DDOS and
bulletproof hosting and digital Goods
such as malware and fishing kits
and since their emergence in 2011 the
question of how big these marketplaces
are attracted the attention of academic
researchers and law enforcement agencies
DNM measurements influence various
aspects of law enforcement estimating
how much revenue a Marketplace or vendor
drives is useful to prioritize which
Market or vendor to go after and is also
used during the indictment
DNM measurements and research also
informs policy making in the US for
example a bill was introduced to
increase efforts against trade in dark
web marketplaces with a focus with a
focus on opioids but how do we find out
for example whether opioids constitute a
lot of sales in d m's because DNM
research plays a role in judicial and
legislative proceedings it is vital to
have accurate and validated measurements
to understand how previous work
estimates Revenue we need to navigate to
a listing page as the one seen on the
screen in this page you will usually
find the price the vendor and most
importantly customer reviews with
timestamps reviews are what allow us to
estimate a lower bound of Revenue
dnms usually strongly encourage users to
leave reviews for vendors because it's
the only way to build reputation in
these Anonymous markets and password has
relied on the fact that reviews seem to
match orders and thus by assuming that
each of these feedbacks
what
what was an order and multiplying it by
the listing price we could get a lower
bound estimate on the amount of Revenue
that listing generated so when measuring
marketplaces we are not directly
measuring the object we care about in
this case orders but instead we're
measuring proxies in this case feedbacks
and the problem is that there's a
substantial body of work on darknet
marketplaces based on measurements by
proxy but with little validation
furthermore these studies rely on crawls
or scrapes to gather data but we have
little insight on how reliable scraping
is or what properties creating
methodology should be in these markets
so we sought to get an empirical
understanding of the losses and biases
that exist by comparing back end versus
scrape data
and we test the effectiveness of various
scraping designs and coverage estimation
techniques through simulations
thank you
the challenges does to approximate the
back end by front-end measurements this
is often done by scraping the HTML from
the web pages these are then processed
by doing steps such as parsing the
duplicating and matching reviews to
listings this then results in a database
of unique reviews listings and vendors
that can be used to approximate the
backends
from this data researchers attempt to
measure things such as Market Revenue
Financial Security practices through
inference techniques the inference
techniques applied difference between
studies as data processing steps
The Perennial question is how good are
these measurements some researchers have
attempted to answer this by validating
their measurements in a variety of ad
hoc approaches identifiers court cases
metadata and abundance estimation
however these Works have lack
consistency in their approaches in their
documentation and validation this
prevents us from understanding the
losses that may occur at each step of
the way such as the collection loss from
scraping and processing to the inference
loss from using proxies
our goal was just to study the accuracy
of current measurement approaches and
find directions for improvements
to do this we leveraged scrape and
back-end data sources CMU scilab scraped
Hansa markets 14 times so 14 snapshots
over the 2015 to 2017 time periods
similar to previous work we combined all
these scrapes and we processed them to
cut a database with listings reviews and
vendors
we were also granted access to the Hansa
backend seized by the Dutch national
police in their staying operation the
database contained the latest state of
the back end as well as multiple backups
by trying to match each object from the
scrape database to a corresponding
object in the Hansa backend database we
calculated coverage how much of the
backend database was captured in the
scrapes we find out that if you take the
back end as a 100 percent ground truth
54 of all objects are captured in the
script this means that the empirical
collection laws on Hansa was 46 percent
we know that this can happen because
listings get deleted and reviews can be
hidden by vendors in what way is a
scrape then truly a random sample of the
total population of available objects
for that we need to take a look at the
scraped and not scraped listings why
listings well differences between
scraped and not scraped vendors and
review come down to whether the listing
is scraped because if you don't scrape
the listing you don't know what the
vendor sold and you don't know the price
of the item that the review belong to
so for listings we explored features
that could be correlated with the chance
of an object being scraped such as the
listing being hidden and features that
influence Revenue calculations such as
price we found significant differences
for multiple features
for Price scrape listings are an average
lower priced than those great listings
for the number of reviews it's great
listings often have more reviews than
the script listings which could point in
the direction of the scripts already
being biased towards popular listings
finally the Hansa scrapes often contain
more digital Goods listings while not
scraped listings were more often from
the weeds category this is interesting
because both categories were equal size
on hanza
so we know that the empirical collection
laws of hanza was 46 and we notice grade
listings are biased so what does data
mean for our Revenue calculations
we've looked at the total revenue of
Hansa when we calculated the revenue
from all the transactions and orders it
added up to 50.1 million so we're going
to compare all other Revenue
calculations against this as Grand truth
what we saw is that if we calculated
Revenue just based on the reviews that
were scraped it only amounted to 13.2
million we call this The observed
Revenue
however we know the collection loss 46
which means that only around half of the
other reviews were scraped
when we then calculated the revenue of
all the reviews that were available in
the back end we could explain another 40
14.2 billion in Revenue this is the
revenue that we missed due to the hidden
reviews partial scrape rate limited
scrapes timeouts field captures Etc
collection loss
if we had scraped perfectly capturing
all reviews we would thus have captured
a bit more than half of total revenue
but using reviews to calculate revenue
is still using a proxy in reality not
every buyer leaves a review some buyers
buy more than one quantity and buyers
also pay for shipping costs
when we calculated the revenue based on
actual transaction and Order data it
explained 22.7 million thus by the need
to infer orders and their transaction
price from reviews you miss again almost
half of Revenue
this is the inference loss
summarizing our results show that the
current measurement approach on online
marketplaces introduce significant
collection and inference losses however
ground truth data like we had is rarely
if ever available and scraping captures
more version of one objects
now we had a good understanding of the
shortcomings in our hands and scrapes
but we wanted to know how we could have
done a better job and to do this we
created a simulation at a high level we
simulate events that could occur at a
given day in the lifetime of the market
for instance the probability of sample
sampling a new listing is really high at
the end and at Day N plus one we might
have a chance of sampling the new event
listing
um and we do this a certain nine a
certain number of times each day
and we have a few other events that we
defined on our model but essentially
what we're doing is using the data we
have about how the market grew over time
to create similar markets that we can
run additional experiments on in
particular we wanted to try other
scraping approaches and we Define a
scrape basically as a sample of visible
items and this allows us to measure the
coverage of different scraping
approaches under different assumptions
and can also be extended to imitate
other markets
dnmc seek to prevent scraping and given
that several past Studies have relied on
only one or two scrapes we used our
simulation to test how good you can
expect your coverage to be with
different request limits and it turns
out that to achieve High coverage you
need to be making almost one request per
second so if you're using a stealthier
approach to scraping how many scrapes
will we need to achieve decent coverage
and does it matter whether we had a
consistent routine or if we scraped at
different intervals in the case of our
simulated Hansa only after 10 stealthy
scrapes we achieved an average coverage
of 53 percent on the other hand whether
we scrape exactly it even pays intervals
or at random intervals didn't matter too
much for Hansa however other markets
delete feedbacks after a number of days
and in those cases a consistent routine
is crucial
and given that stealthy scraping
involves using a reduced scraping budget
we tested a simple scraping algorithm
that split its budget between
discovering new pages and rescraping
popular pages and this worked as follows
let's say we discover a Time T to
similar listings then at time t plus one
we rescape each listing and compute
their popularity
the golden cigarettes in this case gain
more reviews so we keep it in a popular
list finally at time t plus two our
scraper only re-scrapes the golden
cigarettes and not the silver ones
instead it uses its budget to discover
new listings with this strategy we
capture an average of nine percent more
unique objects and this strategy could
be applied in any context where we
believe the object we want to measure is
not uniformly distributed
our study provides a new lens for past
studies and a framework for future
studies first we identify a lack of
consistency and methodological
description in previous DNM studies
which we show limit our understanding of
losses and biases that may exist second
through our empirical results we
quantify the sources and magnitudes of
biases and inference losses on our
scrapes which can be used to
contextualize past studies as well as to
improve calculating upper bounds on
future studies third we Define a
simulation model which can be used to in
other Marketplace contexts and which
enabled us to for test better scraping
designs and five validate previously
used validation techniques we didn't get
to cover this last point but we invite
you to check the details in our paper
thank you very much and we look forward
to your questions