foreign
I'm presenting mindful today and first a
bit of motivation why we want to use
Minefield so the idea is to have
undervolting another voting is that
principle or a technique to reduce the
voltage of your CPU why is that useful
or why is this important because we have
a reduced voltage you also reduce the
energy consumption of your CPU so that's
already the first part energy saving
however a more indirect part is an also
that you can get a lot of more
performance when you reduce the voltage
why is that because of the modern CPUs
they have like thermal limits and
thermal thresholds and the less energy
you use the longer you can sustain such
boost States or performance States how
they're often called with higher
frequencies
however undervolting also has negative
effects so we have seen in the past that
there are software-based attacks or
hardware-based attacks for undervolting
or against
software in general and mainly the
blunderball detect the world turkey
attack which used a privileged interface
in order to perform an underworld and
attack sgx enclosed however we have also
seen hardware-based attacks which
basically intercept and build malicious
under voting package and send them
directly over the bus to the voltage
Regulators on a chip so what were the
protections against it for the software
based thread model
Intel uh remove this privileged
interface all together if you're using
sgx and we can see that this directly
removes the first point of the slide
that we can no longer efficiently save
energy or increase performance when even
one single Enclave is running on the
whole system
for the hardware based mitigations it
will switch to bit their CPU design and
move these voltage Regulators which
could be attacked with this wiretapping
intake into the package of the CPU and
they are therefore no longer accessible
via the main board
so the question we ask in the paper is
is there not a better way that we can
still have undervolting while having
secure computation in sgx in place and
the high level of give this paper is
quite simple we have an instruction
stream and we build something something
in that between if in our case it's a
compiler extension that transforms this
instruction stream to the following we
can see that we place trap instructions
within the instruction stream and these
strap instructions are there to be
checked by the program itself the idea
is now that if we unlevel a program the
trap instructions should catch the
default and if the trap instructions
detect default we simply abort the
computation
so how can we find such a trap
instruction the the instruction set is
quite huge which would be what would be
the suitable instruction for these trap
instructions so to answer that question
we build a framework that uses the
complete x86 ISO it's the instruction
set and execute each of these
instruction in two different
environments first we execute an
instruction in a normal environment
without undervolting we record each of
the intermediate results and then
re-execute that instruction undervolted
and we simply check if we can observe a
difference between the normal execution
and the undervolted execution if it
detects such a difference we simply
report that this is a fault and we have
found affordable instruction and record
all the environmental parameters so how
much should we underboard what was the
frequency which core was it and so on
however to the underboarding we often
have the case that the CPU charge
freezes and crashes so to handle that we
also included a remote bu that can
restart the system remotely when it
detects the fault
the results of this analysis revealed
the following so we can see here in the
left we see the graph where we have on
the x-axis the frequency domain on the
y-axis the amount of undervolting
offsets we apply and we can see across
the frequency axis that the IMO
instruction is the instruction that
towards the earliest so these are the
forwarding points when we saw the first
point during undervolting
we tested overall more 1 200
instructions approximately across
different CPUs and we found over 71 for
all the building structures
and if you now use this imel instruction
which basically Falls the earliest we
can already detect 92 percent of all
other faults with the email instruction
if you want to have more more certainty
on certain CPUs they have to be
different we also need additional
instructions to protect against these
remaining cases so we have not found our
trap instructions suitable for the
mitigation it's the IMO instruction
which was previously used in the text
too so we cannot use the ammo
instructions to basically protect our
programs let's consider these three
instructions
we now use the compiler to basically at
first insert a state and each basic
block we start the basic block by
checking if these two registers in our
case are 12 and or 13 are still matching
they should always have the same value
otherwise we have to take the default
and securely abort the computation
we then insert this imod instructions in
between and we can also handle some
cases where the IML instruction
basically alter the state of the program
because the IML instruction also orders
the flex register on x86
at the end of each basic block we also
make sure that the basic block contains
an even number of multiplications so
that we always have the guarantee at the
beginning of a basic block these two
registers will match
what this compiler extension enables us
is that it's like a dropping replacement
and we can recompile the complete sjx
SDK and get forward suppression support
so we can detect faults and we Define a
fault Handler where we can abort the
program safely
since we've added now a lot of
instructions we have also to talk about
the negative side of this mitigation the
runtime obviously we add new
instructions into an enclave execution
so we increase the execution time
however remember back at the beginning
this Benchmark only affects sjx enclaves
and allows the remaining system to run
undervolted and probably gain a lot from
that undervolt also as a factor here we
can also choose how many trap
instructions we insert after a certain
instruction so if we just insert one
instruction we call it a placement
density of one that's actually the
x-axis you see and if you insert two
trap instructions after each normal
instructions there will be a placement
density of two the more then placement
density they have the higher your
protection should be so we can see that
we have a linear runtime increase due to
the added instructions also the size is
growing linear linearly compile time
and we also wanted to take a look at
software that had already
um
software-based fault protections built
in so we took a look at the MLS library
and more specifically on the RSA
encryption there so the the they verify
each encrypted decks by decrypting it
again and checking if the plain text
match so if we now remove this check and
replace it with our Minefield
implementation we can see that there are
even cases where Minefield outperforms
this classic random random density check
yes
so
however this is all the performance side
how does it look on the deduction side
we also took a look at that so we reused
the blunderwald PLC in some some parts
of the blunderball POC where you just
tried to fold the result of
multiplications and this is basically
the worst case as we also use the IMO
instruction as trap instruction so we
benchmarking a instruction that was
really likely to forward against another
that's really likely to fall
and we can see on the top left we can
see the recall across the placement
density and can see that we have a good
recall about 90 percent
however the recoil is declining after
certain placement density and that's
also reflected because the recoil does
not consider the case where we observed
faults only in the trap instructions
therefore we also included the
mitigation rate basically if you see a
Ford in a trap instruction you already
know that the system is running near the
critical limits and you should no longer
guarantee to execute The sjx Enclave
code on the system
so that already brings me to my
conclusion so we open source the
complete llvm extension also there's the
access to care the modifications are in
the GitHub reversibility so check that
out if you are interested we also passed
the artifact Evolution for the the best
other Refrigeration for the compiler
extension and all the code and also the
undervolting framework to find
interesting instructions is online and
available if you're more interested in
more details like the exact floating
points of each instructions the analysis
over the whole CPU range and also the
defaulting method so how does default
actually look like for different results
please take a look in the paper and I'm
happy to take any questions