hi my name is I'm from Princeton
University I'm glad to present our work
mitigating membership influence attack
special distillation through another
Ensemble architecture this is a joint
work with my collaborator said leeway
protect from Princeton University and we
write Milad Amir from UMass Amherst
in this work we focus on membership
inference attacks Against the Machine
learning models under the Black Box
access assumption so the Machinery model
will only output the predictions for
each query and for the Target sample the
texture will make corresponding queries
to a Target machine learning model and
guess whether this sample is used to
train a model or not
membership influence attacks can lead to
substantial privacy leakage first this
attack can real private information in
real world scenarios for example knowing
victims presence in hospital analogy
data set reveals that this victim was
once a patient in this Hospital Second
this attack can be Foundation of
stronger tax such as data extraction
attack from large language models as
membership infrastructure tax imposes
severe privacy threats we need to design
defenses against this attacks and to
design defenses we first need to
understand how membership inference
attack works the success of membership
influence attacks is usually because the
machine learning models have different
behaviors our members and now members so
he here the members are samples in our
training search and numbers are samples
not in the training set I use a red card
for members and blue color for numbers
so it might look a little strange on the
presentation but I hope this card works
and
so here is a distribution of
cross-entropy loss members and numbers
and we can see the significant
difference between these two
distributions and our defense intuition
is that we should enforce a model to
behave similarly on all samples so both
include members and not members
in this work we propose a new membership
inference differences called sanana to
enforce the model to behave similarly
our members and our members so the
training data is first used to train the
machine learning models in our first
component split AI after that we will do
the self-destellation and after the
self-disolation process we finally
output the final protective model the
experimental results show that our
defense can achieve a good utility
browse the trade-off we can achieve both
High classification accuracy and also
effectively mitigate the Practical
membership influence attacks
I will first introduce our design
intuition and after that I will explain
our defense framework so we need to
enforce our model to behave similarly
our members and not members but how
let's consider true samples sample a is
in our training set and Sample B is not
in the training set with learning a
machine learning model using this
training search and we can see that
sample a here is a member for this
machine learning model then for the
memory sample a the curve a will follow
the distribution of members and for the
non-member B the curve B will follow the
distribution of non members how can we
make these two queries to follow the
same distribution
so how about removing a from the
training set before the model training
Now sample A and B both are not in a
training set and we will train a new
machine learning model from scratch by
using this new training search and we
can see here sample a is a non-member so
the curve a will follow the distribution
of null members and Sample B is also not
members so could be also called the
distribution number members so now both
queries follow same distribution which
is good however the problem here is that
we cannot remove all points from
training search as we still need
training data to train the models
so how about we consider this design on
multiple models this motivates our
design of split AI
here is a training procedure in splitter
eye we will train case some models in
total so we need case subsets
each training sample will only appear in
K minus L of the okay subsets so a
training sample is memory for k-manner
sales and models and now members for the
remaining else models here consider a as
a member sample and is used to train the
top and a middle model so a is a noun
member for the bottom model after we
generate the subsets we can change some
model with one subset and this is a
training procedure in splitteri now I'll
explain a double inference in Split AI
the intuition for adult influence
follows our design intuition
so sample a is a member and Sample B is
a null member so the bottom model is now
trained with sample A and B so the query
of A and B on the bottom model should
both follow the distribution of null
members
specifically let's use ux to denote some
models which are now trained with this
member sample X if the curry sample is a
member we will average your production
vectors on a member sample X by only
using L sub models which are not trained
with this member sample so here for the
member sample X only the bottom model is
not trained with a so we'll use this
bottom model to get the output
Productions
if the query sample is a non-member we
will randomly select a member sample X
Program and we will average the
production vectors on X by using other
models which are notion with some
non-member sample X a membership
so for the non-member example B suppose
the random select member sample is a
which decides that we should choose the
bottom model so we use this border model
to get the output predictions which also
for the distribution of null members
we analyze the price implications of
Solitaire eye so if the attacker would
only directly creates the model on the
target sample once we call this attack
as direct single core attack which is
also one major attack of direction of
membership influence attacks we're
proofing on paper that that the attacker
cannot infer the membership of this
sample under the directional career
attack the intuitive explanation here is
that no matter whether the sample is
used to transably I or not the output
distribution of this sample are
identical
however the attack is not limited to
only directly clearing the target sample
so here for the memory sample a instead
of occurring a their character can add
small noise to sample a and turn a into
a prime so let's say I will record a
prime as a noun member and might use the
models which are trained with X Prime
for example might use operator model and
the final Productions will follow the
distribution of members the perturbed
member attack motivates our design of
second component self-disolation
we now already have a model splitter eye
which we have similarly about some
members and non-members from a direct
single query attack perspective and we
want a new model to behave similarly
from this perspective to do this we
consider distillation by using the
training a new model using the soft
labels of the training set as we are
using the exact same training set we
call this process as self-disolation
other distillation process we will
remove splitter eye and stuff labels and
only allow the queries to the final to
this new model
a transferability of neural networks
enabled a new model to have similar good
property as split AI so this new model
will also behave similarly for some
members and now members from a direct
single crochetype perspective moreover
the new model also serves a limitation
of split AI in the particular member
attack
in a distillation process we will only
query each exact training sample once
and the tracker only has access can only
include the final project model and
cannot interact with the distillation
process
and that's all for these our design
defenses and for evaluation we consider
three data sets which are also widely
used in previous membership privacy
research and here is those statistics
for training samples and also more
architecture we also investigate
different mode architectures for the
ablation story in the following slides I
will focus on purchase 100 with this
default study
We compare our differences with two
state of our membership infrastructure
defenses including adversary
Equalization and mem card we also
include undefended model as a Baseline
for the evaluation metric we consider
the utility price trade-off so we
consider the classification accuracy for
utility and for privacy analysis we
consider the membership influence
average attack accuracy where the
Baseline in random gas equal to 50
percent
so here is the results the defense
method include undefined model mem card
advocation and art defense and we have
an accuracy and tested the higher the
better and also the best attack accuracy
the lower the better compare our defense
to our different model mm guards are
defense only increase 3.9 classification
access drop but the membership inference
attacks is much more reduced our defense
is 13 lower than our different model and
11.5 percent lower than memguard
compare all defense to the adversary
localization we can say that all
different countries both higher
classification accuracy and also lower
best membership attack accuracy
for more experimental results please
check our paper
in this work we propose a new membership
interest differences called certain
consists of splitter eye and
self-sellation all defense lies in a
categorical membership defenses or
improved membership privacy and high
utility and as shown by the rad plot
where the x-axis is classification
accuracy the the writer the better and
also the y-axis is membership attack
accuracy the lower the battery our
defense can achieve a better utility
membership privacy trade-off compared to
previous defenses we hope our work can
provide insights on membership privacy
either on how to improve the utility for
the DP based approach or how to provide
more probable guarantee for all
differences without losing utility also
feel free to check the artifact on our
GitHub page thank you now I'm ready for
questions