hello everyone I'm reubenhood from
Georgia University today I'd like to
talk about our work on OK Siri or hey
Google evaluating voice brings
distinctiveness via contents based Pro
score
this is our agenda first I'm going to
motivate our work and then talk about
its challenging methodology
then I will introduce how to define a
pro score and wrap up my talk with
findings and conclusions as the end of
talk what I'd like you to take away is
to understand what content can improve
the security of voice print
so what is voice print it's basically a
marable characteristic of a human voice
it is widely used in many scenarios so
the security of voice print is important
so a very nature question is that what
is the security of voice print in this
paper we focus on one aspect which is
distinctiveness that is given any two
user one will not be classified as the
other for instance in a family a normal
case is Alice as a mom can control the
smart speaker with Scranton's voice
print
and if the distinctiveness is low her
some part can impersonate Alice and use
the smart speaker to place block music
that's what we don't want to say
so what's determining the
distinctiveness of voice print
record the example in the previous what
Alice and her son says determines the
voice print so if she see another phrase
hey Siri does her son impersonate her
voice print this paper wants to answer
the question what types of speech
content can provide secure voice print
in terms of distinctiveness
we contrast a voice print security
scouting magic for example when you
input the speech content okay Siri the
scoring function will calculate the
security score give you a security level
and some suggestions and if you put hey
Google it will give you another score
and the referring to the suggestions we
can generate more secure words for voice
print
actually our security score is
statistically related to the
distinctiveness that means high security
score words like Okay Siri is voice
print will be low Force recognition rate
where first recognition contains false
acceptance and false rejection
a very typical scenario to use our Pro
score is Breakup Rewards
smart speaker vendors spent much efforts
finding good recap words and now most of
commercial wake-up words consist of one
or two words and with a prefix words
like OK Google but are they actually
able to provide enough distinctiveness
in voice print our metric can help them
to answer three important questions
whether their pickup was Secure why is
it secure and how to improve them
so how to contrast the scoring metric
we first investigate the automatic
speaker verification system referring to
the workflow we can find the security of
voice print is affected by all modules
including speakers which content
environments and ASP model so how to get
a pro score while the user provides
content but not the rest
the question actually to construct a
universal score it contains two
Challengers when is the score should
adapt to most of Mario speakers and
environment that means the score will
not tell you whether Alice and pop have
the same voice print in a certain model
it gives you statistical results
the other is the capability of handling
the most of speech content that means we
can't measure it from The Limited
corporate
so the basic idea to generate the
universal score is to use the
statistical results of a large scale
measurement
in the measurements for a given speech
content we can get the statistical
results of first recognition rate we
conduct our experiment with over 2 000
speakers and over 1 000 hour samples we
select three typical models including
classical and advanced models ivector X
vector and U level and I believe they
are represents most of cases
and two adapt to most of speech content
we use the basic unit forms to compose
of test audios with arbitrary content we
segments the whole order to phone clips
and the resembles them to test audios so
that over 40 minute orders contain all
kinds of forms
our methodology can be divided into
three key steps we first analyze what
phonetic factors we can derive from
speech content then to test the
relationship between the content and
distinctiveness we construct a data set
that have General enough content
and to conduct a model fitting on the
measurement results in this set to get
the true score
next we'll introduce the component of
the scoring metric Pro score
to study the effect of speech content we
look into it and represents speech
content with some features
since the phone is the basic unit of
language a sentence can be viewed as a
sequence of phones we Define four
phonetic factors which needs lens
elements and order we take OK Google as
an example gaming is from sequence and
phonetic factors
then with maps of magic factors to
security score
the scoring function have seven
variables including four fanatic factors
and three implicit variables they are
models bigger and environment
because output of function proof score
so far we get the input of pro score and
then we are going to parameterize the
function based on the statistical
results of first recognition rate
it consists of two parts one is the fact
of single Factor the other is which
factor is important
for richness we give the statistical
result of far and frr or audios with
different richness we can find as the
richness increases the security
increases as well and when the richness
is larger than 5 its impact is
negligible we can fit the impact as
Financial function we take hey Google
and Google as examples to show the
difference in bridgeness we can find hey
increases the richness by three that has
an improvement on security
so we get the finding the richness of
content should be at least five
for length the statistical result is
similar to that of richness the
difference is that when the lens is
larger than 30 its impact is negligible
we take cell 2 and cell 2 cell 2 as
examples it repeating the word events
increases the length by seven so we get
the finding the contents should be at
least the contain certain forms
for elements we give the sum of far and
frr on diverse forms we're having low
bar means high security we find some
magic phones they have low phosphate
condition rates and better for
generating voice print
for example it is better than all in
three typical models we take two prefix
words okay and hello as examples and
find o as a magic form so we had better
choose more secure forms
for the last Factor order we randomly
change the order of form a and Form B
order has almost no effect on security
we can't consider order in selecting
speech content we also analyze the
combination effect of two factors to
ranking them
we find elements is more important than
lens and the less important than
richness
according to this finding we're obtain
the true score function by data fitting
foreign
magic what can we do with it when
scenario is to help select the secure
recap Awards
first we answer the question whether the
current recap of words are secure we
assess 30 recup words from commercial
products and calculates the approved
score on ivector X vector and u11 models
respectively
we can guess the following finding the
first one we don't worry the richness
because almost all week upwards have
enough richness
even if the richness is enough the
length of most wake up words is
inadequate so we suggest repeating ones
to improve the security
for example repeating Alexa once as
Alexa Elixir it's security score
increases by about 1.
in addition we find an interesting
phenomena Chinese wake-up words prefer
repeating like so too so do it may
derive from linguist habits
but by coincidence that actually
improves the security
we find another interesting phenomena
most of wake up words in English use a
prefix word like hey or hello do they
have an impact on voice print security
We compare the average true score of 7
week upwards with or without prefix
words and calculates the Improvement in
score we find prefix words can increase
the pro score by around the 24 percent
because of its increase the length which
needs and Magic forms and the better
prefix Awards is okay
with the scrolling magic we developed a
voice print security scrolling tool and
make it public on the website here we
have a demo to demonstrate how to assess
and select pickup words possible users
of voice assistants such as
manufacturers and customers can select a
model and input words to generate the
score as an example we compare okay Siri
and hey Google mentioned in the title
and find okay Siri is better than hey
Google in generating secure voice print
to conclude in this work we proposed a
scoring metric called prus score to
quantify the security level of speech
content especially for wake up Awards we
assess 30 commercial wake-up words and
the reviews behind the reason whether it
is cure or not we developed an easy to
use scoring tool to help manufacturers
and users select the secure recap words
in the future we will study the effect
of essence and improve the transfability
of magic across murders
this is my presentation thanks for your
attention