hi my name is Simon and today we're
going to talk about spoofing sign odf
documents and how signatures can be used
for code execution
this book was a joint work with
Christian vladislav and York
so let's start with the basics
in this picture we see an extracted odf
document the contact XML file contains
the main part of the visible content of
the document and the Manifest XML
references to all other files in the rdf
package so the application quickly knows
which files are included there are some
other files in the package which contain
for example format settings or stuff
like that
and if the document contains macros
there's also a basic or scripts
directory that contains a macro code and
in this example the model 1 XML file
contains a simple message box macro and
if we want to run this macro when the
document is opened we also need a
trigger inside the content XML file
and to protect users from malicious
macro codes there are four security
levels so on level very high only macros
from trusted file locations are executed
on level high which means which is the
default level means only side macros
from trusted locations are executed and
on level medium execution must be
confirmed by the user and on level low
no confirmation is required at all and
doing our research we focused on the
level default which requires a trusted
sign Macross
there are two types of signatures in
odaf and micro signatures protects only
the files inside the basic or scripts
directory while document signatures are
calculated over the whole package and
except for the document signatures XML
file
and for document signatures there exist
three different
signature States first the signature is
valid and trusted second the signature
is developed but not trusted for example
because of sales sign certificate was
used for signing
and served the signature's invalid for
example because the content of the
document has been manipulated
so what are the manipulation
possibilities the easiest way is to
manipulate the content directly in the
content XML file
but this of course changes the hash
value of content XML and results in an
invalid signature the second option is
to add a new file uh Evo XML for example
which may overlay the content of the
content XML file but because of the
missing reference in manifest XML the
application will interpret the document
as corrupted
so if we add a reference to the evil XML
file before signing the document and
that's the evil file after some then the
signature is displayed as invalid
because partial signatures are not
allowed according to the odf
specification
so our last our last manipulation
possibility is the signature file itself
and this picture we see the structure of
the signature file
um the sign info part contains
references and hash values to all files
in the document or in case of macro
signatures to all macro files
and in the signature properties we find
the signing time or something's relevant
Parts the signature value element
contains the signed hash value of signed
info and the key info element contains a
signer certificate
um document signatures are based on
classic XML signatures according to the
w3c recommendation and macro signatures
are typically implemented in the same
way
but this also means that the key element
is not protected by the signature
let's start with the attacks on audio X
signatures the certificate doubling
attack works for macro and for document
signatures
and according to the XML schema it is
allowed to add multiple x559
certificates
so the idea of the attack is to confuse
the application by using multiple
certificates in the same signature file
and the attacker's goal is that
different certificates are used for
crypto and for the trust validation
so first the attacker signs and macros
with its own private key and his own
certificate those included and the
signature file as a signer certificate
and on the Second Step the attacker adds
a new X 509 data element to the key info
element
and in this new element for the attacker
inserts a public certificate from a
trusted entity that the victim trusts
for macro code execution
so for example the attacker could
extract the certificate from another
signed document or maybe from a signed
as my email
when the victim opens the manipulated
documents the application checks the
signature and two steps so first it
checks whether the signatures
cryptographically or valid and for this
purpose the first certificate is used so
the attackers certificates that was used
to sign the macro code
and since the public key belongs to the
signing key this check is completed
successfully
and in the Second Step the application
checks whether the signer is trusted and
for this purpose the second certificate
of The Trusted entity is used
and those both checks are parsed and the
macro code is executed
the second attack for today is the
certificate validation bypass attack and
in this attack only works for document
signature the idea of the attack is to
disturb the trust validation process
with unexpected certificate data in
order to turn an untrusted signer into a
trusted one and all we need for this
attack is a safe created and self-signed
certificate
the attacker choose the content of the
document and signs it with its own
private key
but of course the victim will not trust
this document because the attacker is
displayed as a signer and the
certificate was not issued by a trusted
CA
so if the attacker manipulates the
issuer and the subject of the signing
certificate for example to Huma Simpson
who uses the safest CA in the world the
certificate becomes invalid and this
also results in an invalid document
signature
foreign
application can verify the certificate
signature only if it knows which signing
algorithm was used to sign the
certificate
so if the attacker changes this oid
value to an invalid one for example to a
member body which is the oid 1.2
then the application interprets any
certificate that's trusted and displaced
with valid and trusted documents
signature to the victim
let's talk about our evaluation we
developed five attacks and tested them
on three desktop operating systems two
mobile operating systems and two online
services in total 18 applications were
tested and all applications supported
macros and odf documents were vulnerable
to the macro variant of the certificate
doubling attack
and 16 applications were vulnerable to
the document signature variant of the
certificate doubling attack and the same
16 applications were also vulnerable to
manipulations of the signature time
stamp through XML signature wrapping
the certificate validation bypass attack
worked only on Windows operating systems
and they are only for OpenOffice
collaboro office and leapfers
and Microsoft Office was only vulnerable
to the signature upgrade attack
so what is the conclusion and what have
we learned from this the complexity of
XML signatures is still a problem
XML signature wrapping is one example
but developers also need to deal with
unsigned Parts like key environment
and so the specifications should be more
precise what to do with multiple key
materials and stuff like that
if you want to test our attacks on your
own software you are welcome to use our
proof of concept files and GitHub and
our evaluation tool Dockers file
thank you for your attention