hello everyone my name is a postdoc
researcher from the Ohio State
University today I'm going to present
our work on mobile game security playing
without paying detecting vulnerable
payment verification in Native batteries
of a Unity mobile games this is the John
work with my advisor Professor ji Chang
Ling in this work we uncover two
important types of vulnerabilities in
the in-game purchase of a Unity based
mobile games we have a corresponding and
developed a payment where static
analysis tool to detect them and found
about and then thousand games continuing
this vulnerabilities so let's get
started
in 2021
the video game Market made 175 billion
in Revenue worldwide surprisingly mobile
platforms have become the largest
segment of game industry which generated
a 52 percent of global Revenue it is
more than the combination of both PC
games and the console games
for a mobile game there are several ways
for monetization such as pay to play
in-game advertising and in-game purchase
which also known as igp in igp the
developer offers a digital products for
users to purchase among them igp is the
most popular one to help developers
Implement igp Play Store provide SDK and
APS for faster implementation however
game developers often use the wrapped
sdks that are provided by game engines
one benefit is that such apis support
across platforms including Android and
iOS so how does ADP work
after the user clicks to purchase the
game first initializes the payment
request to the App Store App Store
processes the transaction by interacting
with the user and it will return the
payment response to the game if the
transaction failed it includes the
reason otherwise it contains the detail
of the transaction including the receipt
which will be used to validate the
transaction
then the game will send the transaction
to the game server for validation and
login
the game server can use the app specific
public key to validate the transaction
signature or it can send the transaction
to the app store for verification after
validating the transaction the game
server
then distributes other digital products
to the user obviously it is uh critical
for the game to verify the transaction
at the server side however we found that
Summer Games implemented igp in the
wrong ways as shown in the picture after
receiving the payment response for the
App Store some games directly trusted
the response without verifying the
transaction since the mobile device is
controlled by users it is easy to hijack
and modify the response in step 3 so
that the payment can be bypassed we call
this vulnerability lack of verification
in another case some game just verify
the transaction locally for the same
reason it is easy for an attacker to
bypass the verification logic such as
making it always written true we call
this vulnerability local verification
both implementations are vulnerable to
payment bypass attacks for the game that
are developed with the different game
engines although the high level steps
are the same the SDK and the
implementation details are different as
such in this work we are targeting the
most popular game engine
um our experiment on 300 000 games
confirmed that Unity is the most popular
one it supports the cross-platforms and
offers an easy to use IDE the program
language is c-sharp however the
compiling process is a euro compared to
normal C sharp program
in particular the social Pro the c-sharp
code will be first compiled to assembles
which are also known as the RL code then
the i o code will be translated to C
plus plus source code and a standard C
plus plus compiler will compile the code
to in into native binary format
eventually the entire process is called
rl2cp it will make the game code secure
and fast however it also makes the game
hard to analyze
let me show you some examples
on the left hand side is the C sharp
source code of the igp processing code
the function name the process purchase
at line 3 is The Wristband of the
payment response from App Store the
parameter in line 4 is the payment
response in the function the game
directly verifies the transaction at
line 11 by using the app specific public
key which is a defined at the line 7.
here is another example it extracts the
transactional receipt at Line 6 and
retrieved the corresponding signature at
line 7 and 8. then put it in a HTTP
request which will be sent to the server
for verification at line 9. next let me
show you the corresponding binary code
in artwork we use gidra to process the
battery the first part is the address
and the byte code the second part is the
disassemble code and the last part is
the p-code that is generated by gidra we
can see that each c-sharp code has been
translated to one or several native
instructions and many symbols are
missing in this work we handle the
native boundaries
so our goal is to identify the
vulnerable igp for the games that are
based on unit engine given a game
battery we want to identify whether its
igp is remote verification local
verification or lack of verification
the first change is how to identify the
vulnerable igp our Insight is to take
advantage of system and unity engine
apis in particular we first abstract the
problem into a data flow analysis
Problem by tracing the data flow of The
Returned transaction if it flows to the
network API then we identify it as a
remote verification if it flows to a
local validation API it is local
verification all other cases are lack of
verification as such for the shown
example the left one should be
classified as the local verification and
the red one is remote verification
the Second Challenge is how to pinpoint
Target apis as mentioned the game binary
does in the contain any symbols without
the symbols we cannot identify the apis
our insert is that r2cp actually packed
the symbols of functions and the classes
into a separate file
which is required for the game Banner
because c-sharp supports features like
reflection which means symbols and such
by analyzing the file we are able to
uncover some symbols
to the last change I ordered to see if
he has submerged the system libraries
and game code together as a result if we
perform traditional data flow analysis
we have to analyze the system Library
when the game called system apis it will
make this analysis too complicated our
Insight is using API summary in
particular we first summarize the
propagation rules for the system and the
unity apis we encounter such an API
instead of analyzing its code we
directly apply the rules
however there is a one indirect data
flow often used in Social programs as
shown in the example at line 8 the code
stored the receipt data in class field
at line four this data could be could be
used by other functions which is uh
which will lead to an indirect upload to
handle such a case our insert is to
build a global class table it indicates
which fields of the classes are
attempted and should be traced as soon
in the top right it is a global class
table please find more details in our
paper if you are interested
with all those insights we have designed
and implemented the payment scope a
static analysis tool based on guitar at
high level it consists of three
components metadata extraction which
uncovers the binary symbols payment
aware data flow analysis and the
vulnerability identification to test the
payment scope we have collected two mini
mobile apps from Google Play and from
the 10 000 mobile games that are
developed based on unity and supports
igp the experiments experiment to serve
almost 28 days to our surprise we found
8 000 games lack of verification and 721
games only verify the transaction
locally
so this means more than 84 percent of
fantastic games are vulnerable to verify
the experimental results we have
conducted FP and F and Analysis manually
we applied the following rules to
collect the sample games in total we
collected 280 games to confirm the
vulnerability we first use our
virtualization tool to inject fake
transactions into the game then we use a
code patching to disable the local
verification API
in the analysis we didn't find the NFP
and the FN is a 29 which means there are
more vulnerable games please refer to
the paper for details
to have a concrete understanding of the
vulnerable games we have grouped the
tested games based on their install
times the polyline in the one is the
vulnerable read of each group we can see
that the vulnerable effects not only
less popular games but also super
popular ones meanwhile from the polyline
we can see that less popular games have
a much higher possibility of being
vulnerable and the developers of popular
games are more careful to secure their
igp then we group with the games based
on the game category we can see that
there are two types of games those
vulnerability read is higher or equal to
90 a possible reason is that the games
in these two categories are more likely
to be a single player game and these
games depend Less on the server
having identified the vulnerabilities we
have made responsible disclosure to both
unity and the game developers in total
we have contacted the 5 000 developers
of the vulnerable games and we have
received the hundreds of responses many
developers promised to patch the
vulnerability in the next version
and for the sake of time I'm going to
skip the limitation and the related work
so in summary in this work we presented
the payment scope a fully automated
system to identify vulnerable igp among
Unity based mobile games our experiment
shows that 84 percent of testy games are
vulnerable the source code or payment
scope is available at the GitHub please
check it out if you are interested
and due to a family issue I cannot join
the conference in person but my advisor
Professor Jason will be there to answer
your questions thank you