yeah thanks for introduction and hi
everyone I'm humbin from Duke University
and today I'm glad to present our paper
poison encoder poisoningly unlevel
pre-training data in contrastive
learning this is a join work with my
colleague Qing and my advisor Neil
supervised learning is a well-known
conventional machine learning Paradigm
given a specific task for instance
traffic sign recognition supervised
learning requires manually labeling a
large amount of Level Training data to
train a classifier given another task
supervised learning will repeat this
process again
so the key challenge of supervised
learning is that it requires a large
amount of labeled training data for each
task
contrast learning aims to address this
challenge
by leveraging a large amount of unlevel
data
which can be images or image test pairs
at least on level data usually comes
from the public internet for instance
social media websites or Google search
givenly unlevel data contrast learning
aims to pre-train a neural network which
is called encoder and a pre-trained
encoder can be used as a general purpose
feature extractor for various Downstream
tasks
suppose we have a pre-training encoder
to build a downstream classifier only
requires small amount of or no leveled
training data
by analogy to the computer system
encoder study the security of encoder is
like the operating system levels
security study in AI ecosystem
next I will introduce more details on
how to pre-train encoder and how to
build downswing classifiers
given an unable pre-training image
we use dataugmentations for instance
random cropping and resizing of
um
render horizontally flipping to create
two random cognitive views we have
encoder and we use it to produce future
vectors for each of them
given another pre-training image we will
repeat the list process again
the encoder is pre-trained in a way such
that It produced similar feature vectors
for two augmented views come from the
same image but these similar feature
vectors for two augmented views comes
from different images
given a set of training inputs of a
downstream task we use the pre-training
encoder to extract feature vectors for
each training input and together with
the corresponding levels we train we
build a downstream classifier
by standard supervised learning way
and during testing time given a testing
input we use the encoder to produce
feature vectors for it and use the trend
function classifier to predict the final
level
in our work we find that the encoder in
contrast learning is vulnerable to
poisoning attacks
and the attacker's goal is to make an
arbitrary attacker chosen image for
instance stop sign image here we call it
Target input to be misclassified by the
downstream classifier built on the
poison encoder to make arbitrary
attacker chosen prediction for instance
speed limit here we call it target class
an attacker can achieve this goal by
Craft and inject the poisoning inputs to
the unleveled pre-training data
we note that the most existing points
and attacks are designed for supervised
learning and our poisoning attack aim is
to poison encoder to make multiple
Target Downstream tasks have attacker
desired Behavior
in terms of our threat model the
attacker picked one target bouncing task
for instance traffic sign recognition
one target input for instance an image
of stop sign
and the target class for instance V
limit
our attack can be used to attack
multiple Target Downstream tasks and
multiple Target inputs more results can
be found in our paper and for a reason
of Simplicity we default to use one
target downswing task and one target
input
our text goal is to make the target
Downstream classifier misclassify the
target input as target class
and in terms of attackers background
knowledge the attacker has access to a
few images from a target class for
instance some speed limit images we call
them reference inputs
the key idea of our attack is to first
we formulate poisoning attack as a
bi-level optimization problem and then
we use non-iterative heuristic solution
to solve that
the first optimization problem
formulates the attacker's goal the
attacker aims to find a set of points
and inputs XP which make the
pre-training encoderstar pre-trained
only clean inputs XC and points need
input XP to make the same to make the
downstream classifier
um produce the same prediction for
Target input XT and reference input XR
that means the encoder will produce
similar feature vectors for Target input
and reference input
we standing up and take average since we
have a set of reference inputs
we not let the pre-train encoderstar
already include another optimization
problem
let's optimizely encoders with Theta by
minimizing the contrast loss
we call the first optimization problem
and a second optimization problem
respectively as alter and inner
optimization problem
it is well known challenging to solve
this high-level optimization problem by
using statistic gradient descent
because every step of optimization for
the outer optimization problem we need
to pre-train a whole encoder to solve
the inner optimization problem so we
resort to heuristic Solutions
given the target input and the reference
input we create the poisoning input by
either horizontally or vertically
combine them
so when the encoder is pre-trained only
poison input it will create two random
augmented views by using render
augmentation by using random cropping
and resizing and the encoder will
pretend in a way to produce similar
future vectors for at least two
augmented views
and we note that at the same time it's
softly in the organization problem which
is pre-trained encoder it simultaneously
solving outer organization problems to
make the encoder produce similar feature
vectors for the augmented views from the
target input and reference inputs we
called it approximately solving because
augmentation augmented views are not
exactly the same as Target input and
reference inputs
we noticed that such kind of combined
images is a real maybe a real world
issue in the public internet
and the next country evaluation part we
pretend encoder using ccrr and
pre-training data set 14k and we also
explore more pre-training algorithms and
more pre-trained data sets including the
full imagenet and this is a default
setting I will report in this talks
experimental results and for building
Downstream classifiers we use three
popular Downstream tasks and using the
downstream classifier as a fully
connected new network
and the target input and target class
are different for different Target
downswing tasks and we choose randomly
choose the reference inputs from each
target class in Target launching task
testing data by default we use 50
reference inputs one percent points and
rate and 10 exp random experimental
trials to report experimental results
and we first want to evaluate the
effectiveness of our attack
so given the target inputs and Target
costs we build the downstream classifier
based on the points encoder if the
reduction classifier make the same
prediction as Target costs our attack
success
otherwise our Tech fails
solely a text success rate is a fraction
of targeted misclassification for
attacker
our experimental result shows that our
attack is highly effective across
different Target Downstream tasks
we also want to evaluate whether our tag
is easy
by evaluating the clean accuracy and
points and accuracy given a clean
testing input we first build Downstream
classifier based on the clean encoder
leads and its testing accuracy is called
clean accuracy we also build Downstream
classifier based on the poison encoder
and its accuracy is called Poison
accuracy
if
ideally The Poisoned accuracy is close
to the clean accuracy our attack is DC
to the encoder provider
and we show that our points encoder
maintains utility which means for each
Target Junction task
the points and accuracy is closely clean
accuracy
and we also explore three types of
defenses against our points and encoder
they include pre-processing improcessing
and post-processing defenses which are
respectedly respectively deployed before
during and after pre-training encoder
due to a time limit I want to conclude
these defenses which so that on
pre-processing defenses are either
insufficient or ineffective
and for with explore 3 in-processing
defenses they are effective but will
sacrifice the utility of encoder for
Downstream classification
and for post-processing defense
we fine-tune pre-training encoder for
extra epochs on some clean images
we find that it's effective without
sacrificing encoder's utility however it
requires manually collecting a large set
of clean images
to run up my presentation
we find that contrast learning is highly
vulnerable to poisoning attack
and insecure encoder may lead to a
single point of failure of a AI
ecosystem because they will impact the
security of multiple Target Downstream
tasks
and defenses are insufficient to defend
against poison encoder and thanks for
listening I'm happy to answer questions