foreign
I'm a PhD student at UC Berkeley and
today I'm happy to be here to talk about
our recent work on polynomial commitment
with a one-to-man approver and
applications
it is a joint work with skin changes
here is
so first of all let's talk about the
background on their knowledge proofs
their knowledge proofs is a
cryptographic tool between two parties
the first party is approver and the
second party is the welfare and in the
protocol the poorer wants to convince
the welfare of some computation or
function C or with input X and W equals
y here x is a public input so X is known
to both parties W is private to the
approver and the verifier time node w
after seeing the output and the proof
the verifier can be sized accept the
statement or reject the statement
and there are three important parties of
their knowledge proofs the first one is
a complaintness it means if the program
is honest the statement is correct then
the verifier will accept it and some is
means if the the proverb is cheating and
the statement is incorrect the verifier
will reject the statement acceptable
negligible probability and their
knowledge means the proof don't leak any
information about the private input of
the proverb
and there are many applications of their
knowledge truths for example we can use
zero knowledge proofs to create
Anonymous payment on blockchain also we
can use the zero improves to build the
JK drop protocol or which is uh which
which can be treated as a solution uh as
one solution for the blockchain
scalability
and in most of the zkp protocols they
just model the function C using a
circuit so as you can see here uh the X
and W is still the input of the circuit
and wise output of the circuit C
so in your traditional setting of The
their knowledge truths there is only one
plural and only one welfare but in our
work we consider a new setting with one
proper and unverfials and we call it one
too many plural so as you can see here
the input is still X and W and the
circuit C Remains the Same but output y
can be divided into n pieces and each
welfare will only get one component of
the output y i and the each welfare does
no other components so that is our new
setting and why are we interested in
this setting because it has some
applications for example a direct
application of of these new settings
verifiable security sharing so uh in the
verifiable secret sharing scheme we have
one plural and Welfare and approver owns
the secret uh as key and he wants to
share the ASCII to earn Wi-Fi so the
unwell first can help him to keep the
secret
so he splits asking into emphasis and
sends his pieces to each welfare along
with a proof
and then if all welfast get together
then they can reconstruct the secret key
here is the stressful T in the scheme
that means any subset of verifiers with
size at least T they can recover the
secret key however any subset of buffers
with size smaller than T they can learn
nothing about the secret and with both T
has the same order as n in general
and VSS has also some applications in
the real world for example it can be
used in the MPC protocol and it can be
used for the cryptocurrency wallet so it
can help the user to keep their secret
key and the VSS can also be used to
construct distribute TK generation and
the random Beacon
and the classic secret sharing scheme is
the Shamir secretary sharing so in the
Shamir secret sharing the proverb
encodes the secret key with the
polynomial f as you can see here and
then he evaluate F on different on
different points from one qn then he
sends all these evaluations to
unveriferous respectively
then the buffer can recover
the polynomial the secret by polynomial
interplation
okay since uh the one who prove when too
many Proverbs that he has some
applications so uh we want to have like
a new and good algorithm for this new
setting and the naive solution is
straightforward so in this case the
poorer just runs the circuit and times
uh for different for a different output
so it will generate in different proofs
and send all these things all these
things to the Belfast individual
respectively
and then it caused the Brewer in time n
times C because it runs the circuit by
end times uh which is not good so we ask
we ask a natural question can the
proverb reduce or improves for the cost
of only rounding circuit was
and the answer is yes
so in our new oxen the prayer can uh
runs the zkb protocol on the 30C only
once to generate uh the earned proofs in
one shot
so the proof uh the period time will be
reduced to a linear in the circuit size
which is also optimal because the plural
at least needs to run the circuit to get
all of the output
and next let us move into the technical
part
so uh in this part we just suppose the
circuit C is layered and you know there
are many zkb protocols like herx Libra
and Virgo working on the layered circuit
and in this uh the heavy protocols uh
the general idea is that they can reduce
the claim about output to the claim of
the input layer by layer
so in the layer search model our Channel
idea is in the first step we insert one
extra layer on top of the output layer
as you can see in this figure we insert
one layer yr on top of output all of the
output Y and you can imagine wire is
just you know random linear combination
of of this y
and then the program runs and protocols
or with an wire files and then they can
he can reduce all of its own claims
about different Yi to the same Claim
about yr so the plural Aggregates and
claims in one layer in one step and the
prior time for this step is only a login
and the next step and verify will share
the same Claim about yr and then the
prayer can run the gcare protocol uh
sorry around the Nicky protocol to
reduce the same claim of the y r to the
claim of the input and all of us should
share the same uh proof so the approver
only needs to run the circuit once the
cost of the proverb is linear in the
circuit size and by combining these two
steps uh the final period time is still
linear in the circuit size
and in our organs there is assumption
that uh all welfare have the same Grand
Miss but that is not true in the inner
in non-interactive model so in our paper
we also post a new virgin transformation
to force all welfares to agree on the
same random challenge I don't have time
uh to talk about this uh the details but
you can check our paper for more details
and then we will have the new one to
many plural algorithm we can apply our
techniques to the uh Shamir secretary so
you know music reassuring the input uh
is is the encoding polynomial F which is
private to the approver and uh wait wait
the circuit is just the the fft circuit
to get an evaluations
so in this case uh our prayer time is
only a login because the size of the fft
circuit is unlocked but the naive
solution is unsquare so we reduce the
plural time from N squared to n log n
and uh we we can we can build the VSS
without a trusted setup if we apply the
transparent zkp protocols like hyrax or
Virgo on the circuit
and that is the experimental result on
our BSS without trusty setup and the
black Square represents our solution and
the blue one represent the naive
solution so as you can see our solution
is much much faster than the naive
solution and the knife solution can now
scale up to the large instances and as
the number of parties increases the Gap
becomes bigger
and additionally we also have uh the
contribution on optimal VSS scheme based
on the kdt and kcg needs a trusted setup
so in original VSS schemes using kdg
commitment uh the plural computation is
unscrewed and the proof size verify uh
verify is constant
and later on in the following work of uh
in a link and their co-authors they
improve the poor computation to unlock
it but it brings our overhead of login
for the proof size per verify
and in our work we aggregate these two
results altogether so we can have a
optimal as a scheme based on kdg which
has constant proof size as well as the
end login prover computation at the same
time
and I don't have time to get into the
details uh you can check the paper for
more details and I'd mentioned here the
same algorithm was also proposed
independently by other researchers if
you are interested you can check with
the GitHub link
and finally that is uh the summary of
our work so in the first part we have a
new one to many plural setting and we
have a new new algorithm for this
setting and apply applying uh the same
techniques to VSS we will get the
proverb optimal VSS scheme without
trusty setup and on the other hand we
also have optimal versus scheme with a
trusty setup based on the kdg commitment
and that's all thank you you can check
our code via the GitHub link and I'm
happy to take the question session