so today I'm going to talk to you about
how you can take some of the ugliest
code terrible code you can find put it
into your process and still somehow
survive
so untrusted code is everywhere with
plugins extensions libraries and somehow
we still need to run it how do we do
this the security Community has come up
with all kinds of different approaches
to handle such untrusted code one of
which is software sandboxing in this
talk I will be focusing on intra process
sandboxing this is where you can take a
bunch of different bits of code put them
into sandboxes of their own and these
sandboxes can only communicate or work
with their environment through a series
of trusted apis
and indeed they cannot affect the
environment in any other way here the
environment refers both to the host
process the other sandboxes in the same
process and the outside world
the primary goal with this of course uh
is safety secondary but still important
goals include performance and ease of
use
and in the space of the web this is
where web assembly comes in
people would like to compile
all kinds of code from all different
languages and still be able to run it in
your browser but this code is generally
untrusted it's the web after all and
thus webassembly was born
webassembly is intended to be safe for
sandboxing indeed it promises
lightweight safe and fast execution of
untrusted code on the web
but notice none of those properties are
necessarily web specific we would like
to do this beyond the web too and indeed
many groups have recognized this and
with things such as wozzi uh webassembly
has now been used beyond the web too
however these promises of safety are
only as safe as the implementation
and this is where our work comes in
our contributions are that we explore
two distinct techniques to achieve
provably safe sandboxing the first is a
formally verified sandboxing compiler
where you get machine checked proofs of
safety the second are wasum provides
competitive performance with provable
safety without the tedium of writing
formal proofs
oops sorry I did mention formal
verification so a very brief dungeon
formal verification provides
mathematically strong guarantees about
software using tools like f-star Daphne
lean and so on we can specify properties
as pre and post conditions and dependent
types and such and then write proofs
about the code these proofs are checked
by the machine
and these proofs look like we're right
lemmas and then insert assertions into
the code these assertions are checked
statically at verification time rather
than the normal assertions you're used
to in most programming languages which
are run at runtime since they're checked
statically these assertions hold for any
possible inputs to your software
you may have heard of some traditional
verified compilers such as with compsert
a traditional verified compiler shows
that the output codes behavior is
equivalent to the behavior of the input
code unfortunately
this means that it's restricted to Safe
input code turning into safe machine
code and indeed it says nothing about
unsafe or malicious input code
with a sandboxing compiler what we would
like to do is have safe code becomes a
stay safe and unsafe or malicious code
becomes safe somehow
and this is where we wasn't comes in
our top level theorem statement written
in simplified form here looks a bit like
this I don't expect you to read that
written in simpler English if we start
the program the compile code at any okay
state
if we run it for any number of steps we
should still remain in an okay state
what does this okay mean
okay means that we only perform
explicitly allowed Behavior
since we're performing an allow list of
behaviors this completely prevents
things like out of bound memory accesses
writing to read only memory for example
or making calls to unsafe apis or
arbitrary system calls and so on thus
sandboxing is guaranteed this way
what is the proof of such a theorem look
like
well it looks a bit like that it's about
3 500 lines of code and proof and this
is just for the sandboxing pass to set
up the infrastructure the environment
and getting all the way to having
compilable runnable code it took about
15 000 lines of code
clearly this takes a lot of effort
so at a high level what does this proof
look like
we first started off with coarse grain
control flow integrity
this allows us to introduce runtime
software fault isolation checks that
cannot be bypassed
with the software fault isolation checks
we ensure that the linear memory in
webassembly the tables and so on are
handled correctly
the checks make sure that all accesses
stay within a statically sized sandbox
but of course this takes a lot of effort
and this is where our wasm comes in it
would be witchcraft if we could provide
these guarantees without the tedium of
formal proofs
our Insight here is that if you lift
untrusted code to a type or memory safe
language then
compile that to machine code
that compiled machine code
is imbued with the properties the safety
properties that the type of memory safe
language had
in the case of R wasm we specifically
pick rust
we've across since it provides
predictable performance it does not have
a garbage collector
for those who are aware we explicitly we
explicitly stay in the safe subset of
rust which means we forbid unsafe
Behavior
the orgasm sandbox saying thus the
safety derives directly from the type
safety and memory safety of rust
the SFI checks still remain runtime
checks however we can now rely upon the
optimizations provided by the rust
compiler
this means that Superfluous or
unnecessary checks are completely
optimized aware
since we're lifting to a higher level
language we can actually experiment with
different ideas uh in the case of our
wasm we support both static and
dynamically sized sandboxes
and indeed other extensions can be
provided easily
this includes things like inline
reference monitors that you can use to
implement tracers and sanitizers
and the really fun part is that these
get optimized in tandem with the code
that you're producing since the
optimizer gets both the inline reference
Monitor and the code and is able to
optimize that together
what is the sort of our wasm compilation
to look like
let's take a toy example where we're
adding a bunch of numbers together
specifically numbers one to N I don't
expect you to read that webassembly code
the lifter or wasm
takes that code and performs almost a
line by line translation
this introduces a whole bunch of
abstractions and indeed naive
compilation of this to machine code
would lead to extremely inefficient code
however the optimizer can kick in and is
able to blast away all of those
abstractions that are introduced and is
able to produce highly optimized code
so how does this perform in practice
we show that we wasm and our wasm are
quite competitive with other compilers
in this graph on the x-axis we have a
collection of webassembly runtimes
including interpreters and compilers
I've highlighted we was in our wasm
there
these are sorted by median performance
on a series of standard wasn't
benchmarks
on the y-axis we have normalized
slowdown on a log scale
this is normalized against pure native
execution where you do not even include
webassembly
of course the inter
are kind of slow
and since we wasm is a compiler it is
able to outperform the interpreters
consistently on every single benchmark
however we wasn't slower than all the
other compilers
our wasm itself trades blows back and
forth with each benchmark
and indeed for some of the longer
running benchmarks it can sometimes be
even two times as fast as even the
fastest on the median which is the one
on the right wavm
so how let's also look at the trade-offs
between we wasm and r wasm qualitatively
for The Trusted Computing base we wasn't
is formally verified with a traditional
TCP which includes things like the
verification language that we used
f-star and The Trusted printer and so on
in contrast R wasms since we're
performing a lifting to a high level
code we get portability across
architectures for free which we wouldn't
get in we wasm since we're directly
talking about machine code
and with Russ optimization we get better
execution speed with our wasm
however if we would like to extend the
properties that we prove
then we wasn't is much better suited
since it is written in a verification
oriented language
however our wasm is better suited for
runtime extensions as I talked about
before
with a high level language we do not
need to worry about how it might for
example mess with the register allocator
if we introduced an inline reference
monitor
in terms of effort our wasm was
significantly easier to work on both for
initial development as well as ongoing
maintenance
in conclusion
in this work we have explored two
concrete compelling points in the design
space for implementing provably safe
sandboxing with webassembly
we have shown that high performance and
strong safety are not mutually exclusive
goals
and indeed there is a wide space that's
interesting and Rich and open for
further exploration
all of our code is open source
thank you