foreign
and thank you for joining the session
whether you're here in person in Boston
or joining virtually
I will be presenting our work today this
was
um a collaboration between Daniel Trace
research in Austria
um Grazie University of Technology and
the sister Helm Health Center for
information security
so kind of the motivation for this work
is some of the horrifying code we see
here
um so micro architectural attacks as I'm
sure many of you are aware and know from
experience
um can be quite complicated to implement
it can be quite frustrating even if
you're familiar with systems programming
and working in assembly we're trying to
do things here that aren't supposed to
be done we're trying to access values
that aren't meant to be architecturally
accessible so we do some really weird
stuff and it can be very difficult to
explain your code to other people
it can be difficult to explain the code
to yourself when you come back to it
after a year or so
so these attacks are super complex to
implement this is slowing progress in
attack research and it's a barrier to
entry for the field
it makes teaching microarchitectural
security really challenging and it also
increases the risk that our mitigations
are incomplete if even implementing
attack to test our mitigations against
is quite challenging and we don't know
if we've got it right
so we asked ourselves what does the
attack development process look like in
these three contexts of attack research
teaching and mitigation
and how similar are these three contexts
are they maybe similar enough that we
can meaningfully talk about some kind of
common attack development process
um and if they are could we maybe
facilitate the development process for
all three of them
spoiler alert they are similar enough
so we did the first systematization of
the micro architectural attack
development process
we did a mixed methods analysis
combining a literature review of Prior
work expert interviews with 16
practitioners from Academia and Industry
and a user study with 28 graduate
students who were taking an introductory
course in side channels and
microarchitectural attacks
and we focused on four research topics
firstly the attack building blocks so
the core Snippets of code that are being
used to implement these attacks and
obviously every attack is slightly
different but we found there were some
common building blocks that were
occurring again and again for example
high resolution timers cash attack
Primitives the ability to modify page
tables
um secondly we also looked into micro
architectural control and techniques
that people have developed for
fine-grained control so that we can have
reliable attacks reliable experimental
results
thirdly the programming languages people
are using and the existing tooling the
worst some existing microarchitectural
attack development libraries and we
evaluated those in our user study
and finally the overall development
process so things like key communication
challenges
um and whether the development process
was iterative
so for the full insights I'd invite you
to take a look at our paper but I would
say some of the most interesting
insights were firstly that we found
practitioners were doing a mix of
evolutionary prototyping so starting
from an initial attack POC and
iteratively improving upon it and also
throw away prototyping so these are
one-off experiments where we might be
trying to test a hypothesis about where
the leakage comes from which micro
architectural element it is or perhaps
just an attack idea that didn't work out
and even these throwaway ones even the
ones that get thrown away never make it
into the paper are a crucial part of the
attack development process the final
attack wouldn't be there if we hadn't
had this initial work
practitioners also always begin in C or
assembly for maximum control
so even if we're trying to make a
browser-based attack we start off in
native code
because this in if you start
implementing in JavaScript straight away
there's just too many variables to
control too many things that could go
wrong if you're trying to debug why you
haven't got leakage
it's very difficult to isolate what's
wrong
also a lot of time goes into developing
custom drivers or custom operating
systems these are often required for the
privileged building blocks for attacks
for example the ability to modify page
tables or to read and write model
specific model specific registers
as you can imagine there's a lot of
Maintenance effort involved in that it's
a big initial time investment but also
needs maintaining as for example the
Linux kernel gets updated
and proof the concept can be really
powerful communication tools and the
obvious example here is in the
disclosure process when we present a POC
to a manufacturer but complexity makes
them less effective and even within a
research group we heard from
practitioners that sometimes they had
difficulty understanding proofs of
concept from their collaborators
for example might be a POC that they
can't run on their own system because
they don't have Intel sgx we're looking
at some strange assembly and trying to
trying to make sense of what's going on
there
so we based on this analysis we
determined that the best way we could
facilitate the attack development
process was by improving upon the
existing software tooling to try and
reduce the complexity of this
implementation
we developed two Frameworks the first
one was libt which is a cross-platform
attack development API in C
provides 142 functions for the most
common attack building blocks that we
identified
It Sports Linux Windows Android which
means you can run it on your phone and
we did
um and it's a single C header with a
supporting kernel driver so it's quite
easy to integrate into existing projects
and for our privileged building blocks
we built upon existing work with PT
editor for modifying page tables and sgx
step for fine grain control over Intel
sgx
secondly we built Firefox
ified version of the Firefox browser
which provides the functionality of
Liberty in JavaScript
why would we want to do this well this
means that we don't need to Port an
attack PSU we have a native code
completely over to JavaScript in one go
we can
basically take our native code proof of
concept use exactly the same functions
so it's almost a native code proof of
concept in the browser and then building
block by building block replace it with
vanilla JavaScript or webassembly and
doing this step-by-step process makes
the attack development process much
easier
so this framework can be used in
directly in the JavaScript shell it's a
spider monkey firefox's JavaScript
engine or in the browser if you want to
investigate interactions with the user
interface as well
one limitation is we have some overhead
from the JS API wrapper so when we
switch execution context from JavaScript
to C plus
that and cause a bit of overhead it
means that you can't run Liberty
functions speculatively so some of your
core attack Primitives do still need to
be implemented in JavaScript
so with these two Frameworks we
determine a process that we call rapid
prototyping which is inspired by the use
of rapid prototyping in other Industries
And I stress here we didn't just plug
this out of thin air this really is
based on the process that we heard from
practitioners what was really
interesting though was that everyone we
interviewed to stressed they didn't have
any kind of common attack process
development process in every attack is
different development always varies I
don't really know what I'm doing I'm
like stumbling around in the dark with
these experiments but hearing from so
many practitioners
across so many different attacks we
really could see that the process was
very iterative even if that wasn't clear
to practitioners themselves
and I can say from experience
implementing attacks often it does feel
just super frustrating and unclear when
you take the high level perspective
we're starting from a hypothesis we
Implement that in native code
and then using SC Firefox as I mentioned
we can take that straight to the browser
and now we can start thinking about
replacing each one of those building
blocks step by step we might need to go
back to lib team and iterate backwards
and forwards because we might have some
building blocks that have never been
implemented in JavaScript before so we
need to do some experiments to
understand how we can achieve that
and eventually we get our fully fledged
attack proof of concept
let's make this a bit more concrete with
an example zombie load in JavaScript
so to recap zombie load is a micro
architectural data sampling attack where
we sample data from the line fill
buffers in CPU
it's triggered by a zombie load so
that's a load that faults triggering a
microcode assist
and transiently some data is returned
from this faulting load but it's not the
data we try to access it data from the
line field office whatever happened to
be there at the time
um so as you can see here we've got the
mindful buffer and this is a really
interesting Target because any loads on
The Sibling hyper thread are going to
come through the line fill buffer into
the L1 cache so we can pick up on these
we decided to implement zombie load
variant 3 because it's the most
practical one for an unprivileged
attacker
and here we need four building blocks we
need two mappings to the same physical
address
we need to have the access bit cleared
on one mapping to trigger a microcode
assist
also we need a way to flush the other
mapping at the same time this causes a
cache line conflict and is also a
crucial part of creating this zombie
load
and we need a way to transiently encode
and recover the leaked data which will
be a cash convert channel has been
demonstrating a lot of private work
so here is Liberty in action um this is
the API I apologize we've got quite so
much crammed on one slide but what I
really wanted to illustrate here is that
we don't need many lines of code
and we tried with the API to make things
as conceptual as possible so get away
from that sort of overhead of thinking
about the implementation details let's
clear the access bit for example in one
line
um and in our core attack Loop you can
see it's as simple as you're saying
flush offers mapping then we have this
speculation start on end block which
looks a bit like an if block that is
actually hiding some assembly code but
we don't need to care about that we
don't want to we want to work at a
higher abstraction level
um so we within this block we have our
two instructions that are going to be
run speculatively
the Liberty access to zero is extending
our transient window and then we access
map2 and we're going to encode that into
our cache cover Channel That's provided
by libt
but because this is zombie load we're
not encoding the actual value map to we
are encoding data from the line fill
buffers and then we have a handy helper
function to create a histogram to plot
the data that we're getting
so we can see here that the sibling
hyper thread is loading the value X
we've got a little bit of noise but the
signal is very clear and we can use
Liberty's paging functions to check that
we did actually achieve what we wanted
we cleared the access bit on our second
mapping and not on our first mapping
so now we want to take this into the
browser
um first we observe that we can get
these two mappings we need if we Port
the PSC to Windows and then we can rely
on memory deduplication Windows
um has memory duplication enabled again
within the same privilege context so we
can just set up two arrays with the same
values weight while windows deduplicates
that for us and now we have two mappings
to the same physical page windows will
also helpfully clear the access bit for
us so that is another privileged
building block that we can now do in
unprivileged JavaScript
the big question though can we leak
without a flush
what we discovered in our prototyping is
that we don't actually need a flush a
speculative access to that first mapping
at a different offset at the same time
we're trying to access the second
mapping still induces a cache line
conflict still gives us zombie loads and
this is a big finding because in the
original zombie load paper it was
documented that the cl flush instruction
was a requirement so one of the
potential mitigations for restricted
environments was instruction filtering
to prevent this flushing but now zombie
load is feasible in the sandbox
so here we see SC Firefox I mentioned
the API is very similar by Design
so a lot of our building blocks we can
put across straight away
as I mentioned we have that JS API
overhead which means that the transient
execution blocks still need to be in
pure JavaScript or webassembly
so we use respect V1 Gadget a
webassembly timer thread and an eviction
reload cover Channel but crucially these
have been solved in Prior work so we
don't need to reinvent the wheel here
and this doesn't hinder our prototyping
process too much
so in our final attack
our scenario is that we trick the victim
into opening a link and reading or
leaving the tab idle for at least five
minutes while we wait for Windows to
de-duplicate the memory for us
we can leak um about 1.48 bytes per
second with decent accuracy this is
comparable to
um the riddle BSC in JavaScript it is a
much lower leakage rate than we see in
native code
um but we do observe we can have a great
leakage rate if we use
um
if we use leverage SC Firefox to do
flush and reload so I think there is
potential here to improve the evictions
that we're using actually improve that
leakage rate but that wasn't the goal
here the goal was to illustrate the
prototyping process
uh one limitations we need to reliably
be on the same call so this isn't yet a
full end-to-end attack
so to sum up
um I would say this work was a first
step towards establishing a methodology
and tooling for microarchitectural
attack development there is plenty of
work left to do so much more tooling we
could build and I would like to see the
API an even higher abstraction level
so that it's easier to use this for
teaching and communicating these attacks
to a broader audience
if there's one thing you take away from
this presentation I'd like it to be that
we can facilitate attack development and
communication by tackling the complexity
of our proof of concept implementations
so always keep that in your mind like
how can we hide some of the
implementation details and complexity
here
um and or Frameworks are available on
GitHub contributions feedback
um very welcome I hope they can be
useful to you in your work and I'm open
for any questions