hi welcome to my talk my name is yachang
Sun I'd like to introduce reject scalpel
regular expression denial of service
redo s defense by localize and fix
imagine a scenario here is a web
application on the server side to verify
whether the input email address is valid
unfortunately the parsing time of the
regular Expressions used here are super
linear for some inputs on the client
side a normal input such as ABC of def
com which can be verified by the server
immediately
but for a malicious input such as yet a
large number of C
it will make the server run out of a lot
of resources without feedback which is
called redu s attack
the existing redus defense strategies
include regex engine substitution input
length restriction and regex repair
the weakness of rejects engine
substitution is omitting extended
features consuming space and bringing
semantic differences or
incompatibilities
the weakness of input length restriction
is facing a dilemma known as Goldilocks
problem namely The Limited length is too
short to accept all valid inputs or the
length is too long to reject malicious
inputs repairing vulnerable rejects can
greatly mitigate their vulnerabilities
our statistics in the table show that
regex repairs the most common defense
strategy adopted by developers or
maintainers accounting for as high as
92.19 percent
however rejects repair is challenging
the repaired rejects returned by
exciting techniques may be still
vulnerable to redus attacks and may not
be semantically equivalent or similar to
its original Rejects to overcome these
challenges we proposed reject scalpel a
rejects redo s vulnerability analysis
and repair framework based on localize
and fix
reject scalpel can preserve the
semantics of the original Rejects and
the iterative repair method also keeps
out vulnerabilities of the repaired
Rejects
reject scalp of first leverages the
fine-grained vulnerability patterns to
localize the vulnerabilities and obtain
the information for the repair
the information includes their
vulnerable patterns the source that is
the pathological sub-rejects is and the
root causes for example the overlapping
sub-rejexes
reject scalpel then fixes the
pathological sub-rejects as according to
the repair patterns and the information
the repair patterns use micro
manipulations for example adding a look
around deleting a quantifier sub-regics
modifying a quantifier sub-regics to
remove the overlapping paths or reducing
the maximum times of backtracking
reject scalpel next determines whether
the repaired rejects are redo as
invulnerable and whether it can pass all
the given test cases if so the repaired
rejects is called a successful one
if not reject scalpel continues the
vulnerability analysis and repairs it
reject scalpel finally returns a
repaired rejects randomly chosen from
the successful ones next I will
introduce the fine-grained vulnerable
patterns
reject scalpel uses these vulnerable
patterns to localize the vulnerabilities
and obtain the information for the
repair
the NQ pattern is a rejects with nested
quantifiers
the NQ pattern has worst case
exponential behavior when a pump string
can be consumed by either an inner
quantifier or an outer one
in order to facilitate fixing the
pathological rejects we subdivided NQ
pattern into three sub patterns that is
nq1 nq2 and nq3 as shown in the table
the qod pattern is a Quantified
disjunction whose multiple inner
sub-rejects is overlap
when matching a pump string there are
multiple choices among the overlapping
sub-rejects with worst case exponential
behavior on a mismatch
we subdivided qod pattern into two sub
patterns that is qo D1 and qod2 as shown
in the table
the qoa pattern is a Quantified rejects
containing two adjacent overlapping
sub-rejexes
a pump string can be consumed by either
of the overlapping adjacencies
we subdivided qoa pattern into five sub
patterns that is qoa1 to qoa5 as shown
in the table
the slq pattern is a reject starting
with the sub-regx with a large
quantifier
the slq pattern may cause the rejects
engine to keep moving the matching
rejects across the malicious string that
does not have a match for the rejects
leading to worst case polynomial
Behavior
we subdivided slq pattern into five sub
patterns that is slq1 to slq5 as shown
in the table
next I will introduce the repair
patterns reject scalpel uses these
repair patterns and vulnerability
information to repair pathological
sub-rejects
the NQ pattern has a redundant
quantifier by Nature so to fix and Q
pattern we can remove the Redundant
quantifier as shown in the table
the qod pattern has multiple matching
paths across the overlapping
disjunctions for a string
we need to ensure that there is a unique
matching path for each string
for that we propose three strategies
namely deleting one overlapping
disjunction adding a look around
constraint to one overlapping
disjunction and modifying one
overlapping disjunction by subtracting
the first set of the other one
the qoa pattern contains the
corresponding two overlapping
adjacencies
we need to ensure that only one
overlapping adjacency would be selected
when matching on a string we propose
three repair strategies that is merging
the overlapping adjacencies adding a
look around constraint to one
overlapping adjacency and modifying one
overlapping adjacency
the slq1 and slq2 patterns contain the
sub-regic starting with a large
quantifier
the slq3 slq for an slq5 patterns
contain the overlapping sub-regexes
the slq pattern makes the rejects engine
slide continuously to determine the
starting position of the match
so to fix slq pattern we need to
eliminate or alleviate continuous
sliding for that we proposed four
strategies namely adding a start of line
anchor to the pathological rejects
replacing the large quantifier in the
pathological rejects with a small one
adding a look around constraint to one
overlapping sub-regics and modifying one
overlapping sub-regics by subtracting
the first set of the other one
take the redo West vulnerable rejects as
an example
the npm package no jstmpl used this
rejects which aims to match the simple
string formatting using the left and
right brace as shown in the phase 1 the
analyzer identified that the
pathological sub-regx in the box is a
possible vulnerability due to its two
components are one and are two overlap
the analyzer returned a triple namely
the vulnerability information
in the phase 2 the repair used for
repair patterns to fix the vulnerability
and then the very fear checked whether
the repaired rejects are successful
as demonstrated in the phase 3 except
for the first one others are successful
we randomly selected the fourth rejects
to report to the maintainers and the
maintainers confirmed it and released no
jstmpl 1.0.5 with a fix
our evaluation was conducted on the
redoase vulnerable rejects as collected
from two widely used sources the solar
Dom Benchmark and real-world common
vulnerabilities and exposures namely
cves
solar da Benchmark contains 34 redus
vulnerable rejects as an npm modules
found by the software Lab at tu
darmstadt cve Benchmark contains 414
redu ways vulnerable rejects is
extracted from 70 Reedus related cves in
recent three years where collected
vulnerabilities without clear
descriptions Live Links or test cases
were discarded for comparison tools we
selected three state-of-the-art tools
belonging to three paradigms that is
rejects engine substitution re2 input
length restriction lli and regex repair
flash rejects we consider a defense is
successful if it passes all the given
test cases and is free from reuse attack
the success defense rate is calculated
by dividing the number of successful
defenses by the total number of
vulnerable rejects under defense
we evaluated the effectiveness of reject
scalpelon 448 reduos vulnerable rejects
comparing with different defense tools
the table shows the number and ratio of
rejects as it have been defended
successfully we can learn that reject
scalpel can effectively defend 98.88 of
vulnerable rejects while the best
exciting work can only defend 21.20
percent of vulnerable Rejects
apart from the automatic defense tools
shown above we compared the repairs made
by reject scalpel with the defending
actions taken by the project maintainers
we can learn from the table that among
the repaired vulnerable rejects is
handcrafted by the maintainers only
77.23 are read us free
reject scalpel outperforms manual fixing
and successfully repairs 99.03 percent
of Rejects
we explored whether reject scalpel can
detect newer us vulnerabilities in
popular real-world projects and
synthesize useful repairs to project
maintainers
as shown in the table reject scalpel
detected and repaired 16 new radio s
rejects as in 10 popular projects all
the 16 repairs were accepted by the
maintainers and merged into subsequent
project releases resulting in eight
confirmed cves
furthermore we calculated the semantic
similarities between the repaired
Rejects and the original ones
to measure the semantic similarity we
try to use the first equation
but the languages can be infinite so we
adopted the second equation
we can learn from the figure that for
the benchmarks most similarities go
beyond 98 percent
on average the semantic similarity is
99.57 percent
this means that the semantics of rejects
are well preserved after the repair
in summary we proposed reject scalpel
which can defend redus attacks by
automatically localizing and repairing
vulnerable Rejects
the evaluation exhibits the remarkable
effectiveness of reject scalpel it
achieves 98.88 successful repair ratio
compared with 21.20 percent achieved by
the best existing work
reject scalpel helped to repair 16
redoase vulnerabilities in the 10 real
world projects and got confirmed by the
maintainers resulting in eight confirmed
cves
furthermore reject scalpel can
synthesize repaired rejects as
preserving the semantics of the original
ones and keeping the semantics as close
as possible to the original ones
thank you for your attention I would be
happy to answer any questions