foreign
secure against malicious clients at semi
honest Coast I am Akash and this is a
joint work with Nisha and Divya and
bhavna
this work is in the problem of secure ml
inference here you have the two parties
the server and decline
this Servo holds the ml model amp and
weight w and client holds the input
Vector X the two parties then interact
in order to in order to allow the client
to learn the inference output we want
the security guarantee from the
interaction that the server learns new
information about the private input of
client and client learns only the
inference output
this actually can be realized through
secure multi-party computation which is
a classic cryptographic technique
one of the applications of secure
inference is in the domain of Dom Health
like Health infrastructure here you have
a hospital which holds the ml model for
disease prediction and you have the
patient who holds the medical report
they can interact in a secure inference
algorithm such that at the end of it
client learns the output of the disease
production only and the server that is
the hospital gets no information about
the patient's record
there are several secure ml inference
algorithms using MPC techniques uh to
obtain semi honest as well as malicious
secure inference protocols now semi
honest uh secure protocols provide this
guarantee that is they provide guarantee
against corrupt parties that follow the
protocol specification but they are only
curious to learn other party's output in
the protocol interaction whereas the
malicious setting allows security
against corrupt parties that can deviate
arbitrarily from the protocol
specification
some of the prior works on semi honor
security setting is kryptonite's Delphi
cryptoflow to name a few
and some of the prior works in the
malicious setting are speeds ponytail
Overdrive
the good thing about semi honest secure
inference protocols is that they are
extremely efficient however as we know
that the security provided by them is
very weak
on the other case it's the reverse for
malicious secure inference protocols
they do provide a strong efficiency
security guarantee but at the cost of
efficiency
so now let's get back to the scenario
that we were at so here we have a server
who is the model owner and it's a single
entity
and the server is usually reputed
therefore if it deviates from the
protocol specification and gets caught
then the consequences can be dire and
because of public accountability of the
server therefore it is reasonable to
assume that the server is semi honest
whereas client there are multiple
clients and they can be anonymous
and there is no incentive as such for
the clients to follow the protocol
Faithfully
and in fact it was shown that if a
malicious client
is being executed on a semi honest
protocol then it can lead to dangerous
attacks some of the attacks are like are
like the model extraction attacks which
allows the malicious client to learn the
approximate model rates W in fact in a
work that got published at usinex last
year that is Muse it gave a very
efficient model extraction attack which
was 24x to 312x faster than all prior
works because it required that many
fewer queries and one good thing about
this attack was that it was able to
extract the model weights exactly
therefore this motivates us to consider
the client malicious threat model where
the server is semi honest and clients
are malicious
in this work we asked the following
question can we design client malicious
secure inference protocols which are as
efficient as semi owners protocols well
the title of the paper is a spoiler so
in case you haven't seen it it's good
yeah so in this work uh we focus on
neural networks which are the prominent
secure inference protocols which are the
prominent inference protocols that you
see around and this has been the focus
of almost all prior secure inference
protocols
and this is the case for our work too so
neural networks comprises of alternate
linear and non-linear layers uh like
linear layer could be the fully
connected layer or a convolution layer
and some of the examples of non-linear
layers are
some of the functions that are computed
that are value Max pool Etc now linear
layers are best represented as
arithmetic circuits therefore it makes
sense to make use of cryptographic
techniques which are efficient and more
compatible with arithmetic circuits say
additive homomorphic encryption whereas
non-linear layers are best represented
as Boolean circuits so therefore it
makes sense to use techniques compatible
with Boolean circuits say garbage
circuits
so as we make use of different
techniques and the linear and the
non-linear layers there is one subtle
issue which will become clear when I
present the next slide
so now let me first start with the semi
honors protocol which are generic and
most efficient in literature so they
have the follow following skeletal so
for the linear layers the server has the
linear layer l and both this server and
the client hold the shares of the input
X
now as mentioned we'll make use of
additive homomorphic encryption scheme
here so client will first encrypt its
share and send it to the server the
server can then uh can then first
reconstruct the and can first obtain the
encryption of reconstructed value X then
it will obtain encryption of the
computation of linear layer on this
reconstructed value and finally it
obtains the ciphertext C Dash
corresponding to the share of the output
y of client it will send this ciphertext
to the client and at the end of it
client will decrypt and at the end of
the computation of the linear layer we
have both parties holding shares of the
output of linear layer y that is output
y
and now uh for the now let's come to the
non-linear layer so now in the
non-linear layer right now that's uh the
input is the output that we obtained
from the linear layers that is the
arithmetic shares of output y
now uh the problem is that here we make
use of gable circuits so first we need
to convert it into inputs that are
compatible with gobble circuits so for
this uh corresponding to input share of
y 0 server can easily send its labels
because it is the one that created the
gobble circuit whereas for clients
output for clients input y1 uh you need
the parties need to be involved in an OT
protocol such that client learns labels
corresponding to input y y one so once
they obtain these values they can run a
gobble circuit to compute shares of the
output of non-linear function f on the
reconstructed value
and obtain the output shares of the
non-linear layer now
you know now uh you know now let's see
how Muse
Builds on this on the previous protocol
that we discussed in order to provide
security guarantee against malicious
clients so here the idea is that we'll
make use of authenticated shares
for the linear layers uh the change is
not significant so I'll not focus it on
this talk so let's directly jump to the
non-linear layer so in the non-linear
layer as mentioned instead of shares of
the output now we will have
authenticated shares that is will have
the shares of Y as well as computation
of one time Mac on y that is alpha y so
once you have this shares
client will obtain uh so client can
obtain labels for its input y1
correspond using the OT protocol can it
be done
actually no because uh your client can
deviate from the protocol right because
client is malicious and it can send some
arbitrary value of y1 and get some get
labels corresponding to arbitrary bits
and can launch the model extraction
attack that we just discussed so for
this Muse suggested that we make use of
that novel protocol which they call it
conditional disclosure of secrets so
this protocol will will output the
labels for y1 only if the Mac check is
consistent
however there is a limitation on this
protocol that is it is computationally
heavy because it make it makes use of
leveled homomorphic encryption
along with that it is also communication
heavy because it makes use of generating
makes use of several authenticated
Beaver triples and generating many of
those as Compu communicationally
expensive
and the rest of the protocol is similar
to the semi honest protocol that we
discussed
and now let's come to our protocol that
is simc which is short for secure
inference against malicious clients so
our first step here is to eliminate the
use of CDs protocol
so this is how we do so again the linear
layer is similar to mues so I won't be
dwelling into it but notice that the
output of the linear layer is
authenticated shares of the output y
that is you have shares of Y and shares
of alpha y and for shares of alpha y I
use the variable V
and now for the non-linear layer uh the
inputs are the shares of the output that
you obtained from the previous linear
layer that is shares of Y and
additionally the server has the Mac key
Alpha so now we consider this following
following circuit so in this circuit we
first reconstruct the value Y and then
we compute uh the Mac again on the input
value that is our we compute alpha y and
then we compute
the output of the non-linear function f
on the reconstructed value and obtain uh
the Mac on this output and finally this
this circuit will output shares of u z
and T those shells are the ones that
correspond to client
and now here we make instead of making
use of CDs protocol we make use of OT
protocol
and you may take think like again uh the
client can deviate from the can deviate
and send some arbitrary values of Y one
year but bear with me for a couple of
seconds I'll resolve that in a minute
so here uh year then will similar to the
previous protocols we make use of garble
circuit in order to compute the circuit
C
and the circuit C then outputs uh the
shares for the client uh corresponding
to variables u z and t and a server in
itself because it was the one that
computed the gobble circuit holds this
shares of corresponding shares of u z
and T
and now uh we perform at the end of the
protocol between every linear and
non-linear layer we perform this
consistency check we check whether the
value V is equal to U that is we check
if Mac U is equal to Mac V
and there is an optimization in which we
can combine all this consistency checks
together into one for all the linear and
non-linear layers put together so the
communication actually becomes really
less
and uh now the server will reveal the
output to the client only if this
consistency check is successful so now
say if the client was to deviate from
the protocol and it sends some arbitrary
values for y1 and it gets some arbitrary
labels but uh the value that it got for
you would be completely garbage and it
would not match the consistency check
and it will fail
so that is where the client will get
caught and it uh server will not reveal
the reveal its share of the output
then uh
the second Improvement that we make over
the previous protocols is Computing uh
this Max efficiently in gobble circuits
so for this let me just uh first
provide the concrete statement for the
problem we are interested in so we want
to compute shares of a into B where a is
known to the gobbler
ah and B is the garbled input so now if
we were to use a knife approach uh in
order to compute this in gobble circuits
the communication complexity would be
order of Kappa square into Lambda where
Kappa is the size of the field and of
the field element that we are in we are
executing our protocols in and Lambda is
the security parameter so now uh this
value B can be split into bits it can be
decomposed into bits B1 to b b Kappa and
now let me denote the labels
corresponding to bit bi as label 0i and
label 1i corresponding to labels for
bits 0 and 1 respectively so now the
gobbler will first randomly sample
random values R1 to R Kappa and then it
will compute a decryption table d as
follows so for a bit for for say bit B1
and for a bit B1 equal to 0 it will
first add the random value R1 with 0 and
xor it with the label corresponding to
label 0 of B1 and for a bit B1 is equal
to 1 it will add R1 which is the random
value to the Mac uh Mac key or the
gobbler known input a and it will absorb
it with uh the label corresponding to
the
bit corresponding to the bit B1 is equal
to one and it will do this for all the
other remaining bits and it will permute
this uh entries using the permit bit of
the Garber that was that in the Garber
circuit corresponding to bit bi
and now once the evaluator gets this
decryption table it will know labels
corresponding to the correct or beta
ones that it is at beta eyes that is it
is currently at in the garbage circuit
computation then it will uh High then it
will identify the entries corresponding
to those values in the decryption table
so these are the ones highlighted in the
figure
and then uh
during that time gobbler will generate
its share corresponding uh to the output
Z in which it it will multiply the
random value RI with its bit position uh
that is 2i minus 1 2 raised to I minus 1
and similarly the evaluator will do the
same with its share of values v i and
you can verify that
Z is equal to a into B
and yeah for due to time constraint like
take my word for it it actually works
out
and uh the communication cost here is uh
two Kappa Square which is order like a
flam security parameter is 128 so you
are getting order of 64 benefit already
and uh now let's come to the concrete
performance analysis of our protocol
compared to Muse
so now uh here Kappa again denotes the
size of the field element and Lambda is
the security parameter the communication
complexity of muse and non-linear layers
2D Lambda plus 190 Kappa Lambda plus 232
Kappa square and here D denotes the
number of and gates to compute the
non-linear function f and whereas our
protocol takes just 2C Lambda plus 4K
Kappa plus 6 Kappa Square where C is
much where C is less than d and for to
concretely see the performance
Improvement let us consider the value
function and set our field size to 44
bits and Lambda to be 128 and we can see
that smic performs 30X and it's like
it's 30X more communication efficient
than mues
now let's see the performance like let's
see the Improvement results
yeah uh so here we we perform our
we we show the performance improve
performance on two Network bandwidths
one is uh 584 megabits per second
megabytes per second and the second is
19.2 megabytes per second and we can see
that for non-linear layers uh protocol
is four for four to forty two x more
efficient in network one compared to
Muse and it is 2 to 16.3 X more
efficient in N2 setting and uh for
evaluating our the performance of our
protocol end to end we consider two
benchmarks one is the a two layer
convolution neural network on amnest
data set and the second one is seven
layers uh CNN for Cipher 10 data set
and here uh the end-to-end performances
as follows like uh
Source consider Benchmark 2 Muse takes
like thousands
1782 seconds whereas our protocol just
takes 150 157 seconds and it is order of
6.2 to 11.3 X more faster in N2 setting
and uh one good uh one interesting thing
to note about simc is that it is
communication it is more communication
efficient than the state-of-the-art semi
honors protocol as well and it is more
efficient in it
so that's an interesting point that we
observed in our implementation results
and uh and then we also performed uh
benchmarks in the pre-processing model
and we observed that our protocol was
five to seven point four x more
performance performant than the bash
known Muse protocol and client malicious
setting yeah thank you