hi welcome to my talk I'm boredom from
my University I'm going to introduce our
work state first
as we know called the coverage you get
in the version using genetic algorithm
is now very useful solution for Fanny
bugs a code coverage you can Define the
first to select to see the prone city
copers under mutated to generate a new
test case
then the father executed the instrument
to the problems with his case and I
received feedback based on feedback to
further check whether the programs
whether the test case hit new code if so
the father preserved this test case in
City Compass as a music
however code coverage guide the
following has a limitations in finding
Rich State targets
here is an example the functional action
received
op and value from users for taking
different actions including set a set B
and vul function
there is an autobunded bug in the viewer
function to trigger this word we need to
set the state a to zero xff under State
B to
buff size then we execute the viewf
function if we refer to see example
program with code coverage get default
list we will find the structure to them
in the beginning many test case hit new
code and and are preserved
the test case one
test case two
three
for now as we can see all codes are
covered and the no new code to hit as a
result no more test case will be saved
even though this test case can set the
correct two states
under the state can easily be changed by
subsequent test case
so it just seems difficult to trigger
the bug there is no sees in Corpus that
can set the correct States
the main reason is that called the
coverage Guide to the father
where you can note his case that the
exercise the same could pass even though
they have explored the new States
we understand well further
so how to perform status well flooding
we summarizes three questions to answer
first what our program States second how
to recognize the program says and track
them during funding
Third how to use problem state is to
guide value for the first question
essentially a problem status the
execution context of a problem
including values of all memory and this
registers however the number of such
States is too large and it is harder to
track them all in practice
thus we believe that a practical further
has to focus on a subset of problem
States reason to work has proposed
several solutions for representing
problem States
researchers propose to manually manually
annotate the targeted programs and the
user annotated data as program States
such menu annotation will involve many
human efforts protocol status code can
also be used to represent program States
however status code is not always
available we find its very common
programs to use the variables to
represent problem States so we propose
that we can only focus on subset of
problem States represented by variables
as a result the second question is
equivalent to how to recognize the
variables that represent the problem
States
and we name these variables that
represent program States
as state variables
we summarize the features of State
variables as it follows first
the these variables have a long lifetime
that you can span different program
states to record state of information
second they can be updated by users for
status transition
third since the program States always
controls the problem's behavior these
variables should be able to affect the
program's counterflower or memory access
we observed that rich State Province
always require multi-stage input
and the different stage of impulse will
achieve the different program actions
for example
iftp server will receive multiple
packets from the client
the FTP user and the FTP package and fpv
pass action will be triggered by a user
a user package and a user a pass packet
the Nino's kernel may receive many
season costs
from user space programs
and the handlers
in Fair operations will be triggered by
this course
we also observed that state variables
are usually shared by different program
actions for example the variable it says
is read by is read by the FTP least
action and updated by FTP has action
therefore we can recognize State
variables by extracting the variables
that have a long Lifetime and shared by
program actions
then we track a program that states by
monitoring those State variables
for the third question a straightforward
idea is used instead coverage as
feedback for button however if we use a
new value of substitute variables as a
new state there are too many values
and a lot of test cases will be
preserved causing cdq explosion and
hurts the performance of value
so we can merge values representing the
same state
and divided each state variables value
space into several ranges
therefore we propose that instead of
tracking values we track Special Value
ranges and extreme values of State
variables as the feedback of value
we built the first type of statist for
Linux driver fighting this is workflow
of statified which includes includes
three major phase
the programs that the recognition stage
first analyze the source code of Linux
Travelers to recognize program States
including the state's variable is the
state variable value ranges
then this instrumentation staging
instrument of targeted program to track
the program state coverage along with
code coverage
in the for the loop stage we extended
the vaginal vocal coverage guide of
others by applying the problem States
feedback to see the preservation and the
city selection
in the program State recognition stage
we first need to identify program
actions in India's drivers the program
actions are the handlers
that can be in multiple system costs we
use inter-procedure and the past
sensitive analysis based on details to
identify program actions
we use an hpet driver example
to show how we recognize State variables
with static with static analysis
we first identify program actions and
they are called the lines
then we extract the variables accessed
by these code lines as we can see the
variable HD hdwr Community red is read
by action 2 and updated by action 1 and
it has a long enough time so we add this
variable into our state variable list we
use intro procedure and the passensive
since that static symbolic execution
two in first state variables value
ranges for example from the conditional
statement in 9 11
we can inverse three value ranges
in the first Loop status uses a
three-dimension feedback mechanisms to
get a status exploration IT issues three
types of feedback signals when the test
case is new code new value range or new
extreme values
then the further preserve the test case
in different types of cobras based on
the feedback types
and the further we are selecting this
from this retires of couples
solidifier is implemented based on
several open source projects we think
store authors for their awesome projects
we evaluated to evaluate the
effectiveness of certified we designed
the several experience and tried to
answer the following questions
we conduct the experience for linear
servers in two environments including
the Nino's Upstream kernel on cumu and
the Qualcomm MSM kernel or Google Plus
over phone
we recognize about six thousands and
five thousand State variables from the
news kernel and the Ms McCullough MSM
kernel irrespectively on average we
recognized about three value ranges for
every state variable
then we investigate the semantical state
variables by analyzing variable names in
the abstract syntax tree the result is
shown in the pattern
we also organized the false positives
and the false negatives the result shows
status first can recognize 90 percent
with State variables and the Precision
is 40 percent
we believe that flooding can tolerate
some force between false positives
because of its best execution speed
our experiment shows that state advice
can achieve higher status coverage and
the code coverage
specifically in the news kernel
steadfast solidified achieves 32 percent
higher value range coverage than
ciscover
immunoscon
and 19 higher code carbon Cisco
more details are shown in our paper
these Armory a total of 2100 are funded
by State Road first we reported all
these 20 percent money with history
developers and the 19 of them are
confirmed among the 19 confirmed
vulnerabilities 14 are assigned to cbids
in the future we will continue to apply
slip first to network service body
and apply status to other Linux drivers
that interact with users through
multiple i o channels rather than system
cores
in summary we've written a new fuzzing
solution status for passing Rich States
programs
stateifies models programs stays with
State variables
we implemented a prototype for by the
new struggles experience shows that
statefast has better performance against
its color in family of travels
thanks for listening any questions are
welcome