okay thank you Dr Lee for the
introduction ah hello everyone good
morning I'm Rahul today I'll be
presenting our research work on
detecting software exploitable Hardware
vulnerabilities in process designs using
our instruction for the hus this is a
joint work between Texas and M
University and Technical University of
darmstadt
the motivation for our research work is
the rising number of Hardware
vulnerabilities even the commercial
Hardware Designs that undergo rigorous
testing using state-of-the-art tools are
becoming victims of Hardware
vulnerabilities when such bugs in
Hardware get exploited from the software
they pose serious security threat to the
secure applications running on software
because most of the times software
applications assume that the hardware is
trusted
based on a study conducted in 2019 63
percentage of organizations have said
that they experienced at least one type
of data breach due to Hardware
vulnerabilities in the previous year
micro organization started recording the
harder vulnerability types in 2020 and
we already have 113 of them
the rising severity of this Hardware
vulnerabilities have motivated our
community to research newer and more
efficient bug detection techniques that
ah coin complement the existing
traditional Hardware verification
techniques like manual inspection formal
verification and regression testing
these existing techniques ah they either
not scale well to large designs ah they
are not automated or not efficient
enough to detect bugs in the modern and
complex Hardware
fuzzing on the other hand is a new and
promising approach in Hardware
verification which can scale well to
large designs it can be automated and it
can penetrate into the complex designs
and find bugs on them
before I get into the design of our
fuzzer I would like to highlight the
pros and cons of existing hardware
fuzzers and discuss the type of coverage
metrics they use using this case study
example the hardware logic we see here
is a stripped down version of cache
controller inspired from the one in
Aryan open source risky processor
it mainly has three components so
the combination logic one generates a
valid signal that determines when the
cache should be activated and
perform the input commands
the max logic N2 uses a password
checking mechanism to secure debug rates
the mux logic in 3 determines when the
cache should be flushed
now we insert three bugs in this example
one in each of the components
bug one is in the combinational logic it
activates the cache even when the enable
input signal is not one this allows an
attacker to bypass security mechanisms
that rely on disabling the cache when
performing untrusted operations
debug in Max logic 2 allows debug reads
even when the password is incorrect
bypassing the password checking and the
bug in mux logic 3 allows the cache to
be flushed even when it is not enabled
this allows an unauthorized attacker to
corrupt the state of the cache and
perform attacks like side channels
so in order for a fuzzer to detect these
bugs it needs to cover for the following
features in Hardware
for bug one the fuzzer needs to cover
all possible combinations of input
values for the combinational logic one
for the books two and three the father
needs to cover the select logic of muxas
for all possible combinations of input
values
now let's look at the existing Hardware
fuzzles arfaz is one of the first
proposed Hardware fuzzer that can fuss
any Hardware Designs
it covers the select signals of muxas
for example if you look at the max 3
here its select signal is cell two and
our first checks if the cell 2 signal
takes a value of 0 and 1 or not
hence it covers the box and Max 3. but
the problem here is when we design
Hardware muxos can be coded in two types
mux can be coded as a control Logic for
example using IF else constructs or it
can also be coded as a purely
combinational logic
our first can detect the first type of
muxas but if the muxes are coded in the
second format it cannot detect them so
for example in this case study if the
mux 2 is coded as a combinational logic
then rfas cannot detect it also arfus
doesn't cover the activities in the
combinational logic and flip flops so
the bugs one and two are also not
covered by Alphas
also it is computationally expensive so
it does not scale to large designs
next we have differs RTL differs RTL is
an improved version of rfas it
eliminates the scalability issues in it
and it is used to First process designs
are differs RTL covers the registers
driving the select logic of muxas for
example here we have mux 3 and its
select logic is the or gate and flush
and enable are the registers that are
driving the select logic so the first
RTL checks if this flush and enable
registers take all possible combinations
of values which is zero zero zero one
one zero and one one or not hence we can
detect bug 3 using differs RTL
but differs RTL also has the same issue
in the sense that it doesn't detect Max
2 and also doesn't cover the activity in
combinational logic and flip flops so it
does not directly cover the bugs one and
two
also the bug comparison happens at the
end of the program in the processor
which is not very efficient
hyper fuzzing is another type of
Hardware fuzzer it proposed new
semantics for SOC security properties
and it generates inputs to prove these
properties so it's very useful when we
want to accelerate property checking in
the soc designs but it's not really
applicable to generic Hardware like fsms
and combination logic because the
properties are more for Master Slave
interactions and bus Communications
we also need to write the security
properties before we can start using the
tool to verify the design
also it only supports a specific
Hardware simulator ah called very later
so that limits its applicability
last but not the least we have a triple
little titled fuzzing Hardware as
software this is another novel approach
towards fuzzing Hardware what happens
here is that we take a hardware design
and convert it into C C plus plus code
and then use software fuzzers to First
the hardware
the advantages of this tool is that we
can quickly put the capabilities of
software fuzzers to First Hardware
but um it requires a
H simulators like vary later which can
convert the hardware design or which is
basically a very long or vhdl code into
C or C plus plus and it doesn't support
a very low constructs like latches and
floating wires so any bugs that are
there involving this logic cannot be
covered with this fuzzer
in summary I discussed four existing
Hardware fuzzers each of them differ in
terms of either the type of component
they cover or the scalability which is
the largest design they first or the
applicability which is the type of
Hardware they can first the type of
simulator they support or the number of
bugs they reported
now moving on to our fazer dihas I'll
first explain the coverage Matrix used
by the house and then the design itself
as we can see on the right we categorize
the hardware logic into various
components like flip flops registers
fsms control logic like muxes and
combinational logic
and dihous uses multiple different
coverage metrics to cover each of these
component for example we have the
condition and expression coverage which
cover the cover all the
select logic and combinational Logic for
all possible combinations of input
values in the hardware using this we can
detect all the three works that we
previously inserted in this case study
example in addition we also have
coverage metrics like Branch toggle and
FSM which cover the other Hardware
components which overall capture all the
activity going on in the hardware
these coverage metrics are in fact used
widely in the semiconductor industry and
are commonly known as Hardware code
coverage metrics
this is the high level diagram of our
fuzzer the house
the fuzzing starts with the generation
of seed inputs
the inputs are nothing but binary
executables because we are fuzzing
process designs ah hence we use the
instruction generator to generate the
assembly level instructions using which
we populate the input programs
the processor is simulated with the
inputs from the database one after the
other
and parallely we use a reference model
which is either a Isa emulator or a
software model of the hardware to
generate the golden outputs to compare
and detect bugs
while the simulation is ongoing we
capture the coverage information and
analyze it to determine if a new path or
logic is explored in the hardware
because of the current input
if yes then we mutate the current input
using 12 types of mutation techniques
that we have and generate newer inputs
and populate them in the input database
the change in ish state after the
simulation of processor and the
reference model for each instruction
executed is compared and report and any
mismatches are reported the cycle
continues till we reach or desired
preset time limit or coverage percentage
we first four Real World open source
processors using the house they are from
Risky and open risk isas and are
commonly used benchmarks when evaluating
Hardware security tools and we found 11
bucks including eight new ones that led
to five CVS
here I am showing five of the eight new
bugs that Hindi has detected we found
bugs in the decoder and cache controller
logic of Aryan we found privileged
released related bugs in mr1kx we found
bucks in the ALU of what 100 so on and
so forth
to demonstrate the software implications
of the hardware bugs found by our tool
we crafted two exploits that can be run
as user level programs
the exploit one can perform arbitrary
code execution bypassing the canary
checks on a ren processor and the
exploit 2 can do privilege escalation on
mr1kx processor
I am skipping the details in the
interest of time for this exploits but
you can check our paper for more details
as far as the coverage results are
concerned because is able to cover more
number of points and also faster
compared to the existing traditional
regression techniques or existing
state-of-the-art hardware
and we also showed that the results are
statistically significant in the paper
in conclusion we designed a new hardware
fuzzer to detect bugs in processor
designs called the house it is
compatible in the sense that we can fuzz
any HDL using any commercial Hardware
simulator so it's compatible with the
existing verification flows it is
automated starting from input generation
to detecting the mismatches it is
practical in the sense that it is easy
to use it is efficient in detecting bugs
in real world processor designs and can
achieve higher coverage than the
existing techniques we demonstrated the
security impact of bugs using two
exploits that we crafted
because does have its own set of
limitations features like fpga emulation
fuzzing non-processor designs fuzzing
for parametric properties of hardware
and fuzzing to detect site Channel
vulnerabilities are all part of our
future work
I would like to thank our sponsors onr
and Intel for funding our research and
also thank everyone here for attending
the talk thank you