hi I'm Ben prinster and I'm going to
present the total eclipse of the heart
disrupting the interplanetary file
system
so what is the interplanetary file
system or ipfs
ipfs is a peer-to-peer hypermedia system
its development is held by protocol apps
and parts of ipfs are used extensively
by other systems the reason why this
works so well is it's fully
decentralized and open and very modular
which means you have different
subsystems interacting with each other
based on well-defined apis and this
whole architecture is extensible so
if you want to Mount Your decentralized
peer-to-peer application you can just
use ipfs add to your subsystem for your
application layer magic and be done with
it because IPS just works and I say that
wholly and ironically it really does so
this is the greatest feat ipv has
managed to pull off in my opinion
because you can just fire up a note join
the network and you're done and it works
you have connectivity you can share
files you can partake in whatever's
happening and this is a feat of
engineering nobody else before has
managed to pull off
so in effect ipfs wants to go from
something like this which is your
typical IP layer topology which requires
a seasoned exercise to cast out its
demons to something like this which
actually makes sense to a normal human
being and is comprehensible by both man
and machine
having introduced ipfs I will need to
talk about the decentralized operation
of peer-to-peer systems before I can
talk about ipfs specifics and finally
I'll explain how we managed to pull our
Dirt Cheap Eclipse attacks on live ipfs
notes
so how do you operate a decentralized
peer-to-peer system in the wild first of
all some basics
you don't have IP layer information
anymore you have abstract identifiers in
this case a B O and C and of course this
information needs to be mapped to a p
layer information such that it actually
works in the real world and we will
focus on our node a here
which has learned VIP layer information
about B C and O out of band
and in order to partake in a
peer-to-peer Network it contacts those
nodes it nodes and queries for IP layer
information on itself and these notes
respond with other node information and
gradually a learns more and more IP
layer information and built its routing
tables and that's what's called
bootstrapping which is basically the
process of joining a peer-to-peer
Network
and once you've joined the network you
can go ahead and query for information
for example s this could be the hash of
some data or the ID of some node you
want to contact
so a asks the notes about s and they
reply with some other notes and finally
a reaches s and can connect which is
nice and the reason why this converges
is that all the nodes have agreed on a
common distance metric and this works
for finding notes and data and this
system as a whole is called the
distributed hash table the data is
identify by hashes basically and this
works well as long as nobody goes ahead
and claims identifies already taken so
obviously you need to do something about
that
we need to lay out some very fundamental
peer-to-peer security techniques you
definitely need self-certifying
identifiers to fix identifier attack so
we generate the public priority key pair
for each node you write it's only from a
public key a new authenticate all
connections and you're basically done
with it and it definitely works so each
identifier in the network is now
verified which is nice except well it's
really not because all those nodes could
be operated by a single entity which
makes your network collapse
so that's what's called a civil attack
and that works because all you know is
identifiers and not whether these
identifiers are actually
owned by distinct entities
and this is of course devastating for
any peer-to-peer Network
but there is another fundamental Clause
of the text that has been haunting pewdp
networks basically since their Inception
so I have my self-certifying identifier
so I can't just choose arbitrary
identifiers but I kind of go ahead and
regenerate identifiers brute force is
basically until I have arrived with
enough identifiers close to some Target
that my evil notes are closest to this
target if I'm very curious for K now all
the requests for K were terminate at my
notes and I can simply pretend K does
not exist and that's what's called an
eclipse attack and this is basically
what we managed to pull off against ipfs
so
how can these problems be fixed well
proposed a solution to these issues
use self-certified identifiers mandate
these joint lookup paths and a
centralized or proof of work based
identifier generation and I mentioned
Academia specifically because the ipfs
white paper cites this strategy but
let's talk some more IP address
specifically let's talk connection
management ipfs is supposed to just work
and in order to achieve that it needs to
natively support relaying and that's
reversal
it's connection oriented so nodes need
to limit the number of active
Connections in order not to become
overburdened but still remain connected
to the network
some nodes need to gauge the importance
of connections and they employ a simple
but effective scoring system to do that
in a sense keep important connections
trim the unimportant ones but there's a
peculiarity to this this system needs to
respect all present and future
subsystems because as I've mentioned
ipfs is extensible so you can mount any
application layer Logic on top of it and
you don't want your important
connections to be trimmed
and they have introduced The Connection
Manager to tackle an issue so how does
it work well first of all the connector
manager sorts all connections by score
which is just the sum of points from all
subsystems usually this is something
like 15 or 20 or 10 or something like
that
then it counts the connections and if
the number of connection is higher than
a configurable high water March it goes
ahead and trims the lowest chord once
down to the second configurable
threshold then it sleeps in one minute
and it does it all over again so you can
configure the maximum and the minimum
amount of connections you want to keep
and this works quite well
so how did we manage to pull off Eclipse
attacks on ipfs
well
we pre-generated identifiers
and if you want to Eclipse some Target
you just pick an ID search through the
ID tool you obtain loads and lots of
identifiers that are very close to the
Target closer than the rest of the
network
then you spawn civil notes assign them
those IDs you connect to the victim
yeah well and then you need some magic
incantation to make a connection manager
actually
trim all the honest connections
and we'll manage to do that within
minutes
so how did we go about this well
of course we inflated the score of high
water many of our evil connections such
that the honest ones are just true and
one ingredient is
our pre-generated identifiers they are
so close to the Target identifier in
comparison to the rest of the network
that we get awarded quite a high amount
of points just because we are so close
to the victim then there's bit swap
similar to what BitTorrent does and you
also get some points for unsolicited
advertisement of content so yeah a
couple of points for free basically
because it doesn't consume any resources
and then there's the relaying subsystem
and this is really a gold mine because
relaying is important for ipfs to work
in a while so
we just went ahead and relay junk
connections over our uh one of our evil
connections
to inflate our score to infinity and
beyond basically because it Awards one
point per connection
so while this sounds like really a cheap
source of points
is a bit more intricate because this is
resource consuming also for the Target
so if you were your attacking machine is
pretty powerful you can end up dosing
your target even if you don't want to
but in the end
you own a node that's basically it you
Eclipse it so within minutes the DHT is
poisoned and within less than an hour no
honest connections to this node are
present anymore
aren't there any easy defenses
yeah well you don't want Civil War packs
and you don't want you don't want cheap
identifier generation but the thing is
you do not want the full civil
resistance because
if you really manage to do that that
each machine is represented by a single
identity well either it's unmanageable
or you run into trouble because ipv4 is
still a thing and if you manage a couple
of ipfs notes running at a company for
example it will still be one public ipv4
address so you would basically lock out
all these machines behind the last hop
at the company that's you don't want
that plus full sip resistance is an
illusion anyways
so but what about proof of work based
defenses well the thing is you can't do
that it's conceptually impossible if you
want an HPC note to be able to join the
network and the cheap smartphone to be
able to join the network
how much work can you mandate for
identify a generation this is a gap
that's simply put impossible to close
you can't do that so that's also not an
issue
so where does that put ipfs today
our original work was carried out in
2020 and we crashed and burned a couple
of times trying to submit our paper
so a lot of time has passed and in the
meantime lots of things have happened
first of all we'd like to thank protocol
apps for their support because they were
nothing but professional and forthcoming
and supportive throughout our research
they allowed us to test out our attack
against some of their bootstrap nodes
which were pre-configured for all their
ipfs notes out there so essentially they
let us Hammer critical infrastructure
so they revised the scoring system for
DHD connections and relays but that's a
delicate subject on its own because you
need to be really really careful not to
screw this up such that actually
important connections remain
also their DHT implementation manages to
actually discriminate between
connections that are useless and
connections that are actually useful
the ipfs DHD is probably the most robust
and best DHT implementation you will
find out there so if you want ADHD you
can go ahead and use that then there
were a slew of other changes to harden
the system and they made some
infrastructure tweaks to their bootstrap
notes so
in effect taking out a single node and
fully eclipsing it now takes days and
Not Mere minutes as before but yeah
that's basically the gist of it there's
much more that happened in the
background and again very grateful to
protocol apps in supporting his research
and yeah that's all for my part
I'll be here in Zoom taking questions