foreign
and this is a joint work with Maya
dotania segulada novezar they're all in
this room
um okay so Twilight Twilight is a
differentially private payment Java
Network so first let me introduce what
payment Channel network is
um so first of all this is Network so we
have relays which are the participants
in the network
uh we have channels channels are the
edges in this network which are locked
coins between two relays so for example
here we have two relays each one of them
locked five coins and then they can just
transfer two coins from one to another
which is just re-divide the same locked
coins
great and we have routes routes is a
list of channels from a specific source
to a specific Target and payments
payments is just using this route to
shift coins across it so for example if
Alice want to transfer two coins to
Charlie in in this example so we can
just adjust the division of the funds of
the locked funds throughout the route
an important thing to notice here is
that if Alice will want to transfer two
more coins to Charlie it will be
impossible because in one of the midi in
the channels in between there is not
enough liquidity and this is the one
that is currently circled there
and permanent Channel networks are is
not something that I just invented uh
the main example here is the lightning
Network which currently has over 100
million dollar in locked funds
um so this is a big thing that we really
need to consider
um and pcn's payment Channel networks
are great uh but they're they're not
private
um in 2017 uh a probing attack was uh
presented to our community uh which
based on the idea that query is cheap an
attacker can just repeatedly query the
same channel over and over again over
time and observe liquidity changes so
for example let's say that the attacker
uses that the route that is now uh
presented in blue
um and he asks hey can I transfer 100
coins and he gets yes from the network
in this example and he will not actually
transfer this 100 coins
um cool so maybe he can do it again
and again
and see the question eventually changes
so for example in here he just got yes
yes yes no
something changed in the network so in
this case you can just ask hey maybe I
can send 50 coins
so this is the probing attack which
leaks different properties on the
network the first one is that it clicks
the current liquidity of the channel it
leaks the existence of the transaction
and the size if the attacker will do
that to many channels in the network it
also leaks what are the identities of
the party who paid whom
um and it's actually silent to both
Alice and Bob because he is not
communicating with them
um and this is the problem that our
system Twilight is trying to overcome so
Twilight is a payment Channel network a
new payment Channel network that
utilizes noise in order to
provide differential privacy guarantees
um we also use trusted execution
environments to deal with selfish relays
all the terms that are currently
underlined will be explained later in
this talk
uh in in the in our paper we also did
both analysis and simulations to the
three properties of cost privacy and
security and we did the full prototype
implementation
awesome so uh in this track heavily I
don't need to explain what differential
privacy is but I do want to highlight uh
our goal our goal here is that the
attacker will not be able to distinguish
between two events the first event is
that Alice paid Bob and the second event
is that Alice didn't pay Bob
um we have so we have that Salon Delta
uh differential private uh
uh definition that we all know and in
our paper we actually did a full
analysis and we were able to provide an
Epsilon a numerical Epsilon and Delta
guarantee to the users of Twilight
um
noise in our case is simple in our case
noise is just a random number I will not
tell you now how we generate this number
um
but the idea is that we use it upon a
request to the relay uh when when we got
the request hey can we transfer m coins
um the answer will be whether the
liquidity minus this random number is
big enough to transfer these endpoints
um and note that a naive solution here
to how to generate this noise is not
good enough right because the attack is
cheap so the attacker can just
uh query the channel over and over again
observe some kind of percentage of how
many yes and how many nodes he gets and
therefore he can just rebuild the
histogram of the noise and know exactly
what is the real liquidity
so we had to use something that is more
uh complex we used here a paper that was
presented in 2011 that provide
differential privacy guarantees under
continual observation
the base idea here is that the noise is
dependent on time
um so here we're utilizing a thing that
is called minimal covering Set uh so for
example if we had a transaction if we
had a coin transfer at a specific time
at T equals one and the attacker queries
uh the channel at T equals two then we
will use noise that uh
we will use the minimal covering set of
the time span until this time of the
query so in this example the node that
is now running in blue is the noise is
the node that we will use to derive the
noise
if the attacker then queries in the next
times timestamp then we will use the
minimal covering set of the whole period
so as you can see here we used the same
noise twice
and because we use the same noise for
every node
we used the same noise to hide the same
coin transfer which means that the
attackers is less different samples of
the random generator that hides the same
coin
uh to conclude in order to uh
uh to answer the question can we
transfer M coin we now need to consider
the time of the query and then we will
just reduce the total noise of the uh of
the nodes in the minimal covering sets
there are much more details in the paper
I'm promising you
cool
um so as you can see adding noise means
that we need to lock more coins in in
the example that I'm showing here in
order to achieve an Epsilon which is
0.15
each really needs to lock much more
coins in this example he needs to lock
extra
9500 coins in order to hide this uh
transfer this one coin transfer
but please note that these locked coins
need to be acquired when are we locking
when we creating the channel but then
when we're distracting the channel we
get all this noise back all these coins
back so therefore if we for example if
the relay will take a loan when creating
the channel and then we'll repay the
loan when you're distracting it you will
only need to pay for the interest
and in our paper we actually showed that
giving that the relay will do at least
77 payments a day for this channel so
with just one percent of free he will
cover all the extra privacy costs
great another thing that I want to
highlight here is that relays are
selfish by being selfish they just have
the incentive to not add the Noise by
adding noise they are saying no to more
transactions to more payments that they
need to handle and they don't want to do
it
in our paper we used these trusted
execution environments in order to force
them to add this noise
teas are isolated Hardware that gives us
the properties of confidentiality and
integrity which means that the relay
cannot change the code that runs inside
X the things but it also can't see the
memory or can see which flow of the
execution has been occurred
um in our system we actually decided to
do a stateless trusted execution
environment
um and this decision has pros and cons
the big Pro is that we don't need to
handle the consensus and to handle the
network protocol of the blockchains but
it also gives us great challenges
uh one example challenge is that the
relay because that is stateless they
really can just re-execute it over and
over again until he will see the result
that he wants we solved all the this
Challenge and many more in the paper are
really uh encourage you to read it
uh we also provide a full prototype
implementation to our system this is
currently an open source that you can
all just gather and say this is a huge
wrapper
um and we got a pretty good performance
uh considering the throughput we up to
we we handle up to 850 payments a second
while the currently the lightning
Network handles
350 which is almost three times the
latency for for intermediate relays is
around one second
um which is I would say sufficient when
you try to pay someone
so to conclude
how we were able to achieve differential
privacy guarantees to Twilight using
continual Observer under continual
observation of the attacker
privacy is something that we're able to
provide but it comes with a cost
relays has had an incentive to not add
noise and we're able to force them using
trusted execution environments and we
provide a full prototype implementation
thank you