all right thanks franzi and a huge thank
you to the conference for the best paper
award I'm Alex Alderman and uh incidents
involving election technology and
processes occur during practically every
election cycle voters see headlines like
these reporting technical glitches as
officials scrambled to reassure the
public
but such incidents are rarely formally
investigated this is a lost opportunity
to improve election accuracy and uphold
public Trust
other fields that prioritize safety and
reliability like Transportation
structural engineering and increasingly
computer security routinely conduct
post-incident investigations these seek
to determine and correct underlying
causes to uncover related issues
disseminate lessons and prevent
recurrence
crucially they are typically not about
establishing blame
my goal in this work is to establish a
model for such rigorous independent and
non-partisan post-incident
investigations within the election space
perhaps the most consequential election
technology incident in recent years
occurred in Antrim County Michigan
during the 2020 presidential election
the County's election Night results were
badly and obviously wrong they showed
Joe Biden and other Democrats winning
this solidly Republican County by a
landslide
officials quickly issued a correction
assuring the public that the problems
were the result of a quote software
update that mistakenly hadn't been
applied to the Dominion voting machines
but the damage had been done the
incident spawned conspiracy theories
that were seized on by President Trump
and have undermined confidence in
elections to this day
in the immediate aftermath a legal team
linked to the Trump campaign sued in
state court and was granted access to
perform a forensic investigation of
antrim's voting system
within only a week a group called Allied
security operations group had produced a
report claiming to have discovered
evidence that the Dominion machines were
quote intentionally and purposefully
designed to facilitate fraud
the attorney behind that lawsuit Matthew
deperno is now the presumptive
Republican nominee for Michigan attorney
general and as of this week he is
reportedly under investigation himself
for breaching the security of boating
equipment
um but when asog's forensic report first
became public deferno called on
President Trump to
um act and it was unclear at the time
what that meant but the Congressional
committee investigating the events of
January 6th obtained a draft executive
order never issued by President Trump
that cites aesag's bindings in Antrim as
a basis to authorize the military to
seize voting machines
in response to the asag report
Michigan's Secretary of State and
attorney general asked me to perform an
independent forensic investigation of
the Antrim incident
I sought to determine what caused the
errors whether they were evidence of an
attack or Foul Play if they had been
fully corrected and whether they were
likely to affect other localities and
also what should be done to prevent such
issues in the future
the state published my complete findings
in March 2021.
before we get into what caused the
incident let me explain how antrim's
election system works the county uses an
election management system that consists
of a Windows 10 PC running Dominion
democracy Suite software this EMS is
used before each election to prepare
election definitions which are data
files that describe what's on the ballot
and afterwards to combine the results
from 18 ballot scanners at local
precincts across the county
there's no network connectivity but
instead files are distributed and
returned using compact flash cards each
scanner outputs both electronic records
of every ballot and also a paper pull
tape summarizing the number of votes for
each candidate for my investigation I
was provided copies of the EMS hard
drive the scanner memory cards and the
poll tapes I also reverse engineered the
undocumented Dominion file formats and
software and built new tools to analyze
them
all right so what did we find
I used logs from the scanners in EMS
first to reconstruct events before the
election
in September County staff had approved
the ballot designs for printing and they
loaded the election definitions onto the
EMS and the scanners as usual
however in early October errors were
discovered in three of the ballot
designs for instance in one Precinct the
ballot showed a school board contest for
the wrong District
workers revised the election definitions
and ordered nude ballots printed and
they loaded the revised election
definitions into the EMS but only
updated two of the 18 scanners this
would prove to be a consequential
mistake
the first sign of trouble though didn't
happen until election night when workers
loaded the results from the scanner
memory cards into the EMS
three cards failed to load despite
multiple attempts rather than
investigating election staff manually
entered these results from the poll
tapes and this process took until four
o'clock in the morning
working so late at night the staffers
kind of understandably neglected to
closely review the county-wide results
before publishing them
later that morning however the county
was told by Outsiders that the results
were obviously wrong staff took them
down and manually entered the remaining
results from the poll tapes to correct
them
so what caused the major errors I was
able to determine the cause by reviewing
the election definitions and the result
files what happened is that internally
the Dominion system represents each
possible Choice across every ballot
Style with a sequential ID number the
correction to the School Board Race
necessitated inserting an additional
Choice which caused the idea of every
subsequent candidate throughout the
county to increase by one
scanners that weren't updated use the
old IDs when the EMS interpreted their
results using the new IDs it assigned
the votes to the wrong candidates as you
can see here on the right in the
presidential race the effect was
essentially that for affected precincts
Biden received the votes cast for Trump
and Trump received the votes cast for
the libertarian candidate and so on down
the ballot
so I confirmed that the major errors had
been corrected uh using several
different tests Each of which produced
the expected results
first I loaded each card into the EMS
using the matching election definition I
also counted the votes from the memory
cards directly myself using software I
wrote without Reliance on the EMS
finally I personally and by hand added
up the individual results from the
scanner pull types across the county and
got exactly the same as the final
results
in addition the state Bureau of
Elections manually recounted all of the
votes from the presidential race using
the original paper ballots
based on these different tests we can be
very sure that the mismatched election
definitions caused the large
discrepancies and that Donald Trump won
Antrim County by nearly 4 000 votes
unfortunately the mismatched election
definition was not the only problem with
antrim's results the county ultimately
reported results five times sometimes
changing candidates totals by thousands
of votes
after the initial erroneous results the
county manually entered totals from the
poll tapes but staff failed to remove
all of the old data the officially
certified results corrected this but the
manual data entry still contained typos
that affected nearly 2.6 percent of
votes Statewide and this is despite the
fact that Michigan law requires County
canvassers to compare the official
results to the poll types before
certifying them
some of the typos were corrected in a
fourth set of results but others
remained and were only corrected in the
final set of results published on
November 21st
despite the unusual attention that
Antrim received I've found that even the
final certified results still contain
errors that affect certain down ballot
races one problem was simply that many
mail-in voters first received the
misprinted ballots and were only later
sent corrected ones some returned each
version but there was no process to
separate them and the scanners were not
programmed to be able to tell them apart
targets for certain contests moved
between the designs so the scanners
miscounted these votes on either the
initial or the revised ballots depending
on which election definition was in use
fortunately I was able to bound the
number of votes that were affected and
no outcome was changed
however I also uncovered a different
error that quite possibly did change the
outcome of one local contest in the
final results
Central Lake Township scanned its
ballots twice because the scanner was
initially programmed with the wrong
School Board race in the first scan a
local marijuana initiative failed in a
tie but in the second scan it passed by
one vote
why the difference well I recovered
partial records that suggest that that
during the second scan whether correctly
or due to human error one particular
ballot was omitted that would have
changed the results
despite the narrow margin nobody
challenged the outcome within the
statutory time frame so the final
results will stand forever
while my analysis was not a Security
review I did note or confirm several
security problems with the EMS along the
way
all users shared a single Windows login
with administrator privileges allowing
them to alter logs or bypass access
controls
SQL management Studio was installed
allowing users to directly alter the
election databases the Windows security
updates were more than two years out of
date and the security log from the
election day had been discarded because
the log had reached a fixed maximum size
the MS also did not use full disk
encryption
these issues are all real security
problems and should be mitigated
promptly but it's important to note that
there is no evidence that they were ever
exploited in antrum
so ultimately my investigation was able
to account for all known anomalies in
antrim's results including several that
I discovered myself
all arose from human error during
unusual circumstances involving ballot
design changes at the last minute which
are unlikely to have occurred widely
elsewhere
although the major errors have been
fully corrected I determined that
certain down ballot contests still
contain smaller errors
several opportunities to discover the
problems were missed due to further
human errors including ones in processes
that are important safeguards for
security and accuracy such as logic and
accuracy testing and pre-certification
canvassing the election software also
certainly could have done more to
prevent the human errors from affecting
results but there's no basis to conclude
it was deliberately designed to
facilitate fraud
based on this understanding of the
events in Antrim County I make a number
of recommendations the common theme is
to bring a more scientific mindset to
election Administration such as by
reviewing and strengthening procedural
fail-safes and improving usability for
poll workers both of which are problems
that badly need more attention from our
research community
I also suggest steps to facilitate
post-election forensics by creating and
better preserving digital records
finally I recommend that future election
incidents when they occur as they
inevitably will should be followed by
officials conducting rigorous
post-election investigations to ensure
the problems are understood and that
lessons are shared to prevent recurrence
I hope this work can serve as a model
for such efforts thank you