thank you all for coming my name is Ben
Burgess today I'll be presenting work we
did on remote proctoring software called
watching the Watchers
so I I'm sure everyone has seen over the
last 10 years we're starting to see
rapid adoption of remote learning
environments and moving away from these
more traditional in-person environments
and through this institutions have been
looking for ways to ensure that they
have exam exam Integrity in these remote
environments so we've been seeing more
and more adoption of remote proctoring
software and through this we've seen
tons of articles that come out that
should say you know students of color
are getting flagged their teachers
because testing software can't see them
along with this General usability
problems for the student and this is
really underscored by high how high
stakes these exams out they're generally
um kind of the Capstone exam for example
like the Bio exam which things like that
that you need to take to actually be
enter the field
we build our work on examining the
examiners which looks at the student
experience concerns around remote
proctoring we do a little bit more of a
technical Deep dive into these Suites
so to start we wanted to see how
prevalent these exam Suites were so we
focused on law schools because
um
they're generally again high stakes
exams
um where you only have a few of them and
they account for most of your course
grade so we went through and we
collected usage statistics from the top
180 ABA accredited law schools and then
we also focused on Bio exam associations
because you need these to actually enter
the field as a lawyer so once you finish
your law school
um
law school you go and take the Bio exam
that you can become a lawyer we
collected these through emails calls
open records requests and scraping
public websites what we found is that
there was three main proctoring Suites
used by law schools exemplify exam for
Electro and electronic Blue Book there
was some other ones like canvas and my
law but those were a much smaller
percentage individually
for the Bible exam itself we see again
three main ones Stand Out exemplify ilg
exam 360 and exam four
so the main question that comes from
this is do these software Suites
actually prevent cheating or is it just
all you know security theater
um
and what we're going to focus on here is
not as much the motivated adversary and
the Very experience the adversary as
much as just kind of the evil law
student and what they would be able to
do to bypass the security features
we can break down the security features
these Suites offer into three main ones
exam content protection session
monitoring and restriction so this is to
serve as kind of like what a impulse and
proactive would do so monitoring what
content you can open and kind of
restricting that and then providing an
audit log after the fact and then
finally we'll talk about identity
verification
so in order to do this what we did is we
obtained the binaries for exemplify exam
four electronic blue book and ilg exam
360. we votes engineered these and then
we took out findings in kind of a
general methodology and we try to
generalize these and we designed an
automated tool from that which will
allow us to hopefully support future
studies where they can build off of our
work
well so if we look at what an evil law
student might do they would want to
potentially get the exam ahead of time
right
um an encryption at West tries to
prevent this because normally what
happens is you'll download your exam
let's say three days or a week ahead of
time and it'll just sit on your computer
and then when you go to take the exam
you're given the password for it and
you're able to open it we see General
wise General pretty good encryption
algorithms being picked here so most of
them are using like AES 256 but the
question from there comes is the system
around that actually being used securely
and what we find is that that's really
not the case so several of these exam
Suites will use HTTP Connections in
their back end to the server and even if
they're using a secure algorithm it
doesn't really matter if your key
derivation process isn't secure and
exemplify in particular uses very few
password derivation iterations so what
this means is if you didn't have a very
long and secure password someone would
be able to easily Brute Force this
an electronic Blue Book actually uses a
fixed password salt called kosher and by
having that fixed and so simple you'd be
able to just pre-compute a lot of these
passwords
so now let's talk a little bit about
session monitoring and restriction this
can kind of break down into three main
categories so you have your process
restrictions clipboard restrictions and
then your virtual machine and device
prevention
the virtual machine device prevention
Works to support the process
restrictions and clipboard restrictions
because if the software suite can't see
a whole computer then you're not really
able to do enforce any of those
restrictions so they make an attempt to
prevent that
so let's see what we found here we see
that almost all of the proximate Suites
Implement some form of virtual machine
detection this normally takes the form
of a block list the same with a virtual
the virtual device detection
what this means is that anything the
developers didn't think of as permitted
which is just insane there so if you
have a suite they didn't think of you
could run that or if you were able to
change the name you'd also be able to
run that
and then if we look at the process
restrictions we see them change it up a
little bit here where we move to an
allow list for some of them and this is
just a pre-approved list of applications
that they allow you to run and that
seems like it would be a lot better than
a block list but that's again until you
look at how the system works once you do
that you figure out that they're not
checking the digital signatures for any
of the proctoring Suites so or so for
any of the
um any of the applications so you'd be
able to easily rename applications to
bypass the restrictions that they put in
place
and some people might from a CS backbone
kind of question why do we even care
about the clipboard right like what do
you copy and paste in
um it ends up with law exams a lot of
the answers you normally have based on
large Blobs of case law and other things
so a student can obtain a massive
advantage over everyone else if they're
able to quickly copy and paste this in
um
but it ends up that you can just get a
USB rubber ducky
um wrote in your essay or whatever case
law you want plug this in during your
exam and it can easily bypass all of the
clipboard management we saw implemented
so this by you don't even have to mess
with virtual machines right
um
and now finally let's talk about
identity verification this is
particularly important because
um okay these Suites are like completely
security theater that's fine but if they
don't have them to use it why do we care
let them use them right but identity
verification is where we can start to
see the main effects on the student and
the main negative impacts of the
adoption we're seeing around remote
clock doing Suites
we picked the exemplify for this
analysis because they do most of their
verification client side so they want
the facial recognition models in the
software they do two specific modes one
is initial verification so what this
does is it acts as a gatekeeper so when
you want to try to begin your exam you
have your ID and some trusted picture so
like your student ID or something like
that they can reference and it takes a
picture of you trying to begin the exam
does some comparison operation and
determines whether or not it thinks it's
you and whether or not you can start the
exam and then continuous verification
just works to make sure that if you pass
this initial verification step you're
the one who continues to take the exam
and you don't just have someone
immediately swap out for you
so you think given that this is working
kind of as a gatekeeper right and could
prevent people from even being able to
take an exam altogether that they would
have picked the best like state of the
out algorithm done extensive testing
make sure it's fair right
well what we found here is they're using
unmodified open source model they just
pulled from GitHub called faceapi.js
along with dweb and this is being used
for all of the verification operations
so in order to discuss how this performs
we need to First have some metrics we
can use to talk about what performance
means in this context so we're going to
talk about two here one is the false
non-match weight so what this means is
if you had a subsequent image of
yourself would the software think that
that is actually you I would say that's
not you you can't take the exam right go
contact somebody
um and this essentially means the
student is being accused of cheating and
this might not I mean this might may
seem fine okay let's go talk to somebody
but you have to remember the stakes here
right these people have this is either
at the end of a semester or at the end
of your law school like a law student
care this is like the gatekeeper to
either being able to graduate or being
able to be a lawyer right so they're
already very stressed out and this is
just another another bio
and then we also have false matches so
what this is is if you have a subsequent
image of a separate person would that be
identified as being you
um and this is this judges this acts as
a proxy for whether or not a student
would be able to potentially cheat and
get away with cheating by having someone
else take the exam for them
so what we find here is that we see
pretty high fnmowers across the board
um 0.66 may seem somewhat low at first
glance but if you think about a thousand
student class this means six people
would likely have difficulty taking the
exam and if you've ever been on a zoom
call like a meat call the images we have
here on the left have controlled
backgrounds that we're testing with
controlled lighting conditions this is
much better than you would probably see
in the field so that is a very
optimistic fnmo
and when we move out to the in the wild
data set BGG phase two which uses varied
backgrounds and things like that we see
this weighs up to 14 which would be
about 140 students in that thousand
person class
um additionally if we look at the false
match weight we see that that's around
for the Patrol images which suggests
that even in optimal conditions this is
merely security theater it's not really
providing much actual security to the
process
so now that we've established that this
doesn't really work well overall we can
look more at the fairness question and
see if we're actually seeing bias in
this is it being unfair between people
from different races and things like
that
so to do this we collected data we use
data sets that have racial
classifications in them we understand
that waste is more nuanced and our
labels cue whack Nuance but we were
using the ones from the original data
set
um so we went with that versus trying to
reclassify
what we see here is significant variance
between subjects of different races with
in some cases for example on BGG Phase 2
Face API had a seven percent difference
so over the Thousand posts in group that
would be 70 students
um and you would expect that given all
the stakes and that they know the
software's gonna be used as a gatekeeper
that they would pick
um a project they didn't have no one
arrows around this right but if we go
back to 2019 there was an open issue on
the repo that they used that states
um
the author directly stated that there
was a bias towards Western faces that
they're aware of in the classify that
exemplify then went and chose for their
software
so what we've established here is that
the software is nearly Universal we
found that it can't meaningfully prevent
cheating from a technical perspective
it's mainly security theater so it looks
looks really strong but it doesn't
actually do too much for you and there's
significant overall usability concerns
with it the facial recognition doesn't
work well overall and it has additional
fairness components so this really leads
us to the question of should this
software be implemented at all and based
on our research we don't think there's
any
there's any place for the software and
production environments
um thank you all
um I'll now take questions