does it work we also about attacking
sensitive English citizens okay so
thanks for the introduction I so I'll be
presenting the paper we wrote with my
coat on a signal Val Minnie Conan so I'm
selling the whole day and in this talk
we're going to see privacy issues with
some kind of searchable encryption so
about searchable encryption even if we
already sold on it when you want to
store data on a server that you do not
trust you can encrypt the data before
sending it so but with traditional
encryption the server will not be able
to do anything useful with this data so
the aim of searchable encryption
protocols is to let you search this data
constant here you see a user asking if
the the data contains the key word
urgent in getting a response yes/no and
the protocol of course must maintain the
privacy of the data but also most of the
time of the courage to so in this stop
will only will mostly focus on this kind
of simple search queries so is this
keyword contained in in the document so
in this paper we study the security of
multi-user searchable encryption or muse
for short that denote searchable
encryption with a large number of users
that we split in two groups the writers
and the readers so the writers upload
encrypted data to the server and they
can choose which readers or a load to
search their data what we found is that
all the efficient existing news kingdom
or provide close to no privacy
as soon as some users even a very small
about them collude with the server
so it makes the design very powerful
because with a very tiny collision
between the server and a very small
number of users you get will see a very
large violation of the privacy the
vulnerability is also extremely simple
so it leads us to wonder who can still
be present so what we do is we show the
seriousness of the attack of the issue
we study the cause of the vulnerability
and we give ideas and tools to avoid
this kind of issues in the design of
future new schemes so the attack that we
present is what we call a leakage abuse
attack so the term was coined by cash er
in their paper at CCS 15 and I often
refer to this paper during the talk a
leakage abuse attack is an attack where
the server combines some information
that is naturally leaked by the
searchable encryption scheme that's
called the leakage profile and it's
combined with some extra information
that was obtained by some other means by
the server so there are many papers
recently on leakage abuse attacks but so
far they have only been applied on
single user searchable encryption and so
we applied them to move to use a
subscription and it get interesting
results so where does the vulnerability
comes on almost all music skins so multi
user searchable encryption schemes even
if they are very different from one
another they are all based on a common
structure that we call the iterative
testing structure illustrated here so in
this structure what the server pods
costs are encrypted indexes you can see
three of them here that all lists of
encrypted key words and
the search operation consists in the
server performing some tests against
each keyword separately okay so here you
can see the test failing on the first
two keyword and passing on third so this
gives a lot of information to the server
because encrypted keywords matching the
same query you can here see down here
that this result end one query to these
two documents and you have two keywords
matching the queries they must be the
same keyword we don't know what they are
but they must be the same keyword and
queries matching the same keyword so the
query of the log in the and her query
that match the same keyword must be the
same query so it was very simple leakage
abuse attack in that if the server
colludes with a user so this one here
the vendor server has access to the
content of all the indexes this user was
allowed to search a detect access to the
so documents in red and there's nothing
we can do about that but because of
these relations between keywords that
the server could see thanks to its
really testing the server will also
recover keywords in all the documents so
this one here
and this is clearly a violation of the
privacy guarantees that we can expect
from the new scheme because as the user
if I didn't authorize this user to
search my document I don't want my
security to depend on his behavior
otherwise why having an authorization
stem at all so the tag is very simple
right but what's maybe less intuitive
and more interesting is how powerful it
is to see that we're in statistical
experiments so we follow a methodology
that's as close as possible to the one
of cashel here we give some some figures
about the the conditions but the the
most important
is this we have 30,000 emails and we
give the server access to only 20 of
them so there are the red documents here
so this is only point zero seven percent
of the whole data set that we reveal to
the seller and then we simulate just
legitimate queries about thousand
queries per reader and here are the
results
by just doing its job of serving queries
the server is able to recover a lot of
chaos 90% of all the documents had at
least 10% of the key was recovered and
half of all documents have at least 30%
of the us recovered and query privacy is
affected too in similar proportion this
is the whole privacy of the data
etiquette for query prophecies about the
same thing so we think that because no
one did these experiments before the
power of this type of attack has been
underestimated and it's probably a first
explanation to why the liberal state
prisons so our tack applies to every
muse scheme that follows the iterative
testing structure that are in red here
so as you can see all them but one but
one in black which is our schema when
produced a vacation but this scheme is
not scalable
it does not scale well to large data
sets so right now I'm going to use a
sociable encryption you have the choice
between a scheme that does not scale and
schemes well you essentially lose all
privacy as soon as just a very small
fraction of the documents irregularly so
how is it possible that so many schemes
are affected by such an attack for all
the one all the papers that are in this
box the reason is very obvious it's just
not in their threat model in these
papers the only threat that is
considered is the server and then never
study what happens if if the users
behave badly so what can we say about
papers that don't include a user server
collusion in the spread model first it's
surprising because in this kind of
system the users tend to be the weakest
point in terms of securing
[Music]
second it it doesn't really make sense
because when when you are in in a
situation where you can trust the users
most of the time it means that you don't
really need an authorization mechanism
to make sure that users will not search
the documents they're not supposed to
see and so in this case you probably
don't need a mule system instead you
should use a symmetric or single user
system that is much much less costly and
what would be ok actually would be to
have some violation of privacy when some
users code with the server if only you
had guarantees that a limited collusion
would would result in a limited
violation but our results show that this
is not necessarily the case so you need
to show that on your system and for that
you need to study user server collision
so that's our first point
do include server user server collisions
in the security analysis of your systems
so now you see that there's one paper
that's not in the box
it's multi key sub table encryption by
poppin sandwich it's mostly known for
being the protocol that he used that is
used in a framework called Mylar so this
paper was the good and moving the good
direction because it is the first to
consider users coding with a server but
unfortunately guess what it used the
iterative testing structure and so it is
affected by your attack just like the
others so we prove this is the case by
breaking the security of the mylar
framework and if you're interested the
code for doing that is publicly
available it also raised on my laptop so
point to do not use iterative testing
structure sadly we do not have an
efficient alternative to this structure
right now so our point is that future
work should focus on finding an
alternative to that final point is on
the misconception that the leakage
induced by iterative testing structure
is equivalent to something called
leakage to code access pattern
leakage here you can see that in the
paper of Mylar the system we checked the
authors acknowledge that their scheme
does not hide the excess pattern now all
the state-of-the-art protocol in
searchable encryption do leech the
access pattern leakage so it makes my
last in preschool but we showed that the
leakage in Dewsbury already testing is
much more dangerous than making no more
than the access pattern so it makes the
statement is misleading
so access pattern in searchable
encryption is the information about what
document matches a given search query so
it's illustrated at the top what the
seller seized with iterate testing is at
the bottom and it is stronger than the
nexus pattern leakage so we call this
leakage
keyword access pattern leakage or lqr
show and we found several papers where
the two types of leakage or considers as
equivalent so
give a formal definition of lky and we
use our statistical simulation to show
that it is indeed much different and
access path leakage that in this name l1
in the classification of cashel so here
we can see the results the results of an
attack against a scheme with the l1
profile and an equivalent attack again a
scheme with a web profile and we can see
that the attack is there the results are
much better with the aircraft profile so
they're called profiles worse in term of
security and and we can see that on the
other graph that l-pipe is actually
closer to an orderly cache profile named
l3 by Cashel and that is much much more
dangerous in terms of security so
conclusion you must include collisions
in security analysis of news and when
you do that with most existing new
schemes you see that security disappear
so we must find an alternative to the
iterative testing structure we must stop
basing we don't need yet another scheme
based on this structure and Noel came up
is not equivalent to leaking the access
pattern actually so it's much worse in
terms of security
okay web than ek success again and
actually it would be already a nice
improvement to have a new scheme that
leaks know much more eloquent so at the
end of the paper we give some ideas that
we're working on for for improving the
state of the art or use but they still
work in progress
[Applause]