and we'll change microphones but it's a
pleasure to welcome Giovanni
who will be talking about basin of
naives and starts the fingerprinting
part of this session now Keith paper has
the distinction that I think the only
paper this year that is from one single
author so we know that it's all his work
and all of that well done
right well thanks George for the
introduction and good morning everyone
so I'm Giovanni kerbin PhD at Royal
Holloway University of London and I'm
going to talk about a method to evaluate
the security of websites in the printing
defenses now website in the printing
attacks have been around for more than a
decade now and and there has been this
massive arms race between new attacks
and new defenses and there are two clear
issues concerning defenses first of all
well they are typically difficult to
design on the top of existing systems or
existing protocols and secondly once we
have a defense well there is no
framework no generic framework to
actually evaluate its security or to
quantify its security in a profit
provable manner so the method I'm going
to introduce is going to give us
security guarantees for any website
fingerprinting defense with respect to a
feature set as I will shortly explain
and it will do so by considering the
defence as a black box and this this
should give great freedom to designing
actually defenses so let me spend a few
words about websites in the painting so
we consider a victim who is browsing
some web page over an encrypted tunnel
now this tunnel could be a VPN it could
be tor more likely what is important
here is that the traffic is encrypted
and that the IP address of the web
server is hidden locally and the
adversary we consider is a local passive
eavesdropper
who looks at these all these encrypted
traffic and and the goal of this
adversary is to predict which web HD the
victim is viewing so as I said the IP
address of the web server is hidden and
we assume well that the adversary cannot
decrypt pockets so essentially the only
information that the adversary can
access is time size and direction of
these encrypted pockets and we call a
sequence of these triplets packet
sequence so our website underpainting
attack is made of two choices the
adversary first has to choose a set of
high-level descriptions of of the
traffic and this is what we call
features so an example of feature is the
total communication time that is how
long it takes to download a web page and
you can see that this feature allows to
discriminate between lightweight
websites and very heavy ones right then
the adversary has to choose a classifier
now a classifier is just an algorithm
that can be trained on some some network
data that the adversary collected in an
offline phase just by loading webpages
many times and and this classifier can
be used to predict the the webpage
corresponding to some to some new
traffic now the method I'm going to
present will give us security bounds for
any possible classifier the user the
adversary can use and it will be fixed
it will be for a fixed feature set but
then I will show that actually this is
not this is not bad news so what sorting
the printing defenses you can imagine
them as adding buckets morphine pockets
within some pocket sequence okay
so let's try to think about how how we
can prove their security and in 2014
Talia told
used a method to which I would refer as
the lookup table approach to demonstrate
the security of over defects they were
proposing that tomorrow now in this in
this method they considered an idealized
adversary who knows exactly what kind of
pocket sequences each webpage can can
produce in other words he can create a
lookup table we're given some pocket
sequence he knows exactly which are the
web pages that might have produced it
and of course the B's adversary will
only commit an error when there are
there is more than one web page
corresponding to the same pocket
sequence and and we can estimate a
security bound for for this adversary we
can estimate is error just by by
counting the collisions within this
lookup table now unfortunately this
method has a few drawbacks first of all
it needs to be a when designing a
defense we need to do so by by keeping
this principles in mind in other words
we need this method needs to be crafted
around the designs being evaluated and
this is actually quite a constraint when
when trying to design defenses on the
top of other systems and secondly this
method is highly highly affected by
noise which means ok let me give you an
example consider two packet sequences
that are almost exactly the same apart
from one pocket which arrived a few
milliseconds later well in that case the
adversary would be able to distinguish
because we have there is no notion of
distance metric in this approach and and
this we will have we will only have
underestimates of Defense's security and
for the same reason of noise
well this method can only be applied to
deterministic defenses okay so let's
sort of take a step back and think about
what it means to distinguish - what the
and let's do so just by considering one
single feature that is total
communication time okay
now the total communication time given
some lightweight web page such as start
page comm will have some probability
distribution okay and given some other
websites a free image is calm which is a
bit heavier it will have some other
probability distribution okay
now assume for a moment that these are
actually the the one plotted here where
the correct distribution that were the
real distributions of data well in this
case is this was the case the best
strategy to distinguish the two webpages
would actually be predicting according
according to these distributions and the
smallest error we would achieve is the
red area you see here now it turns out
this is actually something well-known
this area has a name and it's called the
base ever so the base error is the error
of this idealized based classifier which
knows the real distribution of data okay
and I want to remark that this bounds is
not it is intrinsic in the distribution
of data is interested in our data and
induce it holds for any classifier even
computationally unbounded now of course
in real word we we do not know the real
distribution of data otherwise machine
learning would be solved and induced we
don't know the real base error however
there are ways to estimate it so let's
go back to the problem of what setting
or painting we consider some adversary
using a certain feature sets sigh and
training a classifier F now we evaluate
these this classifier with the with its
probability of error that's our F okay
and from what we have seen
the previous slide well the probability
of error for any classifier is lower
bounded by the Bayes error which we
don't know and now it would be nice to
find some lower bound of these and it
turns out that are a nice result by
covering heart from 67 shows that this
weird expression which is something we
can actually make in proxies lower
bounds the base error enters the error
of any classifier now let me walk you
through this expression so we need to
know the number of websites being
classified the number of unique websites
that is L and then we need we need to
have a data set okay of network traces
of the defended natural traces and we
need to run the nearest neighbor
classifier on these data sets to to
pretend predict et cetera and that's
exactly these are nm and we know that
asymptotically these this asymptotic ly
as as the the size of these data that we
have available increases well
this result will hold now in the paper
as well as I said this result is
asymptotic and in the paper you can find
details about how we can Arista Cali
sorry
example how we can you Rishta cailli
evaluate convergence of this bound so we
have an error bound and we may need
something more because an error bound on
its own does not tell us much about the
setting in three classes classification
setting that is the adversary has to
pick between three websites well by
random guessing this would be his error
in a two classes classes classification
he would have much better much smaller
ever just by random guessing which is
why I proposed this privacy parameter
epsilon which normalizes the error
boundary competive we computed in the
previous slide
the error of random guessing and in the
paper you can find details about how
this is related to the cryptographic
concept of advantage with respect to
random guessing right so this slide
presents the privacy of many well-known
defenses now epsilon the privacy
parameter takes value 1 for a perfectly
private defense so what you can see here
are defenses essentially listed in
increasing in order of increasing
privacy and I think the takeaway of this
slide is that it is absolutely possible
with this method to to impact is to
balance trade-offs between privacy and
overheads maybe also taking into account
engineering difficulties ok so there is
just one last question we need to answer
does it make sense at all to have a
privacy metric which depends on a set of
features now recall that a website
fingerprinting attack is made of a
choice I think can be improved by
improving feature sets or classifiers
and what you are seeing here is the
evolution of feature set since 2006 so
each color represents a different
defense and each each point for each
attack represents the smallest error
achievable with that with that specific
feature set and well website think the
painting attacks did improve a lot in
the past years however as you can see
here bear feature set did not improve
much which means we were able to improve
classifiers but not as much feature set
and this sort of leads to to think that
actually improving features is very hard
and which sort of justifies our privacy
metric depending on features and also
leads us to think that maybe finding
improving features is the next big
direct
in website finger-painting so to
conclude great I propose these these
methods these black box night so to
evaluate the security of any website
fingerprinting defense with respect to a
set of features now I've shown why it
makes sense to actually make make this
assumption but of course the next
natural research question is can we
actually produce some bounds that are
independent of these features then a
second required research question is can
we try other base error estimate and you
can find more on the paper about about
this and finally I would like to stress
that this method this technique is not
bound to the problem of what's a single
printing and whenever an adversary has
to distinguish between some scenarios
and to do so has to train on some some
data well we can immediately collect the
data set and estimate these error bounds
and so I can see these applied in
traffic analysis in side-channel attacks
this morning the first presentation for
example was trying to the to determine
to distinguish between real skies
traffic and Skype traffic with some
cover channel well we may actually be
able to use this to to derive security
bound for that and and note that if for
some of these attacks the adversary have
had only access to a limited to some
limited information so it didn't have to
extract features well we would
immediately have this epsilon break
privacy guarantees so thanks a lot for
listening and I'll be looking forward to
your questions okay great thank you very
much
so I get to answer the first question so
I'm very