hi everybody welcome back from lunch and
welcome to our afternoon sessions of hot
pets I'm Kelly cane and I'll be chairing
the privacy policy session for the next
roughly an hour our talks this afternoon
will go just like the talks this morning
they'll be about 15 minutes for the talk
and plenty of time with that ten minutes
for questions again as a reminder we
would like hot pets to be very
interactive our first talk of the
afternoon is by hottie asghari renee Moo
pratik metal and Rachel Green stat and
hotties going to be talking about the
right of access as a tool for privacy
governance welcome honey thank you good
afternoon everybody is the volume good
enough yeah okay well yeah I'm excited
to present some of the work I've been
doing with my colleagues my name is Adi
Ascari I'm a researcher at Delft
University of Technology in the
Netherlands and this is work together
with my student Rena Mayo and colleagues
pratik and Rachel so the motivation
behind the work is kinda we all know we
need much more transparency there's a
large information asymmetry between what
the collectors of data are doing and
what kind of we know about them and the
public I mean even the academics I think
a lot of the measurement work that's
presented here or for instance the fake
news discussion all of that shows to
what extent and how hard kind of the
community is working to open up more
what's going there and this kind of was
another idea at some point me and Rachel
were brainstorming about what other ways
would be to increase transparency and
the idea we came up was whether we could
use the EU access rights as kind of an
empirical tool I'll describe what they
are in a minute
and mainly the access rights have been
used by activists in the past so you
might have heard for instance about max
friends using it so the right of access
it's defined in the European Data
Protection Directive and also in the
upcoming general data protection
regulation it basically says that data
subject that's any any natural person
can ask a data controller for a copy of
their data and they should also explain
what the purpose was that they collected
the data and who they shared the data
with and some other things so this is
what a access request looks like it's in
Dutch because I've sent it to my Dutch
bank but basically the first paragraph
I'm saying please give me everything you
have on me and then I'm explaining the
legal basis and I'm saying that I've
included a copy of my passport and this
is what they respond so they send me
back a letter Y a few weeks afterwards
it includes my personal details name
address etc it includes the list of
contracts I have with the bank so that's
my accounts and it includes a list of
documents they have they didn't send
back the actual documents but they said
for instance they have I don't know my
passport copy they have my financial
statement etc and on this page they were
explaining the the other two parts of
the law which says like who are you
sharing into it and why have you
collected it they've answered it rather
broadly so just very broad bullet points
so we thought can we like can we turn
this into kind of a study where we
collect more of this this data and I
will show that a bit more of that in a
bit but before that we did kind of a
preliminary study where we decided to
kind of test how different organizations
respond to access requests so we
together with Renaye we did about 50
access requests
thirty two organizations intense
different sectors and for organizations
didn't respond actually so which is
illegal they could be fined for that
twelve organizations which said that
they have no data or they gave a
referral and sixteen gave back some form
of data on average in six weeks
for the authentication as you can
imagine this can be quite weird if you
send an email on behalf of someone else
so a lot of people just accepted the
copy of the passport but some
organizations called to verify and two
organizations actually asked me to go in
person before they would hand over the
data and the responses are very
heterogeneous so I'm going to show you a
few different ones this is an example I
have a MasterCard I sent a requested
them and they basically we didn't give
back any data and they use the technical
legal term thing that they are a data
processor not a data controller and they
said that I have to go to my bank which
I kind of agree with them in this sense
but it could be a question mark whether
this is agreeable or not but it's a
legal question I would guess a stranger
answer we got from Amsterdam Airport
they again said they have no data and
then they list that they said all the
data in the airport is controlled by
third parties and they list a very long
list of third parties that might have
the data but this made no sense to us
because an airport has centralized
infrastructure right who controls your
luggage that's the airport is not going
to give that to someone else or and this
is an actual sticker in in Sybil which
has a Wi-Fi tracking kind of warning so
we sent a follow-up request asking can
you explain who the third parties are
for exactly baggage and Wi-Fi and then
they sent another response saying well
they actually do collect data but they
deleted regularly so they said it's
deleted after a few days so I don't know
how we can test this it might be an
example of actually excellent privacy
design if they delete the data or it
might require further digging
we sent a request to my public transport
card they were they
responded pretty quickly and they gave
actually a lot of data which indicates
they have kind of a nice workflow for
this in place but interesting enough
they sent back prints of screenshots of
their CRM system so even though this
company and this was pretty normal like
this is what I got from a lot of people
they like it seems like organizations
don't have a fully automated system in
place to produce these reports and for
instance there was also a big screenshot
of my face this was the more interesting
stuff which was all my check-ins and
checkouts with my cart and the amount I
paid there is one thing missing here I
don't know if you can see it was a
really important thing missing there are
no location information in it so we
actually asked them back and they say
they don't keep the location they just
keep the costs I I don't know it's a
interesting question again this is a
request to the police so you can
actually even send to the intelligence
services or the police everybody has to
answer this one was sent by Rene he got
back a report of the times he'd been to
the police once as a witness once
there's an accident what we noticed was
missing was that he actually had
witnessed shooting in 2009 and that
wasn't in the report so again a letter
back what about that and then they
eventually sent another system with that
information in it and they explained
actually that like they keep data from
before five years in a different system
so their systems are not connected they
have to go to the archives etc so one of
the things we noticed was that there is
a lot of back-and-forth involved in
getting this kind of data so if you
remember one of the elements the law
said was that they have to show who they
share the data with the city of The
Hague actually did the most extensive
thing in that where they sent back a
very detailed kind of logged by some
kind of system where it lists for
instance that they've shared this is
again Rene's information they shared it
with data Lloyd this information but it
doesn't have any of the values it's just
the labels of what they shared and if
you dig through it sometimes you kind of
come up with strange things for instance
the financial market authorities they
queried his date of death probably as
kind of normal thing this their system
does we sent one request to TU delft
actually and this was kind of
interesting so they know me so they kind
of recognize my name I got an email from
them saying like what is this and I
responded well it's EU law answered as
you normally would and they said they've
never had one of these requests which is
interesting if you think that this law
exists for 20 years and tu delft has
thousands of students and employees and
I'm the first one to ask so I eventually
get back he responds it's actually a
pretty detailed response it's on all of
those are like the different systems the
university owns what kind of personal
data and is each system and illegal but
not he actually didn't send back the
actual like labels of like the actual
data but just categories of what date it
is I want what legal basis is collected
the guy who sent this made the kind of
interview with like appointment with me
follow-up appointment he wanted to know
how I would benchmark them compared to
other organizations which was
interesting because it indicated that
actually this has the potential of some
kind of learning for the organizations
and I actually asked him how long it
took them to send me this that he said
80 hours so if it's it kind of seems
very unfair that I can to do it in five
minutes and it will take him 80 hours
but I think maybe they will do the
second one faster so this kind of brings
us to our main idea which I'd like to
get a bit feedback from you guys we're
thinking of like getting hundreds or
maybe a thousand volunteers to send out
these access requests and these are the
kind of insights we think we can get
from the data so the first is we get we
get insights on the processes that
companies have and they're basically
very high level data practices we are
actually hoping that it will teach us
stuff about the data flows so the and
that might be useful as ground truth for
people doing a
forms of measurements like external
measurements etc and also we want to
evaluate the users on how they feel
about the data so like are you appalled
or what and we think it's useful for a
bunch of different groups including the
organization's two key challenges we see
are the data is very unstructured so we
would like to share of course this data
said after we created but it's so
unstructured we are thinking still
what's the best way to do that and of
course all of the privacy implications
of like how do we share that so yeah if
you have any ideas so we've been kind of
doing where we receive the seed grant
from Princeton to kind of start the
project and based on that we've started
with for now some UI sketch ups this
part actually already exists this is the
tool I used to generate the request from
it's run by the Dutch NGO bits of
freedom who've also been very kind and
advised us on a lot of the work where
you kind of choose the company and it
generates the letter with the correct
address as you saw there's a lot of
back-and-forth involved and you have two
companies like mr. deadlines so you have
to send them reminder letters etc so we
first see that one of the nice things
this is kind of a mock-up we've done
would be that for a user that says the
request we kind of tell them hey this
one you need to kind of send a reminder
and we just keep a track of what the
process looks like for them we will then
be asking users to upload their
responses at the moment we've thought at
least we will give them the option to
black out things that they think
shouldn't be even seen by the admins of
the system or by like the PI's and like
this could be a very simple evaluation
where we ask them you know how did was
the data complete because they have they
are the ones who can answer that
question right better than anybody else
and a lot of the answers responses when
we got it required like really
discussing does it make sense that the
company says they don't have this or
they do and so this we envision like the
form will also be an important part of
kind of the platform and all of this
will kind of generate data which should
be helpful this is how we envision it
could be shared this is like a somewhat
simple model but it would be like they
only so what they share on the forum is
basically their choice the users choice
the kind of what they share with us and
kind of the constant form for these
volunteers that we want to get will be
that they will share most of it with us
we are actually now starting with five
first volunteers as a test to see how
people feel about that about sharing
everything and with other researchers at
the moment like we would have to share
the data in pride in a
privacy-preserving manner at the moment
our thought is to do kind of case by
case so we see a request and then we see
like manually how can we get that out
from the data add like I don't know
noise if necessary etc to make sure it
remains and also ask users extra consent
based on the research that's been asked
for it so that's it in summary we think
access requests have a lot of potential
to create transparency we're building
this platform and if you have any
requests already you think there's a
specific type of data that would be
helpful or if you have tips a lot of you
guys have a lot of experience with I
don't know crowdsource projects if you
have any tips you think with something
important to know from the start or if
you think you have resources we would be
very happy to hear from you
[Applause]