can you hear me okay okay I guess it's
time to start welcome everyone to the
second session of the afternoon
and here we have Henry and he's an
undergrad at Princeton University
he has joint work with pratik and now
he's going to present his work on using
PGP to cry bogus TLS certificate okay so
I'm from Princeton University and over
the last year I've been doing some
really interesting work which actually
ties a lot into our keynote that we just
heard about using BGP attacks to get
bogus TLS certificates so let's just
take a step back and motivate this
problem when I go to login to my login
page at Princeton University the login
server is hosted at fed Princeton dot
edu but I'm on somebody else's network
how do I know that I'm actually getting
the correct server well the answer is
that they present their public key in a
certificate and their certificate has to
be signed by a certificate authority
that I trust so we've heard a lot about
certificate authorities but just to
demonstrate here's the chain of trust my
browser trust the certificate because
comodo signed it and this is the way
that even on first-time connections
going to sites that you've never been to
before you know that you can trust them
however if we kind of take some steps
back we can realize that vulnerabilities
in BGP actually allow an adversary to
break this root of trust and have these
trusted roots vouch for them even though
they're not the legitimate domain owner
so let's take a look at how these
certificates are signed what process do
they use to make sure that you actually
control the domain so if you want a
certificate you simply put in a
certificate signing request containing
the domain that you'd like the
certificate for and the certificate
authority can't sign immediately they
have to come back with a challenge to
show that you actually own the domain so
this is normally in the form of putting
a document up on the root of your web
server and once you've performed those
challenges presuming that you actually
own the domain you let the certificate
authority know that you did it and then
they go and check to make sure that that
documents actually there so they just
send a web connection to perform that
check and then once they get the proper
response they give you your certificate
so it's a really simple protocol
but if we take a step back and look at
this check from an adversarial point of
view this is the only communication in
the whole protocol that matters because
you can be any client asked for any
domain you want and as long as this
check from the certificate authority to
the domain goes through you can get the
certificate so in the second half of
this talk we're going to look at simply
ways the adversary can intercept this
check and fake the response so sort of
in another domain how my two adversary
do this and it turns out BGP attacks
actually provide a really good means of
doing this so this is a very simple
network diagram all of these are
autonomous systems and that's um it's an
entity in the BGP routing protocol
that's the backbone routing protocol for
the internet and they pretty much
represent ISPs Internet service
providers and so here we have the
certificate authority the victims domain
and the adversary and in BGP
when the victim announces that they
control a prefix of IP addresses the
routing protocol converges and then
traffic goes straight from the
certificate authority to the victim and
the adversary unless they're a major
backbone provider and happen to be on
this router already they really can't
get a fake certificate for you but now
let's look at an attack that the
adversary could perform so if you
announced some more specific prefix than
the one that the original victim
advertised so unfortunately this is a
slash 24 being 24 bits of network mask
and that's more specific containing 250
right 250 for IP addresses as opposed to
the slash 23 up there um as a result the
adversaries route will be preferred by
all of these routers because it's longer
more specific and all the traffic will
go to the adversary so in this case now
obviously the adversary can forge this
request because the traffic is going to
go to them instead of the real victim
and get a certificate so it's a very
straightforward attack we see these on
the internet quite often but there's
sort of a downside from an adversarial
point of view and that's that you're
going to break connectivity to the
victim and that's not very stealthy the
victims websites going to go down all
services running on that IP block will
be affected and even if you think you're
a clever adversary and you try to
say forward to traffic to the real
victim every a s on the internet
believes that you're the real victim
because you had the real the real
destination because you have the more
specific route so if you try doing that
they'll actually just forward the
traffic back to you so unless this
adversary has a tunnel right to the
victim's ISP which we can assume is very
unlikely there's no way to get the
traffic to the victim to preserve
connectivity so this is a very
noticeable attack somehow they still go
unnoticed but from a networking point of
view it's quite easy to detect these now
there's a black hat talk and 2015 that
looked at a slightly more stealthy
variant and notice that I moved the
certificate authority from up here to a
little bit closer to the adversary and
that's because if the adversary
announces an equal length prefix so this
is the same slash 23 prefix size as the
victim what they'll do is the thoughts
they split Internet traffic in half
so a s is that are closer to the
adversary will prefer the adversaries
announcement and a s is closer to the
victim will continue to route to the
true victim so if your certificate
authority happens to be in your part of
the internet once again you can get the
certificate because it's in this
affected region that's going to get
routed to that or adversary and this
increases stealthiness by a lot because
a s is up here not only will they not
take this announcement they won't even
hear the announcement it will never even
propagate to them so you can imagine
trying to evade monitoring framework
evade the certificate authority from
really noticing what real users still
going to the website you get a lot more
stealthiness with this attack but in my
opinion the primary limitation here is
that some adversaries just can't do it
and this is important to know because I
think the adversarial model that we
should consider is an adversary that's
really one fixed compromised a s they
don't really get to choose where on the
internet they launch these attacks from
and if you're kind of at the bottom of
the internet far away from a lot of
certificate authorities this attack is
pretty much useless to you you're never
going to capture enough traffic to get
the certificate so that brings me to the
attack that our works been focusing on
and that's this sub prefix interception
attack so the idea behind this is that
we go and we announce some more
like prefix just like we did before but
excited instead of taking ownership of
the prefix we actually announce our
legitimate route to get to that prefix
so we're just saying we can get to it
through a s floor so to all these other
routers this is a more specific
announcement meaning that's going to be
preferred over the more general one
however as4 in order to stop from
importing a route that would have a loop
it's going to see that it has its own
ass number in this announcement and as
result is not going to import it so to
as4 the proper route to - - - - it's
still the slash 23 that the victim
announced so as an adversary all you
have to do is put a forwarding rule in
to say well if it's not from the
certificate authority I'm just going to
forward it to the victim but if it is
I'm going to answer it and get the
certificate so this is somewhat less
stealthy at a control plane level but I
would argue the data plane is more
important and this has complete
stealthiness as a data plane level as
you'll see in a moment and once you
perform this attack and you get the
certificate you're already routing the
entire internet through you so perfect
time to start using the certificate to
intercept connections so what I want to
do next is I want to show you how we
actually perform these attacks and some
some opening remarks before we do this
we control everything pretty much the
only real entity involved is let's
encrypt the certificate authority and
it's real backbone routers that are
making these announcements thanks to the
peering framework in a very ethical way
compliant with their guidelines but this
is a real website out on the real
Internet so as long as things go right
um I just want to show my demo setup
here it's really small but this is an
HTTP web page for DC t2g ttk and it has
the lock so it's browser trusted secured
and it's also running an ajax script
going over HTTP as well it's continually
phoning home to the server and
descending potentially secret data so
this is an innocuous client that we
didn't introduce in the last frame and
here I have some command terminals up
for various entities here this is the
victim's terminal in blue and this is by
the way the victims in a network in Los
Angeles
and we're just going to start packet
sniffing on this so if you look we're
listening to the packets and you can see
them coming in as the Ajax calls are
going on the two terminals down here are
from the adversary server and it's going
to make its announcements from Amsterdam
so really all the way across the world
and we're going to start packet sniffing
on that note packets because the
adversary hasn't made any announcements
and by the way if there any questions
about the live demo feel free to
interrupt me I want this to be sort of
responsive and part of the Q&A time and
so right now the adversaries not hearing
anything and that makes sense
so one more step before the adversary is
going to go on and that's what they're
going to ask let's encrypt for a
certificate okay I'll just make sure I
type that sorry I had these pre type of
them use the right letter well thank you
hopefully it works so let's hold the
applause okay whether that IP address
logging you can actually you perform
this action from any IP address so the
final piece of the setup is to get this
document right here
that's the verification document we have
to upload to the web server so I'm just
going to copy that
take it out to another terminal I have
opened on the adversary and just put
that up on their web server should okay
okay so from the adversaries point of
view right now it's totally ready and
all I'm going to do now is make the
arousing announcement so watch closely
as a traffic from up here if it works
starts being seen down there as well
okay we configured correctly and there
we go so what's happening here is that
this is an interception attack by the
way this is an interception attack so
the victims still getting traffic and
this traffic looks exactly the same as
before we launch the attack same source
IPS and everything but the traffic's now
going through the adversary too and if
you look closely at this packet trace
every packets doubled up twice and
that's because the adversary sees it
once on the way in and where TCP dumps
located sees it again on the way out so
that's how we know that we're
intercepting traffic but there's a rule
in the adversaries route table so that
if we hear traffic from let's encrypt
which until hopefully in a couple months
just uses one fixed IP to do all their
verification it's going to perform the
verification so we wait for this just
one moment and there we go we get
congratulated for getting a fake
certificate and the victim so far has
seen completely nothing to them this is
just normal traffic going on going about
their day and now all that we're going
to do is actually use the fake
certificate to be in intercepting
traffic okay so now watch the webserver
output and this is pretty much just
going to restart the adversary's web
server let it start using the
certificate and there we go so what's
happened here is that the traffic was
always going through the adversary ever
since I made the announcement but now
that we got the certificate the
adversary can authoritative Lee answer
that traffic it can really pretend to be
the webserver and as a result these Ajax
calls are no longer being answered by
the victim you can see it's packet log
is pretty much dried up and they're
actually all going to the adversary
instead but to the browser this is still
a totally secure connection you can see
the lock up there and if we reload the
page we now got it copy from the
adversary and so it just changed
certificates the browser was looking at
let's encrypt
I used let's encrypt for both the
certificates they're really convenient
but it was looking at let's encrypt
certificates before but looking at a
certificate before with one private key
I mean one public key and then we just
decided to change public keys on it we
didn't provide any explanation but
thanks to the partial implementation
status of certificate pinning browsers
will accept this and they really don't
care even though it just saw a different
public key in the same browsing session
yeah Oh a buddy you might see some
packets going in on this trace that's
because the nature of the interception
attack as you remember from before some
assr still routing to the real victim so
it's not going to completely disappear
so fortunately that actually launched
and now we perform similar attacks we
actually went through and performed all
three of the types of attacks I
mentioned before and we looked at five
of the major CAS in the industry right
now and there really is no difference
they even though less encrypts the only
one that overtly automates it
none of them require human interaction
they're all going to sign your
certificate really quickly and they're
all vulnerable to this attack none of
them are using multiple vantage points
yet so let's encrypt could be the first
yeah and in terms of countermeasures
this is the main focus of our ongoing
work we like to look at this problem at
the certificate authority level just
because there are way fewer of them
still a lot but way fewer then trying to
get adaptation of something by websites
or clients and we want to first force
announcements to be totally globally
visible so no more local announcements
and this can be done by having multiple
dispersed vantage points and forces the
adversary pretty much to announce a more
specific prefix and that makes their
announcement really easy to see by
network operators so first we make the
announcement visible and then we want to
actually give the network operators time
to respond
currently BGP hijacks are handled sorted
by social connections you know you wake
up you notice there's a hijack you call
somebody who calls somebody who calls
somebody so we need time for that
process to happen and that's why we
advise that certificate authorities
implement
bgp monitoring and only use routes that
have been announced for longer than a
threshold value and we're running false
positives and heuristics on that and
trying to integrate with let's encrypt
in semantics to try to get their
infrastructure to help us out and we're
also have developed part of an open
source solution we're looking to further
that so I guess takeaways if you're
going to remember this digital
certificates are the foundation of our
secure internet communications but yet
there are over fifty thousand BGP
speaking routers and pretty much almost
any of them can perform one of these
attacks to get a digital certificate for
you
it happens in seconds CAS will sign your
certificate immediately and then you can
start intercepting connections from that
moment before certificate transparency
logs even notice the certificate and we
think that this is sort of a call to
action to CAS to implement
countermeasures and not just think about
implementing countermeasures and also I
think important notice don't forget
about routing security like we think
we're secure because we're putting
pushing security up the stock to the
application layer but sometimes these
application layer protocols are really
not secured unless we have secure
routing so don't forget about BGP SEC
and yeah I guess I'll open the floor to
questions
[Applause]