next up we have she's brought me in
systemization
security and reliability of normal
memories in particular she will be Auto
market this University's three-piece
with her this will be talking about
security media in whole paper so hello
everyone my name is Prada and as dr.
material says that I'm going to
introduce you a new secure data
generation scheme for solid-state drives
or SSDs this facility outside of my talk
and I'm going to start with an
introduction on why we are focusing on
SSDs
as a German you may know excesses are
becoming the dominant storage system in
many computer devices as from very small
like you nor small devices like a
smartphone to very large data centers
mainly because they are very high they
have higher storage density than hard
disk drives they have a better energy
consumption they have better access
latency but the thing is it has this
unique property of remappable right
which can be considered as an security
or privacy threat this minimal right
property creates a trail of the previous
version of data which we call them
invalid data so let's see how this
invalid data can be afraid
continuous receive attack in which the
user has to disclose both key and the
data to the attacker
what is the data on the facility data
analysis it can be includes
valid and invalid data while user access
in a validator the invalid data is not
he is not aware of the existence of the
invalid data which can be a privacy
trick so the best advanced approaches is
strategy would be that the SSD vendor
has to provide secure duration and
scheme and give this ability to the user
to trigger this scheme to make sure that
it invalid data
from the disk now let's see how this
invalid data actually created on
assistance if it has two basic
operations of write and erase which
write is going to change 1 to 0 while
array is going to change 0 to 1 this can
make a problem when the array is done at
the granularity of block 1 take write
are done as a granular G of pages so for
example if I have this kind of data on
my SSD and for example I want to update
something on blood 0 I have to copy
everything else number then erase the
block and then copy everything back to
the block 0 as well as a new version of
the data which means that it's going to
become very time consuming and energy
consuming so what a proposes they say
that why not often do update data for
its meaning that when the update King
they have to first write a new version
into someplace new and then invalidate
the old version invalidating the old
version does not mean deleting the old
version means that the data is still a
necessity but it is not accessible
accessible through user interface so
let's see when this invalidate actually
deleted from SSD there is this garbage
collection property procedure on SSD
which is in charge of the internet
deleting all the invalid data what's
basically garbage collection do this
when the it's selected block it's not
coffee every valid pages to someplace
else in the city and then irate the
whole block although this is actually
there in other states but it might be
too late from Project privacy
perspective because the purpose of doing
garbage collection is to empty new block
for me opening the risk of I mean
request so our goal here is that you
want to securely delete all the invalid
pages at user requests not whenever the
discourses and then we want to make sure
that valid data is still accessible to
the user and detect that the actual goal
is that we want to minimize the cost of
this operation remember in the previous
slides when you want to do the
garbage collection we have to move all
the invalid data which is going to be
the migration of the value data across
census and then we have to erase
something here we have a K in our K
integer which is going to show that my
array is much more costly than migration
pregnant morgana agency usually can be
categorized into three groups the first
one of Sanitation which basically they
are like trying to arrange everything
they don't care if the data is valid or
invalid they just erase everything and
just make sure that nothing is on the
SSD anymore which is far from God what
is our code the next the type of group
called scrubbing they what they do is
they target invalid pages but what they
are trying to physically reprogram that
page using because if you remember what
changes want to zero so they are saying
that why not changing the rest of one's
in the page to zero so this page is not
readily access all but the point is
there is this program mister protect
innocence which means if you do such a
thing
the various neighboring data may not be
accessible anymore and the lack of words
are trying to encrypt files delete a key
and then taking that the data is not
there anymore but the problem is with
this kind of approach you are not able
to do it invalid pages you are only able
to delete a valid data of a file so what
we are going to propose and I'm going to
start with a motivated example let's see
if we have such data on RSS feed and
very really the solution is that by not
erasing just abort that containing
invalid pages with doing so we have to
first migrate all the valid data which
is going to this 14 migration in this
case and then erase all the books that
contain invalid pages it is going to be
quite costly didn't approach that came
to my mind is that why not encrypting
data and then deleting the keys pair of
invalid pages if I want to store one
keeper each page over head is going to
be a lot so why not group pages together
in this case we group the page
at the same position in the world
together and increase all these pages
with one chip so for example in this
case you only need inches for all of our
data so now if I want to delete an
invalid page I have to erase the key but
you see here we have the invalid pages
and validated sharing one tea if I can't
do this
erase the key advantages are not going
to be accessed at all so I have to first
migrate those valid pages which is going
to be first I have to decrypt it with
the Alt key increasingly the nuclear and
write it back into someplace else and I
have to do this for all the invalid
pages and then I have to be able to
erase those key because the data the
valid data or is still accessible in
this case is still active in migration
and one rate which is not good enough so
I thought why not
combining these two together and the
copies scheme eraser corrector in this
scheme we are saying that let's first
start choosing which blocks to e-rate
and which keys to do it for example in
our probe in our example we are using if
you are choosing the first law to for
the erasure based scheme meaning that
the Orgel are going to migrate the valid
pages and then erase it and then when we
have to only delete the kids for two or
not off the road so we have to do
deleting the keyboard cheat Row 3 and
rule 7 and then we have to write back
the key into the place which is going to
be tree migration and to erase which is
quite better than the other two okay the
question is in this kind of scheme you
have to make sure you select the best
combination of blocks and kids for a
razor and deletion what we did first we
try to formalize our problem we say that
okay let's come convert this solution to
a matrix of the status and then say that
okay invalid pages are shown with one
and
very stages are shown with zero then I
said okay I'll have two other vectors
this the first one is the D plus it
showed that whether the plot is chosen
for erasure or not and the second one is
the group which means that if the group
is selected for its G to be deleted or
not
so our constraint if you remember our
constraint which was releasing and all
the invited stages can be translated to
this in the sense of the page is the one
which is invalid either its group or
block should be selected for delay
secure deletion and then the code can be
translated into this meaning that
migration is that if the set of lock is
0 you have them if one of its group or
block is selected for a secure deletion
meaning that you have to do a migration
and for original simply you have to
count a number of ones in the in the
vector D block so Indian program is
going to be really complicated so what
we taught us we are not changing it to a
very well-known problem of maximum h bar
click in bipartite graph and for those
who may not know what is this problem is
that if you have this bipartite graph
and if you want to create a bike week
out of it you have to remove the some
deep black vertices and these edges to
make sure that the remaining graph in
the remaining gas each emergencies in
one set is connected to all the vertices
in the other set so here by our matrix
what we do is what we did is said okay
let's have one record for each group in
one set and have one vertices for each
block in the other set and then we
connect each node each no together if
the if you have a valid page we are
going to connect it through to is the
block and I have to do the same thing
for everything and you remember we have
this K vector in our equation to
implement this case I grant
consider it here we are going to add a
extra group to both our matrix and our
graph here I for the sake of
simplification as I choose k equals 1
and but later in the result I'm going to
change this so now you can see that this
is can if you find a bike maximum by
click must respect my problem in this
the remaining nodes are going to want
that we can choose for selecting for
erasing or deleting which is going to be
the same as the one that I show you in
the example hopefully this is a
well-known problem and it has this
although it isn't unconscious to a
problem if there isn't a heuristic
solution to this problem let's go to our
results I implemented all these skins in
disk simpler and definitely modal
provided by Microsoft we use the
Microsoft we abort races that they
collected folder from their service and
then I what I did is we try to compare
this desert to ordered me to intuitive
resolution the third one is our proposal
scheme and the last one is the optimal
because it's IFE and now let's see I
have no chance to be second because the
latency of a rate divided by the latency
of migration is almost 7 and then as you
can see if it gets a very close to
optimal result here and as always shows
that the this algorithm works well this
cop actually can be translated into
migration and erase and let's see what
happened in the micro there's also
migration and irate I provided these two
graphs for you and as you can see
arranger base always has the border
a erase because it's so it just erases
the block and then we have the
cryptographic base it has the lowest
number of rays because it's only erases
the keyboard it doesn't need to erase
the valid pages inviting pages and then
as we can see that the number of
migration depends on the distribution of
their value pages in some some of our
benchmarks the distribution of magic
pages or or vegetation or disciplines
like somehow gather in block what in
others are gathered in groups so it
depends on the benchmark is and have
different the value for the tool skins
but for us is always getting the best
results and now if I want to translate
these two actually through energy and
latency you can see that we can get 36%
of energy reduction and 65% of latency
reduction to summarize what I did is
that we try to address this situation
problem in assistive while other is the
approach was costly or either they lose
them the validator we were able to
resolve this issue and ago what to still
cheat the validator and minimize the
cost and we be compounded through basic
solution together convert it to a well
known problem and then you can see that
the achieved in near optimal results and
thank you for listening
you