touken video see that was such on
photography Sakura start we have four
very exciting panel today in Seoul six
regions burner are protecting memory
access projects to secure community data
information leaks year GPUs as well for
anybody with an ability for first first
up we have dr. Patrick social is second
eighty students at Cornell and he got me
interested in photography
cryptocurrencies and hope man maybe
he'll give us externally verifiable
obliviously all right thank you I'm
Joshua so today I'm talking about a new
security notes notion for oblivious RAM
this work is done in collaboration with
my collaborators Adam curves and ours
ledger so today people put a lot of
private data on the cloud of course we
don't always trust the cloud so we have
to have some way it pretends no data so
what we do of course is we encrypt our
data files however as we have seen
earlier today this is not always perfect
because the cloud can still learn about
the indices of our data into the
database forming these things which we
call access patterns to see why this is
dangerous just to recap cancer days to
access patterns seen here on the top
access pattern the user accesses data
files number one two three four five six
which is consistent with a linear scan
of the data on the bottom instead the
user accesses data files to eight to
eight to eight which is not consistent
with a linear scan just shows that if
the server can see the excess pattern of
the data that server can infer what kind
of algorithm you're using on the data
which in turn reveals a lot of semantic
content if instead we can obfuscate the
access patterns of our data the server
has a lot less information now the
server only basically knows how much
data we have and how often we access it
which is a lot less information
fortunately there is a standard
cryptographic technique for achieving
this which is called oblivious rap here
is an abstract diagram of the oblivious
Ram protocol
on the left we have the user interface
in with the oblivious RAM protocol the
user gives us input n which is the index
for so this is for each axis so unless
the user gives their index n which is
the index in the database they which to
access the user also gives this data
block interesting in black which is the
data block that they wish to write to
the database each access on the volume
of the of the protocol for the users
output these are to get this block seen
here in blue which by the security of
the or M protocol is the true and this
data block on the right we have the
server just interfacing back and forth
of the protocol exchanging seemingly
random data blocks and the security
Doerun protocol the server learns
nothing about the actual index of any of
these data blocks we focus on this work
on to modern web schemes path and Ringo
Ram for certain use cases they're
definitely efficient enough to use in
practice both schemes give about a log
in bandwidth blow-up in the worst case
so basically now we've solved the issue
of data confidentiality however note
that integrity of this data is still
problem the OEM protocol basically just
moves round data blocks but has no
protections about one of the not these
data blocks are correct to the user
fortunately modern protocols are known
to be compatible with standard
techniques the standard technique of
Merkle trees which is which is we can
use because the ERM protocols has this
natural binary tree structure to the
data here the user stores a small
constant information which called the
root and the outlet to the user is not
only the end of state of lock but also a
new root prime along with this small log
and size proof
indeed the user can run this algorithm
which we call check proofs which given
the old root the new root any data that
was given to the protocol any data given
back to the user as well with this check
mark the this algorithm will return a
boolean this boolean is true
when integrity is preserved which means
that this new route is we of course want
to a sound update of the database given
the old route and this proof crucially
this check proof function is only a
protocol it's only a function of the OEM
transcript which by the security of the
OEM protocol reveals no private
information about the users data what
this means is that if a third party has
access to the transcript the third party
can actually validate this proof itself
which means that you have some kind of
simple transfer ability about this proof
that's now we are solved basically both
data confidentiality and data integrity
however we have not yet addressed data
availability this protocol as it is does
not say anything about what happens if
the server goes offline and this is what
we we try to answer this question is
what we try to answer our work what
guarantees can we give to data
availability while preserving or RAM
security using our protocol first let's
define what a fail build means for a
server to become unavailable it means
that it's unable to follow a correct
attribution of the protocol note that
this covers both non-response and also
data loss because we consider checking
integrity of the data as part of the
correct execution of the protocol now if
the server goes offline we can't
actually force the server to come off to
come back online obviously so what we do
is the next best thing what we trying to
do is compel the server to give a
compensation to the client in return for
a lapse in availability this
compensation will come this repercussion
will come from some kind of other
financial agent who has some kind of
financial leverage over the server
however this financial agent cannot
trust the client to witness availability
otherwise almost just client could abuse
this trust for gain so what we do
instead is how the client prove
availability loss to the financial agent
which we call this external verifier
what that will happen is that verify
will check the proof given to them by
the client and if it is good they may
then just Lee penalize the server
note that by the way that this proof
must be interactive
because the verifier must be able to
witness non-responsive the cough the
server note also that this external
verifier is mostly acting as a deterrent
from his behavior from the server we
expect this proof to only happen in the
event of actual availability lapse
otherwise the protocol should be to
proceed just as before so now we can
sketch what our protocol will look like
in the average case the optimistic case
exactly as before except the protocol
will proceed exactly as before except
with a few checkpoint signatures which
are exchanged east access between the
client and the server these checkpoint
signatures serve as agreements between
the client and server over the state of
the database what actually happens is
that the signature will basically be the
Merkle tree root along with a counter
which will enforce data freshness in the
event of an availability lapse the
client will then solve the ordinary
execution of the protocol the client and
server then will revert state to the
most recent state agreed to by these
secular signatures now what happens is
the client initiates a verified access
of the protocol in this protocol mode
the client and server will route the
entire protocol through the verifier
while blinded the actual data was a
verifier down with access to is the OEM
transcript along with these checkpoint
signatures seam here and here using the
transcript the very product can then
check semantic correctness of the
protocol both for the client and the
server recall before that integrity
checking can be done by third party if
they have access to the transcript and
although these checkpoint signatures can
be seen to be easily publicly verifiable
at any party while running the around
transcript or a protocol violates any
semantic correctness properties or times
out the verifier now can count this as a
failure of that party and the end of the
access the verify of it either okay
cheat s or cheat c GS means that the
misbehavior of the server has been
detected by the verifier similarly TC
means that the client has somehow
misbehaved
of course what we want is that if the
client is honest and the server has
experience with sort of failure the
verifiable alpha cheetahs similarly if
the server is honest and the client is
defies the very travel achieves see
recall it's this might happen because we
want to protect the server in the case
of the client is malicious otherwise the
very private law could okay this can
generally happen if there's a failure
which the client detects but it is too
short to be picked up by the verifier in
a nutshell our security claim or sort of
the requirement for the protocol is that
security holds whenever a malicious
client cannot force cheat s and
similarly for the server a malicious
server cannot force cheat C to happen
this security definition is formalized
in our paper as an ideal functionality
cryptographic ideal functionality this
set of properties here is collectively
what we call external data file 'ti note
however that this verifier is trusted
for correctness but not secret e what
this means is that the security must if
the verifier is correct the security
definition will hold but maybe not at
the Securities Inc is the verifiers
incorrect however the OEM transcript can
be trusted to be completely public which
means that the verifier doesn't actually
need to hold any secret state in our
paper we give the security definition
for externally verifiable Oh Ram called
Evo Ram we get even your extensions to
both pass entering o Ram and along the
way we also give a novel integrity
checking scheme for ring o Ram this is
subtle because ring o Ram does not
strictly adhere to this binary tree
structure which I alluded to earlier now
we can talk about implementation in our
implementation the interesting thing
here is that the verifier can actually
be implemented as in a theory in the
smart contract which moves the protocol
back from a three person protocol to a
two person protocol effectively so I
will talk about how that happens
atheria massively distributed consensus
protocol which meant maintains a notion
of currency as in Bitcoin but also
maintains a notion of smart contracts so
our contracts are essentially programs
which are executed as part of the
contentious protocol by the security of
the consensus protocol we get that these
programs can be trusted to be executed
correctly here is just a small schematic
of what means to be a smart contract
over here we have an end-user
interfacing with a smart contract which
is collectively executed by all the
members of the etherium blockchain since
this smart contract is collectively
executed by all of these members it must
be that the contract must have some kind
of public state there's no secret state
that this contract can have this
contract in addition to performing
arbitrary computations can also hold and
manipulate the currency maintained by
etherium itself so that we this is why
we actually call it a contract because
that can actually enforce some kind of
financial capabilities additionally
assuming that the etherion blockchain is
still running and that you connect can
connect to it you can assume that these
contracts are available there's no
reason that these contracts would time
out if the etherion blockchain is
running is normal
of course the punchline here is that
these four properties are exactly the
same programming model as our verifier
which means that the are verified access
as talked about before can actually run
where the verifier is itself a smart
contract on the etherion blockchain now
we'll talk a little bit about
implementation we have meant our client
and server code for the overrun Protocol
locally as well as the verifier is about
dreams of lines of solidity which is the
scripting language for aetherium smart
contracts the bottlenecks for these
kinds of systems is of course caused by
the blockchain itself
oh the time for ejected so what happens
in the etherion Network is that there's
this notion of time club blocks which
are admitted once every 15 seconds
whenever I send a message to the boxing
this message actually has to wait for
the next block to attach itself to these
books are come very slowly which means
that there's actually a wild Legion see
in these kind of systems our protocol
has six messages total which means that
if each message is taking about every
ten or twenty seconds that I can run for
maybe a minute and a half which is not
very good another issue with smart
contracts is that contracts yes no
another issues small contracts is that
they cost currency for themselves to
execute as of when you wrote the paper
for a simulated tender by database
access it only cost 33 cents for this
contract execute however as I theory
became more valuable over time this
price actually skyrocketed to 15 dollars
which is less than practical what the
showing that those capabilities well
this is an interesting idea its
capability of smart contract systems is
still a major open area now I'll just
wrap up by mentioning a few for the
directions what we essentially do in
this paper is extendo Ram by adding a
minimal amount of information which we
call an audit trail which can be
verifiably which can be externally
verified by a third party
of course this methodology can probably
be extended to other protocols such as
secure multi-party computation or
protocols of outsourced computation and
so on another thing we talk about
another thing which would be interesting
for the research is more efficient use
of these smart contracts quick
conventional crypto papers don't really
talk about the case where we have a very
very limited execution environment as
advent of smart contract which it brings
up introduced interesting notions about
computation cost and also around
complexity
so if you're just in this work I invite
you to look at my look at my code here
and see if there's anything you would
like to see it I would note that this
might be interesting to you if you're
interested in spark contract programming
in general not just oh rap stuff because
there's a lot in here that you could
learn just with the smart contracts than
generally thank you
[Applause]