suppose of continuing from today and
talk about Crusaders
thank you for introduction the good news
is it's the last part of this session so
we can take a break after all today I'm
gonna talk about our recent funding
recent findings on how to perform secure
civil matching at real-world skills
this is joint work with my adviser
professor couch on fire and profits or
start early and shiner from two
Darmstadt dr. somewhere is also an
alumni from a group who currently works
in Google this is the outline of my
presentation first I'm going to talk
about what is a stable matching followed
by a visual example then I will talk
about why we need privacy in this task
then I will talk about the OHS garble
circuit vertical which we have utilized
in our solution and the majority of my
talk is dedicated to our two main
contributions and the first one is
helping your site circuit and the next
one is thirdly termination technique I
will compare the complexity of our
computation with rewards and we have
done extensive experimental results
which I've provided you so a stable
matching is the process of assigning the
members of two groups to each other one
by one where each person has the
preference list this preference list
shows how person values each person of
the other group the assignment should
satisfy one condition and that the
assignment
there should be no pair such that they
prefer each other over than they are the
assigned partners stable matching is
used in many applications for example in
national resiliency matching program
where a group of medical students are
matched to residency programs civil
matching is also used in capital markets
to sign consumers and suppliers
so it more fun to describe to matching
the context of marriage so on the
left-hand side you have group of boys
and on the right-hand side you have a
group of girls
of course this where each person has a
preference list so if we assign the
member of these two verbs to each other
in this order it is not a civil match
because of this link as you can see
Alice prefers Ryan over jack
they're already assigned partner based
on the preference list and also Ryan
prefers Alice over sir he's currently
sign partner so this is not a stable
match however if you assign them in this
order and there is no such pair that
violates the condition and therefore
just tourists able match in the secure
stable night setting we want to perform
stable matching without revealing each
party's preferences to any other part so
why is it important picked either
multiple answers first there are
multiple studies that show that if
assert if an individual knows the
preferences of other people he or she
can manipulate the outcome in her favor
by changing his own preference list
second in some scenarios the data is
confidential by law so we need to
respect that and the third reason is
that of course privacy no one likes to
feel he or she wasn't their first choice
we have used a yellowjacket protocol the
GC protocol is a classic two-party
secure function evaluation method
introduced by Andrea in 1986 at a very
high level GC emulates a trusted third
party to which two parties three to
which two parties can give their inputs
and receive the results however this is
a conceptual description and reality
there is no third party and the particle
is run between two parties only a very
simplified explanation of the GC
protocol is a so it has three main
phases in the first phase Bob has to
describe the functionality as a
we inserted between put cakes so here
the functionality would be the stable
matching algorithm next he will assign
random keys to each wire in the circuit
and for each gate he increased the
output wire using inputs were keys and
forms called garbled tables in the
second phase Alice received all garbled
tables together with the keys
corresponding to her input and in the
third phase Alice's start decrypting
each gate one by one until she reaches
that true output result of the
computation random access is a very
costly operation in GC because at the
same time we need to hide the access
pattern the address and the data the
basic solution is to put a multiplexer
inside the circuit that accesses each
flip-flop and the control signals
amongst would be the addressed output
would be the data that we want but since
in GC we cannot escape garbling and
evaluating any gates the access code for
single access is linear in terms of the
number of gates or simply the memory
size which is very costly the more
complex but more efficient solution
oblivious ram which has the best one has
logarithmic axis complexity but due to
the high initialization cost of the or M
it doesn't out there for months up to a
certain point so this is mirror size and
this is the access code this is the
global flow of our end-to-end system it
starts with describing a functionality
as a boolean circuit so we have written
the dual matching algorithm in very
large and hardware description language
then we have said that into a hardware
synthesis tool to get the necklace then
we topologically sort in athletes to
avoid any deadlock and at the end we
have a sorted nathless of the function
this is an input to the GC protocol that
is run by two servers one acting has
gurgler and
acting as evaluators these stages here
are offline and they have to performed
only once and these building blocks here
are the description of the GC portico
that I discussed before garbling
communication evaluating and merging the
results so each party that want to want
to participate in this table matching
has to send two different encryptions
which is the exhaust share of their
inputs preference leads to two servers
then two servers run the GC protocol
using these sorted methods and at the
end they merge the results who outputs
this table matchless Gail she plays the
other is an algorithm for finding the
stable match as you can see it's a
iterative algorithm and at each
iteration a free man who is not already
assigned to in partner what so called
proposes to a woman that he prefers the
most but he has not yet proposed to and
the algorithm continues until the match
list is a stable in the worst case
scenario we need to run this loop for n
s squared because it has the N squared
complexity but here finding a free man
is not trivial in the GC protocol
because we need to linearly scan all the
memories to find a free one so here we
have a specific module in the circuit to
perform this task which I'll describe
later as I mentioned the worst case
scenario for the algorithm is n s
squared but due to the invalid proposals
and that we have in the GC protocol we
actually have even worse than worst
mathematical worst case of the algorithm
when run in the GC protocol we have also
done some is that it's a statistical
analysis on the average number of
proposals and as you can see it is
scales linearly instead of n s squared
with the number of participants or sub
sites
this is the traumatic view of our
sub-linear sign circuit the sublunary is
with respect to the number of
participants in each group I'll describe
each building block in more detail
so this sub module acts as a control
flow of the whole circuit and it
basically implements the majority of the
code in the soul matching algorithm this
circuit finds the freemen in the
previous life cycle and fit it to the
ACC address combinational circuit and
this part of the circuit is memory which
can be implemented either as monks or
Orem and as I talked before to in order
to avoid invaluable puzzles we have
introduced a technique which is called
hair determination that finds whether a
match at least is a stable or not
because in regular execution everything
in the GC portable is garbled so we
cannot really tell if the masculine is
stable at this time or not but using
this protocol we can reveal one piece of
information at each clock cycle and see
if the match is disabled or not of
course this is not free it comes at the
cost of revealing the total number of
purple cells needed to reach a stable
match and it's an optional module that
we can use or avoid so easy T can be
used in any iterative based algorithms
for example it's using camp appeal which
is a secure spreadsheet company and they
have used our technique in their
security products as they have announced
in the security model so depending on
which type of program used in the
circuit you get different complexities
the vertical bar showed different kind
of warrant and the horizontal bar shows
different variants of stable matching we
have linear Orland or M which is
basically using monks school route or M
and circuit work and for the horizontal
board we have general stable matching
general matching plus ccTLD termination
technique
and limited civil magic the limited
stable matching is when the preference
list for this person is limited to a
constant number like 20 whereas we can
have like thousand people in set size
and as you can see a linear or M is
better up to a certain point and both
for MS after which a square root a
square root or M comes in and out
performs months up to certain points
which is around 4000 people after that
circuit where I performed all of the
solutions here is the complexity
comparison with very work the first
solution had the total computation
complexity and communication with n to
power 5 which is very to use during time
it's reduced to 2 down to nsns squared
like 3 and as you can see our work
together with killer it's all solution
and have the best asymptotic complexity
it's important to note that the majority
of operation are socially symmetric key
encryption whereas the initial solutions
are public key based which are for more
extensive so here's the experimental
results for different sizes and
different worn scheme the upper table
shows the result for regular execution
the down table shows the result when
using error determination for
experiments with that took more than few
hours we use our cost function to get
the result
I know these numbers may sound
astronomical but this is due to the
hardness of this problem
for example comparing to killer it's all
solution for set size of 8,000 people
they report 10 to power 12 second
execution time estimated so which is
equivalent to forty seven thousand years
and what we need a slightly more than a
day to compute is functionality
comparing to the original paper for
square root or M they have delayed three
hours execution time for set size of 512
same scenario where we have eight hours
of execution time without using Itt
slightly I mean close to five minutes
education time when using Itt
concurrent a concurrent work that was
published in CCS 2016 they introduced
oblivious link list and they report for
the eight minute execution time versus
same set size and scenario which is less
than our regular execution but more than
our execution with PTT so in conclusion
we have a study the program secure
stable matching and in particular we
have introduced a sub linear side
circuit for this time for this time for
first time and also we have introduced
early termination technique which can
significantly reduce the execution time
of the GC protocol for any iterative
based algorithms and has already been
adapted in security for them thank you
very much and I have to answer English
[Applause]