okay we're going to rig the next speaker
who is mark juarez from cage 11 and
aptly he's going to talk to us about
website fingerprinting defenses at the
application layer thank you thank you so
good morning everyone I'm going to
present a joint work with Giovanni
Kerwin who you already know from real
holloway Jamie Hayes from UCL and myself
and this is work on defenses against
website fingerprinting
so as Giovanni already explained what's
the fingerprinting is an attack that
allows an adversary that is sitting
between the user and the entry guard and
looking at this traffic to identify the
pages that users are browsing through
tor even though the traffic has been
encrypted and anonymized by tor the main
intuition behind the attack is that
pages are very different to each other
so they have different images different
text and all these differences can be
observed in the traffic and this is the
side channel that the attacker exploits
so so in particular in this paper we
focus on hidden services these are
websites that can only be accessed
through tor and users can visit them
without having to resolve the domain
name to an IP which makes them very
suitable to a host sensitive content
because they cannot be located
geographically or it's very hard here we
see some examples of hidden services I
won't get into my detail on how the
protocol works but you need to know that
it's very different with respect to the
protocol that tor users to browse
regular sites so no normally tor builds
three hop circuits and actually for
hidden services they are six hop but
there are other differences and in 2015
a paper by Khan and others shown that
these differences can also be observed
in the traffic and can be used to
distinguish visits to regulars
from hidden services so this is very
threatening for website fingerprinting
hidden services because an adversary
that wants to fingerprint the hidden
service can filter out all the visits to
the other sides and then the world
becomes much smaller
there are many less many fewer hidden
services and there does potentially more
identifiable and on top of that they are
as I already said they are more likely
to host sensitive content and this means
that users that visit these hidden
services may face more serious
consequences if they are if the attack
is successful so we that's why we
decided to focus on hidden services so
defenses how do we protect against visit
duck so there have been already some
defenses that have been proposed in the
literature we can see you can see some
of the names on the slide and the main
primitive they use to defend is to
generate dummy packets fake fake packets
or messages that are mixed with real
traffic to perturb the features that the
attacker exploits and for this to be
effective the dummy messages have to be
indistinguishable from real messages and
the padding should run at least one hop
further than what the adversity can see
these defenses were theoretical and they
were designed in the network layer so
these messages the fake messages are
actually TCP packets and for this reason
they require control over how TCP
generates these packets and the timing
of these packets which is very difficult
to implement in practice so this brings
me to the main the key point of the
paper which is that we propose to design
the defenses at the application layer we
argue that it's as effective as doing it
at the network layer because if you can
conceal the features at the application
layer which is where the identifying
information of the
Paige is found then the patterns will
follow down the stack and they will
still be concealed although also the
network layer so if you think about it
if you have two identical pages at the
application layer they have the same
images the same content they should be
also indistinguishable at the network
layer right and this has some advantages
so the main advantage is that they so
they are much easier to deploy the
application layer defenses you don't
require you don't depend on tort to
implement them they built on top of door
and also come with some disadvantages
for example the padding has to run
end-to-end as opposed to network layer
defenses where the padding was dropped
at the entry or the middle and depending
on how they are designed they may
require server collaboration but this is
not a problem for us because since we
are taking the case of hidden services
we assume that hidden services are
interested in providing privacy to their
visitors so they probably have
incentives to support these defenses so
let me introduce you to two defenses
that we have developed and evaluated to
explore the space of application layer
defenses so the first one is llama
it's a client-side defense implemented
as a Firefox add-on for the tor browser
it's a it applies on so the operation is
on the HTTP requests and if that's more
delay it's focused on adding delays and
as you see this is what I meant by they
don't depend on tour because I user the
ones to get the benefits of this defense
can just install the add-on on the tor
browser and that's all
then alpaca is a server-side defense
it's actually the first server-side
defense that has been developed and
evaluated against website fingerprinting
and it's applied on the actual files in
the server so we implement that this is
a script that we crawl the files in the
server and apply the padding on on these
files and
and like the service operator can just
run the script doesn't depend on Thor
and just to clarify this is not that
client-server solution these are two
independent solutions that can run Stan
standalone and this is how we evaluated
them so I will explain alpaca first
alpaca defines the page as a set of
objects so the only important features
since the contents are encrypted the
only important features are the number
of objects and the sizes of the obvious
objects and the protection strategy is
to given a original page and a target
page it will part the objects in the
original page to match the objects in
size and number of objects in the target
page so we didn't want to impact digital
experience we wanted the pages to the
user not to see any difference in the
page when it's presented to him so we
came up with some tricks to do that so
for example we added random the padding
at random strings in the comments of as
comments in the HTML of the page or we
added the random strings in the metadata
of the images and also we had fake
objects we would use the hidden CSS
style in the HTML so the padding is
still sent over the wire but the user
doesn't know this so how to define this
target page so there are two ways this
can be done so first when this target
page exists so in this case you want if
you want to protect secure drop you and
you want to annotate pages Facebook you
good path
alpaca would arrange the object in
secure drop so that it adds the optimal
padding to make these objects look like
some other objects in in facebook then
the other strategy is given so the other
strategies is to create a collision so
two pages that are slightly similar we
may you
the right padding in each one to create
a collision and the classifier will
confuse them for that there are two ways
of doing this so one is based on two
parameters that define the the padding
so we part the the objects to the next
multiple of these parameters so for
example here if sakura table has two
objects and facebook has three objects
then and the parameter is five let's say
or four in the example then you would
add as many objects as to reach four
objects so this case like anonymity set
of the pages and these pages will
collude the other way is probabilistic
we crawled the hidden service space and
we estimated the empirical distribution
of number of objects and the sizes of
these objects and what we do is when we
protect the other page we sample from
this distribution randomly so the other
defense is llama it's inspired by
randomized pipelining its goal is to
randomize HTTP requests and we do it by
adding some random delays in the HTTP
requests and then we repeat also
previous requests to generate fiving
responses it's more of an experiment to
test randomized pipelining because
randomize pipelining
were shown to fail in several
evaluations and we want to see if it was
because of the way it was implemented so
we implemented it as an add-on we don't
require a server collaboration so the
evaluation is very simple the mythology
is very simple we just cached 100 hidden
services in our own hidden service that
we were running and we visited these
pages with and without the defense and
we then measured security by applying
the state-of-the-art attacks on the
unprotected and the protective case and
then we compared the accuracies that we
got we measure performance by measuring
the latency and one with overheads after
apply
the defense so I will just give a
highlight of the results of the
evaluation so here you see the results
for alpaca we we tested several
configurations but I'm only showing the
best one so in this case in the left
side you can see the blue bar is the
unprotected case so one thing to notice
here is that actually the accuracy in
the protective case is very small
compared to it's quite smaller than the
accuracies that typically web-surfing
everything attacks achieved on regular
sites we believe this is because hidden
services are very small and they are
very similar to each other and they are
more likely to collude in some of the
features actually in the length features
so we see that in the base case in the
best best case for the offence when we
apply the probabilistic alpaca with the
accuracy of the attack desist to 15% and
the bandwidth so they decrease in
accuracy with ranges between 60 and 40%
for all the configurations and the
bandwidths overheads are for the
probabilistic are 50% latency and 80%
85% bandwidth overheads and these
numbers are in the range of the values
that network level defenses achieved
llama on the other hand didn't seem to
provide as good a level of protection as
alpaca we see that the accuracy only
decreased around 20 and 30 percent and
the layer although the latency and
bandwidth overheads were very low it was
a it's a very lightweight defense but
probably it's not enough and we believe
this is because randomizing the requests
is very hard because there are some
dependencies on the content that is
requested
so this limits how much we can randomize
and this
probably the same reason why randomize
pipelining is failing but we we haven't
tested how much randomization do we have
so the main takeaways are that website
fingerprinting defenses are easier to
implement and deploy on the application
layer and they are as effective as in
the network layer we have shown that
hidden services have incentives to
support these defenses we have developed
our servers the first server-side
defense in TOR and actually we were
contacted by secure drop our
whistleblowing platform that runs a
hidden search hidden services and is has
been implemented the prototype of alpaca
that will eventually be deployed an
alpaca is also running in this hidden
service if you want to visit for a demo
and the source code is available on
github if you want to play with it so
yeah that's all
[Applause]