a pleasure to welcome you to the
afternoon session of pets session on
location privacy I want a few
housekeeping notes the first is that we
actually don't have a mic for the QA so
I'm going to ask all the speakers to
repeat the questions and then answer the
questions and so with that it's a great
pleasure to introduce recoop we'll be
talking about location privacy for
ranked based geo query systems okay so
good afternoon my name is Rinku diri I
am with the University of Denver this
work was done mostly by my student we
some alpha German and my colleague at D
you Ramakrishna to lamella we Samus has
graduated so it's not here to give the
talk anymore so I'll present on his
behalf here so I'm going to start with
an application a web application that we
created just to motivate what is what is
it that we're going to talk about
okay so essentially we are going to just
do some kind of a google search for some
py so I'm just going to put let's say
Indian food there
that's removing the space there because
it switches to the next slide but we
will take care of that there and then
color all the women so this is going to
show me indian places they can get
indian food near this location and so
what we are looking at is so we're using
google aps for this and we are listing
down the top ten places that we will
they pay as a return and that's what
this left table is now you can take a
look at where those are located quickly
as just as a point there if i just so
this is india house which basically is
ranked at number three according to the
results that was returned so as you can
see here that Google is not ranking
these matches just based on distance it
is using other kind of factors to also
use in the in the ranking method so what
we're going to do is maybe move the
query point that that red marker is
where the current query point is and
then let me just take it out a little
bit and see what the result said would
be like when I do that you see if I move
it and this is I have moved it out
around 1.2 miles and we see that the
results it is still the same which again
is a reinstatement of the fact that you
were seeing results that are not
dominated just by distance but by other
factors when this ranking is going on
and we can do this a little bit more and
you will start to see changes because at
some point the distance factor also
dominates symbol here
yeah so in a on all directions you can
move the pointer and then see that there
is all that is different of course we do
not know where the shift
exactly happened and it depends from
keyboard to keyboard you search and also
depends on where you are located okay so
the factors that go into this kind of
ranking so we I'm going to just list out
two of those there could be others one
is the density of objects so you could
have objects the querying objects being
very sparse in the neighborhood where
you are making the query and so in that
case what happens is when you move so
when the query point is B moves around
the result that there really doesn't
change a whole lot you're looking for 10
here is something there is only 10 of
those so you can move around a whole lot
without really affecting the results ok
other case would be you could have dense
spread of the py so this could be
something that you could find almost
every block cafe or whatever so in this
case you can think that yeah if I move
around then the results that I get would
be sensitive to my movement so if we can
move around the mile and and things may
change a whole lot okay but then there
is another factor that goes into
retrieving this result set which is the
ranking function and remember the
ranking function is not made up of only
distance it is also made up of what we
call prominence factors okay so other
things that are used along with the
distance so as a result of which this
ranking function helps offset kind of
like the sensitivity you get when you
have spots a P wise which means that
when ranking functions are in play you
could have you could move around a lot
and still be only seeing the same
results so the sensitivity you get
because of having a sparse viewer
distribution kind of is offset because
of the use of other factors in the
ranking so given the given such ranking
functions are in existence or in use you
can think of
centering around you there could be what
we call zones so what essentially means
is that for example we could find a zone
wherein if you move around the result
doesn't change at all so you get the
same result set then there could be an
adjacent zone where if you move around
yeah if you go out into that zone you
still get to see most of the results
that you would see in your actual
location but maybe one mismatch so one
of the points might have just might be
they're different now so similarly if
you move out a little bit more you could
get two mismatches and so on and so
forth the whole idea being that the
change is progressive in the sense that
it does this you know that probably
change I'm here is the top ten result
here if I move two miles out my result
is all different doesn't really happen
whole lot specially when ranking
functions are in play here so just to
again another kind of validation on that
would be this is just what this plot is
showing is it's showing the results from
doing I think this was alone around a
million queries around LA and so we
picked a point in LA to do a query I
think that carriers for cafe or
something and then we picked a point
within a I remember correctly within two
kilometers of that query point and then
we sort of checked okay what was the
overlap in the result set so this kind
of distribution is showing you okay what
where do you see so essentially what we
are seeing is that even without doing
any kind of technique and you kind of
previa privacy-preserving technique if I
just maybe randomly pick a point within
a certain distance of where I am I am
still will be able to see many of the
correct results or at least the same
results that I would see if I use my
true location okay so the rest of what
I'm going to talk about is to just make
sure that this happens more often and of
course with some kind of a privacy bound
so I just don't want to give it out to
chance I want it so that it happens most
of the time
so I'll let me just give you a brief
idea sure if you have worked in location
privacy you're familiar with this idea
but otherwise what is this mechanism we
are talking about so think of the
mechanism as some kind of process that
takes some kind of a hidden location of
course there are query parameters other
kind of parameters also there and we
consider all of those to be public
knowledge and then the mechanism spits
out some output the output could be
another perturb location from which the
query will actually be made and in our
case if the output really is a mix of
locations and sets and things like that
so you have some outputs that are being
generated the idea is that from an
adverse event of view the idea is to
figure out what was the hidden input
whatever the hidden location we are
talking about location privacy given
that you are observing certain outputs
and that you know the mechanism you know
the parameters involved in the mechanism
all that kind of stuff now this to do
that inference you could be the
adversity could be using some kind of a
background knowledge the background
knowledge could be prior knowledge that
the adversary has on where a certain
user is likely going to be all that kind
of stuff now it's very difficult to
tackle background knowledge because they
assume something or and then do your
process based on that so so that's why
we adopt a different kind of notion
again it's not as it's appeared in 2013
costas is here somewhere so the idea of
Geo indistinguishability was proposed so
instead of looking at prior knowledge
which we asked this question ok let's
look at the output and ask the question
what is the start of the chances as the
different locations actually produce
this particular output ok and we're
looking at the ratio of these
probabilities given some two locations
and an L prime could be any locations
and s could be any output at the method
generator then we say and we call let's
say we call it the indistinguishability
ratio or something like that ok and then
we say ok if this value is 1 essentially
what it is saying
is that that given s there is no way
essentially it's independent of Elvis
and there's no way you can figure out if
L was used to generate F or L primers
use the generators okay then and as you
move away from this point you are saying
that locations are becoming more and
more distinguishing the ratio is
basically going away from one and third
point okay so then as privacy mechanisms
what you can try to do is you can say
okay I am going not going to allow this
ratio to just go on and on forever on
either side I'm going to bound it to
some limit okay so on either side we are
going to say that the ratio is going to
is going to be between those two points
okay now you can bound it to some fixed
value yeah or as geo indistinguishable
it does they say okay let's bound it
based on some property of the two
locations and in which case enjoy
indistinguishability that would be the
distance between two locations so what
it means is that if the locations are
closer then it will be more difficult
for you to distinguish between basically
compute then the distinguishing ratio
will be closer to one in that sense it
will be more difficult for you tell
which location was used to generate the
output the more closer they are okay so
moving on we can now also talk about
something similar but instead of just
using distance we are going to say okay
let's try to do that but let's not take
this thing of distance let's think of
the similarity of results so we will say
that two locations will be more and more
indistinguishable which will be closer
to one if they are producing similar
results okay so if the produced similar
laser it will be more in diction and
that's what the idea is in this paper
which is moving extending the whole idea
from distance to other kind of functions
okay
so then again what we are going to say
what we are saying is that two locations
in the same zone so same zone means they
produce the same results that they
should be indistinguishable okay and
then if you move out to a different zone
then the degree of
distinguishability will depend on what
kind of a mismatch or match is there
between the two sets okay if you like
equations that's how basically you state
it out or do to this go to paper and
take a look at that but that's the whole
idea that essentially what we're trying
to capture is the same or similar two
locations are in terms of results to
produce the more distinguishable we will
say there will be okay now it's not
necessary that you think of or you
compare this location just in terms of
query results you can use other kinds of
functions also we have not tried that so
you can say okay we want I want liquid
dislocations to be distinguishable based
on I don't know the demographics of the
people staying there
so you can your accordingly your
function will be different in that case
okay
so using this principle we then develop
the mechanism that's more or less the
core idea we develop the mechanism to
enforce it in terms of a Pui search
environment so what the mechanism does
is go through it quickly it's kind of
multi-step process it generates a part
of location first of all so we are
somewhere in here
it was generate a perturbed location you
can do it uniformly you can use you in
distinguishability for that which are
mechanizing in use you end up with some
location that is not the to location and
then you do a big search rounded
location essentially you say will give
me all the POS relevant POS in a big
radius okay and then what you retrieve
at this point is minimal information you
can get like location and prominence
data only you don't get details of the
POS in this case okay so you get that
then we compute that we locally compute
the rank for all this POS using that
location and prominence information and
in the paper we talk about the nature of
the ranking function if the ranking
function is more or less linear than you
can club together you can do this
ranking without revealing what the
function is
so then you move ahead and you you do a
computation on the top case results at
multiple points within a certain area
surrounding your perturb point okay and
then you assign a score the score is
assigned based on how much similarity is
between that point and then between a
point and the true result set so you
basically match do a set intersection
and look at the overlap in and then we
use a sampling method to pick one of
these sets for as the final answer and
this sampling is done using the standard
exponential mechanism essentially you
give us a exponentially higher way to
more high-quality set and then you do a
sampling and you then retrieve the
details under sampling and this is just
showing you an idea about the
probability of picking matches when you
do this exponential sampling okay so
quickly just just cover the general for
the results part this is this is showing
you the probability of you getting more
number of matches in the in terms of the
result set which is a top 10 search here
and this would this data were generated
for 15 different keywords across five
different cities overall around seven as
in seven to 50,000 different queries
okay and then the overall the point here
to take is that the chances of getting
eight or more matches is essentially you
reach levels like 95% there so there's
one or two miss can happen there now
when you do miss them you will see that
the misses happen mostly in the lower
ranked results so it's not that you miss
higher rank entities and that's what we
are trying to show in here this is
basically the rank of the missed objects
quick note on the timing if you are
because there's local computation
involved overall the whole process is
taking for a query around two-and-a-half
to three seconds again if you just do a
regular query it's going to take
somewhere around two and a half seconds
anyways okay
okay I'll leave out this part this is
mostly a comparative study that we did
with you in this thing you should be
eating okay
so conclusion wise I just want to
highlight this point that the whole idea
is the landscape of query results is
often not just it's often platitude in
in places based on where the location in
versus view our distribution all this
kind of Service and the privacy methods
we have seen till now doesn't exploit
that so it it would be useful to exploit
that particular latitude nature of the
landscape and design may be stronger
privacy and mechanisms in future okay
thank you
[Applause]