same as possible okay so I'm going to be
talking about hoarding the stratum the
recommended protocol and I would like to
start the discussion with it's good and
everybody hearing I would like to start
this discussion by very briefly
describing the Bitcoin mining process
now this is the process that Bitcoin
network uses to create new coins and
essentially participating nodes which we
call miners are supposed to solve
compete to solve this very simple
mathematical puzzle for which they get
rewarded this newly created coins now
first of all they need to create what we
call a template a block template which
is depicted here in the figure with a
letter F and what goes into these
template is are these parameters that
actually reflect the current state of
the Bitcoin network you can see we have
some transactions depicted there we also
have a previous pointer to to the
previous block into the blockchain and
we also have the coinbase transaction
which is a special transaction that
records the newly created coins and we
also have a little more details on the
creation of this template but they're
not very important for our discussion
but it is really important though is
that they're supposed to also figure out
this nonsense they they create actually
two nonsense they're supposed to find
these values switch that when they
applied a double sha-256 function we get
at least deleting zero bits as you can
imagine the more leading 0 bits that we
require the harder is to solve this
puzzle and this allows us to introduce
the notion of the difficulty of the
puzzle it turns out that these
difficulties adapted so that means that
the Bitcoin network is constantly
updating this difficulty in order to
keep the rate of the newly created coins
are constant now as you can imagine the
current Bitcoin difficulty as more
miners have been joining this process
the currently this difficulty has has
increased so high that a smaller or
lower ability miners are not able to
of this puzzle by themselves so they
start to do is they start aggregating
into these mining pools essentially
engaging into a master/slave paradigm
and now this pool servers are actually
supposed to create these jobs and I find
them to the miners of course these jobs
are all over smaller difficulty so they
can solve them right and the solutions
to these jobs are actually a we call
them now shares it turns out that for
the pool server to redistribute the
reward they just need to count the
shares that the miners have submitted
and also take into account the
difficulty that these shares were
created now in order to exchange all
this communication they needed a new
protocol and that's how the Stratton
protocol was born we are depicting in
this figure here the minimal set of
packages that any protocol would would
need to exchange we needed to exchange
are for instance a set share difficulty
packet we also need to be able to assign
jobs and finally we also need to be able
to submit shares now the most important
problem with this protocol is that
everything is done in clear text and
this is what we're going to be
exploiting on the following attacks now
this is what a sample timeline of the
straddle protocol looks like on the
x-axis we have the time where the packet
was collected and on the y-axis which we
have the message type indicated by
height and also by color I would like to
draw your attention to a couple of
observations here the most of the
difficulty packets occur at the
beginning of the exchange you can barely
see these on this thick yellow line at
the beginning and also another important
observation is that the majority of the
share submissions are actually accepted
which are the green bars at the bottom
and only very few of them are rejected
or ignored which are the red bars and
the black bars on there now the
importance of these observations are
going to become apparent once we start
talking about the attacks but we
actually evaluate it which is which is
what we never talk about next
now we evaluated three types of attacks
of attacks in increasing level of
education of our adversary the first
attack is a normal a distraught act and
we require that the adversary is able to
observe all the information inside each
of these packets
now the next sophistication in attack is
an attacker that does no longer need all
this information but it only requires
the metadata of the packet so we are
maybe this is something like the
adversary was able to get a hold of the
ISP logs and finally the most
sophisticated attacker is able to take
advantage of injecting with playing and
modifying packets so let's take a look
at the first attack this is a passive
attack and we call this tridip attack
this is where the attacker is able to
observe all the communication of the
stratum exchange and the goal of this
attack is to figure out how much is the
victim miner earning from the mining
activity now if we live in a country
like the US this is probably not a very
big deal right but it turns out that if
you are in a strong third world
countries or in a country where your
government is not very respectful of
your rights this can actually expose you
to quite a lot of danger
maybe extortion or kidnapping or even
prosecution like some notable cases that
have been documented for instance in
Venezuela or Vietnam now in order to
carry out this attack the adversary
actually is very simple to perform first
he needs to identify an interval of
constant difficulty and he can do that
because he can identify these yellow
bars which are the share difficulty
packet and once he'd identify this this
interval he measures the length of the
interval and he also measures the amount
of shares that have been submitted there
with that with those informations he can
actually calculate the average time but
the miner requires in order to solve
this puzzle and he also needs the
difficulty that he also reads off from
the set difficulty packages and now
using all this information he actually
gets a whole the hash rate value which
is a concept that we haven't talked
about yet but the essential
it's proportional to the amount of
computational power that the miner has
actually contributed to the bull and so
with this hash weed he essentially uses
a conversion rate between hash weight to
become a two-bit going tail and he
essentially obtains the earnings of the
nine
now most polls actually publish this
hash which to be TC conversion rate here
for transparency purposes now this
shouldn't be very surprising right
because I mean that fool is actually
obtaining the same exact with the same
information that the attacker is
actually using so if the tool is able to
do it why shouldn't the attacker do it
however what is a little bit more
surprising is that the attacker actually
does not need to know all this
information he this is and this is the
our second level of attack
sophistication in this in this scenario
the attacker is no longer allowed to
take a look at the payload of the packet
and however he can still recover the
payout of the victim by obsessing some
crucial observations that we're going to
talk about next so the first observation
is that approximately the first 50
packet of the stratum are exchanged are
not a share difficulty change of packet
and so we again have an interval of
constant difficulty the next thing that
it it realizes is that most tools
actually set a default difficulty in our
case this was a 1024 value so the
attacker simply uses that value again
and finally the the last observation
that we talked about before is that most
Australian packages are actually share
submissions which are accepted so he
simply counts the first 50 packets he
takes the time that these packets
require in order to be transmitted and
he uses the default difficulty so again
he uses the same formula and again he
first did actual payout of the victim
now the importance of this s scenario is
not vizionary itself is that it is
actually very similar to on a scenario
where your packets are actually
protected with something like TLS or
something like Duncan encryption again
in the other scenario the attacker is
not able to take a look at the packets
payload however he is able to infer some
information from the metadata of the
packet so the success of this attack is
actually telling as the encryption is
not enough now
this is these are the results of our
attacks we have on the x-axis we vary
the frequency of our mining device and
this is actually simulating several
mining equipment now the blue disks this
is the series of the archer straight-up
prediction and I suspect that this is
very similar to the actual payout our is
a little bit surprising is that by using
the procedure that we just described we
can actually predict the actual paired
with a pretty good accuracy as measured
by the mean square error and mean
percentage err now the last attack that
I would like to talk about is this
active attack and essentially it is
starts with the other side of things
obtaining the job assignment from the
booth server and injecting this
assignment into the mining making a
believe that it comes from the pool
server and as soon as the server as soon
as the miner submits this year the
adversary intersects this year and
submits it to the pool server as if it
was from from the adversary and
essentially claiming credit for it now I
have a design of our proof-of-concept
solution it uses IP tables in order to
capture packet it also uses this copy
for packet manipulation and also packet
the coding we also develop a wireless
middleware that is supposed to maintain
the TCP synchronization activation
colonization of the TCP hijacking
activities and finally the byte coin
module that is supposed to keep track of
all this job as new job
assignments on the share hijacking now
how do we solve this so for us a good
solution is supposed to protect against
the stratum attacks that we just
described but it should also be
resilient to attack the target the
solution itself another requirement for
our solution was that you needed we
recognized the job assignments and share
submissions are very common package so
any efficient solution should try to
actively avoid encrypting these very
common packets and finally we want to
propose minimum modifications to the
stratum protocol so that the solution is
actually doing 3d adaptability of our
solution now let me walk you through the
motivations of our solution which we
call bedrock remember that the attackers
in attacks one and two they use
crucially the fact that they could
actually measure the difficulty of the
jobs so we essentially a sensible choice
would be to just encrypt this that
difficulty packet and of course this is
totally useless if you will still allow
the pool to set the default difficulty
so we are further proposing that it is
the miner who actually sets the initial
difficulty a City result the attacker
can still reconstruct the template
because he has the information from the
job submission so the job assignment and
it also has of course the information
from the from the shared submissions
which other nonsense as I was actually
here so with with all this information
the attacker simply calculates the
double-shot 52 to 56 function and we'd
solve the leading bits of the hash and
he can still recover an estimate of the
difficulty of all this yet now in order
to solve this problem we introduced the
concept of mining cookies that
essentially
introduce a shared secret between the
liner and the pool and we are the pixel
here with the letter R M and essentially
this shared secret goes into the process
of creating this block template now
since these are M is not
ever exchange in clear text on the wire
the attacker is not able to recreate the
template and he's not able to actually
get a hold of the Payette earnings of
the miner we also include in this mining
cookies we also include the usually and
so we essentially avoid a second attack
to with lasted our goals
the final requirement is that we
proposed minimum modifications to the
strata protocol we are essentially
proposing using an unused field in the
block of the beta of the vehicle block
but any other unused field can be used
as well and this is our evaluation of
our solution we compared to SSL or
Blanca TLS or blanket encryption and as
far as passive attacks bedrock actually
provides equivalent protection with a
lot less overhead which we see in this
graph it's a couple of orders of orders
of magnitudes better in performance and
it turns out that as far as active
attacks bedrock actually provides a
little bit better protection than SSL by
defeating attack the target the
encryption cryptography this means that
it doesn't matter if you choose your
primes incorrectly or if you use a
foreign eyes encryption algorithm
because the Bitcoin be crystal mining
cookie concept is the simple security is
based on the hashing algorithm then this
active attacks are also prevented now
assists only I have introduced three
attacks and stratum that allow us to do
PR disclosure it also allows us to steal
computational resources I have also
shown that encryption is not only
insufficient but it is also not
necessary to protect from for this
attacks and I have introduced the
bedrock solution and the concept of
mining cookies and I have also shown
that the bedrock actually outperforms
TLS and
laughter solutions and with that I will
now take questions
[Applause]