okay so I'm Steven Engelhardt and I may
be talking about assessing privacy and
web standards and specifically looking
at it through the battery status API
which I think has had a really
interesting development right it was
introduced into browsers people found a
bunch of vulnerabilities and was
eventually ripped out of a couple
browsers and so I think that's kind of
unusual and we want to look at what
happened and what led to it and so I
don't I'm sure I don't really need to
convince anyone here that new web
features lead to privacy concerns right
but I think the one example I like to
give of how things might be changing is
virtual reality and specifically web VR
and so you can have virtual reality in
the browser right you can go to a page
they can drop you into this VR session
but part of doing VR is configuring the
headset and part of configuring a
headset is knowing some parameters about
the user's eyes and specifically the
interpupillary distance and so the
initial version of this spec exposed
this this IP D to sites if you were in
this VR mode and so my point being if I
was a tracker having the distance
between the pupils of the person who's
looking at the page right now might be
pretty useful to track them across sites
and I don't mean to pick on this spec I
think they've actually done a good job
of looking at privacy and security
issues but my point is that things are
changing and maybe we should see how we
address take a look at how we address
privacy and standards and so the w3c has
a couple things in place to help with
this the first is this self review
questionnaire and so this basically says
two spec authors hey you know think
about different threat models ask
yourself a bunch of questions here and
examples are like do you have any PII do
you have high-value data are you
creating any new State on the browser
that's not cleared when the user clears
their cookies you know something that
could allow tracking after the user
clears cookies and then has a couple
different suggestions and this one I
thought was interesting it says you know
drop the feature four point three so
maybe just don't implement it after
you're done with this I don't know how
often people will take that
recommendation but it's definitely a
great document and then there's also the
privacy interest group
and I've given their statement here but
I think point three is really important
and basically they provide guidance and
advice for respect authors and so the
idea here is you can either go to them
with your privacy assessment or security
assessment already completed and say hey
does this look appropriate to you or you
can actually I think ask them for advice
or help in doing the assessment and so
let's look at the battery status API
it's pretty simple it basically gives
you the charge level of the device so
anyone any script in JavaScript could
say hey you know what's the current
charge level is that if the battery or
the device currently charging and how
long will it take to discharge or charge
depending on if it's charging and we in
the paper we go through this big series
of events right and I won't have time to
talk about all of the important events
during the talk today so I encourage you
to check the paper out it's available on
any of our websites but instead I'll
focus on kind of the high level I think
more important points in the development
and the first is that when the spec
advanced to the candidate recommendation
level it added in this privacy and
security section here it was the first
version to add that but it basically
said the information disclosed by the
API has a minimal impact on
fingerprinting or privacy and therefore
you know we don't put any limits on how
it's exposed and so I think this is
important because it's fine like the
spec office clearly found something that
they felt had a privacy impact but
instead of enumerated what that was they
just kind of said it was minimal and so
we don't recommend any any protection
measures and then within you know after
that candidate recommendation during
that time it was implemented in Firefox
it was implemented in Safari but I don't
think it absolutely ever shipped and
eventually influenced in Chrome and then
later on some new research exposed a
couple vulnerabilities the first was
this leaking battery paper by Lukesh and
it found kind of kind of two main points
that are relevant here the first is that
the battery status API could be used as
kind of a short-term identifier and the
example I like to give here is like
let's say you have a bunch of MacBook
Pros behind an
at their fingerprint maybe pretty
similar because the device is the the
hardware itself is pretty similar but
you know you could use the battery
status of each of them if they were in
various charging States to differentiate
and the second example is Firefox on
Linux was actually returning high
precision values and that could allow an
attacker to recover of the battery
capacity of that device and I won't have
time to go into details on that but you
can check out this paper and the second
paper was a measurement paper done by
myself and Arvind and we found basically
that not only is this a theoretical
attack but we see finger printing
scripts in the wild collecting the
battery status while they're collecting
a bunch of other finger print vectors so
they're definitely using it as part of
something to identify devices and users
and the spec was updated to address
these vulnerabilities specifically they
said you know you should avoid these
high precision readouts that would
prevent this long-term battery capacity
recovery and you should inform the user
when and who's using the API in this I
actually haven't seen in any of the
browsers so I don't it's a
recommendation but I'm not seeing it
implemented and then maybe ask for
permission maybe up this gate or expose
fake values if you'd like to and then in
late 2016 this kind of came as a
surprise to us having done these
measurement papers we thought maybe the
spec would change but we didn't think
this would happen
Mozilla actually proposed to remove the
API so they sent out a post on dead
platform their mailing list and said can
basically can anyone point to a real web
site using the battery API for some
legitimate purpose that we want to
support and after some back-and-forth
kind of the one of the last posts in the
thread said ok so everyone agrees there
are some theoretical good things that
can be done but we just don't observe
them and then early 2017 they ended up
restricting it to non web content so the
browser could obviously still use the
API but no one could on the web
so far we ended up pulling it out of the
tree like I said I don't think it
actually ever shipped but they removed
it so therefore it's kind
indication they have no intention to
ship it in the future
in chrome it's still unknown there's an
open bug there's been some discussion
but it's not clear where that's going to
go and then we just wanted to point out
Yandex browser maybe it doesn't have as
large of the market share as the others
but they ended up switching this to an
opt-in only model so the user would have
to go and enable the API if they
actually want want to be able to use it
and I think that decision was made kind
of on very little information the dev
platform mailing list basically you know
there were I don't know five or six
responders who gave some you know
anecdotal examples of where they seen
the API in use but we wanted to go and
do a full measurement so we looked at
the tops of 2,000 sites to see does this
reflect kind of what Mozilla was
thinking in the dev platform mailing
list and it basically does we found 33
third parties using it about half of
them for tracking eight we're using it
for these kind of benign purposes
basically performance measurement and I
don't think that's really the model or
that's really what the spec offers we're
thinking about when they implemented the
API they didn't just wanted to make it
easier to do some performance
measurements and nine of them we had a
little trouble classifying because they
were very simple scripts it wasn't clear
what their purpose was and so how can we
improve the privacy review process and
this for this this is the section of the
talk where me as someone who's never
done never participated in a
specification process is going to give
advice on how to do privacy reviews in
the specification process and actually
you know Lukesh is the kind of expert
here but I think this has been my first
time moving into it and I'd love to hear
your thoughts and our ideas and maybe
pointing out why the things we think can
work or can't work and so on and so
first I think the specification process
should include a review privacy review
of the implementations and so it's best
to move through the various levels needs
to interoperable implementations and so
to me it's it's you know why not also
require privacy review of those
implementations so not only have a
section in your paper but review what
the various browser vendors have done
and I think that would have helped catch
this double-precision issues that cause
this long-term tracking identifier to be
possible for the battery API and
actually Lucas participated in a review
of the ambient light sensor API in which
they did basically find the same
vulnerabilities they found that it was
returning these high double precision
values and the second recommendation is
that you should audit and this is
telling for me I think craft as a
measurement researcher but audit the use
of API is after implementation and I
think the the point I want to stress is
that trackers will be the early adopters
of basically any new API at least this
is what I've seen doing fingerprinting
measurements over and over and so I
think you know you'll have people that
are sites that are using it as intended
right you'll have some cool demo that
comes out after you release the API
you'll have a couple sites being early
adopters but then for the unattended
case you'll have some tracker
implemented right and that tracker
happens to be present on hundreds of
sites and now the majority of your
brand-new API use is for tracking which
is probably not what you hoped but I
think it provides an opportunity right
if you do this auditing right after or
shortly after releasing the API you can
probably correct some of the
vulnerabilities in the API before it
becomes adopted by things that you don't
want to break right the intended uses so
you're less constrained early on to make
these changes and the next is that where
we're not sure that the measurement
community will continue to support the
same kind of level of fingerprinting
studies that they have and the concerns
are basically the you know lack of
novelty and measurement techniques for
new techniques right because that's part
of the way reason we're able to publish
these results that the measurement of
each new API is kind of a smaller
contribution and so it's you know if
some new API comes out and I want to do
a measurement study on it it's going to
be a little difficult to publish that
and maybe the specs can't wait for the
publication cycle and so the suggestions
are you know to do measurement through
telemetry probes and I know that that
exists right now and it's typically
whether or not an API is being used
but I think actually it would be
important to have things like which
properties are being accessed which
methods are being accessed for the API
and if we could figure out a way to do
it privately even kind of the arguments
or the return values for those those
properties and that's really what we
need to use when we do this kind of
fingerprinting measurement and then
maybe we can move measurement to browser
vendors or perhaps something like an NGO
or archive.org right where you can still
do crawls not have it be based on users
but have some kind of regular
measurement happening and lastly I think
specification authors should to do
assessments with multiple threat models
and this might sound again like sort of
a simple recommendation but I think it's
helpful to go through an example here
looking at the Ottawa Audio API and so
we measured this we discovered this
being used for fingerprinting last year
and we wanted to see okay you know how
identifying is this like what is this
providing you in terms of identifying or
differentiating users so we collected a
bunch of data for real users and we
found it's essentially the users
operating system and their browser right
it's kind of correlated to those two
pieces of information so for the average
device it's like okay you can get that
so the user agent string so it's no big
deal but I think it would be useful for
something like the tor browser to know
that this will reveal the users OS or
the users browser and tor browser in
particular wants you know Windows Mac
Linux to all can appear or have the same
fingerprint and so we had a bunch of
other recommendations in the paper I
didn't have time to go over all them
today but looking forward to the
discussion to your thoughts
[Applause]