[Music]
tsubasa bark yawning Burke and Carolyn
Union and it's Yahoo we'll get the top
so hi
good morning I'm Yali uh currently a
third year PhD student in health
diversity of california-irvine
so our paper is about cross-cultural
privacy prediction it is based on one of
the privacy theory from Othman so in
1975 our early autumn I in his book
privacy and freedom describe different
behaviors that people use to regulate
their interpersonal privacy from a rich
set of ethnographic data in a variety of
cultures and he concluded that while the
capability for privacy regulation is
culturally universal the specific
behaviors and techniques may be quite
different from one culture to another so
taking this ah to the technology age we
found that more and more technologies
are now used at a global scale but most
practice studies still focus on a narrow
population in a single country and there
are a lot of multinational organizations
who have users from different cultural
backgrounds but their data collection
strategies as you almost similar and
some of the previous studies have
already looked at the culture influence
on privacy attitudes or behaviors and
basically they found that individualism
will increase the
level of privacy concerns and decreased
the information disclosure behavior and
increase the privacy protection
behaviors but most of these studies
focus on the general privacy attitudes
or behaviors and it has been shown that
privacy decisions is highly dependent on
the context so with that in mind and on
the other hand privacy decision-making
support is a popular a popular topic
recently because users are faced with
increasing number of privacy decisions
when they are interact with technologies
and most of the decisions are somewhat
complex to users because of three
reasons first the incomplete information
for example users when their personal
information is collected they have no
idea where this information will go and
who will have the access to the personal
information and heuristics and
heuristics and bounded rationality for
example when users disclose their
personal information to a organization
they will think about the organization's
name or reputation instead of the
specific privacy practice and third is a
cognitive and behavioral biases for
example our information disclosure is
greatly influenced by what other people
disclose instead of the comfort that we
may feel or the consequences that we may
have so to solve these problems there
has been a lot of solution proposed to
assist the privacy decision-making such
as recommending better decisions for
users or educating them about the
privacy and the security or provides on
feedbacks before or after the decision
so our approach is following these
tracks we want to predict users privacy
decisions by first contextualizing the
privacy decisions and mitigating the
cognitive bias reducing users
effort and most importantly we want to
consider the cultural differences
especially the culture differences that
users perceive the context or and
attitudinal factors um with that
approach we want to answer three
research questions first do we need to
include culture factors in predicting
privacy decisions and second how should
we measure privacy in the privacy
prediction and third how does culture
interact with context or and attitudinal
factors to answer those we collect some
data and the scope of the data
collection is organizational data
collection so users disclose their
personal data to organizations we run a
online survey in eight countries Canada
China Germany United States the United
Kingdom Sweden Australia and India and
the figures indicate the the percentage
of the respondent we have in each
country so generally around 12,000 per
country so totally we have almost 10,000
our responses and in the survey we
collected their demographics
informations their country of residence
their spoken language and their general
privacy attitudes and in addition to
that we also randomly show each
participant six scenarios each of them
continued a combination of for context
role arrivals this is an example of the
scenario from my mobile device I will
provide my current location and contact
list to a service provider this is a
selection method the service provider is
a company with no location in my country
which describes the entity that is
collecting the data the service provider
will use the information as I go I
agreed this is a usage purpose of the
data collection it will also save me
time or money which describes the value
exchange from the data collection then
the participants will indicate their
disclosure intent as except acceptable
or not successful and based on their
reported country of residence we also
make the Hofstede's culture values for
each country so a brief introduction to
help this cultural framework is that it
includes six dimensions power distance
individualism uncertainty avoidance
indulgence masculinity and pragmatism
and on each dimension is each country
will score from 0 to 100 so we use two
methods the first one is as simple as
supervised machine learning with
decision trees the input features are
demographic features attitudes
contextual variables country of
residence language and Hofstede culture
values and the account feature a
variable is disclosure intent which is
binary also a beaut models with and
without culture sectors which are
country language and Hofstede's values
and we found that adding the cultural
factors improved performance performance
in terms of the accuracy and F major and
especially Hofstede cultural values
outperform either country or language um
we also compared the six dimensions of
Hostess culture dimensions we found that
individualism and indulgence or performs
other cultural dimensions in terms of
the prediction performance and as
individual is already intensively
studied we think that indulgence is less
studied in the previous literature so
indulgence describes the extent to which
people try to control their desires the
higher indulgent a person is the more
like the more important he will perceive
the personal life control or the
in freedom so it is likely that the more
indulgent a person is more likely he
will be concerned with his privacy
and we also know a set of robustness
analysis we use other support supervised
machine learning algorithms and we run
each model eight more times with each
time with one country excluded and we
also use other culture frameworks which
are more recent and we got the same
result and the second method is
generalized linear mix effects model and
this time we add interaction terms
between individualism and contextual or
attitudinal predictors we found that
they adding the interaction terms
significantly improve the model feat and
this is the interaction effects between
uses purples and individualism with the
x-axis is individualism the y-axis is
the probability of a disability we found
that in lowly individualist country
there are more okay ways automatically
autonomously make decisions and
customize options well in highly
individualist country these are less ok
and this figure shows that in lowly
individualist country but users are more
ok with the purpose being benefited
community providing a compelling value
or save me some time or money well some
of these are not very accessible in
highly individualistic country and this
shows the interaction effect between
entity and individualism so in lowly
individualist country they're more ok
with the government the employer or the
foreign service provider we're in highly
individual is the country they're more
ok with the paid service provider or the
service provider that they have an
existing relationship with we haven't a
figure for this interaction sense but
generally we found that lowly
individualistic country are more ok with
the different collections through mobile
for mobile devices while in highly
individual is the country they're more
ok with the computer and lowly
individual
this country they're more okay with if
the data collection is is about follow
our video that are taken at work well in
highly individualist country it's more
okay in public and both of them are not
okay with at home and this reflects that
interaction in fact switching attitude
and individualism so perception of
third-party accountability means that
whether how much the participants think
the third party should be accountable
the data collection in loading
individualist country it decreased
acceptability which is a kind of
interesting we think that one reason
maybe they have different understanding
of the third party as the previous
figure show that they are more okay with
government or employer and it may also
reflect the disconnection between
privacy attitude and the actual behavior
so in summary we found that culture
matters and we found that in
individualism and indulgence is better
than other measurements and we also
found significant interactions effects
between contextual attitudinal sectors
and culture also we suggest that future
privacy research should consider the
cultural background of the participants
and they should restrict their private
their research either to one country or
control the cultural backgrounds and
cultural values is better than country
or language and we suggest that
multinational organizations should
customize their data collection
strategies for example they can
differentiate their data collection
purpose or value exchange for the users
and we also suggest that future privacy
decision support systems should
incorporate the culture factors like
they can determine the country of
residence based on the IP other some
other information and there's very
limitation of our study first we only
have a country's and we only measure the
disclosure intent which has may have
some disconnection with the actual
behavior and we did not
considered original culture or language
differences and there is some there are
some limitations of Hofstede's
culture dimensions for example for
equating the nation with culture but so
far it's the most widely well of the
most widely used culture frameworks so
that's my presentation thank you and
I'll take questions
[Applause]
yes please