perfect
okay let's go
so
i'm charlie and i'm here to tell you a
little bit about the past quantum
squirrel
uh
what is it all about
you'll understand during the talk of
foolish
but this is just a bad pun
um
to begin with
what's the first about quantum mechanics
and well
unless you've been living in a cave i
guess you've heard about quantum
mechanicals
there is no scaling quantum computer but
the thing is that there's a yet here and
while we don't know when they will come
up it's starting to get more and more
probable that one day we will see them
and so on the security side we need to
be ready for them in a sense
and the issue is that uh we know that
theoretically if they exist they will
break a lot of things that we use
nowadays to prove optical secures
and typically they will break rsa and
they can compute discrete
logarithms and so in terms of security
the issue is that we need new primitives
so
new encryptions new signatures uh we new
protocols based on those new primitives
and finally and it's the parts that we
will be interested in today we need new
proofs of security against those quantum
markers
so i'm from the computer-related
verification side and in this
field a lot of tools have been designed
over the years to prove the security of
a protocol
against a polynomial time during machine
that occurs and not controlling ones so
natural question is then for those tools
are they correct when you
shift to a quantum matter settings
and well spoiler alert the answer is no
um so with that in mind our contribution
uh
started
from looking at the logic
which is some kind of high level
abstraction which allows you to make
proofs of protocols by abstracting a lot
of details and then
you still get a computational
computational guarantees so those are
the guarantees against
uh
turing machine i was talking about and
we made this sound then we looked at the
squirrel prover so the squirrel the
famous post quantum squirrel
which is
an interactive cover for this logic
so you can think of it as also a theorem
proverb in the same mind friend as the
previous talk essentially
and
we extended it to support the post
quantum zone version of the beast logic
and finally
we used it to prove a bunch of protocols
in terms of created work
it's quite a recent question how to deal
with quantum mechanical so there's not a
lot to say here but
going back 10 years ago
somebody first identified let's say the
core issues that we have when we're
moving from classical to automate occurs
then some people looked at
what happens after pain and paper for
pen and paper proofs
and finally like last year
one of the theorem proverbs for the
computational reward was proved our was
adapted to be post quantum sound
but this one is mostly used for
primitives
while we will be talking about protocols
um so i want to give you a bit more
details on background on
why classical proofs may fail
and for that very quick intro to basic
crypto101
uh how do we prove that protocol is
secure in the classical setting
especially we go from a computational
hardness assumption we assume that
something is hard to do for any computer
and then we want to show that it implies
the security of the protocol
and to do that we tend to go the other
way around we assume the existence of an
attacker on the protocol and through a
so-called reduction we're going to build
a new attacker from this first one by
manipulating it in many ways until we
can build an attacker on the assumption
so
essentially we have two big ingredients
on one side an assumption
and then a reduction from this
assumption if you're a bit familiar like
with complexity or decidability theory
it's the same kind of reduction
in essence
[Music]
then the big question is what happens
when we want to map those two
ingredients to the case of quantum
computers
and here we have two issues the first
one is that
for some assumptions that we
use a lot in protocols
there is no drop in
quantum replacement
so i'm thinking here about different
groups and
so for those there is no nice equivalent
in the quantum setting and this is why
we have to redesign a lot of new
protocols
and
perhaps more surprisingly at least it
was for me
there's actually also an issue in the
second point
in the reduction part because
there are ways to manipulate
a classical attacker
inside a reduction that just cannot be
done that are impossible with a quantum
metal
so
let's just very briefly see how we can
model a probabilistic attacker model um
and one thing we do very often is just
to say instead of having a probabilistic
attacker we just consider a determinist
a deterministic attacker wu is given an
infinite random string which is from the
source of its randomness and the
sequence of inputs so
this is just
some deterministic thing and we took
away the we made explicit the source of
randomness and then typically inside
reductions we can use this kind of
this model
to for instance simulate
article executions that would have never
happened in the real world but typically
we can run with the same fixed source
of randomness twice the summary curve on
two different
set of inputs so it's like re-running
the attacker
on two distinct inputs and we're kind of
cheating and simulating the attacker and
the issue that we have typically is that
this is an impossible computation with a
quantum attacker
essentially
with a quantum attacker it's impossible
to run it twice with a fixed randomness
and it's essentially due to the knock
learning theorem uh here i'm just
talking about actually quantum physics
which i don't know a lot so please don't
ask complicated question but
there's a big theorem in this field
which is that
you cannot duplicate uh with a level of
precision essentially
a quantum state
and it essentially essentially means
that you cannot do this trick
of uh having access to the
to the
source of randomness of the attacker and
typically
one
widely used technique in computational
proofs
is the so-called rewinding
which needs to have an explicit access
to the source of randomness of the
attacker
and it becomes impossible
um so
there are multiple consequences actually
actually through this just no cloning
theorem
and
if you're trying to do a computational
proof uh for quantum medicare
then there are kind of many pitfalls and
a pen and paper proof will
quite likely be wrong for quantum
medicals
as soon as you're talking about the
attacker's inner state in a sense
because it's no quantum so be careful
and especially also otherwise saying the
article randomness is very tricky to
talk about
and some additional concerns that i
won't really look into but
also if you want to use a random oracle
model it gets very messy
and as soon as you want to talk about
classical arguments about complexity
classes and whether something is np or
ix or whatever you don't have to do it
for quantum computers of course
of course the computational tools the
term improvers
do these kind of things
sometimes behind the curtain so
now the question is how do we make them
post quantum sound essentially
very believe briefly
what is a squirrel what is a squirrel
power
so its goal is to enable
mechanized proofs of protocol
and we're trying to
make it at a high level of abstraction
so that
when you use it you shouldn't see too
many details about probabilities or
things like that
you're focusing about possible
executions traces and
using cryptographic assumption
and
this abstraction level should allow you
to
prove big protocols and complex security
properties
but in the end you still get
computational guarantees which means you
you still get guarantees against a
turing machine
to make it post quantum sound we have to
take care of the new primitive part so
designed
new
axioms and rules inside the tool inside
the theorem provider for those new
primitives
we have to verify the
post-confirmation-ness of each
rule or tactic or a proof step
inside the
inside the tool and check that we never
manipulate the attacker in a bad way in
this part
and we also have to verify for the last
brick is the course on this result
essentially we need to check that if
there is a turing machine that occur in
the real world
there exists a mapping to an attack in
the world of the logic what i call the
logical word
and once again here we also need to
check if we manipulate the attacker in a
bad way
the first one is quite straightforward
it's mostly thanks to the design of the
tool essentially that we get
it's easy to extend and quite modular
the second one was a question of
checking each
proof step and everything was fine
but of course uh at some point it
doesn't work anymore
uh in the course on this result which
actually you never see
um when you're using the tool
but one of the big issues
which
is that so i i say it's behind the cure
time because you are never gonna see it
um
a proof in squirrel was not for
an interactive record but actually for a
set of one shot that occurs
who would only share a common source of
randomness
then
a valid question would be why then do we
claim that we have proofs for
any attacker in the real world
the fact is that actually in the
classical setting when uh if you give me
an interactive recur
i can just cut this attacker into many
independent machines one for each step
one for
each step of the computation
and essentially
the
second step the second independent
attacker machine will just have to
recompute the state of the first one
using the same source of randomness to
be able to simulate the execution of the
interactive machine
here
if you remember when i was talking about
the knock learning theorem
this is the core part the technical
issue that made everything
not work essentially for the sql program
for this to be possible
atu must be able to compute exactly the
same the same state as a1 otherwise we
are not simulating the
true interactive mission
and this is impossible with quantum
turing machines
so essentially
our main contribution
on this side was purely theoretical
it was
to change the sumness result
for the vc logic and come up with a
variant which would work for interactive
black box attackers instead of a set of
single one-shot
attackers
the issues that it produces it
introduced actually kind of uh what i
call a cascade of changes
because then we had to reduce the
explosivity of the tool of the logic
to forbid essentially things that were
previously possible but
become impossible in the new
interpretation
what we did is come up with a set of
syntactic conditions
syntactic
restrictions let's say on what you can
write down in the logic on the tool
and those are necessary because for each
of those
things we added we could otherwise write
down things that don't make sense in the
quantum world
uh they were sufficient to to obtain the
sunlight of our tool
and
we went uh
we tried to have it simple and syntactic
so
at first when we were trying to do it we
came up with like i don't know 10 11 12
different side active conditions and it
was getting completely messy and
impossible
uh once we tried once we in the end we
were able to come up with only three
and then actually patching squirrel uh
to
have those three synthetic conditions
where kind of was kind of
straightforward
to give you an idea uh of what we were
able to prove currently um
uh what kind of key exchanges we looked
at
are essentially recent proposal of uh oh
you can try to
replace the film and like key exchanges
using a key encapsulation mechanisms so
those are the
kebc gnp and ke fx xy
typically proposals
and
well this table is mostly to give you
kind of an idea of the fact that we
can manage multiple kinds of assumptions
so we manage uh here i'm using
encryption signatures xor
and ashes
we're able to prove multiple kind of
security properties because we can
manage any equivalence-based security
property
so
typically strong security and
authentication but it can also go to
unlinkability
and
most of the proofs
so line of code is always a quite loose
indication of the complexity
of a proof but
typically here we don't we never go over
700 line of codes
for the specification and the proof
which i think is quite reasonable
in this kind of things
so to conclude
the contribution is twofold
first an interactive proverb that can be
used
and you have guarantees against quantum
attackers and this interactive allowed
us to make the first uh computer
verified proofs of some recently
proposed post quantum key exchanges
and well the extensions are quite
natural we want to scale to bigger calls
and maybe check out some proposal of tls
of alternative
post quantum alternatives to tls
or otherwise look at more complex
properties for key exchanges typically
like
compromise security that we get in the
messaging setting
thank you and if you have questions
i'm happy to hear them
thank you very much for the great talk
the quantum world is scary uh work like
this is uh gonna help us it make less
scary at least in terms of cryptographic
protocols
um we
will be happy to have questions if there
are any
questions okay uh then i can ask a
question
uh so for your case studies that you had
in the paper uh there are three that you
found not to be uh sorry i'm so sorry
to be not post quantum secure
uh and that was particularly because
they were relying on diffie-hellman and
you mentioned rewinding
but you also mentioned that rewinding in
some constrained scenarios can be proven
to be in a post quantum world can be
proven to be secure do you think those
constrained scenarios could be used to
prove the security of the three
protocols
uh
no because as you said they will rely on
the different assumptions so in a sense
they are inherently not person to
secure
however it's a question whether we want
to try to integrate those let's say more
fine-grained variants
uh to squirrel for like modeling
those kind of rewindings and being able
to prove the protocols that rely on them
the thing when we looked at it is that
it looks like it won't yield
let's say a generic
modification to the logic so
it may be very complicated to use in a
sense that's why we didn't do it yet
okay it sounds good no one has any other
question
okay i can ask one other question then
so one of the things that i found was
that uh the modeling process of pq
square all took like several weeks
uh or something is there a way to
automate it to
reduce the time several weeks seems a
bit uh so it's of course
one of the research projects that we
have to try to automate it more
but it's
kind of complicated those kind of things
as i said we're essentially coming up
whenever you have a proof
it means that you have a reduction right
and it's kind of like trying to automate
complexity or decidability proofs in a
sense so
that's why the question is quite
difficult
we are trying to simplify some parts at
least so that it's as automated as
possible but i don't think we will be
able to get a fully automated tool
that can do this essentially
right uh thank you so much for answering
my questions
since there are no other questions let's
uh thank the president
[Applause]