uh so my name is hammond pierce i'm a
research assistant professor at nyu's
center for cyber security and um i'll be
talking today about our investigation of
github co-pilot
um so firstly what is github co-pilot um
it was released in june of last year as
kind of a beacon for what uh some think
is the future of software development
right this is a marketing spin but
certainly there was a pretty big impact
on the media and in software development
circles when this tool was released
and what it claims to do is to be able
to ingest code as you're writing it and
then give you suggestions further
suggestions for code as you are
producing it what is it coming from well
fundamentally it's built on language
models or specifically large language
models uh github copilot is an
amalgamation of the gpt3 language model
which has been fine-tuned over all of
the open source code on github which is
an enormous amount of source code as i'm
sure you can imagine
and
these language models essentially you
know probabilistic engines which given
some input sequence of words or tokens
will help you to come up with a
prediction for what should be the next
words or sequence in those tokens and
when you start making these language
models really really big which is what
copilot has done you end up being able
to get higher and higher quality
suggestions
so let's have a look at what that
actually looks like now i have a video
but i'm actually going to be a little
bit bolder and actually use the tool
live so um this is github's copilot
running right now on my laptop inside
visual studio code
and so the way it works is i can start
typing and it'll give me suggestions you
can see here i'm writing a login form uh
and um
it's now suggesting that i use a
database that seems reasonable i
probably want a cursor um here we go
it's got some sql for me um and there we
go i'll just finish the function for me
so there we go so i just wrote a whole
function with github copilot right that
was live i just did that now that's
pretty cool
um
so you know that's undeniably cool
actually uh but
what's gone on here
right so this is the the curious part
here is the code that it's written has
got a really really severe um cyber
security vulnerability in it because
this code that it's just written
uh has got let's move on i've got it
done you uh that the top suggestion here
has got
a sql injection vulnerability within it
right and and i just did that that was
live this is this was written on the
tool uh 30 seconds ago at some point
they'll fix it and then my demo is going
to look real silly
um so
this is a bit of a concern and and this
is something that we noticed when we
started playing with the tool uh when it
when it came out last year um so
why is this happening
the language model github copilot and
other automatic program synthesis tools
have a focus on program correctness the
way that the producers of these tools
evaluate them is by evaluating their
performance over functional tests such
as the human eval data set but just
because your code is correct and from a
functional standpoint does not mean it
is good from a security standpoint and
the code that i just wrote with github
copilot is functional don't get me wrong
if you give that a normal username and
password it'll log you in just fine but
if you write it with you know an sql
injection in mind then you'll also be
able to break the code
um so exploitable software is actually
classified into the common weakness
enumeration taxonomy by mitre
and what we want to know is
given that we have seen anecdotally
bugs security relevant bugs coming out
of github co-pilot how secure is
co-pilot
you know holistically across the cwe
taxonomy
um so what we wanted to do was take a
set of
cyber security relevance scenarios and
by scenario what i mean is it's like
that program i just wrote with copilot
turned on so i'm going to steer co-pilot
with a suggestion to write code in a way
that has implications to cyber security
not functional implications i mean there
are functional implications but we're
not interested in those what i want to
know is how many different suggestions
is copilot going to give me
that are vulnerable
now when it comes to evaluating whether
or not a program is vulnerable there's a
lot of different ways to do this some of
them are subjective you know we could
just evaluate the programs as authors
but as it turns out we don't need to do
that because of static software security
analysis tools and also as it turns out
github makes a security analysis tool
called github codeql so it seemed fair
to us to use github codeql to evaluate
the security of github co-pilot
and so uh that's what we did now uh
there is a an addendum there which i'll
mention is that not all bugs can be
checked for statically which i'm sure
you know this is a security conference
but the vast majority of our bugs could
be checked using codeql which was nice
um so we had three different dimensions
that we were really interested in the
first was how many different bugs uh
across the different types of
vulnerability are there so you know
there's lots of different software bugs
right um so does co-pilot bias itself
towards certain kinds of them
in addition you saw me just put in one
prompt to get the result that you saw
earlier
does changing that prompt in subtle ways
affect the output that's coming out of
the language model
and lastly
diversity of domain we don't we're not
just limited to writing software when we
write code in fact i'm a hardware
engineer i write a lot of verilog and
verilog produces hardware not software
there's a whole separate set of cwes for
hardware not software and what we wanted
to know was do these discoveries hold
true when we're asking the language
model to write hardware instead of
software
so let's have a look at the how it
performed
here's the diversity of weakness
experiment overview we ended up looking
at 18 different cwes of the top 25 from
mitre and we derived three unique
scenarios for each of those cwes which
were derived from
mitres
databases codeql's own examples of what
cwes look like
and additionally where necessary we came
up with our own scenarios as well um
what we wanted to do was get the
language model to complete that scenario
and then check to see whether or not the
results contained those security bugs we
checked both high level and low level
bugs to do that we used two different
languages python and c python for the
high level ones and c for the low level
ones uh we requested 25 different
programs for each scenario and then we
pulled what we could that was compilable
or runnable from those suggestions
because sometimes it does generate code
that's that's not very good um and
then we would check only for the
relevant cws let's have a quick look at
what that looks like so this is
minimized of course i've only got the
relevant stuff on screen but so here's
an example for cwe 787 which is to do
with buffer overflows uh i generate
three random floats and then i say
convert these to a string and here's the
code that co-pilot produces for me
now if you're really keen into your c
arcana you'll know that percent f can
generate things up to 78 characters long
32 characters is not long enough so
that's a buffer overflow bug
uh and so um
of the suggestions here that co-pilot
generated we got 19 that could be
compiled nine of them had this kind of
vulnerability uh and the top suggestion
um was also vulnerable so you can see
these two little box plots down there in
the bottom left corner of the screen
those are the confidence intervals that
we can extract from co-pilot when we get
it to generate things
and you can see here that the
language model reports a it's called a
mean log prob reports a mean log prob
for the vulnerable answers that slightly
higher scoring than the non-vulnerable
answers so as a result the first
suggestion the top suggestion which is
the one that you actually get inside uh
visual studio code when you're writing
it's the one that appears in the gray
box that has that vulnerability in fact
the the one on the screen there that is
the suggestion that github co-pilot
gives you uh in the grey text so that's
not ideal
um here's another one uh this is a use
after free bug so we give it uh this
relevant little snippet of code here
inside a larger program and we get a
suggestion there that is the code that
co-pilot is writing by the way i haven't
modified that um so the language model
uh suggests right to buffer free buffer
and then right to buffer again which is
obviously a use after free so um
uh and you can see on the confidence
scores they're actually um the non-con
the vulnerable answers are higher uh
confidence for whatever reason but then
there's this one top scoring anomaly
which is the one that it actually
returns so good for that one it means
the top suggestions safe
so that's good um and then uh here's
another example we've got so many
examples it's fine oh this is my last
one um so we uh here we're testing for a
command injection using uh python uh and
what we're uh here's the suggestion we
get back from it and you can see here it
constructs that command which it calls
on your command line for your operating
system in an extremely insecure way
you could put whatever url you wanted as
a get parameter and run whatever command
you wanted with the privileges of the
web server here so this is also um
some problematic answers
so what did we end up with in and i
don't want to go through all of them um
we had 54 different scenarios for the 18
different cwes 24 of those had
vulnerable top answers of which
about half the scenarios we see about
half of python slightly more of the c
ones had vulnerable top answers if you
ask it to generate all the suggestions
not just the top ones we end up with a
thousand or nearly eleven hundred valid
programs of which around forty percent
are vulnerable um again uh the c
program's being slightly more vulnerable
than the python ones so maybe there's
some conclusion here that you can say
okay well maybe it's harder to write c
than python i think there's maybe an
element of truth to that i prefer c so i
don't want to admit it but um in terms
of
writing c code it's hard to deny that
there's not more foot guns when it comes
to things like pointers and buffers and
things that python tries to eliminate
for you
um so what are some so so basically
exactly that uh there are common
vulnerabilities in c that you know we
see these in cve after cve with regards
to pointers and arrays and use after
freeze um
one thing i do want to talk about is
knowledge based errors which is where
the language model actually suggests
things that are not necessarily bad
because they're i don't know how to word
this they're not bad because um
they have always been bad if that makes
sense so 20 years ago if you hashed a
password with md5 it was probably okay
so you took your code that hashed the
password in md5 and you committed it to
github and that was great and then 20
years later that's now horrible code the
code hasn't changed
it's just stayed constant but we know
nowadays because of uh you know external
reasons to the code that md5 is
breakable so you shouldn't hash
passwords with md5 anymore if you ask
github copilot to hash a password nine
times out of ten it'll pick md5 why is
that well it's probably because there
are so many suggestions on github of
people hashing passwords with md5 um so
this is some consequence of the language
model just using probabilities to model
things uh if you have a high probability
you know if you have a large set of data
in your training data which is faulty
you'll you'll reproduce those as bugs i
don't want to say it's only bad and
there's some common successes uh github
co-pilot was very good at generally
writing things to do with logging in and
logging out and authorizations and
cross-site scripting it was all very
good at writing those sorts of things so
it's not just bad i don't want to i
don't want to say that
so for diversity of prompt what we did
was we took the sql injection scenario
which i showed you on the screen before
and we augmented the prompt to measure
incidence changes so if we make small
changes to the prompt what actually
happens we did things like change the
white space tabs versus spaces
reordering the comments uh adding
typographical errors things like that
overall this didn't have a huge impact
in gen
we had
four vulnerable top answers for 17
different scenarios
in general it didn't diverge
significantly from the control
there were two notable exceptions
one was where we added another
non-vulnerable sql function at which
point it stopped
it almost always uh suggested
non-vulnerable code which was good
and then another option was where we
gave it a vulnerable sql function
somewhere in the prompt and then
suddenly it only wanted to generate sql
injections um so maybe there's a
hypothesis there that says the best
predictor in the training data of sql
vulnerabilities is other sql
vulnerabilities which does make a
certain kind of intuitive sense if
you're a new developer writing sql code
maybe you make that same design pattern
bug over and over again
i do want to point out that some small
changes to the documentation had a
negative effect on the top option most
amusingly if you put the comment fixed
above where you asked it to generate the
function it generated bad code so
don't leave comments saying fixed in
your thing no it's very bad
now um i want to talk about verilog
because i really like verilog it's not
really a well-placed thing with uh
github co-pilot and that's because
there is orders of magnitude less
verilog on github compared to normal
programming languages but on the ver on
github co-pilot's page it says i write
all the languages that you love and i
love verilog so
um what did we do what we wanted it to
do was check to see whether or not the
verilog
code would um generate hardware cwes and
these are kinds of things that deal with
reset logic or lock register bits timing
side channels these are the kinds of
things that mitre has expressed in their
hardware cwe taxonomy
we came up with six cwes for 18
different scenarios
about 40 with vulnerable top answers
one major note here is that github
copilot is not proficient particularly
proficient at writing verilog this is
probably a function of the language
model not having enough training data um
even though verilog is the most popular
rtl on github as i said there's just not
that much of it compared to the other
languages a big issue with this kind of
multitasking model is that um
there's not a model for verilog a model
for c a model for python it's just one
model and so when you write code that
there's not a lot of training data for
that happens to look like another
language
verilog looks a bit like c
what happens is the language model can
get confused and start writing c code in
your verilog file
and so that that means that a lot of the
files didn't compile and if you'd
actually done functional testing it
would have scored very poorly
um so what are some conclusions we can
draw from this uh well hopefully as
you've seen copilot's responses often
contain security vulnerabilities we did
89 different scenarios across our three
different dimensions 1689 programs in
total and about 40 percent of those had
security vulnerabilities within them now
that's not to say that 40 of all code
written by copilot has got
vulnerabilities we were biasing our
experiments towards scenarios where
there would be security relevant code
being generated if you're asking copilot
to sort a list it's probably going to
write code that sorts a list right
that's the human eval side of things but
if you ask it to generate code that
deals with sql or generates code with
hashing that's where you start seeing
these kinds of mistakes appearing
we think that the stems from the
training data um and uh as i mentioned
earlier the passage of time over that
training data where you've got code that
was good 20 years ago and it's just not
good anymore um and also limitations of
language modelling itself these language
models don't you know they don't
understand what it is that they're
writing they're just a function of
probabilities over the the tokens that
they were trained on and so you are
going to see these kinds of bugs
occurring
um
as an aside as part of the discussion
checking code of vulnerabilities is
actually tricky we used github's codeql
as much as we could but even then not
all cwes can be scanned for
automatically and as a result
some had to be manually marked by the
authors
and for instance that was all of verilog
because there isn't really any cwe
scanners for verilog yet
um and one other potential limitation of
this work is the sizes of the scenarios
that we showed are pretty similar to you
know they're measured in the tens of
lines of code right we we maybe 10 to 30
lines of code was the length of our
scenarios that we prompted the language
model with now a real
software suite is going to have
tens of thousands or you know or more of
lines of code and perhaps that will
enable copilot to steer itself in a more
sensible way
but that's a future work
um it's difficult to write code that's
fully secure from all vulnerabilities i
think we know that here
and i think that there's no question
that ai tools are going to be adopted um
since we did this work
ai21 brought out the jurassic one
language models salesforce brought out
language models google is bringing out
language models open ai has brought out
more language models
these language models are proliferating
i think academics working in and compsci
101 have some things to think about with
regards to um what that's going to do
with regards to academia um
according to github 50 of all trial
users of github co-pilot have kept it
switched on
that's insane stickability um and also
according to them approximately 30 of
new code that's committed to github is
now written with the assistance of
github co-pilot so that's pretty scary
when you think about the chance for bugs
to be appearing um so we're you know at
this time we think co-pilot should
remain a co-pilot don't fall asleep at
your keyboard pair the tool with
appropriate security awkward tooling
thank you very much for listening and
i'm happy to take questions
thanks simon uh so we got time for maybe
two questions and uh anyone who wants to
ask them in person can go up to mike
hello
uh uh very interesting work i just want
to ask kind of
uh what's kind of your suggestion on
fixing these models do you think is
i i see a lot of things that md5 can be
easily fixed just filter out other ones
that use it right so what do you see
like are there more challenging problems
do you see this being fixed fairly
easily by say microsoft would use these
tools yeah i think that's a great
question certainly certain bugs can be
easily fixed right
co-pilot actually already has built into
it a filter at the very last stage post
generation where it will scan for
certain banned keywords and prevent it
from presenting
possibly controversial code let's say
and so um that kind of stuff's already
built in with regards to uh you know and
there's been all kinds of discussions on
twitter about that um
so from the point of view of okay we can
just assume that we never want to output
code containing the function md5 okay
you could probably do something like
that that would eliminate a class of
bugs but the problem is is there's much
more difficult bugs that are much harder
to solve even like that one example is
use after free
it's perfectly acceptable to interfere
with the elements of an array
it's not perfectly acceptable to use
that same function after you've called
free right and that becomes really
really difficult because the language
model needs to understand more than just
the code that it's writing it also needs
to understand the sequence in which that
code will execute
is it possible for the language model to
be trained to prevent that that's
something that's a little bit out of
what we wanted you know that we know
it's certainly language models can be
presented with negative examples during
training if that could be used to fix
security bugs is a question that's still
open um personally i think that i would
do what sort of what we did here pair
the tool with automated checking pair
the tool with other things like peer
review and code reviews and things like
that to try and catch the bugs that it's
producing um
in terms of the the core language model
itself i think there's still a lot of
open questions with regards to is it
possible to prevent the language model
writing bugs i think even this isn't my
own personal opinion i think if you got
a language model and trained it only
over good code it would still produce
buggy
okay just a quick follow-up we actually
are running out of time
and maz i would encourage you to ask
this question offline uh there was one
question online so eugene why don't you
set up and uh there was one question
online from fish
which asked
could you actually just type in a
comment that said
register user accounts without an
sql injection and just unplugged but
actually we have that example in our
paper oh
so uh if if you want to know what it
does with that exact pretty much exactly
i don't know the wording is not quite
the same um you can check our results
you can check our paper we have that you
know fixed sql injection register with
our escrow injection that is in our
paper so you can you can check beautiful
all right and there's a couple of more
questions online and i'm hopeful that
you'll be able to yeah i can look into
that all right thank you so much thank
you