again thank you
yeah thank you ian for the introduction
good morning my name is xiao jiang james
stu
i'm a professor at the stevens institute
of technology today we're going to i'm
going to present
the work that done with my student how
shi
chen longfu and my collaborator chanzan
so the title is called the delay rack
talk on your smart home
which is a delay-based automation
interference attacks
so we all know from familiar with smart
homes i'll go quickly smart homes we can
use for remote monitoring control you
can do voice control and also they
provide data virtualization most
importantly provide home automation
this particular work
actually utilizes another work from our
group which is called iot phantom delay
attack
the fentanyl attack worker was actually
done before this attack but the due
diligence reason was uh
published later than this one so it will
appear next month in dsn 2022 okay next
month okay so i will briefly mention
this uh fenton delay attack which is a
stepping stone for the
attacks in this paper okay so in
defendant delay attack what we found is
that the timeout detection implemented
in the current
iot tcp layers is decoupled from the
data protection provided by the tls
layer okay and we did the experiment we
found out that actually an attacker
could for both the iot device as well as
the server or cloud platform
to believe that
sessions is still healthy while the
attacker is delaying the iot event
message or command message
ranging from
tens of seconds up to several hours we
experimented on more than 50 popular iot
devices
and
although the integrity integrity is
still protected by tos okay
so the most important feature of this
attack it does not utilize any
implementation
vulnerability
it actually is very stealthy such that
it does not cause any alarm
from any layer of the iot protocol
due to the time reason i will not be
able to talk too much about this attack
but if you're interested please pay
attention to our upcoming uh
presentation the dsn in the paper okay
so again this is the stepping stone for
our work in this paper okay
so with the delay attack basically the
the fenton delay attack will delay iot
event message or command for ranging
again from uh dozens of seconds to even
hours okay with the delay attack
we found there are two issues one is
called the disorder the other is called
inconsistency i'll explain those issues
so basically we categorize those iot
systems into three categories for smart
homes for smart home if the user usually
have a bunch of iot devices if the user
only use one platform say
smartsync or you know google or alexa
whatever one platform
and all the devices using one
communication path this is called a
single platform single pass there's no
such problem okay
another category is
okay the user has a bunch of iot devices
at home and he still only uses one
platform
however there are different devices
there are wi-fi devices directly
connected to wi-fi router zigbee z-wave
and bluetooth and also google has the
trend
protocol they connect to a hub first and
then hub connect to the wireless router
and then
going up so those are we refer to
multi-pass
scenario in this case
uh the problem is the order of the
messages may not be preserved let me
give you a simple example device
generate an event like a motion event
first and then device b say
during another event later
however if
the delay attack delay this link
then the
event one actually will arrive the
platform later okay so basically let's
change the order of the message okay
um
the third case is the user which is more
often i'll show you the survey uh
user uses multiple iot platforms at home
including for example samsung smart
things
alexa
apple
and so on iftd so this is called the
multi-platform and those
scenarios there are not only the order
issue but also the inconsistency issue
i'll just explain the inconsistent issue
to you which is very straightforward so
look at this example i have a remote
smart plug i turn it on okay and it will
send a state update to the cloud so
the wim cloud will show its own now but
if i launch a text to delete any link
here
then
the
status on will be delayed and the smart
thing platform will not receive the only
status it was still showing the plug is
off so basically even though the plug
right now is on this is showing how this
is zeroing off so
two different platforms um
managing the same device showing
different status this is what we call
the you know consistent issue so those
are the main
two main issues that
uh
enabled the
attacks that we present in the paper
okay
so basically based on
those
discoveries
let me first talk about this so we did
the
user study through amazon mechanic turf
so the purpose is to find out the real
deployment in real smart homes okay
including iot devices what platform they
use and automation apps and so on so we
already did that and we found out
from about 85 users that
most users do use multiple platforms
okay so about sixty two percent user
uses multiple platforms
and about twenty percent use the single
platform but the different passes like
they have wi-fi device so they have
zigbee zero and so on okay so as you can
see they add together like the more than
80 percent user use either multi-pass or
multi-platform which could have the
attack that i'm going to talk about okay
so this just shows you the for the
multi-platforms like most serious two
and like some use
three and about ten percent use four and
more okay
all right
so again with this uh
there are two uh main reasons one is the
phantom delay attack which we published
in another paper and the other reason is
the multi-pass or multi-platform uh it's
we find out that there are those what we
so-called delay-based automation
interference attack in short we call the
dai attack
there are some
difference
important difference from the
cross-rule interference
i don't have time to explain that right
now okay so but if you're interesting
ask me
so let me give you an example i'll use
this example okay
so the user has two platform a and b
each platform there's a one rule let's
say this is rule one rule one is when
the user leaves home he set the home
motor to be away and then when he drives
car away
and the rule will you know check this is
a trigger this is the condition if the
user away drives away it will
automatically close the garage door this
is the rule one rule two is the one
on a different platform when the garage
door is closed
and if the user is away i'm gonna also
make sure the front door is locked okay
so those are two different rules running
on different platforms
so what the attack could happen is
the the attacker could delay
the uh user away message on platform b
okay
so the user away message was
not sent to platform b
okay and then platform b will check
condition it does not satisfy it will
not lock the front door which means when
the user left the home the front door is
left open okay could it could be left
open so that's one example
uh in this research we did the
systematic study of the dai attack and
we used some formulation and we
categorize those di attack into seven
categories and summarize the in this
table and in the paper unfortunately i
don't have time to explain each one in
very detail so basically we look at the
because as you know for the home
automation rules typically use the
trigger condition action uh
you know
triplet and based on those combinations
whether they're overlapping where
they're conflicting and so on we
categorize into seven categories
uh and the main issue being explored are
the two issues i mentioned inconsistency
and disorder and sometimes directly from
the delay like the you can actually
attack and delay a command sent to the
iot device like lock the door or
send the fire alarm stuff like that okay
so the consequences could be either some
intended wanted action being
canceled out not executed or there could
be unwanted chain execution or there
could be infinite loop or like it could
be some two action usually should be
a happen first b happened second but
due to the attack that the two action
could have different orders
so
i will explain uh like three in details
okay again i don't have time to go
through each one okay
so let's look at some example in detail
this is one of them called the condition
overlapping attack i'll start with the
example and then summarize the attack
okay
so in this uh example again there are
two platforms the user uses two
platforms platform a there's a rule says
when motion detected either investment
or in the in the house
and if the user is at home turn off the
camera for like a privacy issue for
private reason
the other rule running on platform b
is when there's motion detected in the
house and if the user away then there's
something wrong right and then i should
like send alarm and the notified user
and so on or send the
security video to either the user or the
security company so those are two rules
what attack could happen is
when the user left the home
the attacker could delay the user away
message that's sent to platform a so in
this case on platform a
on the cloud is still showing on local
server it's still showing user status at
home so it'll shut down the camera and
which will prevent the
second rule on platform b from executing
and if there's some burglar or intruder
get in then it will not be
kept captured by the camera so that's
the condition overlapping attack and
this kind of attack would not happen in
the normal situation because as you can
see they have the same trigger they have
a different condition if they are on the
same platform it should not happen uh
you know both
at the same time okay however if they're
running on the different platform and
also if there's a delay attack then this
could happen okay
so
i'm going to skip the summarizing okay
so let me go to the next uh example the
other exam example i want to present to
you is
called action disordering a tag
in this case i see i only have three
minutes left i'll skip this one i'll
talk about next one okay next one is a
little bit more interesting so this is
called condition enabling attack in this
case there's still two rules uh one rule
is
the user setup when he come back home
and so he first will enter
the house and then the door will be
front door be locked closed and then the
home was in away mode then the rule will
you know set home to the home mode and
the closed garage door say that's the
evening okay
and the other rule is running on
different platform is called when the
user leaves the home it will be
used it's when
user after user left at home and the
front door closed
and it was in the home mode and then
you know it will open the garage so
the user can drive the car out and then
and so on okay so what could happen is
say when the owner is back home and
again the home was set away mode
then
both this two rules will be triggered
because
you know this happened okay
the attack happens is
the attacker could delay the front door
closed event to platform b so this has
been delayed it's not executed
immediately this is being executed and
it's set to the home mode and it delay
like say
20 seconds or 60 seconds and then
release it okay and then when the rule 3
receive the delayed uh door open message
you're around this rule and the home
mode already is set to home and landing
will open the garage so what happens is
when after user come home during night
the garage door will left open so that's
a safety issue okay
i'm running out of time so i'm going to
go fast so we evaluated the da attack
using two real smart home test pad those
are the technology uh the configuration
of testbed
with those numbers are representing
different iot device we bought a
commercial device okay
for the two test bed we use a total of
55 iot devices connecting to six
cloud-based platforms including smart
things amazon alexa wemo and so on and
two local platforms including apple
homekit and philip hughes and we
installed a total of 36 automation rules
those rules are obtained from the
official app store and from existing
papers iot papers all from the
existing iot foreign so those are not
like we randomly made up those rules
okay
okay so
those are part of the rules again i
don't have time to go through it sorry
um
so we validated several things
first we measure the the actual delay
that
could be caused
for different kind of da attack those
are different attack
type
and those are what kind of like a iot
event or command command being delayed
including like a motion active event
door close event
user away mode set and so on okay and
this tells you you know what channel to
delay it we implement all those okay
and those are the delay range depend on
several you know factors
so
anyway
so the delay ranges from 10 seconds up
to
like 600 seconds and for the apple
right now their implementation if
there's an event being sent to the local
server they don't send acknowledgement
so
for this
case you can delay for as long as you
want i mean uh so it could be tested
like up to 40 minutes or even longer
okay
and we validated all the seven
categories of da attack in our test bed
uh with one experiment is without attack
everything runs normal okay so like the
lock is supposed to be locked it got
locked
in the garage door lock got locked
and if there's an attack then where's
the
things could happen like the garage door
is not locked
or the
outlet is supposed to be turned on but
it turned off after like two seconds the
heater turned on which messed up the the
what the user wanted and in this case
the camera turned on uh after like over
500 seconds this is because the delay
attack okay it's supposed to be turned
on like immediately so anyway
we violated all the
da attacks and all being validated
the other experiment we did is
we also measured the attack
opportunities and the success rate
over a week and this is the summary for
some of the tax
the success rate is pretty high
but some of them are not like always you
can have the attack
again depends on the configuration the
user activity and so on and most
importantly uh so some of the hacks you
need to delay to be like
long enough like a 20 second or 15
seconds sometimes so such that all the
conditions satisfy okay so not
all uh are that high success rate okay
but over the time you know even with 50
percent once in a while the attacker
will have opportunity to launch the
attack okay
okay so i think i'm
almost done so uh this paper mainly
presented the new set of uh tags on
almost all the iot devices that we
tested well all the devices testers have
this vulnerability but we did not test
all the iot devices because there's tens
of thousands okay
so we proposed some simple preliminary
possible content measurement like from
the user side
if possible the user could isolate their
iot using a different wi-fi network from
other users last year like the same
wi-fi network from the vendor side they
could revise the iot protocol such as
reduce the keep alive
time and the timeout limit so to reduce
the attack window
and from the researcher point of view
like us we could think about what kind
of approach we can use to detect the
potential conflicting automation rules
again those automation rules if you look
at them you don't see any problem but
because delay attack and the multi-pass
multi platform
that could be those serious problems
okay so let me summarize that
so again uh
okay we disclosed that this won't be to
a number of iot vendors including google
uh apple simply save for ring and so on
and uh
several companies acknowledge the
problem like google they awarded us five
hundred dollars uh and simply saved in
the ring they actually
they tested themselves and they they
found that they do have this problem and
they said they're gonna improve their
protocol okay so let me summarize my
talk okay so basically we utilize the
primitive which is the fenton delay
attack which is
our another paper this which is a
stepping stone based on stepping stone
and based on multi-pass multi-platform
we found their disorder and
inconsistency issue and based on that we
found another family of new attacks
which called the dai attack on
automation rule which could cause
serious consequences on smart homes
including door opening fires and so on
and if we evaluate it onto real world
testbed
we propose some simple preliminary
counter measurement that's all thank you
so thanks xiao jiang there is one
question from online like kushar kumar
asked
all the categories of attacks observed
in all platforms for example google home
kit
have you identified any devices that are
resistant to these attacks
again we tested like uh 50 different
devices for the device we tested
they are vulnerable to those attacks but
uh i don't want to say
uh you know it works for every device
i'm not 100 sure there could be
exceptions uh yeah again there's tens of
thousands iot devices so
uh but based on the popular device we
tested that they all worked
thanks for talking uh chairwoman from
rsu i have a question about
uh can you talk about about how you
implement the attack do you send the
jamming signals and how long the delay
uh how long delay the attack should be
okay okay so this basically um
is the the question for the other paper
but i can briefly answer it uh it's not
the jamming exec it's totally different
from jimmy and tiger the main difference
is we're not discarding the packet we're
just holding the packet and we will
at some point release the packet
and
the the server side or the iot site will
receive the message and there's no alarm
timeout being caused okay jamming is you
jam it the packet got dropped uh but
and then you have to reset stuff like
that disconnect reset but in our case
the attack
uh the package has never been dropped
but the factory will be delivered at
some point
and
the other party the receiver side does
not notice any problem okay so that's
the one main difference
um
how to implement attack let's remove a
lot of details uh maybe you can contact
me offline and i can send you the other
paper it takes a lot of time to explain
the details yeah thank you i want to ask
how long the delay should be the attack
because uh okay you know the the iot
slave iot devices they report
periodically their status to the master
device yeah and when the for example
activator close the door and after it
complete the task it would report the
status so yeah the delay consider
this
yeah we consider all this factor we
again we experiment on uh 50 popular iot
devices
those are the some of the range the
short one could be like 10 seconds at
the longer one to 600 seconds and as i
mentioned some of the apple devices you
can delete at least 40 minutes
or even longer yeah so it depends on the
device depending on their timeout
mechanism keep a live
session and so on yeah yeah
thank you sure thank you so thanks
xiaojiang and thanks everyone for the
questions there are actually more
questions online maybe shut down you can
address them like oh blend and if you
like anyone else want to ask questions
you can talk to the author of line
because we are really running behind
yeah
okay thank you thank you