hi everyone uh thank you all for coming
today
uh so
what's the big picture of this talk well
dp is well studied in local and central
models but today we're going to focus on
the newer shuffle model
in this model like uh earlier protocols
for histograms demanded many messages
from users
our work reduces that cost and we
discover a neat side effect of that
reduction
so to set up this talk i'll define some
terms uh well
users are going to be human beings so
some raw personal data
that we want to keep private
and an analyzer is something or someone
who wants statistics
which concern the population
and we'll consider an adversary who
wants data on a individual level
right so given this terminology uh
let's define differential privacy well
loosely speaking it ensures that an
adversary's view
is insensitive to any one user
so we'll consider two data sets to be
neighboring if they differ from one
user's data and the protocol is going to
be differentiate private
uh if for all like neighboring inputs
and for all outcomes
uh the likelihood of that outcome
changes only slightly when we change
inputs
all right so
the slight change is quantified by
epsilon and delta which is a hybrid
multiplicative additive bound
but the question uh
we have to ask is like how is this
protocol structured
and who generates that view that we're
going to be looking at
right so in our work we studied the
shuffle model uh it has its roots in
batodol and was formally defined in my
work
while we modeled the analyzer as being
untrustworthy the adversary could
control it
which means users perform local
randomization to protect their data
but unlike the local model which you saw
previously there's also a service or
functionality called the shuffler
it takes in the end user messages
and applies a random permutation to them
right so it's like you're dropping off
envelopes in the mailbox and processing
random order
well the important thing
is that we designed the randomizer such
that the
this big box is privacy preserving uh n
executions of the randomizer followed by
a shuffle
uh unlike local privacy we don't care
how private r is on its own
uh we only care about the composition of
shuffling and privatization
notice that we're allowing multiple
messages
from each user so everybody drops off
multiple envelopes in them by box
right of course well we like to keep the
volume down because that's like
communication cost
so that's like one thing we want to
measure
of course like why should we study this
model of all possible models well
there's existing literature on shuffling
uh ranging from mixnets and anonymous
communication more generally
and of course anonymity is inherently
appealing to users like if you want to
sell something or a product to your user
base anonymity is a nice thing to have
and the final more theoretically
interesting property is that shuffling
bits is like the same as adding bits or
counting
this is very neat because
it implies easy deployment of some
centrally private algorithms
okay so i've defined the shuffle model
but what's the problem i'm going to
solve
it's called histograms
and in this problem each user has some
discrete value
and the goal is to privately estimate
the counts of each domain element
so every j in
j in a set one through d
and so we'll try to minimize minimize l
infinity norm which is the maximum error
of any bin
all right so
the question we'll explore is can we get
low error private histograms in this new
model
and can we do so using a few messages
per user
and just to clarify by low error i mean
like polynomial and one over this
privacy parameter and like log terms
all right so the answer is yes uh we
demand only uh two messages per user
one n is sufficiently large
and a side effect is that the estimates
are robust to malicious users
uh who wants to bias the computation
all right so
that's the answer to our question but
just to put things in context let's
compare our work for some prior work
and probably work with victor balzer i
have a protocol for with d messages per
user which is very large because that's
the number of bins
this was improved by work uh by gaussian
doll down to polylog d
but then the same roughly the same team
got the result that was vanishing with n
so as you increase the number of users
the number of messages per user actually
goes down
uh but there is like a linear indeed
term which is not that good and in our
work we get best of both
we have a poly logarithmic dependence on
d and like a vanishing of n uh property
right so for the rest of the talk i'll
explore like what this protocol exactly
is the experiments and a robustness
property that the protocol has
so without further ado let's look at the
protocol
so
in our protocol like each user will do
the following
they'll encode their value as a one hot
string
the position of one is their value
then they flip each bit with a small
probability so in the local privacy
letter that's called randomized response
the next step is to construct extra
strings of all zeros
and then repeat the bit flipping
procedure
right so in other words like
each user makes k fake users who each
have a zero string and then we just
apply the randomized response to all
strings
right when we're sending all these
strings to the shuffler who then sends
it on to the analyzer
who then computes some estimate based on
this set of strings
all right so it's a somewhat
straightforward protocol but
like how do we choose parameters for
privacy like why is it private
well without loss of generality let's
look at like two neighboring inputs well
in one input i have a one and the other
would have a two and everybody else is
the same in both data sets
and so that notice that if we give x to
the protocol uh the first user encodes
one as a one hot string one followed by
zeros
in the neighboring data set we have a
zero one followed by zeros so like we
change one user
they change their encoding
and like fake users in either case they
encode the zero as like a string of all
zeros right
uh but and but these strings are not
sent to the shuffler uh they get
randomized first
so like what happens well the one gets
mapped to bring nearly one minus q and
zeros get mapped to a bernoulli queue so
this is what the first user sends it's a
one long string that's randomized
and then
the in the other case using one sends a
different randomization we just shift
the bias position
and in both cases the fake user sends a
message from uh the product distribution
uh bernoulli queue
all right so these are messages sent by
each user
now notice that like the suffix of each
message is like basically the same
distribution
they contain no information about the
user data so it's safe to ignore the
suffix
right the coins do not depend on user
data so we ignore them
but also notice that on
the first input
the mode of the message is one zero
and on the other input the mode is zero
one
and we focus on the mode because that
ends up being the hard case with the
venture privacy
right so
given this like how does our privacy
analysis work well we saw the
observation that uh the shell first
output is determined by counts
so
it's another collection of messages so
all we really have are a histogram of
value frequency the frequency of
messages
and so we can represent this as like a
bar chart or a histogram
and again like i note that we have two
different inputs neighboring and the
hard case is where we have the modes you
know each user reports the mode
and this is 0 1 0
on input x and zero one on input x prime
we also have fake users contributing
messages so we'll draw them as purple
bars
and these are random values
and the second observation we have is
that well the odds that fake user
reports zero one is the same as the odds
their point one zero
right so it's a 50 50 or a fair coin
which bar they end up being in
so when there are m fake users reporting
one of these two values
the count of zero one is going to be a
binomial
m comma one half
right so because you have m people
flipping of your coin this is what the
frequency is end up being
ends up being
all right so we have this binomial
distribution so why is this interesting
well it's interesting because of the
following reason
adding this noise to account ensures
differential privacy well
whenever this m parameter is
large relative to privacy parameters
all right so all we have to do is ensure
that m is large
and in our protocol recall that m is the
number of fake users
who send either 0 1 or 1 0.
this happens with a known probability
for each fake user we can just look at
the distribution that we created earlier
and by linearity the expectation is
going to be this
somewhat simple expression
but the point is that this
random variable is concentrated around
the expectation so when the number of
users is large
the number of fake users per real user
can be any positive value
and then we'll set q to be
this appropriate value which ends up
being like 1 over n k
so one over number of
number of real users times number of
fake users per real user
all right so that's the settings for
differential privacy but like how do we
actually compute with this
set of strings
well remember that the shuffler sends a
bag of strings to the analyzer so we can
compute an unbiased estimator
from
all these strings i won't go into
details but suffice to say it's a linear
function
of t sub j where
it's number of shuffle strings of a one
at index j
and the standard deviation of this
estimator is going to be
this function of q epsilon and delta
the smaller the privacy parameters the
more error you get
but on the other hand small q leads to
less error
and note that this error bound is for
one bin
to cap the maximum error we perform a
union bound over d so we get a log d
term
and now remember that q was said to be
something vanishing with one over n k
and if you plug it back into this
expression it's n k over this function
but the upshot is that
if i increase the number of fake users k
we
we reduce the scale of error so this
factor approaches 1 from above
right so this is an interesting property
which bears out in the experiments
so what exactly are experiments
well to start off we downloaded a list
of english words and then a set of
tweets from prior work sampling one word
per tweet
and then we ran this fake user protocol
with varying choices of k
and for this fixed set of privacy
parameters
and then we also simulated an earlier
protocol the same epsilon delta
and as we expected increasing the count
of fake users reduces the error up to a
point because it starts approach one
from above and so it levels off at
around four but the change is still
noticeable
and we also compare two protocols uh the
prior work has worse error in our
experiments
it's an order of magnitude worse uh this
comes from the fact that the prior work
was designed for a large d
uh but in our case like the
dimensionality was smaller than one over
delta so our protocol does better in our
experiments
uh let's close off a robustness property
so what is robustness well
we're imagining
a user who is malicious they can send
arbitrary messages to the shuffler which
will affect their computation performed
by the analyzer
obviously
so as a baseline example you can run the
randomizer on value one which means it's
gonna be some bias towards one when
maybe there shouldn't be
but there are potentially other ways of
biasing the computation
so what's the worst that can happen
well it turns out the uh our protocol is
robust to anything
malicious user can do
and this comes from the fact that we
have an estimator that's a linear
function of this count t sub j where
it's number of messages that have a one
in position j
and the point is that each message
shifts this counts by one right it's a
count
and any user sends a bounded number of
messages k plus one messages
so what this means that a crop user's
influence is bounded by
k plus one times this scaling factor
and so this influence is a constant
whenever k is
small right so as long as k is small we
have a bounded influence per user
and so uh we also know that other
protocols have this similar linear
dependence on number of messages and so
as they have more messages they have a
worse uh
they're less robust than malicious users
now whether or not this is inherent is
an interesting open question uh
and with that i'll conclude my talk
[Applause]
great we have a quite a bit of time for
questions so please if you have any
questions step up to the podium
so hi albert uh i wonder what's the size
of those messages
sorry what's that uh what's the size of
those messages right so uh the naive
thing i drew is like
the size is the length of the number of
bins okay so if you have d bins you have
d bit string okay but in principle you
can compress it uh because like the
flipping rate is small so number one is
small so you can like just send them the
positions okay at one okay how does that
compare to the naive scheme if you
compress it how
what will be the um for example the
theoretical performance of that right so
it will be uh
so if the length knife scheme is d
the compressed scheme is will be like d
over
n times like primes some function of
privacy parameters oh so as increased
number of users like you can like shrink
it more okay thank you
great
i have one question so can you say a
little bit about what happens when k is
large so i think you showed that
robustness holds for constant k so what
are the challenges for extending beyond
constant k
right so when k is large like any user
has more influence so like you'd be less
robust uh
but on the other hand like yeah the
error in the non-corrupted case will be
less too because like we also have this
property where we have more fake users
reduces the scale the scaling factor
that we have
so
okay
are there other questions
you have not then let's thank the
speaker again
[Applause]