yeah thank you for the kind introduction
um again i will present our work about
finding and exploiting cpu features
using msr templating
so today i'm going to show you first of
all a bit of motivation why this would
make sense and why we need it in general
and overall in this paper we built a
framework to even also classify msrs and
find the effects on instructions and
finally i will convince you with a few
case studies why this framework is
actually usable and why the findings
have security implement implications on
modern systems
so let's start off with a bit of
motivation so what are actually these
model specific registers so you can
think of a model specific register as an
interface to the actual cpus
implementation so like an api
and usually these registers are 64 bit
wide and they live at exist in a 32-bit
address space so you can imagine that
there are quite a lot of configuration
options on a modern cpu
furthermore usually the documented in
these manuals we know the intel's volume
4 manual which basically has these huge
tables in there documenting the bits of
the actual msrs however due to the shear
size and some different constraints some
of these msrs are usually not documented
or only documentation is only available
to specific vendors
so
the general motivation of this paper was
to find msr bits and detect their
influences on the microarray actual
behavior of certain instructions
furthermore as we've seen due to recent
microarchitectural attacks or spectra
meltdown and algae's mds sampling
variants we have seen that micro
batches often add additional msrs which
expose some configuration options to the
operating system in order to give the
operating system some way of configuring
the actual mitigation
and finally as we've seen in the past
there was previous work from thomas
thomas at
domes on its own
and basically found that there was an
msr which enabled a completely new
instruction set on the certain cpu so
that's basically the motivation why we
wanted to look deeper into this huge
address space of the samsungs
so
um
so in the paper we built this framework
so the framework is split into two main
parts we have on the left side we have
this detection mechanism and on the
right side we have this classification
part the main part of the framework
itself is the msr scanning part
we use basically these two instructions
which are on each cpu to access these
msrs so we have to read msr instruction
to read an msr and we have to write them
as our instruction to write a specific
msr on that address if we now combine
these two
instructions and the property that if
this operation is not permitted on a
given msr we can basically scan the
complete 32-bit address base and
furthermore also detect which of these
msrs are rewritable or read and
writeable or simply not present
so
after the step we have a complete list
of all the msrs available
and then we wanted to focus a bit more
on this documented and undocumented
aspect so what we did there is we built
an
official document browser so we use the
official documentation available to the
public domain and build a byten script
that can basically extract these data
structures we see in these pdfs and
after this step we have further
granulised the list of msrs and split
them into documented msrs and
undocumented msrs
we then focused a lot more on these
undocumented msrs and more precisely on
so-called we named them dynamic msrs so
dynamic msrs you can think of as an msr
which exposes a sensor value think of a
thermal reading
energy reading or something like that so
basically a time continuous signal which
is changing
and since we know how to deal with
time-continuous signals we can use
signal processing like a correlation
analysis to find documented msrs which
correlate with these signals and that
will basically give us an estimate or a
hint to what the actual signal is
exposing
for example we can see that we found an
msr which is highly correlating to
monotonic counters so our guess is that
this msr is also exposing a monotonic
counter
so after this step of the framework we
have now a complete list for each
undocumented dynamic msrs which some
candidates which are highly correlating
to are some source hints of the actual
signal
in the next phase of the framework we
then focused on the second group which
is remaining these are the static um
the static msrs so static msrs are
basically the opposite they are
unchanging and there the assumption we
had was that static msrs expose
configuration bits so since
configuration bits are not fluctuating
or not changing that often in a normal
cpu
these are usually static
okay so and now as i mentioned in the
beginning the goal was to find the
influences of these certain bits to a
given instruction so how can we do this
we basically execute the given
instruction once without changing the
bit in an msr and then we execute the
instruction again with the flip bit and
the msr
and there we use a cool feature of
modern cpus the so-called performance
monitoring counters so these performance
monitoring counters are basically an
interface to the microarchitectural
world of the cpu you can configure them
and you can record certain events on the
cpu and then we simply make a difference
between these two executions and see if
we have a significant difference in the
performance counter readings when
flipping that specific bit or more
precisely more often more than one
specific bit
if we don't analyze this bmc difference
we can simply report
this bit as influencing a certain
instruction and we can find these
instructions
and for the final step of the framework
we then wanted to focus a bit more on
the search base itself and if you you
you might know the bios is one of the
places where you have the most
configuration options for your cpu so
here we had the idea that we wanted to
extend the search space for the
framework by simply changing a bios
feature feature in bios
which usually has more documentation
as you think of biases which have which
are feature-rich bios's they usually
have more options for a certain cpu then
they're actually maybe documented in a
manual so the idea was to flip a bios
feature and then trace the difference to
specific msrs and basically get an
insight to what this bios feature
actually uses in the background which
msr's affected and furthermore we can
also combine it with the remaining
framework to actually see if it affects
some instructions
so to just summarize the framework which
the framework is capable of we can first
search the complete address space and
find each available msr we can find
dynamic msrs and the source hints or
correlating documented msrs to get an
insight on what this signal is actually
which um
what this msi is actually exposing
and finally for static msrs we can trace
their configuration bits back to certain
instructions
and for buyers we can track which msrs
are actually affected
yeah so after we built this framework we
wanted to motivate and
show that you can actually find security
vulnerability
sorry
which can actually find msrs which has
an effect on system security we did that
in six case studies and we have both um
attack case studies and more defensive
case studies and interestingly as we
heard in the talk before the brief
brief software prefetch instructions can
actually be used for certain attacks
here we focus more on amd systems so it
doesn't directly correlate to the
previous talk but you can also think of
refresh-based attacks in some sense like
um in in the regards of like a kernel
address-based layout randomization break
so on the left we see a virtual address
based layout and the box is marking
where the kernel resides in virtual
address space if you now use the
prefetch side channel we see a dynamic
difference where the kernel is actually
located and we see a clear signal at the
position 88
so we can now use the framework to
search for configuration bits which
influence the prefetch instruction
and on amd systems we found actually an
msr which basically
changed the load dispatch counter by
exactly one
interestingly a prefetch should usually
perform exactly one load so we argued
that these bits basically disable the
prefetch instructions
we can then test the brief the case lab
break from before and we can see with
disabled prefetch instructions we no
longer see a signal at the specific
offset so basically we have mitigated
prefetch software software based
prefetch case casella breaks on amd
systems
overall only one percent of um binaries
on a debian installation use actual
prefix instructions this is also
reflected in the spec benchmark so there
is no real overhead however keep in mind
that there might be some
applications which highly rely on
prefetch instructions which are not
reflected in that case study
for the next case study we focused a lot
on this asi instruction set so the as9
instruction set is basically the
hardware implementation a side channel
resistant implementation of aes on
modern hardware
more specifically we focused on a lock
bit a lock bit is a bit which usually
gets set after the configuration is
finished by the bios and then it
prevents further modification of a
specific feature
however if we now move to a more
advanced thread model let's say the hdx
thread model we can basically flash
flush
flash sorry we flush the flash just
too much prefetch in the stock sorry so
we flush the bios and basically remove
this protection and then we gain a
primitive we gain the ability to disable
as9 the as9 instruction set during the
sjx execution exactly once
and now you might think what can i do
with that but if you now take a look at
the mtls library which basically has a
side channel resistant mutation of asn i
which is usually often used in
microcontrollers or low embedded systems
and we bring it to sgx we can see
exactly this pattern we're looking for
first it tries to verify if aside is
available and if it's unavailable and we
basically use single stepping or some
different um way to basically interrupt
an enclave at this point we can then
disable as9 at this check and force the
cryptographic library to fall back to t
table implementation and as you all
might know detail implementations have
an effect on cache and you can recover
that so we simulated a last primary
probe attack on the last level cache
since we understand model and we can
actually see the two different keys
unexpectedly have two different cache
access traces we then showed in the
paper that we can build a sub solver and
simply recover the full key based on
this attack
so for our next case study we focused a
bit more on mitigation of existing
attacks so there's this crosstalk attack
i can't go into much detail what you
have done so how it actually works but
it just leaks random numbers generated
on a cpu
so
for this talk we just focus on the
unprivileged use case and since uh for
the unprivileged use case and basically
we evaluated the leakage capabilities of
crosstalk attack and we can see that we
need to either dispute the instruction
or rdc instruction to leak this randomly
generated data and we can see that the
cpu at the instruction is way more
effective in leaking the actual data so
we can leak 88 percent of the generated
random bytes with the cpu destruction
but only 0.4
percent of the bytes generated
generated by eiran when leaking with
receipt
so we then use again our framework to
basically search for configuration bits
which influence the security instruction
and interestingly we found one we found
a cpu msr bit which basically converted
the cpuid instruction to trap
instruction
this does mean that you can no longer
execute cpuid um as you would
usually but instead it or it always
falls when you execute it
we can then basically build a kernel um
where we can build a kernel module to
basically catch these faults and emulate
the beauty on a system
what have we achieved what can be
achieved with that we can basically
remove the cpuid primitive from this
unprivileged attacker and harden the
system against
the crosstalk attack by around by factor
200.
for the for the next case study we then
focused a lot on hypervisors
due to the nature of the hypervisor they
have to closely interact with the
hardware and basically emulate a lot of
features for the guest since the guest
expects a classical hardware to run on
more interestingly the xen hypervisor
implemented the so-called deny list for
msr accesses due to the nature of a
denialist undocumented msrs are not
present in the denialist and the xan
hypervisor simply allowed read access to
undocumented msrs so if you use rdmsr in
the guest first the hypervisor checks if
it's allowed
and if if it's undocumented or unknown
it simply forwards it to the hardware
and basically returns the actual value
of
of the msr and if you remember closely
this msr we're reading here is exactly
the msr which was highly correlating to
this timing msrs so basically we can
enable a new timer in a in a guest
even if the the hypervisor implements
some sort of hardening against
timing based attacks we can then use
this timer to distinguish cast fields
from transmissions again and basically
re-enable the four-shield attack in such
highly restricted environments and
finally we can achieve a leakage rate of
200 bytes per sec approximately 200
bytes per second
and one of the most interesting case
studies was that we can similar to the
instruction behavior analysis we can
also use the framework to basically give
microcode batches so for instance we
install a microcode update we monitor
all the msrs and then we update the
microcode and see which msrs are newly
added and also which msr which
instructions were affected by dsms are
bits
why is this important because we have
seen a few cases where these microcode
updates are usually deployed months
before the public disclosure meaning
that an
adversary
can get an advantage or a long time span
to reverse engineer the actual effect of
the mitigation and that already brings
me to the conclusion so this framework
is available
on this github link
i've shown you a few case studies where
we use this framework to show that
they're actually msrs which can affect
um security in a positive sense to build
new defenses and also this msrs can open
the attack vectors and for more details
and main monitors on case studies please
read the paper the qr code is actually
working so thank you and i'm open for
questions
[Applause]
thank you for the talk i'll start with a
question from the uh online from another
question yanyon cars asks
couldn't an msr value change influence
an instruction in a different way that
is not visible in performance counters
yes totally you can think of we focused
on more on microarchitectural effects
but you can also think of architectural
effects like the rounding behavior of
floating point instruction is actually i
think configurable was some msrs and
there you have an architectural change
we won't detect in the micro hydration
behavior
so this is out it was a bit out of scope
for for that frequently thanks
hey uh great talk um
interesting work i just have like uh two
small questions is one is uh did you
notice when you were um
kind of playing with the msr
configurations if they affected the
behavior of the pmcs and
how you then use that to monitor
the effect on the instruction
yet a best example is basically the
brief instruction use case we basically
flipped one bit and suddenly we saw a
decrease in the load counter for the
prefetch instructions
oh okay okay okay so so basically you
first flip the bit then you record and
then you diff and suddenly you see a
significant difference so you usually
have a few fluctuations here which you
can get rid of if you execute it
multiple times i actually was referring
to the behavior of the pmc itself so you
use the ms to configure their behavior
yeah yeah they actually notice that
yes
ms pmc actually configure it via msrs so
you have to exclude them because
otherwise you're fussing your own
monitoring framework yeah and you didn't
find any undocumented
okay and the second one is um did you
think or do you think there's any
opportunity to evaluate how like the msr
configuration registers might affect
memory like the layout of memory with
respect as opposed to just focusing on
instructions you know so like in arms
style processors there's configuration
registers where we'll basically invert
the order right of how memory is whether
msb lsb i guess you could also i'm not
sure if it's reflected as you said in
the pmcs but if it is you would detect
it or as already here but i guess there
might be some extent
you might have to think about a
benchmark where you can see a difference
and then just replace the performance
counter with the difference detection
and it should basically work
sure
hi uh thanks for the work and the talk
uh there are like a lot of msr register
and each one contains a lot of bits so
how do you realistically uh try to flip
each bits and that's the super cross
register and all the content that's
that's
basically a lot of focus on the paper is
to optimize that so uh first of all you
can for the search base you can't
parallelize it with the course it's a
native idea uh i would refer you to the
paper for the more details but basically
we also used like an optimization
approach so we had like a limited bound
for they're also like enum fields for
msrs usually don't have single bits you
have like four bits defining something
and actually we said that these are
independent of each other and then you
can just use 16 writes to msr to test
everything and yeah they're way more
details in the paper so okay and if i
have time for one more question
so there are also a lot of undocumented
msr
how much msr did you manage to classify
and uh
on the commented side
so i have one additional slide for that
so that's actually the table in the
paper it's way too complex to describe
what we found around imd has a lot of
msrs which have um
we have today um the small caveat here
is that most of the msrs are just read
and writeable but they ignore everything
so you can write to them if you read it
back it doesn't make any sense uh thing
for the msrs which are more uh have a
dynamic effect or a similar effect we
described it in the paper but there was
nothing interesting so nothing
interesting we could find there might be
some more effects it's a huge search
base we focus on this six case studies
we could fit in the paper and in the
time frame okay thank you very much sure
thank you very much uh thanks
[Applause]
you