everyone i'm young the kim
in this talk i'll be presenting our
paper for usb
hybrid disabled fuzzing of usb gadget
stacks
usb is the most common data
communication protocol for peripherals
and smart devices
it is a versatile and prevalent protocol
for serial device interface
and recently the emergence of the new
usb port connector type c allows usb to
have additional functionality
like advanced power delivery and non-usb
video data
the usb is essentially a communication
between usb host and usb device so once
the usb device is plugged into the host
machine
usb host initiate usb connection and
established communication channel
and then fully control the following
data exchange whereas usb device
operates like a peripheral
usb host has its software stack which is
called usb host stack
likewise modern usb device like
smartphone has its own usb stick called
usb adjuster
here i'd like to briefly introduce both
usb stacks
in the usb host stack there is a
physically at the bottom called usb host
controller which physically delivers usb
data
right above that
corresponding host control driver
directly communicate with the controller
in the mirror
usb core bridges between higher and
lower layer in the usb host stack
on top of that there are multiple usb
host drivers
so different host drivers provide
different functions depending on what
device is connected to the host
and there is an application layer at the
top
usb gadget stack on the right looks
similar but instead of host function
they provide gadget specific functions
and each layer in the gadget stack
responds to the same level layer in the
whole stack
so let's take a look at an example of
usb gadgets on android
so in usb device mode
android supports multiple usb gadgets
such as mtp and midi
which are all implemented in the
corresponding gadget drivers
within the android usb gadget stack
so when android mobile device is plugged
into the host computer like the
description on the right
users are allowed to choose a particular
usb gadget that they want to use
such as various usb gadget functions are
implemented in the usb gadget software
stacks and from security perspective
it has a lot larger sort of surface and
could be easily vulnerable
and severe when being exploited
so here i'll be talking more about usb
security in particular we observed the
goal of modern usb security is to make
the usb host secure
so they tried to defend usb host by
detecting and preventing malicious input
that are coming from usb device
likewise existing usb folders
are designed to find vulnerabilities
within usb host stacks
which prevent malicious usb device from
compromising and exploiting them
so in their both threat model usb device
the one who behaves in a malicious way
providing unexpected input for
exploitation on the usb host
such an assumption sounds reasonable
considering recent real-world attacks
from usb device
like a battery usb
but meanwhile
securing usb gadget stack is left behind
even though it is possible for usb host
to be malicious
so in this work what we are going to do
is the other way around
our goal is to make usb gadget stacks
secure
through forcing technique
there have been recent studies showing
security concerns and real attacks on
usb device
so they show the attackers are
essentially able to unlock the lock
screen through usb connection and then
they have access to
private information in a victim
smartphone
this clearly shows malicious usb host is
a real thread and usb gadget device
should be secure against that
other than such a security issue we
particularly focus on two features of
usb communication from the gadget's
perspective
so that we design frozen technique we
use we get the stacks much better
first usb gadget has multiple input
channels
so it takes inputs from usb host as well
as its application side
second
usb gadget operates in a stateful way
to be specific usb gadget works based on
the state change and in each state it
requires different input value to move
on to the next state
so if any of these two feature is not
considered
then our usb gadget fuzzing is going to
be shallow
and unable to perform all the gadget
functions
based on these observations we present
as usb
audio usb is the first usb forcing
technique designed for usb gadget
devices to the best of our knowledge
it realizes state-guided and
multi-channel fuzzing or usb gadget
software stacks
but usb maximizes its fuzzing coverage
by taking inputs from the host and
application side
assuming they both can be malicious
and its mutation is guided by extracting
stain machine
and mutation rules
also usb comes with several key
at first steam machine is the one that
guides our stiffener impermutation
instability using problem analysis
before fuzzing execution
second 4gsb uses a state coverage
tracking method that is suited for our
state machine based mutation
mutation rules allows users to adjust
stateful mutation strategy in detail
an actual mutation is done guided by
stain machine and mutation rules
and mutated inputs will be delivered
into appropriate input channel
we build the custom stain machine from
usb gadget code
so our state machine is focused on
representing stable behavior of usb
gadget
particularly in our steam machine
state and transitions are related to
program points where input is taken from
input channel
so that we make the whole state machine
fully controllable by our fuzzy inputs
we call such a program point transition
point
and we do extract the stain machine
using program analysis techniques
here i'm going to walk through an
example of a steam machine extraction
from the entry point of usb gadget code
redo symbol execution
until at the transition point what
termination is encountered
and we solve the symbol constraint to
obtain
input value of each state transition
and we repeat this
for every transition point
so as a result there will be set of
transition path
and we merge all of such a partial path
into single state machine
instead of code coverage tracking
fuzz jsp uses state and transition
coverage to facilitate the state machine
based mutation
so we define two coverage tracking
method
state coverage shows whether given
states are explored or not
transition coverage presents the
coverage of explored state transitions
transition coverage might be useful
to increase fossil coverage
because our steam machine is
bi-directional
but for flexibility we leave this for
users to decide
for state proposing fosu-esp provides
some flexibility of the state away
mutation by allowing users to choose
detailed mutation strategy
to do so we define permutation rules
first
users are allowed to specify state
transition interval so that they can
stay in a state
for given time
second users are allowed to pick either
state or transition coverage with state
coverage tracking
third
users are allowed to
specify its preference for the next
state if there are more than one states
that the current state can move to
lastly users are allowed to react when
transition phase
in this step we generate and mutate the
stateful input
which is fully driven by the steam
machine as specified mutation rules
so input could be generated
towards unexplored states or transitions
so we would cover and execute more
functionality of the target usb gadget
then the generate input will be
delivered to the appropriate input
channel
which is specified in the state machine
as well
here i will walk you through how our
stafford mutation works
essentially the mutation is based on the
state machine and mutation rules
so let's assume the current state is s2
so now we are going to generate stable
input to trigger state transition from
s2
so we trigger a state transition after
three seconds according to the mutation
rule r1
to descend
we refer to state machine table and
figure out next stage could be either s3
or s4
we decide to take as fast next state
because on explode state is preferred
according to the mutation rule r3 and r2
so now we know the next state is
s4
in order to move to s4
we refer to the relevant entry of the
table
and generate the input value right and
deliver that to the input channel number
two
and then the state transition will
happen right away
if the transition fails
we will try this transition according to
the r4
we implement fuzz usb prototype based on
well-known kind of objectives color
in particular we customize this square
to make it work for usb gadget stack
buzzing
for underlying usb device controller
we rely on virtual connection using
dummy udc color module
which implements software bridge between
usb host usb gadget at the udc drive
layer
we use clear for symbolic analysis for
state machine generation
and for bio detection
we use known corner memory sanitizers
such as kazan
for evaluation we use 28 gadgets that
are coming from the latest linux and
android corners
we conducted prior experiment using 16
different combination of mutation rules
so that we use the fixed rule set the
rest of the experiment
which produces the best coverage result
based on the implementation and
experimental setup
we run fuzzy speed for the given target
usb gadgets
in the meantime
we found 34 new security bugs
out of them
[Music]
27 get confirmed and 10 got fixed
by the corresponding community
with high security impacts
we have gotten eight cvs
we evaluate the code coverage
enhancement of usb cancel that
to highlight the effectiveness of the
virginia space features we additionally
define 2k edge folders and compared to
wizard
first
g4g is a baseline gadget folder that
does not know about both state guidance
and multiple input channels
a false usb sl is a stainless version of
file usb
so it disables the state-guided mutation
a multi-channel implementation remains
the result is 4gsp showed three times
the improvement over the jeep version
coverage
ensure two times better coverage
over the spsl
which implies a multiple input channels
as they fully input generation are
essential for usb gadget step fuzzing
this is a bulky example happened in usb
accessory gadget
as you can see a point of a global
variable is assigned in thread 1
and then it is freed in thread 2.
without the validation check of such a
global variable pointer
the thread one tries to access invalid
global object
and causing memory corruption
such a bargain deep state path is more
likely to be triggered
by false usb
because fuzzy usb provides a
multi-channel impulse and stable
mutation to reach this code
even though we cover whole usb gadget
stack we rely on particular udc driver
for virtual connection
to first more udc drivers
we need to emulate corresponding udc
hardware
and we extend fuzzy speed to cover
freebsd usb added stack
but to be more scalable to closest usb
gadget stacks
we need to handle more issues like a
state machine extraction without source
code
lastly
we used a fixed mutation rule that has
shown the best coverage result in our
prior experiment
but the best rule set may depends on usb
gadget
different usb gadget could have
different best route set
relief that for future work
so for three speed stiffer and
multi-channel usb fuzzing that is
designed for usb cache device
first usb has found 33 unique security
box
and assigned acvs
fuzzy spears shows better code coverage
and both findings here compared to
baseline usb gadget folders
and we open sources for usb in this
repository
thank you for your attention to
advertise myself i will be on the job
market this year looking for a faculty
position thank you
[Applause]
county uh can you hear us
i can show you clearly can you hear me
yes
okay
now we have time for questions
anybody
um let me get started so can fast usb be
applied to other platforms such as
windows and are there any challenges if
you do that
yeah uh thank you for the question
well other than just linux and android
usb gadget stacks we
have extended volume speed to couple
more usb gadgets texts
such as freebsd already
and in our evaluation it showed a
good performance for sure so if you're
thinking about extending to
uh more usb gadget steps like it's not
open source then we could think about
more issues
for example
for gsp is uh
what is
essentially requires the source cost to
extract the state machine
and
but uh windows usb gas stack
is not a source source code is not
available so we may need to think about
some how to pay to extract the state
motion
and you need to emulate some other utc
hardware
[Music]
and etc so we need to think about that
kind of technical challenges i hope yeah
cool let's see
um any other questions
um
okay one more follow-up so you um
looks like fast usb the key contribution
is a stateful
state for state awareness and uh
why the existing approaches uh they
didn't notice this so any insights on
this uh state 4000
uh well
thank you for the question and so
yeah
[Music]
as
i explained in my presentation we are
the
first is began to buzzing and existing
use that they have been using usb
watching
android uh they are
a usb host version that genji project
and
yes uh we
brought up a couple of uh challenges and
uh motivation like a stiffness and
multi-channel
fuzzing
uh multigeneral multiple input channels
so
so you're testing usb
uh for just i mean you testing is post
modules uh
uh in
i mean usb is basically um
interactive protocol so usb host and usb
gadget
should operate in a stateful way so
meaning that you're supposed to actually
operate but if it has a stableness so
uh your interesting usb host folders
uh
they do not actually uh focus on like
improving the housing uh coverage of our
specifically focused on something
some other issues like
uh hardware emulation like to implement
a malicious usb device or some other usb
was launchers uh their particular design
to file system
initial step of usb communication output
out of the whole usb communication
so
uh there is a difference
so we could focus on the we our usb
devices focusing on the two
challenges to pictures yeah yeah it
makes sense so i think we have a
question
um
young hee from university of virginia uh
nice to meet you and uh
i have a one question that you know you
have way more blocks covered because of
those leveraging all these stateful and
i kind of assume that a lot of bugs that
you find new is just because of
those stateful
can you comment on those blocks that you
covered more
uh essentially actually attribute to
find more bugs and
are they all i mean are all bugs you
find new or because of your stateful
exploration or there are some
you know other
reasons that you can find more bugs
well actually
i think i haven't covered all this
evaluation step in my presentation
because of limited time but you know
evaluation you can see that
uh the how uh each feature of our
technique contributes to the whole
overall performance like code coverages
so we can see that
or i can say that there's a big
difference
between
i mean among the different baseline in
our filing technique we just enable that
we increment enable and disable the each
feature of our technique i mean
stiffness and the
multichain input so we can
you can refer to our paper for more
detailed questions for multi-tiered
information
uh but
uh well
we found 32
new vulnerabilities and we
we cannot say the most bound by our
stiffness or of posing but i
guess uh half of that
i could find uh
by our uh feature our challenge solution
so
yeah i think that's a good question i i
think uh uh it would be really
interesting to see like you know what
was the reason and then like like you
know how we can go further uh because
you know some techniques may be more
effective than the others may have
different techniques have
you know different combination that can
find more bugs thank you so much
thank you
all right let's thank uh continue one
more time