all right thank you
um hi everyone Liz is jumpling I this is
a joy in the work with your teacher from
Penn State yuhang Wu from Northwestern
University don't move from hajjung
University of Science and Technology
changing from George Washington
University seeing using from
Northwestern University and I can't live
from Baidu USA public release work was
was done a value estate when I was an
intern there
so Linux kernel is a piece of software
that has become a part of our daily life
according to a recent statistic 85
percent of smartphones long Linux kernel
around 39 websites are powered by Linux
kernel therefore the security of Linux
kernel is the security of our
infrastructure
however despite Linux kernel is securely
critical it's buggy
so this is a number of bugs found by six
boats which is a continuous passing
platform that runs the kernel fuzzle
in the past four years
it reported around five thousand bucks
among those bucks around 1 000 bucks are
still unfixed
since it's not really hard to find bugs
in Linux kernel you often get exploited
by the hacker community
we successfully demonstrate a local
privilege as collation on the last
latest version of Ubuntu system at least
a Year's pontoon events
with so many bugs in Linux kernel it's
important to know their exploitability
first of all knowing the exploitability
could guide the design of Kernel
hardening based on the observation of
Kernel exploits meaning kernel hardening
are developed to eliminate eliminate the
exploit component
second knowing the exploitability of
bugs promotes bug fix in Upper string
and fixed adoption in a downstream
we have seen many cases that severe a
severe bug being public in a city boat
but not getting enough attention until
being exploited
besides there are also many bugs being
fixed in Upstream kernel but there they
don't notify the downstream vendors
about the exploitability as a result
those silver bugs are ignored and
downstream kernel stays unfixed leaving
the kernel vulnerable to attacks
benefits Google has ACT to promote
research on kernel exploitation from
kctf program Google pays up to 91
330 37 US dollars for exploits in a
vulnerability in this kernel
to assess the exploitability of Kernel
box a straightforward way is to rightly
exploit however this is very hard first
Kono is complex analyzing kernel box
requires expertise
second writing kernel exploits is time
consuming it often takes experts days to
write the proof of concept
therefore
given a large amount of bugs in kernel
it's not realistic to utilize manufo
in practice with security researchers
assess the exploitability of bugs by
approximating the likelihood of
exploitation based on the error behavior
of bugs
in general most error behaviors like use
of the free Autobahn access double three
are exploitable
because let me demonstrate powerful
memory corruption capability to override
critical data
for error behaviors like non-pointer
derivance and general protection fault
they are less likely to be exploitable
since their memory corruption capability
is limited
for error behaviors like warning bugong
and info these are logs from kernel
developer which don't demonstrate memory
corruption capability so they are also
considered as less likely to be
exploitable
and this classic classification aligns
with the CVS score on the types of
vulnerabilities memory corruption bugs
like use auto-free has have highest
serious score while error locks is a
lawyers
this practical approach has been used by
mostly security researchers however
sometimes it might underestimate the
exploitability
because it's possible that the severe
memory corruption bug just doesn't show
memory corruption capability
for example you see a warning error
behavior of a bug indeed is the use of
the three
and it's possible that a severe memory
corruption bug may only show limited
memory corruption capability for example
you wouldn't see a non-pointed reference
Arrow front back which is considered as
less likely to be exploitable but when
you trigger the bug differently it may
show a memory a severe memory corruption
here I want to show a real world example
of a severe bug
the bug was personally found by this
boat and was reported as a warning Arrow
based on the approximation approach the
warning arrow is considered as less
likely to be exploitable
because it doesn't have any memory
corruption capability
in Upstream the Box still got fixed
after a period of time however sometimes
screen vendors didn't part the fix to
their kernel so it was unfixed the email
kernel
and at the time there was no CV assigned
for the buck no discussion and no public
exploit nobody was aware of the
exploitability
until we found its use of the free
Behavior with gravy and developed a
working exploit for it
responsibly describes the exploit
details to Red Hat they acknowledged our
fundings and finally patch their kernel
redhead also helped us notify other
effect vendors and the CV was assigned
for this bug to keep track of it
this tells us that a kernel bug could
have multiple error behaviors
as we can see from Stevie the bug could
have a warning Arrow
and the use of the free Arrow
to illustrate this assuming the red node
is the side of root cause
when it's triggers through Cisco a in a
picture the kernel crash at 11 node
but when the root cause is triggered
from analysis call the kernel crash at a
different place
with different inputs the kernel May
execute on different contacts and crash
at different place which shows different
error behaviors
so giving one Arrow to find other error
behaviors of the bug represent gravy and
object driven kernel buzzer
of the inside is that first the
implementation of Linux kernel is object
oriented following a strict hierarchy in
each layer the data is stored in the
object for their
as you can see in the picture in the
upper layer the data is installed in
obja
while in lower layer the data is stored
in objp
second in order to trigger the root
cause of a bug operations on some kernel
objects are necessary
for instance assuming the red node is
the side of root cause the green node is
the allocation side of the vulnerable
object
to trigger the bug the kernel has to
allocate the vulnerable object first
without allocating the vulnerable object
to set up the contacts the kernel may
actually execute to other parts thus
fail the trigger of the root cause
third
data internal propagates through kernel
objects
assuming that the yellow node is the
side of
the use side of vulnerable object the
data in a vulnerable object can be
propagated to different yellow nodes
within the scope
from a high level point of view giving
giving a error back arrow Behavior
could be starts from the crash inside
and then identify critical kernel
objects to the bug with backward and
Analysis the object identified not only
helps us set not only have the buzzer
set up the contacts needed to trigger
the bug but also Bond the advancing
scope which avoid the faster to explore
codes in a related context
to identify the critical objects to the
kernel back we first identified the
source of the tender analysis a Linux
kernel back many faced Arrow Behavior
because some check conditions are not
satisfied those checks comes around
either from the developer competitor or
that it may remains Union
for example in the left node in left
side it's a wall on check making sure
the work list is empty otherwise the
condition is unsatisfied and kernel
compliance
in the in the right side the compiler
generates the checks before the memory
read and write operation for the source
code in line 2. if the memory access is
legal the kernel also complains
to perform tent analysis we use the
variables in the checking condition as a
tender source
starting from the 10 Source we will tend
to parent structure variables if its
field is tended for example
if the base field is tended the variable
timer will be tinted as well eventually
the 10 will be propagated to variable
API and T value
we also tend to Loop counter if a loop
iterator extended the intuition is that
if there is an overflow in the loop the
loop countermeability issue of causing
this overflow look at the example
function here
in line four there is the Overflow in
the buff buffer array this possibly is
because the loop counter is too large
the 10 analysis is terminated when it
reaches to the definition of 10
variables you also terminate
when there is no colorful function for
example
Cisco entry or interrupting handle
with the analysis discussed before we
will find out many objects however the
analysis will include objects from the
abstraction layer of Kernel which is
very popular
if the object used for the fasting is
very popular it might not be useful for
two bundle buzzing therefore in this
work we first rank the popularity of
objects then we fill out popular objects
for more details of this part please
refer to our paper
with the object on hands we then use you
utilize a customized compiler to
instrument the basic block involved with
the operation of critical objects
the instrumentation will send object
feedback to the puzzle when it's
executed
so in addition to code coverage we also
have object coverage as a feedback to
the fuzzle
different from traditional puzzles the
maximize code coverage gravy maximize
the object coverage during the buzzing
only inputs reaching these sites
containing objects are interesting to
the fuzzle and the fuzzle will try to
find more
coverage or object coverage
to evaluate the Effectiveness and
efficiency of greeby
we we use a 60 kernel box in the Raw
Tour on and this is called for
comparison
after getting the result we utilize menu
efforts to realize the bug
the results are twofold the first part
is the exploitability escalation
in this part we aim to find whether bugs
that originally behave is less likely to
exploit could be turned into behaviors
blowing belonging to likely to be
explored
in the result could be identified 26
bucks with exploitability escalation
forces 4 by 6 color
the second part is to explore more
exploit potential giving a likely to
exploit bug
the use case of this will be like you
see a bug with use of the free read
Behavior you would like to see if there
is any other use of the free red
capability of the bug which provides
stronger primitive for exploitation
in this part will be identified eight
bugs with least potential while six
color only identified one of them
I want to highlight several takeaways
here
first Colonel bug could have multiple
error behaviors in our experiment we
found 34 bugs in our data set our tool
could find at least one additional error
Behavior
second exposing multiviral Behavior
contributes to more precise
exploitability estimation
ex multiplayer Behavior represents
different effects of bugs exposing other
error behaviors help us understand the
worst effect of the bug
third in a comparison to this color we
show that our approach to funding
multiple error behavior is much more
effective and efficient
we have open source our tool so feel
free to try out and feel free to contact
me if you have any questions thank you
[Applause]
questions
hi very interesting talk
um I'm Kyle Zane from Arizona State
University
I have a question about this work
um actually it's a comparison between
this work and a very recent work called
ciscope so both works are trying to find
the different behaviors of it of the
initial uh bug report
I think Cisco Cisco uses another
approach which is uh I'm not going to go
details about that but one of the
approaches basically is saying that
um
the CIS color which is grab is based on
will try to find the first report first
bug report
for example a warning but this is
actually not a good idea when you're
trying to do behavioral exploration
because for example after triggering the
warning it will trigger it for example
yourself very right do you think this
um work is complementary to your work
and maybe combining these two or you can
can give us a better Behavior
exploration tool yeah I think so so one
difference if I remember correctly one
difference between our work with and
their work is they don't
vibrate the input to the bug they don't
they just use the input from the
original report and try to find the true
effects of the input can trigger
so I think that's complementary
to this world thank you so much
hi Crystal Carnegie Mellon um
so you talk about kind of tracing
through the data structures uh the
kernel objects
how do you does that
does your tool automatically discover
that or do you need to tell your tool
about some amount of the structure the
kernel objects before being able to
trace those can you can you
explain that a little bit so we start
from a kernel crash when you crash you
see you can see the crash point where
the crash happens so from the crash
point we extract some variables from the
side and we start from this side and do
a backward 10 analysis to find some
structures
okay so you're just building the
structures from from the crash point and
and the data that's around that crash
Point correct
okay thanks
all right let's thank the speaker again
thank you
[Applause]