all right
uh thanks for the kind introduction
let's get this rolling
um
yeah this work that i'm gonna present is
uh joint work together with my
colleagues from the max planck institute
and the war university both both being
in bochum germany
and it's going to be about the ieee
standard 1735 for hardwired ip
protection
so just to give you some background i
guess most of you will already know
but
modern chips are like increasingly
realized a system so called system on
chips
that means that you have such a sock
that consists of
dozens or even hundreds of different
functional modules and those functional
modules are indeed called ip cores you
can see an example on the right side
like a sketched example
with a cpu some crypto accelerator
machine learning accelerator so
different functional components on one
chip
and due to the increasing complexity and
the time to market pressure um
we uh like
design houses hardware design hoses are
required to often resort to well-proven
third-party ips supplied by some other
ip ip author ipvendor
all right and of course if you use third
party ip there is some security
challenges that arise with that
the first one of course being that the
ip author so the guy who made the ip
actually
wants to prevent infringement of the ip
or even its licenses
second being that the user so the person
who
takes eip and incorporates it into their
design
needs some kind of assurances on the
absence of hardware trojans or
manipulations
and of course the tools that operate
with the ip that work on vip
at the ip user's workstation for example
you take like vip core and you need to
be able to
integrate it into your design so the
tools need to be able to work with the
with the ip that you get out of the box
um operate on the plain text for for
example for synthesis implementation
simulation whatever
and this is the exact reason why ieee
1735 was established
in some words on the standard it's a
kind of an industry's industry-wide
standard
and it introduces a common format for
asic and fpga fpga ip
to ensure inter operability between
different design tools
um it's some kind of a transport
encryption so the
ip is encrypted by the ip author so
the people the guy that created the ip
and is then sent over to the user of the
ip uh who then loads it into the into
the design tool and the design tool
moves on to decrypt the ip
um within memory
and as i said it's industry-wide so it's
implemented by all major tool providers
for example synopsis cadence siemens
intel xilinx and many more
and our contributions in our paper are
threefold the first one or at first we
discussed the insecurity of ieee 1735
which i'll do in a second
then we present six case studies on
implementations from intel xilinx
cadence siemens lattice and microchip
um that all lead to a full break of the
confidentiality and integrity of the
protected ip
and
in the process of doing like the case
studies we stumbled upon three white box
rsa white box schemes and if you don't
know what an rsa white box is yet uh
you'll find out in like five to ten
minutes
um but we successfully attacked those
white boxes and we're able to like break
them
all right
some words on the encryption and
decryption of ieee 1735
the encryption as i said is performed by
the ipvendor by the author of the ip
core
so we have the vendor um the vendor
creates some some ipcor
and uh generates an aes session key
and then the ip coin the session key i
used to encrypt the
the ip core using aes
at the same time the tool vendor so the
guy or the company that supplied the
design tool publishes one or more public
keys rsa public keys actually
and these public keys are then used to
encrypt the
session key and both the encrypted
session key and the encrypted ip core
are combined into something that the
standard refers to as an envelope
on the decryption side so within the ip
user's
design tool so on the workstation of the
ip user this envelope is again split
into the encrypted ip core and the
encrypted session key
then there is an rsa private key that is
embedded into the design tool and this
is loaded from the design tool and used
to first recover the a session key and
that aes session key is then again used
to recover the plain text ip
and then you can like the design tool
can go on to ucip for as i said
synthesis implementation
all kinds of different tasks that need
to be done during hardware design
so the problems with the standard um i'm
having a couple of quotes here that come
right from the standard document first
one being a decryption tool sure manage
its secrets in a private secure manner
it may harden such secrets directly into
the software you use an external
persistent storage scheme
of course the rsa private keys are kind
of a valuable target for an attacker if
you've got those you can decrypt any ip
that has been encrypted with them
and in practice um you have like one or
only a few hours eight keys per per
vendor or even per tool so for example
if we talk about xilinx vivado they have
right now i think six keys within their
two or six hours eight keys but that's
very limited and those are global across
all tool instances so there's no
different keys between between
instances of the software installed on
different different workstations
you can see the problem already i guess
not a single vendor of the ones we
analyzed in our case studies uses the
external storage scheme
that that's out of the picture
and of course recovery of a key
compromises confidentiality and
integrity of the a
protected id entirely because you can
decrypt you can manipulate re-encrypt
all that kind of stuff next problem
between tool vendors and their users an
agreement for use of the tool should
forbid tempering and reverse engineering
without being granted explicit
permission
recall that this like the tool design
tools i run on the untrusted in an
untrusted execution environment hence on
the ip user's workstations
and how ieee 1735 tackles this is just
by forbidding reverse engineering
and of course like if you have an
elaborate
malicious and albert attacker with
malicious intent he's probably not going
to be stopped by a legal agreement
um
and third last but not least if the
disclosure happens because a tool is act
that is an implementation issue each
tool vendor needs to decide what if any
software protection technologies they
will use here so what they basically do
is just to
disregard the disclosure of rp as an
implementation issue that is out of
scope of the standard
they consider the protection of private
keys out of scope
and they explicitly do not require any
protections at all
um
but as i already said like the rsa
private keys are really the trust anchor
of the standard so what you or what we
wanted to find out then
our research question was how is this
actually done in practice
and this is why we looked at six tools
uh those you can see here from uh intel
over cadence lettuce siemens microsemi
xilinx
so a wide range of larger companies and
smaller companies as well and what we've
seen is that three of those companies
did not protect their keys at all
those are the top three ones and of
course if you have no protections
recovery of the key is in the range of
hours sometimes even an hour only or
less than an hour
for the bottom three
tools we analyzed we have some form of
protection
that's actually increasing the further
down the table you go
um so for siemens we have only whitebox
crypto what i'm going to talk about in a
second and for the others we also have
code objection and anti-debugging and
for those the time to break was actually
around the range of days to weeks
i think the the
strongest one was xilinx was two weeks
um
again we successfully extracted all keys
that we could find in the tools
and the problem here being that commonly
hardware ip supports multiple of these
tools at the same time so for example if
i produce a key and an ip core for
lattice radiant let this radiant will
always also use model them from siemens
and that way they need to support both
tools they need to encrypt their session
key for both tools and now even if
siemens model them is somewhat secure
as long as lattice isn't secure the ip
core is lost anyway
so recovering a single rsa private key
can already compromise vast numbers of
ip cores what we're going to talk about
today is just xilinx vivado because that
was the most elaborate case study we did
and i'm only giving you a high level
overview if you want to see more of the
details
i would ask you to look into our paper
there's a lot more technical details
although we had to
refrain from
telling you everything
all right
how we proceeded was that we started
with identifying cryptographic
subroutines by matching against function
signatures that means that for
like open source cryptographic libraries
you can compile them and you can see how
the function stops look the first couple
of bytes of the function look and then
you can match that against the software
you're analyzing and find where
cryptographic implementations within
that software result
that way we were able to discover the
rs8 encryption and dump one out of five
keys that violins has embedded into
their software they update their keys
every one to two years so there's a
couple of new keys and old ones are
getting deprecated after five to ten
years
so they have always or at that point
they had five keys now they have six
because we got five of them um
and okay we dumped the first key but we
couldn't really find the other four keys
that they are using
and the one we got was actually the
oldest one of them all
so what we did was backtracing the
function calls uh from the decryption
routine we discovered and then after a
while we found this uh decrypt
decryption this picture that basically
selected the decryption function
depending on the key that was input to
or the key that was requested from the
tool
um
what this dispatch sadly does is make
heavy use of code obfuscation and
anti-debugging
but that wasn't too much of a of an
issue because the anti-debugging was
quickly defeated using publicly
available tooling
um and the code application was then
defeated using dynamic analysis which
was possible since we defeated entity
debugging
and that way we actually discovered
another cryptographic routine that is
called for all the four other keys
the problem is that it behaves like an
rsa decryption but looks completely
different
so we were unable to find the secret key
within the implementation or within the
memory
but we could observe that the routine
actually outputs an aes session key and
actually the a session key that we want
because we know what ipcore we put in
there we encrypted that ourselves so
we know what we are looking for but
we couldn't find like the hours a key
so after a while of
googling we figured out that this must
be some kind of a white box
implementation of an rs80 script
decryption
and now we get to finally get to what
white box cryptography actually is and
the idea here is to protect like a
secret or a secret key by merging it
right into the implementation of the
cryptographic algorithm itself so that's
actually a mathematical concept that's
not just obfuscation there's a lot of
work on the symmetric side
and
again you merge the key into the
algorithm or the implementation of the
algorithm
and then the attacker model under which
this needs to be secure is that the
attacker's full access to the software
and its execution environment like we
had
so the attacker can perform static and
dynamic software analysis
they can arbitrarily execute the white
box algorithm they can examine and
manipulate intermediate values at
runtime
and even under such hostile uh
conditions
um the implementation must remain secure
so
yeah and what what does secure mean
under like in in this setting
and this is actually where the two
security notions of white box
cryptography come into play the first
one that's a kind of natural one
security against key extraction
so
if you embed or if you merge the key
into the algorithm you kind of want to
prevent someone getting it out again
and this is what this is about but then
of course the question arises okay if
the key is within the decryption
algorithm i can just take the
description algorithm and run it to
decrypt so i don't need the key at all
and this is what uh what is called code
lifting so um white box or one one of
the the second security notion is uh
that such white box algorithm should be
secure against code lifting so you
should not be able to take the
decryption algorithm out of the software
it is embedded to that can for example
be done using hardware binding and stuff
like that
but it's a kind of a hard problem in
reality
all right
what we did for the islings and again we
have a lot of details on the white box
that dialings implemented in our paper
so if you're interested take a look
there's a lot of math in there
but for here
i'm just going to say that we replicated
the white box in python so we did
basically code lifting we perform code
lifting but when what we also wanted to
know
is can we get the keys out so we wanted
to
to analyze both white box properties
basically and of course like we we
generated an algorithmic description
from the from the python code and took
that algorithmic description to go to
alexander meyer one of the crypto
professors at our university
and like two hours after we entered his
office we left with the with five five
rsa keys and have actually factorized uh
for 48
bit keys in the process but that was
quite fast um
and then in the end you can use both the
decryption oracle that you got by
replicating the the algorithm in python
or the extracted keys to decrypt any ip
core that has been encrypted for xilinx
vivado
yeah again see technical
paper for technical details
so conclusions there's a couple
first as as you've seen ieee 1735 has
some structural weaknesses that
completely undermine its security
for example it allows for extraction of
the private rs8 tools keys of the design
tool vendors
and
subsequently allows for ip chord
decryption and manipulation
um
hence like the ieee 1735 the standard is
in dire need for a version and a
revision is actually underway and was
supposed to be published last year but i
think it was pushed back due to corona
um
and within that revision they must also
make sure to protect integrity and
authenticity because in the talks with
the vendors we've actually learned that
for for
some settings integrity and authenticity
are way more important than
confidentiality
they must point out the significance of
private key protection and of course
have a clear discussion on
confidentiality and its limitations
because
within the setting we are operating here
we will never have complete
confidentiality
that's just cryptographically impossible
so what we can do is only like implement
razorback countermeasures
so use software protection techniques
that should also be required by the
standard to increase the economic effort
of an attack and
in the end we also have public key white
box cryptography and what we've also
seen in our work is that like it lacks
public scrutiny so there is one or two
publications on public key white box
cryptography only
but a lot of companies are offering
different white box techniques for
example rsa white boxes
so you should take all the all those
implementations with a grain of salt and
be careful about proprietary such
proprietary solutions and only deploy
them with other software protection
measures in place
and that concludes my talk so if you
have any questions feel free to ask
thanks for the great talk
[Applause]
hello nice presentation uh my name is
animesh university of florida so in our
cc-17 work we found out weaknesses in
the ieee standard
and
open responsible disclosure
we got a seasoned design noticed by one
of the vendors how was your interaction
with the vendors
i prefer not to comment
i mean for for the six vendors we have
published here
they were they were nice to us so we had
a good exchange with them and
productive exchange actually and most of
them have already tackled the issues
like they have deployed
stronger
software protections
but yeah on the rest i prefer not to
comment
hi great talk jeremy epstein national
science foundation what i was curious
about is um
given that in your chart and and your
slides weren't numbered so i can't tell
you which uh one where you talked about
uh
several of them having no protection and
several of them having partial
protection
um
what i was curious about is given that
it only took a few weeks
uh
is the sum protection really any better
than no protection given that an
adversary presumably can stand to wait a
few weeks it seems to me that there's no
difference between those at the top of
the chart and those at the bottom of the
chart
i mean
at least for for
some of the unprotected ones
even unskilled reverse engineers are
able to recover the keys
so
so there is a difference
for example for xilinx i think the
attack took around two weeks that we did
that we performed
they have improved their their
obfuscation and our guess is that they
would now it would now take us a month
if not if not longer to actually recover
the keys
so there is actually it makes a
difference whether you protect your keys
or not but of course key protection is
not the only issue here because like
even if the keys are protected the
plaintext ip might still be in memory at
some point
and recovering plaintext ip can be done
all over the software because it's used
all over the design tool and you cannot
really protect everything thank you
all right let's uh thanks to speaker
again
[Applause]