now it's working yeah thanks for the
introduction sasha welcome everyone to
the presentation of our paper how does
usable security not end up in software
products
this is my colleague marco goodflash my
name is jan klemmer and together we are
presenting joint work with our core
authors nicholas busch yasmina ja angela
zasa and zashafar
let's start with the first look on some
motivating examples of our work
and one thing we see and i think that's
a common problem is that cryptography is
often hard to use and one of the best
examples and probably one of the oldest
ones is
secure email and encrypted email and we
know at least for 20 years since the
seminal paper by written at tiger that
pgp has several
usable security problems
and even today if we look about what the
adoption of secure and encrypted email
is
my colleague chris outlined it in his
talk it's only about
0.0.6 percent of encrypted email and
what we can conclude from this is that
if we have a security mechanism that is
hard to use we only see that there's a
very poor or low adoption
another great example are passwords and
their related challenges
so
we also know that passwords might be
very secure if chosen and handled
correctly but in the end we know there
are problems like reusing passwords
pinning them on a monitor and writing
them in a post-it or simply choosing to
short or easily guessable passwords and
again that shows that human factors
somehow impact security
this and other examples also from
research show that if we want to achieve
effective security in the end we do not
need to only consider security alone but
also usability and human factors
and while there is actually lots of
research and our community gained many
insights especially on end user usable
security
we think there is some problem and maybe
some yeah lack of usable security
knowledge in the industry because we see
many software products that still have
yeah let's say much room for improvement
regarding usable security and might have
severe issues in that area
and this brings us to what we did in our
paper
so for us we think it's somehow unclear
whether companies and their software
teams take care of usable security if
they know what usable security is at all
and how their processes for usable
security look in the wild
and in this paper we answered the
research question which factors in the
software development process and in the
company's influence usable security what
are contributors and blockers for usable
security in the software development and
third when and where in the software
development process are important
decisions made that influence usable
security
to answer and explore these research
questions
we somehow needed to get insights into
industry and the software development
teams
and therefore we decided to conduct
interviews and in the end we conducted
25 semi-structured 90-minute interviews
with important stakeholders from the
software development process so on the
one hand obviously this includes
developers
but it was a very diverse set so we also
talked to manager and sea level roles
and also
guys more from the usability side so for
example ux experts
and also in terms of the companies it
was very diverse so from very small
companies to very big companies with
more than 5 000 employees working in
different industry branches for example
on security products like password
managers but also other things like
variables or automotive
we recruited the 25 participants on
various channels so
one thing was our professional networks
and uh freelancers from upwork we uh
yeah that we are the
most common recruitment channel but we
also had some participants through um
social media advertisements
and
every participant then had to fill a
pre-questionnaire which handled getting
content gathering some demographic
information and especially also some
background on their
security and usability
experience to prepare and
yeah save time in the interview in the
end
the actual interview started with some
warm-up questions and some individual
questions that
yeah
got us more about the background of the
participant and then in the actual main
part of the interview we try to focus on
an example from the participants
professional career and we split our
sections
five sections
in the interview guide so
we tried to reconstruct somehow the
software development process and
therefore we started basically with the
first section
we called the communication phase so
that includes basically requirements
engineering and gathering and then going
on through a modeling phase a planning
phase contract and construction phase
which actually handles the
implementation and ending with the
deployment phase
and
in each interview we did this in two
sections so first we
did all these five sections for
usability with a deep focus on usability
and then in a separate
section in the same interview also for
security to focus on both and depth
before we then in the end focused on
yeah the intersection of both which is
usable security and ask some specific
questions on that
so more details on that especially on
coding are
in the paper but this is just the
overview and with that i would like to
head over to marco for the results
okay thank you
so um let's start with the results
we basically analyzed those
software teams in terms of whether they
were able to
to understand what usability means in
terms of security whether they were
aware of usable security and also we
analyzed them what kind of user standard
methods did they perform like do they do
proper user
research at the beginning do they do any
kind of usability evaluation at the end
and we came up with those four
categories
give me an example here um
for example this quadrant here um you
could see that we found five companies
which were a rare feasible security
which also did proper user research or
like which processes were characterized
by user centered methods
and in this for example um they weren't
aware of use both the qt's the majority
of all companies um we investigated here
and they also prefer they really had the
lack and users android methods
i will guide you to through those
categories now
um let's have a look on that
okay is the first one on the table you
see for example the kind of product the
teams
worked on you also see the company side
and whether they were aware or like
whether they have uh use of hundred
measures within their processes
so we saw a lot of misconceptions there
about usable security and what we also
experienced within this category was
that
usability or
ux experts were really rarely involved
if at all
in the next one we also
found two companies which
did pretty well in terms of usability
but security was of lower priority
priority for them so even one
participant described that they
specifically decrease the security to
increase the usability and that is kind
of a usability trait of what we saw here
and this is indeed also a misconception
because this is way more complex than
just trading usability against security
or vice versa
the next
group here is this is actually the group
which performed best from all we found
here
so for example um the
um the
participant which reported us about the
password manager explained that they had
indeed usable security as part of the
business goals yes the password manager
indeed solves a huge usable security
problem
and
we also thought that there was a lot of
um
active user feedback gathering so most
of the product teams they had um
dedicated so they actively gathered
feedback from their communities
and we also saw there that there was at
least one person who tried to build the
gap at the bridge between the usability
people and the security people
the next group that was also really
interesting because um we found six
companies uh within this category
and five of them were specifically um
focused on security and they were all
aware of usable security that usability
is important for security
but
only one company had an actively
involved designer within the processes
and also
they did not perform um
well user-friendly methods in the
process they were they really had a lack
of in that in their processes
and even one uh when
participant described it that they were
looking for a ux designer with a
security background and as they didn't
found anyone they just continued as they
usually did
so um let me now conclude this a little
bit and give you the most important
things which we found out that
blocks usable security or that
contributes usable acuity but for more
details i would recommend you to just
have a look at the paper because there
are more factors
so we start with the first one here
limited resources we saw
we got quite a lot um the answer like
we don't have time for anything um we
don't have budget for that so we don't
have budget for security or usability
and also a lot of people told us that
they like had really pressure to develop
features and record this like the
functionality first attitude
the next point here i also explained
this
a couple of minutes ago
we found a lot of misconceptions about
usable security what this actually is
and even we got participants which
described us that if the technology is
not used correctly it's definitely the
users for it and they were really
blaming the users for that
but we also
experienced that usability is indeed
sometimes not taken seriously we saw
this as we had a lot of requirement
specification in terms of security but
when it comes to usability it was more
like yeah yeah we were just doing this
so it was not often specified within the
initial requirement phase
a next point here um we saw also that i
already told like designers or ux
experts were really involved valley and
we also got direct statements from our
participants that
there wasn't
there weren't either sure whether the
designer in that case was able to grab
the fronted engineer in terms of
security
so that really kind of a communication
barrier
and now let's come to the things which
we um
figured out to be contributing towards
usable security and um
for example we saw that there was at
least one per in the context which did
well there was at least one person
which actively tried to build the gap to
close the gap between usability people
and security people and that does not
necessarily have to be like a usable
security champion which may have equal
domain knowledge on the security or
usability side we quite often saw cases
where we had like security people who
knew a little bit about usability or
vice versa
and even one participant described that
he he involved his design team in threat
modeling activities with the security
team
the next thing of course if we think of
the password manager example they had
definitely a commitment towards
usability
and
sometimes we also experience that
usability was indeed
demanded by the company lead or its
customers
the next thing here of course
like software teams have to be aware
about usable security and they also
need to have at least a little bit of
knowledge what they can do to improve
the product's usability
okay let's come to some takeaways to
conclude here a little bit so um we have
seen that several factors impact user
both security
and also that decisions are made at
different stages by different
stakeholders in the software development
process so this is not only about
developers
and we also have theme that this topic
is also interdisciplinary in practice
so um what could we recommend people in
industry so first of all like try to
figure out whether people are aware of
usable security if not create awareness
try to strengthen the communication
among subject matter experts so like
maybe security people or usability
people
try to do everything quite early in the
process so please do not just
stick at the end and do only usability
evaluation try to do this early measure
and track your activities um you're
trying to integrate and you're trying to
adapt
and
last message here may be usable usable
for qt champions may be helpful but rare
and we have seen that it also work for
the companies when you have people who
have either domain knowledge on one of
the sites
so for research um we have seen
so what does it mean for research we
have seen that there is quite a huge
knowledge gap between industry and
academia
um so like we're just at the point where
people are not aware of what usable
security is
and we have also
seen that we need kind of a holistic
view on the software development process
because it is not only about developers
their decisions made at different
stages
and
we also have seen that we have teams
which have really have a lot of pressure
which really pressed to
produce features and we can't demand
from them to just change all the
processes from today to tomorrow so we
also need uh
lightweight um
measures that we also could help them
like maybe secure defaults or any kind
of tooling which they could easily
integrate
so and with that
thank you for listening and we're up for
christians
[Applause]
all right do we have questions
i think like they may you come to the
microphone oh yeah
yeah so do you know if there is any
government in any country or any agency
that has identified this problem and
that has given recommendations or
may try to
have some standard for the companies to
follow to solve this problem
at least what so what we've experienced
in our cases that
we have we found a lot of requirements
in terms of security but the specific
crypto standard has to be used that pen
test has to perform stuff like that but
what we haven't seen
is like specific requirement for usable
security so like in any case that you
that software has to be tested and we
can test if
if users can use it or not that is what
our research is about we can test this
and that's something we did not found in
that that extent there
so
okay thanks
hi this is naman from wisconsin uh did
you find any key differences in open
source software versus
private software
oh yes i think we had um
let me think one or two open source
projects
so um
it's just like
maybe this is more like a feeling right
now but um
in so they really had communities in the
in the one open source project which
they talked about they had really a
community where they tried to get
feedback but also um they had also not
really involved our
design team there
so um
it was also mainly driven by one
development team
thank you
hi chris anasia carnegie mellon um
did you
record anything say for more traditional
like waterfall
based development approaches versus
devops-based development approaches and
how that impacts how usable security
integrates into the software development
process
oh that's a nice question
um so
just um to give you some information so
we mainly had agile teams
so i think we had one or two companies
who did waterfall in software
development
so and if i remember correctly
there's like
i think the loop of feedback within the
waterfall was less
effective i would say like you know you
just do it once and then it's developed
and the kind of user feedback which we
saw on those companies which did pretty
well in this five context
they really tried to get in the feedback
and there was something which was
lacking a little bit i would say in the
one waterfall case we had um doing the
interviews
so i mean so one of the comments you
made was there's a lot of pressure for
feature development right where because
i mean this almost feels like a case
where
the feature development is driven harder
in agile in in devops and whereas you
know
you don't get your product out as fast
or maybe even the product that you want
with waterfall but you could probably
get the usable security in and i'm
wondering how you would give advice to
um
you know for the companies to kind of
adjust between the two and get the
feedback they want in usable security
in the development process between the
two models
so i mean like what could we recommend
to people who like do waterfall
development well in both processes right
because
the because you put so much on the front
end in waterfall
um you have more time to actually work
through that usable security up front
but you know that kind of you know you
can't make any adjustments right so
that's the obvious achilles hill
i think one important point is um
that we sometimes think that we just
like could
could get people to do things you know
like um and we can't developers so in
agile terms teams are responsible for
developing their own processes for like
improving their things but we need to
give them also the time and room and
that is something i think that is on the
list of the management who really should
like the commitment towards usability
which should allow those teams to
develop to to adapt their processes and
then we also need to give them tools
like knowledge what they can do
so i don't think it's just that we could
force them to do something we need to
give them room and space also for
develop towards more usable security
thank you
hello masterfuner from mpi first thank
you for the great talk and i do have a
question regarding open source
development teams versus industry
in industry you basically have
the different
difference between developers and
designers and ux experts
and in open source team did you get any
notion if the teams are more mixed or
people having different roles in the
same person
oh yes so we had like
an open source project i think it was
about a secure messenger that was
developed
open source and they really working as
on chronos as they had people sped all
over the world so they worked a lot with
commits so in security terms
and they really had rarely meetings so
because of that kind of time zone
difference and people are spread all
over the world and like all those people
and at least in that case were not
working specifically and only at that
project it was like we had like three
main developers and then like a team of
like like say like 10 or something which
also contributed to that kind of project
so that may
make things a little bit more difficult
in terms of user feedback and agile
development
great thank you
all right let's thank jan and marco
again