all right we'll get this show going
good morning good afternoon good evening
everyone
welcome to snp 2022 wherever you're
joining from
i'm incredibly delighted and grateful
that you're all here in person and
joining us online
so this is our third year at this space
and i'm really excited we could be back
in person
this is our second year on hop in slash
gather dot down platforms for our
virtual uh participation
so um we had
this is the first hybrid conference we
had ordered you know two mode conference
we've done so we've
learned a lot of stuff so
we appreciate your patience and support
there are a few things that may not be
as smooth as as you are used to either
in an in-person or in virtual so thank
you for being patient with us before i
um jump in just a quick thing for those
joining us remotely on hoppin
this snapshot is not exactly what you
see but the thing i wanted to point out
is
when you're attending a session on a
stage
if you have questions or if you want to
chat about the current session then you
go to this stage tab and type your
questions or chat with people in that
session
under that
tab
if you have event related questions or
find the other people in the event then
you go to the events tab so that's the
that's one thing i want to point to that
point out before i dive in for those
joining remotely
same thing for
chat as well
stage versus event so be mindful of that
what a year it has been
as i mentioned i'm incredibly
grateful and delighted that so many of
you showed up in person
this opening session is a bit crowded
because
we wanted to avoid the time it takes to
switch
kick us out and sub you know put the
barrier back on for the sessions it
takes 45 minutes and we have a very
tight schedule so after this session you
should be able to spread out a little
bit more
in the three three tracks okay so the
first dual mode conference as i
mentioned
so
thank you for your support and patience
146 papers this year in three tracks
it's a 27 increase from last year and
this is the first time we are doing
three tracks in person and
tom and thorsten will talk about this
later
748 unique participants we had about 644
in 2019 when we did this in person of
course our virtual conferences had a lot
more audiences
they're more accessible given you know
folks didn't have to travel but 553 in
person is incredible thank you and we
have 200 people joining virtually
we hope you will find the conference
experience is similar to what you had in
you know um last year's virtual
conference but um we we will work to
improve as we move forward
we were able to give out about 73
000 in student travel support
54 student travel grants and nine
registration grants for for just those
participating remotely
this is thanks to our funding agencies
nsf um arl uh
onr
and ibm and ieee technical comm um
committee so
thank you so much for your support and
helping students participate in this
conference
finally we had 145k in new donations
this year we are incredibly grateful for
the donors without whom this conference
cannot be the way we do it
and even with so much support you will
see
there are some things we couldn't do
this year like we don't have breakfast
our apologies but hopefully we can
work towards fixing that
so this
is not possible
without the incredible effort and
support of a lot of um you know
hard-working and energetic group of
people so please join me in thanking our
organizing committee they have put in an
incredible amount of
work almost a year and a half
so we have a long um committee and this
year
uh alvaro cardenas who was our general
chair last year stepped up to work on
the virtual experience as well the
website doesn't reflect it but i wanted
to mention it here so he's also our
unofficial virtual chair
we have a steering company now i i don't
think we've had this
the last time we were here in person but
got incredible support and advice uh
from our steering committee
and our incredible technical committee
on um tc on security and privacy brian
gabriela yong and tegan thank thank you
all for your support
as i mentioned this conference wouldn't
be possible in in some of the things
that we do wouldn't be possible without
the incredible support from our donors
we are grateful for nsf arl ibm onr um
for their um travel grants and ieee
technical committee and
incredible as you can see many of these
are long time supporters we also have
some new ones intel inl and skyflow this
year and certik
so we thank them for their continued
support and hopefully many of our
past donors who haven't come back
since during the virtual times will be
coming back next year to us
we have a very tight and incredible and
exciting program of events we have a
poster
and networking reception this evening in
pacific concourse so one level below
from 5 30 to 7 30. our poster share has
done an incredible job and thank you for
the suggestions from the community for
those who were aimed who weren't able to
present their papers in 2020 and 2021 in
person we offered them the opportunity
to bring their papers as posters so they
have opportunity to showcase their work
from the last two years okay
so we have about 45 uh posters um in
person we have another 10 that will be
we'll be doing virtually
networking on hop in is always open so
you can click on the networking
button on the side and you will be
randomly paid with some paid with
someone
that was a very popular feature
but during our student speed mentoring
session this evening at 6 00 pm
that networking feature on hop in
will be configured to pair students with
non-students so they can have a virtual
mentoring experience so please
participate
and otherwise networking is always open
up open on hop in not just for those who
are participating virtually for
everybody here all of you should have
access to the hop-in platform and you
can take advantage of that
um virtual poster session as i said
there are some
posters that are just virtual and all of
our posters will be available in the
virtual poster session for for our
remote participants and this will take
place at 7 15 a.m
and again on wednesday evening in two
different time slots for so the people
joining from different time zones um may
may be able to participate
we have shot talks in parallel um on
tuesday evening uh five to six in
ballroom a
and this year we have uh for the first
time at snp um lgbtq plus allies social
hour everyone is welcome this will this
is going to happen in waterfront a b
and thanks to google for sponsoring
drinks for the social hour
we have a tc business meeting tuesday
evening 6 to 7 15
this will be entirely virtual this year
on zoom as we wanted to open it up for
all our tc members which is about 3 000
people
and also our tc chairs
couldn't join us in person so this was
you know
and a better way to do this
um i know
there were some concerns about um costs
of snp so that will be a topic that we
will discuss uh during the tc meeting so
please join us
you should all receive as uh zoom link
soon if you haven't already okay
as i mentioned virtual poster session on
wednesday evening after the last
technical session okay
we have an incredible set of workshops
six workshops on thursday may 25th and
the programs and links are available on
our webpage
a couple reminders
this is also printed behind all of your
badges it's not visible because you have
probably
maybe a food card behind your badge
obscuring it but
the proceedings from this conference are
available at this link and there is a
password in the username that is printed
behind your badge so please access them
and in the tradition of snp
you will have access to preceding all
snp proceedings from past years as well
once you go to this link okay
and please
tweet
using the hashtag sp22 or ieee sp
and a few announcements so as you see
seating in each room we've tried to
reduce the number of seats at the tables
to allow for distancing so seats in each
room might be a little tight so help
each other find seats
this room is a little bit more packed
than we expect just because we are doing
uh all um all 500 people in in in this
room
um
as always this is the third time and for
those of you who haven't been in this
space if you see outside we are right
next to the street san francisco and
it's an open space so please be mindful
of your belongings
people can access this space easily so
just wanted to give you um a warning
apparently people know that there are a
lot of conferences happening here so
apparently a
spot for professional thieves
we have reduced seating at lunch tables
this year to allow for a little bit more
distance
and there will also be a few tables with
even more reduced seating available if
if you prefer to do it that way okay
and with that
i have to confess to a little royal mess
up on my part
um you all have
this
what i thought was an awesome
program for the conference
but
there is a copy paste error
uh sessions eight and b
the paper listings is not accurate
so thankfully our website and hop in um
you can maintain an agenda on our hop in
mobile app we'll give the right listing
of papers my the apologies for the
authors in those sessions
i'm gonna see if i can find a workaround
but right now i have a plan but until i
can execute it i will keep it to myself
thank you and my apologies again for the
authors in in those two sessions
uh finally um code of conduct we have
instituted a code of conduct in 2018
it's available we want to make this
conference a welcoming place for
everyone um if please review the policy
and i hope all of you adhere to this
policy we
typically don't have um too many issues
but i i hope it continues that way but
if at all you you find something that
violates this code of contact there is a
number on our website that you can call
it'll allow you to reach me and there's
you can also report uh by email
and there are also folks
walking around with this
code steward badges you can find them
and report any incidents you
have noticed or experienced as well
finally
you've seen this
while you're speaking on stage it's okay
to not have your mask
since there is enough distance and while
eating
we have to take them off but at all
other times we request that you keep
your masks on
we understand
that many of us are vaccinated and
maybe this is
some of us might feel this is not a
requirement but
many of us have to travel back in
testing positive will put a damper on
your travel plan so that's why we have
this in place so please kindly keep them
on and help all of us get back safe and
healthy
with that i will introduce our
incredible program chairs thorsten and
thomas
to come on stage and talk about the
program this year
[Applause]
okay yeah a wall a warm welcome also
from my side so either here in person or
remote my name is dawson halls and
together with tom riston part i had the
great pleasure to organize this year's
program
but first of all i would
again like to thank rakesh and this team
because rakesh not only organized an
in-person conference but he also
organized an online conference so two
conferences and this was an incredible
amount of work and it's a great pleasure
to be here today
this is the 43rd edition of the
symposium and it's the first hybrid one
so you will see that everything is
probably a bit new to us so we will have
a mix of both in-person presentations
remote presentations which are
pre-recorded videos
so after two years of
just virtual events we are now getting
back here in person but you will still
feel that we are in the middle of a
pandemic
so we have about 40 papers that are
where the authors are not able to come
here either because they cannot leave
the country due to the pandemic or they
didn't get a visa or due to other issues
so we try our best to make this still
and a good experience for everyone and
so the next three days will be exciting
so enjoy the time meet people talk to
people in the hallway and it's good to
be back to in-person events
still given that we are in the pandemic
please wear the mask and be a bit
cautious we heard the reports from acm
kai where a lot of people got infected
so honestly i hope that we will not have
it here at ieee the symposium on
security privacy
on thursday we will have one day of
workshops rakesh already mentioned this
so there's vood langsag dls and several
others so
in case you stay here or probably you
can also register if you want to stay
longer so this is an interesting week
full of
papers on security and privacy
in the next about 50 minutes i want to
present an overview of how we came here
so basically what was the processed the
process used in order to assemble the
program
everything started back in january last
year when tom
or when it became clear that tom serves
together with me as the pc chair so the
first step was to assemble a program
committee
we assembled a pc with more than 170
members
this is about 170 members because some
people had to step down during the
process given that it's a huge
commitment for one year or they had to
pause in one cycle but we had about 170
members in each
of the review cycles helping us to
review all these papers
what we tried to do is to cover a wide
geographical distribution so we had
people from the us from europe asia
australia we had people from industry
from academia so we
tried to assemble a pc with a broad
expertise given that the symposium
receives quite a wide variety of papers
ranging from theoretical results over
implementations usability aspects and
many other topics so we had to make sure
that we have the right people on the pc
and i think this worked also in most
cases
a challenge was that the conference is
growing year over year so we had more
than 1 000 submissions this year and so
we had to scale the whole procedure and
what we introduced for the first time
was the concept of associate shares so
these were specific people that helped
us especially with scaling
so in the first phase for example they
proposed us pc members which we could
invite then they helped us to manage
reviews they supported the discussion
and the rebuttal phase and helped us
also to converge on decisions
so without these associate shares it
would have been impossible for tom and
me to actually manage
all of this so
i'm very glad that we found a few people
who served in this role
the pc members reviewed on average about
20 papers across three cycles so per
cycle about six to eight papers and
reviewing 20 papers is a major
commitment
so without the pc we also would not have
been possible to assemble the program
and on the website you find all these
names of these people and so they did
most of the work in order to actually
assemble the program we will enjoy in
the next three days
we always strive for positive and
constructive reviews so we always
encourage them to provide constructive
actionable feedback that the authors
could use
of course this is a bit subjective some
of the reviews you have received
might not have this feeling but
this is the typical process and we tried
our best and what we also try to do is
to have a positive communication and
online discussion i think this worked in
most cases and i'll come back to some of
the mechanisms we used on the next few
slides
given the current situation we didn't
organize a physical pc meeting and also
no virtual one but what we did is all
discussions took place in hot crap so we
only had online discussions in order to
decide on which papers to accept or
reject
i think overall we had a good experience
maybe the process can also be improved
in the future but that's something tom
and patrick can figure out in the next
years
for the review process what we did is we
reduced the number of deadlines from
four to three
this was based on a discussion we had
last year in the community and also the
experience from last year where the
number of submissions in the first
deadline was rather low so therefore we
decided to skip this and stick to three
submission deadlines
and in each of these
review cycles we had two rounds of
reviews
in the first round we assigned two pc
members for each paper and if both
reviews were clearly negative so if
there was clearly no chance that the
paper would end up in the program then
we decided to early reject this paper
and these early reject notifications
were sent out after about one and a half
months
in the second preview phase we assigned
two in certain cases also three
additional pc members especially for
controversial papers in order to make
sure to get additional opinions so for
each paper we had at least four pc
members who reviewed this
what we then also introduced is an
interactive rebuttal phase where the
basic idea is that we released the
reviews after the second round and then
we had about one one and a half weeks in
order to exchange messages between the
authors and the reviewers
so the basic idea is that the authors
receive the reviews they can comment and
answer questions but the reviewers could
also
react to these responses
so honestly i think a closer interaction
between authors and reviews really helps
so i think we had overall a pretty good
experience
many cases where there was a lively
discussion between authors and reviewers
but on the other hand we also had cases
where
either reviewers were not really
responsive or authors only submitted
their rebuttal on the last day of the
rebuttal phase so in many cases this
also did not work but i think we learned
a few lessons and if you have ideas how
this whole process can be improved
please let us know because i think this
is also one of the challenges to solve
for the future how can we have a more
constructive discussion between authors
and reviewers to improve the review
process
notifications were sent out after about
two and a half months and we had
three cases of ultimate decisions
and this is also something where we did
the change in the review form because we
did not use the let's say traditional
form of accept weak accept reject reject
and strong reject or variance of this
but we only had three decisions that the
reviewers could take
so either they could recommend to accept
the paper
they could accept
recommend a major revision or reject so
only three choices because we think that
reviewers should stick with what they
should
see as the ultimate outcome of this
and this generated also quite a few
lively discussions and
i think what we learned is that it makes
sense to also have a separate category
so shepherding and this is something
that is also reflected in next year's
call for papers
major visions were handled similar to
last year's so
the reviewers
came up with a list of revision
expectations
these were communicated via hot crap and
the authors of these papers had two
cycles in order to address their
revision expectations submit the paper
again and we also used hot crab as an
anonymous communication channel so in
case authors had questions they could
send these questions directly to the
reviewers and this also helped to
clarify some of these expectations
what we try to do is we try to assign
the same pc members such that they can
check whether the revision expectations
have been met
this worked in many cases in some cases
reviews disappeared but overall we were
pretty happy with how everything worked
out
this then led to the following
submission statistics so what you can
see on the slide is for each of the
three cycles in blue the number of
submitted papers so we see a bit of
growth over time
in red you see the accepted papers you
see we are quite selective so the
attributes and posium on security
privacy is a rather selective conference
that's something that we also see here
directly in the numbers and in green you
see all the papers that received a major
vision decision
so you see actually quite a few of the
papers also received a major revision
and across all three cycles we received
a bit more than one thousand so 1012
papers
from submissions to program is actually
quite a complicated process that i want
to explain as part of this figure
so overall across all three cycles we
had 1012 submissions
of which 55 were directly accepted
so this means these papers
directly made it into the program and
the reviewers recommended to accept it
potentially with a with an assigned
shepherd
overall across all three cycles we also
had three submissions of 104 papers so
these were papers that were either from
last year's symposium where they
received a major revision decision or
they received a major revision decision
this year and the authors also opted to
resubmit to one of our three deadlines
so for example a paper that was
submitted to the first deadline received
a major revision could have been
resubmitted to the second or third
deadline and this is the pool of 104
major revisions
out of this pool 92 papers were accepted
and also
and 12 were rejected so you see the
acceptance rate for major revisions is
about 88 so the vast majority of these
papers actually eventually make it into
the program
overall we have this 55 direct accepts
plus the 92 accepted revised papers
which is a total of 147 papers which
leads to an acceptance rate of 14.5
percent for this year's
program which is slightly higher
compared to the last years where we had
about 12
on average
overall 144 papers received a major
revision decision so this includes
so therefore these two errors are not
really mutually exclusive but 144 papers
across all three cycles received a major
revision decision and the remaining
papers were rejected
taking a look back to the quarterly
submissions in the past years we see
that we see a
rather steady
growth year to year
typically we see more submissions in the
fall and winter deadlines i think this
is more
related to the traditional deadlines we
used to have earlier and also the fact
that the conference is in may
taking a
even further look back so historically
back until 2010 we see that the
community is growing so compared to last
year we have about six percent more
submissions for the first time more than
1 000 submissions
acceptance rate is a bit higher compared
to last year's but still rather
selective
and
maybe this is also something we as a
community can somehow address
that the number of accepted papers is
rather lowish
what we introduced this year is a
so-called research ethics committee
so if you attended last year's
conference you probably remember the
other discussions we had related to the
hypocrite commits paper and this is a
direct reaction to this
so we introduced a new committee and the
committee is a subcommittee of the
program committee
in order to check paper for
ethical considerations and also subject
human subjects research
so what we did in the first step is we
updated the call for papers to better
reflect the expectations and this is a
lesson learned based on last year's
conference
in the review form we added a new
checkbox where reviewers could mark a
paper for ethical review
and then each of these papers that was
marked by at least one pc member was
checked by the research ethics committee
so typically one or two
rec members were assigned to review the
ethical concerns
these were discussed potentially also
based on feedback during the interactive
rebuttal phase and then the rec had
separate discussion so outside of the
typical pc discussions where they
discussed all these papers they also
organized video calls in order to decide
on recommendations
we had two cases where the research
ethics committee recommended to reject
papers based on ethical grounds
in both cases the paper was also
rejected based on technical crowns so
this was actually no real effect in
practice but it shows i think that the
process works
what we plan to do is also to do a
write-up on the lessons learned of
organizing the research ethics committee
for the first time because i think there
are some valuable lessons learned
by this committee that also the broader
community should learn especially
because we had many recurring types of
discussions related to vulnerability
disclosure how to treat human subjects
and other topics so i think
this
committee can also develop guidelines in
order to guide future research in this
area
okay talking about
papers now so here you see a word cloud
of all the 147 papers
accepted this year
i would just want to briefly comment on
two things
first
one of the keywords you see quite often
is attack and attacks that's basically
right in the middle and this is
i'm not sure whether i should see say
varying trend but definitely a trend i'm
not sure whether this is good or bad so
honestly i think it's a bit bad but
maybe you're
you think different about this so what
we see is that we have quite a few
attacks papers being submitted and also
accepted
so
many people spend quite a lot of time on
breaking stuff
while papers that propose defenses or
basically how we can protect security
and privacy in better ways have a harder
time
so i can only encourage you to also work
more on the defensive side
because i think we should not only break
stuff we should we as a community should
also make sure that people are safe and
secure so please also focus more on the
defensive side and i think we have
several great papers that propose
defenses or mechanisms or methods how we
can actually for example do private
computations or how we
can fix problems in practice
another keyword that's pride from quite
prominent is model so we see quite a few
machine learning papers and especially
this intersection of machine learning
and security is getting more and more
traction so i think this will also
influence our community in the next
years to come
then a few statistics and i will keep
this a bit shorter in the interest of
time
but two things that i just want to
mention is here is first an overview of
the paper topics so on the x-axis you
see basically the categories you see
that we received quite a few mission
learning papers then we have system
security and applied crypto as the top
three submission topics and hate and
harassment is
on the right hand side so but this is
for the number of submitted papers so
this is about the 1 000 papers
interestingly when we turn to the number
of accepted papers it changes a bit
so now attacks is number one as i
mentioned earlier we've spent probably
too much time on just attacking stuff
machine learning drops to number six so
it seems like many of the ml papers that
are submitted are eventually rejected
and
not sure what's funny about this but
okay great um so i love mln securities
it's not that i'm i'm dissing them no
it's great great work great work people
please continue
um
what um
so this is basically just a rough alpha
outline we will dig
deeper into the numbers and also plan to
hopefully write up a pc chair report but
this was an interesting statistic that i
saw
yes question
yeah this is cut cut down so this is
security and privacy of something so
this is not the title of the full thing
obviously
and then
one thing that i found interesting is or
not interesting but impressive is
how much
work is actually put here by the pc and
all the members so we have more than
3100 reviews written with close to 2
million words being written and more
than 10 000 comments so there was quite
a lot of commitment
based on the pc
the associate chairs the research ethics
committee and all people involved
what we plan to do is to
publish a more detailed write-up of what
we have learned how this also
corresponds to lessons learned in the
past years
this will take a bit time because it's
quite a bit of data that we want to
process
but
in case you have feedback of how author
thing can be done better feel free to
reach out because i think scaling our
community to larger numbers is something
challenging and that's something we need
to address in the years to come
and with this i would like to conclude
uh with a thank you for quite many
people who have made all of this
possible
so first they are of course all the
authors and speakers because without you
we wouldn't have this program of about
140 papers that will be presented in the
next three days
the pc and all the external reviewers
spend quite a lot of time on reviewing
these papers providing constructive
feedback so without them and without all
their paid unpaid work everything would
not have been possible
and then my special gratitude goes to
the organizing committee i already
mentioned rakesh and his team there were
many many other people for example
scott as a video chair
then we had mother who was preparing the
website we have awards we have people
working
for the posters and everything so
actually a lot of people who make this
possible with behind the scene work and
without all of them being involved
everything would not have been possible
then we have the technic committee with
brian and gabriela who provided a lot of
guidance especially in tricky situations
we have the steering committee to which
we also reached out in order to get some
clarifications on the general policy so
this was also very helpful and then of
course it's you
either in person or remote so we had
more than 700 people attending this
event in the next three days so thanks a
lot for coming for making this possible
and then there are people like
kate or
other people from executive events who
make sure that everything runs very
smoothly so thanks a lot for all these
organizing people and enjoy the hybrid
conference in the next days to come
thank you
[Applause]
i think we should definitely have an
extra round of applause for thorson if
you didn't realize it's a two-year
service commitment thank you very much
and as with the rest of our working
relationship he did all the hard work on
the presentation stats and i get to do
the fun stuff
including awards
so
uh
we had an award selection process for
distinguished
paper awards
uh procedurally thorson and i
chaired the award selection committee
and we had a number of pc members who
generously donated some time to do some
extra work at the end of the review
process in the last few months to try to
select some papers for their overall
excellence
and quality
so we shortlisted based on uh overall
rankings from reviews as well as
nominations and had about 16 papers that
the committee then looked at in more
detail
to decide which ones uh were worthy of a
distinguished paper award and we ended
up with four distinguished paper awards
this year
so i'll just ask
that the
authors when i announce the paper stand
up if you're here
or if you're on zoom i guess you can
dance in your chair or whatever um
and uh
and while we give a round of applause to
the authors uh and then uh you can sit
down we'll go on to the next paper
so do we need a drum roll perhaps
all right
so the first paper in no particular
order is uh four attacks and approved
for telegram uh congratulations
[Applause]
number two
asleep at the keyboard assessing the
security of github copilot's code
contributions
[Applause]
number three is invisible finger
practical electromagnetic interference
attack on touchscreen based electronic
devices congratulations
and finally last but not least committed
to trust a qualitative study on security
and trust in open source software
projects congratulations
so if you saw at the bottom we have the
sessions indicated for these uh award
papers congratulations to all the
authors and uh just a small token for
what i'm sure was a ton of hard work on
these uh technical papers
and with that we will move on to uh test
of time awards and try to make sure that
uh our remote presenter can join
all right so um thank you everyone i
apologize for not being able to uh
be at a conference um
it is it's my honor to cheer this um
test of time award uh committee um
so
um
next slide please tom
i already did it can you see what the
slides are
not really but i'm just assuming that
now it says the 2020 to
a world committee so um so this uh
uh this committee we have uh thorsten
uh the current uh pc chair uh we have
recruiter uh chris krugel myself uh nina
um oprah and adrian perrick now these
are either current chairs or past chairs
uh so i would get that i think i think
we actually have a very good
uh committee uh with uh
with us being
seasoned and active
researchers
next slide please
good
yep
so in terms of um
in terms of the criteria so first of all
test of time means that your paper is so
good that after a while people still
talking about it or still referencing
your work
so um for our committee
our tasks is to look at
papers uh from 2010 through
2012. so these are three editions of the
the oakland conferences at the
conference and then um so that so you
say what criteria do we use to decide
tests of test of time award is very
simple lasting impact on both research
and practice
and
so they say how do you decide that a
paper has
a lasting impact so obviously we want to
look at some objective evidence
then we're going to rely on our
experience and expertise
to discuss uh so that we don't let our
you know uh subjective opinion um
take control uh so
so what i did was um
i inherited a set of guidelines and and
documents from the previous committees
the committees of the previous years so
essentially we are essentially following
basically the same set of
criteria and process
i add a little bit to say that
let's be more concrete when we talk
about objective evidence so what i did
was
for all the three
conferences i mean the three editions of
the conference i actually looked at all
the papers and then
and then i created a list of uh you know
for each paper i essentially i use a
google scholar to find out the um
citation counts so i provided the whole
committee a list of papers and the
citation counts and tell them that hey
look we should use this as a you know
essential starting point so that when we
say this paper is good at least we can
point to say hey look look i mean some
evidence that this paper has been
referenced many times but that's only
one of the criteria that we use
like as it's only starting point that we
rely on our
expertise and and uh being active
research in the field we essentially
discuss why this paper is good okay so
so those are the
um how we set it up and in terms of the
the more detailed process
uh one thing that we uh try to make sure
we can do is uh
make sure that we want to avoid uh
potential conflict of interest
like i said we are you know we we are
from many different places so we have
collaborators sometimes our own papers
so i told committee members that they
should send their nomination directly to
me so that it does you know doesn't have
to be out in open initially so once i
have the uh list of nominations
from the committee members now share
with them i share with the committee
then we essentially you know uh vote to
say hey which you know what let's say
top one top three or top two top three
papers and then we discuss and they make
a final decision that's the process that
we agree upon
uh in reality it went a lot smoother
than i wanted to describe
i think i think when i presented
in the next few slides you would
understand what what i'm talking about
so basically
the papers that really started that
should uh should get this awards they're
essentially getting a unanimous or near
unanimous votes
so they almost okay we're done there's
no need to
discuss it's that simple
um
so um so with that i'm going to
move to the next slide tom please
okay it's one of the awards slides are
you ready for that
yeah okay everybody everybody should be
here to say thank you shut up let's
let's get to the world okay here we go
here we go
yeah so so i'm going to present
essentially chronological order reverse
chronological order so the first one is
uh
the mayhem paper in 2012
so this is actually a great paper i mean
so actually i use some of the materials
in my in my lecture slides uh i mean
nobody's gonna
to say that's not cool i mean i think
everybody should should say that's cool
that somebody read your paper and they
incorporate materials in in in their
lectures so this paper is about you know
um let me look at binary uh say hey
there's vulnerability how do you know
the vulnerability actually is serious or
actionable so the main hand paper talks
about hey when i tell you about report i
actually accompanied the probably
actually exploitable uh uh
with a real attack meaning that hey
here's a here's the input that you can
you can uh cause the export meaning that
you can't just spawn a shell that's a
big deal uh so so really that's born a
lot of follow following work in um on
malware
in software security analysis attack
defense you know the data grant
challenge you name it in terms of
techniques the authors did a great job
uh in terms of saying that hey how do we
make sure that when we are using symbol
execution or call execution we can
actually achieve both accuracy and
scalability and and
efficiency that's awesome paper uh is
really everybody on the company really
uh love this paper so
with that so tom do we have the um
authors coming up or we wait until the
last uh
yeah come on up to you guys let's give a
round of applause yep great thank you
all right
yeah that's really great congrats again
like i said this is a great paper and i
use it in my lectures as well okay tom
can we go to the next slide
please right ready
yep great so so now uh 2011 this uh this
uh
essentially
i mean this is a again this is an area
that a lot of people
felt like wow this is amazing piece of
work uh talking about how to analyze the
uh essentially
uh the question that people
talk about spams are people sending
instruments so annoying but why would
they send spam how do they make money so
all those questions actually i think
this is one of the first paper that did
a very systematic study
of the whole value chain uh behind spam
and and also you know multiple
uh parties uh in this whole
infrastructure i'm not talking about the
technical infrastructure such as writing
uh exploits or you know dropping malware
or the the hosting infrastructure i'm
talking about the actual value chain the
the money trail so this really awesome
piece of work again i actually use a
whole you know i use eye dag in my one
of my uh
in my in my class
uh that's one of the favorite uh
lectures that students really enjoy
uh again this also spawned a ton of
follow-up work not just by the same
group but also by many other researchers
looking at you know sort of the economic
factors
and what we can do uh in addition to
this technical means to counter these
kind of internet scale
threats and thoughts so again great
piece of work really congratulations
thank you i think i think that jeff and
nick will be
there so let's have the
authors come up to receive the awards
please
three
[Applause]
great congrats again uh so uh next slide
please
ah ready
okay great
so um
so the next slide so again we uh
we actually we love the paper so much
that we we decided to uh to give a three
words so this is the last of course not
the least so this is science uh so so
again actually i talked to agent a lot
about this paper like almost every time
we met at a conference we would talk
about this paper
and uh you know i keep repeating this
actually i'm using some of these
materials in my lecture as well so a lot
of what we do in security is about
patching patching stuff i'm sure
agent felt the same way about internet
security routing security so so again in
2011 they have this science uh science
paper
essentially talks about
essentially a new kind of internet
architecture
where you have explicit trust so using
chest domains to essentially uh isolate
and negotiate uh
some of these routing
decisions so that you can provide
resilience and better security and i
would say that
you know i know uh by talking to adrian
that he's actually taking this into
practice i mean he has star you know uh
technology technology transfer
efforts and start company and pushing
this technology so really i think this
is actually one of those one of the very
few examples where
the work is not just academically
outstanding but
but
it is actually going to make a huge
impact in practice so again
congratulations
i think agent is going to
come up together get the award as well
yeah congrats
yeah so that's great congrats again to
all the award winners like i said their
work really um have uh their work really
has had a lasting impact that really
make our job a lot easier i would also
like to thank uh the the whole award
committee i i think i think we did a
great job uh you know of course that's
patting ourselves in the back but really
like i said uh these authors they did
great job that made our work so much
easier so congrats i hope to see you
guys soon in the next conference okay
all right thank you thank you wenger
announcement
thank you venky uh that concludes this
session just for our award winners we'll
have awards that will be available on
tuesday tomorrow sometime so we'll we'll
keep you posted um that's that concludes
this session uh the next session we're
running a bit over so we will play some
uh
we can start our break and start going
to our sessions but all the places we
will play the
teaser videos for the next nine papers
in the sessions thank you everyone for
joining and
hope you all enjoy the conference over
the next
and workshops over the next four days
thank you
[Applause]