hello and welcome to our talk my name is
christian schramsky and today i will
present you the results of our paper 27
years and 81 million opportunities later
investigating the use of email
encryption for an entire university
we analyzed 81 million emails over a
time span of 27 years to identify the
usage of email encryption at a large
german university we've looked at s1 and
pgp specifically
but everyone on our team already
expected low numbers because everyone
already knows that no one encrypts right
so why is this important then
email encryption has a long history of
research with many prominent papers such
as the paper why johnny can't encrypt
from 1999 and many more johnny papers in
the following decades however there's
one issue with these research papers
there were mostly only short lab studies
with few participants to evaluate the
usability of different email encryption
tools which were used as a base for the
common knowledge that email encryption
is too hard for layman
of course there were a few papers that
looked at real world data however none
of these looked at email encryption in
general the 1996 paper from woodticker
at all looked at how email users handle
an increasing volume of incoming emails
for that they looked at
2482 emails from 18 users this was
reproduced in 2006 by fisher at all with
600 mailboxes and 28 660 emails
the closest to our topic was in 2005 by
root at all where they analyzed which
security mechanism would have been the
best choice for the users
for that they looked at 139 000 emails
from 17 users
in 2009 we wish had all analyzed public
pgp key databases and looked at 2.7
million pgp keys to analyze key
properties and graph topologies
in 2018 there was another paper by
avigdor a grapply at all where they
analyzed 5 million emails to label email
threads with machine learning techniques
from that we can already see that there
has been no research on the actual real
world usage of email encryption so far
so our research questions were can we
confirm the security community's
anecdotal knowledge about low adaption
and provide ground truth and can we
validate results from previous work and
can we identify underexplored challenges
of course ethics and data protection
important for such a project so we spent
over a year on preparation to adhere to
the strict german privacy protection
laws the european general data
protection regulation
and oil short gdpr
we also involved the data protection
officer and the works committee early on
this took multiple alterations to
discuss open questions and fixture
effects issues
we made sure that researchers never got
access to raw data when needed data was
pseudonymized with secure hash functions
with random sorts that were unavailable
to the researchers
the whole data collection
pipeline was executed by the university
it staff who operate the email
infrastructure
and we of course reduced the amount of
data to the absolute minimum we required
to investigate our research questions
how did the data collection pipeline
work
it was structured as follows in the
first step we created a dedicated email
box with as many predefined test cases
as we could come up with and export this
as a json file to develop our data
collection and set organization scripts
after we finished the local development
the script was run by the university iit
staff against our own email boxes to
identify further issues
we repeated this step until we
encountered no further errors on our own
email boxes
in the third step the scripts were again
evaluated by the university it staff and
then executed on the secondary email
server
during the theodomization process we
also used additional asserts to make
sure that no personal data would be in
the results to account for weird email
clients that might write something into
unexpected header fields that should not
contain any personal data
if one of the inserts failed the whole
email data would be removed and marked
as an error
as a last step the resulting csv was
analyzed by the researchers to answer
the research questions
so let's continue with the results
in general our dataset covers a time
span of 27 years 37 089 users and about
81 million emails
five point four six percent of all users
ever used s mime or pgp at least once to
send an email
however that also means 94 94.5 percent
did not
smile certificates are free at our
university and most email users in the
data set are highly educated so we can
assume that this data set over reports
on email encryption in comparison to
other populations where users would need
to pay for an smarm certificate
we could observe an expected
exponential growth of email between 1994
and 2020 as you can see in the graph on
the right side
the skates are logarithmic so the
percentages are very hard to see here
in total we found that overall only 0.06
percent of the emails were encrypted and
2.8 percent were signed
in general smim was more widely used
than pgp
let's take a look at the different user
groups
these user groups were assigned to one
of five
user groups based on the sub-domains
these user groups include scientific
staff students external and lastly
nx internal which is used for subdomains
that don't exist anymore
the svm and pgp usage differs between
these groups
starting with fm we can see that users
from the staff group have the highest
usage of smart signatures with
3.26 percent of all send emails being
signed and the scientific group on the
other hand only signs two points
percent of the emails
furthermore students are only signing
0.43 of their emails
if you look at pgp we can see that the
order changes while the amount of signed
mails in general is much lower
users in the scientific group lead with
0.56 percent of signed p2p mails which
is only a quarter of the signed smm
emails that they are sending
second place are students with 0.32
of signed pgp merits
and lastly followed by staff users with
0.06 percent of signed mails
these results are not surprising since
most staff users are most likely using
pre-configured devices and work at the
university for a longer period
while students are using their own
devices
let's take a look at the most commonly
used clients for email encryption
the leader by a large margin is
thunderbird in combination with anecd
which accounted for 65 percent of the
sent smile and pgp emails
this is followed by outlook which was
used for 18.2 percent of the send s mime
and pgp emails
third place is taken by apple mail
however we cannot determine the
percentage of send emails as the copy
placed in the outbox by apple mail does
not contain the xml header which is
included in the actual send email
one thing that we could observe was that
the usage of multiple clients led to a
huge difference in signed smile emails
as you can see if only a single client
is used the percentage of signed emails
after the first signed email is on
median over 60
however if two or more different clients
are used by a user the percentage of
signed emails drops heavily
this indicates that users might have
problems configuring their certificates
on a different client
interestingly the percentage is growing
with more clients used which indicates
that power users might be able to
configure their clients
for pgp the picture looks a little bit
different
in general the amount of signed emails
is much lower it seems most users test
it and drop it later on again
however we can again see that the usage
of more than one client leads to a lower
usage of pgp
let's take a look at the pgp keys
themselves
as we can see in the early years dsr
keys are the most dominant choice around
2008 the usage of asr started to
overtake dsa until 2013
13 where most keys are using 2048 bits
which then changes to 4096 bits
with the introduction of autocrypt 2017
the key sizes of new sr keys are lowered
to 2048 or 3072 bits to accommodate
header size limits in emails
in 2019 elliptic curve crypto keys are
starting to gain traction in summary we
can conclude that pgp key types and
sizes are technology driven only a small
number of insecure keys exist
however more than a third of the keys do
not have an exploration date set
in contrast to pgp we could observe that
some algorithms and configurations
clearly dominate
default settings are widely used and
hardly customized more than 90 of the
keys were of the asr 2048 type
this means that elliptic curves and
larger sr keys are not relevant
fortunately we were able to identify
very few small asr keys and the last key
with sr512 was generated more than 10
years ago
this should no longer be valid today
on the other hand keys of airs are 1024
were still generated in 2020
for digital signatures we could see a
similar picture
77 percent of the certificates supported
chart 256.
fortunately the last md5 certificate was
generated in 2017.
in summary the trolling algorithms are
very homogeneous with the configurations
in the smile
the trust system in smart circuits is
based on third parties the certificate
authorities here we could identify clear
dominance of the deutsche telecom as
root certificate authority of 65 percent
of all certificates this also includes
certificates from sub-tas
the deutsche telekom is a big telecom
company in germany and signs the root
certificate of the dfn which is used by
most german universities to sign their
certificates
in contrast only 12 percent were
self-signed and thus not confirmed by a
third party
the use of asman thus tends to take
place in the context of organizations
unlike pgp keys smarm certificates have
a final expiration date after that the
certificate is invalid and it cannot be
extended users must then create a new
certificate and have it reconfirmed by a
certificate authority but this is done
and if so when
630 email addresses from the university
used their smart certificate one-third
of them actually had two or more
certificates
so of the few people some actually
created a certificate more often but
when
we were able to identify 364 rollovers
and 229 of them occurred in time before
the expiration
for 42 certificates there was a period
of time without a relativity kit
the university informs about the
exploration of a certificate by email
this occurs a few weeks before
expiration and is marked with the red
line in the graphic
many users heeded this notice and
generated a new certificate
in addition there's a large number of
rollovers which occurred fine in advance
one year and more
the reasons for this can be manifold and
are not clear to us but in many cases
such kids are probably simply lost
let us now look at some findings from
related work
buy it all reported that participants
had concerns and misconceptions about
how keys are managed across multiple
devices
similar comments can be found in early
publications on end-to-end encryption we
observed the impact of these concerns in
practice
in our data set we could see that even
the use of multiple email clients
significantly reduces the use of
end-to-end encryption one reason for
this certainly that the transfer of keys
between applications and especially
between devices is complicated
furthermore we could observe only three
instances of private pgp keys being sent
via email these emails were sent by the
users to their own mailboxes
probably in an attempt to distribute the
key to a different device
this is not necessarily a problem as
long as the chosen path race for the
private key is adequate
this means private key leakage through
email attachment was not an issue for
our users
at waterhead or argues that
semi-automated key distribution allows
users to send secure email
others argue others argue similarly and
we also agree with the statement s-mime
supports this by sending the certificate
with every signed email
at the same time however we observed
that significantly more emails were
signed than encrypted in addition we
could see that encryption was not always
used even after a successful key
exchange only 3.4 percent of emails are
encrypted so people did not always
encrypt although it would have been
possible we cannot say why but one
possible solution would be automated
encryption if it is possible
in summary previous research has so far
only focused on short-term studies
and we have conducted the first
large-scale analyzers of e-mail
encryption with a focus on swim and bgp
over a time span of two decades
we could observe the impact of the usage
of different multiple email clients
and we could observe the key exchanges
via email and the impact on further
encryption
our key findings are entry and encrypted
emails are very rare and we were able to
check the effect of certain events for
example the snowden leaks which doubles
the percentage of encrypted emails from
0.035
to
0.07 percent
and the covered 19 pandemic which lead
to an increase of general email traffic
as well as a slight increase of signed
emails
but at the same time a decrease of
end-to-end encrypted emails
furthermore in 2020 one-third fewer
certificates were issued to users
and we could confirm common beliefs and
results from previous lab studies
and with that i would like to thank you
for your attention
[Applause]
alright do we have questions
okay
so my question about by the way my name
is isa haril from qatar computing
research institute
my question is um about why do we have
this rare end-to-end encryption
is it because the organizations
themselves they do not encourage this
because you know i mean
maybe some tools like spam detection and
spam filtering they may not be
as effective when it comes to encrypted
emails i mean how can do do we think or
do you think that this could be one of
the reasons why we don't have that
adoption or popular adoption of
end-to-end encryption in addition to
usability and other things
sure yes i think that's one of the
problems that
most companies don't encourage it
at our university there was no rule
before we did the study that
the user should use smam it was always
an optional thing
during the covet pandemic which was
after our data collection
the university doctor also introduced an
rule that fm certificates should be used
by everyone so this might
have lead to an increase afterwards but
we can't say
that for sure because we did not
we did the collection before that
yuvraj from carnegie mellon thank you
for the talk so
i noticed you mentioned that like
there's multiple emails have different
administrative domains and everybody has
to sort of do that if you want into an
encryption so i was wondering now that
many people are on gmail or google apps
and if and they're moving to web like
using webmail if somebody like google
did this so that it was sort of not only
between
gmail.com but also if your google apps
would that help with that option just
because then you don't have to configure
anything because presumably it's all on
the web right so
do you see that might help
um sure i think if the if it would work
in within the webinar clients it would
certainly help with adoption um one
thing that would be needed was be
something like let's encrypt for
s9 certificates for email so that
those certificates would not be shown as
invalid
by most email clients
but if something like that would be
introduced i'm pretty sure it would help
at least with assigning efforts
automatically and also if encryption
would be enabled by defaulting then it
would certainly have adoption okay thank
you
hi jeremy epstein national science
foundation um
i'm curious if the increase in use of
smtp
uh over https or or over other
i'm sorry not over hbs over tls and
other encrypted email
uh at the point-to-point level is
reducing the perceived threat and
therefore
even though more people are aware of the
risk of unencrypted email because more
and more email is going encrypted not
end to end whether that changes
perceptions and maybe it's a rational
decision
not to bother with
svm or pgp
um i think in general there's a large
misconception among users that
email is
secure so um
in another paper that we did and we
heard from many users that they thought
that email email would be secure because
it's encrypted by default so they
do not
did not understand that it's not
end-to-end encrypted but think that it's
always
secure no matter how it's just how it's
sent
but it depends to some extent on what
your threat model is if your threat
model is is somebody in the uh coffee
shop listening to your email then it
doesn't matter if it's end to end as
long as it gets to the
gmail server or whatever encrypted
that's probably good enough but if your
threat model is a person in the middle
then it's a different animal
yes sure that there's a difference
all right any more questions
um maybe i can ask one um what would you
suggest for the next johnny paper now
for the next journey paper that's a good
question so um
yeah i'm not exactly sure so
something like um
yeah i'm not i have no idea sorry
we don't need another journey paper um
let's thank christian again