thank you for the introduction uh good
morning everyone uh my name's welcome to
our presentation my name is ho chi chan
and i will be representing my colleagues
from university of florida and the
university of new hampshire to present
our work today the invisible finger a
practical electromagnetic interference
attack on touchscreen devices
so what exactly is our attack and in
short invisible finger is a remote
precise touchy vein injection attack
against a capacitive touchscreen device
using iemi signal so in detail there are
some characteristics associated with our
attack for instance our attack can be
used to inject touch events on
touchscreen devices from a distance up
to three centimeters
and our attack can introduce short tap
long press omnidirectional swipe on
touchscreen devices as well so it also
works on different type of device
touchscreen device with respect to
different scanning and driving mechanism
things like that
and comparing with previous touch screen
attacks it is also practical attack with
a combination of our
screen locators our touch event
detectors and we also build a website
you know to introduce our attack in
detail and
also there are some video demonstrations
so if you are interested uh please go
ahead and check it out later after this
presentation all right so before we jump
into the mid of our presentation i want
to show a quick video demonstration to
give a hand on what we can achieve using
our attacks okay so
once we generate a sufficient iemi
signal with certain parameters say
frequency voltage amplitude signal shape
things like that and we can generate a
short tab to induce a keystrokes we can
also turn that into a long press and we
eventually can turn into that any
duration omnidirectional swipe as you
can see on the screen and you can also
notice that there are three uh
acrylic shapes between the antennas and
between our target device so you can see
like the attack is launched from the
remote from a distance
so
one second
in detail today we'll be going to for
example a bit of background knowledge
and the theoretical analysis on
touchscreen devices and how to generate
a precise touch event and finally we'll
go to how do we conduct a practical
attack using such techniques
so for more than capacitive touchscreen
which everyone is using right now i
probably are holding that in your hands
right now and there are two main type of
capacitive touchscreen sensor technology
self-capacitive and mutual capacitive
sensors so a self-capacitive system
measures the change
in capacitance with respect to the
earth's ground while on the contrary the
mutual capacitive touchscreen devices
which allows the use to to use two
electrodes together and then it measures
the capacitance change when user finger
touches it so in our work we many target
on mutual capacitance touch screen as
it's actually going to be the major
capacitance technology that has been
using widely in the field
so once we have a proper target that we
want we decide to attack now let's take
a look at this fundamentally how mutual
capacitance touchscreen works so the
mutual capacity touchscreen often
consists with
multiple pairs of transmitting and
receiving electrodes and excitation
signal generator qt sensor adc and micro
microprocessor etc etc
and when a human finger is presented on
the touchscreen so it alters the current
capacitance of the touchscreen and this
change can be either positive can be
either negative really depends on human
impedance variation and
so now we can see that fundamentally all
things this capacitance touchscreen just
does just you know measure the
capacitance and see if it changes if it
changes then there's a finger charge
that's it right so it's pretty simple
and but internally how does this
mechanism is implement in circuit level
so here we show a simplified version of
the touchscreen design which is also
known as charge transfer circuit
topology and on the left side we can see
that there's a we use a voltage source
to represent how electro's on touch
screen is charged by excitation signal
and on the right side we can see there's
an opm design to turn this kind of
capacitance in of the mutual capacitor
cm into a voltage view where you can
just use adc and such to measure it and
so this is why it's actually called
charge transfer circuit because the cm
gets charged and then the capacitance is
transferred to cs afterwards
so in order to make this circuit working
properly the switch of the chart transit
uh transfer topology is maybe
coordinated and be switched on off in a
pattern and in general this different
switch will be on off you know based on
the charging period sensing period
resetting period and such the frequency
of this switching signal is also
important uh to conduct attack which we
will discuss later so now we know that
human fingers touches us if the human
finger touch the screen then there will
be capacitance change but what about
when we have a emi noise so the emi
noise that is directly applied on the
touchscreen is equivalent to a tiny
voltage source that interferes with the
capacitance sensing part and eventually
be recognized as the voltage change and
the finger finger charge so now we have
a sufficient idea on how what is a touch
screen and how it exactly it works and
what makes our work different than
previous approaches so we know that if i
work in siri you know to act like
fingers but what kind of emi signal
actually works and can be recognized as
a touch event so here comes our one of
our major contribution we couple the
theoretical analysis and the actual
attack vectors
as we see before that the charge
transfer sensor also known as qt sensor
measures the capacitance right and if
there's a finger touch finger touch the
capacitance changes the voltage change
the voltage output of opm changes you
know if there's touch so now let's say
if we are using a sine wave i am a
signal as v and you know perform this
similar approach approach and we can
also see the major voltage changes and
the passive threshold and basically in
siri we just induce attachment
using our current model we can get the
needed amplitude and frequency to induce
enough voltage changes and that can be
recognized as a touch event although we
don't really show a very detailed uh
duration process over here because like
in the paper we spent two and a half
pages on doing that so we don't have
enough to in time time today but
uh the needed voltage is actually
associated with the mutual capacitance
charge transfer capacitance and qt
sensor switching frequency and the
switching signal duties etc
so we also provided the needed frequency
here but you should notice that most
importantly that the frequency of
inducing a successful attack is actually
not unique there's multiple frequency
you know based on our serial analysis
removable frequency can be used to
induce a successful touch event and but
that's just a theory like we need to
validate it right so how do we validate
our model and analysis we use a
chromebook which is equipped with
touchscreen diagnostic software to
perform the data collection and
while we're applying the imi signal and
we use two copper plates once on the
front of the panel the lead and once on
the another one is on the back side of
it to induce the iem
as antenna so the chromebook
diagnostic software will tell us when
where and how event touchy bank is
generated so now we can try all the
combination of the e field the strings
the frequency and see if our equation is
correct or not right so by recording the
minimum e field that is and associated
frequency that we can induce
the touch event we can notice that
there's a pattern of the recorded uh e
field which is aligned with our equation
and our analysis so in a word mentioned
that different touch event a different
touch screen will have like a different
parameters and the design is a little
bit different but still our analysis
will just allow us to narrow down what
could be the combination of the e-fuel
strength and what could come
and what could be
the uh iemi signal attack frequency so
you can just perform this kind of attack
quick and fast
so once we know how to generate the
touch event using our calculated imi
signal parameter and we now need to
resolve the issue
how do we make this attack accurate and
precise so comparing with the previous
approach it was which was published on
smp and usenix recently and another one
of our major contribution lies on
generating a precise touch event and
conducting solo experiments
so
what is a challenge exactly you know of
generating a precise touch but the
challenge comes from sensing and driving
mechanism used by different touchscreen
controller in general there are two type
of the method to perform scanning or
driving on electrical grid so one of
them is sequential and one of them is uh
it's parallel so the sequential scanning
scanning mechanic mechanism will excise
the x or y electrodes one by one and
then sends each line on y or x
electrodes respectively and where
the parallel scanning will try to encode
this excitation signal and drives x or y
electrodes on the same time and then
sensor the other side of the uh
electrodes
and try to measure the capacitance so on
this slice we can also see how this kind
of driving signal actually looks like
you know on a real device one of them is
collected on iphone 11 or pro and
another one is correct on pixel with
respect to a
parallel and sequential driving
mechanism so the previous approach
generally only works on you know on
sequential driving mechanism where
because you know there's a certain
pattern and this padding is actually
pretty easy to identify right so the
attacker can measure the driving signal
and choose what is the correct timing to
inject the iemi signal and however it
like for example just like this like the
attacker trying to measure and see okay
this is the time this column or this row
is measured this is excited i'm going to
inject i am a signal at this precise
moment to uh make sure to make this
press
touch event precise
but as you can also see because the
parallel scanning is all on the same
time so it won't really work when the
touchscreen
uses embedded parallel driving mechanism
so our attack which on the country does
not require a particular driving
mechanism instead we use antenna design
where it can generate
actually a very focused field to apply
the interference on the very specific
and narrow region on your touch screen
and we apply this appropriate emi signal
and we wait for that place to be scanned
by the touchscreen controller which is
just like human fingers right so your
fingers is actually like pressing the uh
pressing the screen and it will be
scanned sometime and we are basically
mimicking the same way that that works
so just like a human finger that comes
our title in the invisible finger right
so another advantage brought about
attack is that we don't not need to
analyze how this driving signal of
different touchscreen controller and
this is how they are designed and where
are the correctly timing yeah you need
to measure that you need to know okay
this is line is the one i'm going to
attack right so we don't really do that
kind of thing
anymore all we need to as as you can see
that we don't need to do all any kind of
encoding and we don't care that what is
the driving signal looks like so we test
our attack on different smart cell phone
tablets from different vendors including
apple google oneplus and even microsoft
and
we also show that all the devices
vulnerable to our attack while the
previous timing based iem injection
which was published before and that we
only was tested on the nexus 5 and so we
increased our test test bench
largely and another noticeable
achievement our attack also on certain
time platforms like for example on ipad
pro and surface pro 7 we can even
achieve like for we can even perform
swipe gesture with any duration so in
general our attack works better on iot
ios device than android device we think
whatever the noise cancellation of
algorithm was employed on ios
touchscreen controller or just the os
driver level kind of actually makes our
attack more efficient and more precise
so now we have a way to know what kind
of emi signal we want to use to perform
a touch touch event injection and we can
also perform tab press and i mean
directional swipe and things like that
with such signal so but everything is
done by us just you know look into the
device and try to use our antenna you
know to inject the touch event right so
we're not even close to actually using
this attack a real scenario so then this
is our third contribution um
we present complete practical attack
vectors so a sequence now we have
established a serial background
knowledge and actual setup you know to
induce a touch event but we're still
missing a really important part right so
in real scenario attack devices probably
is attached at the you know as a under
the table and the phone for example you
see the victim walks around walks
towards the table and then place his or
her cell phone directly on the table and
the phone will be randomly located so as
the attacker we won't know that where
the phone is located and so in that case
we develop a phone locator techniques
and also for the attack scenario there's
multiple touches at multiple uh
locations and sometimes there is even a
swipe gesture this kind of like a
gesture involved if you want to perform
a successful attack so in that case we
develop a touch event detector to
resolve this issue so as for the phone
locator a little bit recap on what the
uh driving signal is actually looks like
on different uh device and we can see
that for different role or column the
driving signal actually looks different
this applies to either sequential or
or parallel driving mechanism and we can
use this pattern to recover where the
phone located so we know ahead that how
our antenna is located how our antenna
is organized and we call and we can use
our antenna to measure what the signal
looks like on the touch screen and using
these two information combine these two
information together we can now know we
can now use that to recover the precise
location and precise orientation of the
target device and we can also see that
if we are using of we are if we are
using more antenna than we are the more
accurate we can recover the phone
location for instance like we are using
12 antennas simultaneously right now and
we can locate our target device without
any displacement so as for the touch
event detector we notice that there's
many of this smartphone will actively
increase active scanning period when
zero to attach and it's detected so it
can make it it runs a little bit more
smooth and runs a little bit more
accurate
so as shown this figure once we stop
this type of inject emi injection the
driving signal pattern that we measured
from is actually different depending on
whether this injection is successful or
not so this will tell you that the
previous iem attack is successful not so
you can long you can decide whether i
should perform the next run of the year
my injection to repeat that or should i
just move the antenna to a different
place and then perform for the next
stage of the attack so combining all
these different aforementioned
techniques together now we have achieved
a successful attack on the following
scenarios and you can find the detail of
this kind of attack on our paper so for
the clickbank attack we have malicious
application installation on android
device we can also connect to malicious
bluetooth profile on ios device and
for more complicated gesture based
attack we can send messages you know
which of all involved with different
keystrokes and we can also use uh use
press and hold on paypal icon to choose
a qr code we can just scan it and then
you know transfer money right and more
complicatedly we can use omnidirectional
gesture attack to unlock your cell phone
if you are using gesture unlocking
mechanism and i'm pretty sure there's
more interesting attacks which you can
achieve using our techniques but as for
the mitigation we propose and evaluate
two mitigations in our paper from vendor
side we can use pressure detection to
decide whether their legitimate user
touch or from the user side a very
simple fabric uh friday fabric is
totally enough to protect yourself from
the emi attack so um again like our all
of our details are our papers our video
demonstration is stored on our website
so if you're interested there's more you
know fun videos where you can watch and
so that'll be for all for today and
thank you guys for listening my talk
please let me know if you have any
questions or suggestions all right
all right let's thank our speaker thank
you
and one really quick question for you uh
yeah so you mentioned being able to you
know change the or
recognize the position of the phone yes
can you actually recognize the type of
device that you have because it seems
like you have a variety of um accuracies
yes that might
change your results right right right
that's a really good question because
like as far we uh we run tests we run
tests around on around like 11 different
type of device from different vendors
and as we can see that when we measure
that the driving signal that we can
measure are totally different on
different devices so the moment you see
that you can just
categorize that into a certain device
fantastic thank you i just want to have
one quick note before we uh we take uh
questions from the microphone i've been
trying all session to get the hop in to
work to take questions online and i i
can't so folks who are watching this
online my apologies you're not being
ignored i just can't see you at all so
with that we have a big line of folks
here and plenty of time please ask away
yeah uh thanks for the talk uh i'm tren
wang from irsu
so have you already applied your attack
to
multiple finger touch so the multiple
finger target what we does it like
every antenna we use can be generated
for like a single touch at single
position so the way we does for
multi-touch is applying different
antennas at different positions and
apply for the iem signal at different
locations so we've done that on ipad
we've done that for the surface we've
done that on certain iphone but that's
not really generic where we can use on
like for example a lot of android device
yet oh so there's no uh inter
interference there's no interface like
we actually measure interface like the
antenna distance the minimum antenna
distance can be around five millimeter
and uh because i like the shape of the
tenon we use so like they really cause
the interference between the uh imi ten
that we use
one quick question yeah so have you uh
uh so i wonder uh because the touch
screen event the target event can also
capture the touch area and the touch
pressure yeah still think that would be
an easy way to
right exactly that's actually another
another way to mitigate this kind of
attack that's precise uh precise yeah
thank you yeah make sure you um
introduce yourself as you ask your
questions
okay hi i'm surya there from penn state
um
so first and foremost fantastic
presentation and work thank you and uh
the first question that i had for you
was you said that the minimum distance
between the antenna and the screen is uh
five millimeters five millimeters but
what's the maximum distance how
so uh the way we does this kind of the
multi-touch or anything like that is
actually we build antenna array as we
also show on the video like we have
antenna over here we have antenna over
here and the maximum distance doesn't
really matter so it depends on what is
the size of your uh
of your target device and how many
different channels of imi signal you
want to apply this on so like the
distance the maximum distance we don't
really have a limitation for that it's
more or less like
if we get too close they may this
antenna is going to interfere with that
antenna so it makes the uh result is a
little bit inconsistent okay yeah
awesome and uh you mentioned that
placing your entire setup underneath the
table to attack on that so uh i'm sure
that you probably have some of this
stuff on your demonstrations but
what kind of materials of the table have
you actually tried this on good question
unless the table we also have done the
evaluation in our paper as well so
unless your table is using use like a
con is made with some kind of metal
which yeah which will block this yeah my
signal otherwise wooden acrylic
everything just works fine okay yeah
yeah so the fundamental part is like
your table cannot block the iem a signal
that's it all right yeah all right thank
you thank you so much for answering
hi i'm daniel antonioli from eurocom
and in your evaluation slide you've
shown that you attack different
platforms from different lenders
and i was wondering if you disclosed
these attacks to the vendors so what did
they say that's a good thing uh where
like we think this type of attack
although we show how to practically
attack but there's still a lot of effort
you need to do it's not like you're
walking in some conference like you can
expect that kind of thing happens like
as you also notice that how giant
our if amplifier can be so in that case
we think at this moment we don't really
see a
emerging threat that people will be
using this kind of attack
to to
uh to actually you know attack people
and but more importantly we think this
is more or less like how the touchscreen
controller vendor instead of how is a
smartphone vendor because they normally
just purchase this kind of solution from
admiral from you know max attacks is a
kind of uh vendor we all we did talk
with some of them and they think it's
just a matter of you know whether they
want to use a more advanced noise
elimination algorithm or not but they
don't really think this uh
this attack you know they just say yeah
this this is a type of like a
interference but that's it
yeah so yeah the practicality of the
attack is kind of right right yeah if
you go back to the slide about the
attack scenario uh
the attacks in arrow
the attack
yeah yeah
so i was wondering how are you detecting
when
you can you know send this malicious
click to install an app
so okay i see that case oh and second
question is
uh sometimes when you have to already
interrupt we have about 30 seconds left
so if you want to get maybe one of those
questions in that would be great and
then please yeah i mean
right right so okay yeah
uh yeah so for the uh malicious
application installation like what we
does like we actually send uh so that's
our assumption we know the target device
target devices the phone number so we
can just send a message over there and
at over there there will be a preview
where we can know this preview is
actually located and we just touch in
injector type event at that precise
array every starting area then we can
just open that event open that window
and then try to proceed for uh
installation and this is definitely
complicated because we measure that
there probably are five six distinct
touch events should be involved and so
you have like a six or five antenna
placed at different place different
location to inject this type event one
by one at a different location to to
eventually install this type of
application all right thanks
thank all of our speakers this is the