okay
hello everyone welcome to my talk
so let's get started
today i'm going to present case
scheduler a generic and effective sys
schedule for fuzzing waze graph
centrality analysis
fuzzing is a popular technique to find
bugs through mutating a set of sets
here is a simplified workflow for
fuzzing it starts with a sit coppers
consisting of multiple sets as shown
here
then we have a cis scheduling module
we'll choose optimal set then the fuzzer
will generate a large number of
mutations
to see if there any
interesting seeds has been found
in this process
a critical component is seed scheduling
because it can create it can greatly
affect fuzzing performance
see scheduling
so what is scheduling
it determines the order in which seats
are selected specifically it will
compute a weight for each set then it
prioritizes weights higher weight
then why is it important
further explore
new code through said mutations
in practice we found mutations from a
good set can lead to discovery of more
code
while mutations from a bad set can
result in discovery of less code
and the goal of fuzzing is to explore
program code as much as possible
hence a good strategy a good scheduling
strategy can greatly boost fuzzing
performance
there are many research works in cis
scheduling
we summarize their uh strat scheduling
strategies in this table
for example
afl fast prioritizes which had rear
passes
and fairfax prioritizes which hit rear
edges
and other fuzzers like eco files entropy
and total first employ different
scheduling strategies such as
number of discover paths
and or entropy of discover edges or head
count of security sensitive coverage
all of them focus on historical mutation
data while ignoring
the structure of the of the control flow
graph
control flow graph in set scheduling
so why safety matters in sit scheduling
the answer is
the cfg can review potential code
coverage gain from mutating each set
let's look at the example on how cfg
reviews potential code coverage gain
say
we have two sets now six coppers shown
this on the right we have a control flow
graph of a program we mark
visiting nodes in white and on this
notes in grey
note that in fuzzing we only care about
unvisited nodes because we want to
explore new code
here is execution path for seat one
marking blue we can see
its execution path is directly connected
to
a single obviously node as marked in red
circle
for c2 its execution path is shown in
red
we can see
it is closer it is close to three on
this denote
for this example
intuitively we can know c2 is a better
set
because the goal fuzzing is to explore
more unvisited nodes and c2 is close to
more unvisited nodes however
existing works might choose c1 because
their decisions are made based on pure
mutation historical data without
consideration of the structure of the
cfg
so
we know safety is important to say
scheduling
then
an ideal scheduling should incorporate
the information of cfg
then question here is
how do we use how to use cfg in
scheduling
well a naive approach is simply traverse
the cfg and count the number of
reachable and obviously notes
but there are there can be many
problems with this approach
first
the graph can be large on real world
programs
and each set require a graph traversal
which makes the process very expensive
second
the unvisited nodes are dynamically
changing during a fuzzing campaign
hence we cannot cache the intermediate
results and to reduce the expensive
runtime overhead
and third the counting treats
all onversion nodes equally
but in practice some nodes might be
guarded by
super complex or super hard or even
infeasible past constraints which make
it almost impossible for father to to
flip or reach
then
instead of this
expensive graph traversal and accounting
maybe we could try to approximate the
count
an approximate approach
the approximate count we would like it
to it should determine sid weight
moreover we would like the proximity
count to
have some desired features that is
suitable to see scheduling
we show these desired features as
follows
the approximate approach should increase
it weight if there are more richmond
nodes
from a
set meanwhile it should decrease seed
weight if if there is a node it's hard
to reach by a fuzzer
in this way we can avoid waste too many
mutations on some complex and hard
branches
we also want the approximation approach
decreasing weight if a node is far away
from sid
because in fuzzing a far away node is
less likely to be reached
in the end we would like this
approximation approach to be efficiently
computed on
large
cfg because in fuzzing cis scheduling is
frequently involved
we observe graph centrality can actually
provide this nice and desired feature to
see scheduling hence it is a natural fit
to our need
a little bit background about graph
centrality
it is a common matrix in social network
analysis it measures influence of each
node it is often used to identify
important nodes
on the right we show a graph example of
the graph centrality analysis on a
social network graph
each node represents a person
and the edge indicates connections
between the people
the node size
is proportional to the centroid score
and the larger node size indicates
higher centrality
for example
the center people marked in the red
circle
is outgoing people is outgoing guys may
some like
social media influencer you know a lot
of friends and he has the largest
central score
while
introverted people like shy people who
have fewer friends
might have lower score
in this work we use cal centrality to
approximate code coverage gain for each
sit
for more information about cod
centrality please check our paper
however there's still one challenging
the conventional cfg is not suitable to
graph centrality analysis
because conventional cfg contains
visited node
while we are only interested in
obviously nodes
because in fuzzing
our goal is to explore obviously node
second
there is no set information in
conventional cfg but we need to compute
centroid score for each node
for each set
our solution is to build a novel edge
horizon graph composed of only obviously
notes and signals
here is an example of edge horizon graph
on the top we have two synth nodes
represent two sets and on the bottom we
have four obviously nodes marked in gray
then we perform graph centrality
analysis
like this
we can have a weight for each note
from this weight we can know that c2 is
a better set since it has higher score
and indicating that it can lead to
larger code coverage gain
we showed the overview of case scheduler
first case scheduler takes in the
cfg
and initial c coppers to build an edge
horizon graph
then perform graph centrality analysis
to identify the optimal set further will
generate mutation to see if there if
there any interesting seed has been
found
if there is then new seed will be added
to 6 coppers we also add the newly
discovered nodes to the visited node set
in the end we'll update the edge horizon
graph on the fly with new data of c
coppers and visiting node set
next i will briefly explain how to build
an edge horizon graph
we first classify nodes in cfg as
visited and unvisited like this
first obtain execution path for set 1
obtain execution path for set 2
now we just mark all under obviously
notes in white and obvious note in grey
second step is to identify edge horizon
node
edge horizon nodes
are unvisited nodes whose parent nodes
are visited
they form the boundary between visiting
node and ours denote
in this graph we can find two edge
horizons as shown in red
next we remove unvisited nodes
we remove visiting nodes from the cfg
like this
and the first step is to insert seed
node
we first insert two syn node
representing the two sets in the coppers
then we connect signal to their directly
connected edge horizon node like this
in the end we can have
an edge horizon graph
lastly we also remove cycles from edge
horizon graph
since our example here doesn't contain
any cycles for more detail please check
our paper
let's look at our evaluation results we
integrate case scheduler on lip fuzzer
fl concolic execution engine qsync to
demonstrate its generic usage
in
various fuzzers the evaluation results
also show superior performance of case
scheduler over existing sales schedulers
on
leap fuzzer we evaluate 12 programs from
google first bench for 10 repeated
rounds and over
24 hours case schedule increase feature
coverage by 26 compared with entropy
we also evaluate in fl havoc mode we
evaluate case scheduler against five
state-of-the-art sys schedulers on the
same 12 programs from google first bench
and the results show that case scheduler
increased edge coverage by four percent
compared with the bad cis scheduling fl
flash
we also interestingly also find
case schedule can even be used to
prioritize paths for concolic execution
engine hence we integrate on cusing
and we compare
we run
a q sim with key schedule on three
programs and the result showcase
schedule can improve qsync by 36 percent
edge coverage compared with default sys
schedule over 24 hour run
in terms of runtime analysis
we break down the wrong time of case
scheduler into two part one is graph
centrality analysis the second part is
fuzzy maintainers
case scheduler adds at most one percent
overhand for graph analysis and
at most two percent for fuzzy
maintainers
in conclusion
case schedule is a generic
cis scheduler for fuzzing le fuzzer efl
and concoli execution engine quizzing
key scheduler approximates potential
code coverage gain for each sit using
graph centrality score
we open source case scheduler and
reproduction package including all the
binary and sig coppers on github
we're also working on integrating his
schedule to live further and live bfl
code repo
thank you i'm ready to questions
[Applause]
questions
hi sam from etheric great talk very
interesting i was wondering this event
horizon graph is basically like one step
away
from the visited notes right you only
follow like one edge and this is what
you collect i was wondering as a
trade-off
could you go further in this graph in
order to trade a little bit of runtime
but you get more coverage
are you asking like how do we construct
the edge horizon graph since we want to
consider that i'm asking the horizon
graph is like by following one edge
like at the boundary of what you what
you have explored so far and then you
you build this to build the graph if you
go like more steps then you will get a
larger horizon graph and then maybe more
accurate results on the node centrality
i was wondering whether this would
actually help and whether you you tried
this out
i see so
let me show uh example my better uh
so here so
this example of the edge horizon node so
basically
we only consider edge horizontal because
we found edge horizontal dominate all
the obviously no set that means if you
want to reach any obviously note you
have to go through this edge horizon
node and this edge horizon node has a
really nice property is the form of
boundary like they can if you link this
at horizon node they can split all the
node as a vc node and office knows that
okay yeah i see it makes sense thanks
oh yes oh very good brief um i'm wally
bernalillo office of naval research so i
was curious as to the uh
any speed up on times of in terms of
code coverage you showed a a a finite
time period of 24 hours but i was
curious if using this you were able
to
if you use a metric of determining the
amount of code coverage compared to
other baselines and if you were able to
have a speed up in terms of of getting
to the same amount of code coverage by
some of these existing approaches
are you asking like achieve the same
amount of code coverage like how fast
are we faster yes yes that's a really
good question actually there's some
interesting finding i can show you
uh here so this is uh on the further 24
hours you can find it's quite
interesting it's
sometimes only one hour case schedule
can achieve
almost 24 hours default and
default or entropy schedule results so
you can check the first point at first
point indicate the one hour result of
the feature coverage yeah
thank you
okay so this is draw from purdue and
very good work so i guess i have a
open questions
so we know that sometimes the number of
nh being covered may matter for the
selections
so do you increa integrate this
information in your algorithms or how do
you think about we count this in the
future research because i know it would
be a trade-off because when we maintain
the number of age being covered will
increase the overhead of the citizen
actions yeah
yeah yeah so
that part is actually uh
this graph so you can see the last
last column it's called the maintenance
that is uh what you're asking so
basically for the for the maintenance
part we basically do is we need to track
for each edge how many how many
how many execution paths how many test
cases has been generated test that edges
and
that part actually is a runtime overhead
but we
check on the leap fuzzy and fl so at
most uh this further maintainers
basically tracking the the hit count for
each edge will
at most
two percent so still uh in a manageable
way okay so you mean you already
considering this information in your
a or somehow selection algorithms yeah
yeah so we we use a hit count it's uh
it's like four to four one some branches
let's say we already had like one minute
time but the father still failed to flip
that branch that means it's too hard for
current first mutation algorithm if you
continue doing to try to flip that
branch that is useless so we try to
de-prioritize yeah because that's too
hard for the current phasor so we do not
waste too much mutation on that okay
great thanks
looks like there's no question in uh in
the chat maybe as a chair i also ask you
a question um you talk about you use uh
inter procedure safety as the graph so
how do you handle let's say indoor call
to build safety
you mean how do we handle the indirect
call yeah yeah that is a
hard it's still open research problem
currently we ignored
uh all the indirect function call but we
have we're planning to incorporate like
more advanced uh static programming as a
pointer now to resolve this in the in
the future version of the case scheduler
great let's uh thank god
one more time
lex