so hello um indeed i'm going to talk
well let's first focus on the mitigating
information leakage fundability but
first um i would like to point out the
beautiful legal disclaimer from my
employer intel who'd like to make it
clear they have nothing to do with this
work whatsoever i did this work at vusek
my previous employer
together with eric and christiano
so the dream i'm going to first talk
about the dream it's kind of what we
would like in a perfect world so i'm a
systems security researcher and so when
i talk about information leakage
vulnerabilities i mean at you know
systems level so we're not talking about
high-level privacy type stuff we're
talking about really like spatial
vulnerabilities
so you know this is you have an
out-of-bounds read and temporal
vulnerabilities you might have a use
after free you might be reading an
initialized memory that was previously
used for something else
and also we're going to talk about you
know architectural vulnerabilities these
are kind of your traditional
non-speculative vulnerabilities and this
is these are things like you know you
have a missing bounds check
but it's 2022 so we're also going to try
and take into account in this mitigation
speculative vulnerabilities for example
the spectre
bounce check where you know your bounce
check is there you don't have a software
bug but the processor will helpfully
speculate right past your check and
still maybe an attacker can use side
channels to leak data so this is the
dream you know this is maybe a a dream i
share with many other people with many
other previous researchers and the
problem is always that we want low
overhead you know we want this to be
practical in um
wants to be practical enough that you
will all deploy it right we want that
magical 10 number that other viewers
want to see
so you know let's throw away the dream
and let's move on to the plan
so the plan is that we're not going to
try mitigating all of this what we're
going to do is we're going to try
splitting things up by type you know and
what do i mean by type well you know i'm
a researcher i want to sell my paper i'm
just going to tell you can define this
as however you want we'll get back to
them in a minute
but in this example let's say you have
some network buffers for your i o code
and you have your private cryptographic
keys right your private cryptographic
keys should not be ending up in your
network buffer this should definitely be
isolated okay and actually we want
fine-grained isolation of all the types
you want so no matter how you're going
to define your types you want to be able
to have this fine grained isolation no
kind of splitting into secret non-secret
and so that's kind of one of the ways
we're going to make our dream become
reality
and
the other thing is that we're going to
rely on the compiler and we're going to
try using compiler magic to keep
pointers in one of these types we're
going to call the regions where we put
one type of data an arena so here we
have one arena for our temporary network
buffers and one wiener one arena for our
private keys
and so let's say we have a pointer
that's pointing into the network socket
into this temporary socket
and
you know there's a vulnerability that
lets you read out of bounds missing
check and so maybe
an attacker can use this to read out of
bounds within this type of data within
the temporary buffers
and we're going to say that's okay
you know we're going to completely
betray our dream and just say yeah it's
the same type of data so we're just not
going to cover it in the interest of
practicality on the other hand we're
going to say that you should not be able
to take a pointer that's pointing into
these network buffers and use them to
point to read out of bounds and read
private keys another type of data right
and so like compiler magic so the hell
the answer is just magic and we move on
no so we have three kind of pieces here
so the first piece is an allocator that
actually allocates things in arenas and
we're gonna organize the address space
in a very careful way
we're gonna have four gigabyte arenas
and so the idea is between each of these
four gigabyte arenas and each of these
arenas has one type of data
we're going to put unmatched guard zones
and those unmarked guard zones are also
going to be four gigabytes this is also
going to be aligned
and one key point here is that a pointer
that's pointing into one of these arenas
so maybe this arena contains your
network buffers
you can go up to four gigabytes in
either direction and you'll either stay
in the same arena or you'll hit unmapped
memory so you can move four gigabytes in
any direction from a pointer
and if you dereference it you're either
going to get the same type of data or
you're going to get a fault
the second step is we're going to need
some way to actually allocate different
types of data into different arenas
and you can do that this previous work
which we lean heavily on in the
evaluation code type after type there's
also annotations there's a bunch of
other techniques but we're just going to
leave it high level here we just use
some way to allocate different types and
then we have the actual component
instrumentation
and kind of the key point of the puzzle
here
is we don't allocate we don't try
instrumenting the loads and stores
we try instrumenting the pointer
arithmetic and so we try and make sure
that when you do what point of
arithmetic there's no way for you to get
a pointer from one type of data to
another type of data
so the trick here is you have what we
call valid safe and unsafe pointers so
there's three classifications of
pointers which we use so a valid pointer
is one that is pointing at the intended
arena so you have a pointer that's meant
to point into your buffers or your keys
that pointer is a valid pointer means
that one is still pointing at that arena
into this four gigabyte chunk
you can move up to four gigabytes in
both directions and that will get you a
safe pointer it's a pointer that you can
de-reference maybe it'll segfault
but it's not going to let if you
dereference this you're not going to be
able to read data
that belongs that it is of a different
type
and then you have an unsafe pointer
which it may not point into another
arena but an unsafe point is one where
we can't prove
that it's pointing into either the arena
or the god zones next to it so an unsafe
pointer might be pointing somewhere else
and what we do is we insert
instrumentation to do what we call
masking masking being we take one of
these safe pointers or unsafe pointers
and we turn it back into a valid pointer
that's pointing at the intended type for
that pointer and because we're
instrumenting points for a repetitive
what we can do is we can just kind of
trace back you know what was the
arithmetic based on in the first place
and we just can make sure that it has
the same type it's pointing at the same
arena as that pointer that was the basis
for a point of arithmetic
so
the way masking works is you know we
want low overheads we want this to be
super cheap we want a super cheap way to
take a pointer and make sure it's
pointing at the arena we want and the
trick is that because we have these
aligned four gigabyte regions
then we can say the lower 32 bits
they're the offset into an arena and the
upper 32 bits they identify the arena
so basically they're kind of a type
identifier
and so we can say that let's add you
know a pretty large value but something
that's still within four gigabytes
and that gets us a safe pointer it might
still point within the same arena or it
might point into your guard zone this is
a safe pointer you can de-reference it
it's fine the upper bits changed in this
example but we don't care we don't have
to apply masking here
but the interesting case is where you
have an unsafe pointer so let's add
another large value we're no longer
within four gigabytes or certainly not
provably so
and so how do you turn this pointer back
into a pointer that points into the
original arena and we just look back to
the original valid pointer and we just
take the upper 32 bits of the pointer
and just stomp over them
and we preserve the lower 32 bits and it
turns out that on x6 for example you can
do this with two zorg operations so it's
actually super cheap to do in practice
and so you know what does this let us do
why is this interesting why is this kind
of a delta
of a previous work again we're going and
the trick is we're going for the fine
grain isolation and the high performance
so here's an example of why
i at least think this is really valuable
trick
and we have an example so one of the
things that we require
is that all of the pointer arguments to
a function they have to be valid
pointers when you pass an argument to a
function
you have to have matched it first if you
can't prove it was already a valid
pointer so you can assume that all of
your pointers are valid or we also
require that all of the points are
stored in memory if added because we
have no way of tracking whether a
pointer that we just read from memory is
valid or not so we just mandate if you
store a pointer to memory if you pass a
pointer as an argument all of the
pointers that kind of escape a local
function boundary they have to be found
and so here we have a loop and it's just
basically you take a valid pointer you
deref you add one you dereference it you
add one you dereference it and you know
you can pass a huge size size can be 64
bits so you can read way out of bounds
with this but you can only do it step by
step
so you know you have your pointer maybe
all the way at the end of an arena and
then you read one and then you read
another one but then at this point this
is going to fault you're going to try
dereferencing something that's in a
guard zone
and it's going to fall so actually you
don't have to add any instrumentation
here we don't need to do any masking
because every time you read from a
pointer that we know is within four
gigabytes
it's either going to be
a valid point it's going to be pointing
into the original arena we can say aha
this is a valid pointer because it
didn't fault
or it's going to be pointing into memory
unmapped memory and it will fault and
then we don't care anymore
the problem comes
when we remember that oh we put
speculation in our threat model and
speculation doesn't really care um that
you might fault on a speculative path
right
and uh you know you might get another
read speculatively around the next loop
and another read
so in this example
the thing is that no matter how fancy
your processor is it's never going to
manage to speculate far enough to get to
the other arena we're adding one byte at
a time you're not going to speculate
four gigabytes of loop ahead so in this
example also speculatively we don't have
to instrument anything and one of the
reasons that this technique works so
well is that we get away without having
to instrument this kind of loop
whatsoever
of course the problem comes that you
know what if you change the stride to
four gigabytes
it's like okay we have a pointer at the
end of the arena and we add four
gigabytes and it's going to fault but
then if you include speculation then
yeah you know your next weed is going to
be in the next arena maybe corresponding
to a different type and at that point
you might well have a problem if an
attacker has a way to disclose this
virus i channel or this kind of thing so
in that case we would have to actually
mask the pointer
but in practice you don't have four
gigabyte strides in real world code
the problem of course is that this loop
might not actually dereference the
pointer every time
and if you can't prove
that these strides are going to actually
that you are going to actually have a
point to dereference without the pointer
getting far enough that you can either
architecturally or speculatively
um
end up with a fault then you know you
are going to have to mask
but okay so this is kind of the very
high level view please read the paper
for a rather more um detailed analysis
of how this works and why it's safe
but then how do you actually implement
this so i mean we implemented using edo
vm we have a compiler pass we have an
allocator and so forth um and those of
you familiar will just say kind of uh
you know you just had in you just
instrumentally get element point of
instructions and those of you more
familiar with things like ugly gaps and
this kind of thing will realize no
there's no way that's gonna work um
we're just gonna call it magic does that
work you know point of confidence or
problem
you know uh no not so much after all
there turned out to be all kinds of
corner cases for example you might have
the pointers might be instructs or
unions and that's a big killer you know
you have a union you add something to it
wait do we need to mask this or not
what's the type of this
c code is full of undefined behavior
especially spec cpu is full of undefined
behavior that you can't touch
and you might have allocations that are
bigger than four gigabytes you might
have all kinds of other problems
and uh
you know we discussed this in the paper
we find solutions but the most important
bit for me is you know does it work
you know i mean there are all kinds of
obstacles which you can think of and you
run across if you try and implement this
but the answer is yes
i mean most importantly we actually
managed to mitigate vulnerabilities so
we took a sample of cves
we also mitigate the spectre
bounce check and also actually some
other spectra vulnerabilities from
google safe slide suite
um and also it actually runs a whole
bunch of software not only cpu 2017
and 2006 and 2000 but also a stack where
we combine nginx open ssl muzzle and
some other libraries
with some patches you know let's be
honest here there is undefined behavior
here there are cases where the compiler
magic is just not able to automatically
identify this
but we discussed in the paper actually a
pretty surprisingly low number of
patches is required for this to work
and you know
okay we wanted the low overhead do we
manage it well kind of the the worst
case i could come up with with nginx so
this is nginx https requests really tiny
requests lots of them on a fiber network
interface and kind of the worst case
overhead is about 8.4
it's less than 10
it's not great
um the the real troublemaker is paul
bench in cpu 2017
where
i have we have real problems with trying
to just reason about some of this
arithmetic in deeply inlined functions
where it's just difficult to keep track
of what's going on from a compiler
perspective
the runtime for the older version of
spec is much more reasonable
i mean this is in terms of actual
runtime but also you can see in the
paper some discussion of the memory
overhead of this arena eradication but
it kind of ends up being about ten
percent
um and a lot of this is really kind of
the terrible worst cases
um so there's a prototype on github
thanks to a couple of my colleagues who
actually made it work
inside the docker
um kind of my takeaways from this work
are that you know point of provenance is
tricky
um there's some great work written on
this the servers paper
um
one big problem that we have is that
we're trying to include speculation here
for example llvm scale evolution just
doesn't there's no way for it to
consider this you just you say what's
the diff what's the maximum distance
between this pointer and this pointer
and it'll say well you know you have a
bounce check here so you know your
maximum distance is four bytes and it
doesn't take into account that under
speculation you know that branch may not
necessarily actually provide you any
guarantees and so for this to work well
i think compilers really need better
static analysis support for trying to
reason out of speculation
and finally kind of glossed over the
whole type thing we do have actually
pretty fine-grained types but for
example in the web server you probably
actually want your types to be more like
different users data for example rather
than actual c level types and then you
really kind of need some manual
intervention but having said all of that
it works pretty well it's low overhead
i'm kind of amazed that it actually
worked out but it seems like much more
promising to me than a lot of the
previous work that's been doing kind of
similar bits and bobs so thank you and
i'd love to hear questions
so we have time for some questions if
you have questions please walk up to the
microphone or if you have questions at
home please type them in the q a box
um okay sorry
so
um first off uh what you talk about is
specifically for a 64-bit architecture
right so have you experimented with
smaller architectures smaller
arena sizes etc
i have not so it's uh it's something
that you it kind of relies on the 64-bit
address space so if you mean kind of
microprocessors it's going to be way
less practical i feel a lot of the wind
here is really that it's so cheap to
replace the 32-bit pointers
but on the other hand there's things
like if you had dedicated processor
features like memory tagging and this
kind of thing i think you could actually
use that in some in some incarnations to
try and implement something similar
even without this kind of memory layer i
see and and
one more quick thing on your slide
number 12
something called equate was actually
faster how did that happen
i
so that one of the
um
[Music]
the problems with this kind of kind of
deeply invasive
um instrumentation is that sometimes you
just make the compiler do something
completely different in the code
animation stage
and it's deeply frustrating because you
change one thing and suddenly you have
um weird results like this
so um but i have no idea
and you change some configuration
options and different benchmarks will
gain
so thank you
great work
if i may offer an educated guess to that
last question
um probably changing instruction
alignment with respect to the eye
and you get a better eye cash hit rate
by accident
no exactly so one of the things i
glossed over here as well is the fact
that um we cover with the heap and the
stack and other allocations and that
means also that you all we allocate on
different stacks
um something we kind of hacked up based
on type as type and that also means that
you change one thing it's like oh oh um
your data cache is completely different
you're you're also yes yeah yeah but
yeah i think icash is a is a really good
guess for why you tend to see these
weird effects i didn't understand you
were also changing the stacks decash
behavior is also an excellent guess in
that case question i want to ask
very interesting work
have you considered any other
programming languages particular
languages that are typically garbage
collected i mean it would be a different
paper i just wondered if you had any
thoughts to share
and not really so one
one obvious question that i ask is why
not web browsers
um you know why not try defending
javascript with this and it turns out
that for example chrome i think already
has partition malloc it already tries to
kind of divide up
allocations into kind of arena type
things so i think certainly for some
languages it wouldn't be that much of a
delta
but on the other hand this kind of if
you want pooled allocations where you're
really trying high efficiency
allocations and you're trying to squeeze
it all into a pool which i think a lot
of garbage collected languages do and
actually i think some of the spec match
marks do
it's tricky it's going to be quite
different but it would be interesting to
see
we should talk offline
okay maybe one more quick question while
the next speaker sets up
so i was wondering how fine-grained can
you make this uh is there an overhead
associated with creating a single arena
and how many arenas can you have in
practice or how many did you have in
your experiments for example so i think
in my experiment it was mostly less than
a thousand you definitely do have a
limit i refer you to the paper because
i'm not going to try doing math in my
head
um but it's in the thousands it's in the
tens of thousands but there's definitely
a limit there and again otherwise you'd
have to kind of shrink your arenas and
stuff
so yeah the fine grained is nice but
there is a limit unfortunately
all right let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]