hi thanks and uh i promise i will be on
time so
expect like five to ten minutes late i
think i'm not sure it's time now and uh
so i'm hao jian i'm going to present our
paper peekaboo so a hub-based approach
to enable transparency in data
processing within smart homes this
project is collaborated with graham
david swaron yuvraj and jason
the initial idea of this project is from
a discussion with google nest team
so the team wants to assure users that
they only collect aggregated data such
as the daily average indoor temperature
but when you think about this problem
it's a surprise it's surprisingly hard
to implement because the edge device the
communication and the server are all
black boxes
and the only solution to achieve this
seems to open source the edge device
however even if developers open source
their software who is going to reduce
the source code and verify their program
behavior
so in this talk i will introduce our
solution called peakable towards this
problem and it explains advantages and
the limitations of our approach
so let me start with a simple example so
imagine that a smart tv developer wants
to know how engaging the device is they
want to know how much time the user has
spent on the tv in the past week
most likely today they will collect the
total table of users video watching
history to the cloud
long term competition there and find the
user spends 25 hours per week
but the issue is that while this data is
just from tv it may expose many
unnecessary insights such as
is used at home when do they watch tv
what are users interests
so to mitigate this type of privacy risk
a simple change is developers can
aggregate the data on the tv device
locally and only collect the number like
25 hours per week
and the question we hear we focus here
is how can developers prove to users
that they only collect 25 hours per week
so a strongman solution is to extend
android permission manifest so for
example android tv can have more
fine-grained permissions in the manifest
and then the developers can declare they
want weekly aggregate data or daily
aggregated data
but this will result in numerous
permissions it will be very hard for
google to offer android tv developer to
implement these apis and it would be
also very hard for developers to learn
this api
and for users it will also be very hard
to implement them or to manage them
and how can we do something better
so we have peekaboo
so people have three key ideas
the first is it's a new way for
developers to program pre-processing
functions
so it's instead of letting developers to
write arbitrary code like python or c
plus code the platform builders should
offer a set of fixed set of operators
and here each operator is a trainable
data processing functions
and the program is a stream oriented
pipeline similar to unix pipes
and the picture is a programming
environment we build in pickable and
here the app developer can drag the
operators from left connect them into a
pipeline and configure the properties of
each operator
and second the app developers can export
the program as a text-based manifest
the text-based manifest this describes
how the app developer wants to like
crack users data the manifest here
describes they want to measure device
engagement and here the manifest pulls
the data from the tv device each week
aggregate the data and post results to
the cloud
and finally a trusted in-home hub will
mediate between the edge devices and the
cloud servers
the hub has a set of pre-loaded
implementations so when the hub loads
the manifest it maps all the operators
to the specific implementation
and based on operator properties and
then assemble a pre-processing pipeline
based on the manifest
and here the many the pipeline will pro
pre-process the complete video watch
history into a numeric value
so in summary the smart home hub store
creates a programming environment and
offers a fixed set of operators
the app developer then creates a
pre-processing pipeline by constructing
a set of by constructing a pipeline
using these operators
and finally the long time will load the
manifest and create the actual program
so in the future the smart home app
store all these apps will be simple text
with manifest
once a user install a new app the hub
will load a new manifest create a
pipeline based on
between the edge device and the cloud
notice the hub device is a local device
in your home
so it can be your future like wi-fi
router
through pickable the hub now became
something a new type of privacy firewall
and a base and which will filter data
based on the manifest declared by
developers
so the design of pickable is motivated
by two insights
so first app developers they must
declare intended data collection
behavior in text based manifest so this
leads to two fundamental differences
between peekaboo and a traditional
firewall
first it is a white list only system
this is feasible because the
functionality of iot devices are much
simpler than pc or mobile mobile phone
it's unnecessary for these iot devices
to have general purpose network access
second
developers are involved in the process
instead of letting the firewall to
figure out which network request is is
legitimate or not
people explicitly ask developers to
declare why do they want to collect data
and what data granularity they want
and the second insight is that most
smart home applications they do not
really need raw data
we collect over 200 smart home id
smartphone ideas and analyze how these
applications can be implemented in the
real world
and indeed
among all these applications less than a
quarter of them really need raw data for
example imagine if we want to have an
application called hello visitor that
you can install on your video adobe
the app wants to recognize the person in
front of the video w but they only need
a face image
or if we want to use alexa to compute
the noise level the device can do it
without sending the data to the cloud
so here comes like a main difference
between peekaboo and a traditional
firewall is peakable does not simply
allow or deny a traffic request
it also pre-process the data to mitigate
all the potential privacy risks so for
example here the hub can pre-process the
complete
video watch history into a numeric value
so to recap there are two main
differences between peakable and a
traditional firewall so first it allows
white listed network requests declared
by developers
and second it pre-processed users data
to mitigate privacy risks
now i will dive into the system to
explain how system works
we assume that the edge devices will
have some form of device api
we create a few device drivers to wrap
up these device apis and prepare them
into a unified data model
there are five types of data streams in
peekaboo
video image audio tabular and scalar
value
and the unique design of peakable is
that we only have a fixed set of
operators
in total we only have 16 operators
the operator idea is inspired by sql
database query language when we think
about this a slack operator in database
it just selects a low from a table
but if we zoom out the id of operators
can be data agnostic for example we can
also select a face from an image
for select we always want to select some
partial content from the raw data
the specific behavior of an operator is
determined by the properties of the
operator
for example if the property of the slack
operator is low the runtime will map the
operator to the low selection
implementation or if the property is
fixed the runtime will map it to the
image cropping one
although there might be multiple
implementation of the same operator but
the input and output semantics would be
consistent because these semantics are
determined by the verb like itself
so using these operators to organize
this implementation can make it much
easier to analyze the program
so notice that the hub will not be a
huge library of pre-loaded
implementations we only need some very
simple and common standard
pre-processing algorithms such as phase
detection tabular aggregation and the
philosophy here is this simple and basic
pre-processing functions can improve
privacy a lot
we only need to process the data into
less privacy invasive format
we then build a system
using like a set of hardware and
software to test our design we build a
physical hub using raspberry pi and a
google usb tpu we also build many smart
home edge devices that are compatible to
the picobrew protocol and we use aws to
host our back-end service
we then implemented these operators in
node.js packages and created and
programming ide and developers drivers
and 23 like preloaded operator
implementations
using this hardware and software we are
able to implement over 200 smart home
applications which i mentioned earlier
so since many manifests can be reused
across different scenarios we finally
implement 68 manifests to cover all
these 200
scenarios
and this manifests can support various
types of data processing
and the example i used in the
presentation are the simple ones so due
to the time limit i will not cover the
most sophisticated one please check them
in my paper
among all these scenarios only three
which is at the bottom is always in raw
data
and for this case developers can simply
connect the poor operator to a
post operator
so
although it does not really offer any
data minimizations here but it makes the
data collection more transparent
we are using some lower end hardware to
build as a whole prototype but the
system performance is efficient is
sufficient to support a typical home
our a prototype can do 25 inference
tasks per second and can do 100
filtering tasks per second and
it introduces a latency between one
millisecond to 80 milliseconds
and remember that we also mentioned as a
few like standard and common
pre-processing algorithms can mitigate
many privacy risks we also run a few
utility privacy tradeoff for example
for example if we insert a noisify
operator for a speech assistant
and we can break the speaker recognition
completely while the speech recognition
accuracy only dropped by two percent
and we also show the tools to developers
and to see if z can learn the api and
the builders manifest quickly we show
developers a few example task
descriptions
and as a programming environment and
unit tests
all developers can learn the api quickly
and spend 6 to 15 minutes to author and
manifest
pickable offers a few important
advantages which is not possible before
the first is now the manifesto can
enforce the data collection behavior
and developer can only collect the data
they specified in the manifest
none of the algorithm or implementation
will be proprietary so the app store can
just make that manifest public to
everyone
and this would make all the data
collection behavior transparent and
whilst the device and
the server would still be proprietary
today large develop large players like
amazon or agnes samsung they only they
can develop their own privacy features
but a big challenge is for these small
developers they have no resource to
build all these privacy features
and what's worse is even if we push
everyone to build their privacy features
it will be very hard for end users
because they have to face all these
distributed interfaces with inconsistent
semantics
and the idea here is peekaboo can
approach this diameter by offering a set
of independent features through the hub
itself
since we only have a small set of
operators and each operator has
predefined semantics
it would be much easier to analyze this
manifest using some simple algorithms
for example i developed a futuristic
based method to turn any manifest into a
privacy nutrition label
but today all these privacy nutrition
labels they have to be they are
self-reported by developers there is no
way to enforce their behavior
but in trust the peak of protocol allows
us to generate all these privacy
nutrition labels automatically and they
always reflect the actual data practice
further we can even make this privacy
nutrition label dynamic and interactive
by editing some of the fields
for example one feature i built can
modify the property of the the inject
operator and insert a noisified operator
between the aggregate and the post
duration so by doing so the app will
only send
like monthly aggregated data rather than
weekly aggregated data and now
developers can get these privacy
features for free because we only need
to build this feature once
and users can manage their privacy in a
centralized and unified manner
so
this is a little bit intimidating data
because we have no animation now
so once adopted this design pattern can
potentially create a new type of privacy
ecosystem
regulators like ftc gdpr they can easily
find out
financial better privacy practices since
the data collection behavior is
transparent and easy to analyze
and privacy editable case can rank as
the app developers to tell you tell
users who is the good developer
and all these small developers they will
be able to get independent privacy
features for free
and finally
users can trust this device because
this architecture will enforce the data
collection behavior
and finally for users they will have
like centralized and unified data
privacy management and they can also
enforce their control to all these iot
devices
so
now i want to conclude my talk the whole
takeaway of my talk is one idea
so traditionally we developed this api
using the permission or a uil and allow
developers to query the data through it
and peekaboo advocates a new design
that is the system developers such as
appstore they can offer a set of
operators to design the api
and app developers can change these
operators into a graph
before they access the data by doing so
platform builders they can offer
fine-grained data access with less
efforts
and app developers can learn the api
quickly and it's much easier to analyze
all this data collection behavior
so to some extent peekaboo is a new type
of domain specific language architecture
whereas a manifest is a program and as
operators zip became the language and at
the runtime is a compiler that simply
assembles this pack pre loaded
implementation like unix pipes
and there are two important implications
of peekaboo which is the computation
there needs to be repetitive and we can
absolutely abstract them into a fixed
set of operators
and only have a few preloaded
implementations
and we also need to build a trusted
runtime
so one example
is
the zoom example
so today like zoom actually can access
all your google calendar information
but also what does they need is only the
calendar events that contain a zoom link
and how can we fix that
so in the future google should offer the
api
with a set of operators
and zoom should alter their data access
in a manifest and upload the manifest to
google to get access there
by doing so
zoom will only be able to access the
events that contain assumed link
so with that i want to conclude the talk
and
i will any questions
[Applause]
uh thank you uh great talk
uh i was wondering how would you go
about backward compatibility for example
a lot of apps that have already been
built would you expect developers to
update their apps to support peekaboo
um yes that's um i would say currently
we do not think too much about back
compatibility at this moment and that's
why we are working with smart home first
because we do not have a smart home app
store yet so it's a good opportunity for
us to do this
but in the future i will see see
android also wants to adopt this
and z can extend the information
manifest like step by step rather than
to have all the things that manifested
at one time they can replace some of the
permission with the graph like a
representation
and to kind of mitigate mitigate the
back probability issue
thank you no problem
nathan dunham rice um great talk really
exciting so my main interest concern is
how you deal with unexpected events
right so it's nice to think a white list
is great you know you get this cross
product uh you know the complexity here
is going to be like somewhere in cubed
or something right yes and so i'm
wondering what you think uh is going to
happen when you get a lot of
interactions when you don't anticipate
what's going on yes so they do exist
like see someone really want to invent
some innovative way to build this
application
and for this type of application so we
will see like have this like the kind of
backdoor approach and people just get
the data and send forward the data to
the cloud
so by doing so there is no operator
involved in this case
but the whole idea is like when we make
all this data collection behavior
transparent
so we can encourage people more to use
this more fine-grained access rather
than using this all nothing api
okay did i answer my question so i think
what you're saying is you have
a
distributed tracing and monitoring layer
that represents every object
and then every different type of device
and then you would trace everything yes
and then that would go to some system
that can then consolidate and say oh
we've seen this many things and now that
we can use that to make our policies yes
and but as a policy is for us it's more
likely for people to specify these
policies in operators
okay awesome thank you so much
hello you want to try from uw medicine
uh very interesting talk so i have one
question so like how do you derive the
set of operators
like
what kind of
criteria did you choose to select the
operators i see so you mean what type so
i would say i guess operators are
basically the semantics you are talking
about the pre-loaded implementations on
the hub
is my understanding oh yeah yeah yeah
yeah that's a very nice question so
there are a few criterias to select this
like implant but first is it's not
really a static scene people can
dynamically add a new
kind of like a preloaded implementation
just like android like os version
but for the implementation to be placed
on the hub there are a few criterias one
is
it needs to be non-proprietary
so for example tabular aggregation is
just a few lines of code and the second
is it should be common enough and which
is commonly used by different
applications
and the third one is it also needs to be
lightweight because the hub itself is
local they will not have like large
computing powers
and so we have some lightweight
computing on the hub this will be able
to handle all these pre-processing and
in our people we actually enumerated
a table like of all these like
pre-processing opportunities we we
explore
in the in the system thank you very much