thank you everyone uh
hi my name is in chile welcome to this
talk and today i'm going to talk about
our work piccolo exposing complex
backdoors in nlp transformer models and
this is a joint research work between
purdue university and rutgers university
backdoor attacks has
has shown a severe threat to the nlp
transformer models and here let me use a
very simple
sentiment classification model to
illustrate what is vector attacks on nlp
models
first
given a bad backdoor nlp models when
facing with clean samples
curling samples it gives the correct
mode of predictions
and when the input contains a trigger
the backdoor models misbehave and give
the wrong predictions or give the
predictions that the attacker deal
desires here in this uh in this case the
trigger is a hash sign
at the beginning of the sentence
besides the character triggers i have
just shown the triggers could also be
like word triggers or phrase triggers
and they can be injected at any place
at any location in the sentence
and the trigger could also be more
complex for example the sentence
structure triggers
the the clean sentence reads as there is
no pleasure in watching a child suffer
and the sentence with the trigger
reads as when you see a child suffer
there is no pleasure note that the
sentence structure is what and when you
subclass is injected at the beginning of
the sentence this when you subclass is
actually a sentence structure triggers
so to combat uh uh back doors in machine
learning in computer vision the trigger
inversion is highly effective in uh
detecting back doors in configuration
so let me first introduce what is
trigger inversion in computer vision it
assumes access to a model and a set of
clean inputs
then it's stamped random trigger on the
clean image and they fit this stamped
image directly into the input layer of
the model
and then optimize the trigger on the
input space such that the model's output
label is flipped to a target class
note that in this case uh a bolt image
is flipped to the target class car
and because the model is differentiable
from the input to the output we can
simply do a gradient descent on the
input and you your words are triggered
that's flip the labels
if a trigger can flip most of the clean
inputs the trigger inversion consider
model trojan
noel
knows that in computer vision the model
is differentiable from the input to the
output
so we follow the classic tech model of
triggering motion in computer we
computer vision we see a lp
classification model is chosen if the
model does not have a non-trivial
accuracy degradation and clean inputs
and the model misclassified input with
the trigger and for defender
setting we we assume that the offender
is given the model and a few clean
sentences
and she needs to determine if the model
is chosen or not and note that defender
has no access to the input split
triggers
before diving into our method let me
first briefly introduce the uh
the typical structure of nlp
transformers
so given a text input given a sentence
the nlp transformers will first
parsing into a list of token ids note
that complex words will pass into
multiple ids for example here the word
uh judgments it's passed into two ids
and then each token id is used to look
up for an embedding vector with a size
of 768.
this e equal table id is indexing our
operation and it is not differentiable
then the embedding vectors are fed into
the transformer to give the final
final output note that in the in
traditional computer vision models the
model is differentiable from input to
output however with the unique structure
of nlp transformers
poses new challenges in trigger
inversion in lp
our first challenge
our first challenge is that the input
space is
is discrete and lp models are not
differentiable to the input this lines
in the table lookup operation that maps
the token id to the
imaging vectors note that this is
indexing our operation and it is not
differentiable
and uh in the uh in in trigonometry in
ccb we can just do the gradient back
propagation from the output to the input
however the gradient propagation in nlp
cannot go through the table lookup to
the token level
so to so to solve the first challenge we
propose a differentiable model
transformation it essentially just
transforms this non-differentiable table
lookup into a differentiable matrix
multiplication that is equivalent
so given a list of token ids we first
transform them into a list of uh one
hardware where where one of the vectors
we call the token vectors so for took
idn the answer element of the welcome
vector is one and all other elements are
zero for example for two id uh for the
first token id 119
the rest of the 119th element is one and
all other elements are zero then instead
of do a table lookup we can simply get
the word embeddings by multiplying the
one
how the token vectors with the
width lookup table and this is
equivalent to the table indexing i will
use a simple example to illustrate this
let's lastly we have a small
lookup table with just four entries and
our token id is one then the indexing of
our operation we will just simply select
the second vector 0.3 0.2 0.7 something
and the corresponding one hold vector is
0. 0 1 0 0 0 where the second element is
1 and all other elements are 0.
then do a matrix multiplication on the
lookup table we can simply also get the
same uh
vector 0.2 0.3 0.7 verb and this is
equivalent so the uh multiplying the one
two vector and the lookup table is
equivalent to the unindexing table and
if we think about it as long as the sum
of the token vector is one the token
vector can also be billed as a
probability distribution of the token
ids so we can
optimize on this tool vector to invert
the trigger
so let's go back to our model
transformation
after we have the bankhold token vectors
we can get the word embeddings by
multiplying the token vectors with the
lookup table
and we can feed the world embeddings to
the transformer to follow the whole pro
whole pipeline
and this uh this of our operation is
differentiable and the gradients can
back propagate from the model output to
the two total convectors and simply
similarly to trigger inversion in cv we
can just inject the trigger vector in
the two comparator level to do the
triggering version
however then we met our second challenge
uh token level optimization technology
reverse engineer complex words with
multiple tokens for example here our
example uh trigger word is word
immensity and in birth it's deleted into
three tokens
am m e and s i t y and assume we know
the number of tokens we need and we use
exactly three trigger two convectors in
trigger inversion and the optimization
shows the result is three tokens imvn
and d-o-t-y and it misses the real
trigger and these three uh inverted
trigger can only flip around like 70 of
clean samples and it is not good uh high
enough for trigger immersion to
determine this model is children
so to invert complex uh trigger word
token level inversion can easily get
stuck in some invalid token combinations
and that misses the real trigger
so to solve the second challenge we
propose word level inversion here i just
showed a trigger took a leveling version
on the left for comparison so give a
text input given a sentence we first do
a uh we first pass it into a list of
word ids note that our word vocabulary
contains many complex words so so they
don't need to be splitted into multiple
tokens for example here the word cha cha
the word judgments only correspond to
one id
and then similarly we can do a one hard
word like uh while hold factorization
and get the word vectors and and
similarly we can uh we can get the two
vectors by multiplying the two word
vectors with the word uh to token matrix
and and we can guess what embeddings by
multiplying the word uh two vectors with
a loop with a lookup table the whole
process is differentiable and we can
similarly we can just invert the trigger
at a word level and here notice that
because we we use a large word
vocabulary we only need one trigger
vector to invert uh complex words such
as immensity and this reduces the
uh the search space and helps the
trigger inversion
so in this slide i will show how to do
the word level inversion first we inject
a vector in the word vectors we call it
trigger probability
trigger probability vector where each
element stands for the probability of
that word uh their corresponding words
being the trigger and since we have made
the whole whole pipeline differentiable
we can just propagate the gradients from
the model output to the word vectors and
optimize this trig trigger probability
vector
in a way that it flips the model
prediction on the clean samples
we also uh bound this trigger
probability like trigger probability
vector to be between zero and one uh by
tangent edge and we also normalize this
trigger probability vector to the sum of
1 in every 30 epochs
so after
the
the optimization words with high values
in the trigger probability vector are
what we call the trigger word candidates
and we test them for the attack success
rate
so here is the overview of our method
uh
given a model m and a clean and a set of
clean inputs
we first transform this model m into a
differentiable equivalent model m prime
and with the clean
inputs uh we do a word uh word level
trigger inversion and get a list of
trigger word candidates and then the
trigger word candidates is it's uh it's
fed into a world discriminativity
analysis and trigger validation to
determine if the model is children or
not uh in the first two straps actually
corresponds to the two challenges i have
talked about and in the word
discriminativity analysis for complex
words it is possible that we only invert
a partial trigger word and it doesn't
have high sr so it has the word
discriminativity of the trigger word
candidates to determine if a model is
trojan
and for trigger validation we simply
test the text success rate of of the
trigger word candidates and determine if
the model is chosen due to the time
limit i will utilize the details of the
last two part
so in evaluation we evaluate piccolo on
seven datasets
amazon
amazon review mdb
sst2 for sentimental classification coll
2003 bncorps and onto nodes for name
entity recognition and we also evaluated
our method on seven lprt architectures
bird distilled bird mobile birds
gilberta jp2 and simple lstm and gru
and we also evaluated our method against
lp models from the trojan computation at
the existing works
and we also evaluate piccolo against 17
different
tech types including the latest
dynamic attacks the sentence structure
trigger
before going into the evaluation details
i want to first briefly introduce what
is iopa's trojan computation it is a
multi-year computation for backdoor
scanning it is still going on right now
and it is open to public so anyone can
participate
and uh it has nine rounds so far
targeting for both computer vision and
nlp
and at each round trojan has like
thousands of models half clean and half
children and they ask the performers to
submit their predictors that predicts
which model is cho uh a uh contest
backdoor
and performers need to submit their
scanners to the 2di remote server which
evaluates the evaluation against
the test and the holdout sets the test
and holdout says uh
we cannot access the test and hold
outsets and they can have a more load
robust your evaluation
so the wrong target is around like 0.34
cross entropy loss which is often
correspond to around like a 90 percent
accuracy
so we uh so the lead the current to ji
leaderboard is accessed can be accessed
at this
website and here i
i show a screenshot of the trojan
leaderboard as you can see you they have
your evaluation server and you can
submit your container to the evaluation
server to to get uh to get it to get
your message tested and here i showed
the
screenshot of the current uh current
rounds to uh total gi leaderboard
so in effectiveness our piccolo achieves
over 0.9 detection accuracy for all the
evaluated attacks
and in children computation
piccolo is the only solution that beats
the round goal in all three lp
classification runs and each
and piccolo achieves the top on two out
of three nlp runs in trojan competition
so here i show a table of the trojan
leaderboard with our method piccolo and
other team's best star mission
choji
competitions release two uh metrics to
measure the scanner's performance ce
loss and roc aoc so a lower c loss and
higher ioc you'll see indicates better
performance and as you can see on
round six and round seven our message
picot piccolo
is the best
among other participants
this is a related work to our message
due to the time limit i will skip this
and also uh we share our method and
our 2s missions on different rounds in
our online code apple
to summarize uh we developed a novel
backdoor scanning technique piccolo
because it's based on a normal word
level encoding and the word
discriminativity analysis and based on
the trojan computation results and
evaluation piccolo achieves a state of
art
results for complex models and a wide
range of backdoor attacks
thank you that's all i'm happy to take
any questions
[Applause]
so we have time for questions and
as usual please feel free to
don't be shy walk to the mic
so they don't have an affiliation
i can probably break the ice no
you have a question
hi uh dirt of the very northeastern
university uh great talk and great work
uh i i have a curiosity to ask you uh
did you notice uh differences in
effectiveness of your
system on different sizes of the models
you analyze like bigger models smaller
models model trains with bigger data
sets smaller data sets yes that's a
great question uh so on
let me go back here
so on the seven different lp
architectures we
uh we uh we do a kind of like uh
statistical check and we we found that
actually on roberta we only uh we are a
little bit worse than both the uh andrew
roberta jpt2 were a little bit worse
than berlin d silver and mobile world uh
and but
overall the architecture does not matter
that much uh in terms of three uh like
different attack tabs we handle the
freeze trigger the worst
because we are inversion technique and
usually it's very hard to invert a whole
phrase
but the details can be found in our
paper thank you
i have a question
um so for you mentioned that uh to to
make the whole model than differentiable
you don't use don't rely on token
inversion anymore but then you use
wording version yes because you have to
do the one hot encoding and then
multiply that matrix and you know to
make it work
um you said that in the example for
instance you need to have the word in
your vocabulary right so how big is the
that's a that's a great question so uh
so in the um so several things uh first
uh
so you know our hours the system that's
uh submitted in the paper
at that time we have like 7000 as the
word vocabulary and the
adaptive attacks we have uh increased
the vocabulary from 7 000 to 30 000 and
uh because the childreni competition is
still going on and in the latest round
around nine we are we increased our
world vocabulary to over a hundred so so
overall hundred thousand based on the
word uh frequency in the wikipedia day
data set right and and how do you see
this improving like have you tried to
compare the performance
uh as as the vocabulary size increases
like there is a point where you have a
saturation point that you know adding
more words doesn't look like you know
yes
that's a good question uh
we have done an adaptive attack on like
if the words is outside the word uh word
vocabulary and uh
we find that as long as we can increase
the size of vocabulary we we can still
have a good performance and in terms of
the competition uh
fulfilling we feel that
the previous rounds uh the the solutions
that works on the like round seven and
round eight it's not that effective on
round nine that's why we go from like
twenty thousand to like over hundreds of
southern income
to achieve good performance in
competition yeah thank you wonderful
thank you thank you
um
so if there are no other
any other questions so we can thank the
speaker
[Applause]