hello
thanks for the introduction also
so my name's lee um so today my talk is
about quantifying blockchain extractable
value how dark is the forest this is a
joint work with kaihua and also
so many of you might have heard of the
book flash voice from michael lewis
so in traditional finance there are
plenty of market manipulation techniques
which is typically regulated by
regulators
so regulators like the
sec in the u.s they typically do two
types of
actions so firstly they
come up with some rules
and they enforce the rules if someone
violates
the policies
so in this particular example we have
seen a company paying 16 million
penalty to the stack
so in d5
very strangely marketing manipulation is
not yet regulated
so on this slide i want to give a high
level overview of the entire default
space so d5 stands for decentralized
finance
so d5 builds upon blockchains and
blockchains have multiple layers we have
the network layer where the transactions
are propagated and we have the consensus
layer and also the application logic
layer so all these device services are
built on punch the blockchain and also
they work with different token standards
such as the functional token
non-functional token and etc
so for this d5 services to function
efficiently and effectively they
typically rely on some market mechanisms
such as arbitrage liquidation and etc
and these market mechanisms actually
leads to market manipulations such as
such as front running and backgrounding
so what is blockchain extractable value
so we typically observe this common
pattern where starting from blockchain
applications
they rely on some events to kind of keep
the protocol functioning and these
events can lead to profitable trading
opportunities so taking the landing
protocol as an example
the landing protocol typically
relies on liquidation um so in the
liquidation basically your collector is
sold by some entity to pay your debt
in traditional finance this process um
so so typically um who liquidates who
triggers the liquidation is rather
certain in traditional finance
so taking home mortgage as an example
typically is the bank who will be
selling your property in order to pay
the debt
however in d5
it's very tricky like who will be
liquidating the position
it can really be anyone anyone means
like it can be a trader sitting in front
of a browser and
triggering the liquidation manually
it can also be a bot
which listens to all the times all types
of transactions on network layer and
then triggering the liquidation
automatically upon the detection of a
profitable
opportunity it can also be a miner who
kind of package the liquidation into the
next block they might
so one thing that's really important to
understand um here is
how the transactions are ordered because
this actually determines who will be the
winner for the bev extraction
opportunities
so in this particular example let's say
we have three transactions t1 t2 and t3
they are received by the minus in this
exact order
and can anyone tell me maybe like why
transaction three is received first but
actually mined as the last transaction
in the next block does anyone know
yeah right after the gas feed yeah
that's right so
miners typically want to maximize their
profit so they are ordering transactions
based on how much fee each of the
transactions are paying
but what's more important is
miners can single-handedly order the
transactions so they can really um do
like order the transactions in any
particular order they want
so this gives them
a like a very big advantage over the
other market players in this
bu extraction game
so you might well you might wonder how
much value has been actually extracted
we have performed
an
empirical evaluation over 32 months
period so we found out that about 540
million usd was extracted in profit
so our data set only captures one single
blockchain that is the ethereum
blockchain
so i would expect the bv to be much
bigger if
if someone measures the entire
blockchain space
so in our data set we found around 11k
unique addresses
extracting vuev
we have also
captured
50k cryptocurrencies and 60k markets
so what i want to highlight here is
the small markets surprisingly actually
contribute more to the bue
extraction activities so it's really
important to capture as as many markets
and cryptocurrencies as possible to get
a holistic view of the entire bub space
so in the paper we looked at three
different be resources normally the
sandwich attacks
the liquidation and arbitrage so
liquidation arbitrage are also common
market
activities in traditional finance
sandwich attack is a bit different from
the other two
but i don't have enough time to go
through in detail in details
if you are interested um
i will welcome you to our poster session
later to discuss about sandwich attacks
so here is how much was extracted from
sandwich attacks
on the x-axis i have the time frame so
that's the 32-month period measured on
the y-axis we have the monthly profit
and also the number of sandwich attacks
we observed on chain
so we can see the profit actually
increased from
just a few hundred dollars
to
roughly almost like 100 million
over the past 32 months
so that's
several magnitudes bigger right
comparing to a few years ago
similarly we observe something similar
for arbitrage
we also have like the time frame on the
x-axis
and the profit also increased from 1k to
roughly 100 million for arbitrage so for
both sandwich and arbitrage the revenue
stream is relatively steady for for
these bv extractors
the third type of bub we measured is
liquidation which is quite different
from the other two
here you can see a big spike
on on the plot
so this is because like liquidations are
triggered
more frequently when the market is
crashing
so in the ust and luna event two weeks
ago i am expecting a lot of liquidations
will be triggered
so in total we captured about like 90
million liquidation
events
okay
so
we have also proposed a new form of
attack which we call transaction replay
attack in the paper
so what's funny is in this attack the
attacker is trying to be a copycat which
basically the attacker observes
transactions on the network layer
and
it's trying to replace
certain data
in the transaction in order to mimic
what the victim is doing
so in a sense the attacker can extract
bev without understanding anything about
what the victim is trying to do
so the algorithm is actually rather
simple so i basically copy the sender
sorry i copy the transaction and replace
the sender with my own address
and also i copy the value
so for those who are not very familiar
with ethereum value basically is the
amount of user the amount of token i
sent in the transaction
and i also copied the input right and in
the input i replace
the victim's address with my own address
so it's basically three nines of code
and this simple algorithm surprisingly
can could have extracted 35 million usd
um over the 32
months period we studied
that is 188 k profitable transactions
roughly 0.02 percent
of the entire
transactions on ethereum
so so this algorithm is real-time we can
on average process every single
transaction on the 0.2 seconds
also you can observe like a huge spark
here right this is actually an attack
so in a sense our 2 can also act as an
intrusion
prevention tool
where we kind of detect the transactions
the attacks from the attackers and as a
white hat hacker i replace the sender in
that transaction with my own address and
then i protect the money by by doing the
attack myself so basically i need to
front-run the attacker
okay so why bub is an important
issue in blockchain what's the security
implementation
so
when the biggest security implications
about bev is
um
miners may attempt to fork the
blockchain in order to steal the bev
opportunities from the other miners
so we did some empiric we did some
an analytical evaluation on this and
based on our evaluation
um it's rational for a miner with ten
percent of hashing power to fork the
blockchain if the bev is four times the
average block reward
but
guess how much what's the biggest bu we
have detected
the biggest opportunity is actually 874
times the block reward
so under such under such a scenario it
means that even the small miners right
they will try to fork the blockchain uh
which is uh which is a huge risk for the
consensus consensus layer of the
blockchain
because this this will increase the
stability rate and also make the double
spending attacks easier
okay so here comes the summary
so in this paper we studied
three different types of bv extraction
mechanisms
nominate arbitrage liquidation and
sandwich attacks so in total we have
observed roughly half a billion profit
extracted during this process
we also
proposed a new attack
mechanism which which we named
transaction replay which could have
extracted roughly 35 million usd in
profit
so we expect so because d5 is still kind
of in its nothing stage so we expect
this bus issue to become more severe in
the future
we encourage researchers to join us on
this exciting topic
lastly please allow me to shamelessly
advertise our d5 mooc course
so it's really a fantastic toss
and
i've learned a lot from the course and
i'm also a ta for the course so yeah
thank you
thank you so much lee
the course will have another iteration
in the fall for those who are interested
any questions from the audience
over there okay great
conley from baidu security so i noticed
that you have the 35 million
extracted over the likes of two years
over the period time right but there's
one event like allow you to extract
maybe like 20 million or something
that's a kick jump could you just
comment about that a little bit yeah
so so this is actually an attack we
[Music]
detected it's actually three
transactions uh exploiting some
vulnerability i think it was the eminent
project
where where the attacker hacked the the
protocol
so
by replacing the sender right with our
own address we could have
acted on that right and exported the
contract ourselves as a white hacker to
to kind of prevent
the attack
does that make sense yeah thank you
i was wondering so how can you protect
against these replay attacks as a like
if you if you if you're trading you
don't want any of these spots to engage
what do you do
good question that's a very
interesting
attack so so in my opinion um because
everything is basically transparent um
on the blockchain especially to the
miners because they are the ones packing
the transactions um so
um
it's
in my opinion right doesn't mean you
have to agree in my opinion there's no
way to prevent replay attacks in general
any more questions from the audience
and i might have one more question so
you you're showing the overlap right
between the replay and the liquidation
and arbitrage why is it so small in the
overlap i would have thought that that
might be if it's if it's a generalized
tool then it should be bigger right yep
so um there are multiple reasons for
this so firstly we only measured um
certain um mev or bev opportunities
right so there can be other activities
which we didn't measure so what we
provided is actually a lower bond on the
total value extracted
so
replay could be
replacing
for example nft minting events or some
other events
so that's why it can be bigger comparing
to the other two degradation arbitrage
circles
and
the other reason i think is um
so for for for liquidations um
typically people will have some
prevention mechanisms such as preventing
like doing some checks on the senders to
make sure the sender has the has the
right address so
this naive replay algorithms might fail
in such cases
wonderful thank you so much lee
[Applause]