good afternoon everyone i'm jinjang from
the national university of singapore
it's my pleasure to present our recent
work share water recommendation guided
separate threat analysis using system
audit records
this is a joint work with xiang
hao yin vong malvajr zhinkai tencen and
geno
recently we have been witnessing a rapid
escalation of cyber threats that
intentionally targeted large
organizations while performing these
attacks attackers inevitably
leaves footprints in the victim
substance a common question faced by
security analysts is how to combat these
cyber threats using
attackers for prints
audio records are common
footprint
which proves to be a valuable data
source for analyzing cyber threat
they can provide a low level view into
system by monitoring system entity
interactions
for example when an attacker is filtered
sensitive data the password file his
activities will be recorded as system
course in the audio records
to facilitate attack detection and the
investigation audio records are usually
navigated through a prevalence graph
that describes the system's historical
context
here by following the data provenance we
can find that the password file is
linked to a remote server through
malicious executables
in general system audit team connects
several separate attack steps
presenting the overall attack scenarios
for security analyst
based on how audio records are used for
service rate analysis existing work can
be categorized into three directions
statistics-based approaches quantify
audio records degrees of suspicion by by
their historical frequency
however the primary concern for this
nano research is a number of
force positives generated by rare
but benign system activities
specification-based approaches can
maintain a low level or low voltage rate
by mapping audio records against the
knowledge base of security policies
however such security policies are are
usually can consumer and error prone to
develop because they heavily depend on
as per knowledge
learning-based approaches typically
train a model of benign behaviors and
then detect deviations as cyber attacks
unfortunately current learning based
approaches only produce detection
signals at the core screen level
specifically behavior level
which requires intensive manual efforts
to review
individual audio records in behaviors
for attack investigation
in this work we aim to address these
limitations
our solution is based on the observation
that cyber threats can be revealed by
determining how likely a system entity
would interact with another system
entity
in particular unlikely or unintended
system entity interactions would reveal
cyber threats
for example sensitive files normally do
not interact with the public networks
which otherwise indicate the daytime
filtration activity
such likelihood can be estimated using
historical system nt interactions
for example if we observe that this
gtcache process
has
interact with the process status file
then it's reasonable for this process to
communicate or access another process
data file
this problem is similar to a
recommendation task
where the primary goal is to determine
how likely a user would would interact
with an item
earlier recommendation systems
comprehend user preferences
by finding similar users
using historical user item interactions
to illustrate this idea we use a
movie recommendation scenario where
alice is a targeted user for
recommendation
since both eddies and bob have watched
the ironman
recommendation systems would uh would
consider these two users users similar
and because the source is bob's favorite
movie recommendation systems would also
recommend the store to edis because
she is similar to bob
unfortunately
user item interactions are insufficient
to recommend
items that are disconnected in user in
historical interactions
for example the avengers queue
to address this issue
modern recommendation systems would
adopt i-10 site information to form a
high-order connectivity that links the
similar items
here because the iron man and the
avengers are connected through
multi-hall passes based on action and
the marvel studios
modern recommendation systems would
recommend the addis to the avengers
because it's similar to airmen
the little woman would not be
recommended because it's disconnected to
addis
inspired by recommendations
we make an observation that similar
system entities in audio records would
share preferences on interactions
for example sensitive data do not like
interacting with the public networks
and to uncover system entities
similarities
we aim to identify high order
connectivity based on sign information
of system entities
for example if we observe that two
process status files are called were
correlated through process status
information
then we would determine that they are
similar and share the preferences of
interacting with the gt cache process
as we as a result we can formulate a
several thread analysis in audio records
as a recommendation task
which models how likely a system entity
would prefer its interactive entities
to perform recommendations on audio
records
we propose shield water
it takes the system records
as input
and then generate a graph neon a graph a
noise graph
and based on this notch graph
sharewatcher will trim a
recommendation model to recommend the
adversarial system entity interactions
to security analyst
first given audio records and encodes
we pass them into a provenance graph
where the nodes in the graph assist
entities for example a process a file or
circuit
and the edges denote the system course
we consider that two system entities are
interacted
as long as there is a path that links
these two system entities in a
provenance graph
and here we extract all the system
entities into a bipartite graph
while system entities society
information plays an important role in
uncovering their semantics
such information is not encoded in a
province graph or by pathograph
however a recent study has shown that
such psychic information can be inferred
from the context in which system
entities are used
as a result to incorporate high order
connectivity as in recommendations
we combine system entity contacts that
represent the site information and the
system entity interactions into a noise
graph
in this work we represent a north graph
as a set of trebles
this treble consists of three elements
a head
a radiation and a tail head and really
head and the tail here represent the
system entities
and the relation denotes the system core
or
interactions
taking the knowledge graph as input our
key idea is to use different other
connectivities in the graph to model the
likelihood of system entity interactions
towards this end we first model first
order connectivity to parameterize
system entities as embeddings
then we try to model higher order
connectivity by propagating embeddings
from neighbors with a graph neural
network
at last
we classify system entity interactions
into normal and anomalous
in what follows
i will elaborate on these phases
by modeling first half connections or
first order connectivity in a program
you know notch graph we aim to map
system entities into a battery space to
preserve their semantics
our intuition is to use a system contact
context to decide the semantics of
system entities
to do so we use a knowledge graph
embedding method chance r
at its core is to use head plus relation
to define tail
in node graphs tables
it's worth mentioning that trends are
will assign distinct semantics of
individual system entities conditioned
on different relations
for example if this gt cache is used on
the right and unlink relation context
it will be given two different
embeddings
which indicates different semantics
beyond the first half connections
multi-hub passes are inherent in a
noisy graph
such high order connectivity not only
supplement similarities among system
entities but also exhibit how system
entities influence each other
the left two half pass shows the
similarity between two process data
files because they both interact with
the gt process the write three hard pass
describes how the password file is
transmitted out of an enterprise
to model such high order connectivity
we adopt a graph neural network to
iteratively propagate information along
with the multi-hard passes in a notch
graph
afterwards we aggregate the embeddings
from all the propagation iterations to
form the final system entity interact in
system mdt semantics
after obtaining system entity intel uh
in
embeddings
we apply inner product on them to
predict how likely a system entity would
not interact with another entity
if the likelihood is beyond our
predefined stress code we would classify
the interaction
as a potential service threat
to keep up with involving system entity
interactions will also enable dynamic
updates of our recombination model
using ns feedback on detection signals
the details of such model update can be
found in your paper
to evaluate shield water we use the six
real world cyber attacks simulated in a
test ban environment
and the four apt attacks from the darpa
transparent computing tc
dataset
we focus on uh evaluating the following
aspects
how effective is shift watcher as a
threat detection signal
to what extent do different other
information facilitate several threat
analysis
and how efficient is shear water in
deployment
in terms of shell washer's effectiveness
in cyberspread detection we aim to
identify service threats based on system
entity interactions in the participation
and the simulated data center
the wrtc data set has over 68 thousand
munitious interactions and around 8
million benign interactions
our experiment result shows that shea
washer only misses 10
malicious interactions and its overall
phosphate rate is well below 1
as for the simulator data set it
consists of 39 malicious interactions
two of which are missed by the shield
watcher
from this table we can see that shea
watcher can distinguish benign and
malicious interactions with a higher
accuracy
to um to answer how different order
connectivity facilitates several strain
analysis
we compare different knowledge graph
embedding algorithms and study the
importance of high order information
propagated by our graph neural networks
the results are summarized in this table
the combination of trends r plus graph
neural network represents our share
watcher
compared with one holding coding
transient and transaction
transar's advantage is to distinguish
semantics of system entities conditioned
on different religions
we observed that shield watcher achieves
the best performance in terms of the auc
venues
which implies that high order
information is beneficial for cyber
threat analysis
and it's important to distinguish
different semantics for such for system
entities under different relation
contexts
we measure share watchers wrong time
overhead on the public dot rtc data set
at different phases
we perform all experiments five times
and report the main results in this
table
from the table we can see that
sharewatcher can pinpoint service
threats for nearly a medium system
entity interactions within several
seconds
we would like to point out that we
obtain these results
by running
sharewater on a gpu machine
by further evaluating shearwater on cpu
machines we observe that shield watcher
can still finish system entity classif
system entity in action interaction
classification within four minutes which
is still practical in real-world
scenarios
to conclude
nowadays we have been every cyber
threats are everywhere leaving traces of
shades in the vatican systems
to reveal these sheets we propose a
sharewater to analyze cyber threats
through recommendations on system entity
interactions
it models a system entity's preferences
on its interactive entities
our key insights are that similar system
entity
entities would share preferences on
interactions
and higher order information can better
correlate similar system entities even
though they are disconnected in a
problems graph
thank you for your time and attention
i'm happy to see any question
[Applause]
thank you very much for the presentation
i
am gonna coordinate the q a we have time
for a few questions uh
i'm keeping an eye on i'm keeping an eye
also in the online
platform from our audience that is
following us from home
if you have any question could you walk
through the microphone
can we turn on the microphone for the
q a
i mean for the sake of simplicity i'm
gonna give
my mic
thank you
that's very interesting talk
my question simple
i noticed that the false positive rate
is
low i mean 0.33 percent it's a great but
we're given 8 million
interactions i mean still this is a big
number i mean
is this manageable i mean we're talking
about
10 000 false positives in absolute
numbers
so
are you satisfied with this how can we
do better
okay thanks for the question uh so first
of all we have uh i need to acknowledge
that like
most anomaly detectors or detectors
share watcher inherits the limitation of
of a high phosphate rate uh because it
detects the anomalous system entity
interaction size cyber stress
and
we uh so first of all shear washer is
used to perform the substrate analysis
and produce the detection signals for
security analysts
and if the security analyst finds that
for supportives
are too many to analyze
we suggest that the security analyst to
use further technologies for example the
threat another trend energy systems to
render all of these uh malicious system
entity interactions so that analysts can
focus on the most important ones
and i believe
this is uh
an open question for all the cyber
threat detection systems and we also
will focus on solving or mitigating this
type of question in our future work
thanks
do we have other questions from the
audience
i just have a small curiosity like
do you feel that this recommendation
system principles could
be extended also to other domains such
as in code analysis
or do you think that these principles
apply already to the audit logs
like the this relationship between the
recommendation systems information
propagation that you use here
and other domains such as program
analysis and code analysis maybe from
our deduction yeah
so yeah that's a very good question
so um
so to my knowledge or to our knowledge
we are the first to use the
recommendation engines
to find further establishment analysis
and this is because we find that the
information propagation in a notch graph
original province graph or build upon
audio records are quite important to
detect service threats
so we believe that recombination
systems or recombination engines can be
a possible future directions for other
security
fields for example the source code
analysis and the binary analysis because
in source code and or
program analysis because in program
analysis we sometimes will construct a
graph for example control
control flow graph or code property
graph out of programs and
since the information propagation is
also important in program analysis maybe
we can use this recombination engine as
a searching engine to find interesting
interactions or activities for us to
analyze some malicious activities
thank you thanks let's have another
round of applause for our speaker