okay
hi
um hi everyone my name is uc woo and i'm
a phd student at georgia tech's school
of interactive computing and today i'll
be presenting our sok paper on social
cyber security that was co-authored with
my advisors keith edwards and travikdas
so many end user smp behaviors are
inherently social we share info about
ourselves with our social networks ask
friends and family for s p advice and
also negotiate with others to protect
our privacy
so whether you call it social cyber
security or socio-technical cyber
security or community oversight or
network privacy or any number of other
names
these emergent perspectives on end user
s p beyond the individual share a common
goal to understand s p behaviors and
threats in an ecosystem of
interconnectedness and influence
so our methodology for taxonomizing the
social cyber security literature
landscape spans three phases one is
gathering private relevant prior work
two identifying common themes across
these papers and three grouping themes
and into taxonomically significant
significant domains
so first we began our search with some
keyword searches such as human and
societal aspects of security and privacy
and social aspects of security and
privacy
and these searches quickly snowballed to
include the terms above and these
keyword searches resulted in about a
thousand articles that mostly fell under
the umbrella of usable security and
privacy from the venues listed on this
slide
so to further pare down these papers
just to those that were specifically
including some element of social
coordination or cooperation we asked
questions like does this work advance
our knowledge of how
social groups uh jointly navigate s p
decisions behaviors threats or tools or
does this information advance our
knowledge of how s p threats tools or
advice affects groups differently than
individuals so for example work on
sharing passwords with others qualifies
as social cyber security since it
involves an element of negotiation and
trust in others
but work on general passive password
usage and usability does not so this
left us with approximately 100 articles
and then for each of the papers we
identified the core research question
methodology
analysis results results and etc and
then we applied a reflexive approach to
thematic analysis so i performed the
initial coding and i tagged these paper
summaries with granular codes like
dating or password sharing or location
etc and then our research team
participated in repeated discussions
together to iteratively organize these
codes and generate categories from these
codes
so across literature we identified four
main behavioral domains
one negotiating access to shared
resources which includes sharing media
accounts devices files physical access
to workspaces
rideshare houses etc
um shared in social authentication which
includes user reliance on others to help
them authenticate as well as systems
that facilitate group authentication
managing self-presentation which
includes disclosing personal info to
build trust self-censorship audience
selection tools context collapse and
curating public profiles
and finally influencing others s p
behaviors which includes consulting with
friends and family for advice sharing
experiences with others social proof
nudges to influence behaviors and
cross-cultural consideration for
appropriate s p advice
and then within each domain we also
looked at how these behaviors drift
differed across different levels of
social distance which was loosely
adapted from hull's proximity theory and
proxemics is the study of how people
non-verbally communicate their level of
intimacy with each other by arranging
each other within like a physical
environment so a hall identifies
basically forest spaces the intimate
space the personal space social space in
the public space
and these scales are just a generally
canonical reference for work on social
relationships and interpersonal
distances
and then within computing these scales
of course extend beyond physical
proximity
and then for s p behavior specifically
as we unpack in the slides to come the
ways that romantic partners families and
households social acquaintances and the
public share resources credentials
advice and about themselves with each
other are all distinct from one another
so let's move on to the meat of the sok
domains
in this section we consider the sharing
of digital services like netflix banking
work accounts
physical devices and physical
environments
so there's often a necessary conflation
between sharing content and sharing the
authentication information that
facilitates access to the content even
though passwords and pins generally come
with advice to never be shared
partners and households do so anyway via
granting access to devices media
finances etc cetera
so that's we include the majority of
password-sharing practices in this
domain
so within intimate relationships
partners share a variety of devices
accounts and resources bank accounts
media descriptions calendars like i
mentioned before
but these sharing practices also present
significant psychological hurdles
especially when the relationship ends
and within the context of intimate
partner violence or ipv these hurdles
grow due to the intimacy and in-person
nature of these relationships of users
can easily access the survivor's devices
and accounts
within family and households there's
actually a lot of similarity to intimate
relationships but more broadly there has
also been empirical work on how smart
home devices can unintendedly share
personal information with other
household members
within social acquaintances there has
been
participatory design work on encouraging
groups of users to envision social
solutions to the access and s p problems
they face as groups but more
specifically we find that people in the
workplace frequently share passwords
with co-workers via unofficial means
like slack email and post-it notes and
while there are technical systems in
place for access control such as like
key card access to physical maker spaces
or work environments these systems are
typically static and don't contain a lot
of nuance such as like if someone has to
access a space in an emergency
and then finally within the public
there is little social s p literature
actually but there are a few case
studies about tensions and trust and
privacy and car ride and accommodation
sharing with strangers
specifically there's been like evidence
of this negotiation of trust where users
want to know more about those who are
sharing resources with them even when
they're trying to hide as much info
about themselves as possible
and there as a result have also been a
few examples of work specifically trying
to anonymize writers and write your apps
and here you might notice that some of
these are highlighted and some of these
are not i'll go over what these mean
later on but just kind of keep them in
the back of your minds and like maybe
consider why they're different from the
others
so moving on to sheridan social
authentication we consider situations
where authentication credentials are
shared for purposes other than giving
access to a resource as well as systems
designed to support group authentication
so as previously mentioned sharing
passwords and sharing access to
resources are often complete conflated
but we didn't find specific literature
on joint or coordinated authentication
by couples
but within family and households there
has been some work done on users who
face accessibility challenges relying on
their family or close household members
to help them authenticate themselves
and these include people with visual
impairments those with language barriers
and users who have less technical
education who might share their
passwords and pins
not to actually share their financial
resources but because they face burdens
communicating or proving their
identities
and then in the workplace there has been
past work on the pitfalls of updating or
removing credentials so for example when
commonly shared passwords don't get
updated often enough people who leave
the company can have on
unauthorized access
and then in place of passwords
researchers have this tried to design
more like quote socially aware systems
for example there's trusted contacts on
facebook where users can rely on a
specific list of friends to help them
log in if they ever get locked out
in other examples employees shared
knowledge or secrets such as identifying
friends and photos to authenticate group
membership or secret knocking or tapping
patterns which are individually like
distinguishable since different people
knock in different ways
and then once again at the public scale
there are fewer examples of coordinated
authentication behaviors but we did find
work on nextdoor which is a neighborhood
oriented social media platform which
authenticates users a membership in a
physical community by either physically
mailing them a unique code or relying on
neighbors to vouch for them
and here again notice that there are a
few more use cases highlighted than than
in the previous section
managing self-representation refers to
the way that users share information
about themselves to their social circle
so this sharing unlike sharing resources
in the first domain specifically means
how users share their personal
information
so in
intimate relationships people hide
information about themselves because
they're embarrassed or worried about
doing something wrong but also to
share to establish trust in their
partners but ipv survivors actually face
pretty unique challenges so for example
when leaving an abusive situation
survivors might create profiles with
false information about themselves so
that their abusers can't find them
but they bear this burden themselves and
there aren't other like existing systems
to help them do this more naturally
within families and households most work
refers to how parents leak information
about their children online whether
through posting photos of their kids or
through surveillance apps that
themselves leak data to unknown third
parties
and then at the social level some users
manage interpersonal relationships as a
proxy for controlling who can see their
posts since context collapse means that
their direct control over these
audiences is diminished so for example
teens and younger adults use coded
language or self-censor themselves
online instead of like using existing
audience selection tools
and then conversely older adults are
less concerned with context collapse and
would prefer to like quote lock
everything down and like not post at all
about themselves but even adults adult
adopt habits from teens to signal
information about themselves for example
by checking into locations online or
sharing certain digital music playlists
to appear cooler to those around them
rather than like legitimately wanting
other people to hear their music
and finally within the public as users
conduct more of their lives online the
boundaries between intimate and public
relationships are increasingly fuzzy
of course in online dating users often
purposefully hide themselves from people
they know and are aware wary of
revealing about themselves even as they
extensively research potential partners
this hints at some sort of socially
expected public sharing but the extent
of this sharing is not super clear so
for example users on grindr feel
compelled to hide their hiv positive
status due to fear of stigmatization but
other users actually purposefully
disclose the status for the very same
reason
more broadly users make assumptions of
why others hide information about like
health status from the public and these
assumptions might pressure individuals
into revealing more about themselves
than they really want to and this
extends all the way to companies like
fitbit trying to nudge users into
sharing health data with insurance
companies
and finally of course there have been
end user tools that could help users
circumvent track tracking and obfuscate
their identities
tor of course is cooperative by design
and that like it requires volunteers to
run relays
but even though there have multiple
similarly cooperative tools developed
these tend to resist mainstream adoption
so there aren't like demonstrable
effects of like a
collective coordinated use
and once again please note that there is
not much highlighted out of all the
the cases i have mentioned
and this final domain advice and
influence covers how social groups can
influence each other's s p behaviors
so at the intimate level uh user
behaviors tend to mirror that of the
family household scale which i'll
discuss in a bit but in ipv scenarios
because abusers often control setup of
devices and households to surveil
survivors
survivors must seek advice from outside
of their relationship and they might go
to social workers or lawyers who might
not be best qualified to give them
advice
and this power and balance continues at
the household level where the most
knowledgeable or technically literate
member is going to be tasked with
setting up devices and networks and
giving out advice
and younger kids ask their parents for s
p advice and older adults in turn also
ask their adult children for advice
in both cases those being consulted
prefer more lock down modes
to s p that are intended to protect
those that are more vulnerable but also
kind of takes away their agency
and then at the social acquaintance
level there's been extensive evidence
that simply sharing stories and
experiences about s p with those around
you can instill a sense of camaraderie
and
social responsibility to protect and
learn more about them and observing
others positive behaviors has been found
to be the most frequent trigger of
change in smp behaviors
[Music]
and
i will actually try to wrap up more
quickly i guess
and then at the public scale there have
been a lot of papers exploring
demographic and cultural variations
um in how users approach ncp smp so
their differences across gender age
countries social economic status etc
and we i cover all these in the paper
and also other work has challenged the
portrayal of users as lazy or
unmotivated and adopting behaviors and
has instead called for more public
advice that specifically targets those
at risk
and finally please note that there are
like no highlighted use cases in this
behavior domain
so throughout all these domains i've
highlighted a few use cases and i will
discuss why they're actually highlighted
so in our sok we used ackerman's social
technical gap or the difference between
what users desire socially and what is
supported technically as a lens to
outline potential areas for future work
so this gap is extensively cited in
broader hci literature
to illustrate how technical systems may
fail to account for human social
behavior
so we developed three questions to
assess this gap across all the use cases
and then i'll go through each of them in
more detail
so for the first question
are there existing systems that help
facilitate this social use case
the answer is kind of of course like a
great deal of
behaviors and use cases involve some
sort of technical system but there's a
distinction between accident systems
that were worked around or modified to
fit social needs and novel systems
designed directly to facilitate these
behaviors
and as an example of the former is the
fact that while audience selection tools
exist on social media platforms teens
choose to use coded language instead to
reach their intended audience
and we also highlighted examples of the
latter throughout so for example the
social and uh shared authentication
domain we highlighted systems that
support group authentication by using
secret knocking patterns or shared
secrets
um we also highlighted tora as an
example that was social by design as
well as next doors authentication
methods but overall there are a few
examples of these novel s p systems that
require direct social interaction
specifically in the advice and influence
behavior domain
and on the second question can users fit
the affordances of existing smp systems
without altering their ideal social
behaviors short answer is no
many smp systems are designed to be
ignorant of social context and force
users to choose between security and
social accessibility
so like even in domains without direct
technical system oh sorry um
uh oh sorry uh even though like audience
selection tools like i mentioned exist
on social media platforms um teens like
choose actively not to use them
and even in domains without direct
technical system like influencing other
s p behaviors users are expected to
abide by institutionally set advice for
existing technologies
and finally the last question can users
use these existing systems as intended
to meet both their ideal social
behaviors and smp goals and once again
typically no so i'll go back to
passwords and personal devices again
they're not designed to be shared but
people do it anyway
and
since these devices and passwords fail
to account for human social behaviors
these systems no longer serve their
intended purpose
um and this shift and intent also means
that essence p s p preferences fall by
the wayside so like when a user shares
their netflix account their burden with
their making their private account
details visible and having personalized
recommendations being disrupted or
exposing their password to others
and like this may change how they use
the app entirely
and like production ready systems like
tor and like also track me not and ad
nauseum which and also employ
collectives for up obfuscation
um
exist um
uh but also like once again they're not
widely adopted
so to summarize across the majority of
social cyber security work there has
been extensive evidence that users might
must either modify their ideal social
behaviors to realize their s p
preferences or modify their id s p
preferences to reduce social friction
um so where do we go from here there's
been a lot of work that identifies the
social inadequacies of s p systems so in
that sense we see a need to design
systems with more social observability
cooperation and stewardship and we also
found little existing work theories or
systems or empirical or otherwise on the
public social scale
so we think that collective action
systems could be explored as a mechanism
for users to directly advocate for more
human-centered smp solutions
especially against things like web
tracking and surveillance technologies
rather than relying on experts to tell
them what's right
thank you and i'm happy to take any
questions now
[Applause]
thank you so much for your amazing talk
loved how you summarized all the
research that there ever was on this
topic in a couple of minutes um
before someone else can get a question
and um
so if someone wanted to actually you
know work in this field after reading
your paper uh where should they start
have you where were they like did you
find any like gaps and holes were like
huh i there should have been research on
this but there wasn't
um i think something that is like sticks
out most that's like most actionable
right now is like
uh ending account sharing so like for
example if you break up with someone um
and like you shared your netflix
password with them you kind of have to
either have an awkward conversation or
like secretly log them out and stuff um
and i'm sure there could be like better
ways to like design something like that
um and this also extends to things like
utility bills like people who used to
live in the same house as you or like
share other resources that it's like i
think those that's like a very
actionable domain
yeah
that that makes sense uh that's
interesting um
from a uh
i want to say like from a threat
perspective uh would you would you say
the um
the majority of like what you were
looking at was more like um
this is terrible this is terrible or
would you say it's more like from a
usability perspective or more from a
this is impractical but it's not
terrible perspective
what's like your overall assessment of
where we are
um
i guess like
uh my overall assessment is like
everything is not like super ideal like
users can
eventually get to the things they want
um
say like just to use the password
sharing example again like
um
they can eventually just like change
their password or like have an awkward
conversation with their ex or whatever
um but like that's not like ideal like
that could be avoided if there are like
better ways to like technically support
that
thank you thank you for this assessment
does anyone else have a question in this
room
all right it doesn't look like it thank
you again for your talk
and your paper