uh i'm samir menon and this is joint
work with david wu uh we present spiral
fast high rate single server pir via fhe
composition
so in private information retrieval a
client wishes to
retrieve an item from a database without
letting the database learn which item
they're retrieving and specifically this
guarantee should hold even when the
server is arbitrarily malicious
um you can imagine as a as a motivating
example um
uh the client wishing to retrieve uh
article about a sensitive medical
condition from uh wikipedia say
our focus is the single server setting
because it is a basic building block in
many other privacy preserving protocols
i've listed some here you can also
imagine you know like just to call out
like private dns as a
motivating example where the client
would like to
look up a dns record without letting the
server know which record it's looking at
when evaluating a pir system there's a
number of efficiency metrics that we
want to look at
the first is the size of the query so
this is how much the client needs to
upload to issue a query
the second is the server throughput this
is the rate at which the server can
process the database to answer a query
so remember
that the server
without pre-processing needs to form a
perform a full linear scan over the
database in order to answer a single
query for privacy so
we measure the server's response time as
throughput um and finally the rate so
this is a kind of crypto word but
basically the rate here uh we refer to
as the ratio of the record size to the
response size so the response is
typically somewhat larger than the
actual item the size of the item that
you're trying to retrieve so
that blow up the inverse of that you
know kind of response overhead is the
rate
there's a fourth metric that we kind of
call out which is
the public parameter size so the client
is allowed to send a set of public
parameters to the server at the start of
the
session um and these parameters are
reasonable for an arbitrary number of
queries and on an arbitrary number of
databases but the size of these
parameters is still important because
the client has to upload it and the
server needs to store it so we also
measure the size of these parameters
so just a summary of our results we
introduce a family of pir protocols that
leverage techniques
to translate between fhe schemes and we
achieve you know significant new results
in single server par
we use automatic parameter selection
based on the database configuration to
choose parameters for our scheme which
of which you know there are a lot to
choose um and
ultimately this lets us achieve
significant simultaneous improvements in
uh query size rate and throughput over
the best state of the art uh prior
but in exchange our public parameters
are larger so you can see here i've
listed
we are
improving on all three key metrics but
the public parameters are getting larger
and
we also examine spiral in a streaming
setting this is where the query
from the client is fixed but the
database is changing so we have multiple
databases and we'd like the answer to
the query on all of those databases this
comes up when you're streaming like a
large file or in other cases that i'll
describe later
but basically in this setting
we achieve much higher rate and
throughput and that's because we use
larger queries
we achieve a rate of 0.81 which i'll
i'll call out you know remember that the
the highest possible rate would be one
so uh in this streaming setting we're
achieving very very high rate uh and um
in addition we're also achieving a
throughput of almost two gigabytes per
second which is 12 times higher than the
previous work the best previous work and
i'll just call out you know on this
target system um the throughput of
running software aes is
five times slower than this so
we are
significantly faster than applying a
symmetric primitive uh and for reference
you know the memory bandwidth of the
system is 10 gigabytes per second so
you know we're a decent
way of the way there
so now i'll talk about how to spiral
work um to do that i need to kind of
explain a little background on fully
homomorphic encryption so
um just to summarize a client can use
homomorphic encryption to encrypt data
using a secret key send it to the server
and the server can then perform
operations on that encrypted data
i've listed some here you can look that
the first two are kind of similar this
is ciphertext edition or plaintext
multiplication in a way these are the
same
but basically the server can evaluate an
additive homomorphism for both of these
and there's also the possibility that
the server could evaluate a
multiplicative homomorphism that's where
you are taking to cyber text and
computing a new ciphertext that encodes
the product of the two inputs um anyway
the server sends back this you know
final response and the client can
decrypt to obtain the result of the
computation
and here
for fully homomorphic encryption we have
the same definition of rate so rate is
the ratio of the plaintext size to the
ciphertext size so the rate of a
homomorphic encryption scheme is very
similar to the rate of a pir scheme
so
this work is about composing schemes
so i'll describe two schemes to you i
won't get into the details of exactly
how they work but i want you to just
know the properties and
we can see the construction from that
level so the first scheme that we use is
for gev's encryption scheme
this scheme gives us very high rate and
has very fast operations but it only
supports an additive homomorphism so you
can only add or multiply by a plain text
and it comes in a matrix variant which
is also called pvw and the thing i'll
call out about the matrix variant of
this scheme is that uh the rate is much
higher than for the scalar variant and
the rate is higher the larger the
matrices that we encrypt so this matrix
variant lets us encrypt matrices and the
bigger the matrices we encrypt the
higher the rate of the resulting
ciphertext
and the second scheme we use is gentry
set high waters or gsw and this scheme
is kind of the opposite so the the rate
is low the operations are slower but um
we support homomorphic multiplication
and interestingly you know these two
schemes they play nice with each other
so you can multiply a gsw ciphertext by
a reg f ciphertext
so i'll talk about two prior works that
use those two schemes to construct par
um so the first prior work is gentry
levy uh in this work uh the query is a
collection of matrix for gev and gsw
ciphertext and what we do to start is we
use the reg f ciphertext to select along
the first dimension of the database so
the database is a matrix of plain text
records and here i've shown as an
example i've marked the target item in a
star and we're doing a vector matrix
multiplication so
we are intuitively we're selecting a row
of the database in this picture um
and you can see we're explaining the
fact that regev ciphertext support a
ciphertext plaintext homomorphism so
that's how we're able to select a row
using these encrypted bits
and then
we can further compress the response
size using the gsw ciphertext so here we
exploit the fact that gsw supports
ciphertext multiplication to basically
repeatedly fold the
output of that first processing until
we're left with basically just a single
ciphertext that encrypts the item that
we wanted
um and so this result is a matrix where
you have cyber text in this prior work
and so it's a very high rate so we've
kind of used both schemes well
i should note this scheme was never
implemented but um you know it would be
it seems like it would be efficient but
there's a big drawback which is that
these gsw ciphertexts that you have to
communicate are very large so the query
becomes quickly too big uh the each
ciphertext is in this example four
megabytes which is to encrypt a single
bit which is a lot um so that's that's a
significant downside there's another
prior work that addresses this downside
so onion pier uh recent work uh shows
how to take
how to make the query much smaller so
here the query is only 64 kilobytes and
it's a single scalar ciphertext and then
they show an expansion procedure
that lets you get the ciphertext you
need for processing um so this expansion
procedure works quite well and you're
able to process the query much like
gentry levy but the query is now much
smaller but there's a problem with this
prior work too which is that the result
is now a scalar regard cipher text so
the expansion procedure that they show
only goes from scalar to scalar and so
um the drawback is that the use of
scalar cipher text ultimately reduces
the rate um and so we don't get that
very high rate that we have in the other
prior work so this work is about getting
the best of both worlds what we want are
the small queries that are in onion pure
and we want the high rate that's in
gentry hell levy
and so to do that we introduce simple
key switching techniques for query
compression uh we show how to basically
convert scalar rig f to matrix and
convert matrix we give to gsw
um
the high level take away is you know you
can get the benefit of really large
ciphertext without the overhead of
actually communicating them on the wire
and our techniques are of general use so
if you use matrix for gav or gsw
ciphertext this transformation is useful
and can minimize communication costs so
this is applicable outside of pir
so this is our you know
final
vanilla version of our scheme uh on the
left here you can see this looks like
onion pure what we're doing is we're
taking a very small query and expanding
it into
for gev and gsw ciphertext that we need
and then on the right it looks like uh
gentry halevi we're processing the
result using matrix ciphertext and so
the rate is high
so this is uh you know us getting the
best of both worlds
um i'll talk about three little
additional tricks that we use in this
scheme
there's more details in the paper but i
just want to call them out the first is
that we choose parameters automatically
so there are as you build these schemes
there are just a explosion of in the
number of knobs that you can tune um we
wanted to choose our parameters
systematically so we built a tool that
takes in the database configuration and
then evaluates many sets of parameters
against a cost model in this case we use
the aws cost model so um what happens is
we
input parameters and we guess the query
size response size and the amount of
time the server will take to compute a
response and then we calculate a cost
from that and the tool is able to output
an optimized set of parameters
um there are two other tricks so another
trick we use is we we choose our
ciphertext modulus kind of carefully
to use so that we can only use 32-bit
multiplication for most of processing
this is actually a big win uh especially
when you remember that using cmd like
avx-512 you can do up to eight 32-bit
multiplications in a single cpu cycle so
this is actually a significant win
and then we also observe a kind of fact
about matrix ciphertext
we basically observed that a large
portion of a matrix ciphertext is less
important than the other parts of it and
so you can more
noisily encode it you can more roughly
encode it there's more details on that
in the paper but that is also of general
interest
so um
the question you're all here for
how does spiral perform uh
on a basic level if we choose the
database configuration preferred by
onionpier uh uh 2 to the 18 record so
that's 250 000 plus records of 30
kilobytes each
spiral is a significant improvement over
the prior work but has larger public
parameters and you can see on an
absolute basis you know the query and
response sizes are getting pretty small
and the server compute is also getting
pretty small so we think this is putting
pir
in striking distance of being practical
and just phrasing those same numbers as
rate and throughput yeah you can see the
rate is now already over one-third and
the throughput is over 300 megabytes per
second
we also compare uh spiral against uh
comparison schemes uh over
varying the number of records and
keeping the record size constant so here
i've chosen a 100 kilobyte records and
i've varied the number of records
um
the first thing to note is indeed
processing is linear in the database
size especially uh as the number of
records increases you can see there's
you know almost all of the schemes
become a line
and
another thing to note is in the top
right you know spiral is getting over
300 megabytes per second of throughput
which is already roughly the speed of
the throughput of software-based aes on
the system when i say software-based i
mean you know not using hardware
acceleration um
but what that means is you know the this
pir processing is
similar to applying a symmetric
primitive and that's kind of an
interesting benchmark we think
and it's not on this slide but
spiral
also does have smaller queries and
response sizes than all of the schemes
pictured here but it does have larger
public parameters
and i should note all our all our
measurements are on a single core single
thread uh this is because the problem's
naively parallel so um for benchmarking
we we always use the single core
so
now i'll talk about analyzing spiral in
that other setting the streaming setting
so
in this setting the same query is reused
over multiple databases and you might
ask you know when would you ever do that
and the answer is actually you know more
frequently than you'd expect so
the first time is you know if you're
streaming a video uh you want the
database item in chunks progressively so
that you can you know stream um so
that's an example and another example
where the streaming setting comes up is
when you're doing a private messaging or
a metadata private messaging or voice
call system so here you are repeatedly
polling the same mailbox and so
the streaming setting applies
in this setting we
only want to minimize the online cost we
only need to minimize the response
overhead and the server compute time and
in return we can consider larger public
parameters or query size because these
are amortized over the entire lifetime
of the stream and so
[Music]
it's it's okay to have a much larger
query because the stream is presumably
has a long lifetime so our approach
which we name spiral stream is basically
make the query very large and so that's
what we do and we measure its
performance so here i've plotted uh
spiral streams performance in purple and
you can see that
this is much faster already than spiral
so you can see that by making the query
much larger here the query is 30
megabytes uh the throughput that you're
able to achieve is much much higher and
this peaks at uh over 1.5 gigabytes per
second which is seven times faster than
previous constructions
and
as a note you know
at this point the the rate is about 50
so the communication overhead here for
single server par is already in this
setting uh only
2x and it was previously you know 4x
with the best uh previous scheme
so a natural question we asked next is
okay it's at 50 can we can we make the
rate even higher so we also think we
kind of reflect back on our scheme and
ask you know
can we make the rate higher so using
larger matrices does make the rate
higher but it lowers the throughput so
uh the idea for a packing transformation
is to
use a small ciphertext during processing
and pack into a large one at the end
and so we do that
it gives us larger public parameters but
better throughput
and
i'll just say you know so just to call
out here the cost of privately streaming
a movie from a database at this point in
settings where the communication is uh
dominating cost uh is less than 2x more
expensive than the no privacy baseline
of just directly retrieving the item and
previously that would have been 17 times
more expensive
and we have a cool demo of the scheme
too
the goal of talk is to convince you that
pr is practical so we actually have a
website up where you can
actually read wikipedia using pir
and uh yeah it achieves pretty good
pretty good results um don't tell the
attack people about the url
but yeah
yeah
and yeah here are some future directions
we're looking at and our demo paper and
code
[Applause]
thanks for the great talk any questions
yeah i wanted to ask about these public
parameters um are they truly public in
the sense that the generation procedure
is public coin and different clients can
use the same public parameters
the generation uh procedure is not
public coin so it depends on the
client's secret key but of course it is
hiding of the client's secret keys okay
that makes a lot of sense and then
actually another question i'm curious
about the evaluation and how parallelism
played a role or didn't play a role in
the evaluation oh sorry say that again
i'm curious about the evaluation and how
parallelism either played a role or
didn't play a role ah okay um yeah so we
we
to
i guess cryptographers are we're all
lazy so most libraries and open source
implementations that implement pir that
we use to do benchmarking don't use
parallelism because you can just write a
note in the paper that says
it's naively parallel so um to make
comparison uh consistent we we don't
implement parallelism if you go to our
rest library it does so it'll use all
the threads it can and it'll be nightly
it'll exploit um the threads yeah gotcha
that makes sense thanks yeah
please keep the question short a little
bit
hi um so you used uh fairly large record
sizes in your database and fairly small
number of records what happens if those
sort of flip around and you have many
very small you know smallish records
yeah it's a great question so um in the
example one of the examples one of the
benchmark databases is a million records
and 256 bytes each right yes and here
here what happens is we what we do is we
just
the the most efficient thing because of
lat because of lattice parameters
there's there is an intuitive or there's
an implicit minimum record size so what
we do is we just pack
many of the smaller records into a
single large record and this hurts the
rate significantly obviously the minimum
response size is now you know several
kilobytes but
it's still very efficient on a
throughput basis and on an absolute
basis downloading you know 10 kilobytes
to retrieve 256 bytes it might be okay
depending on the circumstance thank you