welcome
hi thanks thanks for the introduction i
am sarov i'll talk about scalable
distributed randomness beacon this is a
joint work with vinith irene and my
advisor ling
so let's get started
so a randomness beacon is uh
can be defined as this ideal
functionality that has a clock in it and
what it what this functionality does it
outputs fresh random string to the
clients after every certain time
interval this is how it will look and in
distributed randomness beacon we want to
replace this ideal functionality with a
distributed protocol so that we get
fault tolerance and all those kind of
things we can formalize the properties
that we want
as we want unpredictability that says
the future random output should be
unpredictable to the adversary even if
it corrupts a fraction of the nodes
the beacon output should be bias
resistant so such that the output should
be uniformly random and the protocol
should always produce fresh outputs
and the output should be publicly
verifiable by any other users who who is
not part of the weekend generation
protocol
so why do we need randomness beaker this
has many applications in consensus and
blockchain protocols
it has applications since auditable
auctions and also lottery
anonymous communication bootstrapping
cryptographic protocols etc
so this is our system model
we work in partially synchronous network
that means networks which are sometimes
synchronous sometimes is asynchronous
that's one way of thinking about it
we operate in n equal to 3t plus 1 where
n is the total number of nodes and t is
the maximum number of faulty nodes
we also only require a transparency term
or a common random string and we only
assume public key infrastructure
this is the
this has the randomness beacon has been
looked in for a while and it has a lot
of work so we only summarize few of
those so here we
only look at
cks 05 which is asynchronous randomness
beacon protocol that has lots of good
properties like optimal fault tolerance
has communication cost of kappa n square
where kappa is the security parameter
but the downside of this protocol is
this requires a trusted setup
we have other protocols such as scrape
which also which are in synchrony but
they have very high communication cost
we have hydrant that that has a better
communication cost but it gives up on
unpredictability property
very decent work but beer and piper also
achieves randomness beacon but they have
high communication cost as well so this
is our result so in this paper we give a
partially synchronous distributed
randomness beacon that that is that
tolerates up to one third failure and
has communication cost of kappa n square
and competition cost order n so this
matches in terms of performance the
cks05
but
and only requires common random string
and public key infrastructure
there are four key techniques that gives
us our result
one is the new publicly verifiable
secret sharing scheme
the second is a new aggregation
verification mechanism third is
something we call simultaneous decision
state machine replication and fourth is
a two two run beacon output
reconstruction protocol i'll briefly
touch upon these things
but before i start i want to give some
brief background on the tools i use one
of the tools i i use in this paper is
called threshold secret sharing i'm sure
many of you are already familiar with
this but let's just recap briefly so
this is a protocol to secret share a
secret z among n nodes such that any
subset of t plus one or more nodes can
recover the secret or use the secret to
do something but
a subset of t or less than less nodes
cannot learn anything about the secret
so
pictorially this is what it looks like
we have a dealer that has a secret z and
then it wants to share a secret so that
everybody outputs a share z1 g2 z3 to g5
so one of the classic example of
threshold secret sharing is the xiaomi's
liquid sharing where you embed the
secret into a polynomial evaluation at
zero where the rest of the coefficients
of the polynomials are random and the
share of each party is a evaluation
point
and it's easy to see that if you pick a
degree t polynomial then any t plus one
or more points will uniquely define the
polynomial and you can get recover the
secret
so in this paper we need something
stronger which we call which is known as
verifiable secret sharing where the idea
is we want to do threshold sql sharing
in a setting where the dealer could be
malicious and also a subset of nodes
could be malicious as well
we need slightly stronger primitive
which we call publicly verifiable secret
sharing scheme which is
verified basically sharing scheme with
some extra stuffs
so this is what it looks like this is
what we want
and i just want to describe what pvss is
so previous has this function locally
computable function which is pbs.share
which takes in a random secret and it
outputs three things three vectors the
first vector is a commitment vector
second is encryption vector and the
third is proof vector which which are
non-interactive your knowledge proofs
such that if the dealer broadcast the
this three tuple vc and pi
then everybody can check that the dealer
did the pbs sharing correctly and each
party can also locally recover their
secret
so we'll use previouses in our
construction
another
tool we need is state machine
replication so this is you can think of
this as block chains
that's the modern name of statement
state machine replication so
it is analogous to a partially
synchronous broadcast protocol there are
some subtle differences but you can
think of that as a like a broadcast
protocol in partial synchronous setting
so we will only review the epoch based
state mission replication protocol where
each every park has a leader so i have a
brief i'll briefly review what how smrs
typically work
so we have four nodes where the first
node is the leader and let's say fourth
node is a malicious node
then
in each epoch let's say the ayat epoch
the leader will propose a new block bi
and then the nodes will participate in
some kind of voting this voting could be
multiple rounds as well such that at the
end of this voting round everybody
decides let's accept this block and they
append this block to the ledger
then we move on to the next epoch where
we have a different leader which will
propose a new blog bi plus one
and then we do the same thing again we
do another round of voting
and then we agree on the new block
so these are the tools we'll use and we
have some other tools
as well that we use in our
paper
so one property that we need from smr we
need a simultaneous decision smr that
that means that if one honest node
outputs then everybody outputs almost
immediately
so we need this simultaneous decision
property for unpredictability the
intuition is that we don't want the
adversary to learn that we cannot put
too far ahead of honest notes we want to
ensure that as soon as adversity
launched the we can output then
everybody else also learns almost
immediately
let's look at how we construct our
protocol
so we as in smr we also run in epochs
every epoch has a leader and we ensure
that whenever the epochs leader is
honest we produce a beacon output
each of our epoch has four phases
commitment phase aggregation phase
agreement phase and reconstruction phase
i'll now
briefly look at all of these faces so
the on top i have the legends that i'll
be using for my figure
in the sharing phase let's say we have
four node and the second node is the
leader
what each node does it know each node
samples a random secret and computes the
pvss transcript of the random secret
sample by the node every node does this
locally
and then these nodes will send this pbss
transcript to the leader
this is the sharing phase during the
aggregation phase the leader will
aggregate this
shares using the additive homomorphic
property of the previous commitment and
also the pbs encryptions
during the agreement phase the leader
will send this aggregated commitment and
aggregated ciphertext using a
simultaneous decision smr
there is one issue the pbss proofs are
not aggregatable so there is a subtlety
here so how do we ensure that the leader
indeed did the aggregation correctly so
for this we have a new distributed
aggregation verification mechanism where
every node only checks a part of the
aggregation mechanism and they
collectively ensure that the global
aggregation was done correctly
and this is very crucial for our uh
random beacon protocol
there is another issue which is a
subtlety in like most of the smr
protocols where it is possible that if
the
leader is bad
then it is possible that some honest
node do not
output the value they will know that the
decision has been reached but they won't
have the value locally
and we address this by using a two round
reconstruction protocol which ensures
that even if this kind of situation
arrives the random beacon protocol still
ensures unpredictability and the
remaining properties
so then at the end of the reconstruction
phase the nodes will output a common
beacon output so this is our
construction
we have some optimizations in for in our
paper where we amortize the leader's
work
in our protocol each node becomes leader
only once in an epoch so
and so that we just
make sure that the node does the
commitment and aggregation phase a
priori so that we can
pipeline the entire system
we also use multi-exponentiation
wherever possible for computation
optimization
let's look at our implementation details
we implement our protocol using golang
atop this quorum code base which
implements a
smr protocol we change the smart
protocol to re-implement a variant of
hot stuff uh smart protocol a popular
smart protocol
and we use
in our protocol bls 12381 elliptic curve
from
ignite crypto library and we also use
their native multi-exponentiation
protocol
in terms of experiments we evaluate our
system using aws across eight regions
we
position one node per vm and we test
with up to 128 nodes
so let's look at our evaluation results
so first we want to look at the average
number of beacons
output per node
how fast is the system how how often can
the system generate beacon outputs and
here if you look at with 64 nodes
our protocol can output about 40 beacons
per minute which is about one beacon
every one and a half second
and in comparison we compared with d
rand which is a variant of the cks
protocol recall this cks05 requires
trusted setup and variancy d-rand is a
synchronous variant of it so even with
much stronger assumption our performance
is slightly better than the rand we
believe this is because of their use of
inefficient broadcast channel and also
some other implementation issues we also
compare with hydrant which has one of
the implementation hydrant has some
unpredictability issue and we
and ours is perfectly unpredictable and
we also still perform much better than
the
these works
we also measure the bandwidth uses and
we see with 64 nodes we spurred each
node for
for per beak and each node has to send
about 60 kilobytes of data this is for
larger nodes is still slightly more
but there is some scopes to
scope to improve here as well
so in summary
we present a distributed roundness
beacon protocol which which only
requires transparent setup it is
partially synchronous can tolerate up to
one third malicious failures
and it has order and computation
amortized per beacon output and
lambda and square
communication cost as per beacon output
and our average latency is order one
rounds but in the worst case it's
possible that we uh we do not produce
any beacon for f rounds so there are
lots of open problems one of the open
problem is to design an asynchronous
randomness beacon protocol that
tolerates the same number of failures
and also reduce this computation cost
and communication cost to worst case
lambda n square instead of amortized and
also reduce the worst case latency to
order one rounds and also
we don't know of any lower bound results
and it's i think it's interesting to
work on
what will be lower bound results on
random speaking protocols
that's it for this talk and
these are my amazing collaborators
[Applause]
okay thanks a lot for this
nice overview and we have time for some
questions
and yeah please state your name and
affiliation
hey this is jorgen from stanford
maybe you mentioned this and i missed it
what pbss scheme are you using so
we we looked at scrape pvss and then
while working on it we have some
improvements on top of the previous ski
the screen previous scheme basically we
can improve the underlying assumption
that they assume and we have our new pvs
schema which is very similar in
principle with the scrape previous
scheme
okay one question from my side in the
evolution you only had to de-rant up to
32 notes is there a conceptual problem
why it doesn't scale to 64 or 128
no we we just couldn't get it running
with 64 nodes so we tried hard and
probably there because they use a very
naive broadcast protocol which is n to
the fourth and as we scale with large
number of nodes the latencies they are
very synchronous protocol they have to
make strong assumptions about network
latencies so if those assumptions are
violated the protocol doesn't produce
the output and throws all sorts of we
just couldn't get it running but there
is no conceptual error with that yeah
okay no conceptual but still practical
practical uh specific to probably that
implementation
yeah
okay more questions
from the audience or online yes sure
um can you clarify the property of the
smr protocol where you mentioned nodes
output at the same time
yes if it is partially synchronous then
um how would they like during a period
of like partial synchrony before gst how
would they output at the same time so
that's that's a very good question so
how we measure this simultaneous
decision in terms of number of rounds so
it's possible that one of the round is
much longer than adversary learns the
beacon output now and adversary
deliberately delays the next round to be
like let's say one year then the nodes
log other nodes will output the beacon
output after a year but if we look at
number of rounds like where the round is
basically the latency of the messages so
we ensure that if adverse if one node
decides then the other nodes can decide
within two message delays
and that's like constant number of
message delays and yes in partial
synchrony each delay could be much
longer but we believe in practice like
delays will be very reasonable yes
thank you
okay so if there are no more questions
let's thank the speaker one more time
[Applause]