hello everyone i will present today
tachara cruising with design for
enhancing significant resource education
in interdependent systems this is mr
abdullah from ece alberta university and
that's based on the joint work with my
colleagues and advisors from four
different institutions
so the agenda for today will be as
follows i will start with the motivation
for our work and then the interdependent
system set up and then we can design our
evaluation and i will then conclude the
all
there are too many challenges in today's
systems security the first one the
security issues because everything is
now connected to the internet there is a
huge increase in cyber threats and the
second
issue is the high costs because the cost
of higher or the high cost of the
successful act so for example here i'm
showing
from the center for strategic and
international studies
that there is exponential growth in the
number of cyber attack incidents with 1
million plus reported losses in the last
decade on institutions and governments
and actually we explore in particular
the human decision making in security
the existence of human and
decision-making security has been
revealed and was explored in several
works but actually most of the
literature
considered optimal decision making such
as these similar works and surveys that
focus that humanitarian maker is
rational and has optimal decision making
strategy however behavioral economics
show that humans are already partly
rational and deviate from such classical
models
prospect theory for example showed that
actually human would deviate from such
classical models
in particular prospect theory showed
that human perceptions of losses and
probabilities would be different from
the true values which would lead to a
significant impact on the security
investments made by the stakeholders or
defenders in particular
it was it has been shown that humans
overweight low risk and underweight high
risk as shown here there are
a huge amount of the literature that
proved such behavior in vertical
here i am showing two similar papers of
predict and gonzalez that has this
mathematical form where alpha controls
the extent of overweighting and
underweighting if alpha equals one
actually here we have a rational
decision maker but if alpha is less than
one we have a behavioral decision maker
that overweight and underweight
probabilities depending on the region
now i provide the interdependent system
setup so we consider a directed acyclic
graph which is general
a general graph g with a set of nodes v
and set of edges e and each node
represent an asset in the system and the
attacker can start her attack from a
source node a
and we have multiple defenders each
defender is responsible for a subset of
the assets for example here defender d2
is responsible for defending
these green nodes
and when an acid v is compromised it can
be used by the attacker to attack
another acid vj if there is a connection
or edge between these two nodes
and this attack on that hvi vg has a
probability of success which is we
denote by bij
and we consider li as the financial loss
that the defender would
have if her asset vi is compromised by
that
under such attack we consider defense
strategies where we consider that the
defender can allocate resources on the
edges to reduce the attack probability
or risk where x ijk is the defense
allocation by defender dk on the lg vivj
and will assume that multiple defenders
can assign defense resources on the same
age for joint defense
therefore the successful attack
probability would be ideally a
decreasing function in the total
investment x ij on that edge
and also we capture the
real world scenario that each defender
does not have infrared budget but each
one has a limited security budget pk
where the summation of all of my
security investments are ever bounded by
these people
before going to formulation of the true
cost of our
problem actually i would like to
emphasize that each asset here can be
attacked using several ways or several
baths so here for example the node vj
can be attacked using this path with two
edges or these paths with three edges
and therefore the attack property on a
bath for example this red colored path
would be the product of the
probabilities of successful attack on
all of the edges on that path and to
assume that the attacker is a worst case
scenario or chooses the most vulnerable
death from the source node a to the
asset
and actually this general or worst case
scenario can be used to model unknown
attacker strategies
therefore the cost of the defender will
be given by this formulation
which is
for each bath we have a probability of
successful attack and we aim to minimize
the maximum bet among all of the
possible benefits to the svm if the
attack succeeded we will have a loss and
m but remember that
the we don't have a single loss but each
defender has several assets and
therefore will do summation over all of
the losses of all of these assets
but we as humans are not rational
decision makers but we are
behavioral decision makers and therefore
here we
consider such uh behavioral bias or
misperception from birth theory where
the perceived cost is pretty similar to
the true cost but with the fact that the
defender would perceive the risk for the
risk of successful attack on each age in
that category
under such setup we seek to answer two
main research questions first one is how
does misreception would lead
to or affect the optimal security
investments and second how can we
incentivize stakeholders and encourage
them for better security decision making
to answer the first question
actually we explored the impact of the
behavior bias on investments and as
shown here actually behavioral
bias would lead to
some optimal investments which would
increase the loss so actually in our
previous work on hsccs last year we
showed that risk misperception would
lead to sub-optimal security investments
and these sub-optimal security
investments would lead to much higher
security loss for example here for this
symbol setup will have 2x increase in
the expected security loss i am just
asking you to imagine how would be the
full increase and the huge increase in
in the expected loss and the system loss
if we have real world
assets that actually
worth millions if compromised
but actually the need for the mechanism
design is twofold
the first reason that i just have
mentioned the effect of behavioral bias
that
sense behavioral defenders invest in a
sub-optimal manner and the second is
that even if the defenders are rational
they actually will invest in a selfish
manner each one will only care about
defending hair sub network
therefore we need central agency
investments or sales or that to lead
ideally to social optimal which is
surely better because it will lead to
essential cost and we proved in the
paper compared to selfish investments
so there are such questions we need to
answer can we design a mechanism that
help the defenders or incentivize the
defenders to invest in a better manner
to protect their systems and the whole
systems and make it more skewed
and actually the idea here is to do
to for the central authority to guide
the behavior defenders and we build on
text-based mechanisms and adapted for
security of interdependent systems
simply our setup is that the cost of
each defender is the original cost plus
attacks and these tax or term tk in the
security tax which is collected by the
central agents and we adapted two
mechanisms the externality and vcg
and also as i will explain later for
these two mechanisms and the effect of
bias on security tax amount we expose
that as well
and actually one other motivation for
our proposal that
cyber insurance is a very promising
direction so because the government can
make participation in cyber insurance a
requisite for the companies to receive
security funding and help them in their
business opportunities and there are
several proposals in the direction for
example the california proposal for
mandatory cyber insurance in that
and this central mechanism has several
properties but you are focusing on one
main property which is which budget
balance property
recall that ti is the security tax paid
by the stakeholder or defender di and n
if the total number of the defenders in
the network so we aim for wpb or we
budget balance which is the summation
all of the taxes made by all defenders
should be non-negative because if that
doesn't hold we will have a budget
deficit case
in which actually the mechanism would
require the mechanism designer or the
central agency to go and
take money
from her bucket and use or and spend it
which is actually external resources
which is not deserved and doesn't make
sense
so now i will uh focus my attention on
the externality mechanisms and how we
adapted to our problem
so actually the idea here of the
externality mechanism that
for each age if one defender invests on
my age i will my cost would be affected
by that so the taxes would be
depending on such externality which is
how much my cost as defender decay
decreased or increased depending on that
investments and therefore the total tax
would be simply
like summation over all of the
externalities by all defenders on my
network so the simple intuition for such
externality mechanism that each defender
will pay a tax amount and this tax
amount is proportional to how much i
gain or what is the positive externality
that i will gain or my cost will
decrease depending on other defenders
investments or my ages which is my
network
also we explore the effect of behavioral
bias on taxes
we prove that under
the externality mechanism the amount of
taxes uh actually made by the defender
is a decreasing function in here
behavior level also in other words the
behavioral defender will pay more taxes
compared to a rational defender
the intuition for that that the
behavioral defender will see a different
drop or higher drop in her perceived
loss or cost due to
cities from other defenders which would
encourage him or her to pay more taxes
the second and the more popular one we
adapted is the physician mechanism
actually the idea of c v
mechanisms depending on how i benefit
that's the society so here if x star
minus k is the equilibrium by all
defenders excluding dk and x-bar is the
equilibrium by all defenders including
dk the tax would be assembly the social
cost of others
excluding me minus the social cost of
others
excluding me but this one with my
investments and this one without my
investments so just
to go like similar without any math like
complexity the idea is that if the
defender decays investments make my
system worse then the tax amount would
be both of them in other words the
mechanism would have a penalty of the
defender because you made the society
more or less secure with more costs but
on the other hand if the defender
investments make the system better or
make the system with less social cost
the taxes would be negative
and therefore
actually the tax will reward you and the
defender will receive a reward for
enhancing our society by reducing the
social cost
so based on such setup and two
mechanisms we adapted for our problem
and the properties we proved now we go
to the evaluation our evaluation try to
answer these questions first what's the
gain of using mechanism design for
helping behavioral defenders to achieve
social optimal and second
how does the level of behavioral bias
affect the outcomes of our mechanisms
are
so to answer these two questions we
evaluate our approach using four attack
graphs based on real-world attack
scenarios and actually these scenarios
were built
using
like well defined standards such as the
nest guidelines and nesco guidelines
first we show the superiority of social
optimal over selfish investments or bme
as shown here the social cost under
social uh under social optimal solution
or sell or defense or
mechanism design or
social defense is actually much lower
compared to the social cost under
selfish investment especially with
behavioral defenders because each one
will be selfish and also waste his
resources
one other thing we observe that the
difference actually between these social
costs is higher as you see here the
dissociation cost is much higher
compared to the social optimal
especially with systems with high degree
of interdependency such as the scada
system
next we show the amount of taxes for
each mechanism so
to begin with the physician mechanism
each player will receive a payment or
pay negative taxes because it will help
and contribute to enhancing the society
cost
on the other hand the externality
mechanism each defender will benefit and
therefore each defender will pay
positive investments or balance however
in both of these scenarios
actually we show in our evaluation that
the amount of taxes increases and the
defenders has more bias or become more
behavioral
finally we also show the superiority of
the sheriff of our baselines so we
compare our approach to sharok with four
biz life approaches and the russian
decision making and we can create the
social cost under each build line
defense allocation as shown here
we we have four systems distributed
energy resource failure scenarios scada
control system ecommerce and voice over
ib and as shown here our approached
shahrukh has superiority or lowest
social cost compared to all of these
seminal baselines
just to conclude by talk we first
adapted to text-based mechanisms for our
general framework this framework
involves attack graph models that model
large-scale interdependent systems that
have multiple defenders
and each human defender in these
entertainment systems misreceived the
risk on each agent the attack graph
and also we proved the impossibility
result that there is no guarantee of
free budget balance in our
interdependent security game but more
details can be found
in the paper
and finally we characterize the impact
of such misperceptions on tax maybe
payments made by each defender
we believe that our work will
help to build better mechanisms and
build better and implement better
security bonuses that can be applied to
enhance the two issues i have mentioned
in the beginning of my talk thank you
and i'm happy to have any questions
okay the perfect
author is on zoom so if there is any
question from the audience
feel free to
no questions
so i will ask one of mine
uh i was with if i thank you for the
this very interesting introducing topic
i was uh wondering if you give some can
give more insight of this um cyber
insurance that you are mentioning
because i understand the concept of
taxes and everything
in practice in real life
yes
thanks for the question
so actually the idea of uh having like
having our idea badminton and cyber
insurance in general is like to have uh
generally instituted the taxes being
just collected collected uh based on
like the social cost or the behavior
which leads to the security investments
it will just be something like bid up
front so i will
in the beginning the
the the company or the center company or
central agency will collect some like
pro amounts and
based on that i will transfer my risk to
here so that so
for example if my system is compromised
as like a stakeholder or as like a sub
company or even a company the the
central agency or the
the government
agency will pay such like
part of all of these security law system
but actually in the our current setup in
the paper we don't consider cyber
insurance so consider that
we will try to collaborate
and each one
make better security policies and based
on such policies we will
pay taxes or receive rewards from the
central regulator based on our behavior
or in other words our security
investments or security bonuses so
that's the difference between just
collecting taxation based on
uh the
behavior or the cyber insurance which is
mainly uh similar to the idea of the
insurance but your the the agency will
take the money up front and based on
that
like if my if my system is compromised
she will like hold like she will like
hold or pay some of the amounts or all
of the security losses that i wouldn't
have so like this like these two uh
ideas i think uh both of them are
applicable as i mentioned there are
several proposals and even several
several initial solutions for that uh
cyber insurance idea but so i think that
that would be like a very interesting uh
like extension though to our current
work
thank you so we have another question
yeah so i was wondering how exactly the
graph was constructed like it seems like
different companies have or defenders
have different ideas of
what their personal cost of not getting
attacked and what the attack
probabilities of successful attacks are
so how do you like build the graph
yes
thanks for the question so i actually
the idea for the
graph generation we try to see what are
all of the possible
like um
what's the possible attack scenarios
based on each like failure scenario so
we had like four like practical systems
which are the distributed energy
resource failure scenario the scada
control system the e-commerce and voice
over ib for each one we'll try we start
with some like well-known failure
scenarios and based on
these failure scenarios we will come up
with some like
a tech graph or graph that represents
such attack scenarios and for the
probability estimation or the
probability of attack default
probability of attack estimation or the
vulnerability estimation with we
followed actually the cve the common
vulnerability exposure database so based
on that each edge should represent an
attack we try to like
come up based on on this attack and
several factors in this like cve
database you can come up with some like
estimation what would be the probability
of the initial probability of attack
without any defense so based on that we
try to like
estimate the initial problems of attack
for each
thank you but surely that estimation may
not be like
it may not be the
the
i mean exactly the same as the province
of attack but that's one one idea would
try to like map david
like databases availability database to
use it to like come up with the initial
probabilities
one last question
okay we have one last question good
hi yeah that was a very interesting
presentation um i was wondering uh if
you consider this uh also low
probability events with catastrophic
failures you were mentioning that scada
systems are very interdependent but i
think another difference is that they
have this
basically rare events the black swan
events that are like occur maybe might
they might not occur in our lifetime
maybe they will maybe this only one is
like earthquakes right only one thing
and then
how the hell so how do you handle those
cases
yes uh thanks for that so actually we um
so uh all of that should like
be reflected in the initial probability
of attack estimation or even
regenerating maybe the attack graph but
actually like for
for our uh for our any for our current
work we don't have like
like variable uh variable probability or
estimation of the probabilities but we
try to in our model incorporate
something called sensitivity so this
sensitivity tries to like
like uh
also
shows how the defense can like how the
security of this age or the security of
our like nodes can be changed according
to like our risk so for example if if a
an edge that has a very real
attack probability
will have two things the first one is
that
the probability of the initial
probability of attack we estimate would
be very low
and the second one
or the second thing we incorporated in
our model that the sensitivity of this
edge will also be like um
will be very high because like
if this is like almost very secure we
don't have to like add more resources on
that
on that edge up front so but but
generally i think that estimation will
be generally based on this initial
probability of successful attack because
as as i mentioned in the beginning of
the talk how we buy how our buyers can
affect that because i think that maybe
also
more extensions or more
trying to explore more what is exactly
the difference um between the low the
low probability
risk and high probability rest because
according to prospect theory like the
like generally we as humans we
overweight rare risks which is
overweight low probabilities and
underweight like high probabilities so
with we try to focus more in this paper
on the high attack probabilities or the
pro the
the higher risk but also i think our
framework like can can handle such other
cases but maybe more detailed like
analysis for seeing what or what would
be does it worth it like to spend more
resources on that or
like or
how much uh a budget should be allocated
to such ages like more detailed like
explanations i think that would be very
interesting like extension to our book
thank you very much for answering those
questions
and that concludes the
well we can thank so sorry we can thanks
again the author for
his presentation thank you