thanks for attending this talk
i'm sure chen of microsoft research asia
this is a joint work with qinghuang
university
the team includes our students
and professor xin duan
the title is timing based browsing
privacy vulnerabilities via site
isolation
let me first explain what site isolation
is
you may know that
before chromium
all commercial browsers were monolithic
they were single process programs
i think
chromium's multi-process architecture
is the deepest rethinking about the
security architecture for modern
browsers
between 2008 when
chrome was released and 2018 when site
isolation was achieved
it took a whole decade for the
architecture to achieve site isolation
which ensures that
a.com's contents and b.coms contents are
rendered by two processes
it was a long journey which also
involved many academic papers
and eventually in 2019
google published the site isolation
paper
in using its security
site isolation
requires a huge effort
to overcome compatibility resource and
performance hurdles
the security benefit is also significant
the chrome team
showed that many well-known security
issues
are mitigated in a fundamental way
including memory exploits
universal cross-site scripting browser
extension security issues
and meltdown and spectra
but there is still a problem
we know that the web is extremely
complex
but process is a scarce resource in the
os
how can this scarce resource accommodate
the complex web for example
a typical cnn news page contains at
least 15 cross-site iframes
because different sites must be rendered
by different processes
one cnn page needs
at least 16 processes
for site isolation now suppose i have 10
tabs
in my browser
does chrome use 160 processes to render
these 10 cnn tabs
that would not be practical
so process scarcity is an inherent
challenge for site isolation
to make setup isolation feasible
same size frames need to aggressively
reuse processes even across tabs
for example it is possible that
the 10 cnn tabs in the previous slide
are rendered by 16 processes
and this leads to the privacy issue we
discover
in this work
we call this privacy issue cross-site
browsing privacy leak
the attack scenario is the following
suppose the user visits the attacker's
site
or any site containing the attacker's
script
the attacker
has
a target site list
which contains hundreds or a few
thousands of sensitive sites then the
attacker
can find out which sites are loaded
in the browser and furthermore the
attacker can monitor
how the user spends time between these
sensitive sites
and in particular
at any moment
the attacker can figure out
which site
is in the foreground tab and which sites
are in the background tabs
here is a demo about
the attacker monitoring a target site
in this video i will show how to play
with the demo
first specify a site or choose it from
the list
for example youtube
click monitor and immediately switch
another tab
ignore the first result
now you see the not present result
meaning that the attacker knows
youtube.com is not present
now i visit youtube
the attacker now knows that youtube is
in the foreground tab
i switch to another tab
the attacker now knows that youtube is
in a background tab
i switch to foreground
i switch to background
and i switch to background
i close youtube
now it is not present
thank you for watching
so how can the attacker see which sites
are present and which sites you are
interacting with
what actually happened is that the
attackers page contains an iframe to
load a youtube url
the attacker can measure the time of the
loading if the time is long youtube is
likely not present otherwise
it is likely present
this is because if youtube is in another
tab the attacker's iframe will reuse the
existing process
otherwise it will create a new process
the difference is tens of milliseconds
which is very big
we measure each of alexa top 3000 sites
in the
not present foreground and background
situations
or mpfgbg
the red bg and the blue mp distributions
are clearly different
the green fp distribution is very wide
so
we have
fg
mp
overlapping also f g b g overlapping
to deal with the overlappings we
identify other timing characteristics
to differentiate fg versus bt and fg
versus mp
for fg versus bg
we find that
chromium assigns a high process priority
to the fg process
if the attacker stresses the cpu with an
infinite loop
the fg process performance will be
impacted less significantly
than a bg process
as you can see
these dots
can be separated along the vertical
dimension which is about the second
measurement
on a stressed cpu
for fg versus mp
we find that
the html parsing performance is lower
when the process is newly created
so the attacker can measure the hdmi
passing time to test if it is an mp
the result is similar
we can now separate
the blue and green dots
that
couldn't separate along the first
dimension
i just talked about
the high level idea there are many
details to make the idea really work
i'm now describing some details
the first detail is about avoiding
network jitters
the attacker is based on inter-process
timing so we do not want the network to
affect the timing
there are two ways
to load a url without generating an
actual network request
the first way
is to use an unsafe port in the url such
as port 1 port 22 etc
for example
we let the iframe load youtube
on port 1.
this request is prohibited
by the browser because port 1 is
considered an unsafe port
however because the request is
prohibited
the iframe loading is
completed immediately
and this gives us
no network delay in the measurement
the second way is to use a static
content
in the disk cache for example
the attacker can pre-load fevicom.ico
or robot.txt
so this static resource is in the disk
cache
then
when the attacker does the actual
measurement
there is no network delay in the result
the second set of details is about
understanding chromium's internals
we explore chromium's internals to find
and understand the timing
characteristics
this was achieved through
design docs and source code
through the ipc layer investigation
and through our runtime testing
the paper describes many details for
example we talk about
inter-process communication
we also focus on the code logic about
render view
which has an interesting cross iframe
effect related
to the pages visibility
in
addition we talk about
the html parsing performance
which is affected by the freshness
of the renderer process
these are sources that
produce timing differences but i need to
skip these details in my talk today
let me now present the evaluation
results
we use the alexa top 3000 sites
to do an evaluation to cover different
cpu powers and different noise workload
levels
specifically we test on a more powerful
desktop pc and a less powerful laptop pc
we create different numbers of extra
tabs loading arbitrary pages
as noise
we have four data sets data set a
is the scenario with five extra tabs on
the desktop pc
and data set b is one extra tab on
desktop pc that is a c is one extra tab
on laptop pc
data set d is five extra tabs
on
laptop pc
you can see that
the results
of
these four data sets
show the similar concept which is that
different colors
can be separate
and then for
most overlapping dots
the second measurement can separate them
we measure the pairwise differentiation
rate
and these are the
average results
they are pretty high
we compiled many versions of chromium
for testing
all the green versions are not
vulnerable
and all the red versions are vulnerable
the first vulnerable version is this one
which is the version in 2018
that enabled site isolation
edge is confirmed vulnerable because it
uses chromium
firefox is a little different
it uses the gecko engine not chromium
project
vision of mozilla
is an experimental feature for site
isolation on firefox
we do the first experiment about mp and
bg
they
can also be separated easily
however the second measurement will
require
a deeper understanding about the
implementation
we haven't spent the effort to dig into
the details
you may notice that
the dots on this diagram appear to be
quantized among the time dimension
this is because
firefox lowers the precision of
javascript's timing api
to 1 millisecond
in order to defend against meltdown and
spectral attack
this is just an interesting side note i
want to mention
to summarize
site isolation introduces a reliable
timing channel
that discloses a user's site visiting
behavior
the main challenge is the tension
between the scarcity of processes
and the objective to separate cross-site
frames in different processes
in this paper
we talk about
our discussions with the
edge and chrome teams about potential
mitigations
one possible mitigation proposed by the
chrome team
is to prohibit
process reuse between a top level frame
and an iframe
we will see whether this reuse policy
gets into the chromium code in the
future
i'm stopping here and
ready to answer your questions
okay
sorry i have a cool down time for the
microphone so if anyone has a question
please use the microphone and state your
name and affiliation
and
okay
different person sorry so i guess you're
the first author
okay
while you warm up i have a question
there is one thing i didn't understand
so to remove the network latency
basically uh you have this trick that
you load something from the cache for
example the icon or you know the robot
xt which is pretty cool
but but then later you say that one of
the source of the timing difference is
the html parser
but you don't actually render the html
in your tab right so you only load like
an icon so
why would the hdmi parser affect the
timing difference
hi
thank you for interest in our work
so actually
the html password is involved
when the arrow page is rendered
so we use the
answer part
which will result in an arrow page in
rendering iframe means that error page
is composed in html
so that process will involve a lot of
different parsing and will add latency
reloading and
that will introduce a latency like a
delay in the original page which is open
in the other tab not in the one you're
measuring the time that loads right
it will involve a latency when
during i3 loading process
and that latency depends on whether
there is a background
or not and whether it's newly started no
okay
questions
we're already one minute late so i think
we can stop here
if you can please check online if you
have also other questions so you can ask
them maybe
you can answer maybe them offline
and in this meantime we can ask the
second speaker to
thank you very much