very much
thanks arthur for the introduction this
is c-star it's joint work with my
colleagues from idiot zurich benjamin
roger and martin
so to start
remember that on public blockchain smart
contracts interact with data which is
stored in clear text on the blockchain
which is accessible to everyone so if
you want to store sensitive information
such as your medical data this is of
course a problem right
and ideally you would have something
like this where the data is hidden
and you can now interact with your data
as before using your smart contracts and
note that this concept of data privacy
does not protect the smart contact
itself but only the data which is stored
this is not a new idea several works
have tried to achieve data privacy but
they have various limitations
some of the early works they bring
privacy to payments mostly but they do
not focus on general smart contracts
some works rely on trusted managers or
hardware to enable data privacy but if
you do not want to trust these hardware
managers this is of course a problem
more recently there have been works
which rely on cryptographic primitives
to enable data privacy but
it turns out that in practice if you
want to use these tools to implement new
applications you actually need to
manually
integrate these cryptographic primitives
which can be quite challenging
in our previous work ck we have tried to
mitigate the problems i just mentioned
but ck has an explosivity problem and
you're restricted to some basic
smart contracts
here i am presenting c star cister is a
system for data privacy on more channels
more contracts
and it does not require you to trust any
trusted manager or hardware and
importantly you do not need
cryptographic expertise to implement
private smart contracts using z-star
caesar is highly expressive and as a
practical benefit you can actually
execute the context on ethereum which is
very nice
conceptually caesar extends our previous
sql work by homomorphic encryption in
order to give you more explicitivity we
will see this in a second
so what's the high level idea of what
you're doing here
consider this example
where we store balances of users on the
blockchain like here alice's and bob's
balance and in order to keep these
balances private we encrypt it under the
public keys of their owner so alice's
balance will be encrypted under alice's
public key
and now suppose alice wants to send one
of her tokens over to bob and to do so
she of course wants to decrease her
balance by 1 and in contrast increase
bob's balance by one
and now of course everything is
encrypted so how can you do this
the following idea is not new like other
work has done this manually and the idea
is to use non-interactive zero-knowledge
proofs and homomorphic encryption to
actually enable this transaction
so
let's distinguish the two cases here
first let's talk about the al
values owned by alice which is the case
self-owned here
and in order for alice to decrease her
balance it's very easy right she will
decrypt her previous balance apply the
desired plaintext operation and then
encrypt it again to get the new
ciphertext
and now of course to make sure that
alice does not cheat
because she could essentially apply any
operation right and send a new cipher
text she will attach a non-interactive
zero-knowledge proof which states that
this plaintext operation has been
applied correctly
in case of bob's value which is what we
call a foreign data here alice can rely
on the homomorphic property of the
encryption scheme so if your encryption
scheme is additively homomorphic alice
can first encrypt the constant one and
then homomorphically integrate this
increment by one inside the bob cipher
text to get a new ciphertext and now
alice will just send the new ciphertext
and the non-interactive serial knowledge
proof to the blockchain for verification
and as i said the previous work has done
this specifically this application here
i've shown you with the balances our
goal here is to automate this whole
process for more channel smart contracts
and there are various questions popping
up here for instance how do you even
distinguish between cell phone and
foreign data at priority it's not clear
what this even means what about the
interactions between these two cases
and also if your encryption scheme is
only partially homomorphic there are
some restrictions of course in what you
can express on the foreign data here so
we need to account for that as well
and finally
we need to talk about what exactly we
need to prove in the zero knowledge
proof and how do we make this efficient
because we will need to reason about
evaluating cryptographic primitives as
part of the zero knowledge proof
so cyster is a system
which actually helps you to bring data
privacy to your smart contracts using
the previous idea
and in c-star developers implement the
application in the custom system
programming language it's very similar
to solidity as it implements the logic
but it also contains privacy annotations
indicating what should be kept private
we will see this in a second
and then you feed this through the
sister compiler which will automatically
introduce additively homomorphic
encryption and ck snarks in order to
certify correctness and get data privacy
and the resulting solidity contract can
be executed on ethereum
so let's have a look at the input
contract
and the sister programming language is
based on privacy types the privacy types
help you to distinguish the foreign and
self-owned data case and to reflect the
restrictions of the homomorphic
encryption scheme
so here i've implemented the example we
had previously in plain solidity so we
just have a balance mapping which stores
for every address the balance owned by
this address and then i have a transfer
function which allows some sender
address which is written as me here to
transfer some value to some recipient
address
and as you can see here we first check
whether the sender has sufficient funds
and then we just update the balance
mapping as expected like
nothing special here and now we would
like to express the fact that the
balances should be kept private
and to this end c star relies on an idea
we introduced previously in our work ck
the idea is to extend data types by
privacy types using this annotation of
the form at owner where owner is some
addox expression indicating the party
allowed to see the data
so let's see this on our concrete
example
like if you want to express that the
balance is private to the respective
party you need to add these blue privacy
annotations
in particular in this line here we use
this syntax to encode the fact that the
balance of alice is owned by alice
meaning that it will be encrypted under
her public key at runtime
here in the transfer function we
annotate the value as at me meaning that
it will be self-owned by the transaction
sender and hidden to everyone else the
recipient address is just kept public
here by not annotating it at all
and now we can just work as usual in the
small contract so decreasing the balance
of the center is very easy you just
write it the same way as it was before
to increase the balance of the recipient
you actually need to add this reveal
expression here this reveal expression
changes the privacy type of the value
which previously was self-owned to the
recipient
this is required because you want to
prevent implicitly leaking information
if you would not write this like you you
will actually leak the value to the
recipient and to make sure that the
developer really wants to do this the
developer needs to add this expression
here and as a result here this addition
actually works on two expressions which
are not owned by the center but by some
other party and this is allowed in c
star and we will actually use the
homomorphic property of the encryption
schemes and note that in the work this
would actually not work
the nice thing about this privacy type
system is that we can reflect the
constraints of the homomorphic
encryption scheme so for instance if
alice was to write the code i've shown
here where she tries to add a value
owned by bob to a value owned by charlie
you would get a type error because these
like two elements will be encrypted on
the different public keys and there's no
way alice could actually combine this at
runtime so that's very nice
finally here for this requirement
statement alice needs to reveal the fact
that the center has sufficient funds
because the fact that the requirements
team statement will actually work out
will leak that this is true so you
actually need to reveal this explicitly
again using this expression
so this is the resulting contract the
nice thing is that developers do not
need any cryptographic expertise to
implement this they just need to
understand the privacy type session
essentially
so let's see how we can automatically
compile this input contract to an output
contract on ethereum and we will see how
we deal with interactions and what
exactly we need to prove in the zero
knowledge proof
i have the example from before here the
transfer function
and the idea is to compile this to a
solidity contract by following the
privacy types we have just seen
remember that whenever some expression
is private through some party according
to the type season in the input it will
be encrypted on the this parties public
key in the output contract
and now the compiler just checks the
input contact for private expressions
for instance consider on the left hand
side the updated balance of the sender
which is just the evaluation of this
subtraction
this will be replaced by a ciphertext
argument new me which will hold the
encrypted new balance at runtime just
like in the example you have seen at the
beginning of the talk and this
ciphertext will be computed by the
sender actually beforehand before
sending it to the blockchain of course
and now we need to make sure that this
ciphertext has been computed correctly
to do so we collect a set of constraints
which will be used in the serial
knowledge proof so what this constraint
said here is quite easy actually so the
idea is that
when you decrypt the previous balance
using your secret key and then from it
subtract the plaintext value and then
from the result like encrypt it again
then you get this new me ciphertext it's
quite obvious here
and note that of course all the secrets
here for instance the secret key of the
center are of course used as weaknesses
in the zero-knowledge proof so they will
not be seen on the blockchain but they
will be hidden
similarly
siesta replaces the new balance of the
recipient
by this new two argument and to compute
this the sender will actually apply this
homomorphic addition operation we've
seen previously and we'll also prove
that this computation has been performed
correctly as part of the zero knowledge
proof here using this additional
constraint
note that while we could in theory apply
this homomorphic addition not inside the
proof circuit but on the solidity
contract we do not do it in order to
save gas costs essentially because it
saves us an operation in the output
and then last but not least also
publicly revealed expressions will be
replaced but this time by plain text
arguments working the same way and then
we add an according constraint should be
rather
clear in this example i guess
and then all you got all you got to do
is just add a verification statement
which checks uh zero knowledge proof
containing the constraints we have just
collected here and this will actually
ensure that you updated your ciphertext
correctly and note that this is all
automated right so you have nothing to
do if you want to implement these
contracts
so note that even though we are relying
on an additively homomorphic encryption
scheme we can also support
multiplications in particular we can
support multiplications of foreign
values by a self-owned
value or a public value you can have a
look at our paper if you want to
find out how this exactly works and of
course in many more details i just
showed you a pretty basic example
it's very interesting to to get a
practical system to work so have a look
at it if you're interested
uh the system here has two important
guarantees which we formalize and proof
in the paper the first guarantee is
correctness meaning that you cannot
actually violate the logic you specified
in input contract
and the second property is privacy
meaning that an active attacker cannot
learn more in the real world then it can
learn which was allowed from the privacy
annotations in an ideal world that's
kind of the idea
so we implemented the system and
evaluated its efficiency
you can find the
source code of this on our github
repository ck here
achieving efficiency was quite tricky
actually using a naive implementation
here using straightforward building
blocks actually led to an explosion of
runtime like it was not usable at all so
we ended up with the following so we use
graph16 ck snarks which are very
efficient and exponential algomal
encryptions over elliptic curves which
gives you an additively homomorphic
encryption scheme
and in order for this elgamal encryption
operation to be efficiently provable as
part of the zero knowledge proof we have
to rely on elliptic curve embedding
which is just some cryptographic
technique which has been used already
previously
as a technicality here exponential gamma
encryption
requires you to solve a discrete
logarithm upon decryption so if you want
decryption to be visible within a few
seconds you actually need to restrict
plain text to around 32 bits we did this
in the implementation and already
reflect this in the in the type system
which will give you a type here if you
try to use a non
32-bit integer with this system here
we implement the 12 example contracts
using our system and these contacts
include a re-implementation of a
previous
private payment system c ether this
system has been manually designed to
give you kind of a private wallet
which is an extension of what we've seen
previously here
and the offers like instantiated this
idea by hand and in contrast you can
just implement this using the privacy
annotations and compile it to something
equivalent so this is very nice
on a commodity desktop machine you get
reasonable transaction generation times
like at most one minute here and this
time is generally dominated by proof
generation time because generating the
zero knowledge proof is like the most
heavy task here
in terms of gas costs this is the cost
you need to pay when you actually
execute the resulting conflict on
ethereum this is around 3340k
gas it's in line to existing
applications such as uniswap
if you want to know how much this is in
terms of dollars i i did this two weeks
ago when i made the presentation it was
around 32 dollars which is quite high
the problem with these numbers is that
it's super volatile like ethereum price
and gas prices they tend to spike a lot
so it's not very useful to talk about
monetary costs here but still i put it
for completeness
so with that i'd like to conclude i've
presented c star allowing you to express
private smart contacts easily and
automatically compiling them to
contracts for solidity thank you very
much
thank you samuel wonderful presentation
any questions from the audience
hello yeah nice presentation i'm sorry
from uiuc so you said you use gross 16
zk snarks and they have this
circuit-based trusted setups like for
each circuit you have to do a different
circuit so a different setup so how do
you like how does this work right now
great question so as you say correctly
the scheme we use requires you to do one
trusted setup pair circuit and this
compilation process produces one circuit
per function so you actually if you want
to deploy your contact you need to
perform this trusted setup phase
yourself this is like out of of of
context of our tool but you actually get
a separate circuit and a separate setup
per function that's true i see and
generate question like what are the next
steps like adopting fully homomorphic
encryption or currently only support
additive right
yeah so a fully homomorphic encryption
is very inefficient so it's very hard to
use in in this blockchain context and
also you would need to reason about
fully homomorphic encryption as part of
zero knowledge proof which i find is
quite tricky what you can do is
integrate other encryption schemes like
multiple multiplicatively homomorphic
encryption but we we just determined
that this is not very useful for example
applications but of course you could try
to do this okay thanks
do we have time
yeah go ahead
uh thank you very much for the
presentation it's really great that you
have this very ordinary user from the
scheme
uh
my question is going to be about this
the ether implementation that you read i
think they had
much higher gas cost in their original
paper i think maybe about like 7 million
or something yes is it because you are
using growth 16 that you gain
from that
so this is a longer discussion so one
problem is that they use a different
version of ethereum which used to have a
big different gas cost for these
cryptographic operations like
unfortunately we could not compare to
their implementation because it was
neither open sourced nor available even
though we asked the offers
even though they use the bulletproof
system which is much more expensive than
graph16 to verify so i think this is the
reason why they even in a newer version
of ethereum would get higher gas costs
than what we have
so you are kind of trading off like
trusted setup with efficiency exactly
and of course in theory you could just
use our system with the bullets proof
proofer then you would likely get higher
costs but you will get rid of the
trusted setup assumption i think okay
thank you thank you
ian myers university of maryland uh
what's the privacy model here a lot of
these attempts to do zero knowledge for
account models either end up
where you leak
access patterns or you have to lock
every account
to do a single transaction yes so in
this work here you leak the access
pattern so the access memory locations
will be published in particular in this
transaction i've shown here the transfer
function you can see it on the screen it
is leaked which parties access the
balance in this mapping yes okay so
you're just hiding the values but not
the identities exactly yeah thank you
excellent um
yep i think then time is up so great
thank you very much