welcome everyone to Kringle Con I'm
super happy to be here at Santa's castle
this is probably the coldest place I've
ever been and for Florida and it's uh
you know even worse I mean we I had to
travel insane distance to get here and
the entire trip was just like
treacherous like I had to like get on a
biking ship at one point and it's just
it's madness but anyway I'm happy to be
here it took forever to get here but
this is amazing I can't believe we're
having a hacker conference at the North
Pole so welcome everyone I am your
speaker in this room my name is Bobo
look and today I'm gonna talk to you
about everything you've ever wanted to
know about password spraying but we're
afraid to ask
so we'll get into what exactly password
spring isn't just a moment but first off
let's talk a little bit about like what
our credentials anyway like what I mean
if you're coming into this if you're
coming into this conference you probably
had to have credentials to even get in
here you probably had to have some sort
of password to even get into this place
so credentials are vital they control
access to your account whenever you go
to website you typically have to sign in
and use a username and password and
attackers will want that password and
when we talk about hacking an
organization or hacking a company or
hacking Christmas for that matter
we can look at the ability to gain
access to credentials as being the first
kind of step into completely taking over
that organization or company or whatever
whatever we're trying to get access to
now a lot of people will think okay well
I'm just this employee of this company
maybe I'm like you know nobody I'm you
know I'm in accounting who would want my
credential what does it matter
well you know whenever we are attacking
a company that utilizes Active Directory
which is very often I would I would put
it in like the 95 percent of companies
that I assess from Black Hills
Information Security from from companies
that we perform penetrations again for
penetration tests against use Active
Directory which is a Microsoft service
which basically is a directory of
of usernames and computers and it helps
to kind of combine everything that you
want to control with an organization
from a computer standpoint it allows you
to push out policies to specific users
that kind of thing well having an act
having access to a single credential of
an Active Directory account typically
gives you a lot more than just access to
that users computer system or to their
specific account Active Directory is is
vast so you know a lot of times we'll
get access to a credential and we can
access things like file shares on the
network things that a normal user can
access that you know their their
credential gives them access to in the
network if for example they use
something like like office 365 a lot of
a lot of companies we assess these days
are moving to the cloud and using things
like office 365 we're now sharepoint and
various documents an Outlook all that
stuff is in the cloud and if I have
access to a credential I can now not
only access that users let's say their
email but I can also access SharePoint
where and a lot of times SharePoint is
where companies store a vast amount of
information regarding their company
things like maybe VPN details internal
documents that kind of thing I was
actually just on an assessment last week
where an internal git repository which
is a typically like a source code
repository of information and internal
to this network anyone met a credential
on the domain anyone who had an Active
Directory credential can access it and
there was a lot of very sensitive
information in that including access
keys to their Amazon AWS account
passwords to a number of different
services and so on so the point trying
to get to here is that having a single
credential will allow access to a number
of other things and be the next step in
the attack
so typically within a Microsoft Active
Directory network your default password
policy is is a minimum of 8 characters
and doesn't include your username so
you're not allowed to set it to your
username and the majority of the time
it's set to what they call password
complexity which is three of the four
categories uppercase
sledders lowercase letters numbers or
non numeric symbols and by default these
accounts typically lock out after about
five attempts within a 30 minute window
so a 30-minute observation window so
what's the password that fits that
policy well fall 2018 and we'll what
kind of get into more more more details
about why that's very key here in a
minute so what are some common password
attacks when we when we look at hacking
an account brute-forcing obviously is
one of the first things that comes to
mind for most most hackers out there and
what that is is essentially trying
thousands of passwords against one
account so this is kind of problematic
when we look at that lockout policy that
we mentioned previously because if we
try 2,000 of passwords against one
account
you're gonna lock them out really quick
another common password attack is
password reuse so if you for example
were part of a breach or part of a if
you had your account on a site or
service that was breached your password
your clear text password might be out
there for the world get their services
such as have I been poned that allow you
to kind of search for your email address
and see if you have been part of a
breach but a lot of times those those
breach credentials are just publicly
available on on various websites and you
know for an attacker they can go grab
those in the Charter we use them and if
you're using the same password for
example like your LinkedIn account as
you are on your corporate Active
Directory account we might be able to
just reuse that password credential
phishing is another huge topic all of
its own this involves social engineering
a target into in putting their creds
into a portal that an attacker controls
so I would basically send you a link to
let's say I wanted to fish your Gmail
credential am i it set up a portal that
looks almost identical to Gmail and then
send you a link telling you that you
need to log in to this this is a very
basic example but a lot of people get
tricked into and putting their
credential and credentials into these
types of sites and then password
spraying and that's what this talk is
all about so we're gonna get more into
the details of that now so take this
picture for example of a ton of locks
just you know locked against a wall
offense so
you know locks are not the perfect
example but this can kind of paint a
picture here so imagine this is an
Active Directory environment where each
one of these locks kind of symbolizes an
account for a user that would log into
their network now you know log
manufacturers a lot of times actually
have common keys or key to like locks
that you know if you have one key you
might you would open multiple locks so
for example here let's say that these
users are the people that put these
locks here could actually choose their
own keys such as the case with passwords
now if I chose a key that was relatively
easy or something common I might be able
to unlock a lot of these locks so this
is kind of similar to what password
spring is so with the lock out policies
preventing us from brute-forcing we have
to think of another way to kind of get
around that restriction and somehow get
access to an account now what if we
tried authenticating using only one
password but against all of those
accounts so let's say we grabbed one key
and we tried one key against all of
those locks we might actually get lucky
and find that one of those locks just
magically opens because it's a common
key so what's gonna happen is we're
gonna generate thousands of fail logins
but they're all single failed logins for
each user so that doesn't actually meet
the lockout threshold for a specific
user so for example if a lockout
threshold is set to 5 attempts in 30
minutes and we only try one attempt per
user we can you know try thousands of
failed logins because we're trying to
log into everyone else's account we're
not trying to log into that one specific
account using multiple passwords which
are having one password and we might get
lucky with something common like season
year or company one two three or
password year so season year is is
perfect in most cases and it's honestly
the most common thing that we find in
most organizations because it lines up
to the default policy for resetting your
password which is 90 days so you know we
find that people are like oh I need to
reset my password let's just try winter
or fall 2018 you know and and then
repeat after 90 days change it to season
year a lot of people do that and then
when we get access to an account we now
have the ability to do those other
things that I mention early like
access to SharePoint and stuff so what
are some ways we can do this so internal
to a domain if you have access to a
system with an Active Directory account
you can use one of the tools that I
wrote called domain password spray which
is a PowerShell script that essentially
just performs password spraying against
all the users within a domain another
way to perform password spraying is with
Metasploit SMB login module and so both
of these will essentially create failed
logins on the target system and i i've
had a number of customers lately who
have started to really detect this type
of activity so we started kind of
thinking like what are some ways you can
kind of evade using this specific
internal domain spray well what if we
hit Outlook Web Access so this is a very
common service as well and a lot of
organizations so Microsoft Exchange and
an Outlook Web Access are very common
across a lot of the organizations we
assess one of the tools that I wrote
called mail sniper has the ability to
perform password spraying ants oo and
the failed logins look a little bit
differently than they do against SMB I
was just on another assessment recently
where I used this this tool and it did
not get detected whereas the previous
tool that I showed you did so when we
when we look at trying to evade logging
this might be another option but we've
also had a lot of customers who have
seen this specific tool when they
started alerting on it as well so what
else can we try against well how about
RDP so remote desktop protocol which is
on by default on most Windows systems so
I tested out using this tool called X
free RDP which is actually a Linux tool
against a Windows server and I was just
kinda going through the process of
trying to figure out if this would maybe
evade some logging and to my surprise
the the failed login event didn't
actually include the source IP address
the host name was there but the IP
wasn't which was very odd so why was
there no idea in the log well it turns
out that RDP within LA which is called
Network clear authentication doesn't
actually log the source IP to a security
log in LA actually pre authenticates the
user so like whenever you you already P
to a system you might be
my comment commonly recognized the the
prompt that kind of comes up that looks
like a traditional like windows prompt
prior to actually getting to the GUI of
Windows that is actually in LA at work
so there's actually supposed to be
another log that in a lei supposed to
write to and this in this event right so
in the event that I fail login using RDP
that has in LA there should be this
event 1:40 filled filled filled log an
event that actually gets logged too
whenever somebody fails but what is
really really misleading about this is
that it only fires when the username is
invalid so if I'm using valid user names
with invalid passwords there is no event
ID 140 log and I've got a quick demo
with this to kind of show you how this
looks so to show you here I've got an
attacker system with an IP address of
192 168 88.2 4 5 and I'm going to
demonstrate using this tool called our
desktop against a Windows Server 2012
where we're gonna attempt to log into
this deviator account and we can see
that we've failed to login now if we go
to look at the actual failed event log
now we will see the username so we
should CD Vader as the account name
there and then we also see that we have
the you know under an unnamed unknown
username or bad password and then also
the workstation name and the source
network address so that's our attacker
IP so total attribution there we know
exactly who performed a failed login
using that tool and the reason that
happened is because our desktop does not
use NLA to authenticate so to kind of
show you a perfect concept here I
created a list of host names so we see
like printer one share one sheriff I
don't look here so these are the list of
host names we'll be sending to this
system and then we also have a list of
usernames here and I have a proof of
concept Python script which I'll show
you a link to that a little bit that
basically takes that host list and the
user list and then performs a password
spraying it's our DP and we can see that
the crud was probably valid so this
means that the actual
users credential fn-2187 was actually
spring 2017 that credential is valid by
the user because they're not anise
trader of this system or they're not in
the RDP group they're not actually able
to RDP to the system but now let's go
look at the audit failures for these
users so again we'll see the username so
we'll see that a field event happened
but if we go look at the workstation him
share five and no source IP that's not
good for trying to track down who
performed this failed login so imagine
now you know you're you're an
administrator on this network and you're
just seeing these failed logins come
from hosts that are already on your
network you know I could give it a list
of your own host names you know I could
I can make it look like people are just
failing to log in from everywhere and
with no source IP it gets really
difficult so again like with with in LA
it should log to this other log but you
know we mentioned before that if we're
using valid user names then it doesn't
actually show up here so let me get out
of this and back over to the
presentation so that's pretty much the
the the rundown for password spraying
and you know I really hope you guys have
a great time here at Kringle con and you
know if you want to follow me up on
through Adaptec and here's the link a
few links to the different tools that i
described so mail sniper domain password
spray and the RDP Spray proof of concept
thanks so much for coming to my talk
guys