hey my name is Chris Davis I'm going to
show you how to decrypt and analyze HP
to traffic and wire shortcut so the
tools that were gonna be using for this
is Wireshark Chrome and curl Wireshark
does the traffic analysis and the
decryption piece while Chrome and curl
allow you to store SSL keys to be able
to decrypt the benefit of Chrome's you
can interact with the website you can
use things like in developer tools which
makes interacting with website a lot
easier
kuroh obviously can be used to help
automate command line interaction again
you can script things up like maybe you
had an API that was HP to enabled and
you needed to automate a task and but
also store the SSL keys for debugging
later this is you would use Chrome for
that so why do we want to use these
unfortunately because there's not a lot
of HTTP to support and a lot of common
tools and frameworks right now for
example one of my favorites is Python
requests it does not have HP to support
as of the time of writing this
unfortunately so I want to quickly show
you or at least give you the commands
you need to build curl with HP - and as
a cell support because at least on
Ubuntu 1604 which is what I use I found
that curl did not have HTTP to support
built-in so I had to go through and I
had to rebuild it myself I had to remove
and then rebuild it myself so these were
the commands that I had used to to be
able to accomplish that it also requires
curl 7.59 or greater to be able to do HP
- also to be able to store the SSL key
logs as well so I had to build that with
that support built in - otherwise you
can't pass the SSL key log environment
variable so going back to what I was
saying the SL key log file can be
specified when we run our curl command
which case we can we just give it the
environment variable equals SSL key logs
about text that's just an arbitrary flat
file txt file location that you want to
specify again and then curl and whatever
curl commands and parameters you want to
pass it including the URL of HTTP -
enabled server again when you do that it
saves that those SSL keys so that we can
decrypt it in water shark later so for
the demo here I'm gonna show you how to
use Chrome to actually store those as a
sub key log so that we can decrypt them
with Wireshark so here again I'm using
this on Windows but I believe the same
can be done with actually Firefox
in chromium on Linux as well I don't not
exactly sure what those command lines
would be but I've been using cogito the
- - SSL key log file path and again I'm
just passing specifying a flat text file
on my desktop and then I'm passing in
the parameter of my local HP - enabled
web server before I move on though I
wanted to show you a couple quick
Wireshark filters so Wireshark is nice
and that it does have Wireshark filters
built in for HP - now which makes things
really easy right for example we could
do HP - headers method equals get if we
wanted it to get just HP - we could type
in just HP - we can specify a path for
example if we were going to grab we
wanted to see styles that CSS we could
specify the path we could also specify a
cookie for example maybe we were trying
to debug users login interaction we need
to see what kind of cookies they were
getting we could specify that
additionally if we wanted to see just
the data itself we could do HP - data
data and then we could also search
inside of HTTP - for arbitrary values
for example username right so if there's
a username form field and a password
form field we could do HP to contains
and then username and then it would
water search smart enough to be able to
parse through HP - and then find that
traffic for us I'm going to show you how
to capture a traffic and then decrypt it
with Wireshark and use Google Chrome to
store those keys so first thing we want
to do is set a traffic capture I'm using
raw caps since by default Wireshark is
unable to sniff localhost on Windows
machines they can on Linux but not on
Windows alright and finally we need to
open up command prompt and we need to
start Chrome with the SSL key log
argument okay so there's our HP -
enabled web interface running on
localhost that we opened up with command
prompt and as you can see we actually
have our SSL client random keys here so
it is actually already storing it thanks
to Chrome we open up Chrome and we can
inspect the traffic here on the web site
and we can do a network
sure and let's just type something in
right so at this point maybe you're a
pen tester and you're trying to analyze
a webform login right maybe you're
trying to hack it you're trying to
figure out what's going on with it or
maybe you're a web developer and there's
an error or you're trying to store those
keys or you know be able to to debug
what's going on with a web application
so in this case let's just say we're
trying to login it doesn't really matter
what we type in here but let's go and
generate some traffic and chrome
actually sees this as the h2 protocol
it's able to interact with it and so we
can see that it's actually making the
login request and we can see our
response even here but that's it that's
all we needed to do so we created some
traffic let's go ahead and close our web
server let's make sure our keys yep
there's more keys for each of those
requests that we made and then let's go
ahead and close our traffic's capture
and then we're going to open up our pcap
flower open okay so the first thing
we're going to notice is that all it
sees is SSL traffic right it sees the
the certificate exchange right and it
can't really do anything with it
right it does see that it's port 4 4 3 3
which is web server that we had set up
but again it can't evaluate as HP 2
because it's all encrypted so what we
can do is Wireshark actually gives us
the option to provide it and as to sell
key log files the one that we just
created in which case it can decrypt the
traffic and then we can evaluate
evaluate it as HP 2 so what we want to
do is you want to go to edit and we want
to go down to preferences and then once
we open up preferences we want to click
on the protocols tree and then we want
to go down to SSL here's a cell under
the premaster secret log file name I
want to open that up and we want to
specify the SSL key log file that we had
created when we do that we can actually
see immediately that some of the traffic
was decrypted so let's go ahead and go
back over to our Wireshark filters that
we provide earlier so fortunately
Wireshark knows how to evaluate hb2 so
HTTP 2 is the filter we type in and when
we do that we can automatically see all
of the HP 2 traffic now one thing to
know is there's you can see that the TCP
stream number is the same
the entire session the entire session is
one TCP stream and that's the the
performance benefit over aged people one
got one because before HP 1.1 what every
time it needed a resource from the
server it would have to reestablish the
TCP handshake and create a new TCP
stream request the resource get back the
response and then close the TCP stream
for example if I was getting index.html
then that HTML would have an image in it
they would have JavaScript in it it
would have all those things each and
every single one of those would have to
be as its own separate TCP request and
we can actually see in here that it's
doing the same thing doing the same core
concept it's grabbing styles.css it's
making post requests to slash a API
slash log and it's making its grabbing
some JavaScript files but each and every
single one of those is done in r1 TCP
stream instead of mini TCP streams so
just looking at here we can actually go
down to where we had done the post API
login and we can actually open up packet
here and Wireshark has already evaluated
it's already parsed all the the hp2
headers and it's provided to us in a
nice little graphical interface we can
actually select just like any other
protocol analysis in Wireshark we can
actually select that value and we can
apply it as a filter and it'll
automatically apply that for us so if we
did HP do header die value equals post
it gives us all of our post requests
which are the the five requests that we
had made previously additionally hb2 has
lots of filters so if we do type in HB 2
and then a period will actually see
Wireshark will populate a bunch of
filters here for us right header values
flag values data values it's it's smart
enough to be able to parse HTTP 2 and
make your life a little bit easier so ok
so we we wanted to evaluate the the post
login right so as we can see here HB 2
has all of our header values so we have
a post all of these things here but
again I think what we're interested in
is the username and the password
form field data and as we can see here
that's nowhere to be found it's actually
not in
Paquette so let's take a look here
because of the way that HP two works
frame number let's start with this
packet here so two four five zeros so
framed number it's greater than or equal
to 2 for five zero so we see here that
the post request from the client is made
for API slash login and then in another
packet in a data packet down further we
actually have the post parameters being
sent and so we could actually do this is
where we got that other filter here that
I was specifying before HP to data data
and if we type that in we can actually
see just the data request right to the
server and from the server data requests
okay so now we're interested in the
username form field so we can do HP to
data data and ampersand understand HP to
contains now the contains feature says
take this protocol I want to find only
inside of these protocols which would be
HP to I want to find this value right
and so we're specifying username we do
that we can actually see again just the
data that has the username form field
value and here we can again we can see
our username and our password and again
this will be come in handy because maybe
you were trying to figure out what the
client-side web application is doing to
the data before it's sent to the server
right and maybe that will help us either
in the pen test or maybe that'll help us
in debugging our application again
another useful one I just want to point
out I don't think is applicable to this
demo but HP headers that set the cookie
right so we can actually parse out
cookie values that way finally the only
thing I wanted to point out as well is
when even after it's been decrypted
unfortunately we can't just do right
click follow TCP stream because when we
do that it just sees it as that SSL
values unfortunately which is just not
super helpful it was if it was HP 1.1
and it was just you know HTTP be without
H without Lissa's he'll we can actually
right click and view that stream and
then see it in plain text again
unfortunately Wireshark does not do that
so it's not completely perfect finally
it will also not allow us to export HTTP
to objects right so when we needed that
HTML or that specific JavaScript file
we can't export it through here we can't
do export objects HP unfortunately just
doesn't show it because it's linked to
the HP protocol not HTTP to