welcome Kringle Con attendees to http/2
because one is in fact the loneliest
number
my name is Chris LG I work at counter
hack challenges building things and
breaking things I'm also in the Army
National Guard I am on the Twitter's I
have too many E's in my last name some
certs and a singing Justin Bieber
toothbrush Chris Davis and I are gonna
talk to you today about HTTP 1.1 and 2.0
and some of the differences there
because it's 2.0 is a technology that
most of us are less familiar with but
it's really pervasive and and we'll look
at that going forward so each created
about 18 years apart and and kind of
preceded by HTTP 9 and 1.0 but really
dot 9 1 and 1.1 aren't are terribly
different at least in terms of the vast
works we're gonna look at today
so with 1.1 and 2.0 they're both gonna
be available in any browser you're using
Safari Chrome Firefox edge whatever they
will speak both of these technologies
now with 1.1 our headers are all ASCII
they're all human readable each header
is a line of code a line of ASCII text
where with 200 it's all byte codes it's
binary so we're not able to read it
anymore but but it's computers talking
to computers so that they can be a
little more compact and how they
communicate so that that saves a little
bit of overhead there also with 1.1 it's
really a connectionless technology your
your client your web browser asks for
one file at a time and gets it back from
the web server one one file at a time
where with 2.0 is it is connection
oriented you will see the term stream
pop up a few times to where basically a
web server can send a bunch of files at
once with a single TCP handshake and a
single tear down at the end with 1.1 we
do still have some unencrypted just
regular HTTP websites but of course most
things we're doing anything sensitive on
are gonna be TLS and that's you know
your social media your email or whatever
with with 200 the RFC actually allows
for an unencrypted HTTP 2 connection but
no browser will speak it really the only
tool I've found that will
unencrypted 2.0 is curl and we'll play
with that here a little bit and finally
with 1.1 that's that's absolutely
totally available in any web server
you're going to go to you really have to
have to contrive an instance where it
where it that wouldn't be available
whereas with tuna no it isn't completely
available across the entire internet but
with any top site with most top sites
it's gonna be up so if we look at the
top alexa sites that fit on my slide all
but three are speaking to data already
and if you think about it from the
perspective of these major providers
there there's a cost savings there right
with with these binary headers with with
fewer tcp handshakes and tear downs
there there are a few fewer bytes in
each transaction for a user which when
you're dealing on the scale of these
type of systems then that could be a
significant cost savings in terms of
network infrastructure so pictorially we
can we can sort of think of it this way
where with 1.1 we would request a URL
like slash or index and then we would
get that HTML file back from the server
and then that since that file referenced
a JavaScript script that needs to be
added then we request it we get it back
it referencing some image we request it
we get it back maybe some CSS request to
get it back all is individual
connections with a three-way handshake
the push of the file and then the
four-way teardown with two now no it is
it is simpler it's a little more kind of
fancy and how it does things but but
there's a single request for slash or
index and then the server can send back
all the files that are necessary in a
single push so again less less overhead
in terms of network traffic to look at
it a bit lower level let's kind of dive
into curl here but so we've got here
just curl or give me a web site - v4
verbose without this curl would just
return the HTML or whatever content
comes back from the server it wouldn't
tell us what's going on kind of under
the hood I'm gonna spin going to specify
- - HTTP - because I want to talk HTTP -
because that's what this talk is about
then we're gonna give it a specific URL
HTTP colon slash slash WWB TOCOM slash
that's the website I want then I'm going
to do this little shorthand for put
standard error into standard out I'm
gonna do this because in order to show
this one screen at a time I'm going to
pipe standard out through the command
les without putting standard error in a
standard out we wouldn't be able to see
the the information that curl is going
to give us about the handshake stuff
when we curl for Bhosle we get the TLS
handshake information and and all that
all that connection errata in standard
error so if we didn't put it into
standard out then it would it would fly
by and wouldn't get caught by the less
command so that's just a little
shorthand there again to combine
standard error and standard out so off
we go our browser curl goes ahead and
reaches out to Baidu and then offers up
a couple different connection methods
using application layer protocol
negotiation or al p.m. it's offering h2
which is just shorthand for HTTP to let
you might guess and then also 1.1 and
then goes forward I'm kind of finished
as a TLS handshake now notice that these
these offerings that the two and the one
that one these happen is part of the TLS
handshake this is this is before any get
requests or anything like that
that's as well they're still determining
how they want to speak securely so so
those are the offers the Baidu server
comes back it says great let's talk 1.1
some certificate information and then
here curl is showing us the regular
ASCII request that we're used to seeing
right as web app pentesters we're used
to get and the slash and all this the
host the user agent which of course here
is curled and then give me back anything
any type of data and then the web server
responds with a typical ASCII header of
200 okay here's some stuff that's coming
at you I don't cache things here's a
cookie so I can so I can track your
status as we go through and then of
course after that comes the HTML now
it's gonna look sim
with with Google we're going to offer
HTTP 2 and 1.1 will complete our TLS
handshake certificates and then Google
says hey let's talk HTTP 2 right I want
to save that little bit of overhead and
you're able to talk it so here we go
now this get request looks a little
funny right because we're talking two we
asked for two we got two back and and
here's our header requesting one not one
I think what happened here with curl is
that it knows we want to see an ASCII
header because we gave it the dash V for
verbose but of course there are no ASCII
headers so it's got to make something up
just just for these for these human eyes
looking at it so it just sort of
defaults to showing get slash HTTP 1.1
even though this really is a 2 dot or
request and we can see that in the
response from google HTTP slash to 200
this is an okay of course this is
actually coming back and forth as byte
codes but kind of kind of abstracting as
as ASCII for us for us humans so we see
that response maybe some headers were
less used to seeing it's still setting
some cookies right because Google still
going to track certain things and then
looking farther down we get the HTML
coming back from Google so there we have
it
just HTTP to at a high level and now
Chris Davis we'll talk more about
looking at the traffic in depth and
decoding it in Wireshark