hello and welcome to Kringle Con this is
Jack Daniel and we're here as Santa has
invited us to work together to avoid
being hacked save Santa save Christmas
make the world a happier place I want to
talk about community building and how we
can work together to save Christmas and
our jobs and all sorts of other things
so I am Jack I one of the people that
makes besides what it is and also work
at tenable and doing a lot of community
building for a very long time it's
really things really made my career but
also my personal life a lot richer from
the folks that I've met and interacted
with through the decades let's start out
with you know what do we mean by
community let's let's go to the boring
dictionary definitions you know a group
of people living in the same place and
not so much us but a feeling of
fellowship with others as a result of
sharing common attitudes interests and
goals that's closer to it we don't
always have the exact same attitudes
interests and goals but in the hacker
community we share information that's
how we learn things we play with things
we break things we fix things and then
we learn the lessons and share and we
all advance from there so why why why go
to the effort of building community
what's you know what do we get from this
activity that that's good for us well
quickly you know we share ideas it's how
we learn as I said it's how we grow
there's no better way to learn something
than to try to teach it to somebody else
share ideas we spark conversations as we
have those conversations we connect we
know who is doing what cool stuff we
know if there's somebody that might be
able to give us a hand or someone that
we can give a hand to especially as that
comes to advancing our careers these
things all work together the the bad
guys are working together we should work
together too now there are some
challenges to building community but
they can overcome them we have to
address them before we can really dig
into
the world better the first one is as
many of you probably noticed there isn't
just one community there are a lot of
communities I like to think of it more
as anthropological tribes and nations
and clams down to family units but
unlike that sort of model we get to be
in multiples we can choose what
communities maybe you're hardcore
cryptography but you also like lock
sport perhaps your day job is policy and
compliance but you really enjoy reverse
engineering malware but the the PCI
things pay you better so we have a bunch
of different categories of people that
that come together and we have some
common interests and you know these
these sometimes divide us but what
really works well is getting together so
those of us who call ourselves hackers
there are a lot of people who still
identify hacker is bad mainstream media
has really done a number to us but a lot
of us are proud to wear that label a lot
of us also are you know InfoSec
professionals but many are hobbyists
some of some like me work and vendor
space as well as in the community and
they're more and more of us who straddle
this divide you know that it used to be
that not many people went to both Def
Con and RSA but it's it's as the
industry is matured I don't wanna say
we've matured that would be boring but
as the industry is matured more of us
cross this divide but we also have the
the stratification between the trench
level warriors and the various strata of
management and executives but we are
best when we bridge these divides and
these are opportunities to learn it's
opportunities to understand as a manager
executive who is actually hands on
keyboard fighting the bad guys and the
other way around what what is it that is
driving your organization when you're in
the trenches so you understand how to
move forward and if you can share these
ideas in community organizations large
and small we all are better off another
challenge in building community is this
one we're pretty much all overworked and
if you're trying to build a community or
strength in your local community it take
some work someone's got to do the work
it doesn't happen magically sometimes a
little bit of coordination goes a long
way and sometimes it takes a lot more
coordination like putting on Kringle
Khan that took a lot of effort and when
we talk about community a lot of this
stuff is is all volunteer work and of
course the the challenge of volunteer
work as Gandhi famously said the problem
with altruism is there's nothing in it
for me the reality is that we get a lot
back out of volunteerism there been a
couple of recent studies and things that
have shown real value in in this you
know but most of us get into doing these
sort of things by learning something and
wanting to share you know that's that
was my path into community I landed as
an IT admin and had to deal with
security issues back in the 90s didn't
know where to turn joined some user
groups learned from people then I had
some problems that managed to fix on my
own so I shared what I have learned and
that has been a story I've heard over
and over and over again we've learned
from the community and it's our turn to
give back so there actually is a lot you
feel great doing it it is good for you
personally and professionally and so
it's not really for me so there are some
secrets to building community and some
obvious things dig into this so I can
describe this in six words Mike my
secrets to a building community in six
words the first three give a darn you
are free to substitute strong hunger
words as appropriate but you have to
actually care about it this is true
whether you're building community for
purely goodwill purposes if you're just
trying to strengthen your local
community if you're trying to bring
people together for whatever reason or
if you're doing it in a commercial
setting if you're if you're working with
the community manager in your
corporation or your job
people have to care if you're interested
in things just for financial gain or for
personal pride or ego people will see
that it's not about giving community so
we have to have people that really care
luckily in the hacker community it is a
passionate group it is is a good bunch
of people you find people that are
like-minded work with them that can
sometimes be difficult because we all
you may have noticed a lot of us and a
hacker crowd have some opinions and hey
they don't always line up but it's a
good exercise in learning how to work
with people for a greater good or common
good so the first part as I said is give
a darn or whatever word you'd like to
use moving beyond that though this is
the part that is important you need to
give a voice to the people in the
community that you're building or
maintaining you need to give them a
platform to show what they know share
what they've learned to be heard about
the direction that your community is
going and here's the key part you have
to listen to them you have to respond
you have to go in the direction of the
community wants you to go that's why you
know at every event you go to we all beg
you to fill out those feedback forms so
we know how you know which speakers were
good what went well what didn't we have
to we have to share what we've learned
and we have to move forward as a
community we have to give people a voice
let them be heard and we have to listen
to them one of the things that I do both
for besides in for my work is I spend a
lot of time talking to people and that's
insignificant what I spend a lot of time
doing is even more time doing is
listening to people taking that
information back wherever it belongs
whether it's to a specific event or
whether it's specific community are
trying to start an initiative or you
know in the corporate setting maybe it's
going back to your product management
team or your support team or your
marketing team to make sure that the
messages are heard in the community
since it is to make sure that your group
whatever it is that you're doing
is actually doing what the people won't
want what your community needs and wants
we have to listen to that voice give
people the opportunity to be heard and
grow and understand that if you're if
you let things go on their own a little
bit of shepherding it becomes a very
powerful community
it grows people's careers advanced
something that I've seen in the decades
of doing this it's really amazing to
watch people come into small groups be
very timid be welcomed into the group
and then discover that they've got there
other people that have their weird
interest and it turns out it's not so
weird they're you know they're old
tracks at Def Con or their entire
courses at sans or their b-sides events
where there's a lot of focus on whatever
your interest is whether it's data
science or authentication or you know
classic red team or physical pin test
you know I've seen seeing people hacking
elevators you find those people you find
your people you work together you have a
sense of friendship Accra Madhuri in
many cases people end up you know as
chosen family and it all comes from
giving people of an opportunity to talk
and listening to that and working
together as a team and so that's my
short little spiel on building community
it's a matter of giving people a voice
and listening to it it's a matter of
playing Shepherd when you need to and
guiding people through and letting the
community grow and strengthen for all of
us so thank you for joining me Jack
Daniel at Kringle con and let's let's
defend Santa save Christmas and make the
world a better place
Merry Christmas