hello everybody and welcome back to
Kringle Con once again a huge huge thank
you to mr. Claus for having us up here
and mrs. Claus I don't know if you guys
are aware of this but mrs. Claus makes
the absolute best cookies in the whole
wide world so I'm basically letting you
all know this because kids you better
start upping your cookie game because
you're gonna do nothing but disappoint
Santa whenever he comes to your house on
Christmas Eve
all right so I wanted to give another
presentation on creating a malware zu zu
and doing malware analysis so let's dive
right in the first thing that you're
gonna have to do when you're setting up
your malware zu is you're going to have
to have an overall concept of what the
design is going to look at Oh
generally wonder if we're creating a
malware analysis lab for creating
malware for implants or doing detection
with Rita and doing analysis we create
an Active Directory environment we
infect a single system on the inside of
that environment and then we have a bro
or Z because it's now called and Rita
system that's watching all of that
traffic that is leaving that particular
environment and this is key because you
want to have that level of visibility
now some people would argue that you
would need full peak apps and full TCP
dump that would be great if everybody
could do that that would be just
fantastic
but a lot of organizations have very
limited number of span ports that they
can use for the Eagers traffic so that
may not be available so just try to tie
up just bro and Rita don't try to get
too crazy with what you're trying to
capture also running VMware VMware is
absolutely essential this is my lab this
is what I use all the time for doing
analysis with Rita and active
countermeasures AI hunter and this
particular lab can scale anywhere from
like a handful of systems like 20 all
the way up to about 70 to 80 systems it
depends on how crazy I want to get with
a lab that I'm trying to create and
VMware is just fantastic for that also
bro
Zeke bro is amazing we should do a
number of we don't we should all get
together here I think that there's some
like ship a little bit south of us I
think some researchers got stranded
there and possibly died horrible painful
cold deaths we could all meet there
because I think all the food stores are
there and I think all the liquors there
but we can all get together later
just do a tabletop session and talk
about bro but bro actually decodes a
large amount of data and I automatically
identify DNS data HTTP data HTTP data
TCP connections it slices it dices it is
fantastic and Rita rides on top of bro
also generating noise is important
anytime you're trying to analyze any
network intrusion detection product it
is really really easy to say the product
works whenever it is just watching for
computer systems and one of those
computer systems is making an outbound
connection that's just stupid easy to do
so this is one of the cool tools that we
created and Hills Information Security
it was one of the first things that a
Systems Administrator that I hired Kent
who's now one of our pen testers did
when he joined bh is he came on board
I'm like here's what I want I want a
PowerShell script that pulls down the
alexia top 500 picks a system or a
website and they alexia top 500 and then
serves to that website for five minutes
closes the connection and then opens up
and starts surfing again so it generates
a tremendous amount of white noise
because literally every single system in
this environment is making those
outbound connections like a standard
user would be making those outbound
connections this allows you to see how
well your implant blends in with the
white noise and it also allows you to
kind of get a baseline on how effective
your network intrusion detection system
or your extrusion detection system is at
detecting attacks as well so check it
out now the goals and objectives we
don't want to get lost in the weeds it's
about identifying and understanding very
specific malware samples this would be
malware samples that you want to
recreate in the lab to test a product
this would be malware samples as a red
teamer that you want to generate and see
if its profile is going to be easily
detected by a target organization that
you're doing an assessment on as well
and we really want to start looking that
this is something that should be done
structurally across the board you should
be constantly testing your IDs IPS user
behavioral and entity analytics your
antivirus products as much as you
possibly can and
trying to create that malware zoo will
allow you to develop the skills and the
techniques to fully vet all the security
products that are out there right now so
watching the malware so whenever I'm
running malware on a system I'll be
watching and making sure that it
actually fires off like it'll basically
pop up and let me know yes it is in fact
working
I will also name my malware something
that's easy for me to identify and that
noise this is all part of an effort to
make sure that it's working properly so
in this example I named my malware
beacon DXE because it's a beacon and
then I ran a little PowerShell script
and that's that - nao b5 we're gonna
pull through select string batch the
pattern beacon and then we're gonna kick
it out to a file called beacon txt this
is a quick way for me to be sure that
the beacon is firing and it does not go
down so the Black Hills Information
Security testers they actually hate me a
lot of the testers are constantly
creating malware specimens dropping
malware specimens in the lab or even in
customer networks where we have Rita
setup for them and they basically say go
and try and check this malware as well
so there's lots of custom malware that
they generate all the time there's all a
lot of off-the-shelf malware that they
create as well and you don't have to be
a test or to create malware there's tons
of examples easy things that you can do
in Metasploit and if you go out and get
a tool like cobalt strike it makes it's
super duper simple to create tons of
different command and control profiles
so let's start with Java so Java is kind
of the lead tester for creating malware
at Black Hills information security
constantly creating payloads and
backdoors that other testers are using
and constantly coming up with new
techniques to bypass endpoint security
products that's just kind of jobs gig
right and that would make sense I mean a
guy is an instructor of the Python class
and that's just what he does so he out
of everybody probably has the biggest
vested interest and trying to find a way
to bypass Rita because if any of my
testers are working on an engagement and
Rita's catching them he immediately is
going to get that phone call so Java
ated a backdoor
called mole-rat with the help of a lot
of other testers Egypt and marchello and
Matt to Seine and Dakota all of these
testers got together and kind of created
a backdoor an implant framework that we
use on our engagements and he set up all
kinds of fun things he set up jitter he
set up all kinds of different profiles
for what is the interval for that jitter
and just a really cool tool well here's
the deal if you have an attacker that's
creating super advanced malware it's not
enough just to be able to analyze that
malware based on its interval so if
you're confused as far as what interval
actually means interval is a lot like a
heartbeat so if you have a heartbeat a
heartbeat can be relatively slow or the
heartbeat could be really really fast as
well so we can identify that heartbeat
what is the consistency in the
connections that are coming out bound so
an attacker can actually randomize that
heartbeat and make it a little bit more
difficult for a lot of tools to detect
that interval however if you take the
output of a tool like Rita and you sort
it by the number of connections some
really cool things come about in this
particular example a 24-hour a period of
time Jaffe's back door at a relatively
low score on the interval only had a
point seven nine interval it means it
was not a perfect interval but whenever
you couple that with the connections you
sorted it on the interval and then by
the connections you saw at his back door
had 72 thousand two hundred and forty
three connections that's because that
backdoor was an interactive backdoor
that was being used by the team at that
specific time so you could actually see
he that backdoor you could work with
that backdoor interact with that
backdoor that basically means it had to
be responsive so whenever you start
coupling the overall beacon score with
the number of connections you start
getting increased visibility in finding
a number of different interesting
backdoors so this is Derek's backdoor
Derek banks is another tester Derek went
even further he actually went through
and created a cobalt strike backdoor
that was going through domain fronting
specifically through cloud front so it
went like when the malware goes
runs it fires up it makes a connection
out to cloud from cloud front looks
inside of that HTTP header and inside of
it it says host and then it says here's
the IP address where you should forward
that traffic it's almost like a proxy
for web content and with that proxy for
web content it can make it very
difficult to detect because many
security products will ignore everything
that goes to CD ends they'll ignore
everything that goes to social media
sites like Google or Facebook they'll
just ignore because it's so much traffic
and the odds of it being malicious are
actually pretty low also he added in all
kinds of randomization and also sleep in
this back door as well and yes we could
detect Derek as well once again when you
have that overall score and the number
of connections combined with each other
it gave you the ability to find this
backdoor the other thing that was really
neat and it's not up here is the
dispersion was very even a lot of
backdoors out there today they will
randomize their entry before so say
there's a 10-second interval I want you
to connect outbound plus or minus two
seconds and what you end up with is 50%
of the connections are going to be
between ten and twelve seconds and
you're gonna have 50% of the connections
are gonna be between ten and eight
seconds when you have that flat kind of
background between fifty percent on one
side fifty percent on that I decided
that flat dispersion it means that you
have another backdoor in your
environment so that's pretty cool just
cool way to take the output of a tool
like Rita import it into a spreadsheet
sort it and then find back doors on a
network so lessons learned additional
things that we've discovered one DNS and
NTP generated ton of beaconing noise
when you're setting up your malware Zoo
you may have to go through and find a
way to deal with that traffic in short
you may want to filter that out for
something like a beaconing algorithm but
you still want that analysis to be done
for like let's say subdomains or hosts
on a domain as well domain fronting is
tough to catch really really tough to
catch folks we've got to be careful a
lot of security products aren't doing
really well unfortunately major vendors
are saying oh we're gonna do away with
domain fronting we're just gonna get rid
of that unfortunately we're not seeing
disappear and that's kind of sad so we
can't just hold on to beaconing it's
going to require us to start doing cross
referencing across multiple different
aspects of how malware actually makes a
connection outbound so beacon and
connection count combining those two is
just one example of how we can do that
as well crypto I spent a lot of time in
the past few months doing analysis on
blockchain technology and crypto
currencies I had some contracts to the
Department of Defense and I also wanted
to have conversations where I could sit
down with Beau and Mike and they
wouldn't look at me and say oh aren't
you cute here's your happy meal why
don't you go sit in the corner while we
talk about real stuff so I really don't
ablack chain and cryptocurrency for a
while and we found out in a lot of the
hunt teams that we're doing the malware
that we're actually detecting isn't even
really malware it's actually
cryptocurrency mining usually Manero
running on a system or systems
administrators running multiple systems
running nice hash on thousands of
computer systems so how do you actually
go through to detect those back doors as
well does a beacon well it turns out in
the example of nice hash no it doesn't
it doesn't actually beacon at all once
again we have to move beyond just
looking at beaconing what are some other
attributes for this potential malware
communicating outbound and we can
instead look at it from the perspective
of how long does that connection stay
alive and in this example we had this
backdoor there was was this situation it
was nice ash which wasn't two back doors
just beacon it was just cryptocurrency
mining and instead of beaconing it would
establish a full connection and never
tear that connection down and this is
interesting this is interesting for a
number of reasons this is interesting
because if we go back in time about
eight years ago a lot of malware that
was out there would actually establish
connections keep those connections up
and running the whole time that could be
hours days weeks months years and that's
just how the malware worked then a lot
of security products started getting
really smart about that and identifying
really long-lived connections and then
would alert people on their firewall
rules about
long lived connections so then malware
switched to beaconing it would basically
pulse out an HTTP or an HTTP session now
you're starting to see tools that are
actually detecting that beaconing so now
we're seeing malware and in this
situation crypto miners go back to
establishing long held connections so
the easiest way to bypass beacon
detection just don't beacon it's much
easier that way
so we need to be looking at beaconing
total number of connections some
mathematical attributes all of those
connections and then also looking for
really long connections as well which
once again Rito's free and it does all
of these if you'd like to get some our
Lenny's Elster has a great web page with
a ton of resources where you can
download all kinds of different malware
and I know that this is important for a
lot of you because you may not know how
to create malware Metasploit may freak
you out a little bit and that's fine
just go download now or just do me a
solid favor don't run this on your
production network free pretty please
just don't don't do that
once again this malware zu creating a
malware as we would to test our implants
to test our security products it's not
malware oh my god everything's on fire
everyone run
once again please don't do that we're in
the North Pole things don't burn here I
wanted to finally say thank you very
much I've provided my phone number my
Twitter handle my websites that I'm at
please check it out once again I'm like
a NASCAR driver with all of these
different organizations that I work with
so thanks again everyone stay warm and
don't forget to check out mrs. Claus's
cookies