I start by specifying that I am not the
founder
we started in six as then I did not
have a privileged role in this
priority thing in this thing
said this I introduce myself I am stimulated
everyone I am 31 years old I work in berlin as
machine learning embankments a and I am part
of you square  coalition sedans that brings
code to Italy and yes they are one of the
best future years of ghent that I am going
to present to you tonight you see the
slides organs so much gives me the black screen
and I'm not sure if we
see it see well it's fine then what is it  it is the
prawn shrimp so many things it is a
community it is a site it is a project the
site itself is configured as a
social bookmarking site which is a
complicated word but to say income or
lobsters or even any use of social
bookmarking sites therefore the  the idea is to have the
centrality of the contents
the agent post articles comment you
can give positive and negative votes and
this selects what an over and a
mechanism that I think  many of you
have said on different sites in Italy
it is not particularly popular
certainly there is no other site or
another social bookmarking for IT
in
Italian except for the
view audit substations so in this sense we are
quite new but it is not
clearly the only innovative element
the idea is to have a
participatory and
technically oriented community what does it mean it means that
many Italian
programming communities are often managed in
a very vertical way with a
board that directs the community
according to its own ideas as its own
principles  and basically little feedback
and many poles we wanted to do
something different because a little because we find ourselves a little because there is
a lack of in Italy and
to create a space for discussion that
misses who is the subject of
digital technology as such, tendentially
programming management of
software systems in  all its forms with
more political themes more social reflections  about
how about how about how the software brings
changes in the real world and how then
software pains that bring changes
aligned with our values the
shrimp tag line as you have seen the beginning is
the quality to understand to discuss
understand how technology is not exciting
hurry was a reflection for which
garda wants to bring to the same place
different figures who deal with
these different aspects because
computer scientists too often see themselves as
a pure figure who does not need
to question the reasons why
cara software or values or  the
political perspective from here creates and
leaves too often the
information debate the
non-technical political reflection
we believe that this is problematic
both for computer scientists and for
our society and our small
contribution wanted is this space in
which it led is for example  to discuss
together with computer journalists
people who are in politics
social entrepreneurs  and so on but
maintaining a clear identity of a
site to inform us then you can
find in sequence a post on the best
practices of cuba unitis and a
reflection on how hard sending hubers
destroy local economies
good at legs even open
source software because we like it  and it is a fork of
lobsters loft punta s that was, let's say,
our English-speaking counterpart, in
reality then they are totally politicians
but let's say the partner is almost
unchanged we have added some things
for our use never more or less the
same thing and you can contribute if
you want  add features you can find it
immediately and as the name clearly rai
sends to love stairs August is a we
called shrimp because it was the only
pun we can do with
a crustacean in Italian and initially
this is a goal that a post went
open and  over time we also wanted a
space in which the competition and the various
communities that already exist
many of these are let's say built
with a 90's forum mentality
this simple in which the goal is to
maximize the number of users to make their
own garden and to dominate
these users
we do not believe that
this thing has also led some of
these to survive for several years
in this  situation their goodness
our idea is of total openness
towards existing communities and which
often do not give space to
political dialogue and therefore the idea of bringing
even let's say probable community among
them ok gand started in July a
year ago so a little less  a year old
professor there is someone with the audio
activated and a bit of a cough a year ago
we started shortly we will publish an
analysis post his ep hand we have
collected about 700 users something like
2,200 posts which means seven articles
a day  more or less from overwhelmingly
known coli and let's say a 5
percent 10 percent are
debate user question posts but the bumps are
contained
we have three we support  I found social networks
with basically bots that
publish our content for
the user community for the convenience
of users twitter telegram i mastodons
link to latin slides if you want and they
have become very central to us if we are
in the project as many a lot of the
games we see  it is on these
platforms consequent on the circulation
of contents more than a 10 while on
legs the same so they are an
integral part of the legs experience
we have six active members in managing
the same an infinity of bad jokes
about the domain or not and on the fact that legs
to the paths but forbids them that one thing
I discovered by going abroad is something
that only Italians think because the
changes can walk in front as
you can see on any video on
youtube
but the Italians are convinced that the
song backwards and therefore the  name
find him the king we have been interviewed
by several relatively old sites and
podcasts and pages and various he has  nno
spoken about us is clearly heroes gysi
another not added to the list
and how long how long it takes
then they know how to look if minute for the
game a slight delay in the way
considered okay at the moment
shrimp
we are satisfied a year later
we are  satisfied the project goes on
alone basically we work
a little on the technical field but the
community for the living is different from
what we had imagined
in the sense that a good part of the
users use it to promote
content that I find interesting that
many who  it is perfectly fine that
being a debate space has become
an amplifier of visibility for certain
contents that we do not mind, however, as
an organization team we try to
stimulate more
discussion, which in any case there is on
very specific issues, it became clear
that then in  evening a sentence for
example the whole immune question and I
love it they are always there to
slaughter but clarify  nte there is precisely
a plot in a phase of continuous
stimulus of the debate for example we
regularly organize sessions of
Afghan feng in which we invite guests of the
title of programmer the famous
Italians to political journalists what
we have soon we will announce 1 with
ferdi and b for  who knows that the
cooperative alternative
also likes these very much
if you have proposals or if you think you are
interesting to come back without coming
forward
we are always open to new posts is
another thing that if it has gone a little
worse is that we will resume
the  'idea of creating software
we are all largely programmers
designers systems engineers and we would like that
sooner or later shrimp as a community would
start producing software for
example in the form of a group of
contributions to existing projects or
with new projects
at the moment in my opinion there is no  'is the
critical mass or there are many people but everyone
has a different competence so it is
difficult to form a  core capable
of completing a project there
was a project that started but did not
start and then if a bit my fault which
is called open source crustaceans
the idea is still waiting for them that the time
is ripe and we have made it understood
too much  soon in general we want to
stimulate networking so conceiving
shrimp also as a meeting point between
skills capable of saying something is not
necessarily within shrimp
but perhaps also in their
private sector in their already existing projects
this is what two notes on writing each other
a shrimp shrimp is by invitation only
this is a precise design choice
that we have taken from the stairs because
even if it creates a bit of a barrier to
entry we have seen that it guarantees
an absolute quality of the contents of the
people who enter we have
practically never banned anyone  we
have practically never avoided
deleted post edited a little bit yes
but let's say that they move by themselves
because all the  only
civil discussion and therefore we keep this thing
of screws but they are very easy to
request you can use this
link a link to some
social profile or some type of information is required
that guarantees you are real people
the system of myths is used more than
anything else for  track the people who
make fake accounts
so you can invite users but
if we see that five people say the
same things they give each other a hand in
chaos there may be a doubt
that the videos of the same person
are actually the same being  human behind
the multiple accounts and the others are
our social accounts you can follow us on
each of these the last one clearly and
federated so you can follow us from
any feed and we are immediately subdued
because why yes because it removes
Italian options ok but clearly it works on
mass  it works on though but it works on
any feat
if we acknowledge that you have in mind
this is how many great they are  ssima
presentation goes from 15 minutes later done
very calmly
[Music]
then thank you very much obviously it is a
maximum limit that of news from
this one wins first it is fine the
same salesman inside there is a
moment for questions from the audience
and if  some of the questions to ask if
always left internal or alternatively
to our telegram group or
alternatively one can remove the ultras and
participate directly in the
conference
if there are no questions it is nice we have
enrico who says commented nice idea is
jesus who says rip mastodons  dot com is
more or less connected with the group
behind it but if by chance there is
also a question I will ask you
the system of myths essentially to
make a filter so it is not is not is not
really a limit let's say that all
people who are also chatting
tonight or in the conference tonight
could request an invitation and then
attend well yes let's say
a lightweight filter has gone  but I specify
that it cuts out all those who would
join the community without
really understanding what it is and or for
example all those who write themselves
then maybe ask help
desk questions on the street or better on obstacles that
just like that are not allowed on the
platform  and then it is basically
not a real constraint it takes 30
seconds or they withdraw the invitation is usually we
approve them all almost always
immediately there are
particular criteria apart from these that you have already
said with whom he was a person
invited on one side and on the other
we call  evaluated to sell
no no actually no one is excluded
growing to return platform no
qualifications are needed indeed we are
more diversified the type my mother
written who barely knows there is a
computer but as a support if you want to
write and there is no  it is no constraint to
this thing here it is just used only for
a user experience that makes it clear
that it is a civilized space in some
mode
[Music]
ok then all we do is
invite all the people who follow us
possibly request access
access through this invitation link
then it will be useful they ask us indicating to the
compounds all of the export to germany
they are not the only one they are all  the others
are mainly Italian students
[Music]
on the exception sorry people how many
people there are currently in the
community and of shrimp
are 700 registered and 700 something
let's say active on a monthly basis I would tell you
100 150 the accesses we see the
platform are many more than
bleachers there is the majority the vast
majority of excesses are of
taxon who just want to enjoy the
contents
here it is little they cannot be estimated
also because we want a lot of
analytics so we only have to
access and therefore we have a precise
about 70 80 doing  the accesses are
ok the day that grammer shrimp is also
one of the communities that on force to
project 42 then found  ate the link
galbero also at the bottom of our
page designs 42 obviously there are
news relevant for the future
we invite us to follow shrimp and
we will in any case put simone or in any case then
40 of the team to let us know any
news through our
telegram group which remains active  for
questions even after the end
of our talk
in short I also never one last thing
wait that I was fast
another thing that we wanted to launch
shortly that can be interesting
for you too is a shared calendar of
events in Haiti and that I have  in italy
participated open using
software called hook that maybe you know
developed in italy by a dispute lab
maker space in turin we are there and there is
one thing that is missing in italy there is not a
single place to have visibility and
all  members or online offline that
there is an open space where to
play well and not easily