welcome back to project 42 today is thursday
but it is tuesday because we are recovering
that was we say the episode of
last thursday as a cause but that
we had some problems we
were not able to correctly record the
videos then I can immediately speak to
federico allegretti that  it was scheduled
with a talk on canvas and then to
federico
good evening good evening everyone i am
federico the secrets of terni unfortunately
transmitting the house the line in hyper the
wind
wirelessly last time there was bad weather and
play easy to maintain a stable connection
we hope that today it is peaceful things go
a little better I would say to
immediately start taking a look at the septum of
this talk so let's say so
what we will talk about today is an object-oriented
programming language but very
visual designed for the development of
applications in  very very fast times
it is called gambas three there was a version
of two but it is now discontinued wind but yes
we can talk about can  vas but in practice
it implies an exhausted leg and the
project is maintained by benoit minisini
I don't know let's say surely it should be
pronounced let's say with French languages
but it is not my foreign language dld
of preference so you will forgive me
if for pronounced but the project is
hosted on  sourceforge.net and if we go
to see in fact the gambas cipale site
which is leg
swatch puntonet we find all the news
the girl at the project the various releases
etc. etc. etc.
installation of the project
because you can obviously develop
compile the project from scratch and then
from the source or if you have little time
and you want to immediately go to
that speech will start programming there
are specific instructions for
many distributions in my
specific case reuse ubuntu and for a
boom  east now from any seen 16
04 and then insert the king voice three of the
team  of development tubs leg steam
leg stress and here and do
the update of the clothes and
install the narrow leg that
we will get all the let's say
most 99 percent of the objects needed
to leg to work the central heart
of the leg programming system
if  the idea that you can launch
just looking for a leg on the
command line but obviously the
distribution distribution
the thing changes the souk that
you will eventually get this the main sea or
spa screen of ideas allows us to
do many things but the thing that us
what interests us at this moment
is certainly to create let's go directly
to see how practically we can start
developing then cosina ings we can do
many things in the leg
more or less what is a series of
present that starts you projects and in the
leg those to whom we say  I am more
accustomed to the ones I use most often
these are the graphic applications
then the typical client applications
server in a corporate environment,
therefore interfacing with
database servers or exchanging
information between various programs that
are running on multiple machines
within the same
network,
nothing prevents that an application could have done
a line command lines
do  video games with a present that
is specifically addressed to
the use of sdl books or
web applications I would not go to look at
the web applications because they are
not dropped I never do it I
do not like them for strictly personal and
therefore there are long networks in that from
you people was one of the questions that
was asked in the latest version
someone asked him which web server is
best suited to interface
with gambas in principle he has to develop
a web server also directly inside
gambas but any type of web server in
that  can interface with
applications to escape the news rai
quietly can use a
progr  amma or a canvas application
as a server then as a server of
cda requests and then all in all in
the end to whatever the important thing
is that in the server machine that will follow
the cgia requests and there is the rag time
with the free and to execute code  cabas
let's go and see and now what is
the chorus I start this introductory part
of relative gambas the
graphic applications as you can see that there are
four big buttons between the divas to
graphic applications 2 that
expressly have of who it was and
gt that the version 2 and  version 3 and a
generic graphic the application and one
related to the e gloomy in practice because
because
the distribution distribution the look
and feel that you will get will be
different if you use the gt that the
votes sometimes there are also bugs
or strange behaviors that
occur using the gtk cuticles and
vice versa or that is resolved
using another very rare book
and are normally resolved abba
quickly this can happen if you
use the application as present
and therefore you do not
expressly know first which library you are
using and then sometimes if it does not
work you approve to convert the
project to the other one to see if the
problem is related to the libraries I
normally  qt application development
then we select our
application points we go ahead and we
come to where to save our project
will be the development folder of the project
itself
in practice it shows you your
folder the tree of your disk me and
you put them in the documents folder
or  after mans it is an oversight in the
interface is that in the beginning as
you can see there is nowhere in the south
a button to create a new
folder then in the end with experience
he knows it and just
do a right button  on the folder
where you want to graft the subfolder
of our project which creates a new
pro art  ject we put in here and
go we make the following
project name title the project while more
than the project can also be quite
explanatory and project test for
introna on canvas the project name
instead must be very concise and
cannot contain spaces so I would say
introna gambas  dop exceed but if we
put a space not bad
the leader tells us that in short we
can not use those
special characters let's put it anders shot and it is not
immediately our project
the object we serve a play does
nothing but render a window on the
screen with some properties  let's say by
default
in practice they are all there as if
you have the code associated with this
first object the parent jet of everything
as you can empty because because the
project all application
intrinsically generates as
a base object a forum main man that you see here
on the left of the  leader which is a
generic window so like all
windows at  possibility the possibility
of being resized minimized
maximizes or closed
obviously closing the
main object also sleeps the application
the property most of the ideas
of these owners can indeed
certainly most of these
properties can be modified by the
editor from the  leader and therefore for
example if we want to avoid that this
window can be reserved for dinner
we can do it by
modifying the owner and satiated the ball by
putting it in fox and we see that
our window
at this point can no longer be enlarged
the handles to resize automatically disappear
we could do the window itself
programmatically and for example we can
associate it with the opening event of
this window
what are the events associated with an
object in practice the trick is to
right-click on the object and how you could
see there  is an event menu item that
gives us a list of all events
associated with ours to our project
obviously this list of events
will change based on the object on which
we did use right we
say the open event and we had already
allocated them simply by double
clicking on the window but if we do the
star another  Once this
right button is turned and we go to look for
the event where it is no longer there
because we have removed it but track tv the open there is
a difference in this specific case
we do not care so much in the end both
will be launched and
trigari and  for example we can decide
we have put back the right jabal rendering
we can decide that at the
start phase the last man object no
longer has because in this case the property
is changed to tell it no longer has
the possibility of being resized
so test main in point and  so
we can already see one of the communities
one of the weee communities of the
slightly more advanced ide when we call
one of the objects point we get t  all
the properties related to this object or
that could be the way this
object what we were interested in was
made of ball
so if you are lazy or do
not care what was the property of the
object
you can see it here and then we get
a l  'auto completion of the code and at
this point we put it to maybe it is also
in this case the leader helps
us by giving us feedback on the fact that
we have written well but if we send at
this point as you can see there is no
longer the possibility to modify the
size of the window but
simply because the
inter system subsystem
the gambas interpreter launches the
project launches the program renders
the image at the moment of the
window when this
forum realizes that you want to remove
the confidentiality property and removes it
we can also take this thing a
little nicer for example
we can put a button on ours
on our screen and put it  and a button
here but we love you leave a button
one by one yes and we make another
against the circus antro v9 they are called
button 1 button two it is not
really good practice to leave the names so
in short, of self-generation of the objects
on the screen for  our
specific case is just to have fun
we can also modify it to I want to
make something we do live yes no now
suppose we want to make the
window sensitive when we press yes
against the past
against the group and instead becomes weighs 0
the false when we press  no and instead
we make it not made ball ball at the
start we throw it and as you can
see and at the start it does not make ball if we
think yes
at this point the safe window of
san zeno can be resized with no
we cannot resize the lines
we have already seen  how to make two
or rather three objects
interact with another object that contains them
and what is a pretty nice thing
obtained with three lines of  the code what
he wants to show to another of the
communities you have seen the button
relating to yes it is called throw 1 if at
this point we wanted to change the
name of the button to make it conform
to the thief and the yen is a boot yes leader
to this  point changes the code
related to the events related to the
button but on one that is now I throw
a yes by changing all the references
to the object so quite comfortable we do not
have to worry about reciprocating
all the references to the button and
we have done things quite
simple times but all in all  in the
end it already knows very very powerful to
make 90 percent of the applications
we work with every day
standard objects that arrive as books
and standards to allocate for the project
so for qt applications there are
buttons lei ball textbox slider tango
button
etcetera etcetera there are
gridview the isthmus we say to ourselves more or less almost
any kind of
visual object  zzatore that interests us that they are
closed by color by date etc. and
container or frame vertical
pane etc.
let's say that slowly with the use
you will surely find out what you
need to do what you need
the timers very useful for making
applications that can
at the same time follow more
background things and certainly the
most interesting thing about the leg if the rich
supply of objects or components that
can allow you to do many many
other things one word I would like to show you
from time to time the possibility of
having a library related to the  '
database access and at this point the database
can be different then but be
but they are those post secular bbc
and if we ever put sql ok the more or
less we have calls to
ham the functions related to the
use of corn sequel
if we only put bim  and sql
automatically he who will also put
the art library for karja action
and at this point if we go to  see the
components
ebi non s heart here it is and he also put the
point of b which is the class it
seems what interests us what I
would like to show you instead is a
quite nice violin game
which is interfacing with istreamer and
therefore with the  dg streamer multimedia library
to show you that really
in a few clicks you can do
even quite complex things that
normally would have required
much more is a lot of code in almost
all programming languages
let's say mainstream an aside
some users had the other
time  asked if there was gambas for
windows
no there is no leg on windows i think you
can compile or try to compile
gambas using the subsystem
i don't remember it's called the one that allows you
to compile linux sources on i
will wear i do not guarantee that it works
natively we are there and you have
seen on the supported platforms on
his outlet that there is no wi  ndows
for the match all in all being
freebsd below maybe there is some
more possibility but my mom senate
on linux is definitely linux of
the reference platform
we put the related objects to
register and then in fact
a milia stage appeared which down at the bottom where
there is a media object the more we try to
make a small application with media
more then for example we can put
a button to open a content to
play seeds for itself
forgive me the gate these other
projects
for this example we do not need and
we also remove them from here and media view
allows us to do quite
nice things as you saw when I
pressed media below and
a little something appeared in practice a kind of
online help that allows us to have
a small description of what it
is  the object we are raving about and here
says this class implements a small
media a simple media player
control or in its controls  but let's see more in
practice for example if one of the
properties of the medieval subject rl and if
we here select a video for
example and launch the project
automatically he loads the
project the video in question which was
simply a screen capture of
some of some time  ago
as you can see there are all the
typical controls of a media
player and therefore the possibility to go
back and forth to pause or
stop the movie and to change the audio of
ways to modify the audio volume
these properties are  editable also
at runtime for example this button 2
we can click and say that
mary a bio 1 point
on the point
the idea was to send it to full
screen
I do not think there is instead no there is no
moncia there is not or at least not  I
remember it well
let's make it botton two we transform it into
an open file file I call it the property
ask the user to click on an
open file button to select the
video to play
then we associate to the click of botton two
it tells it we make a
string path variable then we say that the
path path is the same dialog
dialog and a native object
of the interpreter open file file and that's it
and then we make it as
beautiful as gradually a point
l the same path  if we launch
the application it no longer goes into play that is it
does not immediately load the
content by itself but if they call you in the file it
gives us the possibility to choose where to
go to look for our content and
as you can see you do nothing because
because in reality I was  it returns you if
there was an error then night was born
to ok ok and there are some errors
let's see another of the
interesting features of the VAT
or the possibility of
debugging then let's put f9 of the bo
of the stop birch  and let's see what
happens during the tape the execution
of the program let's blaine let's press and
we are already here path is empty ok so it
is quite compatible with the fact  or
that we have allocated the variable as
soon as we are choosing one of
a movie we select it and at this
point we go to see what it is
error path
did not open it
we pass bug patrons it has traveled
so at least we have the other point of
path is still empty to true sorry
because it is wrong so you wrote wrong
precisely because the
dialogue ben file function does not return
the apat of the file but establishes if it is
too much perhaps it has been opened or closed at
this point instead we have to ask and
put in the  variable path your
own from the dialog's pub and now if
we go to see in fact
at this point there is still nothing
but dialogue point hit the right path
we go on the path
actually this there was no
error so path is the right one and
we put it in the media property of 1
point rl and at this point we have the
media player ready to
reproduce our contribution which is
black however the audio is heard and we choose
another if at this point we want to
remove all these watchmen was
watch and go with them always
phenomena we remove them we take this
ocher we look for section and as you can
see we have a peaceful one we will have to
bring this we have made a
small  a small media player
we have seen how to put the watched
stop watchers to
debug our code online
we have seen how to load a few
objects to do some
more nice jobs and I would say that maybe
I don't know if we
have arrived we have  time is over or not I don't
realize yes we have reached the
time limit we are fine in the sense
that then these productions and we do
simply to give inspiration
to people so I think that if a
person wants to deepen he goes to
look for things  in a way but then someone if
you want to
close with those two questions that
were asked by users for
a  rriva all'asl at sea life lab that
comic lazarus pascal and that how
the code is distributed then fast of the
thief spa scale number I know so
I can not tell you if better or worse than
gambas would certainly not make an
answer not a date as
regards  the distribution of the
code of your application then you can
simply create the executable of
your project and distribute this
intro leg cue gambas however this
means that in the other machine where
you will run this application there
must be at least the drian
low runtime and the libraries that  you have
used
or you can create an
installation package and the installation package the
installation package utility
allows you to create a
package containing everything you need
to deploy your
application on the machine or
machines of your
partners of your customers  your
friends can choose license there is the
possibility  lity seems to me
I almost never even there indicate
which distribution you are
going to put to distribute
the application in this way let's say it
makes the application more compatible
from distribution to distribution
it seems to me that we have said everything thank you very
much  if you want to give references on
how the penalty hit anyway on your
look of reference linux user group and
linux user group of terni and my email
I attach faith gmail.com and in any case they
can also be reached on display and where I have
most of my projects  which
are often developed on skilled efforts
and for example one is this or 20v
architecture which serves precisely to
manage a multichannel multiplex of
television with a single client for
the insertion of contents and the
management of the various channels is a
similar thing area and  related instead to the
world of radio always on his
effort so if you are looking for me on his
effort or look for how tv architecture
developed by hig  h end trader strange and
here you will find everything and my
my my applications and you can
contact me safely then
thank you very much for your availability and
for sharing your experience with us
thank you thank you for
the hospitality