ok then I wanted to do the pilot of
starting to tell you exactly what it is and what
sense does it still have now to maintain the
community especially on telegram of
gicos italia starting from my story
of where I come from and why I started
giving linux and that it turned around done for
getting to need this community
practically since 2000 and I
always started using the nous 2000 and I knew
almost nothing so I had a hard time
installing any distribution
because not knowing even the
technical terms and especially in a vill
internet is a task of sight  between read
all or it is difficult to be able to
install linux
in 2006 an ubuntu distribution arrived
that comes from
automobiles for the installation and
then finally I can do an
installation in a very short time to buy
than that computer licola in
an hour  left washes linux and i had the
feeling now or linux so i
'm okay and i'm not going to move to
other distribuz  ions because ubuntu
quickly made me install so it is
stable then time I started
wanting to learn some music some
graphics some software are not up to
date and so I need
libreoffice
at the time there was still open office more
updated
I need to have the latest version of
mozilla firefox is instead free and the
older one to derubricare and on walls
towards ubuntu shores you put links to
sardines launch pads that have the
possibility of having more updated software and
the thing I noticed is  that
having 30 and serving a year teams all
behind the list of repositories between
them were in conflict with the
libraries and therefore every tot type the mega
for mere six months and began to
grow a bit everything and there is and
we should never format the  fifth at 0
so I did not have a way of being able to
have a stable system to say from
now on in the lighthouse because in the space of six
months
I was more or less able to get back on my
feet the person I had before  then for
some reason unknown to me it grew
because I want to try a newer thing
I can't go back
because that to a newer party I
can't bring the clean package to the side it
grows me to the whole system
formed and reinstalls so the
alternatives are  been in the last few years
and those to try to move suisse
ubuntu because xfce seemed to
mess up if less ok I was missing
something but I tried to move to kde
neon and also I was missing something that
belongs to a was much more and is
still in development  e was stuck
boasted and about many things
then five years ago more or less I was
returning to youtube a tool which I had
already configured as I was interested contact me
via internet  itas a lot I want more
in a group I bring us was born deals
with the technical information of this
distribution so I care years ago but
you have installed it I would have done f  at the
end of the day
I didn't even have to be installed yet and
I miss it pupils the cascin on dropbox
so I had under the sub a tumor in
my mind above the new thomas indro box and I
did it for three months that I gave her assistance to the
group of people who came in to do the
installation  going into dropbox
then certain point I said is the system
is growing me because mine for three I
can't understand why I can't go
to the ubuntu desktop
but if I'm inside my dropbox
with and open susa is working for me
then what did I do  I said one day
format and I put the system directly
the laptop nothing from that day I
have no longer formatted importable because
over five years and I am left with the laptop
with the versions of these people per
day
and this made me understand that ok is a
solution  solid distribution is a
coherent distribution then we will also see what
the camcorder coffin tends to for coherence of the distribution
the interesting thing is that in the group
that abb  we decided to create on telegram
at the beginning it was thought only
these users enter we give them
basic information to make installations which now
finished the installation these will be
users who can by themselves maybe
come out of the wolf
and arranging for cabbage them instead the
thing that has us  left a little amazed is
that the telegram group enters in
that the minimal information to do
the installation when it has installed does not
leave the group because it has not only had
the information from there the administrators
can not from and in the sense that lately
there is  and 23 guys who have had
experiences on video cards with buoys
those who are on import africa in
italy is an nvidia inside and one
even broke the boxes and
compiled some software that was then
put on an official software that
it is called suse prime and then exits does the
switch of the video card and from in Italy
to the media without having to restart the
computer
so being the expert of those
cards when in the tram user that to
those needs at pleasure to
answer him and give him all the
support possible so what I
have had feedback from users
who enter is that it is not a community
as I have heard many say at the moment
in the forum or  in the ubuntu charts
where there are more than a thousand people as soon as
I ask a question that is burnt for them
the fund loved that reading
these pages on the internet but sorry because
cyclical and second that are trivial and for
us instead there is nothing trivial
because there is what he sells from windows
so he has no experience
asking us what a terminal there is what
he comes from so the
similarities between what he did with
ubuntu and what he would like to do here so
some codes can say yes the  do it in
this other way some other we are not
going to do them because here it is not expected or
to do it and so there is a
completely different solution dictionary
the community is just the fact that a
pe  riodo that it was like Trevisi not even
that many users entered inside
I started to tell everyone
please don't do the [ __ ]
spread around that we want to
let users in because I don't care about
the number and there is a talk we said
you  that you are interested in having an
adequate number of people who enter c
from b that is, it is not mandatory that
we have what Milan and the users in
rather in this period that does not see
people we try to structure ourselves to
say
which is a standard that we can thus
give  the basic user who enters wants to
try open susa is the thing that now
I will show you three very simple things the
basis that this distribution that
distinguishes it from all the
others which makes it solid in the sense that it is
impossible to clear it to
bomb it having to say  I have to format because
there is always a way to go back and
restore everything even without
internet access and even without access to the
graphical interface
then the first thing to say is that for
those who are expert in linux
the first thing that one of the first things
that fear us when it is installed
asks which is the filesystem to
install open on visa proposes by
default and tr flash which is a  file
system
in the other distributions little
used and a default link vtr
parties of open susa plus another
related technology which are the gis shot
and it works in this way
today a day two seconds before
updating the system the
operating system alone is technique  notice it
creates a slapshot there is a save
the whole system and puts it in the list
in the grab at startup in order of date
and when the update is finished I
restarted if the restart is decreed
created successful in auto brand mini I
did a  another step to close
the update grateful to mourinho and the
actions are the difference between
the installation first installation after
let's say launched very quickly
and the interesting thing  is that it can
happen that one makes a mistake and maybe you
download the dredging of the owner
of the nvidia card model different
from his puts it on and because maybe
he didn't know he had gt because maybe
because I know that heck model a and
installing naba you install smith and on the
carnet  when the system starts
the driver preceding the video card has been elevated and it
is tried to start the
tv card drivers or wrong say by
having wrong for the video card
so users is on foot
then in this case here is the
possibility to go to the grab video the
next previous I go back
thirty seconds and I am already in the
precise version of having done the update
and or the usual my problem
another thing that you did see and
heavy vico ii last then in
hockey on da  there is a panel
called the
administrator lipid hosts towards this
panel it is next to here on my right
I put a magnifying glass to
let you see
certainly give the entries because you can't
read them all and I find it interesting
that this panel has everything you
need to set the operating system
from safety how many snap shots
I want to keep if maybe or small disk
and then I want to keep 5 is the sixth
delete everything  and how to set up the
repositories how to set up things or
more specifics for systems engineers like auto
yast me with figures a pc as god
commands then i go to introduce the
auspices cover them posted clips of this
pc and replicate them for all pc that
will have installed here susa  as a client
and they will already have all the settings whose
list is the season plus
software configurations installed but the software
already does the outlast system so I do
n't know clone the one of the re disk row
or do many installations and pass out
to reinstall everything now stalled
his done I wrote it marina of
what I had to install so
everything is already set here the other thing that
is  revolutionary on or for the success of
pro apposta firefox
here is one thing that is interesting
we see to users who enter
into open susa and do not find your
program
ok because when I installed for the
south with the cai you only have the repositories of
defaults that contain
free software not proprietary and
leading software out there the packages
of the repositories the leaves are few and
are not specific for the music of the
graphics for which for education
the educational now I write that arises
search
her
download or for sud and opensuse search
here it is then there is something
that is revolutionary called but no
this is the meaning of the home page id
opensuse build service
here it is this here that is open susa to
a mega server called ubs and  it is not
a bit bs studio it is open build service
inside all the users of
obe susa and also the developers
can create their 3 place and comes
for example there
is no what is spotify i create the
spotify package for open susa but the beauty is that you
create the package by saying this is the
source guitar
and I link it to this server the
best place there the compilation of the
package is done by the server and checks he
never said he wants to make people laugh
compatible with this program for the
current version that is 15 1
the version that will arrive in July there is the
here says between two then there is I will play
healing create the tabloid it is also
the limit ok putting the flags in the
right places and the serves  does the check and me
and himself the package is compatible and ideas
to all the dependencies for the three verse
liter chosen if
the package is usable what
I write spotify
from I try
not to see ok cohabits places all the
servers that have spotify inside for
example
wikimedia up spotify deezer and pm
what I gave for the installation and
then from here 8 nov to see the server
in server stalls that is by clicking on the
server that is a technology called
on  and click that automatically opens the
list of repositories puts
inside itself the deposit we have chosen knows
which program to install it
refreshes the list of repositories and the
programs that are inside them and
installs the program and therefore the
system and  the package is self installed on the web
and it was fantastic these
weight packages destiny in various
deposits can be present in more than one
cost so the only a little
studied something called priority and for
whom a brochure was there and there is
there should still be pinging
and because I am like you possible by
giving the right priorities alien then
falconer I can say take a package from
that repository rather than another
so if I know that the packages are
older in the system
I have put in repository of  multimedia
because it will give me the newest packages of the
hour priority to a p mib so that it
will come to take the buffs from the last and
not from the oldest ones that are inside
the repositories  ry standard and all this
works I am amazed that other
systems have not copied this
technology because all opel so it
can do very well from
that other institutions could
apply the same technology and we would not
get angry and then to say it all
his and many people do not know  opensuse
but it is new in reality it is not new
because the open suda derives from a
situation that would now come to
mind the name but I have an
interested image I download immediately and vera pulled
out one of the first distributions in the
assumption that was created
between now  it is the water drain a moment
that I find it immediately here it is then
I save
on the oviesse ok then here I close on the abs
I will have the limbs trips on the fa here I open the
full screen
ok and you see them a little better here it is
the guard
the name excuse me  then the lawsuit but
of the very first distributions
ever is the fleeting still works
still maintained I still think by
only one developer so it is a  bit slow
in development
the interesting thing is that here you see
suse susa ignorant
from here
take opensuse but I guarantee you that in
July they merge the two kings placed
the suse ok merged for one thing that
now makeshift of the last three minutes
we have noticed that many  users a little
savvy at a corporate level also
tried for susa because I wanted to understand
if it could go well as needed at
a company level it is fine in the end
when I have made the figurations if
we want to pass people with
the assistance then open susa and the
free one without  susa assistance and from
assistance you can pay depending on the
type of assistance you want
nicotra suffered 4 pay more
working hours pay less they had to
format the server and reinstall and
with the face that contained the
susa repositories because they were in a bit different as it
was and  repository formations instead of the
change they will make of 15 number 15 23
then tris of the good from the same source
so just cam  name the king
removed from within the operating system already
installed make a crest of
the port list ii and maybe launch a
stop of time to see if any
package
to update or to go back
with respect to the version entrusted because
the versions rendered by the e  obviously it
could be a bit more conservative
and in any case it does not format before
this is the nice thing the thing I
like that people have entered
saying that this reason what I
say to myself I do not install it I think I
have no intention of saving it but I hear
about  in this group
ivo seems like the fan boy of open susa
who seems to be the top the stem I know
why when something likes there is
something I struggle sebastiano he
likes land summer camp so much and therefore it is obvious that
if you vary with him often  is you think at that
time that they are how we will do it
and we will do it we will physically do it to
him he would do it ue reduced and it is right
that he talks about it because it is what he
is at  heart talks about it and so i'm done
too i was gave her that she enters because she
wants to understand the dynamics how to then
maybe live that sucks
ok I ended up predicting that sucks he says a
lot that this is version of yoox and very
cool and that in the group we are all
curly  and then you go inside we slaughter each other
and when a user manages to
make the system work you throw him
out because you don't want to give
assistance it has never happened in fact it has never
happened to people who at the beginning like
me went machine and  after i did i
find them a computer is stalled because i
think it has an added value having
said that i ran out of minutes and 30
seconds more that i wanted to say
at the end
this evening is an evening that i
thought on purpose forerunner because why
life the  amazing anticipation as I
said that there is or bs you need and you
can create them there ad hoc
for certain
needs of the users of my group
musicians have decided to create a
deposit for themselves  c to put
musical stops in it
not only also to put in all
those facilities that allows you to
create open sweats for the authors of the
configuration of the whole system to
make music
because whoever tried it took more to
install jack then I had to
configure it in a certain  so look at
the legacy guides of the logs because if you do not
set it it does not work instead the
settings here are all
preconfigured install and pre-
configured by and by all
working
so next week
the super mega technicians will arrive who will shoot me
[ __ ] because elected [ __ ] today and
therefore city network also the
digital sector as it was as it is going
a thank you very much in a put to bed
because sometimes interesting so
we hope precisely that being at the
production center then they will still be
followed as we said related to the
other sub-project and your
community and  after they are already as they
are said the time of the questions so
we have a  Still time until 9.30pm
if anyone has any questions to ask there
was one in chat which is rarely asked a
question but from the observation on the
pronunciation on susa you operate susa
then if you want I can show you if a
video of a programmer who  he said
that it is strange to read open susa but
for example so much for the moon she is a girl
who is never really narrated who is
part of the open susa board that racca
president of libreoffice will be called
libreoffice italia now she is inside herself
inside dom fondation is everywhere  it is a serious
ramiro to have a bow she lightly
for suse and here she says you cannot read it
as it wants to be law so because I
have to contradict for the super mega of the
bosses
we have to celebrate but here you have
done me good
hatching in our group they gave the phone
clean well  three or four people who
are physically salaried and work
for Suse run away as programmers and
therefore are really technicians and
civilians but often going to write the
barzi  lla we have problems because
that is cells as we keep them for
us does not work the [ __ ] he all
institutions should work in
this way not only ours because
so grow your
distribution do it there for your
education
well then there  there are other questions you can
ask them as usual in our
telegram group as well those in chat or by
removing my inside by selling
directly in the conference
otherwise I would ask you arrival anyway
if you have references to leave
regarding this however to the
community then yes I give you the references
immediately large protal mask I give you
the link of the telegram then where
did it go michele grant elena ok
lg play whole under which I do not open so
I change little here it is then our
community is this here u sonata finish
the couple
then
from here I would have for practice  lippi
the entry to the rebel group graham then
we also have a page on others view
but if v  enite and that the formal documents
for the installation what we say that
after installing you have to follow the
guides that have been revised
we wrote and above all that you lost
a finger the guide tell me where you are lost
why do you want to live the guide because you
are always  the same way that she cannot
understand and I will have to we should not rewrite
the guides
the patient let's say that for those who have not
read the chat she looks for on telegram operis
usa and italy just that others are
all there because among other things those books and
a little  old and we have to keep it but
know that the Susa brand is a
registered trademark and therefore it could not be
used we would have had to use
gicos gallizio varia di they knew a
little too late so since a moment
ago on the international telegram channel
they have in its links
some national groups  let's say they
put our golf open purr opes usa
and then i said then we are so
for mixed g spot free org if this
see sorry arr  ivo how to put it
only we are main is the thing is and
what does not link to the links to the hatay the big ones
there
is also that because you could not see
only ok
I have to do so then I ask but it's ok
here you see it can read
here it is yes  no
who is the bellini and milito is
susa italy wins now if here on the
second page I do then we see
the right page is brought back or those on
facebook we also have a
better facebook channel forward to use it
ok this is altervista g so among
others life  org point
here it is some this you
spin you
the party meetings this here is our
single seat my name is the installation handouts
[Music]
and like a blog ok it's not much more
you have to install it comes in place of for the
proprietary codecs ok c  'is the explanation
of how to do it
you want to know how envy
is it seems to me that having put
the suction then let's say on its users
who have found problems have
drawn the android solution write
to the int  erno del
we take off the permissions I
do do is not a big deal
to him