so hi everyone then let's talk about
gildo and here we have in this interview
two of the maintainers of this project is
the first thing I ask the two
markers this project to introduce you
then introduce you tell me that you are
on the side there are yes giordano
groves i am the one  that then go he
created jackass italia ex precious italy
and and nothing kneads then after we get
with
fabio speeches hi I am really penseri and
I joined a little later but for a
mother let's say to keep the packages is
equal to stuff for the presentation it will be
very fast very good then and how many
of you explain or together do you see
what the leave project is then
first of all how it started started
that basically it was needed by me that is
I am an admirer of hope and it is used
as a distribution because I consider it a
work  est a professional workstation
of a good level that has also allowed me to
work even in companies with
Barilani so I needed de  the
audio packages and then I started to create
this repositories where to insert what
I needed because let's say nobody had
yet approached audio talk about
this on this distribution
until one day let's say I began to
see that the packages were many
and could become a project then
I met  fabius who also had the
same needs just an
electronic gram and then nothing
quite
naturally began to populate has become
a real project that involves
practically bringing a professional into
this distribution fabio to add
something
no other than us  however we find to
collaborate as much as possible with up
steam
we also have contacts with those who
keep high and disc of a musical nature
so basically we feel well
integrated into the ecosystem if we
want free software of gnu linux it is said
what concerns the antiquated audio world
then  a clarification because maybe
who n  Someone from the music world and I
heard you say from those who do not know what it is
boh remains a bit confused here who of you
do has explained what it is but
basically I give digital audio
workstation so any computer
can also be an art now  a computer
anything that used to manage
the audio in a complete way
basically ok another question is in the
group there are roles on role formats if
they are formed how
these roles were formed but they are formed and at the
end it is quite natural because if
first if the needs because I want to
reiterate that we basically use
all these software because we are
musicians and therefore everything comes from there I
am more towards metal rock is a genre
more let's say analogical let's say analogous
basic while fabius and more on digital
so in the end we  we compensate and by that
many companies regarding licenses because
he is much more inclined than me and towards
licenses and various things so you all
something fabio no no conf  ermo what
I said george and they are quite
natural and also constant roles that the
[ __ ] that is not here because it is right
so always spread them that for the
language you should
n't have a hand in creating parking spaces and
maintaining those that are there  already therefore
basically our
teamwork is also very independent to
say state
we work independently we
coordinate on some things more we say
yes then he in the specific case manages
tumbleweed that another version of
precious which is a rolling since he
also uses he plays  and uses tumbleweed
he manages that thing that if we
officially support the lipke is the
version we say stable
so if you want one can also use a
tumbleweed that we can
manage thanks to him then you
have talked about packaging oh well
I know it is xvi for me  taken for granted, however, I think
it is right to explain how packaging works
in general in the south which
is very different from other s  systems
let's say yes user uses let's say you can
do everything via the web
in the case of fabio you also use the
specific tool to make backups in case
of disasters you never know
practically it is a bit particular because
compared to others practically a cloud
therefore inside c  'it is precisely the
distribution then all the
updated packages of the distribution are
loaded the sources that are
packaged year are already known
then guided Italian saying over
the current version of the
operating system that a nationalized so it is
a bit like doing
practically a complication stain
like  if you compile it on the machine
you are physically using then
this is the advantage of that easy
management coordination possibility of
coordinating upstream chosen means
made a package send it directly
to the managers of the main repositories which
site they accept becomes part of the
distribution officially because
we  also like to work  and in this
way it is not that we want to keep
everything to ourselves or do the
open source philosophy and this too, in short,
then the soldier maybe
a given information that is what you do
explained is ubs that is not oviesse studio
is or not  if a service instead and it would be
a web service you skipped
it and the fact that the service is
called ubs are people do not understand
how you do everything by claudio there is
only this if in the end it is simply
the graphical interface  simply
so to speak
because then there is a whole ecosystem of
euros in which you manage as I said now
I have done well to reiterate it because
then let's say that if the users who
are here or those who will watch the
video are trying to understand
something  they should have guessed that it is
a repository so they should first
install one of the two versions
we said of open closed open suse
I experienced how we want to call it
always the same and then they should
a  add commissioner place more then
that 6 3 the bad game now I can
take we have searched thanks to
some offensive features of the
one click bucket which is nothing more than
an xml that is recognized by the
system
this is a little technical can click
on  the one click image or the link
is automatically installed in
our case a package that will then
carry around the whole basic system to
make a professional workstation already
configured after the first reboot that is,
just go to our site which is there
automatically  installed denis repository
exploded the package is installed
all the software even
preconfigured and we wish the basic one
of two rosters and therefore the famous dr
because therefore at the first start or already
working I do not have to go there to get my
hands to write some pharma
secretly this is the  what is
important enough to show
why I could get any
debian based distribution and ok
mentor stopping place lips studio then
after they love I have to go and see all
the guides layer work and configure
lard do it I'm not active in
two minutes three minutes the time we
say there is to configure problems
on the memory limits for real
time
you know  what basic things to configure
linux that on our distribution with
our place is the system that
allows us to have open if we have
everything configured in the restart in this
case forced a little to the windows but
unfortunately it is needed because in any case
the kernel is also configured at  I start
for a real time use to unlock
the memory and then still have
the audio now in real time
ok the questions to the one you have already
answered a bit but in any case I do it
anyway because every musician or a
producer should choose this
system to
do  music in a classic
windows or mac system
the key word I think is
the reliability that this is not that
other distributions do not  n are reliable
but let's say that open suse particularly
stino will have to be a workstation
so we are talking about the lim no
of the tumbleweed that more from geeks
so not the rolling version is
practically based on suse enterprise that
have merged with complexes so it has become
the  ip written the apps so
practically it is a completely
reliable code used regularly even
for work or even at high levels by
systems engineers and now you can build a
bit of anything then it depends on the
projects that are basic however you
can use music  it is not like
other distributions that have focused
on music and struggle maybe they have
high de carneri in particularly
heavy configurations you can use it
anyway as a
professional workstation then in the evening
you can play your music quietly if it is
imported in a fixed it is relevant and
therefore  it is reliability in first of
all is three years now will come out the
new version of the 15.2 opens  to three
years of support with the various service packs
as it was the enterprise so for three
years you have the guarantee of less an
ultra stable system to make music
so if a recording exhibition
even x lam studio wanting there is not
so this is the main reason
fabio then to add something we
could talk about the
flexibility that a system
like ours offers as in general what we
find in the world of free software
because sometimes
we therefore say a little bit of evil
looking with admiration of software
owners who do these do
those have been life these are
felt that we do not stop to
reflect on what we have at
our disposal is a whole series of a
world of software experiments related to the
field of sound design
the pole dc sound paolo di più d '  age
I speak of supercollider excellent also for
everything with the sc I thought control
all this world it is very difficult to
access this world when it is not
full control of the first machine
so basically here are all the
historical musicians and sound designers who
are listening to this talk
surely there is a place for you too
using this time
then we can do the
unprecedented parallels for those who perhaps know
softer and more  blazoned for a fee
as digital audio nation and maybe the
user software or
guitar software and say if there is something
parallel to our distribution or if
the food or if there is no parallelism
lyon necessarily went to him you have to
forget everything you did
before  from here you have to work in a
completely different way
before my field which is more guitar and
other types of sounds so not
electronic the answer a bit in the middle
in the sense that it is difficult to make a
parallel between the software and then there is a
way to work  that it is a little different
this does not mean that you have to
forget everything let's say that if love
exists in a different way p  lugin they
do similar things but have another kind
of
approach the example approach is closed windows and
mac is a little different and always
on fetching better we let cracks
do another thing still
fetch so what's what  it is the
best that I heard those who use
that of j
here one has to forget that
approach to enter the conception of
professional music as a
producer would do wrong product sees the
dj todt state such who uses listen and there is
a lot of stuff  really good and
professional and linux
but you have to timi didn't know how to listen
this is perhaps the only difficulty that there
may be because anyway you don't have it is not
used by everyone yes on linux still
music on linux still you have to hope
but there are some absurd software  like
someone who mentioned to me a few days ago
fabio about the guitar because I was
complaining a little bit about the lack of
guitar software, that is, I act on the
amplifiers and nutrients  one hardware
we found this low profile which
is practically a camper of the poor but
then it is not of the poor in reality because it
works very well I have
profiled sounds that this on the hardware and it is
practically the
same spit the response is excellent
dynamics even it can regulate the
voltages  of the finals for those who are
guitarists maybe for those who are not
anyway good stuff is done from here
shortly I will make profiles to put on
our repositories of various
mesa fender amplifiers
the ua that what it is so that
one downloads the excess profile  of that
amplifier which is practically like
having a camper via software
so the possibilities are actually there
that we will need to momentarily and what we
try to do is to inform people
so because we have done it the site
we have about makes it easy to access
we have a  support channel but we
also have the support channel of gex
italia so on the difficulty of
installing dal to this is imp  ortante
because many distributions maybe have
the forum
but then afterwards they give you answers if
we have as many as 200 users in
the main channel so there is a
difficulty here distribution problems
there are no problems then there are always us
one never arrives we
take and compile immediately  on the
repositories that is we are many activities
on listening just what you need
even for people who want to play
I want not to go through the
technicalities to do it we have
main software for the creation of I don't know a
piece of music as if we were in the studio it
depends on the genre however  if there are
we are finally managing and
configuring and packages giving as
digital audio main workstation is
that we have a brand new
version the know all version compiled even with
all the rivals workaround of the case
because in any case maybe the
mp3 exports to and not all
distributions do  but we also take care of
these details because we care about ch  and
everything must be working because equal
to the person says but because it is not sport
mp3 we are not taking and throwing
the software over but we try to
bring them to the beginning of mass 2 produces
time music even joe you have done
whole with this system
if  if you can do everything and therefore already the
matter is when you put on hardware
you have seen all the pages having to put
up to make it 100
% operational it does not help it does we
also did a brainstorming storming right
in the group look for a soul of the  users
even who helped us this
we got the tiziano we understood
what the main problem is
we made peace that is so we are
active from this point of view
so the software inside is
still tested and working
perfectly by us  it is certain that if the
trans from a new person excess that I
aim the big shot within six months to
get to produce the first song if
this starts  every day to report
I don't know how to do this he never makes a mistake
I don't know how to do this other loves found a way
of working his own but there is no peace
we make it to him we
collaborate with these people because
they would improve the mac system and
we send it to  that country
you are absolutely not is vast
and your way
hello and the pil to jean both us is useful
for the project just this thing
because maybe you ask inside we are
more experienced so many things solve them
a little on the fly and you always make
everything work  practice to the person so it is up
to me not to work then maybe create a
custom program that clears up
something that is we try to
improve even for the average user that is the
one there that I know from windows
there is not there to tinker but that
however  let's try to be as easy as
possible one has to arrive sonal
basically that then have
mother if you want a little bit if the audio works just a little
bit to be
told  I wonder minutes then discovered a
type of audio yes yes
[Music]
tell me the battle is made with various
programs for linux
from there the car comes or not no for the
drums actually I did a trick
but why the  I give that is me in the
sense of using carla with a
windows plugin and in this case she was
telling me why things even if one is
our group and the no I to bring those
sounds or plug in is forbidden to problems
because we have put  this rack
carla there is little time but we have
also compiled it with the support for
windows vst
I wanted to bring some little things there is
no alternative on the battery yes we
have many epson me who have
particular needs but
if things  then there can also be a
question of reactive for example and
samples clearly do not depend on
the operating system but there are flags in
which, for example, have higher quality
because in which they always have
lower quality this does not depend on how
third appointment to increase the
possibilities
and then what he wants to proceed with the
coma
at this moment of an
electronic song by a user of the fai never
paid in full for some
[Music]
no
we have ten seconds
practically we are finished now of the
romance right questions right
highlighting bands we can do it
very well
or we have all been exhaustive
coloring a question I join in the
chat to say as soon as I answered a
stalled rally for his servant in himself
I put on by abbott or I start from the
iso of tap and the cut for suse and  then
put the repository and as soon as you put them
all you need explodes you will have
minimal already configured from the site it is
very simple as long as you go the
instructions are three steps to do in
a cross one click with firefox and the
whole installation starts and the configuration
will be distributed  in a never explodes
nothing ever goes but the packets when
the view them the area more al and the term
explodes because from  packets packets from
compressed open so that the
term that is used that in question is
the example the salary yes yes but the age of
goa the switch explodes is not true
I ask a question for how long have you been
working professionally with
audino and  since the time of linux I
began to eyebrow the point goes well I
linux I started that it was 98 99
still except for windows
then gradually more and more to linux with the
fact that in any case and more and more
improved until then it is used that it
finally did  of stable
completely linux windows and they have been for
twenty years more or less in the same years
so it has been a parallel path
and then oh well this project
has a clear net and a half but I have
always played regardless
of the project
instead  let's say that I have been using more linux for
about fifteen years they have been more or less for the
same time even if with ups and
downs they are not so much I am a
professional and the music is in a
parish choir and p  On my own then I
really like music and clearly you
do things also experiments
electronic music of this type but let's say
I'm more for the side if we want
software in particular I am interested in
software development and even if I have
never tried my hand at
software development  my audio but now I am
putting a way very often to that
of others so ok I will ask me two
questions one perhaps he did not understand that the
rich one if you are the founder
you play the founder of everything
practically we have the votes co
founder let's say of jacks italia yes
could of checa 2 if practically co
founder of cegos doc which is ok so
this is what then there is another question
from anonymous anonymous guest in the 80s
with a friend using a software I
don't remember the name it allowed me to
sample record  a sound for
example a sneeze meow anyway
short clips and then being able to recreate a
stock of musical score by associating
remote the sampled sound there is also  and
this possibility
go fabius yes yes there is this possibility
the software used by our friend
babil put a tracker ok and there are
several and even more modern ones therefore
that do not use
the bitmap type interface some use
the interface is  more modern for example
I make a Turkish name that uses
averages then using this
tool but there are others like milk i
tracker that precisely allows you to do
this in a much more apologetic way
so basically almost a
sampling function that is
clearly part of the fire  and here
there are some of tucker, indeed we also have
some that can be used on the command line and
not only this I would like to add that
a particular attention to try
to have software also use
blind people within the
group
so it is something that you are  building
slowly with too much we have many
users and who are able to test
this thing firsthand and we
ch  obviously we don't have this
possibility but there is still a cure
an idea of having this software so
we hope that in the future game store will be
easy to use even for the teeth not to
see well then me or rai
with a big thanks to giordano and fabio
for  have been here with us
tonight to share their
experience on then for the chance
thank you all from my heart