I was born as a technician but having
a certainty I got a bit bored the
technology is too complex and the
kitchen is usually found in people
happier than technology
so I will show you something that
comes from my Apulian destination because
precisely by staying in pavia it is  a trio 3 place
in the province of Milan even if
they don't know it from Prato where they only know how to make
clear soup that this group is
credible and the heavenly cake that is
heavenly by little so from my
Apulian side comes with the
sugary mangone that is this  what you
need here a pot pan better if made
of aluminum because you need to be
quick to heat up and cool down
this is what I use I put it
over spam
the diameter will be 25 or 28 cm with
these it can do up to half a kilo
normally when  I was a little less
experienced there is a maximum of 100 grams
at a time
ingredients almonds these are three
ounces dry two duets of almonds and one
ounce of sugar in this  ta photo with
sugar there is no sugar you can see it
here behind a spoon so they are about
25 grams budget I don't like the
complication simple business I like
the twine so these are three
ounces of dried fruit and sugar priests
with a drop  of water as you can see
the water is low
when it seems to me too little in the
most methods and bonivento reminds me a little of
my Mantuan meta how I make the
sauce I boil the grapes for about 10 20
minutes but some say put half the grapes  and
half water and boil for four hours
the only gun if you add the water has to
wait for it to dry and it doesn't make much
sense
so in this case we have 2 teas of
almonds and a pound of beach the show is
even if it is not with  cher because if you
speak an Apulian of fireflies
everyone looks badly it seems to me that a
percentage is the right one so with
this situation we find ourselves
lighting a fire and this thing boils well it
makes a kind of infernal marble be
careful that the temperat  ura of this
object is well above the temperature
of the stadium.I use in fact with the pan
and a little oil or if you want to open the
sugar you can detach all the
components from the marley plates in one
go.The problem is that you have to rent
an apartment first to  then make area
that week so that the
stench passes anyway this manga in braking
very high temperature bubbles and and bubbles
again and bubbles slowly the foam
becomes clearer and
denser up to this situation here in
which it is probably the right situation
to make  see this thing here so
what happens I also hear
the audio you probably don't have
this situation of an infernal marble
that boils at absurd temperatures until
it gradually becomes more and more solid
and at this point we need to
start mixing in this
situation must be removed from the heat
with the whole because otherwise it becomes
crunchy which is another thing we
see dop  or because you have a few
minutes then in storage it is
removed from the heat and we find ourselves having to
carry out this type of operation
which is to mix then mix with the
almonds on the fire and when you see that
it melts too much that you do the
liquid part on the  fund this must be removed from the
fire to collect in practice
I send them to make them a shoe then when
it is melted it takes off the heat to
collect the sugar and a little at a
time today it comes from four everything
is what
we all do and therefore yes  mix with
what's left is basically
this the first times I did it I
was left with a lot of makeup with a
minimum of experience comes this thing
here for which it lends even little events is
a setting that observes hammer and
chisel to clean the pan
or simply  water and
time factor because sugar dissolves
that water luckily and the result is
this photo but a little darker than
q  what it should be because I
did with photography it is not clear
that taking pictures while working is
just one thing always a so this
is a question is something that usually
square today took it
to a client because I went away
I kept it  some for me when you eat
mondello pleasantly this thing
are much better than those
found at the fair
in the sense that these things are
also bought in some way here be careful
they burn they burn they discover then
put they surface is
not possible even so that they reach
room temperature before  to eat them
after which one says something I do with
all this doubt here what do I do
for a long time white blue that I took it are two
ounces of sugar here in the background there
were two ounces of almonds this
shiny photo of being because it is a double
in this  if I personally prefer to
send them for the long time it was
a bit boring job because they must be taken
individually for less  not to give us a
demo once they made half
a kilo of macondo cutting boards so as to
cut in one stroke only 5 for
the long one you can also do it with
whole almonds or with chopped almonds
this according to personal preferences
to me brutally  like them this
way so what happens then that you
put everything still are the same
doses are 100 g of sugar for every 100
grams of dried fruit and an ocean of
water in this case we have already
added to the water so what
also happens this  photo with an
unfair right because I realized the
mistake before lighting the fire
the water looks like an era because you can only do
a kilo of pumpkin in a spoonful
of water
we don't really do that much but
we just need to get it done otherwise point
it is  just to wait another
important thing is to prepare yourself as
you can see here this photo there must
have been no wrong water misery behind the
parchment paper because when it is crunchy it
comes out  about 850 gr
adida from the aluminum pan must
be on the parchment paper otherwise
whatever in place one carbonizes it two
does not come off anymore then just put it
on a classic cutting board finish with it check
that you will eat plastic and sugar in
equal parts then carefully
prepare the surface to  start
here I exaggerated a little more for two ounces
in the end you can see it took me a
little less and it is once again a
thing that boils allnet boils and then it started it
will go dark and put the one says oh god
my eyes burn
this time  I'm dying oh my it's hot
on 28 hands co2 pot holders better 3 the
temperature is very high this point one
says ex q it's
not enough let's go on like this instead it's
nice dark no it's not enough here this
was enough I don't remember if it's the last
one too it's a  like reason a
liquid phase in which it is just a nice
dark completely liquid broth
who knows it burns the eyes a
horrible thing but currently to get the
c  good things you always need to make a
certain effort there is this effort of
reaching it
the beautiful thing is then this
is finally more or less the right coloring to
be good at not being able to even salt
a spoonful of this sugar but do
not care  a lot and at this point
you take it down you turn off the heat and don't take it
down the recipe cocer says with half a
lemon
because it doesn't stick on the lemon and
gives us that minimum of robinho that doesn't hurt us
unfortunately when I tried with
lemon  I always got annoyed
with lemon thumb so I do it with two
spoons which unfortunately we will sell at the
counter with a little encrusted with sugar and
filing them in the end there is a bit of
sugar even once the procedure is
hammer and chisel or water and how
long they count  always it is the result
is this
of this you do not see it is a full chopping board
plus a little bit about this
sheet taste hot and soft they were
terrible chorus if you try to detach it from
for  no it comes from a ridge you have a disaster in your
hand wait for the iris at
room temperature
but
if you are in sicily in puglia you put it
in a bowl and all happy if you are
in lombardy puts it closed because
it drinks water an evening with
some  friends I had my barter the cap with the
cap I put it in the middle of the table but
two hours of chat in which everyone
discharged it seems the cap was enough for
a kind of rubber half a finger is enough to
press on five because simple carla
a really horrible thing so
when it was temperature mind close it
if you live in an unhealthy place 6b letters
in a healthy place here I would say that to esc
the humid of those swamps dc to the tent
they say or eat immediately or if it closes
sterile and closed environment this is the
result of
the dishes  they are not standard they are a little
bigger than a normal dish these
are three ounces of dried fruit contracted
of sugar these are two ounces of
almonds with two types of tuk this is
u  n another list that the same thing and
I hope I have balanced the polytechnics
of the first presentation with a
presentation that I hope you will not look
at 2 because this already took
about half the expected time thanks
thanks
ruby here is the time to get ready and
brats emanuele sugary  I
started at 12 00 and I finished
12 and 12 so he said I'm afraid almost to
do it in real time except then to
position the camera etc.
and to pop it may
take a while so time is
still much faster than what it
seems to
find the first time if it gets bad
eat it alone and so the second
time it is better you can give it to
friends or follow this  politics I do a
lot of tests between the toucan it is bad
if there is a good ingredients I eat everything
myself and I don't know that no one
even I suffer because I ran out of
lawn once  thank you then let's see if
anyone has any questions if not we are
one also this time
well together with the next question is the
question that the next aiscat
says yes I surely then had
done on the chat I am more like a razor
than the ex is a  solo chat perote
the allegro male is a
90's rock the year I have a slow machine that
works well for the boxes the
debian package has a
default configuration that I don't like my
configuration of the built over the
years so that's okay
I demand my privacy only my choice
the window manager there is a question on the
chat
this was from a massive use
maybe you also do those on the chat
because I still feel clicks or
on the download it follows
not only because everything else follows if
you also feel not  necessarily if I
sing about shoes to munch a
friend of mine is an elite pastry chef that
pastry is practically chemical
so you have to do everything with sling bars
right programs how do you do
things eye
well I can only like you do I
miss the second half doing the things
I have
well in the east surely the faces then the
fools worried a tour in the oven
or many other good things  to do here in the
east because there will be if there will be the former
thing that still seems to me not quite
this is not not yet sure yes
everything then ruby and that we thank a
lot for this a little particular
will open the series of bulls in  he cooks with
ruby
[Music]
and then obviously if there will be
skyrocketing we are waiting for you with the role you cook from the
east
okay I heard meta but I guess
what was said
thank you all