so i'm ruggiero who was
everyone what i do in life i'm a
doctoral student from as saint ares
toulouse not in italy anyway i live in
trieste and i'm more or less stable here
my job mainly consists in
predicting the states were i  money of
silicon and silicon surfaces
so it is far from being that of a
programmer or
what is related
but the fact that however I am in
a sector of a computational calculation
so much and the high data analysis
leads me to interface we begin  with the
world of programming very often
and therefore to develop code we are not
in a structural way but more in a
way based on the needs here I am part
of the mister what is the meter skillfully
reb for those who do not know it is a hacker
space where we do things  we see people it is
a European aspect it is a
physical place in this period it is a more
virtual than physical place where we meet and
discuss projects and development  iluppi
I love with the philosophy of having
free things for everyone in the end
learn and share and share
knowledge
we are here to talk york mod ok all
mode is a tip of a pyramid I wanted to
do the road a little better but I didn't
make it in time  let's say that at the base of
all this top there is max which I hope
we see after sip it is max we will insert
space max and on space max insert
work mode and then we will discuss
york modes very quickly
however the idea of the pyramid that the
base  and it is max and on this then we build
what is max ok is max everyone
knows it as a simple
simple text editor open quotes things
quotes but in reality it is much more
than all this through the extensions
that can be installed it becomes a
main client  news rivera a debugger a
calendar a psychologist a project
planner can practically become an
operating system with a lot of
software inside it
now the is max is quite compl
icato hiding teams that are used for
at least never to complicated and that
binding are not anything but
intuitive because it is a software that does not
have much graphical interface
to overcome this problem
for people who come from wim as a
corridor there are distributions  of
and max among these distributions we find
space max precisely that it is a
distribution that
basically provides all that bindings
of wim are reported in the world is
max in quotation marks all the
functions of are reported in the
world is max and the in addition are inserted
some
much more native me monici and consistent
is the one before it was
obviously not the space maxi logo
space max logo this is the one before it was
a fun game that can be enabled
in the worst of the introduction so at the
base we have a magical this text
editor  with lots of plugins text
editor with lots of plugins we
install space max space max c from a
set of that bin  ding to manage all
the very human plugins
plus the wim structure which is the one
with which we get used to which at least I
am used
to everything we are going to
discuss I will discuss in this
context
it is not the only context that is space max is
a distribution via max there are at
work there are infinite and if you want to
take care of your own and in addition we
the binding I will give are
only those for the most part
are by default of space max
but one can use those of is  max
that are very different the basic concepts
that one must know how to manage to
approach this context are
first of all what they are what the
structure of e max that is how
the files are managed within e max is
max is composed in bayern
each file that  we open creates a new
buffer each service we launch creates
a new buffer when we open a buffer
this is a hooker bottom line a
line at the bottom of the page that in the cast
of space max has u  similar to what we
see in this image
on the left action large number of
buffers we are looking at then after there is
the status of the buffer that can be
saved unsaved in this case it is
saved cannot be saved the
buffer size of the associated file the name the
major mode and the and some mine or mod
the major way basically the
main plugin we are using
inside the buffer in this case
heard mode however there may be mailer
there may be a plugin for milk that each
language to its plugin principles
there is this  operation to do that to
contact marco
and in contacting marco has a priority
of type a which is high
so we can go to define a
we have deadline deadline.com of
this inserts a dead line
for the action of priorities com priority
abc  to see the priorities the comasche
you're dead line
dave kaye johnson and this brings us to the
company because we have heard the
dates we wonder how it
fits  sce the agenda in all this
then first of all it costs to do that
you have to add the file to the agenda
as you add the file to
the company against the c square bracket you add
to make people at this point you have to
open the agenda control yes  sa is the
open agenda we are offered this
screen which is said to let us
choose between various options in
quotation marks a for the classic agenda t we
make a list
of all the tutus on two entries that we have
available at the moment the others
let's leave it alone they are the most sophisticated ex
that is the every entry to which essentially
an expo area on all the files that are
available
have been loaded and followed by the
agenda in this case I have elaborated a
little to see how it turns out
if I go to see them all  the next
actions to do that letter t
you see that we are shown in this
case the actions organized by order
by priority we have the contact marco
who was that of those before we
entered  ito first in our file
we have a tag for the file that the pug
that was associated first alterations that
are inserted below with their
respective tags and we have tutu that
was always open in the action
before that it was possible to play the
ranelli file  junod
if instead we show the program for the
week with a letter we can
open the whole program we see
that there is a tube let's say that for example
we have the meeting of this card evening
sky sworn at a date now then after
there is the tutu  to contact marco who is
down because it has to be done in three days
there is the email
the deadline which is for Sunday as
we move in this phase we move
in this agenda obviously the keys are
and jay kay out as any rhyme with
user yes  would wait with hulk space
we can open a table a table
with a thousand other options
in particular attention must be given to the
headlines this allows us
to change the status qu directly from the agenda  then
move a tool two to dan on next so
on
i have some that allows us to change the
date remove the molding team
schedule one thing for the future and so
on
returning to the meeting the meeting is
nothing more than a time stamp with a time stamp
in this case when I was
writing my project I
arrive at the adv to the point at the claim that
tells me where is mine that tells me where
is the meeting is the keyword meeting
which an extra keyword has nothing to do
and there more than anything else because I
personally I use it to remind me the
meeting is one ago paragraph of head for
gate inter time stamp the time the many
offers one day you tell him
I want it 9 pm I want it to last two hours
so in full plus two automatically
times dampyr  is created and this thing
is added to the agenda
among the last features I wanted
to tell you about is time tracking because
we can also manage our
how much time we spend on each pocket
time tracking is accessible more or less
everywhere  que in is max so you don't need to be
in a word mode file with maxi it
allows me to open it anyway so that
the simplest thing
is this fantastic screen
where you have the various timers you can click
in in a headline click out from a
headline  jumping has a clock that you have
active if you are used to using
Pomodoro timer you have the Pomodoro timer
integrated and in the end when you have
done some clock hynek lockout on some
actions what happens that the various
pockets you have will be more or less of
this type  they will have included this
logbook it is called drawer technically a
particular drawer where it is
assigned every time you have made the
blocks in the glok auto is assigned
the total time spent in the action this
always remains a text file so if you make a
mistake it would just
go  on the line avoid the time
that you have wrong comma
comma all times are updated
automatically and when you are finished  to a
very nice thing that you can do the
final report and it tells you how much you
spent on each section
and how much was the total time
you spent on the project
and
that's it. horwood conclusions a great piece
of software provides you to get organized
but it's up to us  deciding how to combine them
space max makes it intuitive for those
coming from wim and there is a lot more than
what I said among other things precisely orc
mode also presentations wanting us to
export it to beemer thanks
we had some software latex mime which
is a software  to make screenshot pdf
cpc to present pdf made in beemer
and some references for those interested
these
realities are links so and I finished
15 seconds early
well then on hear and ruggiero
because he had to make a change of
nurseries  except I feel very well then I
thank you as they say you were
one of those players who split the
second
or rather unpacking and in the meantime, however,
these were the in  interpretation as
we are now used to hearing on
our Thursdays at this point not
as usual there is space for the questions
that you answer so I look for a moment in
chat if any of the questions to
ask can be asked through our own
of the stracciati di  terna or
the legrand group or remove the
mood and enter directly into the
conference
now I here from the device cannot
read the questions, however, so I don't know
if there are questions to rediscover the chat
for now only the one
ok no then the beautiful ciato  it seems that
there is no question if if you are not
normally I make it a hero who was and
representations reality he did it
directly in beemer the question is
how the presentation was made
is a gamer
because it is true that jorge mode is comfortable for
then do the outline you do it nord mode
the notes I took them all nord mod
but then the end used beemer because
let's say that personally I work a
lot more on it and  so I am much more
immediate and it is much more immediate for me to
make presentations beemer moreover the
amount of customization that can be
obtained by exporting dormo from beemer is
very constrained by the pre-
built formats that they
impose on you in that case
ok I replied then it was
max's question so now our technician is what
you can do ficili and I'll
ask you a question me you this amorous software a
long time me the first time I
would marry mode was
a year ago now a year and a half ago and I just
started using it  to
manage outline ok so in a
very banal way with how I did
at the beginning to take some notes,
little things like that and then later I slowly
discovered the other functions and I
expanded a bit I began to manage the
voodoo slowly and to  today they use a
lot of youtube outlines the link
file with other files the link is such a big
thing to be able to
manage me in large projects
where there are so many files that keep
different notes of different things
the diary I don't use it a lot in reality I
use the tour a lot to know what is
next but I don't use
the diary itself a lot as an organizing tool
ok
if the question I take question but I
have not understood very well what it is I am
fine
for several things but he seems to flow
of the features that spend
existence
you give me with richer with inter than a
rich to take notes in all
respects is a  set of scripts that
act on text files is a
collection of scripts with speech
text files the end of the day how
after you combine these vip to get the
best result for itself is another matter
if I can try milling
again also another way to  to see it is
that horwood was born as a wrapper
around a library of outlines default
was born only to manage outlines this
was its main goal
then after these outlines like hotlines
they lend themselves very well to the management of
tutu the whole
part of gaza james has been developed from another
quotation mark which is the work philosophy
added all these scripts that
allow you to organize your
life but let's say that the basic
idea is  that you do not require a way to
organize yourself that is there are ok if you feel
comfortable with these scripts and they are for you or
rearrange them to get the most out of
your work it is okay if not you do not use them ok
so it is not just a thing in
format and also  an
interface function is also a question of
wall street what