thank you alright alright alright so I
apologize it's taking a little while to
get started a little bit of setup in
this so I've been doing a talk or I'll
do I dissing well I couldn't do it a
couple dollars for a couple years about
social I'm here and the first one was
called something smells fishy eh and I'm
also a pity so so then I wouldn't do a
little more technical skin on me so mind
that we got the other forgive this
presentation of supplying the wire for
hires ultimate tackle box I guess and
then I was talking to her friend of mine
young man who I actually goes to school
really closely here named Solomon who
least we saw a version of his
presentation he says you should call it
a hackle box so so the name is stuffing
and in my way that was very easy so um
so anyway so here's use all the things
for that inspiration let me see if I can
hey here it's alright so a little bit of
selfless side or shameless
self-promotion I myself as well I found
some those you don't know about found
some other than the tool bounce of
witches have no warrants called human
skin or some such nonsense Nelson was
was founded in nineteen ninety nine we
were bought by mcafee in 2004 inquired
by Intel mcafee was acquired by Hill by
2011 so last year so I had become me
hacker inside nothin what I always
wanted to be so found some professional
services worldwide in fact me you
probably know Carrie Dooley by any
chance on your period yeah okay well
Gary is leading our found some Mia units
so over in Europe right now and actually
we just sent
they should lead that charge over there
so thanks for growing we're growing we
are hiring another way we say that again
the ohio union so yes eight o'clock
we're out there on social media some of
you may know the name brand tomlin see
there's a lot of wireless researches up
brent has just taken off recently gotten
really into the research in stone and
he's kind of behind the atoms own
Twitter angle there's a few others fso
media open found some blog not open
security research comments have our long
side just recently it lost a little bit
about me I just kind of the alphabet out
there after my name I tend to collect
certifications in fact the most recent
1i got was the q SI ya okay yes I'm so
so where do i bought my two giant
fortune 500 yeah about money address
traitor this true I was kind of bought
and sold yeah yeah i was paid for what i
got here right so anyway I've been in
the industry since 1998 everyone here
was born in okay good if you were like
although you can probably had better
back me over so anyway I George found
some of my specialty is social
engineering I do physical security also
do wireless internal external the
traditional pin deadlines I pretty much
do what they tell me ah my claim that
they may is most recently was placing
second place in the social meeting CTF
at Def Con yeah i would highly recommend
that experience fat legs a lot of fun
Chris Chris makes you feel like you're
expert so it's really meant food so
alright so so on to the top now this
talk usually structured sort of in the
reversal rate is now so if I if I true
up and think something's next we i
actually just met through
I'm sorry so but anyway the idea here is
a is a kit of sorts also now call it a
half a box of basically a collection of
utilities that a physical social
engineer we use in their health and the
whole concept here is that I wanted to
collect these things and put it into a
kit that I could ship across the country
because believe it or not we have more
social engineering business that I can
personally myself so we have another
consultant to it and so I wanted to be
able to just kind of ship this kit and
so I don't know three or four years ago
I started assembling these things and
just different pieces and parts and so
so now I've created this kid so what I'm
going to do is just kind of take you
through what's in it quickly because
there's a lot of stuff in it and there's
all kind of story but on everything but
i'll spare you that give you some tips
off where I got some of this stuff and
where you can get it and then kind of
highlight a few of the cooler tools that
are in the kit at least I think we're
technical in that time so and then I
also got a little surprise for you a
preview of a tool that I've been working
on a part of all now that I plan to kind
of presented hip bone this was kind of a
scallop excuse me on letting me talk I
thought you might i'll be doing a
preview of something else improve end up
on the outside oh we love groups all
right okay so what's there alrighty
hackle box as it is I'll sure how much
you can see there with you guys in the
back of it if you want to talk
afterwards I actually had the physical
kid living because i'm using pieces and
parts of it so i just say you're angry
only right ah but to highlight a few
things here first of all there's some
laminating sheets turn this song so i go
i'm gonna close are here alright so
first of all some laminating sheets to
make your own magic
all these stages it didn't for some
double-sided tape why not duct tape
because of a double sided the Lord one
thing about when you're making these
kids you want things that have multiple
purposes hi I next how do you see this
real well but it's a cell phone holster
and basically that's you so that you can
put the camera outpacing on your cell
phone video things while you're doing
especially eating good video of badges I
like politics Kootenai all right there's
a young blood this is particular model
is the pump blood delete that also has
the rise of a car the extra ethernet
adapter and smooth all right I the
pocket Andy very useful you walk in the
building and you to plug into their
network right instead of tote entire
laptop your notice sometimes of that
this is not a pretty long drive and
basically the reason it's kink is
basically this is the thing that you
into the receptionist and say could you
print out my boy that's right don't link
this some evil-looking hackery and a
date what I do is I made a pink and so
if she asks although that's a pretty
bunker up yes my daughter she gave it to
the pub all smiling because I'm a family
right and of course they plug it right
in and they'd Oklahoma media right
that's all that's a little crossover
connector just in case you can't get to
the network in unity the next to a
machine yes okay yeah these are eating
they don't cost much it's just it's just
maybe you have with you this is in case
you're publishing alright so here's a
teensy of the dougie the TC up here
which some of you are very later and
maybe you're not familiar with the ducky
hack pod right now okay you're right has
no itz end up and in Canada this
business card of course it doesn't have
to be dead
talent to shut up but he was at the CTA
up and everything I got me that was cool
but it mostly mostly because this is
card doubles as a lockpick kit it's not
a great Locker but in an inch to the
work and so you can also get other
business cards in water ok next one of
my latest acquisitions is a new color
running CNG mod 7 in that track 5 know
if you play around this ask well worth
the time and pulling learning you know
messing around with it oh it actually is
a functioning that track distribution is
the long distribution although you know
getting graphical with it is not all
that fun community kind of slow or that
way on a true lockpick set I got from
vegan here to a little shout out through
school there retractable cat5 cable here
we might be with those and let's see an
output of one walk wireless adapter that
can go with the moon plug we're doing
the equal a piece of or just reviewing
wireless of general knoxx mar 3 you're
not familiar with RFID communal that's a
good automated devices on the art IV bag
good in a in a one tier line USB Drive
is katana konbu etc um I lutely just one
factor so that I could hold probably
katana which takes I guess it up some
tea museum or being here but also if I
want to hold my rainbow tables and I
want to pull okay so i gotta have a
minimum care like me that I'm and that
by the way that that USB Drive is about
sizable cell phone so David pocket that
was another requirement okay most of
this stuff that you see in here other
than the Pope plug just about everything
will fit in a pocket leave it on the
decoder will fit in a pocket on the side
of jeans so um so if you don't have to
you know had to be positive crap or
right let's see if I'm Lisa firewire
cables so that just in case old quarter
trick of connecting to the maxi dress
Alyssa had it been so much of that
lately after of all the cables female to
the patch so yeah good for that and it
finally I think I hit button camera down
here on these are mounter books i guess
and really easy to to report things
without people knowing it's amazing how
program you really are um you can put
this in like go tell the jacket little
button because it will help uh most life
is good the jacket is black people
notice you can film this right up close
and a big deal I say me especially if
you're doing you know if your client
won't be your couz what you getting into
a going away I do not allowing you
alright so that's the haggle box um so
where did you get a hackle off flow you
can assemble it by going to eat all the
supply stores and go up Pony Express a
lot of PR TAC 5p or venue an ex-con mood
by the way he said just just to be a
beta of their mac burden you're not
familiar will come to them I'm going to
do a little bit oh I and without that
its just oh let's see katana I get half
a pack of a cave by the way that were
here the hottest around you heard here
thurs i was talking running earlier this
week and we collaborate on some
enhancements it economy right how long
has it been since consider development
to maybe in three years crossmark 33
another but ok so you could all these
places or you go to X handbook ok pretty
much everything in my kid you can get it
exactly alright so I promise hey where I
would ditch it makes
a little screenshot you guys get out
there you know big boss today okay
you're going to be here by the way so
all right so um the pump luckily I this
is just like to me to somebody said this
whole ssss a shell is like magic okay
it's just one of those things it's like
in that it's like an egg cactus it's
just those those those things that you
come across that are just too cool and
you just have to use you have to try to
use the whole concept so the concept
behind the phone plug is you plug it
into a network and in some way finds its
way out of the network to connect to a
server that you have on the internet all
right that's the concept and you can do
it through just straight regular les shu
can do it through essential hyborean it
is yes I ICP dns you know whatever
magnetized networks element some kind of
magic can also do to add a part but the
really cool thing in my mind is you
don't necessarily have to be seeing
their monitoring your server on the
outside holding the connection happens
and you can do that but you don't have
to and so this leads you to a little bit
o real quick like I said it's just a
little quick nice convenient thing that
possible okay yeah alright so so with
the lighting the lighting is can feel a
little bit rough to see here but all
doesn't so what you see on the left hand
side is it is an app on my phone is a
screenshot of my phone alright my
android phone the home baked and then on
the right-hand side is the is an ssh
session with a server on here so when
the pump blood starts up home place
starts up it connects to the server on
the internet
and this is all configurable but
essentially we did when it creates a
connection all you see on your internet
server is a port open okay in this case
for 3333 yeah okay and basically this
little historical night right no big
deal so he cranks up this connection on
on 30 30 30 30 and it often indicates
with whatever user you want it uses like
digital certificates so you don't you
hassle animosity because so-and-so you
see the pump blood okay and then what
happens is it sends an email to your
phone at your provider which is
translated into an SMS nest so you're
just bobbing along you don't have to
worry about checking move I think you
just do xmas it says something like all
aboard the Pony Express unplug the
shelve it reached its destination so
it's kind of like eating out and okay
master I'm ready right kind of cool very
convenient then you just go and you you
just do a local ssh to that port 3333 oh
you get prompted you log in and you're
on so now your shell on the humbug of
course you can see it's got a little
Conrad a lot address a new unit amici
singing and all that so whatever
utilities are sitting on the boat blood
you have use of and all that goes right
is half as good alright what we're going
to see the kind of kind of extra stuff
today with what you're going to see is
is he taking this concept kind of to the
next level or one level there's a lot of
waiting buildings okay see your bedroom
okay so um so the teensy in the dougie
to do here has heard of heart failure
pee yew tee ILY a Maitre D' vertical
fears I
okay okay maybe over the name I don't
remember the guys name but he has
created this it's a lot like what they
did was said but it kind of goes into
it's just for programming that easy and
so is he's got about 12 different
choices of different payloads you can do
anything he made it a little bit more
customizable I'm speaking from someone
who doesn't know see this including
kotas way out of a paper bag oh that's
pretty help and he keeps adding these
new halos as x is also Google Affiliate
and if you like messing around with the
teensy and i will say playing with your
pc but give you a night keep you playing
mess around with ptc device I'll tenia
is worth checking out okay he's got some
kind of weird wet out halos and sorry
city all right right right so they'll
actually accept if you're including for
you to choose payloads kind of odd that
a long time ago right yeah I've seen
yourself yeah there's well yeah I guess
I guess my point for pointing out
affiliate um is is this is usually you
can use with that you know being kind of
annuvin you have a girl it being a
non-covered right oh because pushing the
code to the TT is probably the easy part
was hit and all that so it basically
looked a change that is creating a nice
work so this universe them now but what
I wanted to highlight here as well is
for the heck guys created this
which they created this little scripting
language which is about the limit of my
coma knowledge and I'm gonna totally
stupid but oh but so they create the
scripting language though that I mean
it's really simple it's like you typed
in string and need you type of like
character you want in too tight
literally in a UT type in here for any
pesky in Turkey so it's truly you know
truly basic so and I have a little I
have a little demo here or a group a
load of all was kind of interesting in
the dougie okay so my first point though
I guess is uh you can you can put this
as the ducky year so so essentially
coming this thing is just it's just
taking a notepad and saving a file and
then using the duck encoder to create a
big ball and saving it on SD card is
pretty much that simple right so what I
do is I use this little SD card to USB
adapter to push the code to it and then
I'll call you in the ducky and then I
found this USB Drive that i had laying
around that i was able to separate
without actually breaking it so i could
actually put it back together and so I
store I even store my little USB to the
SD card in the same compartment of the
USB Drive so that way I've got with me
and if I decide to change palos you know
it's for a moment I can always change
palos likes it in the bathroom including
or something it will behave chain
payload figure out something that's so
it is been all kind of a blur all right
don't you get wrong impressive there's
all you were shelled and getting around
ad all that yourself but I came across a
payload that someone coded and I thought
it was kind of cute so i plug in it easy
and I'm hoping he'll be over
um and so you may have seen this payload
I was human yeah so you can tell this
bar Simpson I learned a lot of my
computer awesome aah if I'm not mistaken
the kid that that code it is like
protein so he submitted this to the poor
of it said I hope you like those I don't
you know I don't have a ducky to test it
on because they're not expensive doing
any bus he didn't have any bus system on
dougie he's like I'm only cooking so I
thought it was you know worked as
groping our users are my mission in life
I guess alright so that's that's all
right okay you won't oh okay so um so
the next two low on a highlight in the
v-neck loss is the proxmark drill and
basically taking that to the next level
so are you getting how the theme here
yet what I did I've been accused of
doing that as a family practice as a kid
you know somebody tells a joke at your
family and someone decides to improve
the joke and retell it with a different
bus line river at augies on all about so
I just kind of want to see that do I
never told a unique ID I disapprove
written others track so so the trick
here is with rocks heart three vin de
tree here is in equal see the antenna
alright eaten is basically the size of a
cd-rom all right are ya how that is and
so the idea the first implementation of
it was oh well I'll just wear a jacket
blazer something new provisional and all
the among smart greet device in the
breast pocket and then I'll run in the
wire down must leave and I'll palm the
antenna so then when i go to become
somebody's heart I'll just get kind of
goes oh man dogs have all moved heart
all right big deal well one day I was
only engagement it was I was in Chicago
it was really hot which i think is
having unique delivery of the television
show and it really cold and rainy and
all that it was really hot so I wasn't
really prepared for it to be hot in
Chicago all right i mean i travel a
little close disguises everything as it
is so i haven't come up with a solution
well I'll talk so I just kind of racking
my brain I end up at a best buy of in
chicago and i find this thing well what
this is is a little all it is right here
it is a USB hard drive case that has an
external pocket so i got the idea all
woman I take the poshmark the inside it
all wired up and input the antenna
outside could i call them hard you know
through the cameras will sure up you can
and the money because I so I need your
practice with it is a whole another you
know idea of me as far as had it on the
card so I'm walking through the streets
of Chicago I'm just wanting to test to
see how many people would notice if i
were to pump their deal with this thing
instead of just my bairn ain't right how
close would I have to get now mind you I
didn't go through life under their
buddies cars come on here okay even if I
did I probably would admit that anyone
but on camera so so anyways like to
start helping people just to kind of get
an idea some problem well I'm walking
incident if your bid of Chicago there is
crowded streets all right especially
during the business day especially here
in oneself and so you can actually stand
with big crowd people waiting on you
know the cross ball change and as soon
as it changes everybody it's almost like
a subway everybody is just dying to get
across the street so there's a lot of
month ago on something okay that's a
good opportunity so I start bumping
people with you know and I'm looking for
ideas and i love it and so then finally
I walking across this one Street and
this lady has her badge okay and it's
they're wearing it she's only there
okay and I'm only don't bump me okay I
remember very sensitive especially if
their badges near their purse right you
know you had this his third eye comes
out of your ear watching that earthside
so I tend to clean the open but the
slave walking you know as Chicagoans do
you know really you know swinging that
bag someone just curious wonder so I
hope to say go and not even have to do
that closer to swing their hand she's
swinging back as she bumps on device
right doesn't even look back and I'm
know she felt because I felt I felt her
hand hit the device so she hit it pretty
hard and I'm just kind of looking at it
I'm kind of look you know really creamy
but she doesn't even look that wow this
is weird so yeah follower like horrible
hawks and she loves it I'll no.67 I
shouldn't have herbalism oh man this is
an awesome so so that was kind of the
birth of this this whole idea of
carrying around it works so great
especially got black pants where do just
don't even notice I don't know what they
think I'm carrying but they just don't
know this they don't care so I can stand
in line at the show games or whatever
well people inside whatever using this
little gap all right so along with the
theme of heavy enhancement for this real
quick or a quick review of our body
hugging everybody knows chris magic
redundant questions i guess came with
the scores but prismatic really brought
into the mainstream of your RFID coning
essentially the device just just acts
like a leader Peter dieses RFID card the
course that it has a play mode right it
just plays back back hard right but the
problem if that is what if you home
somebody's car you only has access to
ability but if they don't have access to
data center or whatever sin severe you
want to get in well then you have to go
back out and plumbing somebody else's
car
every time you call the car there's a
chance get caught you know I don't like
it God he's not here is one game
leveraging so enter proximity is anybody
here heard of Roxbury relations Jason
yeah got one okay okay okay you got a
cool kid print well so it works with the
products on a great would be chip and in
your like the Delaware him anyway sorry
budget ok so what pops group does is not
only brand in town which came up with
this well i was on a gig and I was
complaining about well now I have to go
to clone somebody else's car he said we
lost you have to do that I can't we just
group tours the employee ID portion of
the garden I mean it's just a whatever i
guess a wee bit for bit character you
know code that this thing is real money
right so it was encoded this thing to
it's just a flash it's just an earlier
class you just update the cross mark 3
firmware with the discard where they
created and so that when you press the
play button instead of just replaying
the one card it actually will play it
will keep the facility ID the same and
it will replay your card but it will
decrement the card ID by one and then
play that for a second and then
decrement the card i do i wanted to play
that percent right so why definite knew
it was the wrong use of the hall exactly
exactly began who got the system we most
harder issued in my clocks 111 they gon
do when you've got the system and
implemented i'll probably issued himself
a card first or at least like a a engine
card backup group to access of
everything card and then we start
issuing to sell many probably issues
security guards that need access
everything involve us and it finally
comes the card that you plum which might
have been the 99th or the you know
whatever 2000 person who got a card and
so I work at your way backwards in the
reverse direction you'll get to a better
card all right someone who got had their
card issue to longer and likely has more
assets yeah a little bit of a warning
about this particular this device that
is this method is every time the
optimist edge across group utility
changes card numbers the card reader
that you're playing on beat so it's a
bit loud quits so imagine you're
standing at the server room door and you
know it's playing very soon possession
is in good mood and the door doesn't let
you in and it plays you know Bob's car
because it doesn't let you in so every
second you right so so you don't want to
do it a little day right you want to
come back later at night to miss
anything in fact I had a consultant tell
me that he did just that and the janitor
showed up it's a wonder about leaving
said a beauty in the door even yeah I'm
having some trouble trouble shooting
this this carburetor he's all I can get
in here anyway min so what why you're
done is right here too if now Debbie
didn't quantities go harder but I can
see good oh that's a very great idea of
actually what I was cloning hardest one
time that's a great story oh I went to
where the clears were you know that
bottle pockets with the cleaners show up
at to come clean the building and i win
and i was having trouble logging in card
so i asked one of the cleaners well
could you test it for me and we test
this roadway make sure your cart orchid
and your cars working oh you're the
supervisor Kayla I need to check your
arse he's like all sharp here take it so
forth while I'm just about to go over
the reader
wonderful patients need every right so
so anyway an interesting utility
detective to the missile all right so um
these are the Nets utility that I think
is just this way too cool it's called
konbu and by the way your predator
category boundaries of futures he said I
have located within nine base
participating in the murder of done news
so yeah absolutely then so so what konbu
does as far as i can tell the developers
not you know we're coming group exactly
the air working group on dude but i
guess understanding essentially what it
does temporarily modifies the system
lubrication right that believe me are a
little crime 12k to start of a disc it
essentially ejects a little bit of code
that tells it whenever whenever receive
a password i'll make that a valid
password so it doesn't matter what
actually you type in now there's a
windows version currently and like i
said before there's a there's a beta
version of mac out there that have
intelligence to you up the chest yet
just kind of issue but but it's actually
what it does it let you elevate the
system so we're purposes of
demonstration and come here um see your
equipment ok so for purposes of
illustration basically what i've done
taking a condom image and configured a
virtual machine to boot up using see
this here but hip i'm using need to be
conjured CD iso to do that Olivia okay
now I could boot it without the CD and
show you that that my vm does not have a
blank password or you could just trust
me that he doesn't have a long password
all right that's a lot yeah rustic are
given the sea out of prison
trust a liar yeah that's usually why I
introduce myself I don't start with hi
I'm a paid liar so which you can see the
konbu the comedy / train it's wrong in
and it's done it's little injection
there and it's booting up and believe it
or not you're confident one has been out
for how long there's a free version
there's a paid version version 2 1
breeze about that I like the idea of
getting virgin too it also has a
privilege escalation utility within it
so in addition to version 1 it's a
little bit of an extra hit there so what
I'm going to do is show you the prison
desolation piece of it after this I can
move and you think I tell you what
instead of a blank password I'll just
compress the number one a bunch of 1000
kids to do with my face on the time in
summer with my English didn't you hear
how they don't wear this am Oh is a
period here we get in there that is a
good they're good outside now that was
not my password that degree crib okay
there is sooo alright alright I don't
know where that you can alright so so
anyway so there we go right through this
up no big deal alright so within this
desktop yeah okay so I'm bringing up
with the main cross and I'm one in as
consultant and you can login as anyone
with a mood as long as you know what
account you log in right you still have
to have to figure that out but let's so
I'm going to do Who am I and that just
shows that I'm insulted and I'm going to
try to add a user and of course I get
access to that
even though the consultant counts in the
ending group you know whatever it's
locked in so what I'm going to do here
is I'm going to copy this is just the
it's just what what the instructions
from come to say is to copy khz sem kwc
and then run cmd.exe right which opens
up a privilege a more privileged amaze
you Who am I now I'm system and of
course i can add account I can do
anything I want system right I just shut
the nav I can you do all and have you
set right wonderful makes perfect sense
alright so that's confident and i've
been in some conversations with with
pure or about you know well actually i
had some trouble is calling is so so i
had to talk to even in all of a sudden
he's like hey we think you wanna be a
beta tester dramatic ok kool en food is
just a room no his name is cuter i'm
saying that right fiat otur and last
name is a painted and then yeah I don't
I'm not trusting gonna get we have a
question I didn't have all his prostate
if you added users with amazed well um I
had an early test attack but that's
certainly somehow I'll confirm I as far
as i remember when i did this before but
i was testing it i rebooted without
pointings of the to the convent and the
user was there because i've tried to get
it got a narrative user
so I know that the when you create the
foul like the CM k pal you have to go in
and delete it because it stays like this
so college to get dinner that we if not
all a scheming and you can see visit
this no actually well the defense
against us which as you can tell I'm
like not really invincible I'll i could
do the off and stuff but yeah the
defense against this is full disk
encryption okay and i've tried that in
tested and try to get around it so yeah
but keep in mind it's cool disk
encryption where there's actually a
password right because most I mean so
some implementations of full disk
encryption they just some even for the
password so you just kind of press enter
in your past so it has to be full
business okay so here's the bonus oh and
I have six minutes so I'm in it I don't
know but they didn't actually be able to
demo this unless you want me to go over
but um the demo takes a few minutes but
waste him but now it lies an internal
bouncing name by the way so you wouldn't
see me marketing it as a lot so much
that I called it in Bobby because up
would be awesome our fan of inbox and
all that but physically glazed him on
advising laptop of any sort there's a
few out there work with esxi
implementation right um num people how
many people know that you can actually
load esxi vmware esxi on a laptop right
there's a few laptops it happen so with
that esxi hypervisor installed then a
few virtual machines one being a linux
video it has some auto type connect
strips much like butter on the phone
book in fact that's where i got i
believe it because there is no that's
right and then a couple
of other virtual machines on my pin wat
i have windows OS attack diem if we run
our life down 17 episode and her cell
phone but i've also got a vm is attacked
by some other BM just for fun ok so why
would you go through the pains of making
a laptop and a poem plug we do all right
well am unplug has what egg layers
processor at the game brand whereas a
laptop you have two and a half Peter
processor you know dual-core blah blah
all this capable stuff and a bunch of
rank right or take you wherever you can
come okay so think of this as a bum flow
put on by a group right yep not too all
right so these cases for pinball there's
some above more places and shipping to
your client new firewall reviews and
house music all those fun things move it
an internal pin testing that comes up on
or you can just as a social engineer
plant this in an environment it had a
consistent connection into their
environment where your tool set is not
really limited I mean you have a
full-fledged whatever you can put on
laptop tool set right there and you can
also crank up the mediums and chef daily
meals and of course thing saga apt I
guess I'll see my movie but every
alright alright so how does how does it
about work you're good okay so
essentially what happens is you take
this this laptop you grow it into the
environment you turn it on I guess
ladies okay so you turn it on and the
other scripts go out and create a little
reverse SSH tunnel to your machine
listening on the internet okay dislike
of own blood um but in addition to
creating this reverse shell it also um
cranks out these little more for words
which I love and I hear the bigger with
doing
I guess it's called reverse or 40 / ssh
right okay okay coat see I used to help
jumbo PCM all right to me that's another
magnet moment right it's pfm that you
can actually for a board that's on your
internet server not necessarily to the
ssh client but blue vs-si spine to
another machine that's like this 90 this
is so cool so also essentially what i
did here is pretty little reverse tunnel
so I can control it if I need to but
mostly just creating these two listeners
on my ear at us that that port forward
through millennium to the internal
interface management interface of the
esxi box why the internal interface
because this VM may not know what IP
address was assigned to the esxi box
right so it doesn't have to because
amazing listens on my being added the
interval matted address so i can hard
code that it doesn't have to know it so
that gives me maybe sphere you know
management interface that i can start up
ians and so down and autism make sense
ok so with a demo it doesn't want them
at times but the idea if maybe later you
want to see the demo kickin we can kind
of get that I've got a couple of network
setup to simulate here all right um we
got a bit there any questions probably
we're hiring go out to the blog we
pretty much have a weekly blog post out
there is pretty consistent that has got
several blog posts in queue and each
week you put some out there put us up on
Twitter any questions oh sorry I'm input
yeah
alright