stairways and gentlemen how we doing
this morning Marty last night all right
you guys are diehard because everyone
else apparently still hung over so I'm
going to make sure I cranked up the
audio when they hit it here Oh Herbie
event okay so we'll get started we got
started no light we had some issues
actually getting in ruins and I've never
had issues getting anything set up so
thank you for sticking with us we
appreciate that so I'll resume no wait
we're actually doing the intro in my
talk or buttons thing kind of thing that
I sorta sleepy on say so the history of
the legend welcome thanks for coming out
I appreciate you making the effort to
either come across the state or really
when you get down to it you may have
just rolled out of bed on a t-shirt and
across town we appreciate that too
definitely so um a quick review of the
staff I'm not sure who this guy is I'm a
good buddy but that being said I'm
skydog I'm one who's responsible for
this I think in many different aspects
or versions of being responsible open up
a legal version after the party I
thought that that was he coke is
actually funny because I'm growing the
beard now is longer than the picture
that's at Def Con last year but I'm
growing my good'n beer down it so if all
the people what we refer to as the meet
Walt are the big guys have short hair
and a longer summer you know what the
wall of me coming in here this is mrs.
skydog who have a round of applause
we were using the victor but anyway um
mrs. skydog is probably a lot more
responsible i this channel owner
Jennifer Lawton very long time miss
skydog is responsible for a majority
that's happening because she patted me
getting things done when I was off
playing around doing other things so we
have some ninja master he actually came
down with a fever of 102.1 when he left
her in last night so I'm hoping he's
okay today but it's entirely possible he
may have been out of town his girlfriend
was with his painting and I just I
really like the bg5 there I think he's
got his work cut out for you PDF pisses
her off um she's currently taking care
of him right now but it that he make it
back out make sure you say hey just went
to bear out of a good mood so cute
everybody had a goal that shoots
together stays together he is normally
the most armed person I'm standing
around respect to be her cut boards in
some ways and safe and others Oh much
left has probably meant much left
portion injured before he is going to be
here a little bit later he's actually
sitting in a shopping cart chair that he
made at our hackers face it gets me the
most natural pose for him kick back and
relax will appear in his hand her tits
on also he's a sweet guy he's a little
bit of mentoring there were some of the
kids they came by the HC before Oh
madness
is currently now freaking out because
he's been in the video instead of moving
on that one this actually was kind of a
joke photograph this is us eating at a
chain of each place in Washington DC's
where most of the foodie so whenever we
show up in town we say i miss something
good inked and he doesn't have told a
wonderful job of doing so it's kind of a
goofy picture the orange shirt is always
very mature when we hit a victory
although I know he wears other things
because he isn't G first standing from
the crowd of people actually yeah
dressed a very professional manner this
character you guys have seen him before
this is like this is tom bolton
rebelling little Scotty Bolton his
handle has been quite assassin for years
and the funny part that goes along as
God is Scott is has become one of the
principles of primary people helps put
this thing on I thought sitting for many
many years we discussed on your
conference he wanted to be one money to
friday i want to be only weekend and for
some reason we're doing it all the
weekend I don't know why I think years
because I doesn't make it less it gets
my Nicki well yeah you make nothing goes
profitable and I did so what but that's
okay Scott I'm going to get you back so
you see Scott here this is actually
Patrick Norton on teeth whatever the TV
thing that he does the screen
broadcasted us then we have Scott I
believe this is actually at shmoocon one
here you'll notice these bring the
forensic unit at which he was famous for
he takes it off we got it on yet take
your hat off you know who that is right
there no one yolk in fact he's handling
a crowd to dispute you when you're
talking about hard drives you don't have
a hat on you might actually think he's
you know just some average show instead
of leading authorities on he also wears
that hat when he's wearing is high
how those two go together but pretty
much he's got to have that handled
everywhere and i think i'm correct ilysm
here we go another high suit coat and
the hat and i think i'm nothing that is
you're talking to he knows who that is
we got to the left the goober the
baseball helical not be found regular no
i got a big boy John Draper right now
this guy has a lot better ring here by
know that's Clifford stole correct yes
bigger so I really do that yeah isn't a
stronger astronomer that turned into a
record yeah he actually found a German
hacker they referred to as Yeager that
he found a 50 cent air in the accounting
system for the University work for and
then spent like a year tracking down
this hacker in Germany and he wrote an
absolutely excellent book about what he
had to go through of course from the
standpoint of his methodology was based
in working out science that he was used
to doing so I'm jealous of you to
actually you know guts and they're
called can be submitters compared at one
time to his book but the only book it
had never been furloughed publish that
you know about 10 comment that one
called hacker he'll steam Adobe's good
actor daily a currently not seeing hug
the one that I found before that was out
of the inner circle about Bill Landreth
I actually read that when I was a young
guy they actually had paper and print
from them I was younger so do I did yeah
yeah that story is told cook is there
and he if you look online he's been on
Ted and things like that he's very
frenetic always bouncing around I it's
like ski boy but anyway oh good she has
chasing this stuff a really nice guy I'm
jealous God forgive me we have irony
irony so I Sydney nothing until the
artwork for his mascot which came and
wonderful high resolution yeah but
everything
but the trouble is I don't know the
trouble is to find a picture of this guy
online everything is thumbnail sized
even in every web page thumbnail sized
it so that's why the blown-up pictures
nice and pixelated like that but I just
put that up there kind of mess with him
the you see the gentlemen in the back
who's relaxed teach her everything that
you have is absolutely pepper looking
good kind of guy there yeah those are
the same people we did have it checked
out for engines own iron geek has helped
put the video system together I did the
hardware end of it this nice little rack
of equipment and TVs and everything
ironed even put together the system
refer to as synchro view that's actually
a copywriter term level of line i'm
using matts on youtube but the general
idea is to have the presentation large
the person that's doing the talk in the
smaller window and his little pile of
the bottom normally divine one of those
systems the underground you did if her
quite free I think that's what the price
tag on is great at this point yeah so he
has he has single-handedly changed how a
lot of conferences actually do their
video by writing some scripting in this
and things with avi sense of human ill
around before agreeing but I've got some
great videos everybody this is CP CP
will be on at about two o'clock because
he's probably curtain right now as a
picture of him at not econ like a week
or so ago I got onto the anodic on radio
with him and he was confirmed as Hamburg
and so there's another couple pictures
to go this Mike I'm not later on but um
CP is our director partying if you went
to the party last night good hi he got
hurt you know what he will do drink oh
yeah he actually said I got a present
for you now I'm actually doing some work
on free sedation
that something tells me the present idea
tonight's probably alcohol-related if
it's not a lot of alcohol at some people
alcohol Anand and consuming so so
housekeeping items on our bathroom so
bathrooms are located down the hall to
the left if you go down there's the ice
maker and stuff like their men women's
if you're not sure which one you're
supposed to go in Carla will help you
with that hopeful ah but the single
seater so enjoy that what they're saying
t-shirt sales so t-shirts will go on
sale at ten o'clock other limited in my
brother included hit do this year
registration and t-shirt sales are going
to close at four o'clock and the reason
is normally if we leave everything open
at the end of the con it takes like six
of us an hour to shovel everything into
boxes and get it out of the room so we
thought we're closing it for we'll still
have some shirts and stuff up here as
may need something but just for the so
we actually get to go the party to have
a good time we're going to shut the
registration down the court how the
t-shirts themselves on we actually had a
problem the reason to kind of limited I
had a guy in Nashville exposed to print
them and unfortunately the he got an
order in that he was working on it had
like a three week I'm spans from
decorating to do it and he had to be the
deadline so I said hey how's it going
got the artwork even my t-shirts keys
man Hindu so Miss Scott are scrambled on
that one and got a place here in Atlanta
to press shirts we would pick him up
yesterday and look great they were great
to work with affect the guy who bounces
won't probably come by later on he was
very impressed with huh yes well he's
also a larger than i am and i think that
football player so he might be easy to
pick up in this grounded hey what what
is this company 19 it was
focusing hang of the company her date
yeah mr. Nate's under another the name
is Leonard really good fellow well I
know we've got scarred somewhere but
he'll come out of it later he was very
interested in checking us out on dinner
signups so he's been here before got the
bonds we scare the absolute of
those people were welcomed or do a lot
of 30 people and we go I were here to
eat so kinda I think last year we call
them the day of and said hey we're
coming out to eat we call them
yesterday's if you need to bring
somebody extra in it would be great no
but we're going to bring a bunch of
people who aren't even loans and the
idea is it's one of the few places
within walking distance that actually
has a upstairs banquet hall kind of room
area we can put a bunch of people
everybody goes over there you get to
hang out and have a few drinks and
pretty good food so the deal with the
signups if you want to know the
registration desk we go we get a general
idea of how many people so we can you
know tell them hey it's going to be 40
people or hey it's going to be 70
because that might make a major
difference to them if you don't mind
you're checking the registration look no
oh midget swag Ziploc how long you been
attending conferences Oh God okay see
you been because if you what you've done
and I'm not being accusatory anyway but
it is not a funny thing Jillian like
midgets you have you have probably
probably pretty close to Scott the
number of conferences you've flown to
all over the place some very interesting
stuff he did work on it now is the only
route on 17 really real problem
well that's why you have a Skylark on
staff shirt is that if you have to have
a beautiful asian zip walking I have a
huge collection of Conrad so much so I
had six rubbermaid totes crammed full
contract now this is from Def Con she
moved on not a con create outer zone is
god oh god so that's not counting like
what I actually have poorly con this is
all my personal stuff so there are
t-shirts in here that were purchased at
Def Con plum bag included of oxidant
never been unfolded me directly from the
time so a lot of that stuff there are a
lot of people that come to algorithm
that aren't going to be able to fly out
to DEFCON it's been two grand to go
party all weekend or whatever and then
go buy a t-shirt so what we decided we
would do is I would bring out my gosh
why I'm gonna go through the sorts of
things out and here on Italy during the
day and the registration area go throw
some stuff out on the table and it is
anywhere from t-shirts to the stuff you
end up eating of the bags to the bags
we've gotten a collection of
unbelievable stuff so as the day rolls
on you will cruise through their check
there's a lot of tripe is really cool it
you know you're not going to be able to
get anymore a lot of situations where
someone handed me something that wasn't
available at the con but you know it's a
t-shirt from the vendor or something
like that he can't get over how exhib
like you brought something i bringing
actual official swag code converters or
so yeah
yeah yeah cool yeah I actually I spent
posing for hours on a Sunday going
through all six these clothes sorting
out certain things that I was going to
bring on here to let people have I'm a
DEFCON goon and I have red shirts
unfortunately we'll never let it tear
away I'm not allowed to give a Richard
away I have a good challenge point if we
ever find a good t-shirt or a challenge
point on ebay the last time we set our
max bid of eleven hundred dollars to get
a challenging on that so that's one of
those things where I'd love to give you
a guinea shirt and we've actually SAT
around and talked about getting you want
you have 100k that I would meet why a
suck-up so yeah I have to ensure that
those don't go guys but I got promoted
really cool stuff I like other people to
have I'm not if I didn't want it I can
throw it away I'd rather have other
people enjoy some of this really cool
stuff housekeeping items hopefully I
would have to explain that's too much to
people but this is something we tell
everybody at every time we go to the
three two one rules anyone ever heard of
it you would Tim any way out not to tell
three two one baby so basically the 3g
one rule is at least three hours of
sleep with the are three meals a day
women know three hours of sleep a day of
screw that slider that italy dearie
edited it i know right now that i put a
con on to deal though it's actually not
three meals a day it is three hours of
sleep and a minimum get some kinda sleep
don't party too hard that you can't I
stay away because you miss all the fun
have at least two meals a day the drill
ideas you starve yourself to death and
he drink some alcohol that goes into a
bad situation I would have that to hear
you um what's HAP and in the end on
shower daily if you don't mind the two
males thing nasties here
you guys are talking about you mind uh
try to help out it won't get you can do
one of those so we're gonna see what we
can put together for that look at my
health get a shower yeah gene actually
is surprisingly holiday of Eid I'm 1807
the gene is surprisingly gentle in the
shower ah nice yes you did detail I want
that piece of video you so how many of
you know it was would be respectful Oh
already part of that is be respectful to
the hotel it is not exactly four seasons
but they do let us come in here and kind
of do whatever we want hard even make a
lot of noise you don't mind trying to
tear everything up but his respectful is
hospital the hotel also your fellow man
we all have a tendency to be kind of
cutting humor and sarcasm so sometimes
you catch people off guard just make
sure you milk with accent too hard also
ski boy yeah ski board does not
understand the concept sarcastic hey it
does not recognize it didn't know if you
mess with him too much and he doesn't
quite catch it it's the swine so are we
loving take good care of him to a lot
easier you could've gone better going to
say that program right so anyway all of
us on Twitter the outer zone is the
backboard you're not already on there
we're going to try to send us some some
trivia things you've ever I know what's
going on if anything interesting is
happening which tends to heaven who
actually saved the hotel it's got a ring
here okay if you called up to register
your room and when you did that you told
them outer zone or actually the code was
out 12 a wine and but it's entirely
possible that they did not get that it
from
correct so one of the ways that we
actually are allowed but are able to do
this is we have to make the certain of a
room nights so if 20 people per night
you know have a room here we don't have
to pay as much for con space so it's
really important that we get credit for
you getting up at Ellering here so if
you don't mind you can go to the
registration desk and let them know up
there what your room number is not
they're going to computing them
overnight ski boy but we'll be able to
turn that in and they'll say okay I'm
this pilgrim I message this person since
room and we'll get credit for it we
really appreciate you did it or you
could you actually considered to miss
skydog and Amazon network and she'll
handle the rest up if you go out you
know what luck table front desk in my
lap way that's month left right over
there we already talked about you and it
was very sweet piece we're not sure that
works because okay sitting in a nice
hotel what's all this valley and trail
of homeless leaving a trail of phone
books I have no idea and actually when
you get down to it I'm want to know and
you used up one of your two questions
for the day do it it's yo so what's in
store the agenda everyone got their
schedule he's got his baggage Doug get
their swagger did you Madison okay
Adrian you don't count um so if you go
into a registration area we've got our
visit pieces you get the schedule a bag
full of goodies a water bottle water
valves are actually from previous
columns recent thing I had a couple
hundred of them my storage know what am
I going to do with water bowl so instead
of having more credit this year you just
brought everything we had we actually
watched everything
and storage but we washed everything so
it's ready for whatever you want to put
in it what it is things and legally I
don't know no its way it's vintage why
yes this is from outer zone forward you
can and that was one of the year's
repaired when signature line so um we
got started a little bit late this
morning mine hope that will be done in
just a bit and then Mad Max is right
behind me if you look on the back of
your badge it actually has the lineup of
everybody and see what's the QR code is
to actually go to web page where the
schedule is let's see i earned East
villagey 181 totter pitch Curt complex
litigation in America that's supposed to
be a very interesting um trip is had
been involved in victim the big tobacco
lawsuits and stuff like that he's also
guy who did hazardous which is a
bittorrent client so he's a crazy mix of
law and coding Chris Silver's did the
variance of the line and sinker clock at
skylark on he actually used one who won
the DEF CON social engineering on Valley
News I can get rid of place but our
second place i'm sorry in social
engineering IE got social engineer an
apple so nothing too rather interesting
one Slim Jim and Jeremy or div before I
can you say slim jim what was it was it
smooth that I met you and I hadn't
helped carry somebody to run them or
something yes oh good because he needed
that silentium were standing there I was
on staff or whatever and just if they
were trying to get a guy to room I
grabbed a shoulder he grabbed the
shoulder we tried this God already got
him taken care of he's like thanks very
much anything I can do feel like no and
I said what guess what you can come talk
to me for me to conference so here he is
how many 90 doesn't like three or four
years now
yes I they said no career general why
beats and three is exciting or feedback
um so in our history there have been two
or three different tops that we did not
record one of them was Billy Hoffman
asked us to turn the camera off before
Bonnie did some the various things which
ability is able to do we have we've had
turned off a couple of times because
people asked us not to report it because
it's entirely possible in trouble for
what they're saying um I think Carl oh
yeah Carla would appreciate if we did
because some of this stuff you may say
something that might not make someone
happy so he has to be not report guess
you got to be here for that one another
125 to you around the balances CP I'm in
jail all 55 there previewing there's
zero day code names still Walter so I've
actually heard what it is when I tell
you what it is you have to be here for
it I can tell you it's going to show you
a lot of people up it's really funny
really cool what they've done he won't
be reported you got to be here for it
and please beat her for it because it's
absolutely awesome Scott actually did
one set amount last year then I would
have given my eyeteeth to be able to
record but I respected his wishes that
he didn't want that reported but it was
an absolutely incredible speech and I
just that's the reason for actually
showing up you can see the videos online
but you miss a lot you're not here in
this translation 6pm the hacker movie
challenged skydog vs CP when CP was on
knock on radio we were trading mecca for
movie lines and it must be a pissing
contest and it was like well I can beat
you at trivia on hacker movies so
there's actually five movies Tron and
trust
hackers sneakers damage with whatever
that were right but Morgan's yes how
were they other quick if I movie yeah
liliane's that's all worrying about 30
times in the theater when I was a kid so
that one I'm thinking we're going on so
we're actually going to do a hacker
movie trivia challenge there's a trophy
for and at me so someone's supposed to
come up trivia question for it it may
end up just as fighting the middle stage
so it'd be fun little scouting Moulton's
going to do your cameras were 300,000
dollars from Microsoft I which sounds
like it could be an absolutely killer
free so I talk to you about a little bit
so he therefore that one at eight-thirty
where the contest prize giveaway we wrap
it up as quickly as we can this year and
there goes our life eat and then I'm
going to get polluted with alcohol
hopefully on arts and crafts always
we've had pizza pieces back in the
registration room to play with and
things like that we have a tub full of
cool artsy craftsy stuff we have some
contest to do one of them is decorators
flash which we have the water bottles
that I had things like that if you get
more you will go back there there's
plenty of stuff to play with make
something inventive creative it doesn't
have to be functional but I'll be
something interesting I agree that's one
of the staff members in that we have
pictures of it or you can take a picture
and get it to us so we can judge it
seems gives me the other one is the
outer zone nine logo and theme contest
um part of the fun part about doing our
zone is um if you noticed I am creative
but not artistic I came up with a great
concept for something by zero artistic
one comes down to it as evidence about
front cover so I can draw a straight
line with a ruler and a pen but there
are people out there that are much
better at designing everything so one of
our things won't that's wasn't me okay
thank you very alright
so what we would like to do is for
someone to design either a logo
specifically private of nine or every
year we've kind of had a different logo
or something for the kind if you can
come up with a concept for hours of just
a logo we can use that would be great
the theme for next year would be racing
come over that and we're going to be
judging all those pitch of this guy
daughter on we have I have one called
the best advice award so a little bit
later this talk we're going to discuss
what is going on with outer zone which
direction we're going if you've got a
great piece of advice the best movie
here we're going to give you a board
board or at least some token of our
esteem oh yeah Oh part of the arts of
grassland who's ever had this whole say
things are these people but the whole
things you put on a sort of pens and you
put different colors and hit it with an
iron and it melts flat no it's argot
about yeah I can't really speed making
or something Oh anyone now I shrink it
into something entirely different
basically we have huge tubs of Legos
these beach actually putting an
arrangement sort of 8-bit pixel
fashion-related piece of material girls
apartment hit it with an iron and it
melts them together I an eight-year-old
read an absolute blast doing it oddly
enough a 16 year old and enjoy de-yummy
over come up with something the fittest
it I'm 22 so we got that we got the Lego
contest we've done that before we've got
a huge tub full of Legos built something
Sam some pictures of it so you can get
it to us or if you can't already catch
us in there and we'll take picture of it
hopefully judging that one on the we
have one called the reboot our zone
viral video contest we have in our nets
we have in our midst of celebrity
three down we don't have any more
nervous so anyway um now there is a new
way we have someone who has done some
great work and we wanted to do what we
should do to help out there is a movie
that's going to be coming out called
reboot and it's it stands to be I think
kind of on the level with rural the
dragon tattoo what I've seen them it's
really interesting we have a QR code if
we go home bored what would want
everybody to do is to shoot small
segments of video so we can combine
those together or what I'm need months
under that were to send those in for the
divine together to make the viral video
so it's rebooted amazone so we actually
have several copies of QR code you will
shoot us if it's a video with your
iphone and things like that you can get
that to us we're have a contest to see
your desk the best one that's not about
right yeah i would just said that there
is what we do website now with a trailer
to the film that you're not at all look
at the toilet and did a get some general
impression so you might any more
reflective your lot of our videos if it
is good these really underlying film the
QR code that we have is if you shoot
that it takes you to the website okay
and the trailers on it I would have
pride you to play but I don't press the
network so yeah it's I really enjoyed it
and I can't wait to see it so if you get
a chance to check it out this is an
appropriate
the other thing you can mention whatever
you want you like this idea trailer and
mobile website or various estates sec
sir a slow leak into a advertised
publish a secretive gain economic I'm
Damien's if I'm you might ease grace or
if you're cold i order now cos obviously
both but once inside the game is not a
typical hacker aimed at it is a tegra
game but the person i'll say as much as
the first three levels are involved okay
goes my pine things in there by using
ember oh job i'm thinking there will
stay an honor p or wherever is it's that
type of a game and that swells and the
top 10 scores however we decided to
close out the competition hopkins
horrible and come short but you know if
you're interested in the money is here
with viral video you might wanna check
out grew up freighter although this
number regarding it was hundred odd
behavior to the oh yeah yeah yeah I've
seen the ten virgins policy yeah the
girl the girl who comes to with the
blew through her hand his super
moon intake through him yeah thnkx off
from there you get a chance to watch the
video because it's it was one of those
where I kept running it back and what
can you do four pieces again now I know
why I was doing so that's going to be
sorry did it yeah absolutely as you can
don't trust goofy the wrist is really
quick what's the store parties there
will be at the breakout ring where the
registration area is they'll be fine
unless you have one in your room you
might want to tell everybody on the back
of the badge this is something I started
with my badges my room number if you
kidding are too inebriated remember that
or we find you and we have to take you
he'll be really nice created room number
on their security purposes I understand
if you don't want to put it there the
room numbers to remember is a man
yelling come to my room blah we're
having a party later on so you can write
that number down and keep tractable oh
let's see dinner got loans tonight sign
up breakfast a lot of us will go to ihop
tomorrow it's kind of become a tradition
for you like if at ihop is any morning
so we will go out there and take over
one of their rings and try to eat
something that will that everything to
drink the night poor sweetie it might
talk huh which I'm going to sit through
outer zone 101 the interest outer zone
oh I professor skydog for a little
adventure here today so introduction of
the founders of icons originally outer
zone was started with five people I
think it's correct fine he's holding
four different states and was put
together in under two weeks so you can
see my reputation for doing this and
short-term motors lady Berlin pres mind
Joe Klein myself no I'm missing
something I know rattle was involved
with money now because decode was in
solarium in Kuala look at some point
that there was um so there's like a
group of five of us that God's talking
about it and decided to to start outer
zone um there are some other people that
have been fixtures Scott of course is
one of those fixtures where you call
them a knob whatever Ziploc you've been
here for many years I know there are a
lot of people that are just kind of a
stable the standard
you can ask them about below and stuff
about outer zone his strict up today
I'll see ya yeah streak is another
person who's been involved with
beginning Billy Hoffman he'll be here
later on today um so they're very a
bunch of people who have been here
pretty much from the start it was here
like I was only one or two whenever and
he's a perv I'm so yeah it uh it started
off as a teeny tiny conference and grew
a small conference something we think so
the history of outer zone starts out
with us five people the reason is um
there is a gentleman in town named Lance
medal is brightening his accra handle
was rocket and rocket um put on
conference called entrance on IMDb RZ 0
NE which is kind of funny miss myself
outer zone gee I was somewhat created
but not much without her so i showed up
it enters them to mirage and i were in
Nashville he said man you want to run
down there and this is back when I was
younger and with Dominic over didn't he
at the top of the hats and we drove from
Nashville down here Patera really not oh
there wasn't a ton of stuff going on but
there were some decent number of people
hanging out and it was my first
introduction to hit his own rocket
everybody involved with that meeting um
I think I'm having a hard time finding
anything on Alpha website archive for
some reason archival or doesn't have you
been I went to I think and enters only
three at harrah's own to is where Billy
Hoffman released his information on
blackboard his first season assists so I
think was where's what was with into
virginal and Billy both release that
they got the first east insist so you
know I bust your cherry what you say and
resume free i think i went to that one
and
get his own for around that was when we
actually decided to be we were really
keen on how things were yelling what
took place was the price to units in
tourism at that point was like a hundred
bucks 120 somehow radius T the reason it
was that expensive his reign was trying
to grow everything as much accelerated
rate so he had like waited most of the
hotel everybody cons face they had and
he had to charge an hour delay but he
really wasn't bringing your content to
justify because you know last year you
know what eff got 150 160 pots when I
first started going it was around two
hundred dollars well this was like six
years ago so he was trying to get an
entry fee than that but really was
bringing quality and we felt brain
wasn't doing it for the love game he was
going to get to make profit now there's
something to be said for that but um the
thing was he had asked people to help
him and he didn't reciprocate take good
care of him he kind of walked on some
people and someone said screw this mama
just go there and have a party okay
sounds like a plan and someone said hey
probably have our own little con me or
we'll just do it because less people get
a ring together and have a party in
other how I beat adults so if you can
imagine the first year we were in a
suite Joe Klein actually fit the bill
for it I showed up and this is in the
two-week period you may badges register
the domain name put everything together
and showed up in course and had a con
they were like 35 people that show up to
this thing so it at that point is just a
joke we're all sitting around doing toss
and drinking and it has a common thing
with this gun um so we do orderable our
little heel and kind of you know to
print which was enemy on the back of the
badge at the funds is attendee and
everything I've got some you know the
house if you flipped around the back it
was
the picture thing it was basically
pointing at you and a rocket on the
bottom anyway I really regret that now
because it was just the meanest thing I
think I've ever done to somebody because
I was having a conversation with even
that post imagine stood around either
see about that tall so I actually had
the only picture I know of a rocket that
was ever taken I couldn't find it
beforehand but I snapped the picture and
I think the best of my knowledge I got
the only one out there did anyone the
evolution of it he had started with one
ring but I sit around everybody said do
this as cool as do to him and they're
really okay Cheryl duty so the second
year we actually met in a river of
children asleep we took Oliver injured
pilot in one corner I went at lunch
you've got a bunch of McDonald's
cheeseburgers walking impossible if you
know one of the beds are won't sit on
and we just had a little funds out of
convict him on it mute grew a mutated
from that to play I was agreed where I
actually called some cons base this is
when there was a convergence ran didn't
do hinder zone after that it basically
became enough a money suck that he
couldn't make it happen anymore so he
stopped at that one there's no reason to
try to do dat same hotel so everyone
said well let's do it again well that
one what do you do except coronas
they're bringing out a conference space
and have me Helen so it kind of went
from there that was three we're now at
hours in a so you can see the review
years where we headed you know that we
actually hit it legitimately we've been
at this hotel for three or four years
now or something like that so until they
throw us out we had to find different
venue we're out of here which brings us
around to the challenges of current
state um so
um there are certain bits and pieces
about our zone that total kind of reflux
um you see there's the sky dog calm
water in the graphics that are out
though yes which 1i put together you get
you can tell um there are things like
the website yeah I got put up 30 days
prior to the conference that on the
site was a red circle hey servicemen
sounds great yeah oh yeah that they
could work oh there I actually had some
pictures I was going to put it here I
went from just recently from an 820
square foot house to a 3300 square foot
house if you can imagine I had enough
to fill any vendor square foot
house for sealing deploys so we've been
in the process of putting our families
together and moving all my stuff from a
lot of it away much to my chagrin and
make me very much happier but so I've
been juggling a lot of stuff you've been
working scott caan we've been working on
the a consortium makers basis in
Nashville I work for a large southern
university two kids houses who owns a
house you realize the fall apart of a
regular basis so we have to mess with
that and you know what grass continues
to Grove no matter what you do to it and
it's just that they're that so around
yeah there's always a lot of that round
it all good master longhorn that's nice
you're on it aren't you well actually we
have a much better thing it's a lot of
this concrete that was one of the
appeals in this place is a huge drive
out front was like I'm going to move
that section yeah we're up beyond 60
know is if you have kid
and paralyzed as soon as they get their
arms up to push the push mower it's time
for them to start um so one of the
problems that are the challenges the
queries that we have at this point is um
you know where we add with everything
outer zone isn't me I'm just a guy who
makes all this stuff come together in
one general area so outer zone is you
guys all right it's the fingers it's the
attendees because honestly I'm only
entertaining for about 30 minutes and
I'm 45 minutes into this so if you guys
are giggling and laughing just to be
nice so I'm not outer zone I'm just the
guy who gets everybody together with a
for shooting website listen goofy
graphics he says hey come on down let's
party it's the attendees and the
speakers that actually make it happen so
I'm only deciding what takes place
merely by someone saying hey nobody go
on you blah blah blah cost less than
what I've got in my life then we can
talk about what we're doing Grover
you're giggling because you know that's
that faintly oh that would be cool well
again um so basically what we're trying
to get down to now is um what is ours on
what he wanted to be so if I was
independently wealthy and trust me I've
dreamed of this many many times we would
be at the Four Seasons right now you
would be sipping champagne or they are
messed up no wonder I don't let oh well
you know enough money they probably
would we've got that money well they're
like yeah if i had the cash we'd be
drinking on we have party you know
caviar whatever you wanted we'd be doing
that we would have the coolest you're
available we've been playing with
everything possible but contrary to
popular belief I am NOT
I am NOT dirt-poor that I worked really
hard not to be there for to be
moderately okay I have enough money I
was it will drive down here but I was
standing in pump going that's its visit
asking so um because the way this is
actually put together however somebody's
paid for out of our pockets it was sky
daughter myself it's basically one of
those things where we're looking at
what's going on what are we going to do
what we spend I'm trying and things like
that there is no outer zone bank account
where there's this big chunk of change
you may have a credit card my things out
of it literally is just directly out of
our bank accounts Scott is also the
exact same way he is the person who is
responsible for booking the hotel
getting the dates its if you follow us
so Scott is actually responsible for
that if we don't get enough friend count
he's on the line theoretically to pay
the tab on the yahoo tell so there isn't
like some huge organization that makes
what's happened it's like yeah I know I
feel that the your website up i'm
going to show you and I said yes dear
I'll that's up and as she told me for
the sixth time to put it up because you
guys send emails to be and then you said
her she responds to you and it's a bit
so um basically outer zone is you guys
you tell me what you want to do and
here's some of the things we've got to
kind of look at UM the size that we're
at about 100 people show up to the
powder 150 depending on what's going on
it's kids are any people we don't count
those you know you're on your own it's
only only button and is he looking for
um some people said hey no can you make
it larger oh yeah absolutely that if you
look at skydog gonna have the entire
infrastructure to do a pull you know
several thousand person conference
without a problem but also requires a
lot more money on more things that front
it with what we've done we're probably
in four not three green right now and
then it's not
like I say out of some you know from the
fairies bank account that's on a credit
card that's out of my pocket it's stuff
like that so if we want to grow out as
only requires that we probably start
selling tickets bellowing and they have
a system in place called ticketleap
through the users have all kind of works
wonderfully but we'd actually have to
sell tickets on the appeals of outer
zones if you show up you want to donate
goal if you don't you don't have to if
you didn't you know you showed up your
love you know what this is a worthless
I can't believe I politic what are
you didn't buy a ticket you didn't have
to tell me so you know you're not going
to go to provide anything that's the way
we like it if you enjoy it though some
cash in the container one of the things
about the cons whether we put it
together is a lot of guys show up wrote
in the back to someone's big you know
ain't going to go with you they show up
there eating cheese and crackers to
survive they don't have any money to
throw the donation tank that's cool we
all have to start somewhere so i will
expect them to be able to pay for it but
i expect them to come out have a good
time so if you're standing there in the
guy next to you is looking at his you
know handful of change trying to figure
out what he's going to do though some
extra in is you gotta help somebody out
help them get their start that's kind of
what we've tried to do a hooker what
we're doing here so do we want to grow
do we want to go to a different hotel
this one lets us do damn near anything
the last time we were in the sky Dogtown
hotel once the once we hit the door they
looked at us and when yeah we really
can't have two parties during
negotiations we were good but right then
in there they so if we go to a larger
hope to help what do we do now we have
the ability to do things here do we want
to grow it if we want to keep it the
same size one of the things on the back
of the t-shirt i think is eight enough
now or eight is enough who knows your
big day that is that we're ziploc
edition you know Tim so the line is
eight enough have we done
now now do we want to keep going as you
go and I'll show up every year because i
don't care i have a good time doing but
what do we want to do you know continue
on if you stop here to be growed gets
smaller um you know you like trying and
all these things are all questions that
we want to ask you guys and no I fans me
right now because if they go longer but
over the course of the day comes up to
us you know well we have the best advice
contest come up with what you are you
think this is the best advice for what
we ought to do but it's not so um what
is in resume got you on the last point
we a Carolina company kind of kind of
run into the same thing and you know
everyone thinks it's kind of an easy
question do we want to get bigger do we
want to you know limit it now but the
problem is is you know people say what
we like to keep it a small you know
group him but what they don't understand
is ok to keep it a small group that
means we have to stop people from coming
to the time I'll putting a liminal yeah
so to keep it small we need to put some
kind of a limit so that means you make
come to the con but your friends may not
be able to make you so now suddenly is
it a good idea to keep the smaller what
you know let anyone in yeah so it's not
it seems like an easy question but it's
not much to do the coupon that's it
tomorrow there's been just rude yeah and
that's what everyone complains about
exactly I agree so the model of shmoocon
did the first year they did they invited
all of their friends and they call the
other people and it was like thousand
people standing there and I went wow
this is pretty cool and in those
thousand people said hey you should come
to shmoocon they're nice but that'll be
really cool and then ticket sales I
think in cheese they sold 500 tickets of
my 12 seconds literally they have a bank
of servers with a custom wrote code for
that operate really a maximum potential
for one hour a year
and they will it literally will crash
them on a regular basis it's become so
popular because there's only 1500
tickets available to the column and
everybody wants to go and then the crux
of the situation is you don't get taken
your buddy gets to go okay screw gun
sucks man there go they're saying
they're going hope you know we have one
of largest venues and washington DC you
can't find the space to put it on so
then what you end up with is you know
then you're being elitist scumbags or
something because you're only letting a
certain number cable app so if you guys
know you go back to the house and I'm
going to computer your cruise and
everything we actually sit down all the
calm organizers will get better go and
you know what do we do about this
because I've set and conversations with
cutting grooves about the direction they
were doing you know with this shrink on
it's what do we do because everybody's
wanting to make it larger if its larger
we live that small-town feel which is
one of the things I mean human kind of
absolutely love because it's a smaller
cop that's really going to get down to
it it's one of the higher encompasses
you're going to go to but it's really a
nice intimate feel so a lot of that is
something we have to kind of deal with
on a regular basis which direction you
go what do we do can you keep everybody
happy everyone said I can't believe put
it on this date right the funny part
about that is I had nothing to do with
the day this guy over here in the
forensic unit happen is one you pick
today and you know what that's based on
it is not based on astrological charts
with a hotel that is they like it when
I'm not on an airplane yeah at the only
thing thing this is the only weekend and
this month that Scotty molten is not an
airplane is in this state oh I am oh
gods like are the dates are this put
them on the website illness that's
literally how that gets decided I have
nothing to do with that part really has
no guy that both orbit on essays all the
difficult nowadays beautify it we get it
3g other pet I origin argue that all
hotel that edit yo gotti the hotel space
so far anytime so how much bounce out
and
think of a project on that one has
reached a list of different conferences
p.m. thurs like is involved in that one
check out do you get points to the
regulation okay it's hard to schedule
something happen if they get it when I
got another content you get it on
Mother's Day yeah okay you put it on
Mother's Day or you put it on the same
weekend as another conferences right
town and you try to explain to why you
did that and then you get in trouble for
that so it's absolutely impossible to
please everybody with what day you put
it on or where you're going to have it
then also once you start to get larger
like we ran it just this year we had
that we've had to find the only but we
had to find the only hotel in the area
that would hold over 300 people yeah
well now we're the hill oh so we'll see
how that ends up this year with our
knees and everything else so but you
paid grieving widow within a thousand
bucks tonight romy room yeah so it's
hard breastess are we stood at a charge
believe up to persuade our poll we did
so and for you Israel yeah that gets
tough also yeah one of the things we've
run into with Scott O'Connor is you pay
X number of dollars what's my return for
you I a try Gaia the man to get food for
you to eat things like that i mean you
know what's what's up what am I giving
back to you because I won't give you
nothing for your money I want you to get
something in return to be able to say
look what I got this is the things I did
so we battled with that all the time to
your yours I'm paying for the bucket
ball you get a decent piece of trying
and imagining that twenty bucks is Colin
like that exactly yeah um which brings
us to what's wrong with profit and
honestly nothing on the property now I
don't think that there's a problem with
making a profit on the conference if
it's men
via profit-based conference as long as
you give the attendees the best paying
for the reductive you can give up and
still make it out alive okay so um you
know I I don't think that the model of
its altruistic I have to lose money is a
great thing to do because honestly you
know I don't have a ton of it sitting
around I do this for fun but if you if
you sit down with Scott said Scott what
do you think about the outer zone the
models gotta go he is kind of display my
why does he do this because Scott's a
businessman we've had conversations and
Scott goes I don't know why you're doin
anyway just the way I want to do stuff
yes okay so probably not bad it's not
really the direction we're set up for
and yet we went after her brand because
what he was trying to do with it but I'm
not trying to turn this into a profit
Center so don't think that we're trying
to grow it to make more money that's not
what we're looking for the con within a
common we actually it was coined makan
within a column by rattle we
theoretically in the hacker con circuit
are the origin of the convent a company
which i hate to actually think I'm
employees for something but is it ok
whatever become within a con the second
iteration with that was barcamp in boot
camp our camp was you know if there was
no boot camp I think and they started
get selective and you could show up
unless you're a developer you did this
that's they started our campus screen
you're everything that was the second
iteration who knows what the third
iteration is flat besides holly cow it
was like hey b-sides you're showing up
for four thousand dollars to black hat
guess what we're going to go sit by a
pool get every class we hear the exact
same talk because the guys going on
stage shake hands get a car go get a
swimsuit and sit by the pool and do this
up so which one do you want to do so ask
me how many people you think go to black
hat because their company pays for it
but just show up you get the rollback of
stuff and then go get
I stirred by the floor b-sides I mean
what you say here what would you say oh
come on hit it already um so the
evolution we had the collapse of
Interzone the debate about whether we do
a real converse is a small kine on the
we have the our current model model is
the no cash no pay if you don't like it
you don't have to pay I think that these
are small did not oh nothing so um it's
funny how the work that I don't care go
get your bifocals um so kind of the way
that we've done it and we feel good
about doing is if you don't have
anything well you will find your son
you're young you don't have any cash you
know last night if you have a box full
of rice krispie treats in the sky or put
together get gas I think straight aight
a rice krispie treat with a kick out on
top of it i'm not sure how that was it
sound like it was pretty good um you
know no lodging you have a place to stay
we will figure out a way to get you in a
hotel room or something some way or
another um you know if you might be
crashing to the floor with somebody else
they'll step over here go to the
bathroom you know though transportation
okay we have right share hey I need to
ride where you at a lot of people will
say hey I'm coming by that area if you
could be ready to go at this time I'll
take you picked up taking around um so
the a lot of the I skipped around in
some distress I'm prone to do it from
time to time do you want to keep the
donation based do you go to the pay
model is up to you guys staying small
and going it there we want to hear what
do we want to do find the time I I am
probably one of the busiest guys I know
just short of what stopped us I Scott
stays awake and worked harder than I
and it scares me to think of that he is
constantly checking the job to making
things happen I need people to actually
help me somehow you the website give up
with a thing you want to come out Carlo
got drafted and we run a navy longer
death yeah we've had a lot of people say
hey Alton website for you well other
watch it was like yeah these guys this
guy dog said you're not doing the
website yeah no you're not you know so I
said how many actin I can put something
up because no you're never doing was
like yeah ok cool so we were talking
when I landed no way yeah we're already
get out number until we put the awesome
website up always ndes we went to went
to a group in Asheville and said hey
here's the deal we need a website with
some identity were you do it for us and
they said sure and it goes would repulse
know like an old and she said love you
you don't have the time to do it if you
suck at me do and everyone knows you
suck at so I know I said you know I saw
ok so a lot of you august do what try
did I was in front page so um so we need
some money that is artistic that
actually has the time when we understand
we've had people say I'll do the website
but stuff happens in your life too you
know and I got married we had a kid and
I don't have time to do it well if you
say you're going to do it I don't do it
and then you come back and say well I
can't do it guess what it's a duty ends
don't stop so we need to find someone
who will actually do the website and
take care of that people who want to get
involved who can devote some time to it
and know they can post some time I'd be
thrilled with that because you know the
last thing you want is me to actually
did website again
we actually were discussing ahead but
the long list of the things that I
actually do with my time but it's boring
I swear um so we have the staff a lot of
people through the standard people that
show up every year and Carlo Carlo came
in one day said hi and Carlo I was in
one of Scott's classes and I said I
hated feel I have a seat right here this
is the video written turn this on if he
went away and then realized Scott
brought him in it's got to play here's
probably is going to work so hitman he
is now the is a core team members gato
con he's actually in charge of using our
corporate sponsorship so he walked in
and said hi and I just assimilated comes
he's been ever since so here come trick
it hit man I love you though man I think
you so we have kind of the standard
complement of staff which we went
through we have a few people like 10 you
said still too long you got drafted into
being part of staff we do some extra
shirts and extra badges everything ain't
river bending and pull this up there's a
shirt you're in charge oh so we have no
problem with people who want to be
involved and want to help out we love it
you can visit time we have the sponsors
the nice little banner right here my
hard drive died someone is up that's
will scott molten over here top dog data
recovery of the three this has got to be
the funnest and day to recover company
that's carlo good to give back my porn
comment you get some stickers you broke
right okay if you really want to freak
out the people at your office photos on
your laptop on top dog LLC is actually
the company that puts on scale qahness
its Robin I it's a couple of the other
logos up here the hacker consortium was
actually where a lot of the like the
stand i have here all that was created
so there's a lot of different groups
come together we have tenacity
the first actual real corporate
sponsorship that we got which was like
hoping our kind of some of the gym it
and then that bring us in the chat can
you go okay she's worthy Saddam's DC 949
we've got tool with deviant irony course
compound we try to and not everybody on
this little banner appears give us
kashering things to people who have
supported us by giving us lag or coming
out and giving us a hand with things are
just being really cool so yeah so we
also have the attendees and speakers you
guys are actually what what what makes
ours don't happen have the for the
longest-running donation-based
conference we know up if there's another
one let us know so we can apologize the
best of our knowledge we are the
longest-running we're looking for our
long-term identity that's kind of what
this is about figuring out what we're
doing where we're going whatever you
want to be it's your con I'm not going
to tell you again good unless it's so
expensive I can make it happen we did um
we were talking about doing outer zone
origami and the easiest way we kind of
put this together he's even got like a
20 in her pocket yeah go put it in the
other stuff haha if you'll take that
length wise here will do this if you
fold it in half this is very weird we're
gonna you'll fold it one more time it's
just the right diameter go into the
donation bucket on the back on here so
that's our version of our zone workout
yes sir yes yes but that's not really
bad as I'm going to working the rolling
to them mr. Stroud she be hatin
beautiful digs up us the squares again
there is an origami said back there but
you have seen the program I'm not native
I don't you're just rages is here he's
wonderful I suck it all that but um so
donations are
vague registration I love you'll see
some people staff out of blue badges
speakers have read if you talk to Amy of
registration what we decided to do is if
you want to be a sponsor if you get a
forty dollars reward will give you a
sponsor baggage which has your name on
it it's great as you say honey those
cash maybe you did that help out the guy
next to you couldn't a rich everyone
that is we wanted to say thank you for
that we want to have everyone's name on
the website yes i will update the
website and we also want to happen to
close you talk to say thank you um one
of our contests here's a trivia quiz
rolled on facts about staff and sponsors
of outer zone a little while they'll be
available back in the registration area
so some trivia that you have to answer
when the contest so idiot enjoy your con
we appreciate you coming out I'm gonna
get offstage sign up on Twitter so we
can simply send some things out teachers
are available from ten o'clock to four
o'clock which should be really soon
where the grating blows is it and like
you guys turn in every project on time
at that time registration closes at four
around the house there are sea grass in
the registration area sign up for dinner
Malone's if you can make breakfast in
the morning if you hungover we
understand any check on this in 11 so
buyer beware we also have a tradition
going to frys on Sunday afternoon if
you're not from around Atlanta it's a
treat if your are from Atlanta will
screw you I don't have a fly every time
I come out here we have to make the tray
Robin sits in the car or wanders around
the store drinks a cup of coffee while I
poo and on touch everything every aisle
so get rid of fries it is like a Walmart
electronic toys as though go with us
it's a lot of fun so yes thanks for
coming out
charge as far as late as we did I figure
about its hand wash