[Music]
good afternoon everybody i'm glad you
could attend my talk I know it is
getting late in the day and you're
probably getting a load of information
so I like to kind of keep this
light-hearted informational and just
have a good time please there's a going
to be a section for answering our
question answer at the end but if you
have something that you really want to
ask by all means raise your hand I'll
try and address it we only have a period
of time so I want to make sure that we
get through the presentation as was
communicating the introduction the topic
of the conversation is could a few lines
of code it all up and this is kind of
looking at some aspects you may bought
not be thinking about when you start
developing in open source so more than
ninety percent of commercial
applications make use of open source
software open source software is great
but you're always concerned about what
you don't know and I'm going to get into
that a little bit more as we start the
conversation today but one of the major
open source packages that people are
using nodejs it's quickly becoming a
leading framework but there's some
issues with the repository in the way
that it's being used in communicated and
downloaded by the consumers of the
technology if you will so I do not know
how to totally pronounce this person's
name right I get take a guess Asia
kakhulu is what I'm going to go with
anyone have any other alternative
spellings or pronunciations no you can't
get creative if you want well there's a
story associated with this this is a
fairly anonymous developer that decided
to liberate his modules following a
disagreement with NPM staff who knows
what NPM we're going to talk about it
but who knows what mpm is very good so
he got into a fight with node package
manner and said fine I'm taking my ball
I'm going home his ball being his coat
you should fall as an example there he
takes his code and goes home among them
was a module named left pat ok he takes
his code how does that affect other
people how does that basically may be
hurt as was mentioned some of the major
organizations in the world this obscure
developer nobody's ever heard of takes
his code and goes home and there's huge
ramifications when somebody was trying
to use an apple you know a package left
had was a dependency and it would cause
things to go awry if you can see you get
all sorts of error messages it's missing
let that it's gone it's no longer a
dependency that the code that they're
trying to use is looking for so
highlight this and this is where we're
kind of going with this conversation
left pad is not an in the NPM registry
you should bug the author to publish it
well you bug him always want he took it
and went home or use the name yourself
anybody know the ramifications of that
and the way NPM works it's only the name
is the identifying piece so if somebody
else wanted to upload into NPM something
called left had everything would then
just consume that there's no versioning
there's no specific mapping to something
else so somebody else could basically
just say up it's gone i'm going to put
it in there and they could put whatever
code they wanted in that piece of in
that piece of download very very
dangerous in the concept so what this
really did was left pad was used by over
40 mpm modules so immediately there were
40 modules that people were using
including the two-parent of reactant in
Babel were used by Facebook and Airbnb
and many others these at these apps just
broke they started to look for that
missing component and they broke this
actually triggered a very conceptual
interesting conversation about how can
this guy just take his coat he put it
out there for use as part of an open
source package and it's gone how can
this happen shouldn't ought to be able
to unpublish his work without a process
what happens to the available module
names again everything is mapped by
their name and if somebody takes it out
and it's gone somebody could jump right
in there and put the same name in there
so you don't know what you're getting
sometimes you have to be very cautious
about the dependencies in the
availability to the code
now we'll talk about the npm platform as
was mentioned the npm platform is in the
upper right hand corner mpm no JS
package manager it is primarily the main
point or managing of open source
packages associated with no jeaious you
can find share reuse packages of code
from hundreds of thousands of developers
and there's around 300,000 modules
available it's a lot of code to choose
from a lot of things you don't have to
do yourself why do you want to reinvent
the wheel when somebody's already
created the wheel for you much easier to
use somebody else's work as long as it's
tested as long as it's used
appropriately from thinking about this
too around a hundred thousand of these
modules have no dependencies they are
what they are however 200,000 of them
actually have dependencies some of them
have many dependencies one of the
biggest numbers we saw on our research
single modules that have more than
80,000 dependencies you got to think
about that that's complexity complexity
we're going to give some examples of you
may not perceive how many dependencies
are actually happening when you download
a there's b c d e f there's many
different modules that basically could
be dangerous we're going to talk about
how this can be dangerous one of the
things to point out by 10pm semantic
versioning it incurred mpm really
suggests and uses semantic versioning
the example on the bottom really gives
you kind of a comical look at the
caveman is now the super robot it's if
you're a dependency is just inherited
there's no control over that so
dependencies are not locked to a certain
version by default for any dependency
the pendency author can push a new
version of the package that's great
keeping up-to-date add new features and
functions however they may add things
you haven't tested in your applications
you put that into a production app they
push it you don't even know you just are
using the application you assume
everything's the same they publish a new
feature
that may cause something to work
inappropriate linear application so
really be cautious about that and I'll
talk about some ways that you can
prevent this in a couple minutes one of
the other things and this is a real
security risk mpm as persistent
authentication you are not logged out
until you manually log out so you open
up the MPN connection you download a
bunch of modules you're using it and you
go to do something else how many people
lock their laptop every time they leave
be honest every every every time I see
like probably ten percent you know I'm
victim of this to you get up you leave
maybe it's only a couple minutes here
with colleagues if you're logged in
there somebody could go in and change
something and upload it to your NPM
registry it's possible you're not logged
out you go and you leave your lap stuff
maybe someone else has a even if you're
locking machine one of your co
developers has access to your machine
has your login credentials they could go
in and publish something under your
repository change one of the things that
is a dependency that you wrote there's a
very you know when you're using this in
a commercial world this is of concern
because you don't know what is going up
you're just basically you're taking the
reviews and the recommendations of other
people out of the word of mouth aspect
but this is definitely a risk this is
something that's a real risk within mpm
it's a centralized registry that means
npm f tongue-tied and PM utilizes a
centralized registry typing m npm
published ships your code to the
registry server or it can be accessed by
anybody very easy to do i have like a
automated demo that shows you how simple
it is it basically publishes it and then
anybody can download that and if the
dependency it's going to come down as
part of that package let's take an
example this is just something to think
about how many people actually are using
NPM today are using nodejs i had one few
a few this is especially if you're not
actually a developer and you're actually
managing teams this is something you
should ask your team's think about this
so for example
there's a package called active
directory it's for authentication pretty
much ldap authentication for auth it had
around 13,000 downloads last month this
is this presentation that might not be
up to date with last month when I Kirk
when the presentation was committed
created that was the actual number a lot
of downloads and then to think about it
it has four dependencies that's what it
lists for dependencies you think that's
the actual value dependencies it has
this is where the the scary aspects of
knowing what is in your code really
happens for dependencies if I click this
this is the install it's a little
animation here this will work for me it
doesn't work in a slide presentation
well this is an animation of the
download and a basic all this chunk of
data pops down and there's a big chunk
of data you don't understand what it is
but hey it works it seems to work it's
in there that's light so this little
interesting math 4 plus 10 plus four
plus one equals 19 query the audience
what do you think that means well we
know for there's four dependencies
there's your r4 dependencies bill
directly from a go there's our four
dependencies and this is going to go
quick and I'm going to talk about one of
the tendencies
each one of these dependencies has
multiple dependencies one of the
dependencies is this very unique small
file called lodash anybody know what lo
dashes it has 82,000 modules that use
this so we'll do the same thing 30
million downloads because of all the
dependencies that using it has zero
dependencies so it's consumed it doesn't
actually consume anything and it has
82,000 dependence so I think about that
preview example with left pad imagine if
this one was taken out how many modules
how many how much code in the world
would break if this was removed and
again with the with the concern about
when you're the persistent log in the
semantic versioning all that really
takes effect on many different types of
application so again a couple lines of
code really could mess everything up
because this is a couple lines of code
this is low dash that's all it is looks
pretty important not that somebody
couldn't do this that by themselves very
very quickly but that's all it does so
if somebody was to take this piece of
code this this low dash out of ndm it
would cause a lot of havoc for a lot of
companies so a couple lines of code
could really mess everything up
questions up to this point a lot of
head-shaking and we already talked about
90,000 89 90 90 s a bigger number
everyone gets impressed by bigger
numbers so let's look at some potential
scenarios you could create a useful
module do some good old marketing push
your module make it sound like it's the
best thing since sliced bread it does
the most amazing computation it saves
you time it does all these things it
gets a mass adoption
hello dash and then you update it you
change it for maybe your own personal
gain maybe financial gain maybe you just
want to mess with people but it is
possible you could create a module with
a similar name it was a security
researcher that had a research project
they uploaded there is a module called
coffeescript Co ffe script they uploaded
c 0 FF II dash script they just change
the name a little bit one letter tons of
people downloaded it thinking it was the
actual coffee script you have to make
sure you know what you're downloading it
was widely widely successful research
project by a security researcher on how
to potentially leverage npm taking over
control of the legit account somebody
walks away from the workstation you know
what you're doing you know you want to
upload you know what the name was
something is you could very easily take
over legit account and publish dangerous
code questionable code insecure code now
we go that was malicious somewhat
actually trying to do something now we
go to careless so again thinking about
the inheritance of the dependencies and
how far down the chain they are so
everybody take a look at this block of
code I know everybody is maybe not a
coder but think about what would be
potentially the vulnerability in this
block of code any any any comments any
any ideas
yeah it's a potential denial service
attack because you're checking for that
loop with the null byte but you're not
checking for any type of size limitation
so we're going to talk about this and
this is kind of where we found some of
these issues i'm going to talk about
some other ones we basically download
the top 50 popular packages in the top
50 dependent upon packages so something
that people are downloading a lot and
then dependencies that are buying being
consumed by the dependent by the popular
packages and some other packages that
you know we thought were pretty cool we
analyzed the results we performed
responsible disclosure to the developer
because all that's information is there
pull them what vulnerabilities we're
happening waited for a patch and then
publish the data this is where the
interesting part happened so here's an
example of what we did one of the things
that's interesting though if you see
here here's some of the packages we scan
when we scan them the loc is the lines
of code some of these are very small we
cut we contact the the owner of the code
it's a you know a couple line we saw it
lodash look like couple lines of code
you could fix something in there really
quickly some of these are large look at
lodash it's a hundred and twenty eight
thousand lines of code so to find the
vulnerability in that code is going to
take some time even if you communicate
the right information it could take a
lot of time for that vulnerability to be
fixed it and for the information to be
published and everyone to be happy so
consider the complexity in the size the
raw size of these applications can
sometimes delay the process for an
accurate remediation so again here's the
code snippet we were able to do with our
platform identify of a denial of service
attack based on that null byte it was
another package that we downloaded node
ecstatic it has a very very large twelve
thousand downloads in the latin this is
not yesterday this is when i create the
presentation was created a twelve
thousand downloads sixty-six thousand
downloads in the last week
seventy eight thousand downloads in the
math last month 369 other packages are
dependent on this in this head the same
vulnerability you can see very similar
to the other vulnerability we have found
okay so we tried to prove it we sent a
load check marks calm with the null and
we reported it to the developer said I
don't think it's a bug not a bug not
worried about it it's not a bug he said
we think it's really an issue nope don't
bother me okay with a 22 k b payload
weight on one second lag 35 kb payload a
three-second lag and an 86 k palin kb
payload the server crashed this is where
it gets interesting so we go back go
back a couple slides there was 369 other
packages dependent on this 369 so well
we showed him the results of the the
payload he said oh okay then this was
just basically for an old browser anyway
and just commented it out these are the
things you have to be concerned about so
the vulnerable code wasn't even real
code I think it was yeah we usually put
that in there for an old browser nobody
uses anymore so we'll just comment it
out uploaded it and then the payload it
actually fixed it we also found this
one's not publish it so I can't tell you
who it is but we also found a command
injection and the variable input was
used as an argument for an OS command
the flaw exists because the original
author used it possible solution just
delete the file it's still in there he
hasn't fixed it but his fix was ah
that's somebody that's not here anymore
we don't really know what it does just
delete it you should be good these are
the things you have to you know this is
carelessness code that's just kicking
around especially with the complexity of
the dependencies and dependencies of
dependencies you have to be
aware of what code you're using open
source is not it's easy not reinventing
the wheel but you've got to understand
the security ramifications of just
taking what you consider a very popular
again popular package this was one of
the popular packages on NPM but these
were issues that were actually found
some other interesting things that we
found in these popular packages command
injection store cross-site scripting
denial of service by loop denial of a
service by regex CSV injection insecure
randomness and open redirects these are
things that are out there right now that
are being used in major commercial
applications so how do you protect
yourself verify the dependencies of the
dependencies when it says again we had
that little exercise for dependencies
for that package it's actually 19
because the dependencies have
dependencies what happens if one of
those vulnerabilities propagates itself
but if lodash has that vulnerability and
propagates itself to tens of thousands
of applications inspect the code you can
download the code take a look at it
manual review static review inspect the
code before you use it yourself don't
allow these the to execute automatically
MPM install ignore scripts don't allow
it to automatically install use NPM
shrink-wrap to lock down your own
dependencies this is so you control them
if there's an update to the dependency
you're not basically just taking a new
dependency that you haven't tested
against you have a snapshot in time of a
version that actually works sometimes
it's better to write your own functions
lodash was this much code if you really
needed that function how long would have
taken you to write that much code I mean
honestly how much time are you saving
yourself and it's yours and it's not at
the whim of somebody else to possibly
change analyze your code but your code
includes your pendants ease again I'm
really harping on a point be careful the
dependencies be careful oh the unknown
or three levers down that you've never
even considered last one is once you're
logged in log out because again it's
persistent if you don't log out
anyone else can access the system some
other examples and these are you can
actually run your own mpm repo all this
research we did we just downloaded
everything and ran our own repo we are
separate from the main registry server
so if there are any updates there any
changes we knew exactly what we were
testing and how to use it and prevent
installing from the main registry so
those dependencies if something is just
arbitrarily pulled down again the name
there's no version if it's a dependency
it'll just come directly down make sure
that you're aware of this how many
people are using open source code right
now there's a lot of that's what I was
look there's a lot of hands so this is
something that's probably on your mind
are you using anything that's concerning
to you are you doing any testing on your
open source code you can raise your
hands to that to know right in the front
yes it is a concern it does save time
but it also introduces risk that is
unmanaged risk especially with the
concept of inheritance and in
dependencies we are a static analysis
company we can we basically have
resource projects on pretty much
anything so always want to be on the
forefront of testing you know all
different types of open source packages
no Jas is just very popular so we make
sure that we want to help extend the
information to the people that are using
the technology that there are risks that
it well I would give you back some time
like wasn't a long presentation but
sometimes there's a ton of questions and
I get really beat up at the end so I
appreciate you guys being kind to me all
right Thank You Man thank you and it's a
sign of appreciation here's a mask on
zipper hooded sweatshirt thank you so
much