[Music]
if you'd like you can navigate to this
URL and have the slides available
because usually when I come to these
type of events projectors kind of fail
you so if you want to download that
there's a link I'll leave it up for
another few seconds so all right so
fairies good all right so a few things I
want to mention before we get started
the doubletree at an Austin here is run
by Satan themselves they'll sell your
room without telling you you'll be woken
up at all hours of the evening if you do
manage to get a room so some of those
are more suggestions and yeah we came in
yesterday three of us came in and they
sold our rooms they didn't even tell us
so things got interesting does it
actually did have a room where woke up
at 5am so yeah with to a fire alarm so
anyways yeah who knows right there are a
lot of questions uh I don't answer
questions where our rooms go yeah so
about this presentation it's for your
benefit that's why I'm here so let's
keep it interactive if you want to ask
questions let's not do QA at the end
stop me will will cover write that in
there I was like 150 slides so what I'm
going to try to do is give you some
broad overview of some of the things I'm
talking about then dig down where
applicable and stay of that when we're
not so seats you have is Ian they
covered that things I like to talk about
our dev if you I don't know if you go to
any of you have seen some of the dev ops
stuff I've talked about before I really
like breaking into dev ops tooling
that's really fun wrote rails goat
and obviously I'm in a day AWS security
alright so I'm the CTO of a security
company that comes with its own
challenges but then using AWS and being
responsible for the security that
infrastructure a whole other set of
challenges right things are changing
pretty pretty quickly pretty often and
we respond responsible for keeping that
secure so what I have come across from
other security teams is situation and
stop me if this sounds familiar
basically you've got developers who are
saying hey we want to push into AWS and
security doesn't necessarily have that
AWS background rate of us security
experience and it's trying to catch up
or maybe you have a little bit of
experience but still a challenge for you
install this something that's new so I
figure give you some of this the
practical lessons I learned maybe that
will help you all right so high level
going to prevent bad stuff from
happening alert ourselves if it's
happening and then recover from it you
know if the worst case does happen so
basically the practical plan consists of
hardening the environment so it's hard
to get to monitoring for changes that
are security impacting monitoring for
people trying to attack you and then
being able to restore from an actual
attack so um if you have not taken it
have not seen it AWS does a great job of
offering different CVTs this one's free
and it's a security fundamentals course
I really recommend it covers a lot of
things at a high level and some a little
bit lower level so it's it's pretty good
but they give you their security plan
and a lot of what I talk about falls in
line with their security plan so nice to
see the practicality matches up with AWS
as a security course all right so things
are not going to talk about s3 bucket
policies SSH security or start security
groups and ssh keys and things of that
nature that's not really what I want to
get into not saying they don't have a
place but there's tons of checklist and
there's
ends of resources out there and this is
really kind of low-hanging fruit and
speaking of that trusted advisor will
help you detect those low hanging fruit
issues so I really recommend an urge you
to use it and there are two checklists
which I believe are fairly important
that everybody should be kind of
following along with in their 80s
environment those are the operational
checklist and the security auditing
checklist offered by amazon and updated
periodically and as I said there's
security fundamentals course free cbt so
how we're not going to cover the basics
those are some of the things that you
know you probably already know we are
going to cover hardening monitoring in
recovery just pause to take a sip of
water have that get up there all right
so I am hardening basics making it
difficult to reach our environment all
right so number one don't use the root
account for operational purposes we're
gonna talk about some of the things you
can do with the root account to secure
it auditing your I am user policies
we're gonna talk about multi-factor
authentication and some other things so
the root account every AWS organization
or sorry every AWS environment has a
root account we all know this only use
it when you absolutely have to use it
though there are only certain situations
in which the root account is actually
required for most operational tasks root
accounts not required and there's a
reason for this when we go throughout
setting up alerts we want to know that
the root accounts has been you the root
account has been used and so you want to
tell your developers or you want to tell
your team rather ahead of time hey we're
going to have to use the root account
for this specific reason and if nobody
tells you that you know hey the root
account is going to be used and you get
an alert that it has been used you know
to freak out at least that's my approach
so removing this is pretty basic remove
so remove the access keys but one thing
I don't mention here is also enable MFA
on the root account that's a no brainer
and I'll give you a
some more information on that we talked
about mfa multi-factor authentication
okay so I am user permissions this is a
really I really find this to be super
complex in the sense that okay so each
user has managed policy and they have in
online policies sorry I shouldn't say it
in a in a singular formats a plural form
so every user has you know they can have
managed policies in line policies that
can belong to groups that also have
additional managed policies and in line
policies and if you have if ever you had
to audit this in a real organization
using AWS it can become this web of
complexity and you don't actually know
what people have access to and obviously
that's a that's a problem and to briefly
describe managed policies are policies
that can be attached to multiple users
groups roles whereas in line policies
are attached only to one user group a
role I wrote some code it's not the most
beautiful code I mean I'm not sitting
here and saying I'm proud of it but it
does do the job it'll create a CSV file
that actually maps out a user name and a
double us to manage policies to inline
policies and then the groups that they
belong to it's up on github and this is
what it looks like so it gives you these
four columns as I said this is zooming
in now this is a real this a scrub
sanitized data from a real client and
you can see how much how many different
things are in this one in line policy
for this one user so it's a little bit
of a little bit of a catastrophe so why
are I am user policies important so if
your organization that how sensitive
data and I am and you have to actually
audit who has access to what they may
have more access than you realize right
you know I've seen basically a situation
where there were some encrypted volumes
and some encrypted instances or sorry
encrypt there were instances that had
encrypted volumes that had limited
access problem is there were snapshots
taking taken of those
sorry unencrypted volumes that were
should have been encrypted and those
unencrypted volume snap shots were taken
and the problem is that anybody with EC
to access can spin up an ec2 instance
and attach an unencrypted volume when
you encrypt the volume however you have
this KMS set up with an AWS which means
to access the key used to encrypt that
that volume you actually have to be
explicitly allowed to do that as a user
so having sensitive data knowing who has
access to what super important you need
to audit that pretty frequently uh what
I will say is too much accent yeah and
actually that's mentioned in the
incident response it's like the one of
the very last slides but I'm glad you
brought it up because yeah it's there's
my code by the way it's not super pretty
but that output is and also security
monkey has great chain change management
tracking and it's open source by Netflix
yep okay so did everybody hear that AWS
has a framework what's it called the
well architected framework that you
should look up and talks a bit about
some of the stuff that we're recovering
okay so AWS is a flexible environment as
well so as that changes you obviously
knew things get spun up you need to know
who has access it's just a good idea to
know who has access to what we talk talk
about multi-factor authentication for
some use a super simple you already know
how to do this for those that don't
multi-factor authentication is
essentially two factor
authentication if your credentials are
guests or stolen this protects you as
any two-factor authentication piece
would you can use Google Authenticator
gemalto hardware Google Authenticator
being one version of like the virtual
device and Gemalto being the like
hardware device for two factor auth put
a full list in here so we're going to
demonstrate enabling MFA real quick on a
high am account for one single account
you go down to security grant chills you
click manage MFA device click on choose
the type of device virtual or hardware
if you've done a virtual device take a
picture with your phone of the QR code
and type in your authentication code
you're good to go so one problem though
is that unless you have the ia and
permissions you won't actually be
allowed to do this right unless you're
less you're an administrator or you have
those I am permissions you're kind of
out of luck so here's a policy that can
actually fix that so I've got a link in
here for that and this will allow a user
to manage their own MFA device now back
to multi-factor authentication for root
you can use TOTP TOTP protocols
essentially what they used to generate
those MFA tokens or can be shared as
well in like LastPass and one password
and I like 1password so all right so API
and mfa multi-factor authentication is
typically thought of for the web console
but what a lot of people don't realize
is that you can actually put
multi-factor authentication on to the
API the API being what's used when you
don't need to log in a web console you
want to automate tasks which usually
means you want to write some code that
does something and we all know Keys
never get stored in source code so
should be fine what happens if keys do
get disclosed anybody heard of code
spaces 12 nobody else that makes sense
they closed down because somebody stole
our secret keys burned down there a
two-base environment and then
that was it for them they just went out
of business granted though that's not
the usually that what happens in the
worst-case scenario what usually happens
if somebody wakes up and they're like it
we got 10,000 20,000 $50,000 and
expenses that now we're a couple for
allow before because we didn't do
anything to secure our eight of us
firemen that's the most likely situation
so let's talk about and by the way you
will mention you will notice i have
mentioned you're financially responsible
later I'll show you a thread that talks
a little bit i'll give you a link to a
thread that talks a little bit about
that and why you're financially
responsible or it could be so all right
so put the put enable basically in force
so we talking about enforcing mfa this
actually enforces mfa the policy about
to show you on on and on whoever has
this policy attached to their account so
this will require you'll see this line
right here it says condition boolean
multi-factor authentication present when
that's on a policy and then attached to
a group or user whatever the cases they
have to use multi-factor authentication
for the web and the API but it's kind of
a pain it kind of causes problems so
really be careful of where you want to
actually or who you want to attach this
to that's for sure but you can use sts I
have I'll give you some code that
actually here's a gist so I'll give you
some code and walk you through it real
quick it's just a proof of concept
obviously you're not going to use this
everyday for operational purposes but it
does explain how sts works with mfa so
essentially you've got this I've got the
screenshot of code and you put in your
access key ID you put in your access key
secret the serial number of your MFA
device and the MFA codes so your google
authenticator code or whatever you're
using and then when you run this for
3600 seconds this is going to be your
the credentials you get back will be
valid right so it what you get back when
you run this script r is a new access
key ID a new access secret and a session
token and it's again
pretty much available for y'all data to
use and you can obviously change the
duration of how long those temporary
credentials are actually good for this
is an example of using it this is a ec2
API tools that AWS put out passing a few
options we actually we actually get a
response back so we know sts does work
with MFA and if you don't like Ruby you
can use Python or Python and bash I
think it's a combination SDS does not
work with the last bean stock so if you
are using elastic Beanstalk the answer
would be to use code pipeline and that
pulls from sa wsss three from code
commit and then also from github um and
then yeah I'm not going to come so
password policy real quickly password
policies should have some level of
complexity I've seen orgs with no
password policies here's an example
password policy don't want to spend all
the time in the world on it but it's it
is still something to mention so again
make credentials hard to guess make them
harder to use if they are stolen and
protect your King which is a room so
this is like sort of the more fun for me
section alright so assuming prevention
is failed so like let's say an access
key of Abdullah here is stolen I
people's guy work with him i'm putting
them on the spot so let's say your
access key is stolen I want to know that
if you're somebody's using those keys to
do something bad inside the environment
I want to know about it right so there
are four services we're going to talk
about and then we're going to show some
integration and some different things so
one thing to mention is some of the
things going to show you have a lot of
noise so when we get to lambda that
should help you avoid some that noise by
pin pinpointing what you want to
actually hear okay so cloud trail that's
essentially logs to where you store your
logs S&S is used for sending
notifications that's a messaging service
config that's like a that pretty much
tells you
what is changing what has changed and it
does that for every resource if you'd
like it to inside of AWS and then
there's cloud watch which is for very
pinpointed fine-grained alerting okay so
at a high level it's sort of all of
these services feeding down into cloud
trail logs being stored and then that
information being parsed to actually
provide you with some notifications
we're really going to focus on is taking
with config and cloud watch from those
cloud trail logs pushing to S&S which
will send you notifications so cloud
trail basically to use it you just turn
it on you give it a name you walk
through a few steps configure a law
group allow creation of the IM role that
happens automatically and you've got
cloud trail enabled really that easy
it's probably one of the easiest things
in AWS to actually do so S&S now when we
talk about SNS there are a few ways that
you can be notified it's actually more
in a few ways but my favorite ways are
SMS email and now lambda which i really
really do like fact that we can push
tool and lambda with SMS and then if you
want to post your own application
jason's available json requests you can
receive so basically when you've got
really important things happening in
your environment when things that you
should be really worried about are
happening this will have the ability to
alert you in real time that something's
going wrong like if you want a text
message so in order to create a topic
inside of so a topic is something that
you subscribe to a topic topic is a root
account usage the rube accounts being
used so I'm gonna create this topic and
then let's to subscribe to it so
basically you can have multiple
subscribers for one topic so you can
have like your VP of engineering or your
head of security or whatever subscribe
to a topic and they'll know that route
accounts being used in this case picture
of SMS email all right so config we're
moving on to config I'm kind of having
to burn through here so config is like I
said
a tool that just tracks anything that's
that at all is changing based off of
what it's used in cloud trail it's
really nice for compliance purposes for
instance incident response what I can
say is that there are these prepackaged
rules and that list started it like
seven and now it's growing and the ones
i wanted to point out that i actually
think are really interesting is config
will let you know if like root account
mfa is no longer enabled or if it
becomes an if there's any change in the
root account having MFA attached to it
you'll know about it I think it's really
cool that you know RDS those databases
write my sequel postgres taken care of
by AWS a service hosted service for AWS
hosts that for you if encryption is no
longer turned on it'll let you know I
think that's really cool but that list
is available here and you can see how
it's growing you can see what other
prepackaged rules you can choose from so
things that you can be really explicit
about any changes in a firewall security
group any changes in the VPC or anything
at all so this is me saying hey I want
to know about changes in the network ACL
and VPS in the VPC but when i get to the
this other option i say no i want to
know about everything if anything at all
changes and this is super noisy if
anything changes let me know about it I
started with this and then had to sort
of refine it from there because that you
get a lot of notifications so these
steps again you can go back through the
slides but we're going to create a
bucket assign it to an SMS topic allow
the role to be created and that is the
gist with clout watch oh sorry config
now cloud watch this is that where where
it gets fine grain we're going to talk
about so the few things we talked about
are putting alarms on like root account
usage we're going to put an alarm on
unauthorized activity failed logins and
then we're going to show integration of
slack and lambda alright so
we can be very particular about what we
want to see these are the four alerts
we're going to walk through let's go
right to building alarm so why do you
care about a billing alarm if you start
spending a lot of money and your
organization what let's say your limit
per month you usually spend fifteen
hundred dollars and all the sudden
you're spending three thirty thousand
dollars clearly something's up I mean
even if it's not a security issue you
obviously need to know about this so
this is a very basic minimum alarm you
should have so you can navigate to
billing and alerts you'd enable your
account to receive billing alerts you go
in and you create a SMS topic called
billing alert subscribe to the topic now
this part i always like to be very clear
about on the left you see I've
highlighted metrics there are two ways
that you primarily build these cloud
watch alarms logs are cloud trail logs
their cloud trails streams log streams
and that's where you want to actually
put in a filter or it's almost like a
regular expression where you say hey I
want to be looking for these specific
things pull them out of the logs
crockett send a notification off when
that thing happens metrics on the other
hand are predetermined values that you
are going to configure some thresholds
on and we'll show that so when we click
on metrics we can go to billing we can
go and choose the currency this is u.s.
dollars we can go in and say hey if our
spend goes above sixteen hundred dollars
cool create an alarm and the exact exact
steps on all of this can be found here
but again this is sort of the threshold
metric portion of what i was talking
about root login alright so i'm going to
tell you real quick how it works at my
organization if you login in my
organization and you've not told
somebody that you're going to use the
root account and you might have a valid
reason for it but if you've not told
anybody we all go into panic mode we all
we we know the limited amount of people
that actually have access to that
account and yeah it's you have to
respond because we'll keep trying you to
make sure that it is actually you and we
start
to go into like I our mode if after a
couple minutes if we're not hearing from
someone so this isn't necessary like a
policy we put together but when we
enabled this alert is a sort of a
byproduct and behavior of what came out
of that so to actually enable this you
want to go to the log section on the
left instead of the metrics choose your
actual cloud trail log go in put in the
filter pattern that makes sense to you
it's very hard to see on this and I
apologize for that but essentially it's
like this big long regex looking string
a little bit easier to see here so
you're going you'll there's really all
of this is very very straightforward you
give it a metric namespace a metric name
and a filter name right then after
that's done you go and you create an
alarm go in and basically what I'm going
to stay here is that if for if somebody
logs in with the root account more than
once within a five-minute period trigger
this alarm and when this alarm goes off
hits S&S S&S hits us so this is really
immediate so the exact steps again have
kept the links all of this inside the
presentation failed logins so this is
really when someone's either fat
fingering their password or they're
actually trying to guess credentials
these steps are fairly are pretty much
the same as the root login in fact I'm
not going to waste your time by covering
those over and over and over again the
filter pattern howrse differ is
different and so the filter just
basically says hey if somebody is trying
to log into the console and there's a
failed login then alert us and exact
steps once again here okay so the last
so at absa qsa Chris gates and I talked
about essentially DevOps the talk was
called DevOps redox right so we talked
about a lot of fixes for insecurity and
DevOps tooling but we also kind
to talk a little bit about attacking and
one of the tools that Chris wrote was
ADA an AWS interrogate tool essentially
he found tons and tons and tons of
access keys out there on the internet
and so what he did is he Bill a little
Python tool that allowed him to and it's
out its out there on github they put in
the secret key and you can sort of
enumerate what each user has access to
so while he was building that you know I
was like well what can we do to actually
alert pretty fairly instantaneously
about about the fact that you're doing
that so that's what this alarm is
actually about it's why it came about so
alerts us to win somebody's trying that
steps are pretty much like I said
exactly the same as root long and it
failed logins filter pattern is
different as always I keep a slide in
here I keep a link in these slides to
how to do this but this is interesting
to me running the AWS interrogate
enumeration tool when you get back some
information about hey this was possible
this wasn't possible with this user
account but I get and my team gets email
and this is actually this was us running
the tool on us respond waiting for the
response from a double yes to tell us
hey something Bad's going on so we got
an email email it tells us hey something
Bad's going on we have the ability to
see what I am user ID it is in numerical
form wish excuse your name but yeah it's
a numeric form shapes kind of trace that
back but again instantaneously we know
someone's trying to do something pretty
bad which makes me sleep better at night
and yeah it's very nice so what I'm
going to talk about next though is
actually doing this with lambda and
slack okay so however if you want to
build your own alarms because it's just
a starting point these felt this link
will give you the filters set so you can
go through and build your own alarms
okay so lambda and slack I want to talk
about this at a high level real quick so
what really happens is you are going to
go first into we're going to go into
lambda you're going to
create a function and that function is
going to use a blueprint blueprint is a
template of code that's already written
for you there's already a slack and
cloud watch blueprint in there so all
you really have to do is you'll go in
there you'll and you can see it here you
go in there you'll choose the cloud
watch slack alarm and then you'll
proceed through the following steps so
you're going to have to go into KMS and
create a KMS being AWS encryption key
management service they'll create a key
KMS key you'll say here are the people
that are allowed to administer that key
you'll use that key to create so you'll
go to slack and you know say hey I want
to use the incoming webhooks tool and
we'll walk through all this but it'll
say okay well if you want an incoming
web hook that's going to send a message
to some slack channel then here's the
URL that you should use so what you do
is you go in with KMS that key that you
just created and you say ok I'm going to
encrypt this URL slack gave me I'm going
it's going to come back base64 encoded
I'm going to put that into this
blueprint this already written up code
and then that code whenever the alarm
gets triggered whatever alarm I've
chosen which in our case is going to be
unauthorized access attempts then I'll
push that over to slack using the
encrypted URL your encrypted base64
encoded URL that you've given me all
right so like I said choose your
blueprint go in and configure a trigger
in this case is going to be SNS to
lambda I'm going to choose my SNS topic
which is unauthorized access attempts
I'm going to get my blueprint my set of
code that's already pre written for me
go over to slack choose incoming web
hooks add a configuration choose the
room that you want to send it to you you
can do things like you can also on this
page like put a picture associated with
the bot that's going in there or you can
change the name you can do things like
that
and then you can grab the web hook URL
go into KMS inside of AWS create a key
given an alias in this case of his slack
alerts okay now this is using the AWS
KMS encrypt tool notice i ate my own dog
food and well maybe you can't notice but
for the profile for the credentials
profile i used sts to actually run this
so i actually did what I'm recommending
here and had a temporary set of
credentials to run this KMS encrypt with
encrypting the slack webhook URL command
so i give back the ciphertext blob that
blob is what i want to use and put
inside of this code right here this is
the actual lambda code says it's got
encrypted encoded URL or encrypted go to
your own slack channel so you put those
two options in and that's it that you're
good at that point to go so the result
is in slack I mean there's a few other
steps but if you just follow along
through everything I just showed you
it's very simple this is a slack alert
and just basically says and I didn't get
very descriptive here there's really no
reason to this is like the basic
template alarm that comes with it you
can get a little bit more specific on
like who was doing that and more
information that you might want that
anyways there's a notification in slack
a couple minutes after I had tried to do
something that wasn't supposed to do
with a test account so it works all
right so now I'm going to move onto
splunk last parts of this or splunk I
just want to quickly talk about that
then we're going to talk about incident
response and then recovery and then I'll
be it so alright so splunk i really like
it i'm sure you go y'all are using it I
like the splunk app for AWS and spunk
add on the things that allows you to do
I'll show you some pictures but you can
see everything from I am activity SSH
key pair activity whatever it is you
want to see they've got a pretty graphic
for it it can even automate building
your network topology
and I'll show you a screenshot for that
as well so pretty screenshot 1 this is
your you sit usage of your abs
environment to put together it's really
nice and pretty this is the network
topology diagram I was talking about
that's really nice and then this is your
billing information pretty much out of
the box there is a little bit
configuration from your side for for AWS
specifically it's actually nothing to do
with splunk but yeah out of the box it's
you do have to have smoked enterprise
obviously because if you don't have a
spunk enterprise you can't install an
app I don't know where you are you
hosting splunk we may or may not have
multiple splunk or multiple AWS
environments maybe maybe not I don't
know sorry security conference there's
only so much i'll say but that's a good
point though i think what you're driving
at is don't put splunk inside of the
environment you want to secure say that
last part again uh-huh right
and now as your hostage so how big is
funked appointment is running into the
u.s. how expensive is that okay not very
expensive and you can go with your that
what's the smallest here like one gig a
month it's 10 gigabits yeah so that I
think it's one gig for the lowest tiered
paid for version you get away with that
we're I think even the free version you
probably be fine with so it's actually
not that you're not really held so by
the way everything you can do inside of
splunk you can do inside of AWS it's not
necessarily held hostage but sometimes
like you you know it's just one place to
go that maybe or second place to go that
you might like I think it's the easy
button frankly and it shows you so much
without you having to do very much so
and actually on that note to create the
account so you create an accountant's
inside of AWS for splunk so splunk can
grab information and basically there's a
policy that you attach to specifically
for this bunk user and yeah attached to
them they'll attach to that spunk user
they'll have the permission to grab what
they need and you going to configure you
configure per service on how you want to
let stuff two feet in there's a little
bit of extra work which i'm not talking
about side of AWS which involves SQS and
SNS to build that like a few things that
builds on top but you know there's
instructions with splunk the splunk app
to do all this so it's not too
complicated and then yeah which is kind
of what I'm kind of just drove at so
again I love yourself when things change
things will get noisy do instant
alerting when when necessary or when it
makes sense to this queue or thread so
this is like one of my favorite things
to read about this topic because there's
a there's a few things to highlight so
one is everybody if you go to this
thread you'll see everybody saying the
same thing yes my access keys were
stolen or they were leaked I run it ran
up a huge bill with AWS over and over
and over again another thing is that AWS
apparently has a board or they can
review your case
and if you've done nothing too hard in
your environment or you've been you just
haven't taken advantage of any of the
things they offer protect your account
you and your organization can be held
legally liable for the costs that you've
incurred and then I think one thing we
all in this room get but whenever I'm
talking to developers I kind of just
mentioned it is that you know there's
bots out there scouring the web his
name's Chris gates and he's looking for
your access keys and I getting your
environment so all right so restoration
and recovery you should know this these
are some basic things not necessarily a
double yes specific know who to contact
know the channels in which to
communicate over practice that and know
where to go to restore data and what how
to figure out like go back through logs
and figure out what happened so my one
recommendation talking about multiple
AWS environments is do not use the same
AWS environment to backup your AWS
environment that'd be huge mistake a
disaster in fact but what I have heard
people are doing is creating a secondary
or tertiary account using glacier and s3
to move their backups over to that
account and that account is highly
restricted to just a couple people or a
few people may be a security maybe the
heads of the engineering organization
whatever the cases so there are some
resources for actually performing
backups but the problem is I can't give
you a silver bullet there's no product
that I'd love to tell you about a
product that somebody had built that is
a silver bullet and backs everything up
for you seamlessly does it off-site or
whatever the case is but there's really
nothing out there so if anybody's
looking for a product ideas there you go
and then in terms of incident response I
don't really want to talk about this in
depth because back to scout to Alex
McCormick at Derby konnen Andrew Krug
had this awesome awesome talk on
Incident Response inside of AWS there's
a youtube video right it's a really good
talk kudos to them so I really recommend
you go and check out that talk
everything you know about instant
response within AWS I think they'll
cover it
really high level okay presentation
recap I think we all know not to stay at
the hilton the deviltry hilton just my
personal opinion what Zack you'd have
free cookies probably laced with saying
anymore anyways so real recap make your
environment harder to reach limit access
if somebody has stolen some credentials
and it's gotten in have a plan for you
know obviously if things go wrong and I
hope also if you have questions and you
don't really want to talk about it here
just I'm at the conference today and
tomorrow just you know come up or after
this or whatever and will hopefully
answer the question I don't know so
that's my information thanks again
appreciate it thanks
[Applause]