[Music]
okay well dive in and talk a little bit
about mythology on information security
first here's a little bit of information
about me and how to contact me I'm
certainly not up here to tell you that I
have all the answers about the topics
we're going to talk about today I'd like
this to be the first part of the
conversation and so please reach out to
me as comments or questions if you don't
have a chance to do it today and I do
think we'll have time for questions at
the end then here's some various ways to
contact me we'd love to for this to be a
part of our longer-term conversation
with all of you I do ask that you hold
off on any comments or questions until
the end of the talk like I say I think
we'll have plenty of time for that but I
want to make sure that we get through
all six meals so we'll go ahead and get
started one common thread that's going
to run through all six of these myths is
that the words we use matter as
professionals in the industry we
ourselves and the others to and to our
audience to choose words wisely the
words that we use impact our attitudes
they impact our actions and more
importantly they packed the attitudes
and actions of our audience and so we
need to be careful and thoughtful about
the words that we use and what that
meaning that conveys so myth number one
there is such a thing as security we
call ourselves information security
professionals we've seen the word
security thrown around a lot at this
conference but is there such a thing and
do we do ourselves a little bit of a
disservice by using the term so freely
so we'll talk a little bit about that I
have to warn you this myth will take
longer than all the others because it
really gets the heart of what we do and
who we are so a couple of examples I
want to run through the first ones
parenting to talk about the the myth of
security and how it impacts us so most
new parents know instinctively that
their number one job is to protect this
new defenseless creature that they had
responsibility for and it's true our job
as parents are our most important job is
to provide safety to our children right
so generally correct of course it is and
that's why we all wrap our children in
bubble wrap and lock them in the rooms
and would never let them do anything
crazy like play sports or riding the car
because those
things are statistically dangerous we
can absolutely show that if you're chill
up child plays sports they're likely to
get hurt at some point and yet we let
our kids do all sorts of dangerous
things in fact I think in that picture
in the upper left-hand corner that kids
actually putting his hand in fire and
some adults taking a picture instead of
stopping them but somehow we we allow
that to happen and the reason is is that
our instincts are wrong that in fact we
don't have the primary job of providing
security it's it's a definite component
but if we take that to an extreme we can
do our children to service we deny them
a lot of the opportunities that they
might otherwise have and so security
though we think it may be our objective
really is that our objectives is more to
find a balance for our children's lives
and we'll see that as a theme throughout
this let's see if we can find another
example of where the word security leads
us to maybe a bad path so global
security agencies there's a huge civil
rights debate going on not just in the
US but but around many parts of the
world right now on privacy versus
security and then we hear it more in our
industry than in others but it's
certainly become a topic for a popular
press as well and to be honest I feel
for these agencies the conversation
generally goes something like this
citizens say there's all these horrible
things in the world and these things are
absolutely horrible governments protect
us from these horrible things protect us
no matter what give us security and
governments create these security
agencies and these security agencies say
ok to secure you absolutely I need to be
able to get all of your data I need a
giant portion of your GDP and then maybe
we can do something about security and
that the fact is the conversation gets
off to the wrong start because we're
focused on security absolute security is
it possible we live in a dangerous world
and as horrible as these things are
there's nothing that any government can
do to absolutely guarantee our safety
from them and so if we start from a
different path if we start the
conversation not about we need security
but about we need some sort of balance
between funds that were able to provide
between privacy and between safety
that is actually a balancing act and
then it becomes a more useful
conversation we end up more in sync with
the security agencies that we're working
with so really there's two problems with
the word security the first is that it
puts the group in charge of security at
odds with whoever's asking for it
because rarely when someone asks for
security is it actually what they want
really what they want is some sort of
balance between taking risks and and
some benefit that those risks might
provide and the other problem with using
the word security is that it's
absolutely impossible we do live in a
dangerous world and none of us can
provide security we can't provide
security as parents as governments and
not as information security
professionals so really what we're
looking for is a balance and so is there
a term that's better to talk about to
imply that what we're looking for is
this balance and to admit from the very
beginning of a conversation that
security isn't possible could it be risk
management you bet it is and so let's
all this applies to information security
as well it applies to us in the
technology risk realm we put ourselves
at odds with businesses when wherever we
try and take our role as security too
seriously I know when I was a new
security professional newly ordained
pulled in from a software development
job and told you're now in charge of
security for this organization I thought
okay great I'll start making decisions
to help secure the organization and so I
started telling people know when they
started taking risk that I thought were
we're going too far and and I was the
decision maker and quickly the CIO
started referring to the department as
the department of now Engineers start
and developers started to try and work
around us instead of work with us
because we said no instead of being
partners in a relationship and then I
realized that this isn't my decision I'm
not the decision maker here and I can't
enforce the will and the company
actually doesn't want absolute security
companies take risks naturally that's
what they do that's how they make money
and so even though they might declare
that we're the security people and and
and this senior business they think that
they want absolute security when they
actually understand that it the the cost
involved
it's not really what they want what they
want is some sort of risk management
they want to find that balance between
being able to take educated and informed
risk and some some level of safety so
talked a little bit about risk
management I want to take a little bit
of time to go through the risk
management process and for any of you
that we're in Karen loo and Josh Sokol's
talk yesterday this this will kind of
amplify some of what they talked about I
take it from a little bit different
perspective but a lot of this the same
bullet points we're going to hit so this
is the there's many different types of
risk management processes this is the
one that we've implemented the company
i'm at now and it works for me I think
that was slight changes this works for
most organizations so this was run
through it so first roll in at risk
management is to identify the risk and
also and I should explicitly put it out
there to assess the risk and I think
this naturally comes to us as
information security professionals this
is what we do anyway there's not much
difference here between information
security and risk management but in the
next step there is where we start to
diverge a little bit so historically in
the information security realm we feel
like it's our job to address the risk
and so we go off and we implement
controls or we would stop software
releases or we do whatever we need to in
order to mitigate risk but I proposes
risk managers our job is to advise and
to become trusted advisors within our
organization and work with the actual
decision makers in deciding which way we
need to go in order to address for us so
we need to focus on the advise as
opposed to the address so how do we do
advise people to address risk there's
four options I'll run through them
really quick I think most of your pretty
familiar with on the first is to avoid
risk most of the time avoiding risk
involves working through processes it's
process re-engineering and the classic
example and unfortunately one that we've
seen before is you work with the vendor
who's going to send out mailers to your
to your customers and so they asked for
a feat of your customer list you're
looking through the feed that they asked
for and they asked for social security
number how do you need social security
number to send out a mailer well we just
needed a unique ID to identify
honey okay I'm not going to use social
security number will send you something
different and simply by changing that
one little thing about doing a slight
reengineering of that business process
you can completely avoid a risk reduced
risk comes it's for me the more
enjoyable part this is really where we
get technical this is where we're
hardening our systems this is where
we're identifying bugs in our software
and working with developers to plug
those holes so generally reducing risk
and implies applying some sort of
technical control it's also implementing
new software or a new software that
provides controls new tools transfer
risk so this is the rare one it's the
really only valid example I've ever
heard is purchasing cyber security
insurance it's made more at a corporate
level it's not something that applies on
risk that you really see on a day-to-day
basis the only thing worth mentioning on
transfer risk is that it should never be
confused with outsourcing outsourcing
does not transfer risk to the to the
outsourced party you still maintain that
risk if something goes wrong your
customers still associate the data with
you not with whoever us or something to
set something to be careful of and then
last except rescues information security
professionals we just always oh that's
not at me when people are willing to
accept risk it just st. always seemed
insane to me but as a risk management
professional there's a lot of reasons to
etc sand the most common one is that we
don't have the staff of the budget right
now to address it and when we don't
maybe because we're working on higher
priority risks and it's part of our
responsibility to be trusted advisors
then it an advice honestly on risk and
recognize the limitations of our
companies when it comes to staffing and
to resources and so it may make sense to
say okay we don't have the resources to
address this now how about in six months
let's set a date let's set a goal and
then we accept the risk but only for a
short time period something that we can
all agree on and we can negotiate that
we can push to make it aggressive and
reasonable but there's plenty of cases
where it makes sense to accept risk for
some period
but accepting risk really doesn't end
there because the other role that we
have is risk managers is not only to
allow groups to accept risk but to make
sure that the right individuals within
the company are accepting a risk and so
take the example if we have a division
manager that's committed to roll out a
new product it's going to be a piece of
software that sits in the DMZ
customer-facing and we test it and a
week before it's supposed to roll out we
find out it's got enough holes for a
truck to roll through there's it's just
a security nightmare and so we take this
back to the division manager he says
we've committed to our customers we've
committed to our investors I'm willing
to accept this risk but the problem that
scenario is that if somebody ends up
owning that server then they can use
that as a foothold to get to the rest of
the DMZ to get to the rest of the
organization that's not a risk for that
division manager to make it's our role
as risk professionals to escalate that
to the proper level and organization to
make sure that someone who has that
broader view of the whole risk to the
company gets an opportunity to be the
ones to make that risk a risk acceptance
decision and so what we find in a lot of
cases is that when we escalate to the
proper level in the organization all of
a sudden there's a little bit more
hesitancy to to accept a risk and so a
lot of times we'll get sent back to that
advise category and people are a little
bit more open to re engineering business
processes a little bit more open to
invest in new controls a little bit more
open to push back a release for another
week or two to at least fix the highest
priority bugs and so that escalation
process is absolutely key to the risk
management risk management process as a
whole but we're not done there so even
if we would completely addressed the
risk by some combination and I don't
know that I mentioned that these
different ways of addressing risk and
advise they're not mutually exclusive a
lot of times we address for his best son
combination of the four but when we
implement controls either through
process re-engineering or implementing a
technical control or even a
purchasing insurance we need something
in place to monitor that control its
effectiveness the simple truth is the
effectiveness of controls if they're
unwatched will degrade over time it just
happens businesses change people stop
watching it somehow that control is
going to become defective and so what we
need to do is as we are initially in
that advised phase we need to be honest
advisors and incorporate the cost of
monitoring into the control that we
propose and monitoring ideally needs to
be whenever possible something is
continuous and automated we don't want
to have to have people checking on
manual processes we don't want to have
people manually running through logs we
want something that's going to
automatically alert us and so the cost
of implementing that it's a little bit
high upfront but it pays off over the
time and we need to make sure that that
cost and that time frame is incorporated
into any controls that we agreed to with
with our clients and then finally
renewal of risks already mentioned that
when wrists are accepted very often
accepted for a fixed time frame that's
important because we hope to put some
mitigation in place but there are times
where risks are accepted without a
mitigation plan those risks especially
the high-risk need to have expiration
dates those shouldn't be able to go on
forever company's appetite for risk
changes over time senior management
changes business conditions change and
so particularly for any high risks that
are accepted those need to have some
type of exploration associated with it
we need to go back for a new risk
acceptance and many cases because
conditions have changed will find that
it's it's worth it's a good time to go
ahead and try and address other ways or
find other ways to address this risk and
then the last part of the process but
really something that needs to go
throughout the whole process is that we
have to track these risk from the point
the point where we first identify them
to where we assess the severity to where
we work with our clients to find
solutions to how to address that we need
to track them so we need some type of
risk register in our organization that's
absolutely key and so just a little bit
of a plug for Josh
anyone that doesn't already have some
type of risk register simple risk is a
great free tool that's available and you
can find it on the bag that you got when
you checked in here but there's there's
plenty of other tools out there that the
commercial ones tend to be a little bit
pricey if you can afford it great but if
not there's a perfectly usable for you
to love me with one thing whatever you
do even if it's just spreadsheets track
the risk that you identify so some up
here information security it leads us
astray it sets us up with an impossible
mission and leaves us frustrate at the
end of the day because people are going
to accept wrist and they're not going to
let you secure the organization the ways
that you think it should be but and
there's just not enough bubble wrap to
protect that baby no matter how much we
add but at the end of the day risk
management gives us a path to find that
balance the right balance for the
organization because all organizations
need to accept risk and if we follow a
solid risk management process than it
helps us find what the right level of
risk acceptance is for our companies
okay myth number two there's a cyber war
going on so this one drives me a little
bit nuts and unfortunately it's going to
draw them even more nuts as tensions
raised between Russia and the US over
the DNC and and other cyber attacks and
I guess it doesn't bother me too much
that we've come over the last few years
to add the word cyber to just about any
type of verb or now that we can find
anywhere and sometimes it's useful
sometimes it's not but I think that we
need to be careful to pay attention to
the meaning of the route work whenever
we add cyber to it we should lose
meaning whenever we add that and so
we'll run through a few words that we
often add cyber to and let's take a look
at what the root word really means and
try and make sure that we as
professionals continue to keep fidelity
with that meaning as we use the word and
can the cyber context so this is war
it's
death on massive scales it's absolutely
horrific event and so when I hear cyber
war this is what I think of and this is
not what we see in our day-to-day lives
certainly there are smart bombs and
smart bullets but it's ultimately
bullets and bombs that kill people in
wars it's not computers and so even
though we use computers more and more
and more fair I think the term cyber war
needs something a little bit
different and I think that we devalue
the word war when we associate when we
use cyber war so freely all of a sudden
we become numb to it as a society and we
think that cyber war something that we
can accept or ignore that's just
commonplace and unavoidable it's a
dangerous path and much rather leaves
the term for something that's a much
more monumental than what were you how
we're using it today assassination so I
occasionally hear the words cyber
assassination thrown about and you might
be able to call it drone strike and
assassination though it's really in the
end like I said it's a bullet or bomb
that's causing the damage it's not
computers there's been some very
interesting research and the tax on
medical devices or vehicles that could
potentially be used in some type of
assassination attempt by that as a cyber
assassination right now luckily it's
more theoretical than it is reality and
so again this is a word that we need to
be a little bit careful with when we add
cyber to it so we don't distort the
meaning propaganda so this is an area
where i can i can understand the use of
the phrase cyber propaganda a little bit
better islamic state's been extremely
successful in using social media to
recruit and to spread the propaganda and
so we see this more and more it's
something that we absolutely is as
security professionals as risk
professionals need to be aware of it and
need to be prepared to combat and so
cyber propaganda gets us closer to the
realm of where i think we need to be and
phrasing and then espionage spying
stealing information ninety-nine point
nine percent of the time when i see the
phrase cyber war or cyber assassination
we're really talking about is cyber
espionage and i think again as security
professionals as risk professionals
should be careful in the words that we
use and I'd love to see us use cyber
espionage much more and replace cyber
war with it's a much more honest telling
of and description of what we're talking
about and then sometimes we add cyber to
something that's just a filled TV show
and very disappointing so the sum up
cyber war we haven't seen one yet we
shouldn't talk about it like it's a real
thing or something that exists it might
come about someday I hope not but we
should still use the word with a little
bit of hesitancy we should use it with a
little bit of reverence and we should
use it as something that we should
absolutely avoid it's not something
commonplace his words matter the next
two we'll talk about will take together
it's all about authentication with three
the password is dead then a lot and then
also hear people talk about two factors
is it necessarily solves every
authentication problem that they've ever
come across and so I want to talk about
these a little bit and dive in a little
bit more deeply and first just the quick
recap of sure you all know there's
traditionally three factors of
authentication something you know
something you have something that you
are lots of talk about a fourth or fifth
factor where you are how you behave it
gets into semantics that we won't dive
into today let's stick with it three
factors their traditional so password is
dead we hear that all the time plenty of
press declares that lots of vendors say
that their product kills passwords and
really when I look at those products at
the heart of them somewhere at an
administrative level there's usually a
password they may be able to keep
end-users away from passwords a little
bit they may be able to distract from
passwords but certainly you can't call
the password dad at the same time you
release a product that uses passwords
and so I think we need to be a little
bit careful there um but passwords do
have a lot of problems and I don't want
to gloss over the subject to make them
long enough so that they can't be easily
brute forest and then users can't
remember them and you make it worse
climate change it all the time as they
write it on a post-it note all the
problems that everybody complains about
are absolutely true but before we
declare the password dead we need to
think a little bit about what are all
turn
azhar and make sure that we have solid
alternative Japan so let's look at our
other factors something that you have so
something you have actually started out
the first time I heard about it was
sheets of paper with random numbers
printed on them and so when you log into
a system you look at the next random
number type it in scratch it off so that
you know the next time you looked at the
next number on that sheet of paper
obviously very cumbersome and
error-prone all rights they change
things and brought made it all more
commonplace so with this pure ID most of
us remember those devices and had them
at some point someone's probably still
do the one problem with secure IDs or
one of the problems with secure IDs was
that because you only used it when you
authenticated you leave it at home on
your nightstand half the time because
didn't need it for anything else and so
we started moving to SMS messages it was
nice she almost always carried your
phone with you we're much more cognizant
of that of course SMS isn't encrypted
and a lot of people have SMS texts show
up on their phone even when the screens
locked so there's some problems with
that so we moved on to phone apps and
that's a much better solution we do
actually remember to carry our phones
with us most of the time and with apps
we can address the screen lock problem
the encryption problem it helps but the
inherent problems with something that
you have just like passwords are you
can't be avoided no matter what
technology we use you can absolutely
lose it and the bigger problem is
someone else can obtain it and no matter
what you do is something you have those
two problems exist and we can mitigate
those risks but they will always exist
so just like passwords something you
have just not like something you know
something you have comes with some
inherent limitations biometrics we have
to give biometrics a lot of credit
remember not too many years ago thinking
that it was pie in the sky and that
would never see it now every one of us
logs into our phones constantly using
almost solely biometrics they've
definitely come a long way they're much
more effective than they used to be
they're much more usable they're much
more cost effective but biometrics also
come with some inherent problems first
of all there's this constant arms race
as good as they are they're certainly
not perfect and you know it started out
as fingerprint readers on on lap
hops that you could bypass with a little
bit of scotch tape pretty easily and now
the fingerprint readers are better but
there's still plenty of ways of
bypassing fingerprint readers and most
of our phones that you can find out on
the internet every time I see a
publication about a great new biometric
technique that either lowers costs or
introduces the new method a few months
later see a security researcher that's
found a way around it and so we have to
recognize that the bot there's an arms
race with biometrics and can't
necessarily bet on it because there's
still a lot of work being done there
another problem with biometrics is how
do you reset your fingerprint if I lose
my password I can reset that if I lose
my phone I can cancel it and get another
one but if I lose control over my
fingerprint or my iris or retinal images
or my DNA how do I get that back how do
i reset that how do I get control over
it again and so that's another concern
that we need to keep in mind with with
biometrics and so all three of our
traditional factors have inherent
problems it doesn't mean that we should
use them we have to they're the only
options that we have but it does mean
that we need to be a little bit careful
but then is an industry we decided okay
so if all three factors have these
inherent problems that we can't get away
from then we'll just combine them with
it that solves all the problems right
and so we'll just use multi-factor
multi-factor fixes everything but does
it and suggests that there's two
problems with with declaring that
multi-factor solves all the
authentication issues the first problem
is that all that every time we use
authentication it depends on how you
implement the factors if I use a
multi-factor authentication system that
has a 46 character alphanumeric password
along with a fingerprint reader that I
can bypass with some scotch tape did
that really make me more secure than a
strong password maybe it depends on the
threats that I'm trying to avoid but
it's certainly not the type of strength
of security we generally think of when
we think of a multi-factor the other
problem with multi factor is that
doesn't necessarily stop all all attacks
and that you really need to consider the
attacks that you're trying to prevent
the threats that you're facing when
you're designing your authentication
program so take a traditional phishing
attack that we see all the time set up a
great multi-factor strong multi-factor
authentication mechanism for my end
users and user receives a link to a web
page they go to a web page that looks
exactly like my applications log in they
dutifully enter their username their
strong password they pull up their app
on the phone and enter the token from it
and they hit submit and then the hackers
immediately have all the credentials
that they need to turn around it and
login as that end user it it's a pretty
common attack that just by declaring
multi-factor we don't we don't avoid or
we don't get a right way from there are
ways to to defend against this type of
attack but we need to be thoughtful
about is this what we're worried about
and are we willing to invest in the
right defense and so we have duo as a
vendor here they've got a great of a
syndication mechanism that they sell
you'll pay for it it costs and there's
plenty of other vendors that use the
depth of off as well and they help
defend against these types of attacks by
changing the number of factors are the
types of factors that are going to be
required depending on the threats that
they see that that's really what is key
when it comes to designing an
authentication system you need to
consider your threats we can't just
blindly declare that we're using multi
factors that fixes all of the all the
issues which factors are we using why
are we using and why do we select those
and do they address the threats that
we're facing it with our systems and so
I'd suggest that a term that it's a
little bit more descriptive a little bit
more helpful is actually threat driven
authentication so if you tell me that
you have a multi-factor system okay it
tells me a little bit but if you tell me
that you have a system that's driven by
a by you through your threats then all
of a sudden I know you've thought about
it I may not know how secure the system
necessarily is I don't necessarily know
what you're using in order to implement
the authentication system but at least I
know that you put some thought into the
threats that your organization's facing
that your systems facing and that you've
tried to design defenses around those
and I think that level of thoughtfulness
is what we need to hold ourselves to is
secure
professionals we can't just decide that
passwords are dead but the two-factor
fixes everything we need to really be
thoughtful about the the threats that
we're facing and what we want to
implement our organization Smith number
five security through obscurity is
useless another one that I've heard
since I first got into the security
industry and and and took for granted
when i first started hearing it but then
the more I looked around the more I
started the question that's it this one
should be pretty easy to address very we
could raise your hand if on your public
web page you publish a complete network
diagram along with data flows IP
addresses and server names of your
organization and that's kind of what i
thought that nobody's going to raise
their hand to that but that ultimately
is just security through obscurity we're
not we don't actually believe that a
determined attacker could gain that
informations the first steps in the kill
chain and attackers are actually pretty
good at gathering that information up
but at the same time we aren't
necessarily going to give it to them
we're going to make their job as hard as
we can we're going to try and slow the
attack down we're going to try and raise
their costs maybe that gets them to look
for another target maybe it gives us
more time to see that we're being
attacked but regardless that we owe it
to ourselves into our company to go
ahead and slow the attacker down and a
little bit of obscurity is effective in
that another method that sometimes is
dismissed by information security
professionals to as a security measure
is as a proxy server speed bump so the
speed bump you may call it something
else but it's basically a page that
comes up in all major proxy servers
support it now when a user goes to an
unclassified web page and it just says
are you sure you want to to go to this
page we don't know what this is and as a
security professional McConnell it's
silly of course in users are just going
to click through that they really don't
care much about security and so how
effective is that as a control it's
meaningless its security through
obscurity it's just slowing them down
but second thought first of all I want
you implement it you find the surprising
number of users actually stop and think
a little bit about whether or not they
want to click through and so we still
see in
around fifty percent of click-throughs
and even though that's still a lot of
people clicking through to this unknown
site it's a lower tech services than we
would have otherwise but more
importantly most malware these days
whether it's ransomware or rat or
anything else as soon as it gets
installed first thing it's going to try
and do is reach out to its command
control server and a lot of the times
that command and control server is is
simply an unclassified site out on the
internet and while it's easy for a human
to click on that link to go ahead and
move on to to get the internet access to
that page for a lot of software it's a
little bit more challenging and so we
see a lot of these these rats a lot of
this ransomware is not able to get out
and talk to the command and control
servers that they need to be able to
talk to and so it stops the attack right
there and of course again it's not
unnatural could you write software that
gets around that absolutely is it
happening I don't know probably but if
it's up some percentage of it that's
still in a good control that we need to
consider in our arsenal but the third
benefit that we get from the proxy
server speed bump is information so if
you see an endpoint calling out to an
unclassified site one hundred five
hundred times a day it's probably not
just really a determined in jeez they're
tryin to get to some random site
probably a piece of malware on your
system that's a pretty reliable
indicator to compromise and something
that you absolutely need to be looking
into and so something as simple as a
proxy server speed bump actually
provides quite a bit of security when we
look at it can all that be bypassed
absolutely but but it still provides
value to your organization really what
it comes down to is layers of Defense
most of the controls we implement
unfortunately simply aren't one hundred
percent effective absolutely your
firewall if you tell it to block and
port it's going to block that for it
every time but most of the controls
whether it's it's a antivirus or our DLP
or anything else that we might implement
as a security measure in our environment
it only has degrees of effectiveness and
we fight that that fact that it's not
fully effective by implementing layered
defenses okay so this isn't going to be
fully effective than we use it in
combination with additional controls and
obscurity is no different than any of
those other controls that aren't fully
effective absolutely it can
workaround absolutely it can be bypassed
but used in conjunction with other
controls it's a strong measure to slow
down your attacker may be diverting to
an easier target and definitely give you
more of a chance to find him and
identify him and stop him before he gets
too far and so it's all about that kill
chain and then myth number six security
theater accomplishes nothing and so I
tried to research this and the first
time I heard the phrase security theater
was a Bruce Schneier article soon after
the the shoe bomber attack and the
phrase may go back earlier I don't know
but I believe he may have point it and
he was upset understandably so because
already long lines it at airports after
nine eleven became even longer as we had
to take off shoes and go through other
security mechanisms as argument
rightfully so is that this doesn't help
stop terrorism the the actually taking
your shoes off and ran them through the
scanner separately probably is it being
a very effective control at what we're
trying to stop and that a determined
attackers simply going to find other
ways to get explosives on board and all
those were valid points but the
counterpoint to that's brought by a
Bruce Sandman and Bruce doctor Sandman
is a a professional in the crisis
managed or crisis communications field
he's done a lot of research here and he
actually takes the formula that we've
traditionally used for risk it and and
says that it's not complete so our
traditional formula is is that the
impact times the likelihood equals our
risk score and says well what you're
actually calculating there is the hazard
it's the chances that something might
happen is the chance that that that
terrorism attack actually comes through
but what it completely ignores is the
outrage level and so we take a look at
how the country was in the wake of the
shoe bombing attack and there were a lot
of people very upset there was a lot of
nervousness and the government was doing
things about it but most of those things
were behind the scenes their
investigations there are policy changes
they're reorganizing our entire defense
industry and so as all that happened the
the people that were expressing concerns
still had no comfort that anything was
changing so the government did something
visible was it necessarily effective at
eliminating the threat probably not I
don't know but but certainly what it did
do is provide a visible mechanism to let
people know that we're doing something
we're watching this we're trying to
protect you and it made people feel
better and there's value in that and so
I would argue that that when you're
writing your wrist when you're assessing
your wrist as part of your risk
management process that you absolutely
need to consider the outrage component
it might be that an auditors identified
a risk that you think's really
relatively low and you don't want to be
distracted by it but if your CIO has an
interest in it or anyone else that's
watching that audit report it's probably
worth a little bit of your time to go
ahead and address that risk that doesn't
become a distraction later it gets down
to the outrage factor we need to
consider it in our our risk calculations
and in fact for all of us his
frustrations with the security theater
mr. Stahr did write another article a
few years later where though I didn't
quote dr. Sandman he referenced very
similar arguments and saying that there
is a place in our industry for security
theater that there are times when people
are so upset that you need to have a
demonstrative show that you're actually
doing something even if what you're
showing them is it especially effective
that sometimes we need to address
people's fear and outrage factors and so
I think there is a group we should be a
little bit less derisive about security
theater and consider that it sometimes
needed and hopefully not often certainly
would all rather focus on the hazard or
rather focus on reducing risk as we
traditionally see it but to completely
ignore outrage I think is a mistake that
we shouldn't make and so again the theme
through all this has been that words
matter that we need to be professionals
and we need to consider the words that
we use very carefully that we need to be
willing to question our beliefs and we
need to consider whether or not how
we're expressing ourselves is really a
the message that we want
to get across and so whether it's
referring to yourself as a risk
professional instead of a security
professional but as talking about cyber
espionage and so cyber war or just being
less derisive when it comes to terms
like security through obscurity or
security theater and recognizing that
those things really can provide benefit
to your organization I think that we
need to be very careful about how we
talk and how we communicate to people
all right thank you very much for your
time really appreciated
[Applause]