[Music]
[Applause]
okay hi everyone
so i'm going to talk today about open
buckets if you don't know what it is yet
it's fine i didn't know either
so
who am i
my name is michal kamenski i'm a
computer science student at a tefnion
i'm working at a studio position at a
cyber intelligence
as a cyber intelligence
analyst
[Music]
so i would like to start this
presentation the same way i started my
job interview for the role
i don't know anything
i don't want to mislead anyone
i want to walk you through
my journey
so
when i say anything i really mean
anything
i
when i started with linux i tried to
type in my password
and couldn't figure out
why i wanted to get typed in
and nothing would show up on the screen
it took me quite a while to figure out
that's just the way it works in linux
so my purpose here today is to walk you
through my journey and
i will do that
by ex walking you through some case
studies from my work that will be more
technical
um
and
well that's it let's begin
so what's the bucket a bucket is a
database that is stored in the cloud
and
the problem is many companies just
misconfigure their buckets and leave
them completely open on like for anyone
to access them
with just a web browser
so that's what a bucket looks like in
the browser
just a list of files
this is a picture i took from
from an article i found on google
and you can see the credit just right
down
right below the picture
and
companies
many companies i was surprised to find
out
just leave a lot of sensitive
information a lot of
customer information their employees of
information just open for anybody
so the first case study i want to talk
about is
this airline
they
left their bucket open on the
on the web
and what did we find in there there were
many many terabytes of
files
for example
[Music]
there were there was source code with
passwords and keys
and i don't know a lot but i
don't think that you're supposed to put
your password inside your code
[Music]
here's a screenshot of course i redacted
the parts that
should be public that they did live
public
their aws keys
their
passwords api keys
trust everything
there were
airplane navigation
and
landing source code including equations
for
calculating landings of airplanes
that had writing permissions
just anyone could go and change the
source code for the
landing of an airplane
um there were
a
security procedures from various
airports around the world
and there was an alert system to send
the urgent messages and alerts for a
pilots while they're flying me there
and many more
okay so
there is all this source code
there are apk files there are java files
i've been told to find passwords keys
i
don't know how to do that i've been told
to look for secrets
i thought like the main stuff that
should be left secret
i they realized it was like a
professional term that meant passwords
and keys
uh after i realized that i knew better
how to google when i knew that
terminology i could know what i should
look for and what i should learn
so i found this open source tool there
are many open source tools for analyzing
information for finding anything you
want to do you
barely need to write anything new
yourself
in this
world of tools so there i use this uh
open source tool called apk leaks
and
it just reverses the code of the
apk files
and
and finds automatically passwords and
keys for example amazon
keys they all start with ikea and then
it's one way you can find the keys in
the
data
and
it just prints out everything you need
to find
so
this was a bucket that
was kind of different from other
brackets that i was working before
it just made me
realize
how bad the situation is with leaving um
just any information open
um why would anyone leave that open
um
and there are so many other buckets just
like that open out there you can you
just can't get
all of them
um
you don't necessarily need some brand
new zero day to attack or to
find a sensitive information you can
just by
misconfiguration of buckets or
other systems get a lot of information
and
i'm no expert but i think that's
something that could get abused by
terrorists and
it just it's good that it got closed
so the thing i like most about my job is
the attribution
um
it's to find who the owner of the bucket
is
it feels like a puzzle something you
need to
figure out you need to search for it you
think creatively um so it can be
difficult but
it's the most interesting part
uh sometimes it's really obvious for
example if it says just besides tlv
in the bucket name
you can assume with a certain certainty
that it belongs to besides okay
but it's not always that simple
so i want to talk about a case study
that involved a bucket full of student
records student names their id numbers
and their
grades in various courses
so the bucket name include the word
israel
all the
newest files in the bucket were from the
same academic
institution in israel
and it was live it was still
there were still new files uploaded
every day and all of them were from this
same institution
academic institution in israel so it
seems pretty obvious right it pro it
probably belongs to this academic
institution
um
but not so fast
while i was going just sampling some
files to see what's in there
i encountered
an invoice
it was an invoice
from
a company a to company b
both of them were from a foreign country
none of them related any way to israel
none of them related to this academic
institution it was
weird
like why would it be in the bucket
um
so
i
sent this
invoice
to my
team leaders i
they told me just it's the bucket of
this academic institution you need to go
over it quickly and we will
send it for remediation so it will get
close as soon as possible
[Music]
but i sent it to them and i was like
wait a second how do you know it belongs
to this academic institution
how why
don't you think it might be something
else for example this i found this
invoice
why would it why would it be there
um
but again
i'm a newbie i don't know
anything who am i to challenge them
um am i just being stubborn
they have a lot of experience if they
saying no
whatever leave it
should i just leave it or should i
like keep going or investigating it or
whatever
but
so i said okay they know better
my brain is still itchy so just for
myself i will go over i will understand
why they believe it's it belongs to this
academic institution
i will just ease my mind
so i started going over the files there
are millions of files you can go over
all of them even if you wanted to and of
course i didn't want to do that's not
not ethical
so what can i do
i looked at the files i tried to
see if there was something that stood
out
and first of all i looked at the dates i
saw that all the old ones
belongs to academic institutions from
a foreign country and all the new ones
belong to this academic institution here
in israel and i managed to find the
exact date when the switch happened
second i
kept looking for things that would stand
out i don't want to just go over
millions of student records it's not
interesting i want to find some proof
who this bucket belongs to
i don't want to report to some random
academic institution about this open
bucket if it's not their bucket
so
i noticed that the invoice that i found
had a slightly different name scheme
than all the other files
they all were just random strings
but there was something different about
the snap scheme so i looked at other
files who had the same name scheme and
most of them were just
a bunch of
stock photos it didn't help me much
but
um then some of them
were screenshots that had some
uh
it was some documents of a company that
was verifying student records
so i googled then i have this company i
found two websites the first one
was a global website
it was of this foreign country
that um
that this company verifies student
records in this country and the second
one was
um
it was the ending of coil
and this
this website was verifying customer
records for this academic institution in
israel
so i just was telling you the road that
finally worked
but
it wasn't that easy it took a lot of
trial and error so
i i just found myself at 3am in the
morning screaming my computer being part
i was really proud of myself
that
i found something that
much more experienced
people my team leaders
didn't find i didn't i wasn't proud of
myself because of the technical steps
none of them were
more than basic
i was proud of myself that i wasn't
scared to research on my own that i
didn't just say then probably know
better i should just listen to them and
leave it and leave this alone
and of course i was i didn't have
anything to be scared of
they were happy i did that they were
part of me
and
that's something i think is very
important for a company that employs
juniors um to have this kind of
atmosphere
okay a few other stuff that i found
really cool at my job during this few
months i'm working there
is that a lot of the boring stuff can be
automated
the research most of the time can't be
or
at least not in a really simple way but
other stuff
can be
i got really excited about regular
expressions
they were mind-blowing
first in a bad way because they were a
little
annoying but
while
when i got the hang of it it was really
cool that you can just with a few rules
and get exactly
the data you want exactly what you're
looking for
other cool stuff i found is that without
any tools anything special just
with using
source code you can find open buckets on
websites
you can see in the network tab in the
dev tools what a sources they are
calling to retrieve images
you can use that to see
where are they calling them from and
sometimes those buckets are open
also
most companies are not very creative
with their names of their buckets most
of the times just companies name
production or fraud
and if you find one there are probably
other ones no one just misconfigures
just this bucket but by mistake if you
know how to configure it you do it
so if you find prod
you follow you probably will find
non-prod
and stuff like that
so i started there i didn't know how to
type a password into the linux terminal
um and after two months
i got to where i'm here
right now
it to this case studies they were just
two months after i started my job
um
i wanted
a
i want to conclude this
first
um by my experience
that you can learn a lot when you're
just a beginner
everything is new to you everything is
interesting you can just learn really
fast
also the company culture is really
important to make the juniors feel that
they can contribute that they will be
heard that they can just
um
they can
speak their mind and that everything
that they won't be dismissed
um also it's important to make friends
that are at the same stage as you are
that
maybe were at the same stage that you
are
just a year ago or two
[Music]
to not take this journey alone
um
and there are no shortcuts just learn
your own and keep trying
and about the technical stuff
you i just the main thing i learned
there are all this cool stuff all these
vulnerabilities zero days
but at the end
the
main vulnerabilities are just stuff that
gets misconfigured
and
you can find a lot of
sensitive data this way
and that's it
so i want to thank besides i wasn't
playing and talking here actually
my friends pressured me to talk here
but i'm glad i did and somehow i got
accepted
[Music]
and i want to thank my team for being
supportive
and i want to thank you for being such a
great audience
[Applause]
[Music]
you