[Music]
uh
[Applause]
[Music]
okay uh thank you for the introduction
by the way
okay i'll just test the clicker because
i have luck okay i have luck today i
hope
hi everyone
my name is noe and i'm super excited to
be right here first of all i want to
thank everyone who actually stayed up
until now i really appreciate it i know
that's like a difficult challenge
um
today i'm going to talk about cipher
injection so my name is noe and
basically i started this research like
one year ago and i just googled for
cipher injections and i find found like
one and a half articles about it
and i was like what but we can't have an
injection
so my whole goal today is that like half
a year from now everyone in this
audience will be able to just publish a
write-up of bad bounty of cypher
injection
that's it
so basically we're going to talk about
what is exactly uh you don't really have
to know what sql injection is but just
to make sure this is not about sql
injection there is one slide about it
this is about safer injection
so let's
start
so i'm working as a security researcher
i was one of the members in the group of
tom rezait who created capture deflect
challenges
and i really like to research stuff and
to learn about new stuff and i also
really like to dance especially after i
find the vulnerability
and i have like the best dog ever in my
opinion but it's more accurate to say
that he actually owns me
okay so i want you to actually have five
takeaways out of this stock today i
really want each one of one of you to
know what is cipher and what are graph
databases
i want you to actually be able to inject
into those graph databases and to be
able to escalate your attack even
further than that to cause as many
damage as you can or as many damage as i
possibly could during my research
i really want you to understand how to
protect from these kind of injections
and also how to minimize the attack
surface in case you have an injection
like that
and eventually not only the talk i also
want to give you some tools to
understand what you do right now i wrote
some cool playground
which i really want you to use it but we
have a lot to talk about so let's start
cypher
so
forget for 40 minutes about everything
you know about the word cipher
we're not talking about scissor cipher
or any cipher of crypto we're talking
about something different we're talking
about opencipher now this is just a
query language that you use so you write
queries in cipher language
and those queries are written to graph
databases so they perform some actions
on graph databases
and this is basically how you use it
so
no sql again only cipher right here and
whenever i say
cipher query injection i'm saying
whenever i say cipher i actually mean
open cipher um so let's proceed
i really wanted to understand what is
graph database because i said these two
words
too many times up until now so let's
take for example relational database we
have those tables and rows and columns
that you're already familiar with
and we have graph database now there is
a circle you can call it a node and
there is an arrow between two nodes you
can call it a relationship so there is
actually you can release that spongebob
lives at pineapple house
um and this is just how the database
looks like no rows no tables and if you
look at the bottom right you can see
that there is neo4j this is one of the
biggest companies that use graph
database nowadays
there is
reduced graph which is just an extension
of cipher you can actually write cypher
queries that perform actions on radius
database and there is also amazon
neptune which also supports cipher query
so it's pretty cool and there are much
more databases that nowadays starting to
support cypher and neo4j actually open
sourced cipher and they actually made
this open cipher so whenever i say
opencipher i actually mean cypher query
okay so we talked about graph databases
and basically what is safer but we want
to know much more about cipher and again
this is not sql this is cypher this is
something that is pretty new to most of
us
so in order to um do this i just created
the word of spongebob in a database
and you can see right here that there
are notes of characters such as mr crab
and spongebob and there are notes of
places such as krustykrab senis freedom
chum bucket and this is how a graph
database actually looks like so you can
see that for example
if we take spongebob who is a friend of
sandy who lives at sunny stream this is
just a relationship between those nodes
and basically this is how we actually
see those graph databases
so we talked about how it looks like
about that it's not like table but let's
understand and dig into the actual
interest in terms of cipher or even of
graph databases
so we talked about nodes and
relationship already we can have an
arrow between two nodes and the
direction doesn't really matter in our
case in all of this talk
and at the bottom you can see
some query dismiss match and return for
a second there is a variable that you
can actually defined in your cipher
query you can call it c right here there
are labels that you can use so there is
character label
some like a type of a node
and there are properties you can
actually assign to nodes so you can
assign name and age and birthday to
spongebob's node
and basically that's it those are the
basic terms of cipher
now if we look at a query example of
cypher then instead of the select from
we have match and return
so for example if you want in cypher
query to get all the characters
then we will write a query to match c
variable that will bring back all the
notes with the type character and return
c we have to use return after mesh so
that safer we know what we want to get
back from the result of the query
and if you want for example to get a
character by a specific name we use the
same match and then where clause so for
example word see that name equals to
spongebob return c
so this is like the basic example of how
use cipher
okay so we talked
pretty too much about safer we just want
to dig into the actually interesting
stuff that most of us came here for the
actual attack the actual exploitation
um
and the leverage of the functionalities
let's just start with sql i promise this
will be the only slide about sql this is
not a sql
talk
but let's just do a very quick brief
about what is sql injection we have an
example right here of a query in sql
where we just get all the characters
from a database
where the name equals to some value
imagine that this spongebob value
actually comes from the user so that's
the user input
in this case we'll bring back to the
user only the data of spongebob but in
the case that the user is actually an
attacker instead of spongebob they will
insert something like spongebob and
double quote and then we'll insert a
term that will return true always and
two dashes to comment out the rest of
the query
so what will actually happen right here
is that for each one of the rows in the
table it will be checked whether the
name is spongebob or whether one equals
one and since one equals one we return
true regardless of the name we will have
this injection we will have this exploit
and we'll be able to get other
information we shouldn't have gotten
so basically this is um just sql
injection in nutshell and we're gonna
use this knowledge from this slide
to actually inject into cypher
okay so let's get back into cipher
injection
we have pretty much similar
query but in cipher so we want to get
all the characters that have some
specific name that we get from the user
so the name equals to some user input
and in this case there is legitimate
user just inputs the spongebob value so
we bring back the node that has the name
spongebob pretty much boring
let's go into the really interesting
part
now in cypher instead of spongebob the
attacker will insert something like
spongebob with single quote and then
again we'll insert a term that will
return true always and return c
with two slashes to comment out the rest
of the query
so what will happen right here is that
we will get not only spongebob node but
other nodes as well
and
we just inserted the injections so
notice that all the red background text
will be actually the injection and this
is what an attacker should probably
insert
but
you can just stop me right now and say
okay we have to know to inject return c
we're an attacker from outside we have
no idea that there is a variable defined
that's called c so how would we know to
insert return c as the injection
and i will tell you that you're totally
right
this is an issue that we are going to
overcome in a few slides so keep that in
mind and let's keep with the injections
for now but we're going to solve this
issue
okay the next thing that an attacker can
actually do is to use this injection not
only to get other data but to actually
be able to tamper with our other data so
he or she will insert delete c
and then what will happen is that the
actual node will be deleted
and this is like pretty similar
injection
but we don't want to do more damage
through all these stock so let's see how
we can just delete everything and not
only our own
poor node
what we will insert this is the same
example
as before but this time we will insert
something like this now of this red
background text will be the actual
injection we will insert again spongebob
with scenic guild quotes to end the
string and then we'll insert two clauses
the first one will be match with all
character so we will create a variable
called all to get all the labels that
has the character and then we'll insert
the little so we will be able to delete
all the characters so again we will do
two actions right here first of all we
will get all the characters and then we
will delete all the characters
and this will be our injection
but we don't see the query
i mean i'm returning to the previous
question that i avoided
we don't actually know that there is a
return c
i mean we don't know to inject return c
we don't know that there is a label
called character in the database because
we are an attacker from outside we have
no idea how the database actually looks
like
so how can we still be able to inject
something because obviously we have to
use this return
but still not break the query let's see
how we're gonna do it
we're gonna exploit three data
eventually we're gonna just
link data to outside and we're gonna do
this by leveraging a very legitimate
functionality in neo4j code load csv now
again neo4j is just one of the biggest
database like graph databases today
and if you search for graph databases
most changes they will come up like top
three or top one
so we're gonna use load csv
functionality neo4j in order to deal
with the issue that we had previously
that we're not able to see the query
we're gonna use this so let's see how
we're gonna use it we have this
functionality and all it does is just
importing data from other external csv
file
so
you just want to for example to insert
data of 20 000
records you don't type it manually you
just use the csv so you will load
from this csv manually um and by that
you'll be able to use the data like this
is very legitimate
but what it does is that it enables you
to use in the query
a method that enables us to actually
send a get request to external service
and that is huge it means that we can
define any service we want and a get
request will be sent using our injection
now let's see actually how we can use it
but basically we have a case of blind
injection right here where we actually
able to inject into a query but we're
not able to see the actual
response that is returned so for that we
get help from low tsv
so we we use it as a kind of a pipe
between the actual database and between
our own controlled server so we'll be
able to leak data from the injection to
outside to us but let's see how we can
actually do it
so i know this is a lot of text but we
actually insert those four lines as the
injection dismiss the last line what we
actually do here will be to
run procedure called db.labels it
actually returns back all the labels in
a database to us
then we use law csv from and we put our
own url to our own server and we will
append the label at the end of the url
so what will actually be is
there will be a get request to our own
server with the leaked labels
and the two slashes of course at the end
of the injection to comment out the rest
of the query
but this will what we will see if we
just use for example burpsuit's
collaborator to see
the request we will get a request to our
own server with the leaked label from
the injection from the database and as
you can see in the second line the user
agent is actually in neolud csv java
which means that the get request was
sent directly from the injection that we
made
with the help of the nice load csv in
neo4j
so
using this technique we can just lick
more and more parts of the database
now we know that there is a label called
character we insert match c character
and again all of this will be in the
injection and then we'll use load csv
from with your own to our own server
epoch deck joints will dismiss this for
a second but keys will see so keys
will actually return all the properties
of the character
and epoch text joins just to turn
transform the list
to a string so we can append it at the
end of the url
and this is basically what we will
return to get back all the properties
so we'll be able to link also the name
properties outside and for each one of
the properties in the database we will
get another get request and again it was
from low csv neo4j so pretty cool
the last thing that we want to link will
be actually the values the fun values of
spongebob and patrick
so we know that there is a label called
character we know that there is a
property called name we want to link
right now c dot name that you see at the
end of the second line
we will leak patrick and mr krab with a
simple typo i made but basically we will
be able to link the values of the actual
names and by that even delete what we
want because right now we linked
anything we wanted from the database and
we'd be able to tamper and just
exploratory data as we wish
so we were able to bypass this issue of
not being able to see
what we inject
but as i said in the beginning we want
to cause as many damage as we can
during all this stock
and it's not enough for us to just
destroy the database to delete data we
want to do much more
so let's see what else we can do we're
going to ask a letter attack and cause
dinar of service we're going to prevent
access to the database we're going to
perform ssrf in rfi and i'm going to
explain why it is when we reach to those
sites but basically we're going to
access sensitive informations files and
leak data outside and even access hidden
endpoints
we're gonna eventually cause lateral
movement in such a way that we'll be
able to leak other data from other
services not only the service that is
vulnerable to the injection itself
and we're gonna also talk about aws dcp
and what else we can leak when we have
access to a machine in the cloud itself
so we're gonna show how it can do all
those things
and eventually we're gonna talk about
alternatives to low csv
and what we can do in other databases as
well and not only in load csv even neo4j
okay so the first thing that we can
actually do in the injection itself we
can call dbms.list connections which
will actually return back all the
connection ids to us we will put this in
the injection itself and we will use
loadcsv to leak all the connection ids
to us and the next thing will be to
either kill a connection or kill a list
of connections
now the connections are not the simple
connections between the user and
applications those are actually the
powerful connections between the server
and the database itself
and if we do so in an automated script
imagine that it can just cause enough
service on the database and prevent from
a lot of queries of legitimate users to
be executed
now i will say that it really depends on
the rows and permissions that you
actually have
if you have the default role of admin
you will be able to do so with a simple
injection with low tsv
but we're going to talk much more about
the rows and
permissions basically we can just drop
databases so we can link the names of
the databases with the load csv trig
and then we can just drop a database
so we were able to close in our service
on the database we're able to delete
data and change data and maybe annoy
some users
but still it's not enough for us so
let's see what else we can do
we're gonna perform ssrf right now now
ssrf is a web based vulnerability where
an attacker actually creates an http
request in such a way that is malicious
it reaches to through the firewall to
the server itself and because of how the
request is constructed then either the
server sends a request to himself or to
another internal server gets the
response from it and then returns the
response to the attacker so it looks
just as if the attacker is actually
sitting after the firewall and not
behind it and is able to just manipulate
the server into sending a lot of
internal requests and access a lot of
sensitive files keys and endpoints and
we're gonna see how we're gonna do this
with load csv this is a pretty simple
trick but you can achieve a lot with it
so we can actually cause ssrf with low
csv
and this is an example so
what we will actually do we have this
same case that we talked about when we
actually have an injection in a
vulnerable server in neo4j we can just
use those csv from but this time we
won't use our own server we use the url
of another internal server and what we
actually happen right here is that the
vulnerable server will send a get
request to one of the internal servers
that we will define from the load csv
from
and it's pretty powerful we can access
hidden endpoints we can enumerate
directories we can use command
improved force directories and files
that we
usually you use in
bounty
and basically if you want to do
something more focused
whether we talk about cloud environments
or gcp or aws for example in aws there
is a service called metadata service
which is a service that sits in a static
iep and it holds a lot of metadata
information about your roles and
permissions and with which other
machines you can actually communicate
with so what you can actually do here is
you can use those csv from to create the
metadata service to get a response back
and to be able to know to each other
machines you can escalate your attack
so
it's pretty much a lot for example if
you see that you have access to query
the secret manager of aws then you're
able to get a lot of sensitive files and
passwords from there and also you can
just escalate
through one machine and another if you
just know that you can communicate with
this other machine in the cloud
so it's pretty much a lot
one fine point to know that in v1 you
can do this but in v2 you cannot because
in v2 there is a session that you have
to establish between the user that wants
to the permission and between the
metadata service so you actually have to
attach your own token in the header of
the request and since we use load csv
from right here
and we cause a get request we need to
actually find a way to attach this token
in the header when we send this request
to the media service and it's like funny
to think you will have a potential
ability to decide on the header that
will be sent in the request
using low csv so i didn't find a way to
do so and it's a nice thing to know
why else you should operate upgrade to
media service version 2.
so we saw basically the concept but
let's talk about actually ciphertext
what we can do right here is i have a
very cringy version of server that holds
in some endpoint you should never
be able to access externally and hold
some very secret um and in this point
i'm i'm going to say that this imagine
these endpoints actually sits in another
server not in the server that actually
runs new 4g in the database
what we do right here will be
all this will be the injection itself
again dismiss the last line um but we
will use to load csv from right here the
first one will be to get the actual
secret value from the other server
and as you can see there is a keys.txt
at the end we will save this value as
secret and then we'll use dot csv from
we will use the url to our own server
this time with the secret appended at
the end
so what will actually happen right here
is that we will get eventually the
secret leaked outside to us and this is
a secret that was sitting inside a
different server not in the server that
we had the injection of so this is kind
of an example how we can actually
escalate to other machines as well
and notice just one thing the secret
with the index zero is because we use
load csv so it actually returns as csv
file but not really
and it doesn't really matter what your
type of the file is it will work
regardless if it's csv or not
okay so we talked about a lot here we
talked about cipher injection and graph
databases dna of service and other fun
stuff with ssrf and escalation in the
cloud
but i really want to talk for a second
about what we actually did after we
discovered all those things so we did
responsible disclosure we actually
contacted neo4j company and told them
about all the risks that you can
actually have when you have low csv
enabled
because we didn't find any way to
disable load csv and we really wanted
away from them to disable csv if we
don't use it so that an attacker won't
be able to escalate like that in the
cloud
they didn't understand
the risk and they're working currently
to provide a solution but unfortunately
since load csv is defined in new 4j as a
clause and not as a function
currently this is not simple to develop
a fix that will be able to
to have you disable csv because imagine
that you cannot obviously disable match
clause so it is actually defined as
clause this law csv you can actually
disable all the functions in csv but
again since slow csv is not a function
as it is
as it is defined in neo4j then you
cannot actually use it right now
but since they're working on
installation i was like okay they will
fix it some at some point in the future
people will be able to disable it i
still want to find a way to be able to
leak the same information but not with
low csv
this time and this is where epoch plugin
comes into the the picture
so i did a little research about what it
is exactly this is just a plugin you can
install in new 4g and i think it is like
the most common plugin in neo4j
um and you can obviously use much more
features when you install the
when you install a plugin so basically
it's just an extension to the language
of cipher in neo4j you can just load
import and import
export other data and what i thought was
okay
we can actually use apocloud json in a
similar way of how we use vote csv
so even if low cc will be blocked at
some point or another we still have it
another way
we can use match for example with c
corrector and then to call apocaly.json
and at the end of this third line in the
leaked we will still be able to append
the liquid information that we want to
to use actually so the same injection we
can actually achieve with a different
thing with epoch library it has to be
installed in your actual database so an
attacker will be able to use it but it's
very familiar to a lot of developers
that actually use neo4j and it's just as
you talk about
loadash in javascript for example a lot
of people
in javascript actually use it and
install it so it's pretty common to to
assume that they probably install it
um
and this is just how it looks like when
you have your own server and use this
injection and you get a request so you
get a request with data json with the
leaked value and it will send directly
from epoch procedures for neo4j
okay so we talked a lot about the
injections a lot about the risk and
pretty much a lot about what we actually
try to do with neo4j
but let's really try to make a value out
of this stock today and understand how
we can be protected from those kind of
injections
first of all in order to be able to
write as a developer
query we have to use parameterized
queries and this is a good example like
we have to use match and
every kind of clause but with a
parameter
inside so you can see the dollar sign of
name and we can see that we put the name
value in a separate parameter of the
function that we run
and it actually means that we take the
name that we get from the user and use
it in a parameter in cipher so
it doesn't matter if the user tries to
insert single quote or double quote it
will be treated as a parameter in query
and it will be mostly escaped so double
quote will be treated as if the double
quote yeah the double quote character
and notice the character that terminates
the string
so this is what we should do if we
develop in graph database and want to
avoid injections
and this is not so good and you should
never do this example
of how we actually able to write a query
in such a way that is prone to injection
we have here a second line string
aggregation of the name we just insert
it like that and don't really do any
validation so the second crime spongebob
will be what he shouldn't do i hope
that's clear enough um
so okay we talked about
remediation but
we are pretty realistic today and we
know that there can come a time when a
new developer will arrive and we will
write some vulnerable query
that will be injectable so we still want
to be able to mitigate our attack
surface
what we can actually do right here if we
talk about neo4j we have role-based
access control we have a very large way
to actually define different users roles
and privileges we can just for example
if we have a sensitive database that we
want to read data from and we have other
less sensitive database that we want to
write to we can use two different users
with two different roles one will have
only right permissions on the sensitive
database and second will be read read
and write permissions on the less
sensitive
so that if there will be an injection in
this sensitive database an attacker will
be able only to read and not to write to
it or to update
and you have kind of really nice granola
rolls in neo4j so every row is built on
the top of the previous row with a few
more rows with with a few more
permissions
and you can actually if you want to be
more protected revoke some privileges
from rows for example you can use some
role such as editor and then revoke all
the permissions to execute functions and
procedures on this specific role so just
to harden it
and eventually i really had to add a
point about it because i think it's cool
uh we actually got a suggestion from
neo4j
regarding epoch procedures
from version 4.3 yeah 4.3 we can
actually have a block list of any apoc
procedures we want so we can actually
define in the configuration of neo4j a
block list of
apple cloud and epoc import for example
and if we actually don't use
epoch we can just uninstall it and by
that prevent this kind of scenario
okay so i really want to say something
about reduced graph
so where this graph is an extension to
redis that enables you to write cipher
queries
and i really try to dig into the
documentation to understand what you can
actually do with it if you have an
equivalent of load csv with it i found
out that there are parameterized queries
there is a support in parameters queries
so that's great
and i found that there is support in
some procedures db dot labels it can
help you if you also want to achieve an
injection in this graph
and regarding low csv i didn't find load
csv in redis graph but i didn't find
case when you can use it as a kind of an
if based with substring so you can for
example get the labels using dividend
labels and check whether the first
letter of the first label equals a and
combine this with
or one equals two and see the result or
see an arrow or c and decide whether
regarding the actual response value of
the query
so you can actually achieve this with
redux graph and when i try to dig into
redis graph more deeply and try to
really understand if we have any way to
have
rows and permissions in a similar way of
neo4j i came across this
question
i have no idea who this person is but
from it's from 2021 a person just begged
to have some kind of arbuck like we have
in neo4j
and i really tried to understand whether
or not this was answered because i
didn't find any reference of
having row-based access control in
radius graph so i didn't find any maybe
there is but i really didn't find any
access control that you have in
in this graph
okay so we talked a lot about
injections cipher graph databases dna of
service ssrf reduced graph also and
mitigation and remediation
but i really want you to have value out
of this talk as i said and not only see
those i hope nice slides
i really want you to understand how the
injections work so what i did i created
a playground in cypher i will put also i
yeah i put a qr code at the end so you
don't really need to um to type it right
now but i really want you to actually
clone it it is all docker composerized
and it just starts up a neo4j database
with data and redis graph and has a nice
swagger and postman collections
and just play it try to understand how
it works
and then either fix existing injections
if you're some security engineer or
research
or just start bug bounty
so you can actually hunt for bugs in
cypher i didn't find any bug bounty
write-up about cipher and i hope that
like half a month from now it will be
much different it would be really
awesome it if it would be that different
and eventually you can just use the
remediation some mitigation that we
talked about if you just some security
engineer or you can just profit from
learning and understanding about another
thing that maybe you didn't know before
also if you're just security enthusiasts
and wants to do this um safer playground
though also go ahead
i want to to give credit to a person
that i i found this blog like one year
ago and this is the part of the low csv
the cool trick and this person also
wrote um kind of like the basic
um github project that i based my
playground on so thank you for that
and that's all so
thank you everyone
[Applause]
thank you so much i would like to say
that yeah this qr code it's obvious but
i still want to say it this qr code
actually is the yeah cypher playground
at the bottom please feel free to talk
with me to tell me what you think tell
me about it you tell me about the
playground and it would be awesome if we
just find more articles and write-ups up
from now about cipher so thank you
everyone
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]