[Music]
[Applause]
well hello everyone hopefully can hear
me well and i don't trip over anything
so my name is chris chris quebeco
uh i'll move out of the way if you don't
know me uh short version is i like to
hack stuff i've hacked a lot of stuff i
started young
and i do a lot with cyber diplomacy as
well as still hacking stuff
especially ron and certain other
countries so i like to have some fun
um so we go back to the beginning of the
ukrainian war
i was actually in ukraine for a very
specific reason part of my background is
nuclear cyber incidents i used to
lecture for gchq's
center for the protection of national
infrastructure so i've been to all of
the uh or i think all of the british
nuclear facilities both enrichment and
power plants
and i've handled about six nuclear cyber
incidents
and i was asked to uh go to ukraine in
case there was a nuclear cyber incident
and to stage
i ended up taking the last air france
flight to ukraine uh before you know
stuff
everything got closed
so
i myself woke up to shelling the rest of
the capital city did
and uh you know we're seeing
paratroopers coming in through from the
sky you know as you do
you know
uh they just blown up the airport and
uh we had decided to go a southern
journey because everyone was going west
towards poland you couldn't go east or
north because belarus or the russians
and um
because i know some very good people
because we decided to go south i asked
them to help out with intelligence
so this great guy dutch osint guy
ended up tracking me to the point where
the first city we went to take a break
in and he told me don't stop in that
city
bombing is imminent and we had a convoy
of 26 people and two vehicles sharply
turned right
and everyone heard
the
sound and boom
uh
a city with no military value had been
blown up
so uh open source intelligence gathering
and intelligence is very important when
you're trying to escape a war
let me tell you
so
it took days to uh actually get to
safety
and during
which
when i was trying to cross into romania
through the syria border crossing i
discovered what microsoft calls the
first
violation of the geneva convention via
malware
because there was a wiper virus that the
russians used against the border patrol
of ukraine and they couldn't verify
information couldn't verify if your
child was yours
and you're not going to leave your kid
behind all sorts of things like that so
if you saw the pictures of people with
kilometers and kilometers of traffic at
all of the border crossings that was
caused because uh the border patrol had
to go to pencil and paper and let one
car through at a time uh at the border
crossing i was at someone froze to death
waiting for to use the bathroom it was
very cold
so i finally get to romania
and i wake up
and in my hotel room i get this weird
message
saying hey chris you got out can you
help this guy named maurice creek it was
one of my special forces buddies from
the us
i have i'm not very good with names i'll
be honest with you and it turns out he
was a famous basketball player
and he was stuck in this place called
mikala
and mikala there is a river
a bridge and the russians were coming in
on the other side the ukrainians were
ready to blow the bridge for defensive
purposes if they circled around
and they closed off any water traffic so
of course he couldn't head east or north
and uh
via some of my intelligence friends they
had
told me to
very nicely inform maurice
don't put anything on social media right
now because some of the russian troops
are actually looking for high value
civilians to kidnap and ransom
so you know just your normal day
and
so
i started getting a lot of information
and contacting a lot of friends i think
i ended up uh hooking up to about 20
some different uh communications mediums
uh getting all sorts of stuff figuring
out drivers drivers from romania there
were some very very cool drivers that
were like we're just gonna go into
ukraine and start picking up people for
free
so there was a concerted effort but
trying to connect these people
and also in the case of mykola we had to
negotiate to get what's called a special
permit to try to go over the bridge
which they only allowed a couple of
hours a day to get maurice out
and luckily we were able to get maurice
out
and he was able to get in a car as
quickly as possible
go to
the moldovan border and then come to
bucharest where we celebrated by having
a lovely meal
so that was good
and
because of the publicity around this
this was from uh people magazine
a bunch of other orgs and ngos and so
forth contacted me going can you help
our people out
and i was like well
the answer is yes
so
ukraine for over a generation has been
known as high-value low-cost education
for a lot of the global south
and folks that just don't have money but
want to study aeronautics medicine
maritime stuff agriculture on a high
level computer science
it gives a lot of people opportunities
uh quite a few people who are educated
in ghana actually speak russian and or
ukrainian from back in the day because
they actually went to ukraine and went
to university
so i get contacted by this one group who
says
we have over a thousand students
in sumi ukraine
and to give you a bit of a picture
russia
sumi
and when the russians started moving in
within a couple of hours it was russian
controlled and here we have students
from india from all sorts of parts of
africa bangladesh asia you name it
and
this was a problem because when the area
started getting controlled by russia
supplies were starting to get restricted
uh the russians were trying to use this
restriction of supplies to force the
population to uh
vote
uh to be part of russia um we ran into
a warlord
um funny thing i had to send a message
to a former intel friend going i need to
negotiate with the warlord this morning
do you have any experience
so it was kind of an odd message for him
to wake up to
we had some humanitarian folks who said
they were humanitarians but found out
that they were actually smuggling lethal
arms
with people which would have put them in
a different category of the geneva
conventions
and some of them were like yeah we'll
bring food and medical supplies but you
have to know we're going to have weapons
we're like we can't have that
uh
it's just a no-go
we had a fake mayor
installed by the russians uh to get
supplies in
uh he said that we had to acknowledge
him so i ended up setting up
a fake website that looked like a media
thing
with robots.txt to keep it from getting
indexed and as soon as he saw that he
let humanitarian supplies in and then i
pulled it down
so these are some of the things that had
to be done
another issue was if they wanted to buy
supplies
they ended up being escorted by a
ukrainian officer which meant the person
buying supplies with this ukrainian
officer could be taken out by a russian
not awesome
um
some of the embassies
gave some terrible advice
uh when it came to technology this was a
problem because we were trying to keep
track of the students because well
um
some of the students were at danger of
being you know victim to various war
crimes then some of the governments were
just corrupt as hell we ran into one
particular ambassador from a particular
country in russia that basically got
paid to uh say oh yeah we want all of
our students in russia and the students
were like no they've been trying to kill
us we don't want to go to russia
um
we also ran into
bad water people were getting infections
people were getting sick so we ended up
uh
writing up a survival manual uh which we
crowdsourced a little bit from escape
students former special forces and
myself
and
um
when we tried to get them evacuated the
first time the russians decided oh we're
going to open a humanitarian corridor
they sent russian buses and say get on
the buses we're taking you to russia the
students are like no and they started
shooting on our students
luckily they were not killed like one in
uh kiev was killed when we finally got
a proper humanitarian corridor
we had buses in the front was the
romanian red cross and in the back with
this convoy of over a thousand students
and i get contacted that the russians
have just kidnapped
uh the red cross
and some of our buses they pushed them
into russia let the red cross come exit
russia and kept those students some as
young as 16.
uh and it's
then they try to stop the buses and try
to pull female students off of the buses
so imagine this is what i'm trying to
deal with and so are many people we need
to get them the hell out of there right
so
we finally get
uh the folks out of sumi and that was
very rough
um
there was a lot of them
so uh then we get contacted that in
kirsten
uh supposedly there's about 60 students
it ends up being 93
and turns out that
some of the
students had covet some did not but some
had various medical issues they could
not get medication they're facing some
of the same challenges
not being allowed to leave because the
russians wanted to keep everyone there
to force them to vote
to be part of russia
we had
one two particular folks where
they were uh a palestinian and an
israeli who are now best friends because
they had to live through this for weeks
uh the bomb shelter they were in the uh
top of the building had already been
destroyed but the electric was still in
the basement so that's what they were
living through
um one particular woman she was a
ukrainian
married to a student eight and a half
months pregnant severe asthma no inhaler
no access to a hospital
some of our other students when they
tried to
look for food and walk to a village they
were kidnapped by
russian soldiers
over zip tied brought to a torture room
um tortured and then put back into a
truck and pushed out
uh near the compound where the rest of
the students were staying
and uh you know all of this we're still
trying to arrange some sort of
humanitarian thing we're trying to
contact commercial companies
uh to actually see if they can extract
they're like well
i'll give you a discount for 150 000 but
i'm telling you if you got 92 93 people
from pregnant women all the way up to
70-year-old professor we're not going to
be able to extract them
then we had some
incredibly
terrible person who
had seen some of the social media videos
and contacted the student leader
and said
i work for the secret service we're
going to extract you give us all of your
contact information for all the students
in the gps locations
and it turns out he was not a federal
person
um
he was a fake preacher
uh who wanted to
contact all of them to read the bible to
them
and the students had packed up
and all of a sudden their dreams were
dashed
and some of them were suicidal because
of this so we had to kind of get them
out as quickly as possible right
uh so we're finally able to get them out
with arranging with romanian and local
drivers
the ukrainians had pushed back the
russian troops at the time and they used
that opportunity
i was asked should they go and i say you
know get the most vulnerable people in
the cars first but go
and that was i think about 3 a.m local
time leave now because they might not
have another chance
and so we routed them safe routes
figured out which bridges and
roads had been bombed out or land mined
to make sure that they didn't drive over
a landmine or if they had to go over a
bridge it was still there
and also
we correlated some of the information
with which border area was safest
because apparently some neo-nazi groups
decided to use the opportunity at some
of the border crossings to beat the hell
out of some of these international
students so we were not going to send
them into getting the hell beat out of
them right so we had to use heat maps
and things like that police reports and
so forth
so
lots of layers sometimes diplomacy
lots of coordination this is from
chimney
he actually is watching this he's one of
the students
and i was so happy that he was able to
get out as well as all of these students
i think in total about 1700
between the two
cities and it was very useful to use
open source intelligence and even closed
source intelligence because i was also
getting fed by
retired
former and active duty military from
various countries
trying to get these students out because
one of the dangers is if the russians
get a hold of
students from a particular country they
can then uh make sure that that
particular country goes
well we're gonna agree with the uh
russians especially if they came from
certain african countries because they
had their kids
imagine how that would look uh so
the risk of being used as a political
pawn
so
i ended up having to go to the press for
help because some of the embassies
were not great or giving really bad
advice
and could have gotten people killed if
they didn't already
and i ended up
from romania going to lisbon to do a
talk at a university and this chap named
gabriel was like hey let's talk let's
meet at this coffee house he didn't
realize it was right next to the russian
embassy
anyway it was not the most comfortable
spot for me we ended up talking for a
lot and he's like we got to get this out
and good tech advice as well
because some of these embassies are
going to kill people
uh so we decided to do that
and
so vice motherboard and a whole bunch of
people
uh ran some stories on it to try to get
the word out with also some of the news
about the technology so that
we could get more students out
before the war there were over 25 000
international students
now luckily there are almost none
but some of them are now in russia being
used as political pawns
uh some of our indian students for
example were pushed into russia we have
not heard from them again
so
i was able to
contact a lot of people
crowd source things like how to get food
and lock pick
food warehouses
um
a lot of the people i contacted were
people like you that i meet at
conferences so if you ever get a dm for
me going can you help with this
it's probably something like this
uh because
we as a community have unique skills
that we can use to save lives every
day so
wanted to give a shout out to dutch who
made sure all 26 of us survived karen
she's been wonderful
uh my now adopted ukrainian family misha
who helped out so much
uh the journalists and everybody else
and all of you for listening thank you
very much
[Applause]
i've got time for questions
yes
[Music]
uh so what i i talked about survival
skills intelligence and that i know a
lot of people my background is i was in
the air force i was one of the first
female air crew members that was allowed
to be in combat so i had to go through
something called sear training which is
survival evasion recovery and escape
uh pow mock-ups they beat the hell out
of you you got to jump
out of an airplane into the water you
know all sorts of things
um and because of that i know a lot of
people who are also in special forces
intelligence my second career was space
command dealing with what's called
command and control systems and also
protecting satellite telemetry data so i
worked a lot in
interesting fields
and so
it has helped me
with interesting people
that can help out in these types of
situations
so it's a great question
there's got to be more questions because
you have a bit of time
one back here
yeah what kept me going doing all this
and i'm actually still involved in a lot
of it
um
seeing
some of the things that had occurred
while
uh we were leaving we almost got killed
we almost got stopped uh but we blew
through the checkpoint of the the wagner
group or wagner group because they had
also secretly set up in certain
locations and we're dropping propaganda
i i do have a picture of the propaganda
dropping truck
um
and then when i got to the border
close enough where i could walk uh
because we had about a four more day
journey
um so misha and i walked up to the
border
and uh we were told about the cyber
attack he showed them my wiki page and
explained why i was there and when we
moved up to the most senior officer he's
like i have to check you out using a
landline because computers weren't
working came back
and said
uh you're on the high value target list
because one of my books that one um
i make fun of putin
um because i like doing that and hacking
things in russia
um
so
i got the refugee light experience
knowing that i got the refugee light
experience and only coming away with uh
let's see
a fractured tibia and ankle
out of the whole thing
um
i couldn't imagine
living
weeks in a bomb shelter
one of the things i had to put in the
survival manual was the
toilet tank water not the bowl was
actually safe to drink because that's
how desperate it was for clean water
and i couldn't imagine myself in that
situation or the situation of being a
woman and getting pulled out and
possibly tortured or raped
um
or anyone else
under those circumstances so that's what
has kept me going this entire
time can we all do to help you with what
you're doing
all right so
one of the things you can do i do take
uh twitter dms
or try my best to follow people that
follow me back or on linkedin
and if you say hey saw your talk
anything i can do i'll try to put you on
a list a secured list it's offline
and if i ever need any assistance if you
have any particular skills
and anything you can think of even from
survival skills intel skills
communication skills what have you
um
then
i might have to reach out to you and go
hey i've got this situation
um map skills routing skills
i just had to route uh via a friend
um a husband wife and child no husband
wife and mother uh for the safest route
to try to get out of ukraine because of
the recent bombings
so keep in contact you don't have to
follow me on twitter but i do take dms
and
if i reach out i hope that you'll help
out with the effort of either this or
any other effort when it involves
possible loss of life
i have four minutes so any other
questions
or i'm gonna have to drink they'll make
me drink i think
ah
uh in ukraine
interesting projects
oh
i do like to hack stuff
um
we do have um
let's see
a bit of an interesting project um
my institute the middle east institute
where i've have a fancy title
we were asked to write the abraham cyber
peace accord so the cyber addendum to
the abraham peace accords which is
supported by
israel
and uae
and we're trying to add to it the
support because i think that in this day
and age we've seen that cyber weaponry
can be used in malicious ways
i suppose i was telling someone earlier
i was supposed to go to burkino faso
earlier this year until um they had a
coup in the capital city and the reason
being is there's a particular islamist
terrorist group
um
that has purchased cyber weaponry from
iran
it's easier to
send them that
than it is to try to smuggle illegal
um
so
we need to realize or at least have our
countries realize
this is no longer fantasy or these
airplane novels or
you know funky movies with lots of
things that blow up
cyber warfare is being used along with
physical warfare and also all sorts of
surveillance
stealing of intellectual properties
trying to dox people
by foreign governments
uh like someone i know last year got put
on iranian uh news with his home address
and one picture of him and his dog from
social media who happens to be an
israeli
so these types of things can be used
against us
and it would uh be to a benefit
that
we try to look at what we do in those
situations
from the country level so that might be
an interesting project
any more questions
got a minute and a half
any questions
all right
done
[Music]
[Applause]
you