[Music]
[Applause]
hi
i think
i think the most like effective like
strategies to shame all those walking
outside but i think it is too late for
that so
sucks for me um
good almost lunch time everyone uh here
at b-side instead of eve and welcome to
my talk ss oh no
yeah yeah you can clap hands yeah yeah
in this talk today you are going to see
all kinds of epic fails and
implementations of sso pages and mostly
learn what not to do if you have them if
you implement them
a lot of silly stuff which you should
actually avoid
so that's me that's a very quick talk
here it's 10 minutes so you can
postpone lunch a bit i'm not going to
speak about myself if you want
scan the qr code it is benign pinky
swear it's just like my linkedin profile
and you can learn about me and yeah
that's chewbacca and he's in every one
of my slides or sorry presentations
single sign-on before we speak about the
fails let's speak about sso
if in the past like decades ago
you need all kinds of passwords for
different apps and usernames
it starts to consolidate you have like a
few years later you have active
directory on-premise maybe and you all
use it in order to log into different
applications but in the last few years
you have cloud you have
all kinds of people working from home
remotely using vpn you can't
sustainably use
all these shenanigans you need a single
identity provider a single authority
single provider of tickets to any ride
in the theme park that anyone will know
and respect and that's basically sso i'm
not going to go into the technicalities
behind it it's not that interesting for
this scope of talk
and we're here not to speak about like
sso per se but about the fails
but first how it all came to be
well basically because i'm as lazy as
chewbacca which is also a star of the
slide
i use sso every day i log into a service
i need to type in azure for example my
full username at my employer's name
domain
my full name is long as you all know
right now so
it is kind of
i try to evade that so i realized that i
can type blah at employer name and still
being redirected it's not a bug it's a
feature the service is unaware of the
actual users used by the sso provider
it makes sense to some extent
and then was the classic what if
eureka moment of every one of these
talks
what if i instead of employer name.com i
put other domain
it's
it will still work like will it redirect
me to a different sso page of a
different company which i have no
affiliation with
you won't be surprised that the answer
is yes and it was like more of a welcome
to the jungle moment
than what if moment in some sense
because like what came up next is
i i've seen so many different classes of
misimplementations that said well
it is worth a talk maybe a quick talk
but a
talk and those classes are
as follows
exposing password reset
functionality in an ssl page because
yeah it makes a lot of sense
why shouldn't you be able to reset users
passwords from the internet
disclosing
partial or not partial email and phone
number information
listing in hundreds and hundreds of
internal assets and providing an
onboarding guide for anyone who wants to
join your organization maybe configure a
vpn device
out there in the internet in an sso
login page
and let's go to the fun examples because
that's like the fun part the the face
palm
part of their talk
that was the the first portal i've seen
and a change password button so i
clicked it and i almost immediately was
shocked that
i i got like a password reset
menu and it even explained me what's the
format of the active directory internal
username so all i need to do is go to
the to linkedin
and and find
one of the
like employees of the company to check
it out
use the format they explained and yeah i
was able to reset the password
you if if i had their mobile device or
email
account but on the other hand they did
provide me the email account and
almost not partial mobile number and you
can cross-reference it with a lot of
leaks
and it is quite easy to get the full
phone number
and remember
lapses maybe
from a few months back
they did thing called seam swapping
which basically means that they hijack
the phone number of their target and it
is not that trivial but it is definitely
a thing which is possible
and if you have the phone number and the
username and the capability to reset a
password from anywhere on elf with
connection to the internet it is a
serious threat and adding insult to
injury they misimplemented the capture
they had the different errors for a
capture username which are incorrect and
it was applied in the wrong order like
the test for what's wrong so
yeah
so okay so
i found all kinds of classes and i
in my essence i am
into austin and i found the google doc
really nice google door google docs for
those who don't know
are
google hack hacks kind of in a search
engine i found something which is not
this of course
which allowed me to find a lot of
like an entire class
of other issues we'll see in a second
using this doc i was able to find over 3
000 websites
who
looked as this
you were able to even log in to the
entire scope of whatever this company
provides
or you were able to login into specific
assets
using the sso service but the list of
assets was exposed in the internet
it had hundreds in some cases of assets
some named our very secret top
crypto project whatever
others were
internal like databases exposed they
weren't quite sure it will be
um this public nevertheless it's just
like you know an sap database
um some kind of an internal website
which was exposed for some odd reason
the very name of the asset was the
domain you could have accessed from the
internet
and
last but not least
this login page
i'm a chatty person so i've seen that
chat with it support button and i
clicked it immediately
but yeah i don't really want to chat
with it it's kind of embarrassing
i don't know how effective it will be so
i just like went to the i.t setup guide
that's strange why do you have an id
setup guide in sso page
and i found this way the guide to
onboard a new employee to the
organization including instructions
about how to configure a vpn device how
to configure all kinds of internal
software
things which shouldn't be out there in
the internet it makes my life as a
potential attacker way easier
and that's i think like the the bottom
line of everything here today
remember that sso login pages are public
by default
there's a lot of information being
exposed there which shouldn't be
it should look like this
and
you you do
might kind of find some sense in the
fact that you
should balance between
security and operational costs you do
need to on board new users for example
however
while that's true you don't need to do
it recklessly for example you can
install a certificate on the devices
which should communicate with this
portal
mutual tls
known as um
[Music]
and this will save a lot of like the
risk
of
you know
being capable to access
what you've seen here today from the
internet or in the case of exposing
hundreds of assets
by name out to the internet you can
expose the same list but for people who
already did some kind of a
form of identification in front of the
organization it shouldn't be pre
off
it makes no sense to me
and with this i think we can conclude
this very quick talk i hope you enjoyed
if you want to speak more about it hear
my contact details
and
that's it thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
you