good afternoon everyone welcome to
containerization for the hybrid cloud i
want to talk to you a little bit about
the containerization like wave coming
through the technology platform right
now I'm going to talk a little bit about
the actual history of containers kind of
where they started where they are today
what need they actually fill we're gonna
look at docker and kubernetes as the two
main technologies for our stuff today
we're gonna move from there into
actually looking at hybrid cloud
architecture kind of seeing how that
would actually look if you're trying to
do that and set it up we're going to
then talk a little bit about security
concerns and what that's going to mean
for your organization
there's a whole lot of questions with
that because you're connecting the cloud
to your on-premise and everything in
between
and last we're gonna talk a little bit
about a couple of tools for trying to
make all this a little bit easier on you
so in the beginning there were servers
and service provided you all sorts of
hardware and CPU and RAM and persistent
disk networking and you could run your
applications on that and it was great
you could run all this stuff we'd never
been able to do before but the problem
was you had all of your applications
living within the same space if you had
one application that needed a certain
library as a dependency and some other
application needed a different version
of that you had do weird things to try
to make those fit together and not
conflict with each other on the system
so people said this is ridiculous why is
this happening why are we having all
these conflicts they got together and
said there's got to be some way we can
actually separate and isolate all of
these things apart from each other and
then we got virtual machines we had
entire operating systems we had all the
libraries everything all packaged up
into one nice little container they said
look at this we can run everything we
want all together no big deal however
that's very heavy we now had all of
these operating systems we had to run
all at the same time and we had all
these libraries there were just copies
of copies of copies and it's very very
heavy on top of our already like heavy
architecture so a bunch more people got
together and said hey can we make this
lighter we've got all of these kind of
shared dependencies for like the Kern
yeah we've got all these things are
doing essentially the same basic thing
on the bottom
can we just package and ignore the
operating system and that got us to
containers and my image that's awesome
live demos in okay
well that's disappointing
okay so it should be a picture of
containers I don't know what happened I
don't know why the containers aren't
there excuse yeah use your imagination
playing in the theater of the mind no
matter how many times you practice this
stuff it never works out when you do a
lot of demo okay pictures of containers
actual shipping containers is what that
should have been what containers give us
is unitized loads same thing for like
shipping containers instead of having to
maneuver all the individual cargo around
on a ship you have to pack it into a
container and then from there you can
like lift it on to a ship and haul it
wherever you want to go the other really
nice thing about shipping containers and
kind of our analogy here as well for
software containers is that they can go
on all of these different modes of
transit you have the same shipping
container can be put onto an actual ship
you can put it onto a train you can put
it on to a truck and it will get it to
where it needs to go and actually kind
of interesting fact two shipping
containers run invented until 1956 so
before that you had all sorts of weird
standards of trying to put things on
boats and trains and everything in
between the shipping container really
revolutionized the modern shipping
industry pretty cool so here's kind of a
big picture of how all of this looks we
were on the servers we had the apps and
we had all this kind of wasted hardware
space you could have your you know maybe
a single server dedicated to your LDAP
server maybe it's a single server
dedicated to your email server but you
didn't put too much stuff on it because
then it sort of conflicting and that was
just a hassle to maintain but again we
were wasting all of this resource power
moving up to virtual machines
well now look this we've got to these
more apps that we can actually run at
the same time on our hardware there
that's great
we've got our base level OS here the
virtualization has a little bit of my
layer by itself that it requires
actually there's also some interesting
work with that you can instead of
running the full OS you can run
hypervisors that just run virtual
machines there's other optimizations
that were made in between here
but essentially you're still running
again another version of different os's
could be even theoretically be the exact
same OS you never have but you'd have a
little a little bit better utilization
of your total power now with actual code
that you care about running
you're not buying hardware to run an
operating system you're buying hardware
to run an application of some sort to do
something useful processing for you
moving up to containers we still have
some wasted overhead with the actual
containerization stuff with the
containers how to actually communicate
is a daemon process in between them and
the OS for our purposes is going to be
the doctor Damon but now you can see
we've gotten a lot better utilization of
our total Hardware with more application
stuff that we care about because of the
lightweightness of a container how
containers work underneath there are two
main technologies that support
containers namespaces and C groups and
they're features of the Linux kernel and
actually when containers first started
it was specifically a Linux only feature
because that was the only way you could
get these two specific features
namespaces restrict what you can
actually see inside your container and
see groups restrict how much of that you
can actually use so the namespace you
have these are the big six here that
actually may contain as possible pin
mounts net user UTS and IPC each one of
these is a separate hierarchy tree that
lives in the host space but it is a
projection into the container space and
what that allows us to do for like the
pin space specifically is restart our
processes at pin 1 which there are a
minute system at pit 1 on the host
system is obviously not running at pit 1
because the host system is running pit 1
but it is a translation layer in between
that says pit one here actually means
you have paid 1524 over here mount
likewise gives us the ability to only
show specific mount points into our
containers net restricts our ability to
use networking what specific network
accessories you can see
user is another thing kind of like kid
where we're allowed to reset our user
space so that route can be user ID zero
which is really really important the UTS
space allows you to change host names
independently between the host and the
container and IPC is inter process
communication so you can use pipes and
other stuff like that inside the
containers without affecting the host so
all of the stuff gets contained within
its own namespace the cgroups
yeah like they what they do is they
actually restrict they put a limit a
hard limit on the amount that you're
allowed to consume if you didn't have C
group seen just had namespaces then you
could use up to the entirety of the
hardware that you had access to with C
groups you can say you know here I can
only use like one core out of my ten
core or 12 cores whatever that have
available memory you can put strict
memory limits so you can't just consume
everything block IO
not only can you restrict the amount of
space you can restrict like actual
throughputs with fats and network also
you can restrict the total amount of
networking you can push through and none
of my image is loaded fantastic all
right so this picture should have been
again in our imaginations a picture of
containers being moved around and this
is what docker allows us to do we have
portability in our unitized workloads
our containers by the way docker works
in fact that whale that is the Dockers
mascot is named a Moby duck and blend
backs so why specifically docker docker
allows us to make containers as a
configuration as code it has a file
called the docker file which actually
sets up what the container has in it and
what specific stuff it can do because of
that we can actually also implement
security in our CI CD pipeline we can
scan these configurations before
anything gets pushed to a production
level environment
because also it's portable we know that
what is running in our dev environment
is the same that is running in our test
environment that is the same as running
in our QA environment that is the same
as running in our production environment
scanning it once we can be sure that
it's the same configuration across all
of them the container registry is a very
powerful feature as well I think of it
kind of like github except for your
actual images for the containers the
really nice new feature of newer feature
is being able to sign your images so you
can be sure that you have exactly the
image that you're getting you can do
hash sums everything like that with LAN
application isolation and network
isolation are both features generally of
containers but docker allows that with a
couple of extra overlay type layers
which are really nice it just kind of
makes the process of creating containers
a lot smoother you can actually just go
and create containers on your own
entirely there's just using straight-up
Linux command line you can just create
containers but that's a very long
drawn-out process of setting namespaces
creating any spaces creating like
binaries into certain places doctor made
all of that a whole lot easier for us
it's a kind of generic docker file it's
their hello world so you'll notice that
every dollar file starts with a from
keyword and that allows us to build
docker files in our build docker
containers in layers the from scratch
means it's a no op base layer there's
nothing that's being done it's just zero
starting from scratch the docker file
copies then this it's actually a binary
it's not shown here but a binary called
hello to the root of the container slash
and at the end what we'll do is run this
CMD command of hello at the root of the
root of the container and if you
actually just do docker run hello world
this is the Apple that you get I did not
have the hello world container on my
local system it's one that's happening
doctor hub so when you start running
docker it looks
for the images to start with on your
local machine if it doesn't find it it
says hey go to the registry and pull it
for me other thing I first mentioned the
registry you don't have to use the
public docker hub registry it's great
it's really convenient there's a lot of
official images there's a lot of like
actual paid services you can you use
through that but you're also more than
welcome to host it private on your own
servers in your own premise that way
you're not pushing and pulling from the
Internet if that is a concern for you
additionally if your again we're talking
about hybrid cloud using any one of the
major cloud providers every one of them
has a container registry that is scoped
in to your specific area so that way
you're not having to again push public
but you're still being able to take
advantage of cloud resources okay so
yeah went up I am pulling this directly
from docker hub because it's their
public docker environment it checks the
latest normally with each one of the
containers you have a tag for it and if
you don't specify a tag it just pulls
the tag at latest by default so cool
stennis down that's it okay we found it
hello world latest and then it runs this
command which outputs hello from docker
so that's a real simple one going up a
little bit there's a lot of ones that
use in docker hub that are based images
that you can build from so if you have
like a base operating system that you
actually want to use CentOS if you want
Braille if you want a bun to fedora what
have you you can grab and start using
from centel's but these also start to be
built as base layers so from scratch we
add all of this stuff that is the CentOS
8 container this is actually the latest
which is why so simple to eat however if
you noticed between these two the hello
world docker file uses the copy command
and the CentOS archive file uses the add
command add is copy on steroids
it has a bunch of additional features
that it knows how to handle and
specifically because we're
come copying a compressed tar file into
our root directory here it says oh I
know that I need to actually
uncompress that on to that root system
there and that way also you don't have
to keep you know the entire list of the
operating system in version control you
put your par files you've built files
into that the labels are useful but not
bad important for we're gonna talk about
we're gonna skip over that but by
default this when you run the the CentOS
just like we had run hello world you get
a batch prompt as you build the layers
you can override whatever that command
is so if you wanted to do something
different
you just put another command you can do
from CentOS and then lower the next
thing just be command hi sure by default
I believe you have root yes and you can
restrict that there's a whole lot of
security configuration that you can say
I want to be using user space this you
can create users in the middle of these
files and there's a lot of them again
that this is a fairly basic one so
you're just a straight up root user into
sent pulse I'm actually going to show
you
docker hubs really nice for this there's
a huge amount of different tags so you
can get versions going back like pretty
far latest by default here you can
actually look at the tags good good and
you can actually see individual commands
as it would be built on the layers you
can see that this specific add file
which is the giant CentOS tar XZ is
adding 68 mega bytes into our image now
one of the other ones you can use that
if you need to some very very very basic
bare-bones is pal pine it's very very
lightweight you can build off of that
for very lightweight container images
just some good practice
okay okay okay well here we are okay so
kubernetes is kind of a another whole
layer on top of docker kubernetes brings
is automation for deployment scaling and
management for our containerized
remember going back unitized or
workloads this picture with a much
larger shipyard imagined in your head
all these containers spread as far as
the eye can see
so Kumari's brings to the table for us
you know where docker you had single
applications at a time inside of your
containers you put a couple of them in
there at the same time there's some
stuff with that but you're still looking
at it at a single application chunk but
when you're deploying anything modern
you're not looking at it as a single
tiny application chunk you may have
here's your front end here's your cash
here's your middle layer here's your
back end
here's microservices one through ten off
to the side doing other crazy stuff all
of these things are pieces that have to
interact and doing that with just the
docker is Park secure Bernays allows us
to abstract up and configure the way
that our containers end up on our
hardware as code again so having
configuration for the containers as code
and the configuration for our
deployments in our environment that's
code not strictly infrastructure is code
which is an important kind of
distinction between what kubernetes
doesn't does not do kubernetes manages
your containers it does not manage the
underlying hardware that it runs on fun
fact
so kubernetes is actually a Google
project originally called project seven
of nine
Google's whole container platform is
called
borg and when they were trying to figure
out a better way to manage this they
created this project seven of nine as a
friendlier Borg so the seven spokes on
the kubernetes wheel are a reference to
the for our reference to project 79
another interesting thing you'll see
kubernetes frequently referred to as k8s
just to make it shorter because
kubernetes is a very long word also
other fun fact could be that ease is a
Greek word meaning helmsman you're
navigating the waters okay so going back
to our diagram a little bit here again
instead of having the container be our
base unit inside of docker our base unit
and kubernetes is the pod and what the
pod does is allow us to group
applications together and this still
with a pod you're supposed to have a
single main application inside of your
pod but it allows you to have a bunch of
helpers along with that pod so again a
messaging service I'm sort of cue a
cache any kind of thing that makes your
app run easier if you have some sort of
communication layer for talking in
between specific apps all of these
things can package into a pod and when
they get deployed they are guaranteed to
be run together and can then talk to
each other it's really cool so stepping
up again kubernetes
is node aware so each one of your
individual pieces of hardware that can
run kubernetes is a node and has to have
kubernetes installed on it to be able to
then accept work from kubernetes so it
understands what the underlying hardware
is but it can't
again manage what that underlying
hardware is so then kubernetes will
there's actually a master and nodes
which I'll show here in just the next
slide but the important thing is the
pods get scheduled onto nodes and they
consume some chunk of resources from
that node some amount of hardware CPU
network persistent storage all of these
different things you can put together
they're really nice thing also about
kubernetes is deployments and what
deployments do is allow you to create an
availability for your application so in
this particular example we've got three
of our purple pod applications we can
call that our front end we want to be
able to call some
have a server available to serve traffic
to our users really important to accept
connections and serve traffic app we
have deployed two of our gold pods yeah
maybe that's some extra monitoring stuff
we've got going on we've got one of the
green pods and that may be our single
analytics thing off to the side running
no big deal if it completes sometime
next week whatever just the things we're
working on and we also have our two
cause for our red application so looking
at how these are spread out kubernetes
attempts to keep nodes our sorry keep
applications separated across the nodes
so that it's highly available and
balanced on the actual nodes themselves
you're not loading up node one with all
of this stuff while node two and three
are sitting idle it tries if there's you
know one per node one pod per node to
keep one of them active at all times on
each one of the nodes there's a bunch of
other different configurations for this
it's configured inside of a deployment
file which is y Amal everybody goes yeah
Mel Gamble's sometimes but then as the
nodes come up and down we can see let's
say if we lost our node to here it says
oh no well I'm supposed to have two of
node two of our red application two of
our gold application and three of my
purple application up what do I do now
it will shift and bring back up the
purple node on one of the other or
purple application on one of the other
nodes maize put now probably put the
gold application over here since there's
not already a gold application on it and
then shift red over to here and not
really shipped it's more of a like re
spin up so so it's gone no big deal but
then you know maybe next week that node
comes back up or maybe five minutes from
now then it comes back up it will again
try to ship the workload to keep
everything evenly distributed and
available for us
all right the really super powerful
thing about kubernetes is labels they
are key value pairs that are attached to
every object across kubernetes that's
your nodes
that's your claimants that's your pods
everything gets labels it's really
really really important you can label
these and then select on them later to
do a bunch of fancy stuff so let's say
well - were a little bit here compliance
if you have part of your application
that is handling PCI data and you want
part of your servers to be compliant to
be able to use and process the PCI data
but you don't want to have to secure
every single bit of your entire
infrastructure against PCI stuff you can
tag your nodes with PCI and then any of
your kubernetes pods that need PCI
compliance can be pushed to the PCI
compliant nodes and you can do the same
thing HIPAA compliance gdpr compliance
another really useful case is Bluegreen
releases you can have pods that are at
the same time you can ship traffic
between them any kind of dimension you
can think of that makes sense for your
application labeling labels are really
really cheap and they're really really
really powerful because they're also
configured as part of the code you can
update them which is also really nice
you don't have to know every single
perfect label across your entire thing
to start with you can do your best guess
right now and then next week you get
some crazy requests hey put all of our
stuff over in you know Europe Wow how do
we do that okay well let's go back in
geo tag all of our specific servers and
the location add regions add whatever
makes sense for your specific
environment the more dimensions you have
the more finely tuned you can mess with
your applications and your nodes really
really really important so what should
you label label everything go crazy with
labels they're really really cheap
people
okay so let's talk a little bit about
hybrid cloud now really the basic
architecture for kubernetes you have a
master node and two worker nodes
technically you don't really need all of
these on separate hardware and
kubernetes has a tool called mini cube
which allows you to basically spin all
these up inside of a single virtual
container this is more of a testing bed
that you can make sure your applications
and configurations are working if you
have anything less than really a
workload that needs two nodes you're
probably better off just doing doctor by
itself at that point you're probably
just in like toy applications stuff
kubernetes is a whole lot more
configuration then you're gonna need for
some toy project but again very very
minimal basic architecture a master and
two nodes directly connected that can
talk to each other the second kind of
end of that is highly available you want
at least three of the master knows if it
ends up if one of them crashes it gets
really weird if you only have two the
you lose your high availability to start
with and that's very bad you've won as
many nodes as you can at minimum three
but you can go from there
and what you'll do is connect the
masters and the nodes in between load
balancers you still want to have the
nodes communicating to a single endpoint
but the Masters will have to be able to
talk back out as well to the nodes there
this is a very very high level architect
design there's a bunch of other layers
of kubernetes it has an API server which
is also really important and we'll talk
a little bit without here in just couple
minutes that API server is really
important and it is how you connect to
kubernetes with your outside clients
your queue control other stuff that you
can do dashboards but specifically you
need the masters to be able to talk to
the nodes and they need to be able to
bounce through a load balancer for
highly available
so it knows where people kubernetes
pretty much everywhere kubernetes runs
on just about anything if you got old
Raspberry Pi sitting around run
kubernetes on them anything higher than
a Raspberry Pi - I think right well - or
better will run kubernetes you've got a
bunch of desktop computers sitting
around that are otherwise idle in the
evening but kubernetes on them now you
have a cluster to run applications on if
you've got a giant data center right and
I'm bare metal
you've got virtualized Hardware right
around your virtual machines kubernetes
runs anywhere but except your kitchen
sink until it gets connected to Wi-Fi
and then it'll run on that - in the
cloud Kyle you have a couple of
different options you're having
essentially the same architectures but
you have two main camps for how you want
to handle your cloud you have
infrastructure as a service or platform
as a service and a lot of that depends
on how much control you want of how your
containers run in the cloud with the
platform as a service essentially you're
not worrying about the underlying
hardware you say I have this application
I want you to go out and just run this
cloud and keep it up make sure it's
available if you get a bunch of traffic
scale it up if you don't have a lot of
traffic scale it down do all that for me
I don't care there's some fine-tune
knobs and it varies between all the
different cloud providers as to what
exactly what control you get for those
but all the different ones habits Amazon
has elastic container service asher has
the azure container service and Google
has App Engine so in those will run
containers in different ways in
different versions the other side of
that is infrastructure as a code your
infrastructure as a service and that
allows you to deploy your code onto
basically just bare compute instances
that gives you a massive amount of
control and if you want that if you need
that
that's an available option but you are
directly installing kubernetes on every
node you're directly managing every node
you can get patched all of these other
standard sa type
are your responsibility here's a kind of
basic idea of a very very basic hybrid
cloud architecture you don't necessarily
have to jump directly all in on the
cloud there are certain things that make
sense to run in the cloud and certain
things that make sense to run on Prem if
you're having a very very sensitive
workload keep all of that data that is
sensitive on Prem but if you've got you
know a bunch of analytics work that
isn't really sensitive for any reason
you know maybe you've got just your
website traffic logs and you want to
analyze those over you know your past
six years of beta well do you really
want to use that on your expensive
secured cluster here or do you want to
just push off to the cloud and say hey
yeah spin up resources get it done
whatever it gets done no big deal do it
cheap at the cloud they still need to
have data that can talk between each
other but they're not strictly one giant
kubernetes cluster at that point the VPN
allows traffic to go between them and
specifically the data so push data that
you don't care about to the cloud or if
it you know if you do have less
sensitive data can also see that in the
cloud very much depends on what your
specific security posture is and what
kind of data you're looking for and
again also the compliance for HIPAA can
GPR PCI and the other dozen standards
that matter for that here's a more
advanced one and we're gonna kind of
talk about this one for a few minutes
the way to do some advanced stuff is
essentially just making one giant
kubernetes cluster between everything
and this is where it requires a bunch of
fancy networking essentially what you'll
need is DNS on local and cloud and your
primary route should be to a load
balancer and you can host that either in
the cloud on Prem don't really matter
where that's hosted the primary DNS
should point to that load balancer but
if that one happens to go down DNS
should have a failover back to a second
load balancer for either
the on-prem work or the cloud and that
way you're not losing both sides of your
cluster if one of them goes down or if
you haven't just loose connectivity
between them for some catastrophic
reason the big thing here is that the
Masters are all in one control plane you
can do that using the cube admin command
cube ADM you join all of them together
and that will work because we have still
a VPN inside of this yeah the dance
pointing to this load balancer will have
the traffic balance between on priming
cloud and that way give us control
across everything which is pretty big
very big picture that is again more
stuff make sure you have firewalls in
place very very high level architecture
more to it than that but that's the
general idea for how you pull this off
this was a fantastic Dilbert comic strip
was so Dilbert complaining to his boss
Bat Yam he was not allowed to make his
applications actually cloud native and
bosses like wait a minute I'm not
allowed to just say you know kubernetes
to make everything work and over it's
just physically discipline all right
security concerns now probably if you
actually come here to a hackathon for
each one of these different pieces we're
going to talk about has different
concerns around it and a lot of it is
questions that you pretty much have to
answer for yourself I don't have any
silver bullets and this actually is
again a very complicated architecture so
it's very very heavily depends on
exactly how you decide implement it a
couple of basic concerns though with
docker container breakouts you have all
of these things scoped pretty well but
it's not perfect
occasionally stuff gets out of the
containers and then
it's on to the main host and then it can
do whatever once it's very rare it's
very hard but it has happened
docker like pretty much everything else
has CBE's against it
another thing you have to worry about is
kernel exploits the kernel being shared
across all of the containers if there's
some sort of malicious exploit with that
getting access out of one container
gives you access to do stuff in other
containers that you may not even know
we're sitting right beside you malicious
images you can mitigate this a little
bit with your trusted images and signed
images and stuff like that but it's a
very valid concern if someone ends up
getting a key and uploading something
that otherwise would be very bad for you
make sure you know what you're running
in your environment very very very
important Dalila service this is kind of
a half security and half not security
kind of thing if you fail to configure
the images properly they don't get to
see groups up a line and then they can
just consume whatever resources they
want so if you don't have the resource
limits you might end up having a
container that spins out of control it
might start just consuming truly
ridiculous quantities of your memory and
then oh well now I'm out of memory and
everything starts crashing around you
very bad again it may be entirely
unintentional maybe entirely
intentionally that's kind of where your
malicious images versus your other
configurations scanning has to happen
other things to worry about within
docker containers is unnecessary package
binaries do you really need to have a
full package manager inside your
container edge you need app you need yum
why put it in the container that's just
one more victory that you have to worry
about same thing like curled up you get
these things you can go and pull things
from the internet yet don't need that
don't put it in there on top of that
like from the security point it also
makes your images lighter which makes
them more efficient we can run more
stuff on Sam and hardware it's good
kubernetes a couple of important things
with kubernetes i mentioned earlier that
there's the API access
Tesla actually had this problem
last year they didn't secure their API
servers for kubernetes and people found
it on the internet and then submitted a
bunch of I think it was Bitcoin mining
pods into Tesla's main cluster and well
that was bad
I found it fixed it but securing your
API access very important so again we
have pods instead of containers but the
containers can if we have other exploits
get privilege escalation there's a set
of containers that kubernetes uses that
kind of does all of the internet working
for its piece of this all the monitoring
all the other stuff and those run within
a privileged space in kubernetes you
don't want your other containers to also
be living in that privileged space and
there's ways to mitigate that
but container privilege escalation is
one of the concerns for kubernetes in
general everybody permits of network
settings if you have things open to the
Internet then you never know what's
gonna happen might end up with a bunch
of blockchain or Bitcoin tires on your
kubernetes cluster bad times lastly and
this is kind of a general everything are
you skating your environment
how are you scanning all of your pods
how are you scanning all of your
clusters what interesting stuff is out
there and what are they doing you know
where your quads are times okay so the
network with hybrid cloud generally
you're going across the public Internet
the way too many have got obviously VPNs
but I want a question you can ask is can
you feasibly co-locate with your cloud
edge a lot of the clouds have services
that you can basically plug directly
into their network and skip the public
Internet entirely it becomes encrypted
to them and your point literally in the
data center by beside each other it's
expensive generally but can you do it is
that actually something that you're
willing to pay for to mitigate something
the VPN can't otherwise handle VPNs for
everything one of the cloud providers
have bandwidth caps so we'll having VPN
actually are
for you enough bandwidth between
on-premise and cloud to satisfy what
you're going to be doing between them
maybe and what happens if one side of
the other goes down is the stuff running
in the cloud really important is the
stuff running on premise really
important can you switch over can you
fail over one or the other entirely
depends on how you design stuff and what
actually is important to you again is it
your analytics load that's just kind of
running queries in the background
generating random reports yeah whatever
is it your main website Jade ranking
millions of dollars they might want to
take a look at that data
where does your data live so another big
concern with hybrid cloud is putting
data in between two of them and
sometimes if you're truly going hybrid
where you're spinning up things back and
forth is your data actually syncing
across properly are you making sure that
you're working on the most recent copy
the best version of your data and then
how do you verify that it's a big
question there's not really a good
single answer does your cloud offer
secure enough storage I specifically
emphasize enough there because every one
of the clouds offers some kind of
security but does it offer the security
that you need for your space you know is
it going to allow you put classified
data on there most of them don't like do
that unless you're in like the gum cloud
kind of space
yeah specific geolocation requirements
for your data again GPR something like
that
you can't put data from over there over
here it's really important to keep
everything separate and last secrets so
with all of this we're spinning
containers up and down we're gonna need
access to the API T's SSH keys all these
other secrets you know database
passwords how are they being stored
inside of your environment kubernetes
actually has stuff before that which was
really cool you can create committees
secrets and they just live inside the
cluster but is that what you're using or
are using some sort of third party like
key store idea how is it being stored
especially - with being partly
on-premise partly in the cloud
quickly can you actually mitigate a loss
of a secret if it goes like if you find
out that it's been compromised how
quickly can you shut it down and get a
new one out and deployed in your
environment do you want to have your
website down for a day yeah probably not
and more importantly than that and kind
of feeding back to that do you have a
plan or a system for rotating your
secrets that will definitely help in the
event that you end up losing all right
last let's talk a little bit about tools
so docker doc that's pretty much it
docker is how you run pretty much
everything through docker back the
kubernetes has two that you will
specifically want to know about for
hybrid cloud cube control which you'll
hear people grasp all sorts of different
ways it's your main API access into
deploying pods to applying deployments
to doing all of the things with
kubernetes that you need to do cube
admin will allow you to actually create
the bare clusters to start with
orchestration so if you are not 100%
convinced on kubernetes there are other
options docker swarm is the official
like darker version of kubernetes it's
the same kind of availability and
everything bringing it up and down
making sure that there are enough
running putting them on nodes keeping
things load balanced it exists but crew
Metty is seems to be the preferred way
of doing it there's mezzos and also DC
OS which is a like enterprise version of
mezzos company about DT IQ puts it out
and there's actually images for it for
it in hazard by default I think a couple
of others are getting to that and also
if you want to just use a container
platform open shipped my hat has that
now i lastly talk a little about the
security docker ee has a bunch of really
important stuff one thing in particular
is security scan it will actually show
you layer by layer what specific CVE
vulnerabilities exist inside of your
containers super nice sto is a
giant by traffic policy engine one
really cool thing about its Google is
using it with kubernetes and their
google kubernetes engine to build hybrid
clouds in a box it has a common control
plane with kubernetes it's their anthos
product it's expensive but it allows you
to just plug it in and go cuckoo Bernays
engine on Prem you get google kubernetes
engine the cloud one thing Google them
all high trust this is another one that
I was working with a little bit over the
summer with contracting they have mostly
VM space so if you're not a hundred
percent sold in two containers at this
point hydrosis is a good place to start
because they also have a container piece
so as you're mitigating or migrating
from VMs to containers you have a common
cool moving you forward and stack rocks
is the one that I really really want to
show you I actually been working with
them on and off again with the
consulting stuff this summer and told
them I was coming they actually gave me
an environment to play with which is
pretty cool I also have two swag pens
and stickers and stuff like that if you
guys want to come up and grab stuff they
have a very nice interface for
essentially profiling your entire
cluster and more importantly they have
what I think is their really big feature
this risk tab that actually prioritizes
all of the running stuff on your
environment they've got this dashboard
here that says okay we got 98 violations
but if you go and spit that as a ticket
you got right 98 violations you're just
gonna get laughed at there's no way to
prioritize that it'll get done when it
gets done whatever but with the priority
ranking that they offer you can actually
see this is why we're doing this there's
weird run conditions there's different
pieces that are old there are pieces
that have high profile CDs that are
easily fixable
so you know maybe submit the top five to
your developers and say hey go fix these
they're really important so start adding
stuff to the backlog
okay so that's the majority a very very
high-level majority for how hybrid
clouds work if you have any questions
I'll be around all weekend come hit me
up come talk to me I love talking about
cool stuff if you're interested in more
of the deep dives
shameless plug go to Lennox Academy comm
they've got stuff for docker containers
kubernetes any of the clouds you want to
learn vary from platform yeah
thanks what
[Applause]
you