welcome to knock knock who's there
identifying assets in the cloud my name
is ben sadigapoor but most people know
me online as the hamsek
i am currently the head of hacker
education at hacker one
i also on my free time create content
and stream hacking on youtube and twitch
you can follow me on all social media
platforms under at nahamsik
i also have tanner barnes here with me
i'll let him introduce himself real
quick
hi thanks ben yes my name is tanner
barnes i am a developer a pen tester
and an occasional bug hunter my day job
i'm a cyber consultant for aeon cyber
solutions
and the tools that i build for the cyber
security community you can find at my
github there and i do some occasional
live development at that twitching
so what's our agenda like today uh we're
going to talk about why the cloud is so
important
we're going to show you all our solution
and how we accomplish all of our scans
and the things that we did with it
then we're going to talk about mass
exploitation and how we found
vulnerabilities
after scanning hundreds of millions of
ip addresses
and of course we're going to have some
really really cool examples to share
with everybody
awesome right so the first question
really
when starting something like this is why
scan the cloud well
for one it was still cheaper for
ourselves to do than buying something
like a census or showdown license
and then secondly it's a really target
rich environment you know nowadays
everyone's in the cloud any type of your
large
you know fortune 100 fortune 500
companies are going to have
assets out in the cloud if you're
looking at
just cloud specific compute ranges
you're looking at
88 million to 100 million ip addresses
out there
available for clients of theirs to spin
up instances on
and the nice thing is we found with
looking at this data that
a lot of the space is used for these
companies to spin up development
instances or things that they're working
on
live so if you're able to get really
high fidelity
and really constant data on what's
out there on those ip ranges you can
actually end up finding a lot of really
exciting targets as they're being
deployed
so to give an example of that we took a
look at some of the dns names we are
finding in these certificates to get a
sense of what is kind of
out there so you're looking at some
corpse some internal which we found
fascinating a lot of
dns names with the name internalism even
though they're out there
on the public internet was very
fascinating dev like we were saying
earlier a lot of companies like to put
their development instances
for new products they're building out
there on the cloud
lots and lots of apis especially as
people look at scaling up their apis for
access to
worldwide audiences and there's an
example of two different
companies out there um oath
for verizon with about five thousand
and yahoo with quite a staggering amount
of 108 000.
so this is the fun part we we're going
to talk a little bit about how we
actually accomplished
covering such a large space like that
so quickly so
as far as the code goes it's building go
i'm a huge fan of that language i
learned it last year
and its go routines
is really built for this type of
distributed
parallel work as far as how it works
it's very simple we're looking at ip
addresses
and pulling out the cname and dns name
records from those certificates
there's not really a lot of magic in the
code it's a very simple
piece of software but the real magic
comes in being able to scale it up
to cover such a large space right so
this is a really fun slide when i showed
this to ben
he was really excited as well as some
other people we're looking at about
1.4 billion unique targets in the space
of about 15 minutes
which comes out to a rate of 1.6 million
a second ends up being about 28 million
identified targets
across 11 different ports that we
identified as kind of
high trafficked ports and the other
magic part is that all this is done for
about 25
in aws charges so with every good side
there's also a bad we learned a lot of
lessons
on our way to that kind of mythical 25
dollars in aws charges
one don't try this with lambda or an
initial try with being able to
spread it out over lambda workers is
impossible they won't let you spin up
that many
and once you start them there is no
stopping them
so we had a handful of aws bills that
were
quite exciting to receive
and on the code side every little bit of
memory and cpu cycle matters especially
when you're trying to cover this work as
quickly as possible
with aws billing you per second the
quicker you can do it
obviously the lower your bill becomes so
once the code was written it was a lot
of work
to kind of profile it with memory and
cpu profilers to get
every little bit of performance out of
it as kind of a final note it was
important
um after we had these resources that we
found from the scanner to make sure
before delving into any of them that
they were
specifically bounty targets we got some
very exciting
angry notes on linkedin and our
email accounts from csos who were not at
all pleased we were taking a look at
their resources
right so once you have the data that's
all well and good but
it's important to you know enrich it in
ways that makes it easier to
process so some of the ways
we identified to enrich this data are
here kind of below so
one thing we did was initially was to
take a list of curated bounty targets
that we were familiar with and that were
out there and known about
and pulled out from our large list of
mappings all those targets which were
bounty targets so that will give you a
quick
one-off way at the start to really
filter your list down to targets that
are for sure in a bounty scope
once we had that data as we started
doing the scans more often
we started doing a diffing of scan to
previous scan
this allowed us to really quickly from
those bounty targets
realize what was most recently
spun up since our previous scan and that
was really
more fresher of the targets which is
more of a ripe
area for finding bounties
another thing that had a lot of really
great benefits for us was doing some v
host discrepancies so taking a host and
accessing it by its ip address accessing
it by
its dns name and then accessing with the
host header of localhost
and checking the response links and
response codes to
seeing hosts that maybe weren't
answering on their dns name
but were accessible with a ip address or
a hostname of localhost
kind of two final things we're pulling
the just the raw
titles of the pages that came back the
response links and status codes to get a
sense of
you know which targets might be more
interesting to go after
and then some general fingerprinting of
services that were live in products
so if for some reason a cve was to
appear
in a product which we'll get to later
something a specific example
we were able to quickly zone in on
or zoom in pardon me on those targets
that
match that service and start looking at
those immediately
right so
1.4 billion targets creates a lot of
noise
uh we found this great
list on github it's a little hard to
pronounce that name so i'm not gonna
butcher it for them i'd hate to say it
wrong
so that list was a great jumping off
point for
finding bounty targets that we could
start filtering
so that filtering was done is done for
us at scan time
and puts it into two separate buckets of
targets that we can start looking at
immediately and processing for
further tooling
right so back to the scan diving so
multiple scans are obviously going to
have
overlap right if somebody like tesla
has their home page out on the cloud
we can pretty reasonably assume that
that is always going to be in a scan
every time until their company goes
under hopefully not
but things like that can really fill up
the scans with noise so it's helpful to
do
a diff scan to scan to kind of weed out
the things that are always there and
look at
what might be new another thing that
diffing has helped us with is it allows
us to learn
how targets over time name their host so
some of these targets we were looking at
some of these bug bounty scopes we were
starting to get a really good
understanding
week over week how these
companies were naming their cloud
resources and in some cases we were able
to already
know what a host's dns name was going to
be before
it was even live which was really
exciting to see
well yes so
after that another fun thing that we
decided to do that would really give
us a deep insight into some of these
hosts was virtual host discrepancies
so you take an ip address and you
send it a request of three different
types so
you send it as a request to the ip
address with a host header of the ip
address
you send it with the ip address and a
host name of the dns name you're
interested in
and then finally the ip address with a
hostname of localhost
and then you look at the response length
and the status codes
of all three of those to look for
discrepancies as an example
on a bounty target this was an aem
instance that was vulnerable
that was only accessible by ip address
so
knowing the host name was helpful but
you wouldn't be able to access it that
way but if you hit it
directly by a p address you were able to
get access to the instance
cool awesome so kicking off the bin to
do some talking about some of the
expectation we were able to do with
these hosts
so when it comes down to mass
exploitation you have two options you
can either go after a single target
or you can just go after every single
one of your targets that you're hacking
on
and look for the same pattern but if you
decide to do a single target this is how
we approached it so first of all
we want to understand how this target
works are there any specific deployment
process they follow what are the apis
being
deployed where are the documentation for
those apis being stored is it going to
be
in a particular folder is it always
swagger is it always an
application.waddle
who knows we want to figure those out
and they want to also understand where
are the internal and corporate sites
so is it corporate.site.com or do they
have an
actual corporate domain where they host
all these things
well as an example with verizon media
we came across a bunch of application
models a bunch of swagger uis
and we noticed that a lot of the
internal targets
were having the port 4443 open
and it was very very interesting so we
decided to keep analyzing this pattern
on every target we went to
but on the other hand when you're doing
multiple targets where you're spraying
four
phones and praying that it comes back as
a valid vulnerability
it's a different approach the first
thing is you look for cves things that
you know are already vulnerable
you look for uh other development
processes like
a back end that companies may use like
spring boot or jolokia where you know
there's going to be potential
vulnerabilities there
of course the api documentation works on
both approaches of
single target and multiple target and
then
last but not least this is my favorite
thing to look for is
looking for sensitive or internal tools
that are not supposed to be exposed
these are things like jenkins gitlab
github jira and of course all of these
are approached differently but it's very
very good to have
now let's talk about when mass
exploitation
and avoiding false positive because if
you want to avoid false positive
identification becomes a very very
important part of this
so how does it look well you have to
understand what you want to go after you
can't just say i want to look for all
these things you have to understand how
graphql
works what apis look like what graphona
looks like
what makes these things unique so for
example
in some in most cases you want to look
for three things
the response header because in the
header sometimes i have a signature that
defines
what this program is or what this
application is the response body because
it could have a signature in the body
that says
powered by so and so company and of
course a specific endpoint that endpoint
could be a logo
it could be an api endpoint it could be
an error page
whatever you're looking for you have to
really understand what that means
so for example we were looking for
swagger i've talked about this up a
bunch of times
if you're looking for swagger 9 out of
10 times you can come across this
endpoint called swagger resources
where it tells you where the location of
the documentation is
and of course there's a keyword swagger
version that you can use
as a part of the fingerprint and we'll
talk about that in a little bit again
and we'll talk
we'll put it together to understand how
to actually look for these in mass
so of course if you don't want to if you
don't look if you don't find the
swagger resources as this one
you can always just spray for swagger
api docs and other
paths that you know of that api
documentation could be stored
within swagger and look for the keyword
base path
the base path is something that every
single documentation will have and
they have to tell you where the api
exists how to access it where to access
it and so on
and before i move on i want to make a
note that just finding this api
documentation is not a vulnerability by
itself
it just helps you not have to play hide
and seek with the api it tells you where
the endpoints are
how they work what to expect and so on
so please don't report you know swagger
documentation on its own
spend some time to understand how the
api works and look for
vulnerabilities within those apis
the next one is graphql what makes
graphql important
or unique is if you hit a slash graphql
endpoint in most cases you're going to
get a 400 error
and it's going to return an error that
says
hey the get query is missing so knowing
that query missing is going to be in
your response
when we hit graphql and we're expanding
expecting a 400 baht request
we can use it for the fingerprint to
always look for graphql instances
across all of our bug bounty programs
another example is one of my favorites
big shout outs to rodonator for doing
this justin gardner
he found a cv in grafana we're looking
at this data
and we'll talk about a little bit but
grafana it's really easy
if you go to the web route it 302 is to
login
and within that response you will see
grafana in the title and you can also
see the public image grafana mask icon
that makes it very very obvious it says
grafana so if you see these three things
there is a high chance that this cannot
be a false positive and grafana instance
actually exists on that ip address
all right well we knew all this but now
that we know how these things
look and how to look for them what do we
do
well while we're developing the scanner
we didn't have a lot of tools of our own
we're still figuring out how to do it
so we decided to use tools that are
already out there
i personally love using meg huge house
of tom nom nom if you're not familiar
with tom
i definitely uh recommend following him
on twitter and checking out all his
awesome tools that he has put out for
bug bounty hunters on his github
but meg allows you to spray a number of
endpoints
against a ton of hosts and it goes a
step further
and it saves the response code in a
folder called out
and it indexes them so as you can see
each line is
a host that i've hit it on the left hand
side
it's where it stored the response
the response code and response headers
and everything that came back
on the right hand side it gives you the
response code and it gives the url of
whatever we hit
so if you go for example i'm looking at
netflix if i go to ls and do ls out on
netflix you can see every ip i just i
have hit it has it organized for me and
within that folder the response
body is fully saved this is all very
very useful
and we'll talk about it a little bit as
well so now that we know all this
information
we want to put a one-liner you can use
whatever language you like
i like doing things with grep and i
promise you this is probably not the
best way to do it
but it worked i made this thing up i
will explain what it does in a sec
but i saved this as a bash alias called
search
and every time i would get done scanning
with meg i would type in search
and look for whatever i was looking for
so
the first thing we're doing in that
command that i just showed earlier is
we're gripping for a response code so if
i'm looking for swagger
if the swagger documentation is there
i'm looking for a status code of 200.
here i'm looking for metrics that
doesn't matter what we're looking for
but we want to make sure the status code
the response code matches first next
we're telling it hey i want you to cut
the output
and tell me where the path for the
response body is
so if you match the 200 tell me where
the file is
where the response body is saved for
that ip or domain address and then we do
a sort you it's a bad habit of mine it's
just to make sure there are no
duplicates
and right after that we're going to pass
it to x-args and we're going to say hey
i want you to loop through all of these
and i want you to grip um for the
fingerprint that we came up with so if
i'm looking for swagger i'm looking for
swagger version
i want you to open every one of those
files in those folders
look for that fingerprint and then after
that i want you to cut it up
and give me the ip address or the domain
where this thing was identified so we've
saved it we ran it and now we're going
to look at some examples
so i like i said i have called this
thing search it's just an easy thing you
can call it whatever you want
i'm looking for 200 the status quo being
200 and again as we mentioned earlier
swagger version is our benchmark or our
fingerprint
whatever you want to call it and then we
ask you know we cut up a little bit more
and on the left side right here all
these
uh the white box right here is pretty
much every ip address that came back
within netflix's infrastructure
that had swagger version uh in that
endpoint that we hit swagger resources
same thing for graphql we did the same
exact thing we said search for
400 and if there is a 400 status code
read the body from that folder
tell us where the keyword missing comes
up and then spin out
all the ipa changes for us so all these
ip addresses had a working
graphql instance that we could have
played with and see if we can find
vulnerabilities in
but all of that is fine but i don't
think it scales
especially when you're going after
millions of ip addresses
and you're mass gaining almost the
entire internet so i'll let tanner
really quickly explain how we approach
this on our own
and how this tool works
right so one of the things we wanted to
do
with all these hosts was get a good
sense of what was running on them
so the easiest way to do that is find
something that is
identifiable in the https response
of these hosts and key off on that and
build yourself a list of those
identifiers that's exactly what we did
it's very simple tools very similar to a
lot of the other fingerprinting tools
we built one kind of ourselves just to
have an easy way to tie
in to our scans
that we run ourselves and this is
triggered automatically after our new
scans come
in so you can see an example over there
sorry to the right where you just have
the name of the service you're
interested in
and the fingerprint or fingerprints that
it's going to be looking for in either
the response body the response headers
or really anywhere in any of that
response data that comes back
and the good thing about this tool is
that you can also add you know this json
body and
add whatever fingerprints you want and
customize it to your needs
we've released this and we'll talk about
it later on during this talk
now let's talk about some bug bounty
examples i think this is where
the fun happens a little bit for us so
we wanted to talk about
asset monitoring as tanner mentioned
earlier we caught on to how this company
was deploying things
what they were deploying and how they
were doing it and it ended up giving us
some really cool
phones unfortunately because it's a
private program
we couldn't do any screenshots but what
i can do is give you a high level
overview of what happened
so about a year ago i discovered xss in
this application
what it was every time that uh you would
go to this website you go to slash demo
demo app it would take you to this
folder in this file where that
parameter had an xss in it we reported
it
never thought of this ever again but i
beat me being me
i saved that path of demo app slash demo
underscore app.html
i put it in my keywords or my word list
if it comes up it comes up
well a year later almost i come across
the same website the same company and i
realized that
this thing came up in a development
environment well that's interesting
i have this in my word list for a reason
i've came across it before
and i've seen this already well let's
create a fingerprint the fingerprint
that we created was a javascript file
that would be called
within the body of this file in the html
file that they relied on on their cdn
so all we had to do was use meg
or use our tool either one and look for
this path right here
and make sure the fingerprint of our
javascript file that we have found was
in there and within our scan we found
six different instances of this where it
was vulnerable to an xss
and that's an easy win so every time a
new asset comes up for this company
we hit this endpoint is it there awesome
that's export for xss and let's report
it
the next one is hunting for cves this is
elite c cve as you can see cv2020 13379
i'm not going to talk about the
technical aspects of this talk if you're
interested
in this please go look up ryan raiders
ssrf and grafana on youtube i think he
did a talk at
activitycon with hacker1 i highly
recommend that it's a very very good
talk on ssrf
and it helped us identify some
vulnerabilities using this bug
so we talked about how to look for
grafana
obviously grafana goes to login when you
hit the web route the keyword grafana's
in there
but then we later on learned that
grafana is also hosted on the port 3000
great let's scan for port 3000 and look
for everything that has grafana in it in
our bug bounty table
so we pulled everything from port 3000
from bug binding table as i mentioned
we also looked for everything that has a
keyword grafana in it
from the bounty table we hit slash login
with meg
we fingerprinted for it all and
we again we use our search thing and we
found all the possible instances
of grafana that were existing in our
database but we could have skipped the
login part and instead of looking for
login since we know the poc for this
thing we could have literally just used
the ssrf
have the ssrf hit the one six nine two
five four one six nine two five four i p
address
where it's the aws metadata instance and
look for the keyword metadata and if
that comes up
then that means it's vulnerable because
it's giving us the
cloud cloud instance or cloud metadata
instance
because it's vulnerable and we can
identify it using meg
so as an example here is what we have
found with
some of the bug bounty programs that we
have hit
one of these companies we identified
several number of
vulnerable instances they were kind of
impressed with how we found it
um and this is kind of how we did it was
with the scan that we're doing
continuously with tanner and there was
not
just that company there were other
companies that were also vulnerable to
this
that we came across so it was really
really fun to be able to find these
things
because of the research that rhino has
done and the research that we were doing
in parallel
between me and tanner and we got to get
some really cool boundaries out of it
takeaways from this is just because a
company has multiple instances of the
same app
it doesn't mean that you're going to get
multiple bounties but multiple instances
sometimes means a higher reward or maybe
a bonus on top
also if you're going to hunt for cves
and o days give them some time to patch
don't do it the same day gets dropped
you're going to piss people off
you may get upset because they're not
going to pay you but just give them
enough time give them
30 days 60 days whatever that is it's
appropriate time whatever you think it's
appropriate
and then if you report it too early you
don't get any money don't get upset
it's just a part of the game that's what
happens when you go and hunt for old
days
the next one is a classic admin we
sprayed admin across our entire bounty
table but we didn't find anything
interesting
except this one instance where we would
hit
admin and we were looking for login but
we realized the login was pretty much
sending us to another path called mgmt
which
we assumed it was management some path
and then login.jsp
and of course mgmt had a login page that
was admin
as you can see on the right this is what
it looked like
and of course if you use the credentials
admin admin
it led us into this website's backend
and it gave us some
user data but that wasn't enough that's
not fun because
we have access to this one back-end so
what the thing that i'm interested in is
is this company reusing this management
backend
over and over on other websites and can
i log into those using the same
admin admin credentials so let's break
the sound apart
the wxyz that we have is the application
name
that always stays the same so if this
was some
weird name that we knew about that's
always going to be there the permutation
was a little bit weird because it wasn't
the traditional
dev internal corporate these
permutations i think were different
platforms where this thing
was being used and then obviously the i
wish i could disclose this target.com
is the domain that we're going after and
the core app is
where you would get logged in so once
you log in to the website
it would center this core application
and that was very interesting because it
was very very unique
so it made it really easy for us to
fingerprint
so i go back to our database we look for
everything that had the app name let me
go back to it so anything that had the
wxyz
we want that and we want to make sure
it's within that domain that we're
hacking on
on i wish i could disclose as we fed
that to meg and our search tool
and then we see how many more came up
and i think we roughly found about 15 i
know it says exact but i think there
were some other
issues with some of the ip addresses but
out of those 15
12 of them were vulnerable and we can
log into 12 of those with admin admin
each of those had access to different
platforms this thing was being used on
and each of those have different users
with pii
and i think it was roughly about a
million users data that was accessible
and also i think the website had rc by
design i think had some really weird
file uploads some stuff to control
servers
so by default we could have probably rc
this thing
but you know when you're inside an
internal website from a
corporate standpoint you don't want to
push those limits without their
permissions
so we reported them pointed out that hey
there could be rce in here and we let
that team take care of the rest of it
and this one is i think our one of our
last examples and one of my favorites
is where we got to fish for employee
sessions by
looking into hip dumps or heaped i'm
sorry of
this particular company and let me
explain
so let's before we get into that let's
talk about what a heap dump
example looks like how we identify it
and so on so if you go on spring boots
documentation
there are a few things that we
understand there are a few really
interesting endpoints
one is the http trace which provides
information about the
request response exchange so if you send
a request to that website
it pretty much stores it on that
endpoint
both your request and the response and
also you know captures the headers
including the cookies and so on the heap
dump obviously just
it's a heap jump from that applications
jvm
and in the response headers there is a
content type that says
application vnd spring brute
actuator whatever version plus json
so three things that we cared about does
the content type return this
is there a 200 for http trace or heap
dump
if there is we need to export this and
we did so
a big shout out to zlz and zayat these
guys really wanted to own
this megacorp this is one of the biggest
companies i've ever had the pleasure to
hack
and unfortunately i can't disclose who
they are but let's just call them
megacorp for this instance
so we went back we dumped every asset we
could find
and we sprayed http trains against all
domains
we discovered and came across a bunch of
different http traces
and the pattern look like x y z
internal proxide actuator http trace
that was the first one we got to
identify
and this is what the response looked
like so if you can see
you can see that the url there it says
what kind of uh request it was it was a
get request
there was a cookie for the the header
for the cookie
and some other information and you can
see at the bottom right there it says
internal prod mega corp and it was weird
why is it both internal and prod
i want to know more so what can we do
we'll go look for x y z whatever the
application name is
and we want to identify different
permutations
so we identified four other instances
one being
the last one being the one that we
already knew about internal prod
then we realized there's also internal
and there's also prod
and there's also just the app.site.com
without any permutations
so we started brute forcing for actuator
http trace and so on and we came across
these last four
which gave us some credentials and
cookies that we could potentially use
and as i mentioned as you can see on the
screen these were a little bit useless
because we couldn't use this
the set of cookies that was given to us
initially but there was something there
we can't just let this go by itself
there's got to be more
stuff coming in so we decided
to look for other endpoints let's forget
about actuator let's forget about heap
dump
are there other things being hosted on
this site and we we found that so the
first one was we found this thing a
folder called core app
we found a folder called application we
found a folder called viewer
and then we found a folder called xyz
services where xyz is this name on the
subdomain
that we had and it just had its own
folder
within it and within all of those
folders we came across more actuators
more heap dumps and more http traces
that had more data in it
so once we were able to collect all that
data we
queried for every single heap dump we
collected every single http trace
we collected everything that had the
keyword cookie in it then we started to
load these cookies into our burp
and started to match and replace and
we're actually able to
eventually log into an externally
exposed internal asset owned by this
megacorp
as you can see here we will log into
some internal site where they had almost
all the employees data
we were able to edit the activate delete
uh this one was some sales website i
believe
we didn't want to dig into it too much
we left it alone as it was
um this is another one i can't explain
really what this one was
unfortunately but these were all
internal tools that we had got
access to but there's a lot of lesson
learned here if you come across
a heap dump for example or an http trace
stop brute forcing so you can monitor
for cookies take a break
come back the next morning hoping that
it's still there
and make sure you monitor for it as you
can see here zlz is like hey
is anyone directory brute forcing yup
it's ben i can see all his
requests going in live can you stop so
we can uh wait for these
companies uh employees to log in and
capture a set of credentials
and then we also realized this isn't the
only place that uses this i've seen this
a number of time on other places
so let's go back and scan a few other
organizations
and see if we can find more results and
of course we were able to find a few
other ones
as you can see on the screen that gave
us some really good vulnerabilities
i'm going to switch over to tanner and
let him talk about some of the cool
stuff that came out of this research
some of the tools and releases that we
have done
[Music]
awesome yeah thanks
so we are going to release two
tools that we use internally with our
scans that we talked about previously
right so we have go fingerprint which
allows you to supply a json file with
your fingerprints
and then a list of urls to test them
against and you see in that top right
what the output looks like you'll get
the url that matched a fingerprint a
colon and then the fingerprint that it
matched
the second one is v host scan so it
takes a
common delimited file a comma delineated
file excuse me
of the host name the ip address
and the port and then for those lines it
will test for those
three different access variations with
the host name with the ip address
and a localhost host header and then it
will turn you
a json file containing all of those
targets with the host
the uh excuse me the
status code and the response length for
those three checks
that you can use to diff the the
differences of to try to find some
vulnerable targets
as well as those two tools we have also
this is going on month two of
recon dev our site for being able to
access the scan
data so we're up to 300 million plus ip
addresses that we're targeting again
across those 12 ports
we update the data weekly we also have
plans as we kind of move along to
possibly updating this data
more frequent frequently but for now
these targets are updated weekly
allows you to query one domain at a time
and you'll return
the data in the json array with the ip
address
the port that it was found on any domain
names from the certificates that were
scanned
along with some other data that we might
be making live here
shortly this is accessible through the
site
sorry about that it is accessible by the
site or through
a cli api off of
just through curling or through python
or however you want to actually access
the data
using it through the site is not
required
awesome thank you tanner let's stop this
up really quickly there are some things
i want to address before
we uh end this talk first of all if
you're getting into bug bounties please
please please take the time to
understand your target
understand how to deploy things where
they do them how they do it
look for patterns look for patterns of
mistakes and abuse those as much as you
can
familiarize yourself with all these
things that you see frequently it could
be a particular app it could be a
particular backend
whatever that is insert locally mess
with it understand it
get really good at fingerprinting if you
want to get into the recon thing
understand how to fingerprint things so
you can identify him on the fly as
you're scanning things
and of course last but not least create
a good database of acid you can hack on
it doesn't have to be
um you have to overdo it like this like
we have
but have a text file have somewhere
where you store all your data
your historic data and always go back to
it and look for differences between your
last scan your current scan
that could be very very helpful if you
want to become successful in bug hunting
a lot of the things that i've mentioned
during the examples retainer
um aren't things that are super new
again when we were doing this research
we did this research in three months we
were going to do it for a year
we cut it down to three months because
we wanted to get ahead of it a little
bit
so we wanted to look for low-hanging
fruits and we did
but think about it from a adversary's
point of view
for example when we had access to those
internal assets from the mega
corp we could have just started our own
campaign within
uh being internal on that company's
internal network on their internal
assets and applications
and see how far that could go the second
thing is
don't just collect assets and data and
pay them spray them with generic word
list
there's a lot of times where you can go
into an application
you need to be logged in before you can
do anything to it so dig deep
go into there log in sign up log in and
do your recon within
your session and not just automate it
where you just throw things at it and
hope something comes back
now a lot of times again you want to
understand your application and you want
to understand that site and that's going
to take you the longest way possible
and there's a lot of hate and there's a
lot of criticism for bug bounties
but i'm going to tell you this from
someone who's been doing bug boundaries
for years
you're only going to get back what you
put in so if you want to
become good at bug hunting find bugs
with actual impact
forget about best practices forget about
missing headers forget about all that
stuff
find ways you can either own a customer
on a user on that side
or own that company's infrastructure and
again i've said this a million times
spend time learning your targets
behaviors and make sure you understand
how they operate
and this is just a meme i wanted to
throw out there there was a lot of
really good vulnerabilities i've talked
about patterns a lot
you see the semicolon pattern there's a
lot of good tips about it there was a
lot of good
uh research that came out because of it
path normalization is really really good
i highly recommend watching orange size
talk on this from a few years ago at
defcon but i wanted to throw that out
there because
we did some stuff with it at uh in mass
with all the data we had
and there was a lot to be done with this
kind of vulnerabilities
and last but not least i want to say a
huge thank you to zayat
zlz donut pointer tom nom nom erb sam
ryan raider and of course tanner for
being a
great partner in crime and thank you all
for watching this talk and we appreciate
you
thanks guys