song young
song presents deep dive into art
android runtime for dynamic binary
analysis
this talk proposed a new technique to
quickly and effectively analyze the app
by modifying the a-r-t
it shows an environment in which an
attacker can still code
interface parameters return value
fields and stack trace of a function
execute
with using a debugger of surfing tools
in real time
hi nice to meet you everyone uh my name
is hanyan song
i work at the fsi of south korea
the fsa is responsible for the security
of korean financial security
and i'm researching mobile security at
fsi
and i do penetration testing for korean
company
i have experience speaking at several
international security
conferences in europe and
asia
today i'd like to analyze how android
runtime works in detail
and based on the analysis research i'm
going to propose a technique
to analyze the app easily and
effectively
by customizing the entry runtime
first of all i want to explain why i
became
interested in the android runtime and
analyzing mobile app is very important
process
for those who work in mobile security
like a mobile analyst
or hackers this is because it's possible
to get
a clear idea of how marvel works or
find vulnerability in your mobile apps
only when
when proper analysis is done beforehand
there are two main ways to analyze
mobile app
first you can analyze the app if it
exists as your file
in general in android bytecode can be
converted
converted back to the original java
source code
using open source tool such as a texture
jar
another way is to analyze the app while
the file
is executed and loaded in memory
there is a dynamic analysis tool called
frida
that can analyze the app during the
runtime
florida is very high web framework and
it's
used by almost all security researchers
today
so application that handles sensitive
information
such as banking gaming
and healthcare also to the security
technique
to protect themselves from their
analysis and
attack we call this technique rasp
runtime application server protection
many secret companies develop rasp
make it as module and share it and
most of apps with sensitive information
are
actually using the module this technique
check
not only whether the os has been
tempered
but they also encrypted transmit or
receive data
in addition to that they detect and
block the
attacker from accessing the memory area
so if you try to analyze analyze an app
protected by
rasp you will be detected and blocked as
shown in the picture here
this top picture shown the process of
decompiling to original java source code
using text which are since the
app is protected by anti-decompile
technique
you are in trouble with convert it back
to the original java source code
the bottom picture here shown warning
message
generated when it detects and detected
running in
uh in a root environment or any
attempted
attempted dynamic analysis using frida
so can we bypass rasp
of course in my thought there does not
exist 100 of security but
what i want is automated and effective
and fast method
however security modules are difficult
to bypass
because they are applied in multi-ways
technique
so what's the problem the problem is
time they also know that the rasp cannot
define the completely
attacker the purpose of the purpose of
the rasp
is to annoy the attacker as much as
possible
and increase the time required for the
attack
there is no perfect mechanism and we are
in state
continue have to fight i want to get
i want to get away from the endless
fight between protection
and bypass just like tom and jerry
so over the past few years i have i have
been thinking about
how to analyze the app easily and
effectively
without being detected by rasp
then i found the two paper published in
using 2010
and amc 2016.
the main subject of paper were about
developing a framework that can
dynamically nearly analyze app by
modifying the runtime of
android it was very interesting as
it modified the os to create the
environment for
analysis but uh
the the advantage of technique was that
app could not be analyzed without
directx the
app apps executable file or memory
but unfortunately the paper were written
for
all the androids so i had to analyze the
new runtime in
android 10 in detail
so i shipped my focus from application
to android os itself and
there is corner and platform
in the past few years i started analyze
the android source code
and develop the custom os
so i ended up building an android os by
customizing the corner and platform
the oss built-in functions such as
backdoor for
privilege escalation sc linux bypass
say protein bypass android verify boot
bypass
and corner memory access driver
i don't think i can cover all of these
today
due to the limit time so in this session
i will focus on presenting how customize
the runtime
for the dynamic analysis of application
ait's abbreviation for android runtime
ait can be called the heart of android
and the player keyword in loading up
binary
application memory management and
execution
and optimization however it
is not easy to analyze in deep how the
runtime works
in the rest restless version of android
this is because the size of code is huge
about
150 gigabyte and various techniques
compiling
profiling and optimization are also
applied to
apply to the rest version of aert in
addition
since google has changed changed the
android runtime drastically each time a
new version of
android is released to optimize the
performance
storage usage and the system of data
webs
how is structured and how it operates
are different
from each runtime version
however since all bytecode of app
is interpreted and executed through the
art
if the attacker understands how exactly
the app works on art all necessary
information
can be stolen in real time to analyze
the app in this speaking therefore aim
to
analyze android 10 aart in detail
i propose a new technique to quickly and
effectively
analyze the app by modifying the alt
to divide from the the existing app
analysis method
this technique is not detected by rasp
and enable dynamic analysis of
all the function executed through the
ait
and i also develop a developer framework
in which an attacker can still code
interface parameters return value
field and stack trace of running
function
in the real time without using debugger
or hooking tool
let's take a right let's take a look at
how android runtime has changed
from version to version
first when we talk about java in java
virtual machine
an android application written in java
language for dynamic
develop for developer productivity and
code mobility
on desktop and server environment a java
program is compiled to the java
byte code which is an intermediate
representation
for java virtual machine
java virtual machine run the java byte
code the java byte code is based on the
stack based
based introduction however since the
performance of stack based
java bytecode on resource-related
mobile device is pure poor
due to slow interpretation
so android researchers have created new
bytecode set
which is a diabetic byte code for uh
for diabetic virtual machine to improve
the performance of android
application in contrast to java byte
code
the uh the direct byte code is based on
register based instruction set therefore
it can reduce the code size
and the running time in mobile device
until android pro and earlier there was
only interpreter
in direct virtual machine every time you
run the app
the interpreter converts all bytecode
into native code
a slowdown apps on startup startup
timeshow battery
in order to in order to boost up the
performance
just in time compiler was introduced in
android pro
on derby virtual machine
just in time compiler cache the code
while generating the native code at the
time of execution
to prevent to prevent to the repeated
generated of native code
for each time of the same function call
as pre-contrary as frequently used
functions
are executed with the native code
that was created in advance the
performance has increased
this code however consume amount or
mountain memory
the runtime structure where jit and
interpreter
were in place had not changed for a
while
the conventional approach result in very
well performance
when compared to the compiled language
like xi and xiplus plus
as a result slow and space constrained
computing device
have tended not to include the virtual
machine
so android kitkat so in android kitkat
google introduced a new runtime
alt in android kitkat art
was experimentally available
starting from android lollipop in 2015
google decided to replace diabetic
virtual machine
and made the ait as a departure on time
to improve the runtime performance
ait adopted ahead of time compile
compilation strategy instead of
interpretation
ait provider compiler called x2080
the dedex 280 will directly compile the
compiled export into native code
during the app installation and then
stored as an
aot file the result is essentially
an er file that that that is then
executed natively so
instead of having bytecode that that is
interpreted by virtual machine
it has native code that can be executed
natively by by the processor this is uh
this
is called the aot compilation but
main different uh main difference is
that art
pre-compiled everything but direct
virtual machine use
heuristic to detect the code that run
most often
and only compile a subset of bytecode
during the execution
and another difference between uh
another difference between
the the old diabetic virtual machine and
art
was the performance as all as
all the execution code of app were run
as
native code the startup speed was
improved compared to the bytecode
in addition to that every time you ran
the app
it didn't use the interpreter but it
called the native code
and it resulted in reducing battery
consumption
since jit wasn't used anymore the memory
usage
was also reduced because it didn't keep
the code caching memory
and and and of the aot compilation
the dex208 compiler can perform multiple
passes for optimization
to achieve better performance
but it uh it lost as much as it gained
the big the biggest problem was it took
too much time to install
it and it took too much time to update
the system
via ota eventually by compiling orbit
code to native code
at install time it gained the app's
performance
however it required much more time to
update app and system
and more storage too then is it really
the
best compile or byte code into native
code
at app insert time we need to first
understand the usage pattern of a mobile
user
in fact we don't use all of the menu in
in the app for example
i use a mobile banking app there are
there are a lot of financial related
menu india
and i just i use just two
first i check how much is in my account
second i transfer money from from the
account
that's it all there are so many
menu in the app i use only two feature
then you don't re uh you don't really
need to compile everything
wasting your time and and storage
or all you need is to selectively
compile the code
that are frequently used by the user
so in android 7 google was reintroduced
just in time compiler there was remove
in
android 5. the justin time compiler
complements
aud compiler and helpful improvement in
help improve runtime performance
and they removed the byte code compiling
step in aot compilation
during the app installation so
when will the aot compiler start working
google introduced a new technique called
profile guide optimization
during the app installation the aot
compiler doesn't
does not operate and uh and the app
isn't
app is not installed immediately as byte
code or when you use the app
the byte code is executed using the
interpreter
and it counts how many times each
individual function is called
called at execution time as the number
of execution
increases it divides the state of
function from
cold to warm and finally hot
once the state of function becomes warm
the profiling is profiling info is
created to the
grid to record the information such as
the number of
execution then save in the
uh save in the mobile device
when you don't use your phone or when
you charge it
based on uh based on the profiling input
the profile service
use aot2 compile the bytecode into
native code
and store it and once the
state of the function which is hot
the byte code is compiled into the
native code by
just in time compiler and store it in
memory
as a cache i explained earlier
that the old compilation method convert
or byte code into native code
and store regardless of of the usage
pattern
it really slow down and update an
installation
and require more space
but now we have profile guide
optimization
that selectively creates a native code
for the feature frequently used
profile guide optimization already
android runtime to help
improve improve on apps performance
by building a profile of a hard code and
focusing each optimization
this widget too big improvement while
reducing the traditional memory
and the storage impact of our
fully compiled air it seemed
we found the perfect balance between app
speed storage usage
and updated time however on project 3
this method turned out to bring another
problem
so what is the problem here
however app runs slowly at first range
because profile guide optimization rely
on device to optimize them
based on this code profile in idle time
which means it could be a few days
before
before the app to run faster
to solve the problem of slow execution
at first launch
of app google introduced the cloud-based
profile technique
in android 9. as shown in figure
the profile information of app greatly
created on each user's device is almost
uploaded to the cloud
server in the cloud server most
apps are share a good amount amount of
code profile information
that are used across across different
users and the device and this can be
globally optimized for everyone
the initial user's device can create a
profile information
for rest of the user space so the
following users can optimize the app
after aot compilation
using cloud-based profile data
at the time of app insert installation
this slide showed the whole process of
how apps are compiled and executed in
android android 10 first
when you try to insert the app apk file
is downloaded to your mobile device
along with the optimized profile data as
described earlier
during the installation the profile
information is used
used by aot compiler to selectively
compile the byte code into aot
code for the function
that are commonly used by user
second when you executed the app
ai detects whether the code of the
running method is compiled
or not if the code is already compiled
by
chip or aot it directly called the
code loaded in memory and executed
immediately
if this code is still bytecode the
interpreter executed
and increase the method execution
counter
if the counter of of the method can
continue to increase
and it become warm state the profile
information
such as a number of method execution is
saved in the device as your file
while you are not using the phone but
just charging overnight
the service company the service compiled
the one
method using the aot compiler
and save it save it in file as your
aud code next time the method will be
executed right away as aot code
from from the beginning and if the
counter keeps
increasing and it finally becomes the
hot state
the method is compiled in real time by
just the entire compiler
and the story uh sorry the memory as a
code cache then the code loaded in
memory
is executed and as soon as a
function is called
as you see here art has various state
state of code and complex structure
where the apps are optimized and
executed
based on the pattern of individual and
entire user base
okay now i'd like to take a closer look
at
the android runtime at code repair
based on that i'm going to propose your
technique to analyze the execution of
app
through the ait customization
as we saw earlier there are three types
of code
in ait the basic text byte code
and compile the aot code and jit code
aot code and byte code are saved in file
while cheat code exists in memory as
cache code
in mobile device there are three files
in in application directory
that sort iot code and byte code
information
the first one is base ait the file
contains
ait internal web representation of some
strings
and currencies rest in in the apk
used to boost up boost to application
startup
the second one is base odx5 the file
contains
aot compile code for method in apk
the rest one is base breedex file this
file contains
redux code of apk with some additional
meta
metadata to speed up the verification
this file can be dumped to desk byte
code and
aot code using the oat dump module
this feature shows the result of dumping
the
base odex file stored in store in the
application directory
if we look at the first line in blue
there is
any function as your first method in in
the class
and the name is uh com applier internal
ac
this inner function exists in two
different form
the part written as a dax code is a
bytecode of
any function
the second part written as code is
compiled code
which was converted from converted from
byte code by
aot compiler and
if we look at the other part you can see
any function
in class com airfryer internal t
uh t dollar one
this function has a dash code
but uh the uh but the chord area just
shows no code it is no compiled code but
it exists only as a byte code
so what does this mean even
even if the function is converted
and saved into the compiled code by aot
compiler
the byte code is saved anyway this
is because the original byte code is
used when the debugging
is required or art is updated to
reoptimize the code in india
if so let's take a look at how byte code
and aot code are loaded into memory
by alt each code is linked to a8 method
object
through the classwinker the a
uart method object is an instantiated
object in the form of c plus plus
class to execute each method within the
java class on art
base odx file contains the oat code and
the
base bidx file contains the byte code
when the app is executed each file is
loaded into memory by runtime
this is a simple simplified picture of
how
oat and byte code are linked to
the ait method object inside the ait
through the class rinker before the
execution
all methods in india are linked to the
execution code
as a art method object
the class wrinkle called the function
set entry point from key compiled code
to assign and assign the address of aut
code
to entry point from key compiled code
variable
of ait method object
and by calling set decline class
function
text cache is assigned to the declaring
class variable
of ait method object now we can call the
byte code through the text cache
in short all function executed by art
are loaded into each
ait method object we can execute
any function through this object
and as we saw earlier as we saw here
there is more than one on one type of
one type of code
we want to execute so we need to call
different
type of code for byte code and compiled
code
as shown in the picture one main
function consists of
several sub function and its sole
function
also consists of several several small
sub functions
let's take a look at the step of core
and
execute the sub function232
main function subfunction2 so function23
so function232 are called in order that
each function exists particularly as a
byte code
and particularly as compiled code
because of that we need to call compiled
code from bytecode
and bytecode from compiled code
this cross code from different code make
a erg structure more complicated
so let's see how ait cross calls the
different code
the first code execution is start from
ait method
this is because the aeit method object
has both byte code and compiled code
if the function exists as a compiled
code
ait message directory invoke the code
and
execute it if the compiled code doesn't
exist
in doesn't exist the interpreter is used
to execute the byte code of function
and after execution of the point typo
function
the compiled code called the interpreter
or vice versa
sometimes the interpreter called the
interpreter again
in this way state change occur
accordingly
within the ait structure
this is a code flow that analyzed the
execution process in art
here compile code called the byte code
and byte code called the compiled code
and byte code also called the byte code
i think it may not be easy to understand
the whole process
at once but if you focus on the code
execution aspect
there are two parts in in horror picture
where code is executed
the first part is compiled code which
called ait quick inbox stop function
through the invoke function in ait
method
this when this function invoke the x
invoke
and execute the compiled code
the second part is byte code which call
xq2m trp inpl or
execute switch impl function through the
interpreter
execution function this function convert
to
bytecode into native code and execute it
all the information required to execute
the app go through the dg2 part
the information contain contains
parameter and return value
the code course tag and so on in other
words
if we watch the ait method inbox and
interpreter execute function
you can trace all code running on
android
is it very possible however
there was one missing piece that we
could not see
uh in flow in in the flow
what is that there's the process
by which compile code called the
compiled code
so why is this corner show shown
in this picture i'd like to go back
and remind you how compiled code is
called
as i explained before ait me so the
inbox call
ait quick inbox soft function to execute
the compiled code by
invoke the code loaded in memory let's
dig into more about
this part
the inbox function of the ait method
class
called the ai to kick inbox stop
function
the ait quick inbox sub function is
written in
arm assembly code to push to boost the
execution
speed this function has
address address of target function to be
invoked and executed
this picture shows the code to get the
address of the function
to be executed this part contain the
address of the variable
and three point from key compiled code
and this variable contain the address of
compiled code
for executing function put this address
into x9
and directly called the compiled code
using branch instruction
let's call this compile code a
then a direct recorded address of next
function b
which is in compiled code again b
directly called address of the next
function c
which also exists on compiled code
unlike
unlike core structure we saw before
you can see the direct call from memory
to memory
when combined code called another
compiled code
if this is if this is the case
it's impossible to trace the code when
compiled code is executed from compiled
code
in addition since compiled code has been
optimized
a lot compared to existing java code
it's tricky to extract the original code
even if
you access the compiled code so
what i did is to change the code
structure
so the byte code always called the
instead compiled code
for for the target function
so i change the ait method inbox
function
to stop executing compiled code
and instead of instead use your
interpreter to execute
bytecode in this method
the ait method inbox function to execute
the compiled code
in the in the exist flow is not called
instead it forced to always provide code
using the
interpreter this allows you to trace the
flow or function because they are
executed using the interpreter
furthermore
you can get original code more easily
because execution code you are getting
in getting is smart code format
for this propose i customize ait
to display all information by adding a
trace
feature to two function ait
method in book and interpreter execute
as shown here no matter whether there is
a compiled code
for the function to be executed in ait
method
it will eventually call byte code
this figure is is a table comparing
the stack trace before and after the
core flow change in ait with the
technique introduced
this in this speaking this
figure is divided into two wizard
the above is a stack trace result before
changing the core structure
and the bottom is the result of stack
trace
after the change before the change
from before the change function that
exists as a
compiled code or called from function
that exists as a compiled code in this
case
it was this chapter introduced a
framework developed with
with the previously described technique
as i shown you earlier
the code has been added to the
customized ait
to give you trace work since the
function
running in ait generated huge data
i need i need a wave filter out
out of data for effective analysis
so i add a configuration file to specify
the information
that i want to to trace from ait
this show the structure of of the
computation file
the first fact is to set the uid
for your analysis you need this you need
to specify the uid of of application you
want to analyze here
second there is an option to output
basic
information of of the function to be
traced
if it is set to y it displays the
information of the target function
such as argument return value and field
so that this is an option to display the
course tag information
of the function to be traced if it is
set to y
it shows you crosstalk information of
the target function
the display code dump option toggle the
output of the code
from the function you trace if you set
it to y
then the smart code is printed for the
target function
lastly there are two options including
an exclude
if we want to track a surface function
put the name here in include then all
function
that contain the string will be
displayed
and if we want to remove the some
unnecessary function
from the output surface file the keyword
in exclude then the matching the
function
er function will not be printed
okay what are please start demo
right is the ubuntu console screen and
the web
is phone mirroring screen the app
uh to be another wise is a centender
used in
argentina first open the configuration
file
on my mobile device uh as explained
in previously chapter here here is a
target wid stack trace option
called dump option and so on
first we get the uid of target app
uid 10 16 8
if you written cha uh hashish
in front of it three times the option
does not work
okay start to app
first we get the uh you can see
all the function executed in art
too many functions are executed you
cannot
you can save it as a rogue and otherwise
the
it later
you can see all functions
executed in art there are
so many functions
uh
second
we will add an option to remove
the deport android function you will
you will only see the custom function
so i
exclude excluded the
android default function and start
it again
the amount of function displayed is much
smaller
than before
and i try to choose you a few of
function that you want to analyze in
detail
first i select com indra function
you only need to insert a partition
string of the function name
to be analyzed
second function ar consontander
function copy and paste
and i search the other function
i find the com flyer function
and copy and paste to
choose your field of function that you
want to analyze in detail
and i try to run the app again
you can only check the execution of the
target function
then i try to set the aig
option to why
now you can see the argument and the
written value
number one and two are fourth and second
parameter
and r is the written value
you can see all the information you can
see
the you can see all
important information really easily
let's take a closer look at the encrypt
function
copy the encrypt function
i target the encrypt function
let's take a closer look at the encrypt
function
then set the code dump option y
set the code down function to
y you can see
small code of target function method
you can see a small code of target
method
in real time
then i try to set the
stack trace option 2y
i started
now you can see stack trace of target
method
in real time
okay walter please finish the demo
please
thank you
in conclusion i developed a new analysis
environment by analyzing
and modifying the modifying the
structure of ait
this method is very easy and effective
and powerful
thank you for listening if you any if
you have any question please contact us
on twitter thank you
you