hello everyone um i guess
congratulations on making it uh to the
uh the closing of the hackathon
hopefully it's been a productive you
know week for you um probably a bit of a
tiring week as well
but uh but if you accomplish some some
good things then that that makes it all
worthwhile and uh
i know this is
this is my favorite part especially when
we're in the um
online and in this virtual format
because
uh you know usually i like to go around
at a different table see what people are
working on kind of learn that as the
hackathon's going on that's a little
more challenging to do in this format
but when we come together for the
closing it's really
really great to see what everyone was
able to do during the course of the week
and some of you i touched face with
in gather and elsewhere but some of you
i haven't really even had a chance to do
that so
really looking forward to to all the
presentations
and let's see we are just about the top
of the hour um
first of all is my audio coming through
okay this is a different computer for me
on a hotel network or on a hotel network
works great
okay great thanks
um
and actually i'm traveling for a
conference and
things are starting to
pick up a little bit looks like there's
a chance our next hackathon will be
in person kind of fingers crossed that
we get good news on that
we'll see how things go
so um
yeah i'm going to go ahead and get
started this is uh being recorded
so um
in case you miss any parts of it but i
figure yeah best to jump in i know it's
it could be a very inconvenient time for
some of you
so we'll uh we'll get going on that
okay
uh just a quick reminder you probably
all know this but this is more for
people who are tuning in perhaps just to
hear these results that a lot of you
accomplished the the whole goal with the
hackathon is really to speed up and
improve the work that we're doing in the
ietf
to to work on
um implementing standards as we're
defining them to get more running code
related to those standards that not only
helps make the standard better but makes
it a lot easier for developers to go and
adopt the standard and implement and add
it add support for it into
whatever it is they're working on
and it's also just a great networking
opportunity too to come together to have
people from from different backgrounds
with different skill sets who all have a
shared um
interest in these standards and but
maybe working on different aspects of it
the implementation of it as opposed to
the definition of it or perhaps a bit of
both
and uh and it's really a great time to
also engage with um what i would say are
often not your are typical
ietf community members people who who
come from maybe from universities from
other sdos from open source
organizations who are aware of and
interested in the ietf but maybe it's
not something they follow on a
day-to-day basis but this is a great
time for them to come in and work really
closely with with people from the ietf
uh we operate under the note well
hopefully you're all familiar with this
but
uh if not you know it's it's really good
to take a a look at this it covers our
processes and and how we work you can
see the uh bcps there at the bottom
uh
you know i think code of contact is we
see a lot of emphasis on this it's
important to look at that
the copyright ip you know disclosures
all that type of thing
good to be aware of what
the rules and what it means to be
participating in the itf so so good to
take a look at that if you haven't
already suggest you do it
asap
um
the agenda as i said we've made it to
the closing um
and after just i'm not gonna spend too
much time going through slides we're
going to spend the bulk of the time
hearing what all of you have
accomplished i have a screenshot there
on the right uh that i took
maybe about an hour ago
and uh don't panic if you've updated it
like if you've added yourself to that
list more recently and you're not in
that slide we're not going to go based
off the slide we're going to go based
off
what's actually currently on that wiki
page or
i was just
messaging with alex in the background he
uploaded all the slides um all the
presentations that have been put in the
um our project repository let me go
forward a bit
uh if you uploaded your your
presentation to this repository those
have been imported into
me techo so we can actually run through
them um from me teca as opposed to you
having to share your screen you can
drive it from me techo
so um
uh barry if you're up for giving that a
try when we get to that point we can try
going through and doing it that way
uh so far it's been working great for me
so i think you may find that an easier
way to go through the presentations as
well
uh but i'm getting ahead of myself a
little bit i also wanted to
share a reminder about the presentations
and hopefully you were all here for the
um the kickoff
and uh these presentations are meant to
be just you know very brief
presentations really uh just covering
what the problem was you were trying to
solve what it was you accomplished and
then just some interesting highlights
about what you learned
things you're going to take back into
your working group and perhaps some
interesting collaboration with
other
sdos or open source organizations or
kind of you know other people outside of
the ietf working group or even if you
collaborated with another ietf working
group that maybe isn't as deeply
involved with um
the standards that you're working on all
that stuff's just uh you know i think
it's very interesting to hear
so now if you can do all that in five
minutes uh that's fantastic and just
this is meant to be a conversation
starter so don't feel like you need to
cover all the nitty-gritty details
really just give us that the high level
that would be fantastic
and we already covered that
and so with that we're going to switch
to
just walking through the presentations
and
[Music]
barry i'm happy to uh
turn it over to you
and uh
we didn't get a chance to discuss this
before barry but uh do you want to just
try driving it from the uploaded
presentations into me techo
yeah
i can i can do that or each person can
write their own using the uh yeah
the slides let's let's try that so um
i'll call you out and
use the
um the share preloaded slides
uh option which is the little piece of
paper with the corner
uh dog ear
click that and we'll allow you to share
the presentation and it will
you know pick your own presentation and
run your own slides if you have trouble
with that let me know and i will run
your slides for you
so why don't we go down in what appears
to be alphabetical order in the wiki
um so and rather in the in the github uh
so we'll start with bmwg
and the next one will be the dns header
people so bmwg
whoever is doing that
requests
requests sharing pre-loaded slides
is there somebody from the bmw group who
wants to talk
you can just unmute yourself and
there we go uh
there you go
okay
can everyone see my screen
your screen go ahead
okay so
i will be doing our projects in his
hackathon 112
is a containerized infrastructure very
much green
so the
main goal of our project is in
continuously hard carton theory is to
figure out control networking
performance in
various crystal oxygen and the result
will be contribute to our draft
consideration for by measuring network
performance in container right
infrastructures the two main features in
this
graph implement in container right
culture with various network models and
verifying performance impacts depending
on configurations testing
now in the hackathon 112 our main
i mean a project is to do the very much
parking lot rate in multiple scenario
with different acceleration technologies
for 2v3 exactly bvp and obs dbdk
and we consider the luma proceduration
for
so to see how it will impact the
performance of cp switch
so inside the head curtain we
the scenario we consider is a multiple
scenario so in our one one one ietr
package so we consider the single signal
boss scenario three only consider the
multiples so basically the traffic
between chinese from the generator to
the toolbox and v-switch and it's about
case mantas cni and use the spacing
hybrid used to create multiple interface
of vnf and we use a layer 2 folding
application at the plugin inside the
port
for the luma alignment we consider
inside
the multiple scenario we have 6 scenario
it can be split into two parts the first
part will be the physique same with the
luma node and the net nfc and the second
be the v6 different window rotate the
nsa
and we denote the cl cf1 in the
port that received the copying package
from t zn
and then change it to the cl2 cl2 will
be the poster chain with the packet back
into the traffic generator
and it's a similar way both to cnf
upgrade in different loop placement
operating shipping incoming packet cnf
and visibly considered
so and we don't consider both choosing
that in different node with 6k but it
will degrade performance but we have
observed in signal plus scenario
this is our configuration for our
testbed and this is a design
basically we have our master node in the
worker node to deploy the port and we
have the traffic signature to
transmit the packet to them
so this is a result that we have
achieved throughout our ideal hackathon
the thing that we learn from this result
is the first thing that in multiple
scenario bpp are performed obs and the
second is the result that we observed
from the luma alignment the first thing
is the
alignment of district and x
and
the element of visual and snake is
almost the same it plays on different
notes when we slightly dig the
performance in a
higher packet size
and the second
observation is cnf and d switch
we also set a separate inplacement of
cnf in significantly degree performance
by 10 to 50 percent and
finally we is a receiving bracket cf1
this week we uh observe
the reverse the reverse result for
obvious dpdk and vpp with oft bdk cmd
and
this week in the same note we have
higher performance meanwhile in vip
cnf and district in different node it
has higher performance
so for the future we
plan to travel through the
cf on basic and numeral alignment
results and we consider multiple vc case
where we will deploy one vision in each
one node and we will plan
to discuss our utility interesting
result with other creative community
so to wrap up our presentation so this
is our team member and we
cooperate with the i2 nsf and fpua team
from the sktu team thank you for
listening
thank you tran
are there any questions for tran
okay hearing none uh thanks again tran
uh good good job um
next one up is the dns editor uh
willamah
yes
uh so i'm i'm going to try this slide
sharing thing
yep
let's see
uh
and the next uh next step will be i2nsf
so get on get ready
yep your slides are up go for it okay
yes so um
yeah so the the dns hackathon was
actually just a single project
which i did with uh
someone else uh tonka park my colleague
and uh so it's not not really denas but
either
and uh
so what's this about
so um
roy irons has a draft which has been
adopted
not so long ago at a
dns working group
which builds upon
extended dns errors extended dns errors
is a mechanism in which
a resolver or authoritative nameserver
can
send back a detailed information about
error that occurs to the
carrier
for example a resolver can send back to
the step resolver or a normal user
that denysec didn't validate because
the signatures expired or
there was a ds record with no signatures
in in the zone or that kind of things
so
the dns air reporting draft builds upon
that
but instead of
informing the clients what went wrong
it informs the authoritative servers
that we're serving the broken songs
about
the error
and uh so it's actually
extended dns error reporting
and therefore i uh so i i know that roy
argens who's on this draft and also met
larson they don't like the funny acronym
either but i i do like it but and
therefore
i called it either
so this was discussed one and a half
week ago
during a dinosaur interview meeting
and there
was what was discussed there the the
mechanism consisted that
or meant that resolver would
send a edns option to the authoritative
saying hey do you have a reporting agent
for me where i can send my errors
and
it was
noted during the interview
the interim meeting that this breaks
some authoritative resolvers
so as a alternative it was suggested
that instead of the resolver requesting
the edns option the authoritative could
also just send the eds option and
solicit it
and it was suggested that resolvers
would be much more resilient to that
than authoritative
towards unknown options
so i proposed that it would be a nice
thing to measure at the upcoming
hackathon
and some people agreed as you can see in
these meeting notes minutes
now two hackathons ago we also
implemented the
reporting agent reporting
in
nsd our authoritative name server but
this time we went a different way
especially because
the authoritative would
send it insulated
unsolicited anyway
we
made a program to do this in a beefy bpf
and if you haven't heard about this yet
it's not
the old berkeley packet filter from
tcpdump but it's you know it's very
exciting and happening
you can run programs in the linux kernel
or very close to the
network card or even on the network card
hardware
and
what i like about it too
we have been playing it with with bpf
and
at in our matlabs
is that you can
augment existing uh name server
installations
so
we made something which is named server
agnostic but you don't have to
anticipate it beforehand if you have
this name server and you want to have
this feature added that it can report
its reporting agents then you just load
this bpf program and it will work but if
i work with bind with not with nsd
doesn't matter
so that's it's pretty cool
here's the
git repository
there's all all sorts of dns experiments
in there
[Music]
and here you see example uh so i i have
this server either dot
lobs dot nl and it's running the either
domain
and
i have not anticipated the dness
error reporting yet
but to do to enable it i just have to do
this clone the repository
initialize the submodule go to the
directory with the option
make load and i'm done
and you can see here
the result
from a dick query that it is indeed
reporting the reported agent in an edns
option
report.netnetlabs.now
and here is a little piece of the
c code of the bpf program
you can see how to configure it with the
reporting agent and what option code to
use
so i think that's really cool and
we also did ripe atlas measurements to
see if
resources would break if they get this
option unsolicited
so
i also created a server with the domain
that does not send this option which is
called meter dot internet labs orton l
and here's the vipe outlast measurement
that
targets this server and then also the
the server rich
doesn't option
i did a very simple measurement so ripe
atlas has 11 000 props currently i think
but
for the hackathon now i did it with just
a thousand uh doing it with all of our
losses a little bit
more work
but it was good to have this experiment
anyway i think so
probes anticipated
the program that processes the results
is there in a link to and what we
learned
was
that 99 of the resolvers don't have an
issue with this
option
and
that
the remaining 1 is also
a little bit unclear
because actually
we had more
answers on
the domain that did send option than on
the domain which did not send option
which was the baseline measurement so
but i think so from initial guess that
support is okay
but of course you know there needs to be
we need to be
do
like
large-scale measurements to to be sure
and
be certain that this can be done
for dns or reporting without causing
problems
another thing uh what we
learned and more that's more discussed
is that this is like dmarc right it
gives operators of
authority of domains dns operators
serving authority domains
authoritatively
confidence to deploy dnsec because they
get feedback from what is happening on
the internet if something breaks etc
so it might be interesting to develop a
new
draft at the rtf
and
which would do
driver and dns right that you can try
the nsx but
if validation breaks the answer will go
to the clients anyway but our error will
be reported to a error reporting agent
so that might be some interesting future
work
and
that's it we just worked with the two of
us on this
because you know everybody is busy and
it's it works better on in a live
meeting but that was nice to do anyway
and i think that maybe we present this a
bit more elaborately at dinosaur next
week
so that's it if anyone has any questions
then i'd be happy to answer them
thanks
welcome
yeah i mean um yeah thanks for the
presentation i found uh
i mean the the potential of helping with
the kind of dns sac deployment problem
is as i understand it is i mean it
sounds really
uh interesting and an encouraging thing
to to try out um
also i was uh
it was interesting to hear you bring up
uh
you were talking about ebpf too right at
the beginning yeah
that's prevalent i think in the
networking space edpf gets uh used a bit
and now i'm hearing it used a lot for
dealing with security
um things that just i don't know it's it
seems like a really neat uh kind of
toolkit no way to to be able to use so
uh interesting to see you using it the
way you did um
it makes me think i need to look into
ebpf a bit more because it seems pretty
pretty powerful pretty flexible
yeah absolutely yeah
yeah we sort of made a toolkit so
this this uses parts of that toolkit to
to implement this
this option
and it's cool yeah
because you know it's also a feat a
feature can be implemented independent
of what you're winning
and it's very fast very suitable for
dealing with uh you know of service
attacks and those kind of things
cool thanks thanks for sharing
thank you
other questions or comments
okay okay thanks again willem and next
up is uh i2nsf followed by ipwave both
of them are paul and your screen request
is approved go for it
hello uh
can you hear me
yes
okay
so hello uh this is uh
john
this is i2 nsf
hackathon project report
so this is a poster for this project
basically uh this hackathon project case
we we don't have your
hunger slides up yet
okay can you see my slide
no
oh no it says my screenshot has been
started but uh oh okay okay okay
okay
there you go
okay good
okay
uh my name is tim perjung this is i2 nsf
hackathon project report
but this is a poster
for itunes f
project
basically this hackathon we want to
implement
distributed network auditing system for
itunes f framework using hyperledger
fabric as a distributed
network auditing system
so
um as you can see this is i2 nsf
framework so i turn as a user giving the
fallacy and then secure controller
translate into level policy
for
the nsf security enforcement
this hackathon project case
item accept the analyzer collects
the monitoring data from
nsf using a monitoring interface
and then that monitoring data
are stored into
hyperledger fabric as a distributed
database
after that secure controller has a
web server and it display the monitoring
data into web
so
this hackathon project we use the
distributed database
based on
the hyperlaser uh fabric so you can see
itunes of analyzer collect mounting data
from nsf amb and then using nested a5
that information will be delivered to
hyperledger
the organization node this is
this should distribute to the database
node and and then
using order and confirm that um
stories and then
the data information delivered to
control law okay and then it can display
that motion data into web
so this is at the push of nsf modding
data
to distribute the data
based using rest api basically i2 nsf
delivered this data
into hyperledger
after that
this
distributed database receives that nsf
modding data
from
i2 and sf analyzer so you can see this
is a json format
so
um
right hand side
so we display
the monitoring data okay so
this is
the system resources such as memory disk
okay something like that and then right
hand side is the network uh traffic so
this
incoming traffic is over that
some threshold means ddos attack okay so
let's take time we use the centralized
database
with the mysql this time we replaced
mysql with the hyperledger as the
distributed database
so what we learn
the
usage of distributed database can tackle
the possibility of data templing
such as a
sprite supply chain attack
and also
the distributed database system
[Music]
also denies the failure of single point
because we are using
distributed
databases like the blockchain overall
the distributed database system can
improve the security and reliability of
our itunes framework
so next step
this time we just stored the i2 nsf nsf
multi-data
but
next time we try to
store more data and
information such as
security policy and nsf capabilities
this is open
source project at github you can get the
source code from this link
so this is one on two source code and
also we
have the demonstration video clip you
can click and you can see our
demonstration
so
this is the member information
we work
for hackathon with the
sunshield university bmwg working group
and ipo web team this is my team members
so also
this time you also work for a hackathon
project so
korean
uh
gathered in the busan
west in joseon hotel in busan we work
for
hakkason bmwg
um i2rsf and ipwave team so this is the
sponsor information
so appendix
explains how to install
opelate our distributed database system
for itunes app
thank you for your
listening questions or comments
thank you paul
questions for paul on i2nsf before he
starts ipwave
okay
okay let's start if you wave
so can i start if your wave report
a very can okay please do it okay
yes but it takes a minute to unmute so
it got cut off okay sorry
okay
may i start ip wave
report
you can see my slides right
okay
okay uh this is the ipo wave hackathon
project report
so this is the
hackathon project poster basically this
time we implemented the
ip wave context over navigation protocol
is called the cmp so robot car
and the web server can communicate with
each other so
we using ipweb cmp
beaker
information
option type
is delivered
over
a world wide web double 3c
pi ss
feeker information
service specification we used
we deliver
information using that
standardization format
also we demonstrated the
text last time we used
a wave
such as a tsrc
so european folks they are
popularly using um
simply takes a cellular feature to
everything so
so in this case we use the simulation
based
information was done
so
i said this ipwave hackathon case we
had two parts first one is the
simulation second one is
robot car based implementation
so
what got done
so we demonstrated
our ip wave context of a navigation
protocol message can be delivered
over cb2x using simulation
also we implemented the ip wave draft
and
w3c standard
it is called the pis s vehicle
information service specification
deliver figure
signal or sensing information to
web server
so the first part
simulation case we use the sumo for
vehicle mobility simulation
and the lower part is
the omf plus with the cv2x module
to simulate
the
car
uh communication based on uh
cbtx okay
so this figure shows our information
implementation of omni plus plus so we
implement the peaker structure
to support the cv2x
also on this is ipv6 stack especially um
the icm 5006
is for context
over navigation protocol okay so we used
this stack
so last time uh we used
elto.11
waiver okay so at the eleven ocb
uh stack so we used on this kind of
mustache
this time uh we demonstrated the the
feasibility of cb tracks
the cbu text is a standard
for cpp so
in future i believe
ipwave can take advantage of
wave stack and
see if we to access stack for vehicular
communication
so this is a remote server and the
vehicle so
using
ip wave
vehicle mobility information message can
be delivered over
w3c standard
such as a free iss figure information
service specification also a general
pre-access figure signal
specification
deliver vehicle sensor or other
signal information can be delivered over
viss format
so this is also
open source project so you can uh get
the first link is
our simulation
for
sibu text the second one is
a local car based
implementation card
so um you can click and then uh this
a
ai on r1
robotics load car can deliver its
sensing information or figure speed
information
using wi-fi
to a web server
a second part
demonstration
this link uh demonstrate the civil text
based context aware navigation protocol
okay
exchange
so we work for
a whole week uh with the sunshine
university vm wg and i2 nsf team
work together
so this is a team member information
so my ph student the pnma and my
the master student chun hee
maekwon
so this is our um korean
um hackathon teams members
so this is a sponsor also we have
appendix for cbu access examination and
also we have
index for our local car implementation
and manipulation for
people
having uh
interesting for our ip wave project
thank you for your attention and
interest
any questions or comments
thank you paul um anybody thank you
yeah um hi paul hey yeah thanks for uh
great presentations uh you always bring
great projects to the hackathon so
appreciate that
um
the cd cd2x um that was a new one to me
which uh
which standards organization uh defines
that
cebu text is 30 cpp
the third party yeah partners right for
5g
you know lt right so recently the 3gpp
uh
also working for 6g but basically
uh korea case we deployed 5g i believe
the united states also solving the 5g
service right for a cell phone right
mobile smartphone
so the vehicle case also the vehicle to
everything
case cputex model 4
case
provide the uh adult fashion
communication which means the vehicle
can communicate with without
the base station okay
so
in that case uh we can
provide the communication
among beakers to avoid the accident also
some detect some obstacles or headers
you can notify
every vehicles of that hazard so civil
text will be
the use per so european country case
carbenders
the
adopted
civil tracks for um vehicular
communication
still the united states case the dsrc
wave case
they consider but i think uh two
technology will be uh co-exist in future
so that's why
if you wave working group
needed to consider cv text for mac and
the file yeah protocol for hyperwave
navigation or other yeah application
yeah
communication technologies okay
okay yeah well thanks
okay thank you charles
what else questions
if not uh thanks again paul and yes
thank you
being a regular hackathon participant
and always bringing your students with
you that's great thank you okay thank
you
and oliver you're next with uh
the aspa um
okay can you hear me
we can
wonderful okay so
uh that was our first
active hackathon what we did i
participated some before as
listening in but
this time we said
uh that we wanted to make one on our own
um
so the the work what we what we did is
and i just go right away in here so the
the
we've worked since a long time in bgp
uh security and
uh we've worked on bgp seg path
validation
uh the bgb orange validation
and for that we created um reference
implementation
reference implementations and
a large software suite what
we know employ also for another uh work
at the sider ops working group uh the
aspa autonomous system provider uh
authorization and the goal of that is
of this hackathon what we started this
time is
to lay the groundworks for future
interoperability tests between different
implementations
and to create
large-scale
um
tests that then can be used to verify
the different
validations performance etc etc etc
um a very quick
explanation how the system in general
works
so
isps or
operators of autonomous system routers
basically register their data in the
rpki database
and
that then will be queried
relatively often by validation caches
that go out
download the x519 certificates etc and
then create something
we can call it maybe a white list
it's
the aspa information that describes the
customer provider relationships and
sends these ones then to the router or a
validation engine
that the router employs
and our interest for this iatf for this
hackathon was
the communication between the validation
cache and the router
so
um
the tools what we used was basically our
list bgp srx software suite
um where we have the aspa verification
implemented actually we
have and
currently the draft is version 8 but
there is an algorithm correction already
that was introduced some iatfs back
that will soon be added to this uh
standards draft and we have the
implementation for that
the other thing is the
[Music]
rfc 8210 is extended
uh to now also carry aspa objects and we
made the reference implementation for
this
um
so we wanted to use our test harness to
basically
um
yeah
run larger scale tests
um so what what was our task for this
hackathon we said okay we want to go out
we
take
sample internet scale asp data and we
use the kata reference data
to specify
they have very good algorithms to
specify the link relations between two
asses
and then we take that and we create the
input file format
for our software what basically
looks the following way you say you have
the aspa you give the f
e that could be uh
b4 b6
then the custom is and a list of
providers for these iss
and um what we then also did we went out
to route views and got some
um
egp updates
maybe follow another goal like so what
what did we do so we went out to the
cater and uh we got data actually i
think it's the data from october
1st 2020 because currently cada
is re revamping their algorithms and do
not provide the latest uh internet data
but for us it was perfectly fine because
we just said we wanted to have something
that
if we use already the internet traffic
we wanted to have data that is
[Music]
compiled out of the
internet topology
we this data produced around 70 000
customer
registration for us and that has over
180 000 link relationships
um
then
we what we did was we wanted to down
select that
and we did that where we said okay if i
don't for example i take a 100
routes a thousand routes 10 000 routes
so what we did we created we created
tools that go out and
create
a unique as path we were not interested
in the prefix because aspa does not look
into the prefix
it tries to identify
route leak space basically so if there's
a route leak um
for one prefix and most likely it's also
for other ones
the the validation here
is basically on on the path itself
um so what we did was we
down selected out of around i think it's
currently around 800 000 prefixes um
uh if depending how you how you run the
b2b dump on the mrt files you get up to
also 800 000 updates
we
down selected that to around 100 000
unique ones and then from there we we
said okay if you if you create a
thousand we only want to have the cata
data
that contains all asses within these uh
this is within the update data stream so
um
because the other ones they just would
lie in the system
dormant
so we created data sets for 100 500 800
1 000 10 020 000
unique as path
and
um
then we performed the aspa validation
very quick explanation on the validation
what it is so if i have a valid then i
didn't um identify your outlet if i have
an invalid then i detected a route leak
if the uh outcome is unknown then i
don't have enough asba information to
make any determination either way
and if an ai set is in the bgp path then
it's unverifiable
um that is one of the results what i
just compiled yesterday night where we
got everything up and running with all
the scripts
and it's to be taken with a little bit
of grain of salt because um
it's a relatively small data set i think
it was around 500 routes
and depending uh it becomes much more
interesting i guess if we go on a higher
one but one interesting thing to see for
example is already that
we
selected a large scale isp and we just
said okay if this isp is my provider
uh how many how many uh prefixes or how
many updates i received from them how
many paths are valid and that is 94 and
how many are invalid that basically
means result into route leaks
three percent and uh another three
percent i could not make a determination
now if i turn that around and say that
now my isp is my customer then of course
i
uh i don't expect 94 percent of valets
and that's what we definitely can verify
here so we have 14 of wallets
we have uh we identify 18 of route leaks
and 68
the data is not there to to make any
distinction in either way
um we didn't had time yet to really dig
deep into the analysis of that whole
thing
um that is something that has to be done
now going forward but
uh for this week we basically wanted to
create the
the infrastructure that one can start
working on that
and so what is the
to be what needs to be done um
currently our experimentation runs with
one implementation on the test with
against one pier it starts becoming
interesting running this against
multiple peers especially when we go
into the performance
testing and
hopefully we will see other
implementations coming
between today and the next hackathon so
then it might be interesting to compare
validations with other implementations
other than ours
to make sure that the validation results
are all
all the same
etc
further further
analysis will be of interest is gradual
deployment because what we did here
right now we had an almost hundred
percent deployment of aspa and if you
roll out a new technology that is not
what happens
um so the interest uh
there is to see
at one at what deployment rate start
aspa becoming really
um
making a
positive impact on detecting route leaks
the
software code of the bgp srx suite is on
github
if you go on github and you just search
for bgp srx
then you will find right away the
uh the software suite the code what we
developed for this hackathon i still
want to clean it up a little bit before
we put it up on github
um but it will be made available as well
and
i didn't make a final decision yet if
you put it on the on the ietf
hackathon github part or if we also run
it in the examples of ours
uh but depending what we will do uh we
will have it at least linked from uh
from the nist github uh part so that you
can find the code the
the scripts and and and so forth
um
yeah that's all what i have for today if
there are any questions
please feel free
to ask
and thanks oliver
questions for oliver
okay hearing nothing thanks again oliver
appreciate the presentation
and the next one up is the ansible api
generator
and the one after that will be whip so
get ready
yeah can you hear me
i can
okay
just waiting for your screen
and we see your screen
got it okay
okay okay thanks
so hello everyone this is tufang from
huawei
and i'm here to give a very brief
introduction of our project
the customized enable api generator
so
the motivation of this work is that we
really appreciate the
simple and efficient network automation
solution provided by ansible to manage
network devices
and we also know that the netcaf young
provides a standardized programming
interface
although the young schema is indeed a
standard
how the data itself is represented may
vary depending on the vendors
however not all vendors provide enviable
api to manage your device through
netconf and when the native vr modules
even though there are some integrated
solutions between edible and different
vendors the generalized enable apis
cannot meet customized requirements
so we really hope that there exists a
tool to generate any desired anabolic
apis so that they can be used directly
to communicate with network devices
through netconfion and these apis can be
used to greatly reduce the workload of
developers and allow them to focus on
their own business
the following gives some of our
specifications the related drafts which
which may be used in this
project so
what got done the our achievement is the
antibody and automatic and the api
generation tool
the generated enable apis could be
integrated into enable framework
automatically and also supports
customized input parameter check or
functionality
and by making use of enable gene we have
already
successfully delivered l3 with vpn
service to have a device through enable
plan book
so the following diagram gives an
architecture of animal gene and the
entire processing flow the user inputs
are related young modules and their
customized api description xml files
these customized api profiles are used
to describe your desired ansible apis
which will be called when delivering
netcup message
to the targeted nodes it's very similar
to netcover message but without values
carried
it could be an edit config get or get
config or rpc operation defined in your
modules
the young passer and xml passer will
check and pass the young modules and xml
description files respectively the
results as the input of adapter which is
responsible for generating the internal
object of animal gene and then
identified by the antibond module great
generator which will generate the angle
apis finally
the generated apis will be deployed in
anger environment automatically which
works as an edible module
when we issue a net conf
request through plan book the related
apis will be called and complete the
configuration management task
so
during this hacksaw week we learned that
the documentation is important for
involving others is even as important as
code we can't expect everyone to know
how to use it just by reading the code
and the second lesson the second lesson
we learned is to test early and often so
we can have more opportunities to catch
backs and more time to fix them
and also i would like to
thanks to panglio tanglio
viva and benson for visiting our project
and providing a very valuable
suggestions and great input
regarding the next step we would like to
support the latest version of and the
ball and we would also want to explore
this to define our enterprise profiles
more efficiently
and besides me
there are frank ching bin wai and xiang
thank you guys for your efforts and the
related outcomes of this project are
giving here the open source code and
a video demo
please feel free to read the video to
them so that you can get more detailed
information about this project
and
uh further contributions are welcome
yeah so this is the end of my
presentation thank you very much
thank you
and are there are there any questions or
comments for chuffon
okay hearing none
thanks again thanks for the presentation
and for the work of that
lorenzo you are up with uh whip
[Applause]
and lorenzo has the magic so i don't
approve his uh sharing
oh yeah sorry i didn't i didn't realize
that apologies
i don't care go for it
okay so this will be a brief report on
the interoperability tests on on weep
and just to
just to summarize producers that are
unfamiliar with it we
comes from a a recently formed working
group called wish which stands for
webrtc ingest signaling over https and
whip is the name of the protocol that is
being standardized there and it recently
went to version zero one which was
actually the
uh the
the main uh the main version that we
tried to
to test in these
in this interoperability test and we
basically wanted to cover two specific
aspects so first of all we wanted to
make sure that
we client and servers could actually
talk to each other using the web
signaling protocol itself but we also
wanted to take advantage of this chance
to also test
the webrtc exchanges beneath mostly
because most of the endpoints that i'll
talk about are not based on libor rtc
which means that they do not share the
same
library that browsers use and so it was
a
very unique chance to test heterogeneous
webrtc stacks instead which can be a bit
more problematic at times
and we actually did a few uh first
interrupt rounds among a limited set of
implementations a few weeks ago that i
documented in a blog post that you can
read there if you want and at the time
we had three clients and three servers
interacting with each other and
basically the results that we got from
that test that eventually were
successful basically helped us identify
a full set of key issues in the zero
zero the version of the of the documents
and basically zero one uh
most of the issues that were addressed
in zero one actually came out of that
interrupt round which was quite helpful
and this time around we wanted to test
more implementations instead and so we
ended up testing four different service
implementations including one that i
wrote myself one that julius wrote galen
sergio wrote
the integration in the medical
standpoint and cameron integrated this
into his own sfu called the cfu and for
clients we had six different clients
instead that we could test and both
servers and clients basically almost all
of them used different webrtc stacks
which is why it was quite interesting to
see how they fared with each other
and the end result was in a nutshell
these so
it was mostly successful and actually
more successful than the picture there
suggests
basically just to give you a quick
understanding a green smiley means that
everything worked fine out of the box a
yellow yellow smiley means that we had
to tweak something in other client of
server to get something working
red meant that nothing worked and so
further investigation is needed and no
arrangements that we couldn't test due
to something that was actually unrelated
to whip itself so like course issues or
stuff like this
and i try to summarize most of these
reports uh
the different results in these slides i
will i will not go very much in detail
in all of these uh
wrappers because they might take more
than the five minutes that i have but
just to give you an idea for instance uh
my client died when you try to talk to
this to the deadliest a few web server
because it made some assumptions and so
actually some assumptions that were made
out of the documents were because of
some of the problems that we experienced
in this case my client assumed that the
location header was always available and
detect field didn't provide it and so
basically that ended up in the crash
that i eventually fixed and so and and
there were a few similar issues as well
i should clarify that in this slide i
meant
i i put weepy which is the uh
the raspberry pi based client that team
wrote uh that basically didn't succeed
with neither galen and the decipher and
this was true up until a few hours ago
and the cause was basically
a nice interrupt issue between
the team's stack and the pi on stack
which is go based and eventually team
managed to find out what the issue was
which was actually more related to the
fire to fire release rather than ice
itself and he also had to address
again an assumption that the pion stack
made with respect to the usage of mid in
webrtc which again was uh an interesting
uh side effect of this test that's uh
that helped helped us identify a webrtc
related issues rather than a weak issue
and then there were some other issues
related again
to
either to assumptions or hard-coded
assumptions because for instance some
clients couldn't talk to some service
just because each of them were
hard-coded to use one codec rather than
another and so in this case this isn't
really a failure in how to how they use
whip but mostly a failure in actually
ended up into a successful negotiation
between the two maybe because the client
only offers bpa decline the server only
accepts h264 and so you end up with a
session that will not work basically
and
apart from this it was mostly issues for
instance related to self-signed
certificates not being accepted which
made it a bit harder to do tests locally
these sort of things
and a few other assumptions like course
issues or missing support for better
tokens which is something that we
actually want to look into sooner or
later and really to summarize what we
wanted to really focus on in this first
uh
first this first round was basically
really focusing on the basics so trying
to get the webrtc stream to be published
using with possibly tweaking trickling
candidates and checking whether or not i
know your video stream is actually
consumable on the other end so we didn't
want to really push it beyond that
mostly because this was the first time
we all met together in order to to try
and do a larger test among among each
other and what we really want to test
next is actually going a bit further
than that so for instance making sure
that the authentication using tokens
actually works as specified in the
documentation how to properly use the
location and link headers to uh to
address whip resources and automatically
configure stun and turn and this would
actually be useful to do in environments
that are actually more limited in terms
of actually setting up a peer connection
than the more open setups that we had
right now addressing also ice restarts
and related risk conditions which is
something that we are actually
discussing right now in the working
group and it's something that we haven't
had the time to actually look into
as as far as the different
implementations are concerned plus some
issues related to sessions cleanup which
is which isn't always done properly by
your clients and service which means
that you can end up sometimes with door
front sessions and things like this so
it's definitely something else that we
need to to address in in future
interrupt tests
and to conclude this is the uh the
interrupt testing team that worked uh
that was together in these past few days
so sergio is actually the whip champion
uh for this for this hackathon uh then
there was me there was tim panton then
jenkins cameron elliott and alberto
gonzalez stoic as well
i don't know if
there is any question for me
thank you
thanks lorenzo questions or comments for
lorenzo
so yeah thanks for the presentation i
have a question for you which uh which
video conferencing tool did you use for
your team to uh collaborate
well actually yeah that's uh the funny
thing is that um webrtc developers tend
to tend to communicate in real time as
as as as low as the community the
real-time communications tend to be as
low as possible so we try to use mostly
synchronous communications like
we we might engage on matrix or twitter
or any kind of messaging platform so it
was mostly this kind of interactions
rather than having a conversation like
we're having right now we tend to be
quite lazy and just
just chat instead of talking to each
other
okay and just one other thought it'd be
interesting on your your slide some of
the problems you identified you uh
you've already fixed so to have a i mean
i'd put like an extra big smiley face on
those the ones that uh
yeah that's true yeah yeah
i had some problems trying to actually
frame this one because the yellow ones
should actually be
a bigger smile because it's an issue we
fixed rather than something that we had
to fix and so it was a bit more of a
frowny face so it may be more of a
messaging
uh
a pure communication on my side so i'll
definitely fix this next time thanks for
the feedback
thanks a good great project and and
thanks for sharing
thank you
other comments for lorenzo
okay thanks again lorenzo and steven
you're up next with uh augmented packet
header
diagrams
it can use
you know
yes
we can see the slides we can hear you
excellent so hi everyone i'm stephen
mccusin from the university of glasgow
and i just want to
briefly talk about the work that we did
this week on the machine readable
documents and their tools project that
we proposed alongside mark petty hugging
so this is a fairly broad project and
it's it's really an umbrella for a
variety of projects that are trying to
use tooling to automate different
aspects of the draft authorship and
standards publication processes
and of the sort of subsequent processing
of these documents
so just give an idea of what we're
talking about this includes tools that
are used to
generate standards documents or drafts
in rfcs so that's things like computer
specifying that mark will talk about
next
it also includes formal and sort of
semi-structured languages like abnf and
yang the augmented packet header
diagrams work that i'll talk about
and the the quick packet notation that
some of you might be familiar with
on the other side we are also
considering tooling that derives meaning
from draft so that might be using
natural language processing run over
drafts and documents or it might be
parsers for these structured languages
here
and in terms of what we want to do with
the documents we're thinking about
things like automatic parser code
generation so generating parser code for
the protocols that the documents
describe automatically from the
documents themselves or producing
mathematical proofs that demonstrate
that the document describes a protocol
or something that is
provably correct
as i say this is quite broad and we're
really
trying to be as inclusive as possible
for all of these techniques and tools
and languages
but this week we worked on two main
projects as i say mark's going to
discuss his work on computer specifying
but i'll just briefly update you on our
work with augmented packet header
diagrams format
so just to briefly introduce this format
we found that most documents that are
specifying protocols do so with a sort
of broadly similar format so you can see
in the right hand side here you know we
have this ascii packet header diagram
and then below that we've got this
description list of each field
describing the length of the field and
its contents
so what we've done with our work is
we've sort of regularized this format so
that we can parse it out of the
documents that use it and then generate
parser code for the protocol that that
document is specifying
and what we've done is we've done this
with really minimal change to the format
as it's typically used today and the
idea here is that we want to limit how
much effort document authors have to put
in to changing their documents and the
way they write their documents to be
able to support our format
and this really balances the sort of
structure and uniformity that we need to
be able to pass these descriptions out
of the documents with the flexibility
that you actually need in the real world
practical use of these documents
and we've got prototype tooling that
supports this input format so you run
our tooling over
a draft and it will produce a parser
code for any protocols that are being
specified using our format and it
produces code in rust that will then let
you parse out packets in that protocol
we're seeing some adoption of the format
so the tcp bis draft that's going
through tcpm uses it
and so in essence you can take that
draft run our tooling over it and
automatically generate a tcp parser
of course there's a lot more information
about all of this we've got a draft that
specifies the sort of rationale behind
what we're trying to do with the format
and that describes the format itself the
draft also has pointers to the github
repositories with uh all of our
prototype tooling in it
and any contributions and any comments
on it is are more than welcome
so in terms of what we did this week we
had lots of very good very useful
discussions about the particular
language that we use in our format so
our format uses sort of structured
english phrases um to indicate where we
start a definition
we had lots of discussions about how
these phrases could be improved so that
they're actually better for you know
humans to read rather than thinking too
much about machine readability
beyond that we also considered what we
might be able to do to mark out the
structured text components of our format
so that you know when we pass drafts to
the rc editor for publication that
they're not actually edited out and no
longer become parsable by our tool
and finally in terms of our prototype
code we started working upon
adding flexibility so adding more
languages that we can produce um parsers
in and adding robustness so we want our
tooling to be able to to run over every
draft even if it doesn't include our
format um and we've really started
working on adding that robustness and uh
in terms of what we do next that's
that's the sort of two strands that
we're going to pick up on as we move
forward with it
um so
all in all it was quite a productive
week a lot of good discussions with
people that that haven't been uh engaged
with the work previously um so it's been
really good to see some new people and
thank you to everyone that came along to
the project table and discussed their
work with us
really appreciate it
and i'll take any questions anyone has
yeah um uh great presentation one
question uh if i wanted to try this out
on a draft that i have or
even an rfc or
um i guess probably on a draft right
because i'll probably have to change
some things or yeah but uh anyways where
where can i go to get uh kind of a
prototype version of this the the best
bet is to uh to find this draft um on
the data tracker and we've got links to
the the github repository at the bottom
of the draft and so all the tooling is
available it's the tooling itself is
written in python
um the instructions should be hopefully
reasonably clear but if there's anything
at all that comes up as you try to use
it then happy to take any any feedback
or any comments
great thanks steve
cheers
else any questions comments
okay thanks steven and mark europe
can we see the slides
hello
yep
we can hear you okay
go for it okay
why are my slide
truncated on the left
right
okay all right
okay
uh hi so
my name is mark pettigoner
as stephen said uh participated in the
project on umbrella which is about uh
machine readable uh specifications
so this will be i will start with a
quick introduction of what computer
specifying is because i think that there
is less than five people on the planet
who knows what i'm talking about
so
uh he started a long time ago and the
goal of this project is to ensure that
example in rfc are correct because
sometimes they are not and because
programmers generally look at example
when they write their code and not add
normative text then we get
implementations that are not
interpretable
so
basically a computer specification is a
document which is written in the format
which is called ascii doc
which is a which is
not a markdown but looks like one and
the big advantage of this format is that
it's extensible without having to modify
the code
as a xml2fc
hondura is in fact provided by the
metanormal project that some of you may
may know so i wrote an extension well
extensions
to
ask askidok that permits to add code
inside a document in the same document
that will be your internet draft or your
lfc you can add code
and the most important thing is that you
can evaluate some of this code
and put the result of this evaluation in
the document itself at the same time
it's generated so
here an example of that which is taken
for uh
like
something
so the idea is that on top the block on
top is a computer right specification
right you have code which you can
recognize because there is a
greater than which is called a bird mark
on the left so this is code and then
underneath this you have text
where you have this um code macro code
column and uh
and the code in
between bracket which will be
evaluated and the result
the result inserted into the generator
text so in the middle you have the
command which is used to to do that and
there is one command that does
everything and it generates
xml to lfc text html and pdf format for
this document and on the bottom you have
the result what will appear in in the
actual document and you can see that the
macro is replaced by the values that are
in fact calculated instead of being
filled
manually by the author of the hrc
the problem of that is that in my
opinion this is not enough right
programmers are still programmer and
some their main output is are still it
still bugs
so i i needed something better than this
i can guarantee that the example are
correct right so there is two way of
doing that you can have verification
tools that verify that the example are
correct
or you can go the less easy way which is
to generate examples that are already
correct by construction right so you
still can verify them but if you forget
to verify them they are still going
the problem is to do that is that you
cannot use any programming language
right all programming language are
equivalent to each other except for
their type system and in this case we
need a type system that can encode
higher order
logic right which there is probably free
programming language that can do this
and the one that shows this it
too
which was designed at the university of
saint andrews in scotland
so
i am done with the computer
specification now what i am working on
is to provide some library in idris
to provide to solve common problems that
internet drafts also
would have why and i'm working on a lot
of this stuff with one of the simpler
and most accessible to everyone is a b
and f right a lot of
internet
of
rfcs contain
abnf so you can see on the bottom an
example of in this case how this library
module works right so i design uh the
domain specific language a dsl that can
be used to define a b and f grammar
right so here i defined alpha
which is probably the most well-known
rule for abnf and then
here
on the top i insert
the the serialization if you want of
this and the result of the serialization
is what you have underneath so
not only it print
a correct
syntactically correct
string but it also format it right it it
does pretty print printing so if there
is not enough size in the line it it
will wrap up the line and and do the
white thing according to analysis
52 34
but
this is not enough to generate an
example remember my goal is still to
generate an example
which is correct so
my first idea was to generate example
from an ibnf but this is a terrible idea
and the reason for that is that an abnf
cannot describe all the constraints that
you have in the pdu it is supposed to
describe right and i found a really nice
example nice because it's shorter it's
uh some symbolic expression that
everyone who wrote
lisp code uh should uh have seen right
and this is a very simply of a version
of
which sx
used by basically from machine to
machine
transfer right here if you look at the
second
rule token you can see that there is a
number a column and then a number of
octa
octet the problem is that the number of
octet is it should be in fact the value
of the number before right so there is
five column you should have five update
after this you cannot encode that that
in
a b and f at all right so this is why
this is a bad idea to
to to base an example on its a b and f
now what we want is to be sure that an
example with generate is also correct
according to the
ibbnf so the right way to do that
is to generate a type for a
symbolic
expression and eventually a dsl that
make it easier to do so sx are easy are
simple so the the code fits inside the
the slides the slide right
but how to be sure that the printable
value of that type
which is an example is correct according
to the ib that's that that was what i
worked during this this week at the
academy
so the solution was was quite simple uh
now that i know what it is one so the
idea
is to
to to build a proof that this string is
correct right and this is why we need
things like idris and that are not we
need to add to use a programming
language like idris because this is the
only one that can
build a chip a type which is actually a
proof right so here we are saying that
we can build an instance of valid of the
type valid only is the string that we
pass and the grammar that we pass are
correct once if the string is correct
according to the
grammar
and so i designed it in a way that you
can directly
insert a value of this type and it will
display the validated string
so the last thing
that one need to do is to write a
conversion between the type which is a
perfect thing
and this right and this is the the the
the thing that you see
uh at the bottom it shows the type of
usually the implementation is missing
and will not fit
but the idea is that we transform an
instance of something of type a
symbolic expression into a list and into
a proof that this list is valid for the
grammar
sx which is on the on the right with a
small s right and then it's simple you
just have to insert the result of all of
that in your text right so
this is how it's done uh you have of our
function example we use a dsl to to to
define
our
symbolic expression and it's
automatically verified
and it generates the text that you see
on the bottom which cannot be an invalid
symbolic expression this is impossible
unless you tweak your compiler
so
this is all i have this is uh thanks to
a a lot of this discussion this week
with stephen colleen and robert and gene
and luke lucas
you can find the all the documentation
and all the links are in the
spec which is an internet draft
even access to the tooling um
there is a link inside to find it which
can be retrieved by with
toronto uh i am
we will be releasing the version 15 this
weekend that will contain these new
things and that's all i have
thanks mark uh yeah i'm really excited
about both the stuff that steven was
talking about and and this stuff
automating
automating this stuff will help us a lot
any anybody have questions or comments
for mark
okay hearing nothing thanks again mark
appreciate the presentation
and with that
we've gone through all the presentations
that i think are uploaded does anybody
have a presentation that they think i
missed
um hey robert uh this is honest um
i thought that i uploaded mine but i i
may be just wrong
and and i failed to upload
well if you want to just present it from
your screen go ahead and request screen
sharing and and yeah
perfect i will do that
okay
give me a second i'm trying to find
can you guys see my screen doesn't work
yes
okay
perfect
okay so um
we worked on on a a little bit broad
topic in some sense on iod security
and um what that meant for us was we
wanted to implement specifications uh
developed in
these different iot security working
groups and we had
been doing hackathons on those topics um
already for a while so we have a
pretty good code base i would say uh but
needless um
to mention that there's obviously a lot
of continuous development in those
groups and on some of the specifications
are not finalized and we try to
integrate integrate them to each other
like the core groups the core group
develops co-op
um
and it's protected using ddls and then
there's uh firmware updates um using
suit and so on and so on many other
groups sort of fall into that bucket
and what we also wanted to do like we
did in previous hackathons was to offer
tutorials um to
help new participants get up to speed a
little bit faster because some of the
development
is embedded development is
complicated
and there's
focus on low level uh programming so
we thought that that would be useful
again
um of course we
to make it uh more exciting we
prepared new presentations new topics um
and
and as i mentioned on this slide um
we managed to hold all the tutorials the
slides and the recordings are available
some people asks for it because they
like time zone differences and other
commitments made it difficult
for everyone who was interested to
participate
we also managed to write some code
of course
such as
sort of extensions
iot specific security extensions to tls
and
worked on empty dls code
also uh code for wireshark was uh
developed and and released and i think
it's already merged into wireshark so uh
you may be able to benefit from this uh
when if you uh use wireshark
we
also enhanced the an open source
implementation called backhammer
that is used for as a lightweight m2m
client lightweight m2m is a device
management solution
that uses co-op and a variety of
extensions uh so that was extended with
uh
security support uh bsa crypto
and uh the connection ids that i
mentioned previously
and so on
um some other folks
uh
didn't manage to get that far
to really sort of release the code
because um
obviously first you have to understand
the real-time operating systems and the
details of it before you can extend them
so they
did the deep dive on on those and how to
and figure out on how to integrate
uh their favorite uh projects
and i expect this to continue this work
to continue um
of course after this week
so we may have some results also in the
next couple of weeks or months
before we meet again at the next
hackathon
um
while doing these uh implementation
activities uh various issues uh were
identified with specifications
specifically in the suit and the deep
working groups and here uh some of them
that i have collected
i won't go into the details
you can
probably going to be discussed at the
meetings next week
so i skipped that um
and
what did we learn um we made some
progress uh on the hacking site again
uh most of us have been at numerous
events already
and uh so there's obviously a lot of
experience and quite fluent already with
uh
with uh various different projects and
uh embedded artists etc
um
we've again managed to identify some
open issues with the specs and i believe
the tutorials based on the participants
uh were useful again uh
i i enjoyed it um
listening to what the other people are
up to
and uh we also had good discussions not
only during the tutorials but also uh
um
during the week in in general which i
think is a big plus
now that we are all traveling less and
have fewer contacts um
these type of events are
really
uh enjoyful
um we did however notice that the online
fatigue
or hackathon fatigue settles in a little
bit uh
sort of this
um what we were used to like sitting
together in a room and having
full attention to the programming
uh isn't quite there when you have all
sorts of other activities going on and
so that makes it makes it really
challenging to make
good progress um
i don't know if other teams had similar
challenges
but but we definitely had um
and so
i i think we tried to make the best out
of it and and i'm happy that we
organized this i also promised um
all the uh participants of our hackathon
to send them hardware
thanks to our bureaucracy uh that's
going to be delayed and i will only send
them the hardware um
in the next few weeks
uh but
it's still uh maybe a takeaway that is
um besides the experience uh and and
the code progress uh there's something
to hold in your hands this one um we had
a bunch of different folks participating
um
two newcomers
who joined uh a number of people who we
had already worked with so there was a
lot of familiar faces in our
in our club so to speak
um so i'm happy that they
keep coming again and again uh from
hackathon to hackathon so
um
if there's one takeaway uh for you if
you care about iod security uh you might
want to have a look at the tutorials and
and the link is uh
on the right hand side so
yeah that's all
all from my side
thomas
yep please
do upload your slides to the
repositories so we have them there
okay i thought i did um sorry if i
who knows where i uploaded them to
yeah it said yeah
on
does anyone have questions or comments
for hummus
okay hearing none thanks again hannes
no problem
and so that ends the presentations are
there any others that we miss ben benson
has one he uh he uploaded and uh
benson i can share your slides if you uh
want
are you able to uh join us through audio
and speak to him
yeah i don't hear you yet benson
okay we're just gonna try this
oh no that didn't work okay let me try
something else
okay i'm having a hard time sharing your
slides here let me let me download them
and share them outside of
let's see if that works better
just a sec
okay i'll try sharing again one more
time
huh
i yeah it won't i get an error each time
i try to share
okay um
i
can most people see the link i guess the
slides online so you can advance them
yourselves
um
i'll paste it in the chat again and then
i'll
uh
start
you see if i can share them
you never know
so
ah yes
all right so just uh say next when
you're ready to go to the next one
dancing
okay thank you very much so uh this is
kind of the usual topic maybe one text
api
um
but a lot of the
uh communication security
have relies
on its standards
um
so move to the client
next slide please
and
motivation is at least in kenya
people want to
introduce taxes on digital payments
in particular for international payments
but this can be
time consuming
because it means you need to register
both where you're operating and
everywhere you want to sell so if
there's some kind of standard tax api um
this might help people
uh particularly if they can register in
one place and be able to sell in many
others
so next slide
uh
so
basically looked at literature uh
initial design specification
learned a little bit about go
try to make a prototype just to look up
tax rates uh using iso codes so these
will allow you to determine locations
they don't all quite respond test
transition so maybe some extension of
that might be lit
next
and um
the north america and europe so not so
much for
african and asian countries
and so we kind of
want to see if we can get something that
will provide a similar solution most
other countries
so this uh next next slide
it provides you
an easy way to find this competition of
the restoration problem
um but it still gives you a way to get
localization
uh
get the tax id right registered so if
you're a business you can actually
reclaim
uh tax on purchases and as you say it
covers mostly the us and europe and
canada
okay next slide please
um
so we want to be able to get the tax
rates and typical things that you might
want it to give you is an identifier
a text type
whether it's active inactive
a region code
a percentage
and
if there's a state
or region uh in addition to the country
and uh some information about last
updates
um just so that you know what you're
using is current
so that's what's in this stripe api um
one could use this as a basis for
extension so next slide
so the number of other bodies that do
standardization
em vco is
probably the most common one
so they do the 3d secure thing
pci
is also commonly used
for verifying how data centers should
run
oecd has taxation guidelines which are
helpful for understanding the area
[Music]
and
kind of business to consumer taxes or
priority for
oecd
that they
suggested an in-person meeting five
years ago but not much has happened
since then
um
relevant rfcs
in particular is 5280
so that's used in both 3d secure which
is kind of commonly used
and also secure electronic transaction
which was proposed but hasn't seen much
adoption
um though it looks like it would be
easier to modify to include taxes in in
the workflow that they have for secure
electronic transaction
next slide please
so what next we want to try and do more
complete api specification um at
examples where we have
direct links to tax authority for
payments
um so that this is can be automated
um
and need to consider security and
privacy aspects in more detail so
some of the rfcs that are being
considered could possibly be implemented
in the standard
um
that would allow this to operate
efficiently and then try implementations
in other languages just to see that it's
easy to generate this
um
next slide
so
thanks
team was composed of
myself and moses leduco and got a lot of
feedback from ali hussein
and thank you for your attention
thanks jensen anybody you have questions
or comments for benson
okay
um thanks again
i'm glad we were able to get your slides
up
thank you
uh anybody else is there any other
slides that uh any other presentations
that someone would like to make that we
haven't done yet
okay
back to charles
well
thanks everyone for all of those great
presentations and uh
we will just go ahead and uh briefly
wrap up then uh in addition to
all the great work that all of you did
it's uh i want to give a big thanks to
cnnec for sponsoring this hackathon
um really appreciate the running code
sponsors that we've had especially
through these
um
you know when we've had to do it online
i think
it's a
it's it's great that we have the
sponsors there and uh and i hope that we
continue to have a good flow of sponsor
so if this is something that interests
you it's called the running code
sponsorship
there's information about it
on the wiki uh sorry not on the wiki but
on the ietf
uh web pages if you have a hard time
finding it i should have included a link
here
but i didn't but i you know i can get
that information to you but but
definitely big thanks to c and nick
and uh
so the next uh ietf meeting is uh the
dates are set
uh we don't know yet whether it's going
to be in person or virtual
if it is
virtual we'll
run it the same format as we did this
one
for the full week before the before
ietf113
if we do manage to meet in person we
will go back to our
format of having it on the weekend
before
so stay tuned for more information about
that we'll see what ends up happening
and uh
one way or another we will have another
hack thumb
and uh you have had the face-to-face
hackathons we've had plenty of remote
participation in them so that will
continue
yeah definitely and when you know some
of these uh great uh you know
improvements in me techo and some of the
other tooling um are just going to help
us out with have even better remote
participation
um
you know better mechanisms for remote
participation
so
uh yeah uh
oliver
yeah hi i have a question so
in case next the next hackathon is on
site
do you also plan to have
a parallel virtual one
another
uh but you can join we uh as barry was
mentioning we typically do have a number
of people who
participate remotely
and uh just by
either and sometimes bringing their own
projects as as you did for this
hackathon
so sometimes the champions and the
project teams actually remote
um
sometimes it's a mix of people who are
in the room and some are remote
so um
yeah we uh you know
yeah we run it as a hybrid one i guess
yeah because
one thing for example we used very much
the gather tool to have our meetings
uh within gather even though we could
have used something else but we thought
okay in case other people might be
interested in joining in
uh that would give them the opportunity
to just pass by so that was my
uh maybe the background for my question
if um
if a hybrid hackathon is
planned
would then the tools would gather still
be available or
uh would it not
yeah i think we're going to be using
gather
for uh hybrid meetings for the
foreseeable future so i i would expect
that
that that you'll that gather will be
available for 113 whether whether we're
in person or not
thank
you yeah great great question though
and uh
let's see
and i think that is
is it in terms of the slides uh that's
it in terms of the hackathon uh huge
thanks to to barry thanks for running us
through the presentations um for me i'm
not on my usual computer so i think
that's why i ran into problems when i
tried to
share those slides i had restart firefox
with the right permission so
but you know i appreciate all your help
and you know huge thanks to the
champions for leading your projects and
really to all of you for for
participating and for putting together
your presentations and sharing them um
really uh great work to everyone
and with that i think people wrap you up
[Music]
thanks to charles for doing a huge
amount of work in setting this up
charles spends a lot of time getting the
hackathon
running
well it's uh it's
thanks for that it's great uh
uh incentive though when i see all the
the wonderful work that gets done so uh
it's easy to motivate myself to put
these things together and yeah the the
secretary and a lot of other people do a
lot of hard work to make this happen too
and
and uh
and focus on me techo and everything so
i'm glad it worked out as well as it did
and uh we'll have a successful hackathon
next time too either in person or uh or
online so
uh thanks to everyone i'll let you go
and uh have a great weekend and great
week of ietf meetings next week
bye