it wasn't disable your sound if it
wasn't like your sound was disabled it
was the button for i can silence you
so i'm still getting used to all these
like slightly different
user interface when you're a chair yeah
yeah if you haven't carried anything in
a while it's a little bit different
the locking queue is new and it's really
nice
yeah
we'll give it another minute or so since
i still see the numbers slightly
climbing
i don't think our agenda is that tight
all right now i no longer see it
climbing so let's go ahead and get
started this is the dane authentication
for iot service hardening and or dance
uh actually that title is the old title
isn't it
um
anyway i am west hartaker i'm here with
my co-chair paul wooters
that is the mailing list and
that is our official icon for ietf112
hopefully i'll find other official icons
for the future
as a reminder i'm sure you've all seen a
slide like this for many times during
the course of the week
by participating in the atf you're going
to agree to follow etf processes and
policies
and you should be aware about
contributions that you give to the etf
and the related patent related uh
decisions and things that go along with
that i'm not a lawyer so i won't try and
summarize that more there's a bunch of
bcps or best current practices that are
about
that in particular including anything
from internet standards process to
working group processes to
anti-harassment to the code of conduct
copyright and patents
specifically on the code of conduct
one of the things that we are trying to
do is make sure that all
members of the atf are welcome to
participate and are treated with respect
please do sleep speak slowly we english
is not the native language of everybody
dispute your ideas by reasoned argument
not by emotional statements i think
that's something that i was just talking
to high school students about this week
it's a good rule of thumb
um and use engineering judgment find the
best solution for the whole internet
we're not here to design just corner
cases and then contribute to the ongoing
work of the ietf by participating in the
mailing lists
and
the general discussion of pushing the
all of the work ietf forward over time
it's not a single meeting
do be aware that all of these rules do
apply to the jabber meet echo
im system 2 not just the microphone
because everything is logged
permanently
on web archives and also in youtube
for working group information we have a
data tracker you've probably seen it and
the purpose of dane in particular is to
extend dane to encompass tls client
authentication which is what we talked
about in the boss that we had about how
to use certificates to
do client authentication and not uh
everything under the sun that's where
we're starting
the mailing list information is there
hopefully you are all subscribed the
mailing list has been kind of quiet it's
time to stir up the pot a little bit and
hopefully this meeting will be able to
kick that off as well
and then there are three drafts that
we'll talk about today as well to
bootstrap our working group
so welcome to the inaugural meeting uh
the chair introduction uh is being done
uh tim has agreed to take notes and is
hopefully in the medical or in the um
notes.ietf room right now
i see he has notes in there already so
that is working is there anybody else
willing to be a backup note taker that
can help him out
i would just say not even so much backup
but just watch what i type about you
because people type a little faster than
i type so i sometimes you know miss
stuff great is there anybody that can
make sure tim doesn't get things wrong
how's that so i figure the speakers can
you know double check what i'm saying
about that yeah
so i will certainly try and
follow some too but
david lawrence can i call on you
you calling on me
yep
can you back up tim on notes
i suppose i could do that
thank you
it should be really just watching tomb
type
all right well thank you to both
one of my favorite pastimes
oh yeah it's not my it's not mine either
so
all right so our conversation this
morning we'll talk uh the way we've
structured it is we're gonna talk about
use cases first i think one of the
things that came out of the buff was
uh people weren't sure exactly how it
was going to be used or where it might
be deployed so we've put together three
use cases this morning
for
how we expect the dance outputs or the
tls client usage to work in um in
various
mechanisms and then ash will talk about
the architecture document that he
started thank you so much for getting
that started uh ash
and then uh schumann will talk about
some of the existing solution documents
and we'll end with any remaining time
for um
for open mic if there's future follow-on
stuff
okay so with that i think we'll turn it
over to bill
so i'm going to hit the ask to share
slides and see what that does
one of you guys now need to hit some
button or something
uh did you ask
[Music]
oh yes here it goes
okay
oh great okay
so that's the
uh let's see
that one
i guess share
no
not that one
sorry
um
actually here well let's see
just ask to share screen
and see if that was working
no i didn't change my mind
yes i want to allow
oh
where were we there we go
okay
sorry
view
slideshow there we go
everybody sees that okay
yes
great all right
whoa now it's uh
advancing automatically all right so
um basically
i'm not gonna try and go into any great
technical detail i'm happy to answer any
questions um
uh in q a so forth i'm just gonna try
and give an overview
of
the use cases that i
am aware of so
one
obvious thing is that
using dane to secure the dns
is a demonstration of good faith eating
our own dog food etc and it's
feels to me kind of ridiculous to do
anything else
so i think as a matter of principle we
should be using dane to secure the dns
in addition
ca certs
or one of our big known vulnerabilities
at this point the ca cert system is
trash and
anybody who wants to see a cert saying
that they're somebody else
has no particular difficulty getting it
at this point and so
those little green lock icons don't
actually mean anything
and i sure as hell don't want to be
depending on them for the dns as well
although that's kind of where we are
right now
so
uh
there are obviously people who ask why
worry about transport layer if we've got
and then security in dns
so dnsec is fine if you actually
validate in the client but nobody does
and
when i say nobody i mean you know it's
not built into the os in
mac or windows or you know most unixes
and uh the zone data was protected up
until the point which it was signed
and that's that's something i think a
lot fewer people have visibility into
but
um you know we do
and
what we see is really scary
um
so
i think uh
we we really need
automatic tools there um
things that are applied by default
rather than
assuming that the people who have the
unsigned zone data
are
fully capable of defending it against
attack
and dnsec is fine if everybody's going
to see the same records right if if
you're never going to distinguish
between
different people and hand different
records to different people then no
issue
but that's also something that people
want
so
uh
dns great for authenticating the content
but doesn't
uh deal with authorization
um
and we already do authorization
throughout the dns publishing chain we
just do it in a variety of awful hacky
ways and what i would like to see
is one nice clean way that applies
at every stage here like each of those
little red arrows
is done the same way not using a
different hack
so if we look at the beginning of the
chain the stub and caching and recursive
we've got this problem of split horizon
where people in enterprise do a lot of
split horizon they depend on a lot of
split horizon
everybody gets that's ugly and not a
good idea but
you know we also get that it's not going
away anytime soon
uh so
what do we do with people working from
home and you know kovid and
zero trust security and so forth we need
some way of supporting split horizon
that does not depend upon an ass in a
seat in an office in a specific location
uh so
tls client authentication solves that
problem very neatly
the
hack that people are mostly using right
now is
using vpn authentication which is
built into
os's
you hand somebody a unique ipv6 address
and then
in the name server in the recursive
server or the caching forwarding server
you give them different answers
depending what ipv6 address the query is
coming in from
um
that's
it's a thing that you may already be
having to do for some reason anyway
but
if all you want to do is give somebody a
different dns answer it's a very heavy
weight
mechanism for doing it
requires a lot of moving parts that are
sort of outside the dns
there's also a huge demand for closed
community recursive resolvers recursive
resolvers that are not public recursive
resolvers in the sense of
answering any query that comes to them
from anybody on the internet
but
are recursive resolvers in the sense
that an enterprise would have had them
internally
prior to zero trust work from home blah
blah blah
so
we have people who want to run a
recursive resolver that has a closed
user community
and is not answering for anybody in the
whole world
um
so we need a way of authenticating a
client for that
uh and again that's you know people are
trying to do vpn auth for that which
is a hassle
between recursive and authoritative um
this
again isn't probably visible to
everybody but
there is a huge amount of
um
iplayer
prioritization that happens between
authoritatives and recursives so
if you're operating large authoritative
you have a list of the ip addresses of
all of the major recursive name servers
all of their upstream transit interfaces
and you try and keep that list up to
date and when a ddos comes in those are
the ip addresses that get the answers
first
uh
that is an immense headache um
you know we've got
google quad 9
cisco
and uh cloudflare at this point
and
you know they've each got anywhere
between 30 and say 500
ip addresses
in v4 and another 30 to 500 ipv
v6 addresses
and
anytime they're changing
we either have to sort of
deduce that by where queries are coming
from and
you know patterns and so forth which is
a mess or we have to communicate it and
that's really just not anything we want
to be having to communicate as a
recursive operator
i don't want to be having to tell every
major authoritative operator what every
ip address i'm using for transit is
and as an authoritative operator i don't
want to be having to track
all the ip addresses of all the
recursive operators
if
i could specify a recursive operator by
domain name
and
see a client cert match that domain name
know that everything was good
that would be much much cleaner
then we've got the authoritative anycast
to the hidden primary
to the dnsx signer that section
is all handled with xfr and
tcig and so forth
that all works but tcig is
shared secret so it's super clunky and
the net effect of this is that people
wind up reusing dcig keys
across multiple sessions multiple
partners
um
you know
organization to organization they may
have a unique key but then they've got a
whole bunch of servers on each side and
they're reusing
they're
having
t-sig keys
floating around
in configuration documents in
documentation in
email in chat you know
it
it is a
a vulnerability
again
tls solves this problem
and then lastly the the thing i
mentioned up front uh
zone data is typically authored
on a machine and by parties who are not
capable of doing dns for the vast
majority of zone data that winds up
signed
the person who authored the zone data is
not the one who's applying the
zone signing keys to it
and getting
the zone data safely into the dns signer
the person who operates the dns-expiner
may be perfectly capable of securing
everything downstream from that
but the upstream side
you know it's one of those situations
that we hope nobody looks very closely
because garbage in garbage out
so
having something
that worked by default that gave
transport layer security between the
authorship of the unsigned data and the
signer
would
make
you know give me one fewer reason to
chew my fingernails
so um that's it for me um
i think we need to be able to
authenticate
both parties of any dns transaction
wherever it is in that chain i think tls
bidirectional auth is the only
reasonable way of doing that i think
dane
tlsa records are
sort of the the reasonable way of
getting tls keys distributed at scale
but you know your mileage may vary and i
don't really care how other people do it
i just need you know the jane tlsa stuff
to be supported in clients
um
that's basically it i just think we need
one solution here not a whole bunch so
that's
it for
me
all right thank you for that bill um as
a reminder you know not everybody has to
agree that all of these use cases are
for them but we're just trying to find
some of where
different people will
apply this resulting technology
um dkg do you have a clarifying question
we're not going to do much discussion or
bashing about things nope okay
uh victor you have a clarifying question
uh
clarifying uh one of the things people
didn't mention is
using dainty lsa to authenticate ongoing
maintenance of dainty let's say or
decide may have missed it if you didn't
say it
uh
so i'd like to see that
uh discover discussed because if we're
actually going to rely on it we also
need to be able to keep it working
bill
we're there and then you left
it is it is possible that uh
uh dkg
i just wanted to ask victor to say a
little bit more about what he means by
maintenance i didn't understand his
question so i'm asking for clarification
on the clarification
okay uh what i mean by that is that some
people are in the habit of uh
uh publishing dainty lsa records
and then not doing a good job of keeping
them correct as they roll with
ease
in part for lack of
sensible mechanisms to make changes to
the dns in part other kinds of planning
things that i may be able to help them
with software for
but i'd like to see
name servers provide a dane-based
mechanism to keep dan records updated
not just initially published
okay
uh
dkj do you have more is that an old hand
yeah no this is this is me back again um
thanks victor i understand that now i do
have a clarifying question about the use
cases here
um the use cases that were presented i
think are
well motivated i see the need for
something that solves those problems but
i am not entirely convinced that client
authentication is the thing that's
needed to solve those problems
so so
right yeah
right
that that not all of these cases you
know you may want to solve something
differently but this is where people
might want to deploy it this we're not
actually arguing
uh that that this is where we are
targeting but it's at least a use case
to consider when we're developing the
protocol
right so we're not actually typically
because it's very good we typically do
it the other way around right where we
say okay what's the problem that we're
trying to solve
and then what are the possible protocols
that we could use to solve it and let's
figure out um
you know what what those protocols are
as someone who's seriously concerned
about the
tying dns queries to individual
identities
i would if we're going to be talking
about how to solve some of these
problems i mean i i think maybe this is
a
i'm i'm more comfortable with the
recursive resolver to authoritative
uh authentication side of things here
um
but the the client um like if we're
trying to solve the problem of how do we
work with a closed community resolver
that has special rules
uh i would much prefer to see a working
group like this
think about non-client authentication
mechanisms that would solve that problem
so if we're talking about that is the
use case i think that it opens the door
to a lot more work
so that makes sense
right this is not the use case or it's
not even a guaranteed use case this is
trying to get models around when we're
talking about the architecture document
and framework
that uh
that somebody has the opportunity when
they start talking about it later that
we've you know seen a presentation on
what they're thinking ahead of it
you are right absolutely that uh that we
are not going to take this on as the use
case it is more as we start working on
the the solution framework
um
is is is this the one that we want to
consider in the future so
um
bill do you have an answer and then we
are going to go on just to get agenda on
time yeah i mean on that specific thing
um blind inserts and role authentication
doesn't have to be individual
authentication tied to a
you know identity on a passport
okay thank you
um ash
you have next up and
uh on device to cloud and the eps case
are sort of both yours
[Music]
i do i will say that i think the eps
case we agreed would be
out of scope for the initial work but
it's still
our initial architecture should enable
that to happen at some point right
yes yeah and so a lot of the stuff that
i'm going to be
uh
some of the stuff i'm going to present
as context but it's definitely
you know how
i would like to note that some of this
stuff is outside the scope of the
charter
um
let me get the presenter view going
all right so first we're going to start
with
uh device to cloud right
so the
device to cloud use case is particular
to iot
but it's very close to
a lot of other sort of
patterns you see even with workstation
access to
cloud applications
so let's let's jump in um this is going
to be brief and it's not going to go
um extremely deep into the the protocol
but i do want to talk about um two
different approaches we might consider
for
anti-abuse
uh and so this is some stuff that kind
of came up i was doing some uh playing
around with some how this might be
implemented and um
and at least should be recorded and we
should uh contextualize the way that we
build the final
standards with uh with this stuff in
mind
so
the problems that we'd like to solve
um you know in dealing with client uh
passion
it's not yet being fully shared
oh
oh my gosh okay
did you click ok and select the screen
i know what i did wrong
i'm sorry okay
okay there we go
all right so um
https device to cloud use case
there are a variety of protocols that
you can use for
device to cloud
sometimes that's mqtt
sometimes that's https
but i'm covering specifically https
for this
um we'll talk about some of the
challenges
with getting client authentication to
work for https and tls
at scale for a great number of devices
and uh we'll discuss
sort of two
sort of ten thousand foot view two
different approaches that we might
consider
for anti-abuse purposes for the protocol
and then we can have a brief q a
the problems specifically that we seek
to solve have to do with
using um public key based identity at
scale uh web applications um and
especially when you start looking at
cloud applications the cloud side can
get decoupled very easily because of
orchestration tools make that
easier to do so you'll have a
you know your tls termination might be
happening on the front of the
application in a dedicated load balancer
and then you'll have web applications
behind that um
you'll manage client configuration you
know roles and and um and identify your
association inside the application um
but you know when you start it becomes
very difficult to do that with uh with
pki because you may have to synchronize
settings between your application and
your load balancer and um
and that can become problematic also
problems that um
you know that we heard earlier with you
know the problems of pki where you can
have
identifiers in one pki
may also appear under another pki and so
naming collisions impersonation
happening that way
and
also when you start looking at
smaller organizations that maybe can't
um
good identity strategies like using
pki-based identities are not as
approachable because of the
infrastructure cost and having to um
to operate your own ca
traditionally or
you know and everything that comes along
with that
so
what we'd like to do is we like to make
pki based identity more accessible we
think that dane can do that
and we go into more detail in the
architecture document with how that
works you know having identity suppliers
but the problems particular to
um
doing this with https
when
if you have a bunch of devices
you know consumed by an organization and
they all need to onboard to a cloud
application oftentimes
you'll see an api to api integration and
this is you know between something
that's acting as a certification
authority and a cloud platform and
they're either moving the trust anchors
over or you may just do a bulk move of
you know device public keys or
certificates and using
dns just to discover entity certificates
by name is a lot
i think a lot cleaner way to do things
but when you get into the implementation
um
you know the way that we've discussed
this so far
is in having the um during the tls
handshake
actually doing the uh the dns lookup and
doing the dane comparison
however
a challenge that comes with that is that
you really need to have an allow list if
you don't have an allow list then
anyone presenting a client certificate
and supporting the dane client id
protocol could possibly trigger a dns
lookup against maybe a maliciously
configured resolver that doesn't respond
very quickly
this is sort of a play on the slow loris
attack
and it presents an interesting
engineering challenge
in the implementation so this is
something that's worth considering um
you know do we do this part inside the
tls handshake
or is there a different way that we can
do this
you know that might make anti-abuse
efforts a little easier to
to manage
and so
we may consider a tls cooperative
client authentication
protocol where you have the tls
terminating load balancer will
authenticate a certificate
and in the
http headers or rather in the uh
something like post data you might have
the dane id indicated and so once that
certificate's authenticated and you know
that the possessor of the private key is
on the other end of that connection the
certificate gets passed through to the
web application as well as the dane id
and so the web application
can then look at the id and make sure
that the
uh the identifier is actually a valid
client for the application before going
to do the dns lookup
and so
you know in this case you wouldn't fail
the um
you wouldn't have the tls connection
fail it would be something signaled by
an http error code
um
but this might add this might make for
an easier implementation
you know within
some cloud applications
anyway these are just some thoughts that
come out of
doing some test implementations
and
you know
for uh by way of illustration
this is what that might look like
uh you have a
uh the device uh abc.device.example
[Music]
on the left has a certificate presented
in dane or using a tlsa record in dns
as it attempts to
authenticate to the load balancer load
balancer is configured to authenticate
any certificate to make sure that the
private key is is held by the
client
and then it passes that through to
the application behind it
the uh the application behind it then
make sure that the um
the client name that's coming through in
the post data is actually on the list of
allowed clients
and then it checks that against dns
and then it can allow it into the
application
and so this makes it
comparing this to a situation
where one might have to to
you know if
if the tls
handshake is held up to do a dns query
and the client is able to sort of game
that process to have a bunch of tls
handshakes
open at the same time that might be a
dos opportunity
so
there's probably a really good way to
solve this
in the tls handshake you know with
managing timeouts or making sure that
there's an
allowed clients list
you know but this is
anyway this just shows
maybe two different approaches we might
consider
for uh for mitigating abuse
on the on the application side
and we can go to q a
uh ben clarifying questions
uh so are you okay i will phrase this as
a clarifying question uh are you
assuming that the client does not ship a
a complete dane search chain
or a signature chain
um the expectation is that the client
will present a certificate um
and
so are we are we talking about the sort
of the tls native method or the uh the
http method
so i i'm neither um i am
[Music]
i i am
uh attempting to to argue to you that
that the right answer here is for us to
say that the the client needs to ship a
complete signature chain to the dns
route
so that the server has no work to do and
they i so i agree that these are real
problems i just think we should
completely prevent them
i think that's a great idea um are you
suggesting ben that that you actually
send the dns keys and the signatures all
the way up to the root so that there's
no dns queries that need to be made
exactly the the server should should not
have to perform any network operations
or rely on any caching uh in order to
validate the client identity
i like it
that sort of unwinds the whole problem
there was sort of that discussed it in
tls at one point um all right victor
i uh
agree in part with ben but i wonder
whether that should be an optional
feature if some server wants to ensure
freshness of the data
the client may be shipping slightly
stale
information right subject to rrsig and
all that
so
it's a it
should be possible to do that we may
need tls extensions to negotiate which
of those scenarios happens
[Music]
engineer that at the moment because
the reason i'm doing clarified questions
is that we can get to all of these when
we get to the architecture discussion
[Music]
uh yeah so i think that's
an option we've discussed in the past we
haven't written it down anywhere but the
possibility is we have a mechanism that
can kind of do that right the tls chain
extension which victor is very familiar
with too
uh only then we would have to
kind of configure it to go the other way
from the client to the server rather
than the server to the client which is
how it was originally envisioned to work
but i think that's
that's a possibility that could be
implemented as part of the dance floor
if there was interest
okay thanks
[Music]
so ash we can go on to the eep case
all right
let me get this going
been asked to use the uh
the pdf sharing version of uh in meat
echo because it takes less bandwidth but
we'll work on that
in a bit okay
for now go ahead
so the the tls use case is a network
access use case and this this could work
for wireless or wired access
for devices um
and so similar flow to the last one um
except a little bit less into the uh
into the protocol we'll talk about some
of the challenges with uh
client identity
and um
and then we'll look at how dane
maps to the uh to the use case
um the challenges with epls supplement
authentication and supplicant is
um is the tls client in the eep
authentication process
so your epls authentication process um
it is
prohibitively expensive for small
organizations to adopt this
authentication mechanism
and that comes with the expense of
operating a
pki or certification authority um
and so
the it's also
limiting when you implement a pki
because you create your own namespace
that is local to the organization or to
the application
and um
and you know there's a there's a time
factor in that as well and this is you
know very often you see this in use in
enterprises but small businesses and
smaller organizations it's uh
it's more difficult to adopt um
and then that identity if you have an
identity issued by your home
organization and say you're a contractor
and going to do work for someone else
you can't use your
your home organization identity at a
client site to access
you know guest
guest wireless for instance and so if
you think about you know the the hoops
then we oftentimes see organizations
jumping through to implement something
that
you know that isn't too complicated for
guest wireless access having time down
tokens and everything like that for
accessing a very specific network it's
a lot of hoops and a lot of automation
that kind of comes into play and i think
that uh using dane for client identity
can cut through a lot of that
unnecessary complexity
so using
using dane for the supplicant
identity gives us one device identity
and because it's represented in dns you
can use it
you know potentially across different
networks different providers
and you can
then it becomes pretty easy to configure
an access list even across organizations
because you're just working with dns
names
you get revocation at the speed of
ttl so you pull the record from dns and
it can't be authenticated
and so that's a really good way of you
know disowning a device that might be
compromised
and
and then you also get the benefit you
know of having a third party you know
poor manufacturer providing an identity
that can then be consumed by an
organization and
and used without them having to operate
their own pki and so that's how you kind
of get to a
um
you know a very low friction uh pki
onboarding process for the network
um
and then you have the uk use case for uh
even leased devices and so if you have
one organization that provides devices
and uh to another organization
uh onboarding those to the network
becomes very easy you can say well i
allow you know
uh you could even do a wild card match
you know to say well i allow any camera
coming from this vendor to uh access
this portion of my network and things
like that so
um it gives a lot of flexibility and you
can be very you know you can use wild
cards you can be very specific
but it seems to be a really good
way and i keep coming back i guess in my
mind to the analogy of using
network access lists and how that you
know makes sense
you know for network flows higher up in
the stack using dane identities to
describe interactions between
clients and servers
seems like a uh a much easier way to do
things
and so
you know the way that you might the
specific on-boarding process for an
implementer is they might you know have
the
get the device in hand
you know and add that dns name to the
network access list
configure the device with the wi-fi ssid
that it needs to attach to and for
traditional
ca based authentication then you would
install the ca certificate for
maybe the radius server that's that's
performing the uh the other server side
of the tls
connection
um
we have discussed you know uh passing uh
you know like passing the dns chain in
the tls handshake that might be a way
around uh having to install a ca
certificate
but that's
that's something we've discussed it's
outside the scope of the charter but i
think it's definitely worth
consideration
because that would act that would make
it dane
end to end both ways
and then your network bootstrapping is
complete and this is without having to
uh
you know to deal with the process of
you know signing a certificate or
issuing
you know a device identity it arrives
with a usable identity and getting it
onto the network is just a matter of a
couple of configuration items
the way that this might look
is a vendor supplies the implementer
with devices
and the vendor places those device
certificates or public keys and dns
um the implementer configures network
access it just adds the um the names of
the devices into you know the radio
servers access list for instance
and then after configuring the devices
to point to that
um
access point or whatever then those
devices are able to authenticate and be
authenticated by um
by the radius server just using the uh
the dns name to do the certificate
comparison using dane
thoughts clarifying questions
[Music]
any questions
hi this is daniel again um
thanks for presenting this how are you
imagining a client selecting
which identity they want to present in
this eaton case
um the client deciding on which identity
to present to the network um
and could i get you to restate your
question
yeah um so i'm trying to understand
how a client would be expected to choose
an identity when when uh
doing
when when doing eep right uh
i think the the use case you described
is sort of a distributed one where the
client is using the same identity to
multiple providers
and i'm i'm just wondering if you have
any thoughts about how a client might
like is this going to encourage people
to always you know
publish their citizen id as they make a
connection or do we think that
people are going to be able to like do
you see this as something that would be
relatively easy for a client to select
which identity they use
um
for any given network like what what are
the sorts of
uh ui affordances that you would that
you would need
to avoid one person having to present
the same identity everywhere
that's a really good question and so i
think that protecting privacy is super
important
this might be a case where you have
multiple identities
having uh identities issued in this way
in a way that doesn't require the
implementer to
to operate the pki
you could purchase a number of
identities from
a from an identity vendor like this uh
so if i go to
you know
identity.example and i purchase you know
a number of pki identities to install
into my device then i might be able to
select one and depending on the network
i'm accessing um you know if it's a
public
public wi-fi network maybe i just
randomly pick from whichever one that i
want
the original
driving use case for this has a lot to
do with
iot and
in the iot use case where you have and
i'll use a specific example
the uh esp32
system on the chip has like four i think
four megs of uh flash storage
and so you're not going to squeeze a
whole bunch of certificates onto that
you know certificates and private keys
onto that device because it's really the
storage is really constrained and so i
think with a lot of iot use cases
especially when you start getting into
that that borderline close to the low
power stuff
um it'll just have one identity that
it'll use for a um
you know for a variety of networks and
with you know when you consider you know
if someone leases a bunch of device uh
you know smart light bulbs
and they want to use etls for them um
then the idea is that you would you know
onboard these devices but they would use
the manufacturer issue certificate to
access an enterprise network
it definitely bears some consideration
uh privacy wise for users and that's
we should make a note of that and make
sure that
if we start prescribing this for user
access
then we have some privacy protection in
place
okay thank you
um let's go on to victor and then we
really need to get moving we're a little
bit behind but we do have a buffer today
so victor
uh
yeah i'm just concerned as
always about this long-term stability of
uh
vendor
credentials right vendors also light
bulb and tomorrow they're gone
so i'm skeptical about this use case
sorry where is not a clarifying question
but i think it's an important
consideration to cover
right so we will
we will we will talk about that when we
get to actually solving that problem but
fair point right all right uh so ash
let's go on to your actually also for
the architecture presentation right
um so instead of if you could unscreen
share and then use the second button
from the left of which is in between the
screen share and the hand icon to share
using that slide deck instead assuming
your slide deck is up
to that should save bandwidth for some
of our downstream users thank you very
much perfect
dance dance architecture
all right and so um
sort of diving into the uh to the
architecture documents uh which was a
part of the original scope
of the working group is to produce this
architecture document together with
guidance for implementing uh dane plant
identity in the tls handshake
uh you're very happy for me
uh could somebody else enjoy say whether
whether it's just me or not
keep doing ash and then we'll um okay
oh it's just me never mind go ahead
so um similar float to the other
presentations we'll start with the
problems we'll look at how dane maps to
the problem space and then we'll go
through some of the
some of the use cases where we think it
might fit
and before we get
uh too far into this disclaimer this
does um
you know in the interest of painting a
larger picture
this does include some non-chartered
items so we talk you know later on about
what if object security were part of
this
this isn't intended
you know to require the
working group to go in that direction
this is to say in the fullness of time
and if there were interest you know
beyond a rechartering
this is what a more complete ecosystem
might look like
so i wanted to preface
this presentation with that
um
again the problems with pki based
identities it's too expensive smaller
organizations can't adopt it
easily
and um and it doesn't really work very
well across organizational boundaries
um it's operationally burdensome that
comes along with the expense you have to
have people to if you're doing it right
then it's not cheap you have to have
people maintaining it and
protecting it
and resource constrained organizations
are left vulnerable because it's hard
for them to adopt
and then the restrictive
you know i've already kind of spoken to
this uh before but you know getting
trust to work across organizational
boundaries and using policies within the
you know uh
within the context of peak kicks is sort
of a challenge and then you still
one pki does not have a way of
preventing other pki from signing
identities with the same
identifier
and so the challenges that come along
with that
it's it's really complicated it's
unnecessarily complicated and i think we
can solve this with dane
i've already talked about that so let's
talk about best practices for a second
um the cloud security alliance
recommends that in their summary
guidance document for identity and
access management for the internet of
things they say that step one a
you should define a common name space
for your iot devices and that makes a
lot of sense i think most people would
pretty much agree with that
um
and so from this decision point
um a lot of architects will say all
right well i want to use you know this
strategy or that strategy i want to you
know indicate the taxonomy of my device
it's from this vendor it does this thing
this is a serial number or maybe it's
just using the hash of the public key as
the identifier
but then you end up
when you're trying to troubleshoot an
audit you then are describing trust
you know trust relationships between
entities represented by two different
namespaces and you know what if instead
of creating a new namespace for clients
we just use the one
that we use for
server identity and that's dns
and so
using dain for client identity
pki namespace being bound to dns
you know it's recognized wherever dns is
used we all agree on the dns and it's
not like you know if you stick something
in blockchain then the next question is
well which blockchain is it in and what
does the api look like and it gets
sort of complicated
um
you know using the dns namespace it's
everywhere you get the ability to look
up public keys by name and a lot of the
uh the challenges
you know with using traditional pki
dealing with
restful apis on cas
just goes away
organizations are then able to purchase
devices or lease devices with
identities that are immediately useful
um and so
that takes the burden off of the
implementer you know or the consumer for
you know provisioning that pki identity
and the network onboarding process
becomes a lot easier
you know uh adding adding a device to a
network uh means adding the dns name of
the device to the access list
uh allowing application access means
that you add the client's dns name to
you know a
an access list or a role inside an
application
and for the object security use case um
using dns for public key lookup um for
signature verification or um object
encryption
it's uh it flows really well works
across organizations um
and the complexity you know that you
have of you know integrating different
apis just goes away if dns is the api
then the sdk's
already built into the operating system
um the example that i'll walk through is
one of uh let's say an autonomous car
use case
and the uh cars.example organization um
has autonomous cars that they allow to
drive around a uh
you know a city and the city is uh falls
within the jurisdiction of gov.example
gov.example says you're only able to
drive that on certain roads that we say
are okay
and you have to report
where your cars are driving
um regularly and so these autonomous
cars also generate a lot of data while
they're driving you know the sensor
readings things like that all kinds of
telemetry pictures
um and so they frequently need to upload
this stuff to a uh you know to a cloud
storage platform for parsing and for
training
machine learning models things like that
um
and so
the
uh cars.example organization has a
relationship with isp.example
isp.example runs a bunch of
consumer premise equipment
all over the uh the jurisdiction and so
they're able to stand up a you know a
wi-fi ssid
that's more or less pervasive everywhere
these cars are going to drive and so
this allows the car to
or any car in the fleet to
access these networks for periodically
uploading you know these massive amounts
of telemetry
um
and so looking at that universal client
credential let's just say that you use
um
use the same credential for network
access as well as everything else
in some cases that's not ideal but for
the purpose of simplicity that's how
i'm going to describe this use case
uh
so car's driving down the road
and it has
the cars configuration says that it
knows that it can authenticate to
public.isp.example ssid is named
public.isp.example
and
and so as it's driving along it detects
that ssid if it needs to upload
information then it's able to do eat tls
client authentication
to any of those access points as it's
driving around the city and it can use
that to
upload information
to the storage platform you know or for
internet access updating maps or machine
learning models whatever general network
access
um and so that same identity works when
it pulls into the parking lot at the
home office and so it can use the same
credential to access
wireless.car.example
and um
the you know uploading telemetry to
api.cars.example
might uh
you know it can use that same client
certificate
for mutual tls authentication with that
restful api and then it can use that to
upload
uh whatever information that it has
um
and for compliance purposes um
yes it submits a a
jws of
um
of different points of uh you know in
space and time where that car was so
that the government entity
can
can confirm that it didn't go outside of
its um of its allowed geofence and so
the way that that interaction happens is
the car uses
the um its certificate as a client
certificate to perform mutual tls
authentication with um
mqt mqtt server
and it put it places that signed jws
document
onto the message broker and so
you know the uh the document can then be
saved
and it can be verified later on when
it's parsed and compared against its
allowed geofence because the uh the jws
document contains you know in addition
to the payload it also contains the dns
name where that public key can be
retrieved for authenticating
the object
and so
what we have here is we have a card that
uses a single identity represented in
dns car54.underscoredevice.cors.example
and it uses that identity to
perform uh eptls client authentication
uh with uh multiple wireless networks um
also
sorry tls client authentication with
multiple wireless networks
uh tls client authentication with uh
with its home organizations api server
as well as the report.gov
that example
mqtt server for delivering that uh
sort of the geolocations and times
and then the um gov.example can then
reach out through dns to do a public key
lookup to verify the messages that are
placed in queue
by the um by the device or by the car
now what we see is as possible
protocol use cases and these are listed
in the in the architecture document
start tls for
um
for the email ecosystem uh eat tls for
network access
https
uh
and mqtts which are particularly useful
for iot
sip and webrtc as well as some
some use cases for lorawan
object security
should we decide to go that direction
after a recharter
jose and cozy
um make a lot of sense
there are some metadata fields already
defined where this fits really well and
xmpp end-to-end encryption
seems like it also might be a really
good fit
and client public key discovery for ssh
is something that might be worth
considering later on as well
and there's a we should also bear in
mind as we do this even though this is
not going to be defined you know
necessarily in
our uh you know within the scope of our
charter we should also keep in mind that
anti-abuse
efforts can really be aided by having a
good solid identity um
especially where the identifier
indicates the owning organization and so
um you know being able to report
misbehaving devices
using a dns names using a dns name you
know sort of takes out the um
you know so some of the what might be
subjectivity and processing a uh you
know a distinguished name from a
certificate or um you know client common
name
so these are things that we should keep
in mind uh
for security's sake i think it's
important to recommend dns over tls
for integrity's sake the stub resolver
should be doing dns validation
and
availability wise
you know we talked about mitigating this
with using the uh
tls chain or the um dns chain in the tls
handshake
but only performing a dns lookup for
allowed
client names is a pretty good way to
you know kind of
close the gap that could be exploited
and a few links to the the working group
the architecture document in data
tracker as well as github
and now we can jump into q a
so i accidentally killed your video ash
if you want to bring it back sorry about
that
um
uh anyway so uh q a so um
anybody have questions about ash's
presentation i will say some of those
items you know were
out of scope again the year for for the
working group at this point the goal is
to create an architecture that may be
usable for you know lots of cases
um
uh you know like epls for example is
even i think declared out of scope
initially and things like that but
enabling it if we want to if the itf
wants to take on that work in the future
is important
anybody have questions or comments uh
this is a time to talk about the
architecture regardless
of this this is not just clarifying
questions at this point we do have time
for discussion
um i think one of the outstanding
questions in my mind is in the
architecture document where you know i
believe that we need to talk about
naming of entities and and make sure
that that architecture framework you
know marries with the rest of the ietf
terminology
as well as
pick uh the best example you know use
case that we can state what it's going
to
look like architecture wise and explain
it so
schumann
[Music]
so um
this
since the architecture presentation that
ash did talked about some
for future looking use cases too i just
wanted to go back to
the suite of use cases that we
uh did discuss prior to that and the one
that i know i mentioned this on the chat
to the one that i noticed that was
conspicuously absent was the smtp
transport security use case and i was
wondering if i could if we could
volunteer victor to say just a few words
about that just to
you know make sure it's on people's mind
well victor does happen to be in the
queue so um
uh yeah uh
didn't have that in a slide deck but but
probably i should have probably poked
victor to make him present slides uh
victor do you want to talk about the
smtp client use case of this at all
uh sure i can briefly describe the uh
the issue so the smgp client that i was
interested in way back when schwein
draft
is is an mta not an end user
with a with a male client
and in the mta to mta
use case
the clients aren't trying to hide their
identity in fact they're trying their
hardest
to in most cases to convince the server
that they're legitimate and should not
be spam filtered
uh
and it would sure be nice to be able to
uh not only
uh
have
uh audit trails in smtp received headers
that uh show you that a message came
from
you know a
source that you can trust
but also to be able to apply a
reputation
uh to
uh instead of ip addresses
to uh
pre-trusted domains we do some of that
these days
uh with uh you know uh dkim and dmarc
and the like those are end-to-end
signals that tell you who wrote the
message
but it's also useful to have transport
security indication
in this case mta to mta
and with dane we could onboard that
incrementally negotiate its use
uh so the goal is to be able to
know who's talking to you as an mta smtp
client
now
uh
so that's all i wanted to say about it
unless people want me to say more i
don't know what else there is that
people want
that's probably good most people have
questions but you also stood up to get a
question probably too right
[Music]
yes which i will try and still uh
remember uh
in this case all right uh it's a
question and sort of a comment one of
the things we're not talking about in
this charter
is
any kind of
exchange of credentials you might start
with dns
to
you know authenticate yourself to some
point in the network
but having achieved that having
authenticated to some sort of
authentication provider
uh
we then i need to think about whether
that's the whole story
or whether we you know federate you know
sort of
in in some way
uh
trust brokers of various sorts that can
then authenticate you to other networks
uh by other means
than than this mechanism you know is is
there a more complete architecture here
one of the things that i had been
looking at but never had cycles to do
was in fact
bootstrapping cross-realm kerberos with
dane which would allow kdc's to
authenticate each other and then make it
possible to have a kerberos mesh that's
kind of internet scale
by using dane between the kdc's but then
user authenticates to local kdc not to
some remote entity
and kdc's have wonderful things in terms
of you know probably dan gilmore will be
happy to hear kdc's can support
anonymous credentials
uh kdc's can do all kinds of renaming
and masking and so on having
authenticated the user they might then
present them with a credential that
authenticates only the organization and
masks the user identity
um things that can't easily be done
uh
if the
architecture is you know single party
all the way to the end
and this is a much bigger problem of
course but i think it's the more
ambitious architecture has some merit we
ought to think about
what is the full life cycle is there a
federation story here
in addition to dns being federated
in terms of trust and so on being
federated as well
and
of course i don't think people have
appetite for these larger architectural
questions but they
they come up
victor um
[Music]
paul
thank you so um this is uh related to
the architecture draft there's a
question about scalability you mentioned
that
a client identity zone is essential for
actually authenticating
but in the event let's say the client
identity zone goes offline or it's
unavailable and you're not able to
authenticate
i do you look at the possibility of a
fallback solution uh the intent to
actually discuss maybe a fallback
solution in case such events occur
uh i
that's that is certainly worthy of
discussion uh we didn't put that in the
architecture document for fear that it
would um
that could be a whole
other sort of area of
uh of study that could be addressed
maybe by a caching strategy on the
server side of the tls connection
whatever application that happens to be
um
but it's um you know is if that's worth
pulling in the architecture document i'm
happy to
and getting some discussion around it
because
having having a good fallback mode
uh could be useful
uh it's definitely an interesting use
case the um
[Music]
uh or
not use case uh side effect and actually
putting
records into the tls client certificate
actually that was discussed earlier you
know potentially one way around that
right if the dns key verification all
the way to the top for example
victor
in terms of scalability and fall back
it sounds a bit like using dane not for
every ongoing authentication but for
enrollment
so you present your gain credentials
initially when you first interact with
some party
and then in many cases you might obtain
a
bilateral credential
and future interactions don't require
good point
all right well i see the queue is empty
and that's probably good because we're
right on time to switch to schumann and
the two existing
solution documents
so
whenever you're ready to present your
slides ideally using the file sharing
mechanism over the screen sharing
mechanism that would be good
okay so how how do i do that i don't
think i've
it's the one to load
slides is it that one
it's the pre share
loaded slides it looks like a file icon
with a slash through
a file icon
oh there's a hand like on which you know
as yeah
and forgive me i'm trying to find it uh
i can share it if you'd rather
uh yeah actually if you don't mind could
you do it
um the name of your use case so let's
see chair
client authentication is that it tls
client authentication yeah
there you go
uh all right okay so uh i'm going to do
a quick overview of uh what we think are
some of the initial
uh protocol building blocks for
implementing the dance architecture and
the various use cases
uh that have been discussed now we've
gone through a little bit of this
already during the boss sessions
leading up to this point so some of you
may have seen bits and pieces of this
already but now that we finally have a
working group i think it's useful
to kind of rehash and refresh everyone
just to make sure we all have a common
understanding so
we have two drafts listed
the first is about dane
client authentication and the second
is about a tls extension to convey
a client's intent to be authenticated by
dane and optionally to actually convey
the full client identity as well
so
next slide please
yes
the goal is to be able to authenticate
the client side of a tls connection with
dane
today as many
uh of you may know dane is used
primarily to authenticate tls servers so
this mechanism is about extending it to
do client authentication too
a little bit about the history these
drafts were originally written
um quite a while back in fact we
presented this work
uh
back in ietf 93 that was the summer of
2015 believe it or not and the dane
working group which existed at that time
and there was quite a bit of
discussion and interest at the time but
then the dane working group
shut down because it had finished its
original charter of work and this item
wasn't on that charter
and kind of the authors didn't really
have the time or energy to continue
pursuing it but the
original target use cases at that time
were
uh iot device authentication
and uh and also authenticating clients
in smtp transport security i think those
use cases are still valid as you've
heard today
and it looks like there are several more
application areas that may benefit from
these protocols to the next slide
a quick
protocol sketch basically the tls client
is expected to have
an identity in the form of a dns domain
name
a public and private key pair and a
certificate binding the public key to
the domain name
and
there is a corresponding dame tlsa
record
signed and published in the dns
the tls server
sends a certificate request message in
the handshake
and the client in its certificate
message
uh
includes a dane client id extension i'll
describe that extension in the next
slide
the tls server then extracts the
client's identity from the presented
certificate
and then obtains the dns tlsa record
authenticates its signature and
validates uh
its sort of record data against the
certificate or public key in the
certificate
uh
next slide please
okay so there is also a proposed new tls
extension for conveying a client stain
identity so generally speaking the tls
server
can find the client name in the client
certificate itself so why would we need
this well it has a couple of purposes
first to signal support for this
protocol which can be done
by uh the client just sending an empty
extension
so
technically both the server and client
could signal this capability
advertisement it's particularly useful
though for the client to do this because
then it can communicate to the server
that it has a date record
that it wishes to be authenticated with
and in environments that may support a
mixture of clients we can ensure that
the tls server attempts to do data
authentication only for the clients that
are suitably configured to make that
possible right
and
secondly
this extension can be used to convey the
actual client's dns identity and maybe
their domain name in cases where it may
be required so there's two cases
where
it's probably required the first is
if
clients are using raw public key
authentication
that's rfc 7250 i think
uh i don't know of anyone that has
actually implemented that in the field
today but it's certainly a possibility
that can be uh supported by the dance
architecture so in that case there is no
certificate at all from which the
client's identity can be extracted so
the client has to communicate that in
some manner and this extension can be
used to do that another case is if the
client certificate has multiple
identities in it and we want to be able
to kind of surgically tell the server
which specific identity has a dane tlsa
record associated with it
to kind of minimize the amount of
unnecessary
work the server might otherwise
have to do to hunt down which of those
identities has a date record
so i also want to make a note about the
privacy implications of this this
extension which was
kind of brought up when we originally
talked about this drafts
because we are potentially sending the
client identity in the extension so when
we first started this work in 2015 we
didn't really have a good solution
to privacy protection
at the time but now we have tls 1.3
which does address this so in tier in
the tls 1.3 version of this protocol
the extension is intended to be carried
in the certificate request and the
certificate messages which are both
encrypted so there's no privacy leakage
in tls 1.2
the client has to send this extension in
the first flight client hello extension
so this can't be protected today without
further enhancements to that version of
the protocol which seems kind of
unlikely at this point so depending on
the application
this privacy leakage may or may not
matter to you but we advise using tls
1.3 if if possible
next slide please
uh the tls
say record format for uh client uh
client authentication
sort of the record data format is
exactly the same as defined in rfc 6698
detain spec
what's different is the
record owner name format
which has to be adapted to something
more suitable for client names so the
spec currently proposes
two formats that we think have wide
applicability but
i think we recognize that applications
could choose something else
uh if they needed to and the draft is
trying not to be prescriptive on this
point
so the first format is what we're
calling service specific client identity
and it allows for the same client to
have different credentials for different
services by encoding the service name
into the first label of the domain name
and it also accommodates wildcards if
the client uses a common credential
across many applications
so in the original version of the spec
in
uh
going back to 2015 we we had actually
proposed the use of
different subject alternative name types
so there's something called srv name
which is described in 49.95 which
supports kind of like a more flexible
way to
encode application specific identifiers
but
in the end we
you know kind of assess that nobody
really uses that in the ecosystem at all
and we kind of took it out and instead
now we have this format
uh next slide please
the second format is what we're calling
iot
device identity and proposes
organizing iod device names under a
common suffix using what we call
a an identity grouping label so that's
underscore device that you can see in
the second label in this example
and this scheme permits an organization
if they wanted to to delegate the
management of the client device stream
to a third party that could offer you
know dns signing services and
maintenance if they wanted to
so to the left of the underscore device
label
uh is the device name which could be
composed of a number of labels and to
the right is the organizational name
which may include other labels within
the organization not just the uh
kind of top-level zone of the
organization
and uh
next slide please
[Music]
and here's a kind of just a made up
example of what what an iot client date
record
might look like and this is straight
from the draft and let's just move on to
the next slide
[Music]
and here's a general diagram of the
protocol protocol flow it's just some
minor enhancements to the typical tls
client
certificate authentication flow so i've
just pointed out the main deltas in red
here
namely that the uh
dane client id extension is sent along
with the client certificate
from the client to the server and that
the tls server needs to perform a lookup
of the client state and tlsa record and
validate the client's certificate of
public key
against the contents of that
authenticated record
and next slide
uh i've also tried to annotate the tls
1.3 handshake message flow with the new
protocol elements
uh this should be fairly
self-explanatory to folks familiar with
the tls protocol
but uh
so this is this slide is the vanilla tls
1.3 handshake so let's move on to the
next slide
and uh in red so this part is optional
so originally this wasn't in the spec we
only had it was kind of a one-way
extension from the client but
some people argued to me that it may be
useful for the tls server to advertise
that they support this capability so
that can be done
by optionally sending the client an
empty client id extension
in the certificate request message from
the server
uh next slide
and
then the client
in its certificate message
includes the dane client id extension so
that can be an empty extension to convey
the client's intent to be authenticated
via dane
in that case the
server needs to extract the client
identity from the certificate
and also it could be used to convey the
client's name
as well which as i mentioned previously
is required in certain use cases for
example if you're using wall public key
authentication
and next slide
and lastly
what the tls server then has to do is
get the client's identity look up the
tlsa are set authenticated and match it
against the client certificate of public
key
so
in the draft is currently
written requires the tls server
to do this in band in in the tls
handshake but
as has already been mentioned
today in previous conversation
that's not the only possibility
we could envision
the client kind of uh conveying
building its full
day and authentication chain and sending
it along
in a tls extension to the server the
reason we hadn't originally put that in
the draft is we were
concerned that one of the
prominent use cases for this protocol
was iot devices
which could potentially be constrained
and that may be too high of complexity
and implementation bar for them
but you know since we're discussing it
we can certainly have a debate about
whether or not
uh that uh
enhancement uh whether it's optional or
not should go into
into this protocol
and uh next slide please
uh yeah okay so i'll stop here for a
discussion uh one parting question
before that to the chairs and the
working group generally though is
are these drafts suitable as protocol
building blocks for dance and if so uh
you know uh
when should we
you know talk about adopting
uh so i'll see the the question with one
question that kind of came up in the
chat which is
uh that device identities are
potentially privacy leaking and should
we consider doing this only for tls 1.3
and ignoring 1.2 do you have thoughts on
that
uh yeah so i mean i was when we were
originally uh doing this work tls 1.3
didn't exist right so we had to kind of
support it until s 1.2 and i had to
grapple with the with the uh with the
privacy question uh a little bit harder
now that we have tls 1.3
i guess it depends on
uh you know the use case and what kind
of uh deployed field of
of client devices we're dealing with
right so if it's the case
that it's like green field applications
where tls 1.3 is omnipresent then yeah i
think we could easily do that but
it may not be the case in certain
environments right so i think
that question i don't know the answer
that question i think you would need
some
uh some research to see you know
which sort of environments we're trying
to apply these solutions to
okay uh dkg i suspect you're in line
specifically because of that
uh no i actually had a question about
the
tls arrangement can you go back to the
slide that have the tls
diagram
yeah um
so
uh
i might be fuzzy it's early in the
morning than the times that i'm in um
but
i seem to recall that with tls the
client has to offer the extension before
the server responds with it so are we
saying that the client hello would be
marked with the client id the dane
client id as well
it's a request response
arrangement and i don't see it in the
first flight from the client
it's not in the first flight from the
client right so that wasn't the original
version of the spec
when tls 1.3
wasn't around
so uh the no i'm not remove the
certificate i'm saying the the extension
because i believe extensions are our
request response
so if the client doesn't offer the
client id
extension then the server can't respond
with it that that is
just the flag that says i do want to do
dane client id
yeah i'm a little fuzzy about that i
don't see why uh
i'm not aware of that requirement so
maybe someone can
uh can elaborate on that restriction a
little bit more
yeah so in this case i mean
so
so that's just just a wrinkle that's
worth thinking about the second thing
that when i'm looking at this
um
it occurs to me that uh
if this is being done in a situation
where you basically
already know your peer
then you have some out of like you have
no other way to authenticate yourself
besides this client search
you could there's no necessary reason
for an extension for this at all
um in fact you've already identified
that the server is who they say they are
and if you know that this client
identity is visible you can just
stuff the information into the
certificate
um
and
let the server figure it out i'm not
even sure that we need a tls extension
for that if
a phony x 509 certificate
uh you know with especially
you know market in some way then you can
let the server take it or not take it
and and that's how it is you might not
need the the tls extension at all yeah
so yeah so daniel i i agree there are so
there are many situations where you may
need not need this at all
so uh there are uh uh situations where
you might know right if you have a like
a kind of like a mixed mode
uh field of uh uh tls clients and some
of them
uh can do uh dane authentication some of
them can't you want a signal from the
tls client to the server that i have
you know please authenticate me be a
dane otherwise
the situation you're going to run into
the tls server may be needlessly trying
to do all these dane look ups in band
with the tls handshake for many clients
that have no dane record and it's doing
useless work right so this is cool right
so
optimization to make sure the client is
not server is not being compelled to do
unnecessary work
so i think you actually need the signal
in the opposite scenario
in the scenario that you're describing
we don't need a tls extension signal we
just need the certificate to be
identifiable as a day insert versus not
a danger fair enough yeah that's another
way to do it if if the certificate
contains some sort of attribute that
uh tells the server that it's uh it has
a dane record that would be another way
of doing it so i i think that's worthy
of discussion yeah yeah and
there is the opposite scenario where you
have
a client that is connecting to servers
and the client has multiple ways to
authenticate and needs to decide which
way to use that's where you would need
the tls extension so that the server can
signal which type of identity the client
should use if we're talking iot that
seems like pretty unlikely right these
devices are going to have one identity
to offer correct correct correct yeah so
i mean that so that second point is
already satisfied by the server
optionally providing that extension so
so maybe it should always provide that
extension if it knows it supports stain
client authentication
i'm hearing a little bit of an echo
should i view myself or it's not going
to reverb here yeah so we were just
talking about the you know
can we go to tls 1-3 only and your
observation was well we might be able to
but we need to check the kind of the use
cases and the user population of the
devices that confused me a little bit
because i thought we were talking about
a green field deployment so
you know regardless of whether i'm using
tls1213 i'm going to have to update my
stack here with this extra dane kind of
and logic and so
you know are we saying we have
circumstances where we can update the
code to do a slightly better or fancier
tls one two processing but there are
certain clients where you know while we
can make that change we can't make the
stack upgrade to 1.3
yeah so that i don't know you may very
well be right roman so i was envisioning
a situation where
you're right stats have to be upgraded
uh regardless to use this mechanism but
it may you know there may be situations
i was imagining i could be wrong where
it's easier to just
enhance the tls 1.2 stacks to do this
rather than upgrading whole hog
everyone to tls 1.3 first i could be
wrong about that maybe
maybe that's not a concern and we're
looking more at greenfield tls 1.3
deployments
ben
hi hi
i i
i'm getting echo too
um
so
you mentioned the question of whether
sending an entire chain would be a
significant burden on iot devices
i want to argue that it's not a
significant burden that from the
perspective of an iot device
it the entire chain is a static block of
opaque data
it doesn't need to know anything about
it it doesn't need to look at it uh it
just would need to ship it in the
in the handshake or in a lot alongside
the certificate message
because
this block of data only changes when uh
at most as frequently as
when the certificate itself
has to change
so ben i think uh there's a little bit
more subtlety here it has to change more
frequently than that it has to change
uh
as uh
ttls and rs things on the time scale of
of of those things in the chain right
it's a full chain
so it's not just the tlsa record
in the um in the leaf zone but it's all
the records above it too
uh
okay
that's um
so it has to be i mean not that it's not
doable but i mean something has to like
periodically regenerate the claim the
chain for the client right either the
client is doing it itself
which may or may not be a computational
burden for them or some out of band
thing is doing it for them
uh
yeah okay i see i see your point here
you can actually rotate the the in the
sense the intermediate
keys more frequently than you rotate the
leaf keys that seems a little weird but
but you can do that and then yeah i mean
in theory you have to be prepared for
the possibility that could it could
happen right which means you want to
be able to always ship a reasonably uh
fresh um
tls chain always right to prevent those
kind of problems
okay that's interesting
typically the upper tree is longer
longer signatures but yeah i agree
typically typically longer it may not be
an issue but uh it's like there's no
guarantee of that in the general things
i think
okay uh thanks for helping me understand
that
uh any my my view here is that um
is that
we want shipping a chain to be something
that servers can require
essentially a profile
of
of this whole system
um
so
that uh i don't think it has to be
mandatory uh but i think servers should
essentially be able to mandate it for
some population of clients that they
work with
okay yeah i think i think that's that's
a reasonable thing to suggest
uh victor and if i could um
beg you to give an explanation at the
same time of the difference between
tlsa
expiry versus signature versus expiry
because there's discussion in the chat
and so i think we might actually clear
up some of the chat discussion if you
want to go over that
uh so to uh clear that up
uh
yes the client needs to actually if it's
gonna send the change it would need to
regenerate
frequently
because one of the most essential
elements in that chain
is the rrsig over the client's tlsa
records
and while the client's public key may be
stable for
days weeks months years
the rsig over that key
from the signing zone
should really only have validity at most
a couple of weeks maybe a month
and so the client would need
to refresh that data from time to time
needed to be on every exchange but it
would need to do it
periodically and well in advance of the
expiration
of the resource record signatures on
this data that it obtains
at some point and needs to again
have a fresh copy of
uh every uh realistically every few
hours uh
i signed
records for one hour uh the um
i don't know if that's enough uh but uh
yeah just a
scholarship element of this of this data
the rest is fairly stable
yeah so just to elaborate on that point
uh victor it's if even if nothing else
changes
the rrsig's inception and expiration
parameters will change right those will
gradually change and those are part of
the
data over which the
is computed
right uh
well there are six are the signatures
then they're not
you you don't sign our rsigs but yes uh
but the dates yes uh yeah yeah i mean
the rsigma the metadata of the rrc is is
included as part of the signature right
and and those should not be you know
ietf.org aside which signs for one year
uh is a bad example the rest of the
world science signs for much less time
one thing i wanted to point out in terms
of this slide and the various extensions
going back and forth
is that in fact a lot of this signaling
could be embedded
in existing signaling in the sense that
if we wanted to go down that route
when the server lists a client
certificate it sends a list of
acceptable ca names
ca names are subject dms
and subject dns have components
you know ous and countries and all that
kind of stuff
uh and there could certainly be
a format for the subject the ends of the
case that the server requests that
essentially implies a dns namespace
and could even you know say you know i
want a client
credential
issued by
essentially gained from this domain and
that could be a form of you know x 509
name all we need to do is get an o it uh
uh you know it's a free we could you
know write one down on a napkin and you
know and then we have a way of signaling
uh that you want if that name component
appears in the certificate list from the
server that means that the server is
willing to accept dane identities
from this portion of the dns tree
and similarly
the client certificate uh could
in at least in the use cases where
uh the tlsa records are of the dane ee
variety right three
uh you know just just carry a public key
essentially the client can mint its own
certificate on the fly
right because all it's presenting is a
public key
and then it can embed in that
certificate any name it chooses at that
point in time or has chosen recently so
it can again signal its name in a
freshly baked cert
uh to indicate you know i am so and so
at such and such a domain
so there's lots of opportunities to move
the signaling from extensions
into bits of
you know certificate like metadata that
we could consider
uh if appropriate it would be
well worth writing up an example vector
and sending to the mailing list so that
people can read it over i think that's a
really good point
um
and at some point i may think harder and
deeper about the role of
an architecture in which we have things
like kdc's
uh mediating multi-hop
interactions here
uh and then we potentially take
advantage of existing uh
protocols there maybe even get
advantages in terms of uh post quantum
and so on if kdc's negotiate symmetric
keys with each other periodically then
we can use symmetric keying for bunches
of this anyway all kinds of interesting
stuff to research
but yep later
yeah sounds good so i think dkg brought
that up
well i think it's certainly worth
investigating whether we can
provide the dane uh signal inside the uh
certificate itself rather than in the
certificate extension
oh yeah so yeah
are there any other uh questions or
people that want to join the queue about
the
solution documents of these
we have plenty of time left we still
have 20 minutes left
only
no audio from you
i think i saw bars
nope
maybe have ollie type type his question
into the chat
you could do that and we could relay it
certainly
[Music]
you know we have microphone problems in
physical rooms too right
all right anybody else uh have comments
so far
otherwise we'll probably dive into next
steps and
probably whenever you're ready
microphone's there
you don't need a request just talk
oh you are super quiet i actually hear
something now
yeah i can hear you extremely faintly
though
that is weird
i just wanted to point
the
name space needs to be discussed i have
a discussion with the nes folks
and uh they want us to look into the
name space so we'll build that in s3
if possible
but that's something we can discuss
later
okay so i i heard uh i think i heard
namespace uh needs to be discussed is
did i get that right i was having a lot
of difficulty
yeah i think that that was the brunt of
it ollie could you could you actually
just type your comment in jabber just so
we can record it in minutes if nothing
else but i think that's a valid point
and we sort of mentioned that earlier as
well
okay
all right if there is nobody else
joining the queue i will talk for a few
seconds to make sure that nobody else
joins the queue
um
yes and the name space needs to be
discussed so that we build a tree
instead of a flat namespace
okay dog point
uh
nope nobody's joining the queue so the
next question i think to
the participants in general
is at what point we want to consider
adopting these documents i believe
schumann that you have said you believe
that the two solution documents are
functionally ready if the working group
uh feels that that is the case is that
correct
uh yeah i think so i mean they may not
be complete but they uh
like appropriately address the
capabilities that we need for that right
if you're willing to turn them over and
have the working group rip them through
shreds and completely rewrite them
got it okay
yes
right
uh having said that does anybody have um
opinions uh pro or nay with respect to
adopting the two documents as is as a
starting point
paul's back
back but i've just been muted because i
don't think things will work out for me
uh so let me actually start a
poll then
um
do
[Music]
documents are ready for adoption
note that this is not the architecture
document
[Music]
uh it's a good point roman i'll get back
to that
so in
chat it would be helpful if people that
have read the documents uh would just
say red
so that we get a feel that um you know
the counts actually match people that
have actually done a
at least a brief summary and analysis of
it
thank you
keep those up
gotta love english
the fact that read and read are the same
spelling has always just
if there was one abomination of this
language it would be that
yeah that two-ish
all right i think
that is a
fairly clear consensus that we are
trending toward their ready
uh the numbers seem to be mostly stable
so we will end the session there with 22
for rey's hands one did not raise hand
out of 23 total participants
i didn't count the number of people that
have read things in this session but
in the jabra session but it seems to be
uh there's quite a bit of people that
have read it so that's a good sign
all right
having said that i think i'm out of
questions unless my illustrious co-chair
or ad has specific things they want to
bring up
and we can give you back 13 minutes of
your day
going once
in
dkg uh i just wondered i saw that one
person said this
document doesn't seem ready for adoption
i wonder if that person wants to say
anything it just might be worth hearing
what they think he's missing
yep that's a very good point thank you
for that uh if the one person that did
not raise their hand wants to
de-anonymize
um please uh feel free to come to the
mic and explain why you think it's not
ready
understanding that you may not want to
de-anonymize and that is the purpose of
a
anonymous poll
all right well uh hopefully discussion
will come up on the mailing list of of
what people find issues with the current
document because that's the purpose of
editing things as a working group in the
first place
so thank you dkg for making sure they
had a chance but otherwise i think we'll
close the inaugural session of
the dance working group and we can all
take an extra 10 minutes to get some
exercise and i suggest dancing it's a
great form of exercise
thanks all
see you in 113
you