so
it's time to start but
i don't see overall yet so i'm going to
wait another minute or so
or maybe not
i just got advice to just go ahead so
that's what we'll do
so uh
welcome to this
monday meeting in the very last
time slot of itf
112.
this is actually the second episode of
the
don and ron show
my co-chair don fedec
is
here to
help me
bring this to a
somewhat successful end
um
there's a high probability that you have
seen the model before this week
but
it's still important
so uh so pay attention to it
and
we've been asked and you probably also
heard this to uh
to
especially point out the code of context
and the anti-harassment
rules
don't do you want to say something about
those
no that was it i mean like
unless anybody has a question but
you should have seen this by now yeah
and uh i'm happy to say that uh
i haven't seen any uh real bad behavior
in the money working group for uh quite
a number of years so uh
keep it that way and we won't have any
of this trouble
okay this is uh some standard stuff
which you also should have experienced
by now
[Music]
we have a money working group
we have a general monet mailing list
we have
a list specifically for reaching the
tiers
overall ratana is our responsible id
and we have an agenda for this meeting
not all you've seen
we can
bash the agenda if somebody wants to
change anything
and we would like to
have some people use the headstock tool
to keep some notes
next up will be the
draft status for uh working group
documents
we have uh
um
the item that
we put on the agenda after some
hesitation because it's really something
that we
should resolve over the mailing list but
while we're here
we may spend a couple of minutes
on this
then we go to
one draft that's still in the working
group that should be
ready
for working group last call unless
somebody has
serious objections
there are
a couple of individual drafts by henning
henningrova who's probably not here
but
we have something to say about
those and
then there's
a very brief revisit of the
future work
agenda item
which we
went into
more extensively in the in itf 111
and then
i'm very glad
to be able to announce that
ed bering has agreed to
present
what's now known as the dti network
management
framework or
architecture
formerly known as asynchronous
management architecture
and now the new name suggests that this
this is purely for dtn
but i hope that in this presentation it
will become clear
why this might also be relevant
for
our working group and how it might
help us deal with one of our charter
items
there are these three internet drafts
which are
centered around
flow control and specifically
diff serverware credit based flow
control
they have been in the
working group for a very long time they
went through a very long uh working
group last call
not because there were so
many comments but because there were so
few
um
[Music]
they have now left the working group
and they are under a transporter area
they're on a review of the early review
of the transport area
a refuel team
specifically
the review will be done by david black
and
we requested
an end date of november 30th
but he has indicated that he may overrun
that with a couple of days but
um
i don't know whether this will lead to
extreme frustration
with the authors but
yeah given the long history
i would be inclined to think
what difference do a couple of days make
so hopefully
somewhere in early december we have the
feedback from david
we
will that
swiftly i hope
then i am
the idea is that
i would become a document
shepard only s they're somebody who's
very keen on
all taking that role
i've never done it before but
i'm
prepared to do it unless
as
it has always been somebody's dream to
do this
let's see if there's anything in the
then um there's there's one uh remaining
uh
draft in the working group which is
really uh belongs to the same
group of
credit based flow control
extensions but one that uses the 82.1 q
header as a
as a distinguishing factor for for flows
instead of dhcp like in a da credit
for some unclear reason this one has
gotten behind the other ones
it's also dependent on on the traffic
classification and the
general credit flow control
documents
so um
the idea is to have a
let's say
two weeks
yeah maybe three weeks
working group last call
um
and then
send it running behind
the other documents that we have sent to
the
transport area refuel team
and then um
now i have already covered uh agenda
item four uh practically
and on agenda item five is a discussion
of these uh uh currently individual
drafts by ending
on a fiscal layer
developer extensions
so to this
rada resolution there was a
rather filed by rick taylor at the
beginning of this year
because
there was something in the in
rc 81
the main d-lab specification
where
it said that
when a discovery signal
was answered
by a modem
vip
addresses source and destination should
be swapped
um unfortunately
for sending back the uh
the reply the acceptance
uh unfortunately this destination
address was a multicast address
so it wouldn't quite work
um
we have been trying to come up with a
better wording
um
at some point uh
that kept stalled
our id
marked uh
recognized the problem
but marked the uh
the rather before uh
as held for document update
but now it's apparently been reopened
and um
recently uh brian citrus
said yeah wait a minute but there's also
something
about the
udp port numbers um
they should also be a visual
but we were already trying to
take care of that
while we were trying to address
ratham 6472
so
rick came up with some words
overall came with up with some words and
so did i
but we never completely resolved it
but i think we should we should just try
harder
because
it should be possible to
have some
ambiguous effects there really
if somebody wants to help uh welcome
if not then i'm going to propose
something on the mailing list
uh i had hoped to do that before this
meeting but i did not get around to it
so
that's uh
one of
a number of apologies that i have to
make
this is basically what i just said
um
oh
go ahead
um thanks ronald so i was going to put
my name forward i have some time in the
next two weeks to work on that errata
just in a very quick summary
the text as it currently stands is
half wrong and half misleading when
talking about replying to a dis to the
multicast discovery packet
the
not only is the response ip address
incorrect but also there's no mention of
what to do with the udp port the fix
should be very simple it's just a matter
of wordsmithing and we should be able to
close off all three of those errata one
of them i think might be a duplicate but
we should be able to fix it
i'll put my name forwards i've got some
time uh starting from tuesday next week
uh to certainly work on that so i'll
i'll make that commitment
and with
with words that are also
that are misleading
comprehensible to
us english speakers
okay i might even include a diagram
yeah but you uh you said uh sometime
back that we couldn't use the
construction neither nor or neither nor
that was to do with the dtn charter but
yeah okay
now that was to do with this
oh okay fine i i like my double my
double negatives
yeah okay
okay
uh yeah glad to help by the way and
thank you
um
overall
uh thanks ronald so so really quick um
yeah i
marked those two routers from brian as
duplicates and uh he uh explained to me
what i missed
uh so i already asked the rc editor to
reopen 64
yeah i know what we're going to do is
i'm going to add there the extra detail
about the udp port
um so just so you guys know health for
document update means this is a valid
errata you know we just didn't agree on
the exact text right
for me to market verified
we need something that will actually
show up
as the actual text so now in the tools
you can go look at the
the router which will actually show up
uh in the document when you see it right
so if
we want that you know that's perfect
i'll just keep this open until we agree
on on text
that again when you go see it it'll show
the new text
instead of of the old one so so that
would be great if if you ever agrees on
on the specific board that rick is going
to work on so again 6472 is the one
we're going to work on
and
he'll have all the details from what
brian added and the original stuff from
rick
thanks
thank you
yes that
clarifies it
and indeed my aim is to come up with
some some good
replacement text
so that people that are consulting 8175
have a possibility to
to see how
how this actually should be implemented
and i think that should be possible
that's a goal that we should set
ourselves
oh rick's back in the queue
oh
just a very quick comment from me um
interestingly all the implementations
i've seen actually do it right so
the intention is obviously fairly
obvious to a developer who reads it who
who says oh well you know obviously you
mean me to reply here but uh obviously
the wording has to be right but the good
news is i don't think this is going to
break loads of implementations from the
ones i've seen anyway
no no but
anything we can do to avoid the
confusion is worth it i think
uh okay i'm going to skip this because i
just said that
unless
somebody now
jumps up
to this virtual floor microphone
and say yeah no no no
so then i'll take it
i'll start a regular group last call
on the mailing list and then you have an
opportunity to still raise any
issues that you see with this
document
then there are the
physical layer related
delay extensions written by enemy rohan
that's my second apology
to running out henning rojo although
he's not here i should have followed
followed up
more
after a previous itf
he has
updated two of the
three drafts
and he has
responded to my review comments
i made just before itf
and somehow i managed to uh to miss
his comments to the melodies uh
and this was mainly about the rationale
for
providing
role parameters like
busy time rx time dx time
to the router and
this is about the general utilization
draft by the way
instead of
having the
modem provide a single
value for general utilization
and
he has argued that there is benefit
of having the raw parameters provided
to the router
i'm not fully convinced but this is a
discussion that we really should
continue on the mailing list then i i
should have done that but
having said that
it shouldn't be only my opinion so if
other people can contribute there that
would be
highly appreciated
the radio band the
d-web extension
is currently expired but can easily be
[Music]
revived i think
it's it's very short and simple
i'm going to ask kenny to do that and i
am inclined to put that dollar warning
for working group adoption
because
i do see some benefits
to having this information about
frequency and bandwidth myself
[Music]
so
i will issue an adoption call
and
if people like objections they can
respond to that
and then there's the radio quality one
and i think even
henning himself has some
doubts about the way that the
information is is
is to be presented to the router
so
yeah
i
i will probably
also start a discussion on that one on
the mailing list and then hopefully uh
those interests
can uh can contribute i know that uh for
instance rick taylor has uh has already
gone have provided some coins
back when they were first published
their first version
early in the year
but
i think we should uh
or i should follow up on this
then
i come to the last of my
chair slides
so we're a bit ahead on the agenda
possibly
which is good because that would mean
that after
ed's presentation
will be some time for discussion
so
future work
um
there was uh some
we have lou in the quick queue oh
go ahead who i i'm happy to wait to the
end of the slide
oh i didn't mean to interrupt you i was
just getting queued for the end of the
slide
so it was for this this slide but not
for the previous one
that's right okay good
um
during an inter-ability uh event
in june
where i was part and heading as well
some problem was discovered
with
olizar v2
routers restarting and then
making a
an lucky pick of some uh
random
some sequence number values that were uh
supposed to be uh
random
uh not the same every time that the
starts
and leading to a problem that
that
topology control information from that
router was no longer accepted by uh by
its neighbors
there was some discussion um
on the list
back in july which brought in uh
christopher dierloff one of the main
authors of philosophy too
he is retired but
was interested in helping out
if we
were to
write an informational
rfc because the idea is that this can be
fixed
without making any actual changes to the
protocol but just
by some
smarter configuration
so
[Music]
this
would probably have to be altered by
chris of
henning and whoever else feels confident
to help
so i will bring that up on the mailing
list
then there was a presentation at the idf
about
the necessity or the
the benefits of having a d-lab
clarifications and lessons learned id
and there was some discussion after that
in which we were actually determining
that this should be standard strike
this presentation in itf 1010 was made
by lou and rick
and
they are both very busy
they simply don't have the cycles to
start this off
so um
again the question to uh other working
group participants
if anybody
would be interested in working on this
don't have to
step up right now
express your interest
on the mailing list
last time we
talked about the fact that there was no
ongoing work on some other uh charter
items not related to dlab
one of those is multicast and
the
the plan to produce a multicast
forwarding information base
um
and
rick taylor
came to the microphone
i said yes well
there are
a lot of uh vendor-specific proprietary
multi-cut solutions in manage out there
and
maybe
there's really nothing to do anymore for
the money working group
i've since come
across one of
one example of such a a vendor solution
or as a step
a different uh
i would say yeah it is
it is a standard of sorts
but not an idf standard
where this is
dealt with below
the ip layer below the network layer
using some cooperative broadcasting
technique
and there may be others out there
um however i'm returning to this
in the next
major bullet
on non-character items
the other character item is his
management and
there
i hope we can draw inspiration from the
presentation that it's
about to
to give
uh my personal uh uh
uh
pet subject and also something i uh i
work on in uh in my day job is a
federation of heterogeneous methods
manage
what if you have
monets
which have
possibly also proprietary routing
protocols
all different
and they have to work together
imagine some disaster relief operation
where different agencies are coming
together each with their own equipment
and
their own uh
uh
metal routing protocols and you want to
connect them together
one way to do that would be to
to have some routing overlay protocol
that they could all speak and then they
could connect with each other and
that
could cover a unicost as well as
multi-cost and then we are back to
multicast
um even though the individual adult
networks may have their proprietary
multicast solutions
they would fail to communicate if
if there is no
no way to
make this talk to each other
or exchange multi-constructing
information in some form
so maybe there is something there after
all
and that's it lou
go ahead hi yeah sorry about jumping in
earlier i thought you weren't going to
go through the detail i thought you're
just going to flip to the next slide so
um on the routing overlay i think there
might be some interesting overlap with
the raw working group
because if you have uh i mean they're
they're focused on the deterministic
service but they have to solve the same
routing overlay where if you have
multiple
uh
radio networks
and you want to provide deterministic
service across them i think you have to
start first solve this routing overlay
problem
ah interesting
and um
[Music]
is the raw working group
uh writing up something about that or
yeah
there's an architecture document on it
um the
i think the architecture document has a
lot of room for improvements there's
some discussion about starting up
weekly or semi-weekly calls on the
architecture so
if i stay tuned to the list for that
list the raw working group list
probably good to join in there into that
discussion
okay
thank you
yeah
i am subscribed to that list by the way
but
maybe also a suggestion for others who
are interested
in this
uh rick
i i'm just gonna add my plus one to lose
comment i'm i'm one of the co-chairs of
raw and uh there is a bit of overlap
with manet i mean we're looking at
reusing d-let within raw
so yeah the federation of heterogeneous
radio networks is very much
part of what we're trying to handle in
raw
looking at the from a deterministic
perspective but
i think there's applicability to man a
and we are really trying to increase the
um
the round trip time in terms of
generating the documents uh for the for
the core frameworks and architectures so
we're trying to hold some some
semi-formal interims to really try and
make progress so i suggest people add
comments to the raw list as well there's
some crossover i'm just kind of
publicizing raw now so uh i'll
i
i guess you mean decrease it around
return instead of increase
yes yes of course
okay
i'll do this alone
go ahead please
uh regarding the over uh
the throating of relieving role usually
they have uh different uh
use case than uh many so uh it's it's
interesting to check to see if it's
applicable this uh
their solution to our
our scenario is the same
so it will be because uh actually as you
said in heterogeneous uh
networking or in the disaster we have
the the royal
nodes and also the many
moving around so both of them
are uh are important to have this let's
say
rooting for
overlay
using both uh networks is important as a
heterogeneous sensors but
still that there are some things to be
added many is different than lln
uh this is my opinion thank you
yes
my my thinking is that if there's a
solution that works for
for a role
with
with the required determinism then it
will also work for
manaes
probably
but not the other way around
anyway
it's
it's good for
at least a number of people in the money
working group to be aware but what's
what's developing in enroll in this
extent so uh
i encourage people to uh to follow that
and with that
i think
i
it's
hey how are you can you hear me
i can hear you
uh
i can see you although you seem to be
very far away
yes yes the signal propagation is a bit
longer because i'm representing dtn
okay
um
the virtual floor is yours
thank you and and thank you for
presenting uh the slides uh for me so
the um
i i wanted to take just uh 20 minutes or
so and thank you so much for for giving
me this opportunity uh to talk about how
we are uh trying to deal with the
problem and the question of network
management in in dtn's
there are an awful lot of slides in this
particular slide deck this was a larger
presentation what i what i would like to
do is try and go over roughly the first
10 to 12 of those to talk about the
problem at large and then for those who
are interested the material is posted in
in terms of a backup material and
additional information and i of course
would be more than happy to talk at
length about this with anyone who is is
interested
uh if we go to the next slide
we started looking at this problem
really uh quite a long time ago uh we
did some early publication uh and and
research associated with what makes
managing dtn's different
we looked at
just generally what are the components
of a management architecture we looked
at whether delays versus disruptions
were the driving uh features we tried to
understand
what sort of
infrastructure infrastructure
information was helpful
and what we drove to was the the concept
of end-to-end closed-loop
uh control over systems in a delayed and
disrupted environment is not going to
get us what we need and and that maybe
seems like an obvious observation uh to
make now
but at the time there was a lot of
energy going into trying to make
networks not be disrupted in the first
place so that you didn't have to deal
with that problem if we accept that we
needed more open loop control and if we
accepted that we had to have local
autonomy and sort of a local management
function separate from a remote
management function then it changed the
tech transfer
opportunities and it changed where we
looked for solutions so then we started
looking at autonomous fault protection
schemes mobile code scripting we looked
a lot at spacecraft because they were
dealing with this problem sooner than
others
and we originally put this together as
something called the delay tolerant
network management protocol uh it was a
product of the research group uh it was
a utility also being looked at and
implemented by nasa uh when it moved
into the dtm working group it was
returned asynchronous management to
refer to the asynchronous nature
of um of the transport not necessarily
the asynchronous nature of the um the
management applications themselves
if we go to the next slide
uh when we started looking at this in
terms of synchronous versus asynchronous
particularly from a transport
perspective we looked at some of the
obvious things at the time simple
network management protocol netconf
there was an armand mib at the time and
those are things that we know are pull
based and session based and don't work
in the kinds of transport environments
uh where we would otherwise uh you know
see bundle protocol uh you know bundle
protocol version six at the time in
version seven now being deployed but the
observation here is that and this is the
work being undertaken in the dtn working
group um is that there are new
capabilities coming out of the ops area
rest comp uh updates to yang yang push
and and and more uh and these have added
a kind of a synchronous operation where
applications can
agents can choose to more intelligently
push data but it still doesn't solve for
us the fundamental asynchronousness of
the underlying transport protocol and
how that drives us to more autonomy on
the local node other than only filtering
autonomy
so if we go to the next slide
so if we if we zoom all the way back and
say what does this look like in a very
very scaled environment
this is perhaps an extreme manet
where we would say that we could have
ground entry points separate from space
based relay separate from landers we
really like talking about these
particular problems using these kinds of
examples partly because these are real
world problems or perhaps real off-world
problems that we're dealing with now but
additionally it helps us reason about
the problems in ways where we are not
going to fall into a local minima of a
solution that is not scalable
if a solution can can work with these
levels of propagation delay and if they
can work with these levels of disruption
then they will work for many cases of
propagation delay and many many frequent
disruptions so this is the management
model that we have
tagged as our hard problem to solve and
in that we see a couple of things
certainly a node a versus a node c but
intermediate nodes where you could have
an intermediate machine to machine
manager and agent relationship separate
from an end to end node a to node c
manager and agent relationship and the
idea that we would be able to have
either in regions or enclaves or spheres
of influence a machine-to-machine
management area a place where data
fusion could happen or a place where you
could have regional management that was
a very powerful
concept for us uh next slide please
so with that and using spacecraft as the
uh as the sort of driving example and
understanding that we wanted to look
more into autonomy and what was
typically a fault protection autonomy we
we did exactly that we looked at
spacecraft fault management systems they
tend to be stimulus response systems uh
focused on heritage implementations and
of course because of the
resource-constrained nature of the
compute environment they had very
deterministic processing and this was a
little different than what we see coming
out of ietf for for example the
management and data centers where
there's a lot of standards and open
source tools and much higher investments
into common solutions to common problems
as opposed to one spacecraft where you
have bespoke solutions to very unique
problems
at the time
and i understand that this slide is a
little bit data but at the time
there was a little more immaturity in
the asynchronousness and even in the
push models
but even today the overall autonomy that
we need for example in data centers is
not quite the same as the autonomy we
would like in these more challenged
environments
when i say inefficient implementations
and protocol layering i solely mean
there that as a as a function of
financial efficiency to reuse vendor
products and to layer things in ways
that that fit in and allow for
more agile
mixing and matching of capabilities we
can tolerate very very large protocol
stacks and separate responsibilities uh
in ways where we could see five ten uh
different protocol stacks together on a
typical spacecraft they compress that
because even the processing capability
is not always there so spacecraft are
not looking at processing you know xml
or large amounts of xml data as an
example far closer to iot than in a very
resourced data center and ultimately we
tried to answer the question if we put
these two worlds together what does that
overlap look like and is that a new
management capability for us
so if we then go to the next slide our
initial answer to that
was uh we felt that we needed something
different and we wanted to describe it
in a couple of different ways
the first was to take that original
delay tolerant network management
protocol dtnmp
and break it as renamed asynchronous
management
and soon to be renamed again in the dtn
working group
and we wanted to break it into three
different statements the first at the
time was uh aspirational what we would
call sort of a manifesto of the needs of
a very challenged environment that was
written down and adopted by the dtn
working group as the asynchronous
management architecture and there is a
reference to that the ama-03
that is a working group item it is being
refreshed it is being renamed
i believe the delay tolerant network
management architecture to really focus
on the fact that we can't just call this
asynchronous because asynchronous
doesn't capture the full richness of
needed autonomy and functioning in these
allocronic
um situat environments where things just
don't exist in the network all at once
and we have a very challenged experience
but aspirationally there needs to be
that problem statement and that overall
architecture
separate from that the data model
becomes very very important because the
data model between a local agent and a
local management function separate from
the relationship between a local
management function and a remote manager
perhaps in a more resourced part of the
network
we need to have a better and more
reliable way of talking about the
autonomy and the expression of behavior
on the far side of the delay and the far
side of the disruption
and so we we term that the asynchronous
management architecture management model
as expressed in the asynchronous
management architecture application data
model or adm
and and this sort of advisory uh model
allows us to build uh managed objects
and and the graphic to the right shows
what a few of those are externally
defined data literals operators controls
like remote procedure calls almost and
table data and custom reports and
variables and so on to us this is an
ecosystem in some ways uh the
information here
includes some things that we don't see
in traditional management models and it
explicitly
prevents or excludes other things that
we sometimes see in traditional
management models and this was sort of
the output of our system engineering
around what we think is important in
this space
and then finally and perhaps even most
simply there was the
to be able to encode these models very
very very compactly uh using seaboard
but also structuring the messages and
the model to entice a more compact
encoding so in the amp the asynchronous
management protocol
we could using the dtn ion reference
implementation say please add a contact
into a contact graph
and this is the nature of the contact
and it is strongly typed and this is
when it starts and tops and data rates
and the node that it um starts from in
the node that it goes to the entire
command to accomplish that is about 26
bytes
and so being able to get those very very
very compressed encodings uh is is
important to us for a variety of reasons
uh and and one of those of course is uh
from an atomic transaction nature you
want as many uh management commands and
controls to be together in a payload at
once but the other isn't a challenge
network bandwidth can sometimes be at a
premium
and you don't want to take a thousand
bytes to take to to communicate
something that otherwise you could send
in 26 bytes we have also had people uh
look at at this set of ama adm and amp
and and the data model associated with
it and want to run it between micro
controllers uh between systems because
even their the efficiency uh and the the
smallness of the data sizes are
motivating as well so very very compact
is important to us as well
so then
if we go uh just one more
uh at currently there are some internet
drafts there are personal drafts and
then there are working group adopted
drafts associated with some of this
for the protocols that are of interest
right now to the delay tolerant
networking working group
such as the application data models
think uh the moral equivalent of yang
models or uh mibs and snmp we have those
for an ama agent itself we have it for
the bundle protocol the bona protocol
security protocol uh ltp uh for ion
nasa's reference implementation of some
of the dtn technologies
and then we are also working to to
define
additionally other encodings and to
bring in and understand how we interact
better with yang
we looked at building our adms our
application data models using and
specifying them in yang but at the time
we were not able to specify
quite everything we needed to and now
that we have yang 1.1 we think we're a
little bit closer to being able to just
represent our autonomy model in the yang
models but that is an ongoing bit of
work between the d10 working group and
then obviously some working groups in
the ops area
uh the next slide just has a couple of
uh forward link references
and then i was going to stop here there
are a couple of additional uh slides in
terms of what we think are important as
part of that overall network management
architecture but in the interest of time
i just wanted to pause and see if there
were any questions about what we've
covered so far
okay
um ron how how are we doing one time
you have uh a good ten minutes
excellent so if if we could then go uh
forward again
if if we poke a little more into what we
think are important architectural
components
the we have laid things out in our
initial architecture document in terms
of service definitions and
desirable properties of the system
from a service definition standpoint we
have to define
management for us as more than the
generation and communication of
performance monitoring data the and this
goes back to the observation that closed
loop control end to end is just not
going to work in the kind of
environments that we operate in
we need
local agents to be able to change their
own configuration
as as we respond to local events without
a remote manager in the loop
we obviously need to be able to generate
reports but we want to be able to
generate reports uh either as a function
of time or a function of local state and
we may generate reports even if we're
not sure that someone is listening
that's a very typical thing to do for
example in a spacecraft system where you
may only check in with your spacecraft
once a week and when you do check in
with the spacecraft as a function of
when you can get dish time or deep space
network time in general then you want
all of the data that was produced
appropriately over time to come down
with the appropriate timestamps so that
you could forensically you know
reconstruct what happened on the
spacecraft while you weren't checking in
and we think that any sort of network
management system needs to be able to
operate in that way the difference of
course is that if you put that together
with autonomous parameterized control
you don't want to simply generate
performance report data and cache it on
the managed node until it could be sent
back to someone at a future time you
want to generate that data and then
have a local management function operate
off of that cache of data so that you
can get local autonomous parameterized
control while the remote manager is not
connected to the system or is too far
away from a propagation perspective
and then lastly to make this
to to be able to to use this system not
just within standard authentication
between nodes in a network you also need
more fine-grained administration as to
who is allowed to see what data and who
is allowed to you know issue what
controls
typically is a function of access
control and role access control
so if those are the fundamental services
larger than performance monitoring the
properties of how we would want to
create that are also important as we
said before the design of the system can
either inhibit or entice
more effective and efficient encodings
and the design of the autonomy model and
the local autonomy engines that go off
of those models
either can lend themselves to more or
less efficient or hardware accelerated
implementation easier or harder to
secure
by role execution and then just more
palatability in terms of what you would
implement in a in a secure or
operational or otherwise um you know far
away system
the first obviously is that the
intelligent push of information is
required here we cannot simply ask we
cannot respond to pull requests from
information we need to determine what we
need on the platform itself we know that
now
minimizing message size is very very big
for us and i mentioned this on the prior
slide if i can get a message out in 26
bytes instead of a thousand bytes
i think we should be tuning our models
to that reality
because very very tiny message sizes are
enabling in many of the areas where we
need this local autonomy as a function
of the challenge of the network or the
challenge of the environment
when we talk about absolute data
identification is part of a network
management system that we can
unambiguously reference data and of
course we can do that in all of our
network management systems however if
you combine absolute data identification
with minimized message size then the
construction of that naming scheme the
uris the hierarchical nature of the
naming trees the ability to truncate and
assign nicknames or encodings or
enumerations of of portions and nodes
within a naming tree
all of that needs to be thought out very
very carefully
if we were to look for example at other
things like i believe yang sids which is
a terrific idea
it is good if we can support say 63-bit
identifiers as hashes over some part of
a naming tree but if you want to run
regular expressions against it and
there's not a hierarchy behind it to
compare different sids then it becomes
hard to do that
that kind of globular naming and
reasoning about things
custom data identification was also
important to us and the idea that you
need it in the context of a mission or
an operational deployment to be able to
build custom reports custom variables
custom
other bits of reporting rules time-based
rule state-based rules and you need to
be able to name those as well and those
don't necessarily have to be globally
unique if they exist within like a
particular operator's name space
and then lastly of course is the
autonomous operation
if we go to the next slide
the the general architecture is not
dramatically different to accomplish
this we have agents and we have managers
we rely again based on minimizing
message size on pre-shared schemas the
ability to communicate that during
periods of configuration and our model
does except for the fact that there are
times when you can share
and you do have end to end connectivity
even if it's in a dtn and it's not
contiguous that eventually you can get a
message from one side of the network to
the other
that you can use that for configuration
as long as that configuration can then
include the the behaviors that need to
be
autonomously managed until the next time
you get an opportunity for more
configuration coming back
next slide
and then sort of lastly in some of the
initial prototyping work that we had
done the application data model to this
autonomy model is something that we
model in json we have also modeled to
the extent that yang at the time could
support some of the expressions that we
needed we also managed or modeled these
in json
and then
if we go one more slide
this becomes the autonomy model again
that that we model uh in json and in
cbor on the wire
and
or past that is just sort of an example
of what that encoding might look like uh
in in json for the bundle protocol
and it it sort of speaks to if we go one
more slide
yes if
the the reason i like to bring this kind
of encoding up and then i will pause
here
is that
we also uh try to build our model
around things that would prevent us from
having to do back and forth exchanges
between
really a local agent and a remote
manager but also even a local agent and
a local manager and the idea behind this
uh is is in the the second uh named item
here bundles by priority where we have a
piece of externally defined data an
unsigned integer that stands for bundles
by priority but this unsigned integer
data value can take a parameter
and the parameter is a mask of the kind
of information that you would like and
so this idea there's some syntactic
sugar built into our model to allow us
to do associative lookups almost like
function calls with the with generation
of even simple data types to avoid
having to say things like what kind of
information do you have or how would you
map that information and then once we
get it back then making a second call to
down select within that set of
information
so just in general that's a little bit
of a history of the ama it's being
picked up and rebranded as delay
tolerant network management it does
still have an aspirational piece which
is the problem we're trying to solve it
has a data modeling piece it has a set
of encodings content encoding separate
from will will eventually also be
transport encodings
and the model has focused on trying to
enable very deterministic autonomy
without requiring building scripting
languages and mobile code because
sometimes there are obviously security
issues around deploying that
particularly in resource constraint
systems that you don't check up on quite
so often
so if anyone is more interested in the
details of this work i would be happy to
answer questions here or talk to people
offline as we go
thank you very much
people need to know that uh
i only asked to do this a couple of days
ago and he stepped up and agreed to do
it so
a big thank you
and i think that
this is this could be relevant uh to uh
to manage also because with our
protocols we try to keep the network
connected but some somehow
the laws of physics get in the way
sometimes and if the distance is too
great for your radio range or or there
are obstacles or
or there's jamming or whatever
then
yeah you were your mayonnaise may easily
break into two or more pieces
and i think that then
this asynchronous management
approach
can help
to
have these
these uh fragments of the uh of the
network uh sort of manage themselves uh
with some uh some uh
guidance that has been uh preloaded into
them
and they can
phone home so to speak as soon as they
can
um
but i would like to hear from from
other uh participants in this session if
they have any comments or ideas we have
just a couple of minutes left
not all at once please
well i i was thinking that
do you think this uh this applies back
to non-delay networks too like is there
benefits that you know looking at
something in the extreme but then say
taking it back to regular networks is
there something you see that
you could also use
absolutely so the the
and a lot of some of the additional
asynchronous behavior that we're seeing
coming out of
ops area is the observation that just
sending everything back to a common
central management place
is is difficult and generates way too
much traffic um in well-resourced
networks because of course the data is
scaling
the next part of that is if you're able
to filter what you choose to push
then you can also start tolerating
operating in different transport
environments and so
all the way down to microscale we have
microprocessors that would say instead
of using something like our map uh there
are times when our processor is just
literally turned off uh and another say
a managing processor is turned off and
then turns back on again and wouldn't it
be nice to be able to have these
communications and you know that's all
on a single embedded platform so we're
not quite talking about delays and
disruptions in that particular way but
the other is if you want a synchronous
behavior without requiring tls sessions
for example this is a good way of saying
that if my if my two nodes are otherwise
resourced but they are they are turned
off and they
when they when they come up they do have
good um
ability to communicate with one another
the real uh benefit here is to be able
to quickly synchronize on what
autonomous actions did you take when i
disconnected from you or when i didn't
have a session with you and if you were
able to have that behavior you can then
start building in the fact that you
don't need the infrastructure and the
cost and the expense to always maintain
those sessions or re-establish those
sessions
and and so the amount of time that your
remote partner actually have to be
online
can be reduced
even if otherwise you could choose the
expense to always have it online and we
think that there are cost savings there
without sacrificing the responsiveness
of the managed device
thank you
and
with that i think we're out of time
um there's one other thing that i forgot
to mention uh at the beginning of the
meeting
is that uh overall made me aware of a
presentation yesterday that i missed on
uh
low earth orbiting satellites
and the
potential
routing problems erotic problems that
they may have in those networks
and
unfortunately i did not have the time to
work through the uh
the draft that was produced there
and presented
but
i
i'm going to be in contact i see that
at least someone from the group was
was attending
linhan
so
i hope to
to be able to uh
to have a chat uh
in the near future and in fact i i'm
going to go into uh gather
after this meeting and if anybody wants
to uh
to talk uh yeah please do
and uh yeah
we're already one minute over so i
expect this uh
this session to end soon uh don anything
from you
and we we do have a participant in the
queue
oh
oh of the shalom yeah make it very quick
yeah there no satellite
satellite i think it was a research
group
uh talking about this uh routing in the
lower lower orbits of life yeah
i i think it was a research it's a
research group
actually
is it
i see your uh rooting working group
no it's a it's a research group it's not
the itf
working group
it's a itfr
researching group
they were talking about uh low orbit
routing
i'm not sure but if
it was a itf
itef
working group please tell us which
or if
the director already knows that if he
can put it on the list so we can check
uh if if you look in the chat people are
saying it was in the
in the routine working group
but uh it could be it could be also in
the irtf because
it is a
a popular topic i guess
and it was also very last year a very
good
presentation on this in the
applied networking
research prize
presentations
okay
well
thank you very much uh for your
attendance
thank you uh
to the people of uh meet echo who helped
me out at the beginning of the session
and for providing me takeover in the
first place of course
and uh
hope to
see you all whether online or
maybe in person even at the next itf
thank you all
thanks
and as i've seen other chairs do i just
stare blankly until uh
well people are either
just waking up and logging out or the
just timeout
yeah i think
so i had a suggestion we should find a
sexy logo
for the group
yes
uh sorry i didn't respond to that
no that's fine
now with this
this all the satellite stuff
maybe you should uh change your airplane
to a satellite
yeah yeah i was thinking about that but
it was actually very simple to do i saw
i saw an example of that
it only it only took about 15 minutes to
do that
ah good
all right
i'll see you next time
on the list
yeah certainly i have a number of
actions
okay
so there are some notes uh that should
be available too so
i will download those yes
okay
doesn't work okay