the role is quite simple um whenever
someone in java just says at mike or
whatever
just pop in the queue and relay that so
people can hear it
we'll do our best to keep an eye on the
conversation as it progresses but it's
it's easy to miss things
thanks lucas appreciate it
you have two scribes in the chat
okay um when we get going uh welcome
everyone to the the first meeting of the
week mask thanks for being here
um
uh
it's quite early for some of us so um
hopefully this is a productive session
nevertheless
um
typical this meeting is recorded
you've used this tool before
if you use this tool before you know how
the all the buttons work at the top but
if you're not they're fairly it's fairly
intuitive um if you want to join the mic
queue just press the button
you do have to unmute yourself uh to
talk and share video um
uh
otherwise you know typical idtf rules
apply in terms of uh queue management
um and as a reminder as well um
just state your name with the mic just
so the the speaker knows
who you are and the note taker can jot
it down
uh this is the notewell
probably have not yet seen this this
week uh because it's the first meeting
um you're expected to be so familiar
with the but what's here
um
i wanna take a moment to briefly uh call
up the code of conduct
um
in essence uh what we are looking for is
people to be you know professional
respectful and courteous to others
and how they engage and
discuss technical details um we are an
international standards body meaning
that uh we do get people with different
views different ways of delivering and
different ways of receiving feedback
um so we just ask as chairs to you know
please please do your best to keep
things and personal focusing on
technical details um
and uh and and
and
just just just be respectful generally
um we've not had any issues in the past
thankfully because everyone who
participates in this group is
our fine
fine engineers
exemplar and members of the ietf
so hopefully we can keep it that way
moving forward
uh eric do you have anything else you'd
like to add
cool beans okay
um here's some links uh the agenda is up
it's also um here in the slide deck uh
we have a note taker thank you robin uh
javascribe thank you lucas
and here is our agenda uh first up we're
going to talk about connect qdp and hd
datagrams
david's going to give those
presentations and then tommy's going to
speak to connect ip the unified proposal
based on the two drafts presented during
the last meeting
and then as time permits we'll talk
about uh
two new work proposal items that is
paying from ben and prioritization from
lucas
uh quickly pause here to see if anyone
wants to do any uh rearrangements or
refactoring
okay
if not
let's proceed
i will stop
sharing and david i'll hand it off to
you
thank you chris
uh let's
ask to share slides
all right
can you see the slides
yes we're all set
awesome all right
good morning afternoon evening absolute
complete middle of the night everyone uh
my name is david snazzy and we're here
to talk about mask uh more specifically
uh this presentation i'll be talking
about both the http datagrams and the
connect udp uh draft
so
ah sorry um
first a quick uh recap uh for if anyone
is new to mask in the room
so the main goal of these two drafts is
to build connect udp which
is like connect which is the tcp method
for proxima sorry the http method for
proxying tcp but for udp
and uh
on in our you know discussions of
requirements over the the
now two years almost that we've been
working on this um
we want this to work over all versions
of http and across intermediaries
and when we're working over http 3 we
really want to leverage the quick
datagram frame which is an extension to
quick version 1
which is currently undergoing asg review
and since
as we started working on this this was
all in one draft
but we realized that there were other
features or applications such as web
transport that were interested in using
datagrams of http but not specifically
in connect udp so we split it into two
drafts
so some other
working groups could depend on the http
datagrams draft without depending on the
connect udp draft
so earlier in april this year we had an
interim to focus on http datagrams and
we kind of redesigned the everything
uh after and had some discussion on the
list and then we merged some pr's which
was great
and then at the next itf meeting we
re-redesigned everything again
which is also great uh but you know it
is causing quite some churn in the
drafts so
hopefully our goal today is um
to if we're redesigning things again
fairly you know reach some point where
we have something that everyone likes so
we can then move on from there
because there are folks who have this uh
in production and
it'd be good to get to a place with the
dresser more stable if we all find a
design that everyone likes
um so
as of the
connectudp draft 6 and http
datagramsdraft5
we have three working completely
independent implementations right now
the uh cloudflare quiche one the
ericsson one and the google quiche one
uh and
both google and erickson have cliented
servers and cloudflare has a client and
we reached successfully drop with all of
these at the hackathon last week so
good news uh things work
[Music]
then let's see where we were kind of
based on these
prior meetings
so a big read a part of the redesign
that we did back in april was to have a
strong and
tight coupling between http datagrams
and http request streams so think of it
like a sidecar
where the main motorcycle the main thing
is your http request which
in quick for example those are on
client-initiated bi-directional streams
and the idea is that datagrams all are
associated with one such stream they
don't exist in a vacuum and that makes
it a lot easier for everyone to reason
about datagrams and where they live in
you know regards to http semantics
we also landed on the capsule protocol
which is a way to send information end
to end between endpoints
as a even if there are http
intermediaries along the way and the
capsule protocol is
as simple as you can kind of get it it's
a
sequence of tlvs
it's uh inside the data stream and by
data stream i mean the for http two and
three what's inside data frames
and it's uh in http one that's just the
the the mainstream of data for a
connection
uh and additionally
one specific capsule that we define is
the datagram capsule that carries an
http datagram and in particular that's
useful for versions of http that work
over tcp so http one and two
because you don't have the quick
datagram frame there so that's how you
convey http datagrams for those versions
and then in terms of encoding for the
quick datagram frame
the
like what at the quick layer is the
payload of a quick datagram frame starts
with a warrant so
i rc 9000 style variable length integer
which has the stream id divided by four
and kind of the tweak of that encoding
is because client-initiated
bidirectional streams which are the
request streams in http 3
are
all divisible by four so we just divided
by four and that saves some bits
and finally because
that encoding could you know potentially
change that on the road and also changes
the semantics of what we see in quick
datagram frames which didn't have
semantics before we negotiate that with
an http 3 setting
all right um
now
where are we
today so
we had some good discussion on the list
last week thanks for kicking things off
empty
and
one of the things that we realized there
is
while there are some parts that you know
we're reaching good agreement on
such as most of what i just talked about
the um bits about um extensibility and
how you demultiplex
aren't quite clear or you know quite
full agreement there so i'm kind of
gonna walk us through
what we're trying to do with those uh
what our requirements are and kind of
explain the current design and how we
could potentially change it
um
so
yeah i'm gonna go through that apologies
if this is kind of a long ramble it is
the complete middle of the night over
here in california but i will try to be
as clear as possible
um feel free to jump in especially with
clarifying questions uh but then once i
have gone through
some set of slides i've definitely left
a lot of time for discussion to
make sure we get something that folks
like
all right um so
this is a set of extensions that have
been discussed in or around the working
group
of protocols that use http data grabs so
to be clear i'm not saying that let's
not try to figure out if those
extensions are a good idea or if there's
something we want to build they're just
random ideas that exist
and
because they're out there and some
people are passionate about them maybe
like we should make sure that the
protocol is extensible enough to allow
building them down the road
so we're you know eventually going to
build connect ip and there is interest
in being able to compress the ap header
on connect ip
um
similarly in connect udp some folks have
expressed interest in being able to
speak ecn or you know if there is ecn
between the proxy and target to be able
to convey that
on the encapsulated path between the
client and the proxy
or similarly if you if the proxy
receives an icmp packet that refers to
that five tuple being able to let the
client know about that is an extension
that someone wants to build
otherwise
there is interest in doing path mtu
discovery for http datagrams so
because the quick datagram frame can't
be fragmented it has a maximal
payload size so an mtu for datagrams
and there is interest in being able to
figure out what that is uh
and that would be an extension so ben
has a presentation about his proposal
there in the end as time permits section
so i won't need to go into too much
detail but there's interest in doing
this at the htp level as opposed to at a
higher level
and then over in web transport there's
discussion of conveying priorities
where potentially instead of just
you know you you can always prioritize
uh any data as you're sending it but
being able to tell your peer how you
want to prioritize it is something that
we might want to be able to do for you
know different types of data grabs
so
the the reason i kind of selected these
extensions in particular
is
they right now we're building you know a
way to send http datagrams uh which you
know okay we're sending these data
payloads um but it sounds like there is
interest in being able to send multiple
different types of payloads at the same
time
and that means demultiplexing so let's
say if i'm sending
you know a connect ap um
uncompressed full ip packet uh and i'm
also sending one that is compressed i
need a way to tell my peer
uh oh when you receive it this one is
compressed and this one is not um
so
that's where we get into demultiplexing
we need a way to tell between these
different formats that we have on the
wire and you know a simple way to do
that is by having an identifier that you
send at the start of each packet
but um what the the big question here
that has come up on the list is
why do we need to care now um can't we
just say
this is extend these are extensions
we'll deal with them when we're done
and that that is absolutely a reasonable
approach we want to keep the core
protocol ideally as simple as possible
but we want to make sure that we don't
paint ourselves into a corner we want to
make sure that when we go to build these
extensions we don't look at what we have
and go
oh if we had just done this bit slightly
differently we would have been able to
extend this easily but now we can't so i
think it's valuable to have this
discussion right now before we publish
this
to make sure that whatever the
extensibility knob or the extensibility
foothold if you will
that we need is in the core protocol
so
that you know as our favorite thing is a
good segue into kind of requirements
what will we want for these extensions
um so the
actual one second
coffee
so the
the first goal for for this specific one
is this idea of demultiplexing we can
have multiple formats that coexist
simultaneously
and we want uh the receiver to be able
to differentiate between them
another requirement is you know we we're
working across intermediaries here and
often intermediaries don't get updated
as often as endpoints so as we've seen
you know with other protocols at the atf
the fewer
uh machines you need to update the more
successful your protocol
is likely to be take you know it was a
lot easier to deploy quick than ipv6 for
example because you know if you only
need to deploy the modify the endpoints
instead of everyone along the way you're
in better shape
so what the way that applies here is if
we can have a way that we can deploy
extensions by modifying the client who
wants it and the proxy who wants it
without having to modify all the
intermediaries that's a big one
another requirement is
there is some interest like the mtu
discovery extension
for extensions that apply to multiple
protocols so i'm saying protocol or
application independently i mean like
what sits on top of http datagram so
that right now the main ones we have in
mind are connect udp connect ip and web
transform
uh and there is some value like this one
isn't absolutely obviously required but
if we have a way to write this once and
for all of them that could be useful
uh
and then another requirement that we
didn't really set off with in the first
versions of http datagrams but that
became very clear
this year
was that uh we want to make this
mechanism optional um there are
implementers that don't want this
feature today and really want to get
things out the door as simple as
possible
so
they really want to be able to pretend
that if we build the system into the
core spec uh to pretend it's not there
so that means you know not only optional
to implement
sorry but also
that they don't need to reason about too
many concept concepts to be able to
implement the core spec
and then a final design requirement is
what i've been calling zero latency
extensibility
which is the fact that were to be
to allow using extensions in the first
application flight i'm gonna i have some
slides to explain into more detail what
that means exactly
um
all right so
on the topic of
you know supporting extensions uh one
important property here
is
if something is not mandatory to
implement or if it's an extension that
means that not everyone will implement
it
and
one of the design properties of http is
when the client wants to send its
request it doesn't know the full feature
set of the proxy it's talking to and
you can't use settings to negotiate
feature capabilities because there could
be an intermediary between the client
and the proxy
so
and that's a common thing across all of
http that is one of the design
constraints that we kind of inherited
from designing deciding to build mask
over http
and
waiting a full round trip from the
between the client and the proxy to get
the
ttp response which could negotiate the
support for an extension
is unacceptable like we're in 2021
latency is the
most important like performance metric
for pretty much everything we do
and we need a way to be able to use
things optimistically and fall back you
know if they're not supported and
without everything breaking we can't but
we can't burn a full round trip to to
wait for these
things um
all right so what what do i mean exactly
by zero latency extensively well what's
your latency setup uh so this is a
pretty standard scenario where you're
just doing the client wants to do
connect udp to a proxy and then inside
those udp payloads it wants to speak
quick to a target server
and
one of the design choices we have in
connect udp
which technically is also possible in
connect but is you send your connect udp
request and alongside it maybe even in
the same packet you can send an http
datagram that contains your quick
initial to the target
and if the proxy
accepts it it'll send a 200 okay back to
the client and at the same time it'll
receive that quick initial and send it
over to the target if the proxy decides
to reject the request it'll just
silently drop that quick initial so
there's no harm no foul
but you've just saved a round trip
between the client and proxy you don't
need to say
request response and then send the
datagram you can send it optimistically
knowing that if for some reason it's
denied it gets dropped not the end of
the world
and
again that that is user-visible latency
for that end-to-end
quick connection between the client and
target that is um being saved so big win
there
um
so
now
uh ian what's up
on the last one so um are you
i'll just go back one slide a few
minutes so um
my understanding is this just requires
the core functionality of
of the draft not the
like any of the optional functionalities
is that accurate or am i missing that's
correct yeah this part is just a
standard one i have a another diagram in
two slides with with extensions okay i
just want to make sure i understood
correctly of like which portions of
these um scenarios that you're trying to
enable like require the extensions and
which dome thanks
absolutely that's a great question that
is perfectly
without any extensive vld multiplexing
required
tommy
all right hello cool i think the audio
is working now
um
just just to jump in a little bit to
respond to ian though as we've been
looking at the different options for how
you communicate
like if context are optional and stuff
that does have an impact on
how you send the early data and like
what capsule types are allowed so it's
just something to keep in mind like this
should be possible with any of the
setups
but
sometimes there are constraints on what
you can send in this first flight
depending on how you negotiate
extensibility
yeah i actually have some slides to
discuss this in uh coming right up
thanks tommy
um
so
uh the
kind of sorry the order of the slides is
kind of a little bit of a mess i'm kind
of jumping back and forth and i
apologize for that um so
as we were saying some of these
extensions they want to be able to send
multiple formats so
what's the simplest way to do that you
put an identifier at the start so when
you're receiving you parse the
identifier and then you know which uh
which format like what parser you should
use to parse this datagram like is this
just a udb payload or is this compressed
or does this have some additional data
at the start at the end
um
and but if we're making this optional
you end up with an interesting conundrum
which is
is that identifier at the start present
or not should i be parsing this
identifier
or should i just assume that it's not
there um
and that that
question is where
some of these complexities for that
extensibility design come from because
in the original version where this was
always there it was a lot easier but but
turns out we can make this work um
so then this is what
tommy was alluding to a little bit now
this is when we want to do extensibility
but without a latency cost so let's say
you're a client you want to talk to a
proxy
and
you want to use some extensions um
your main goal is to do connect udp to a
target uh you still want to you know
send you have your end-to-end quick
connection to your connect udp proxy but
maybe you want to use let's say the ecn
extension um
you just don't know for sure
uh if the proxy supports it at the
moment you start so you kind of send
your request and mention you know
potentially with a header or something
as part of your request that you're also
going to want to use extensibility
and you still send your http datagram
you just need to make sure to let the
proxy know that
this datagram for example doesn't have a
demultiplexing identifier at the start
so there's no confusion even if the
proxy does or does not support this
extension and then it can you know
seamlessly without a round trip forward
that over to the target
and let you know with his response that
extensions are
supported on this connection or sorry on
this uh for this request
all right so what is the current design
we have and that's you know as we're
always not set in stone uh what we have
uh today
is uh we
been
vinnie go ahead sorry
slight understand
can you just clarify a little bit um
absolutely
so the proxy actually doesn't know
anything about that extension in that
scenario you described it just allowed
that extension to work and end
is that correct
uh so
let me clarify that's a that's a great
question uh
what we mean in this case by end to end
because there are multiple ends in this
protocol and it does make things
confusing
in this case an extension would be
between the client and proxy so the
client and proxy have to know about the
extension so let's say for example in
the ecn scenario
this extension would allow when the
proxy is reading udp packets from the
target
those could have ecn markings on them at
the ip layer between the proxy and the
target
and this extension would allow the proxy
to communicate those markings to the
client as it's forwarding these
encapsulated udp payloads
like as it's sending a udp payload you
could say oh this one was marked ect 0
this one was marked congestion
experienced so
in the context of
that extension the ants are the client
in the proxy they're the ones that need
to know about the extension but if we
have an intermediary in the middle
between the client and the proxy that
doesn't need to know about the extension
ted
uh so a kind of a clarifying question
here on what you do then if you're
expecting an extension uh to pass
through the proxy and head on toward the
target and i'm thinking here
about rfc 5795 style robust header
compression for ip headers so you can
imagine using that in two different ways
one of which is saying hey i'm going to
use rock and my compressing ip headers
to you the proxy
or to tell the proxy that you expect
rock to go end to end to the target
so in that second case
i assume from this design you wouldn't
negotiate the extension through the
proxy
it would then just take the the connect
ip uh payload and treated like it
it was an
uncompressed
ip
um
packet send it out and if it failed that
was on on the client for not
understanding that what it was sending
is that approximately correct
uh yes actually
sorry ted some feedback um
please use headphones or mute
um so the
extensions that are like transparent to
the proxy in the sense that are client
to target are kind of out of scope here
because
they're
they'll work but the proxy doesn't even
need to know so what i'm all the
extensions i'm talking about are
extensions between the client and the
proxy
um like for example in this case
if they're extensions inside this
end-to-end client to target connection
the proxy doesn't need to know or care
there and it can't even because they're
encrypted inside quick
so uh when i say extensions here uh to
clarify i'm specifically talking about
extensions between the client and proxy
where both the client and the proxy know
about them
thanks for the question that was clear
uh that mostly does i do think that
there there may come some cases where
the the proxy has to know that what's
going on
isn't malformed
because obviously
uh ip with rock headers and
and presumption of context looks
different from standard ip um but it
probably doesn't need to do a lot to
support it but i i think this is
probably not the main
topic so let's move on
no thanks i think there's
there's utility and value there but yeah
that's not what we're trying to specify
what i'm trying to
specifically solve in in these set of
slides thanks
uh ian
clarifying i think comment the proxy
here is what echo referred to as a
forward proxy and the target here
is one or more
reverse proxies machines application
front ends yada yada that received the
traffic right like just to clarify like
like the target could be like one or
more machines and we kind of don't care
because it just should just all work
because like reverse proxy providers
need to deal with this stuff themselves
is that accurate
uh absolutely so in this scenario let's
say you're using uh connect2udp as uh
like an ip blinding service um
it from from the client in the proxy's
perspective the target is just an an ip
address on the internet and a udp port
that you're sending things to and that
you're receiving things from
there's worlds of complexity and servers
and machinery behind the target but from
our perspective we don't know we don't
care the is this could all be running on
a raspberry pi on a corner or it could
be you know backed by a giant google
data center
completely oblivious to us we don't care
um but the the from the client's
perspective there could still be an
interpreter in a proxy which
like in general the client doesn't
really need to care all it knows is it's
trying to connect to a
connect udp proxy with a given authority
um
what we just need to build here is make
sure that the if the
entity that wants to deploy the connect
udp proxy wants to deploy that behind a
front end in other words behind
intermediary that needs to work in
practice it doesn't really change the
protocol much but it just impacts some
design requirements like the fact that
we can't rely on settings for everything
for example
all right so
all right
why can't we rely on settings here
because i i think i i'm not i'm i'm
missing why we can't rely on settings
no no no no on the contrary this is
really useful because these are trivial
points thank you
the so you're
in a in a given http deployment uh it
interpret areas are pretty common so
like take our setup we have the google
front end and then we have back ends so
mapping to like the the terminology here
the google front end is an intermediary
and the google backend would be the one
implementing connect udp and which we
the one that we list as the proxy and
that could be the egress to the internet
in some scenarios
the
settings are hub by hop at the http
layer
whereas requests are end to end in that
scenario where the end is the proxy you
could be running something into that um
but
the request could flow through an
interpret area and we have folks in the
working group that wish to deploy that
this way uh in particular for web
transport
so to walk back let me try to reset this
in in more terms that like i am you know
that are very focused on hardware
infrastructure so like in this case like
google is running like a target which is
like
you know
probably at least two and sometimes
three layers of load balancers uh stuck
in in front of like an application front
and
you're saying that the first load
balancer needs to make sure to
communicate the right settings for all
the things behind it because otherwise
like bad things could happen right
is that yeah so
well yeah so so let's say i think the
web transport example is perhaps a
better one where you have a front end
which is also a load balancer
and you know you talk through that to a
myriad of back ends as a client you
don't even know that there are you know
front-ends and back-ends you just know
that you
like the front-end sir and the or in
other words the interpreter
served you with the appropriate
approved for the tls certificate
and when you send your requests you
gotta reply maybe you went through that
to a different machine
but potentially let's say some of the
fleet
uh supports the this web transport with
extension some of it supports web
transport without extensions
um and the front end doesn't know all of
these so like supported protocols
features extensions of all of its back
ends necessarily
uh and so it can't synthesize a setting
frame for you that covers everyone in
the back
uh you need to go and send the request
and get a response to know fully what
they support
but just to like kind of really like
slice this down to like the very
specific points so the
so the the server the the
um the load balancer
needs to know whether say connect ip
connect udp connect
or web transport is supported because
the way you load balance those protocols
is just like transformatively different
from standard http so like you're just
not getting away without like having
that knowledge of the the terminating
um load balancer but
still so i think so to clarify that um
you need to and that's that's
specifically
what we're picking at so let me just
clarify on what you're saying
the intermediary needs to know how to
proxy http datagrams and especially for
web transfer where transport has other
custom things that need to be proxied
such as like custom unidirectional
streams for example so the interpreter
needs to be aware of this
but if we for example want to add in the
future an extension
the the goal there is that this front
end that was modified once to speak web
transport doesn't need to be modified
every time we want to deploy a web
transport extension
um
that is the
kind of distinction
okay that makes sense to me i i think i
i think we should just move on because i
think we've kind of gotten it down to
the point where i just wanted to get it
to which is
the
yeah the load balancer does actually
need to know like whether web transport
for example is supported but it's it's
valid to say once web transport is
supported that maybe there's some other
stuff you want to like um tunnel to the
to the actual application front end that
you don't want to make every single hop
in the middle be aware of um so why
don't we move forward through what the
extensions are and then maybe that'll
clarify everything for me thanks cool
well dude thanks no no that was that was
a great point um
and that was what i was trying to get
across but yeah taking the time to
actually state it clearly really
important so thanks for your help
um
so yeah the the current design
how do we do this um
it introduces the concept of datagram
format types
which is a okay this is the semantics of
my payload so
for example in our current drafts
connect udp registers the
udp payload datagram format type
and the client starts off by recall
sorry by sending a registered datagram
capsule that says hey
i'm going to be sending udp payloads on
here um
good like those are the ones that you
need to when you get the payload you
then put that
you write that into your udp socket to
the target
um and
additionally we have this
de-multiplexing mechanism which is
inside this
uh box on
and so you you negotiate using the
secu's datagram context's http header
and the draft introduces the concept of
a context um and the idea is when this
is in use
every datagram starts with a warrant
that is a context so for example you
could say okay i want to register the
udp payload context and i want to
register a udp payload with two bits of
ecn at the start context for the ecn
extension
or you could register the
icmp context extension so then when the
other side receives um a an http
datagram it knows
it'll read this warrant off the head and
then say oh this is just a udp pillow
let me put this into my udp stack or
this one oh i need to parse these first
two bits for ecn or this one's kind of a
separate sidecar of icmp or something
and it knows how it can parse and what
actions it needs to take
based on this demultiplexing identifier
at the start
um
and
mt mentioned on the list that
this is he he says that this is overly
complicated i don't disagree and
actually we had a good conversation with
him and others uh last week
and
the fundamental
um
thought that mta got across you which i
i think is very very reasonable is like
concepts aren't free when you meant a
new concept you have to keep it in mind
forever and if you ever got anything
wrong in the definition of that concept
you're gonna like pay it for for many
years um so if we can get something even
simpler
that's better so so we have an issue to
track that
um
and we we kind of came up with a new
design that i just wanted to run people
with and then as soon as
i'm done running through that i'll have
a slide and then we can like jump into a
full discussion
sorry so the
idea there is um
i initially thought that like the
datagram format type was our best
extensibility joint or foothold if you
will to enable all this extensibility
but it turns out after some more
thinking and discussion um it's possible
to get the extensibility we need without
introducing this concept and
um i think that that's a nice property
we want to have an extensibility joint
um but we kind of already have one in
the protocol it's capsule types so as a
reminder capsule is this client to proxy
protocol
where you just send a sequence of tlvs
and the t there this type is something
where you can mint new one they're
registered with viana
and that's a really good extensibility
joint because uh proxies and clients
will drop any capsule that it doesn't
understand
so a new extension protocol anything can
define its own capsule um
and
so this this pro 115 the idea is we
remove those registration capsules uh
because we don't need them in the core
spec we remove datagram format types
then we we add some text to say okay if
you're an extension
you'll be able to use these capsule
types as your extensibility mechanism um
and so what what the with this potential
design what you say is you send a header
uh as part of your request
to
when you're the client and you wanted
this demultiplexing functionality you
send that header
and
if the
proxy
replies with that header as well it
means okay we both
have like support at least one of these
extensions we think there's value here
we want this demultiplexing so when
we've negotiated that now every single
http datagram starts with this the
multiplexing variant
which we call the context id
the idea there is that context id maps
to a context for example let's say if
you're doing a p compression and you're
like removing the ip addresses
this context would be a struct somewhere
in your memory that contains the ip
addresses that have been removed so when
you parse the incoming datagram you
could put them back in before you feed
it into your ip stack
um and the because we know this we
wanted this idea of zero latency
extensibility
we add the concept of
data we add multiple capsules for
datagram
for to to convey the ones that
explicitly have or do not have context
so the idea there is
while you're negotiating the headers so
as a client before you've received the
headers
you can't send the like regular quick
datagram http datagram because there
could be some confusion about whether
that warrant is present or not
so until you know for sure and have
gotten the sort of response you use
these separate capsules that are
crystal clear they're self-describing in
other words
and once you've known the response then
you know you both agree on what the
format is you can send this or not
um
yes ian
the shape of what you're describing
sounds good one kind of wording
suggestion or comment is we're using the
word demultiplexing here
at any point do you actually mean like
an intermediary or a proxy or something
like that taking a single stream
and then sending it to two entirely
different locations or are you really
talking about like
um i might even call it like format
conversion or compression or something
like that where basically
you've developed like a better
formatting for whether it's like ecn or
ip compression or whatever and the thing
that terminates the proxy is responsible
which is in some sense and hop um is
responsible for saying like okay i
understand this format
and i know how to convert it to like you
know edp or ip or whatever i need to pop
out the other end and so it's it's kind
of
it's a format conversion it's a
compression i don't know like some other
so or is it actually multiplexing like a
load balancer differently
so so no that's a great question i i'm
using demultiplexing to say
[Music]
separating between
multiple things inside an incoming flow
of things so that's horribly unclear
what i mean by that is it's the goal
isn't to say like let's say you're a
connectudp proxy it's not to say
these uh these packets go here these
packets go there it's
let's say your connect ip it's this
packet came here
that is an uncompressed ip packet let me
just put it directly into my kernel ip
stack this one is a compressed ip packet
let me first decompress it and then put
it into the stack so you're
demultiplexing into your application
parsing logic not too necessarily a
different target
i think what you're talking about david
this is not demultiplexing in the sense
of going to a different piece of
hardware it's demultiplexing in the
sense of going to the piece of software
that knows what to do next with it
yeah
um exactly i i just wanted to kind of
make sure that everyone was on the same
page about that sorry another clarifying
question please no no yeah those are
extremely helpful thank you
um
cool and so
what does this means in in terms of the
like design requirements that we're
talking about earlier um
the so it's clear that this has
this has this multiplexing
for the definition we just talked about
it supports this well it's clear that
intermediaries are not involved as part
of this at all so
we are you'd be able to deploy this
later without having to modify the
intermediary which is really cool
um
it allows you because it's done at the
http datagram layer to
have extensions such as benz mtu
discovery extension that you can write
once and then use for web transform
connect udp and connect ip
uh it has this view latency property
thanks to that separate capsule but i
want to insist a little bit on the
optionality because that's been the
sticking point for folks who
don't want this concept to who don't
want to implement it
so i did i went through the mental
exercise of
if we took all this like the
multiplexing context all this body of
work and said and ripped it out of the
http datagramsdraft and created like an
http datagramscontext
extension draft
what would be the foothold that we need
to make sure the
we can
like ship that later
and the only thing we need is those
capsules
that allow you to send
things before you know what the server
supports
and so right now instead of having just
a datagram capsule
uh in the draft you would need so you
would move the datagram with context
capsule to that extension draft but
you're still left with two in the base
draft there's the datagram one which
might or might not have the context
and the datagram without context one so
conceptually you know maybe we
if we split it out of the draft and we
didn't want to have the word context
anywhere in this draft we'd call it
unextended datagram
and we would just require
implementations of http datagrams that
are not extended to
parse both of these capsules in the
exact same way whatever you do you get
one or the other you just take the
payload and you parse it as a payload um
that's the only kind of foothold we need
and an extension can kind of slightly
tweak these semantics and say well the
datagram capsule might have the context
id if it's negotiated but the unextended
datagram capsule never has it and
that'll that's the little
the kind of the hack that allows you to
send things
during
like the um before you've gotten the
responses so
my general idea is
we've managed to pare this down to kind
of the simplest thing possible the only
extensibility joint that we require that
is a burden for implementation that
don't care
is that they need to understand two
capsule types instead of one and put the
exact same machinery so you would put
you know two switch statements back to
back uh when you're parsing um
and i think yes that is
the end of my long ramble about uh all
these things
now uh let's bring everyone in for
discussion um in particular
are there requirements that we've
discussed here or that we haven't
discussed that you care about and that
you want
or are there properties of this system
that don't work for you for some reason
or do you have any other random thoughts
comments questions uh and i think like
we have some agenda time i haven't been
keeping too much track carrick you can
tell me how much more we have but we
have some time allocated for discussion
here
please come on up to the mic line
go ahead eric
so i think we're going to try to time
box this to about 15 minutes
and
when we get to the end of that we'll see
where we are if we've completely face
planted we'll go from there and if we
haven't then that's wonderful so let's
try and keep comments as short as
possible to let everybody get some time
in
vinnie go ahead
uh you know ideally the the less complex
this is the better so i like the idea
that you've kind of constrained some of
these things um
i assume just standard all the proxy
authentication methods will work with
with mask is that a correct assumption
uh absolutely so
mask uh in particular in this case uh
connect udp but all there are things
we're discussing are traditional http
requests and responses
uh like so connect udp now we're using
extend connect we'll talk about that in
a minute but
you can send any http header alongside
it including the pre-existing
authentication headers so absolutely
that just works that way
empty
not all right um
i can't even see myself
i can hear and see you though
it seems it's uh dark where you are as
well
very dark mode as alan said so um
this discussion
do you mind going back to the last slide
where we talk about the requirements
uh this one or the one that has just
this just has a summary right you've got
a couple of points here um
and there's there's a lot here that's
bound up with the design of the
different protocols that i can be using
the h3 datagram stuff
uh
and i've been
sort of
convinced back and forth throughout your
discussion of all of these things about
the
the virtues of some of these other
things but ultimately
uh what i think we want here
is the ability
to send a stream of data to the other
end bi-directional
and associate a bunch of datagrams with
it and that's it
the ability to fold stuff back in the
ability to add extensions the ability to
identify that this particular datagram
belongs to this particular subcontext
is
something those protocols can deal with
and
if the intermediary
understood that protocol then it can
participate in that if it doesn't
understand that protocol then it
probably has no business
in participating in that protocol
and we can have a much
simpler design here and probably a much
simpler design all over
if we just have
those capabilities that means no
capsules period
and that that would be something that i
think we could probably
make work
so
uh let's pick on that um one of the and
actually i didn't talk about this in the
slides because that part has been in the
draft for a while um so
we have a datagram capsule
and the goal there is to be able to send
datagrams over
versions of http that aren't http 3
and
a pretty common deployment model that
people have talked about here is that
you're going to have http 3 from the
client to the first intermediary in
other words your front end and then it's
common for folks to use let's say http 2
from the that intermediary to the proxy
and
if as a client you're sending your
datagrams in a quick datagram frame the
intermediary is going to have to convert
those into a datagram capsule to be able
to send it to
um the
the back end in other words the proxy
and
i think that the idea here or at least
in the draft as it's currently written
is you have a capsule
that is the datagram capsule
and the interpretatory speaks that
because it's going to need to do this
conversion and and then kind of you're
done that way you don't need to reinvent
this datagram capsule for each protocol
um is that what you're suggesting
i'm i'm actually suggesting that we
reinvent them
because that
it's not reinventing them i think the
idea is pretty simple uh but the
the protocol that the the intermediary
speaks that does involve
folding datagrams into the stream or
pulling them out again on a hot by hop
basis is something that can be
negotiated
on a hot by hot basis this is something
that what transport already does
you're you're talking about lifting
stuff out of these protocols that are
specific to those protocols and and
putting them in in a framework and then
imposing that framework on everyone who
uses datagrams in http
and i think that's a poor choice
so
that makes at the end of the day were
the question there is do we want to
have a common way to do this across
protocols or do we want each protocol to
do their their out uh
my general sense and i see more people
getting in the queue so um is
it feels silly to have everyone reinvent
the same wheel uh when like
suppo folks seem to like capsules
because you know how can you get any
more simpler than a sequence of tlvs
um but yeah i i see that we're we have
you and i don't necessarily agree on
that one
all right i'll jump to ben in the queue
hi
i
uh
there's a lot going on here i think that
it is getting a little confusing because
we're talking about multiple layers that
are really quite independent here so i
think a lot of people following this
presentation um
may not have
have
caught that the the datagram format
types
are
pretty much unrelated to the capsule
discussion
um that they they run end to end and are
not connected to that
um
i do think that we need to be clear that
there are there are two kinds of
intermediaries that we're actually
discussing here we're discussing
essentially
smart intermediaries and and sort of
dumb intermediaries
so we have
smart intermediaries that that can do
this kind of
http version conversion magic
with interleaving and de-interleaving to
convert to like merge datagrams into a
tcp stream or something
we also have dumb intermediaries that
just forward
things directly
and both of those are fine
but the the case that gets you in
trouble is dumb intermediaries
that are trying to talk to an h2 back
end so imagine that i'm an intermediary
i've advertised h3 datagram support to
my to to the clients because i do
support h3 datagrams
but
uh
there's one of the back ends that i talk
to is h2 only a protocol comes in i
don't even know what that protocol is i
don't know if it uses capsules
and so
i can't forward these datagrams and i
also can't signal that
the datagrams have failed
that's the
that's the case that worries me the most
uh
and it i i will just float that if you
think that all of this is too
complicated
um
you know
this complexity a lot of this is because
we're effectively reproducing a lot of
the functionality of web transport
in my view
because we need it and so if you think
this is too complicated
uh
i i would suggest weighing the
alternative which would be to run all of
this over web transport
all right thank you ben
ecker
all right um
so
i think perhaps we have some
disagreement requirements
which is i don't understand how you get
into the state then suggests which is to
say you have been configured
with the
you'll be you've been configured with
the url and settings of a of an endpoint
that you're connecting to
that endpoint that should not happen if
there's a distribution embed suggests in
which the european configure with that
and
then the back end doesn't work simply
should not happen but you should not be
configured with it and if it does the
answer is within an error so it's not
like only discovery here is happening in
settings because we're not discovering
like it's not like we're discovering
that you can use you know compression we
were talking about a specific service
which configured the client either via
some mechanism it was advertised by the
server so what i'm saying is don't do it
say simply not configure system that way
and the problem will go away so um the
the word intermediary appears in this
document on 30-ish times it should
appear zero times and the right answer
is that the um that the front that the
front end the thing which you initially
quit connect to
should um advertise only things that
make sense and if and it is its
responsibility to translate the things
that make sense to it things make sense
behind it and so i i i guess i i'm
persuaded that any of this machinery is
required um so i i guess that and so so
i i think that would be my put um and um
i i i think that probably that is that's
preparatory to like any discussion of
how to actually implement the
functionality you should see the
desiring here
thanks i mean that's uh in the sense
that um you know folks want to deploy
this behind
front ends so intermediaries uh one
potential design is what you're saying
is we terminate everything at that first
hop and conceptually then there's no
more intermediary because you say that
any protocol that supports http
datagrams
must kind of terminate that request it
can send another request behind it if it
wants but conceptually those are no
longer the same one
i don't think that particularly
simplifies things and my main concern
there personally
is that it means that now you can't
anytime you want to extend anything you
need to modify the front end as opposed
to just the client in the back end and
given you know software update cycles
aren't always the same on front end and
back ends you that could prevent you
from deploying extensions down the road
and that so that's why i would prefer an
approach where some of this is
transparent to intermediaries which then
means that there's a document needs to
acknowledge that intermediaries exist
i'm sorry i need to repeat that argument
so the
so
let's say for for example let's focus on
web transport
folks want to deploy web transport on
back ends through a front end i think
that's
that is going to happen um
and there are two ways of doing that you
can either say
the request is end to end from client to
back end and there is an intermediary or
you can say what so that's like the
design in the draft right now what
you're proposing i think is to say the
the front end terminates the request
and
if it and it then it creates a separate
disconnected request from the front end
to the back end
um
and so in that what that means is then
you no longer have uh
discussion of intermediaries in the http
datagram's draft because then you have
ngb intermediaries from client to front
end and from front end to back end
separately but then there is no sharing
of state or anything between them
but what that means however is if you
want to add any extension to web
transport
you need because the middle
intermediary needs to support support
that extension you need to modify it as
opposed to only having to modify the
client in the back end
does that make sense that helps yes i
and what i'm saying so i think what i'm
saying is one way to do is to terminate
and the other way is to have a private
arrangement between that between between
the intermediary the front end and the
back end which describes exactly how
which parts of the channel are clear on
parts of the channel are not clear and
that um and that the what's happening
here is you're hoisting all that
complexity on the client um because you
know because you don't want to make that
privilege and they put this between the
server and and and between the origin
and the immediate area but the truth of
the matter is is that there are many
such arrangements in many different many
different configurations and that um
and like and i think the tri the the the
attempting to dictate the behaviors
intermediaries has proven to be
extraordinarily difficult in both hdp
and sip and that um it's far so
important when you're modeling this b2b
ways and that then the bbx whatever the
heck they want and it's simply not a
non-memphis standardization so yeah i
think that i think that that actually
imports into a lot of complexity later
but anyway i think i i see there's a
cube behind me um so i'm going to stop
all right thanks um all right folks i've
heard of building i think we're getting
either close to or already out of time
so uh let's all try to be a bit quicker
uh victor
yeah i just wanted to say that like at
some level uh
the ways just document the way this
model's extensibility for things like
connect udp is that connect udp is a
resource
uh and fundamentally any extension to
connect utps that you negotiate is a
property of an individual resource
uh as opposed to property of the
connection
uh and
to comment on akka's point i do things
that of
proxy to back and require
standardization because in cases like
cdns those are
uh the objects that are
operated by different entities
and even in cases that aren't they're
operated by same entities uh there often
the software is implemented by
uh different people like for instance me
running nginx as a reverse proxy
uh so i do believe that we are
fundamentally
uh
do need to standardize those and that
works for http so that should work for
uh mask
or what so
thanks victor so to clarify what you're
saying uh you you're suggesting that we
have http datagrams function end-to-end
from client to proxy in such a way that
we don't need to modify the interpreter
to terminate things on the intermediate
area is that what you were saying
uh
yes
i i believe that like similar to things
like http headers that
those should be also my thing tells me
to stop talking so i'm going to stop
talking
awesome thanks victor um
alan
uh
yeah so the timer just expired um
and uh there's been a lot of discussion
going around back and forth i think at
this point it's fairly clear that
there's a lot of uh
different hot takes on you know what the
straps should do uh and and what the
requirements are
um and what the what the simplest thing
is moving forward so what eric and i
would like to do is propose a design
team uh to sort of resolve these
particular issues
um
followed by an interim meeting between
now and itf 113 to present the results
um and hopefully drive towards consensus
uh so
if you would like uh to participate on
this design team
uh please either like send eric or
myself an email or just you know
drop a note in the in the chat and we'll
make sure you're on it um
[Music]
david since you've been so instrumental
in moving this strap forward um
wondering if you'd be willing to to lead
the effort um
and and
help make
yeah happy too so
uh folks if you want to like i don't
know apply you know type
dt plus or something in the in the chat
i'll i'll make sure to gather everyone's
names uh and then we can have a side
beating sometime soon um
so or that are you can i
better than i will help coordinate
logistics uh to make it easier for you
all to focus on the technical details
rather than uh
dealing with time zones and whatnot um
so
um
thank you um
uh in the interest of time al and lucas
tell me if you have uh
clarifying questions that still can be
asked or um
or you still like to ask of course you
can ask them
but if the things that can be punted to
the design team uh later on uh i'd
encourage you to do that
all right
thanks um all right uh
lucas you're still in the queue
yeah i just i just want to say that the
decision like people have been arguing
about getting rid of capsules but if we
do that we're back to where this draft
started is hb3 datagram
the whole point of adding capsules was
to support datagram over http 2 which
was a use case people wanted and hb1 as
well so
if we're revisiting that it would make
me sad but
um and i'd want to know why and we can
have that discussion in the design team
or later ones so thanks
cool
um thanks lucas um
all right um
let me see
uh where was i
right
so
i had another question uh for this draft
about uh wait no that's uh there was an
alternate proposal and a discussion on
reliable datagram but i think i'm going
to punt this to after that after the
design team because
there's no point going even resolving
this until we know next so let let's
kind of switch gears and talk about
connect udp for a bit
um
so
where are we with connect udp so the
connect udp draft was kind of on hold
for a while um while we were you know
redesigning http datagrams uh and then
we kind of since we landed on
a vastly different design for http
datagrams i took some time to update
connect udp to
reference that and also to update some
of the discussions we had in the past
and the the main
change there is that um we connect udp
is no longer the connect udp method
it is now the connect udp http upgrade
token
which is the registry of things you can
use with upgrade in h1 or with extended
connect in h2 and h3
so we said we now say connect udp relies
on extended connect which is
uh
rfc 8441 and h2 and a draft that's
currently in the http working group for
h3
and the idea is the server sends a
setting to say i now allow a new pseudo
header which is the colon protocol
header and so you send a connect method
with with a colon protocol
and you send that with connect udp
so that was the one of the major changes
to the draft which we had discussed
pardon me in the previous meeting um
and it kind of simplifies things and
people are saying that it'll also be
easier to deploy given existing um
infrastructure
and then another important change was
configuration of
on the client so let's say you're you
want to tell your web browser for
example to use this connect udp
uh proxy uh before you would just you
know give it a host import
and now we say we use a uri template so
at the bottom of the slide here i have
like three random examples of how you
would connect configure the uh client
and conceptually what it means is that
you
send the
target so the target again is the server
that you want to proxy to
in the uh in the path uh pseudo header
uh when you're sending it and the
important distinction there is
so in almost every http method under the
sun
the authority is the authority of the
proxy
and then the path is how you tell
what you want you know your actual
target what you want to talk to
connect was its own beast uh where
in the authority it kind of in the
authority instead of having the
authority of the proxy you had the
authority of the target of the duality
sorry the host name
and port of the target um a lot of folks
were saying that that
design choice for connect was odd and we
didn't want to replicate that for
connect udp
so here we're back to a more traditional
http design where the authority header
contains the authority of the proxy
you're talking to
and then the
target is encoded in the path um
so right now we have in the draft is a
uri template for this um
uh
so that said um the ui template was
something that i forgot who proposed a
few atf's to go uh when i went to
implement this for the hackathon last
week
it was way more of a pain than i thought
it ever could be um
so for folks that i have read the rfc on
uri templates
they're
very complicated ways of encoding uri
templates and
i mean it's okay don't worry it's not
like anyone has introduced security
vulnerabilities by having mistakes in
their parser before
and so my thought was
do we actually need a uri template here
because
the really cool properties
that we rely on is the property that we
have a your uri for configuration but it
doesn't necessarily need to be a
template because if we have a uri for
configuration it means that
the scheme is decided at configuration
time
and that also conveys the um authority
of the proxy at configuration time which
you obviously need
and it allows you to rely on the path so
for example you could have behind the
same authority multiple paths for
proxying and you could pass in you know
as a http query parameter like the user
name or whatever you fancy
um and so the question is do we want to
uh how do we send than the target post
import that you want to connect to do we
send it in the path with a uri template
or do we say no the path is reserved for
like just configuration elements and
it's send in a separate header um i
initially thought the uri template was
really great but it ended up being way
more complex to implement and
that wasn't great and i'm not sure we
should replicate
this uh the so ui template really made
sense for something like dough because
it allowed you to
you know just type in
your query into like curl and get um a
response like directly from the account
which was really neat that's not
something you're going to want to do for
connect udp
and the other property is when we so in
the connect ip draft tell me we'll be
talking about later we decided to mimic
connect udp at the end of the day let's
try to keep them as close to pos
together as possible but the ui template
parameters were different so
i thought it would be really cool that
you could configure your mask proxy with
one configuration string
but if you're using a ui template you
can't really or you need all those
parameters in there
so if we have a uri for configuration
and not a template and we use headers
you can then reuse them for multiple
mask methods which
i thought would be kind of neat
so i personally would be inclined to
switching to headers
what do folks think about that
empty
here and
why would you move
resource identity to a header
sorry the
we you still need to wait like 10
seconds before your mic starts working
can you repeat the beginning of that
please
so um i i guess the question that you
want to ask here is
what resource are you identifying here
are you identifying a generic resource
that's got the ability to connect to
anything
such that
having
different ip addresses
um
in the url would be a mistake or are you
identifying a resource that has generic
connectivity properties
uh anyway and that's actually that that
is exactly the question that we're
trying to answer from a like so i was
asking it in terms of like practical you
know wine coding matter you're asking in
terms of like conceptual matter but i
totally agree it's the same question do
you are we saying that we are like the
the resource were you know in http terms
the resource that we're going to
is that the part of the proxy that
handles connect udp is that the resource
or is the target the resource and if the
resource is the target then we want
this to be encode like the target host
and port to be encoded in the path if
the resource is the proxy proxying
capability
then we don't want to encode it in the
path we want to encode it in a separate
header uh that's the question we're
trying to answer here yeah but might you
want to have different access control
depending on the destination that you're
going
to that suggests a uri
i mean you can perform access control
based on those other headers as well
right
you can do all sorts of
interesting things with editors
but when you start to use those headers
to identify resources then
they're no longer really headers anymore
i
i agree and and i guess conceptually i'm
saying that maybe the the resource isn't
the target the resource is the proxy inc
capability
um vinnie
a couple seconds here uh can you just
elaborate on how
you envision header parsing being
uh
simpler than template parsing like i
didn't understand that point
they both gonna have the same kind of
parser type
bugs would happen in both right
um no uh and that's a great question i
guess i should have been more clear uh
so right now on the client um
so i need to parse the uri template
uh so the the
uh you you're gonna have to run some
code on the client which as input is
going to take
the configuration
and
the
target so let's say your configuration
is a uri or ui template that's how you
refer to the proxy
and and you're going to take like the
at the moment your browser is saying i
want to connect to this target over
there so you're going to take those two
bits of information and combine them
into an http headers frame
and so
right now
what you need to do is parse the ui
template
uh
in order to like the technical term from
that rsc is to expand the ui template
into a fully resolved uri
and so you're gonna need to if you're
using a uri template look at the line at
the bottom you're gonna need to
understand that that
that is like a level three uri template
where you're gonna have to say okay well
my authority is proxy example.org port
443 and my path is
slash mask
question mark target host equals 1.2.3.4
ampersand target port equals
one two three four and that's that
parsing that you need for a ui template
whereas if we use the uri
regular uri for configuration you
wouldn't need that because you would
take the uri and you would parse it just
in order to split the authority off from
the path you put the authority in the
art authority pseudoheader you put the
path in the path to the header and you
put what separately you got as your
target ip into its new header and your
target port into its new header uh that
also makes parsing on the server on the
proxy side easier
because now you don't need to go and
parse some of this to get the ip address
you just say well i look at this
header and there it's there i don't need
to split it out in any way
echo
oh right i'm waiting i forgot
um
so i mean i guess i don't feel super
strongly about this but i also don't
think that the arguments you're offering
are very persuasive um no you have an
s509 parser so like i don't think like i
mean i don't think like the additional
security like like like overhead of
personal ui template is like is like
that bigger crisis um i i i i didn't
know i do i do know the comments but how
complicated it is i think i thought i
thought lucas's suggestion that maybe
your profile level one would be fairly
persuasive um the um
um i do think from a philosophical
perspective like which i mean is not
necessarily terminative the the header
is wrong um i mean the verb is connect
the the resource is the thing you want
to connect to and if if the if there if
the if the um if what you wanted to say
was um that the thing you're connecting
to is somehow the proxy then that
reaches the proxy then the verb should
not be connected to something else um
and you know we already have this worked
example of regular connect which is how
this works um so i i guess you know
that's like not disposed of necessarily
um you know one could argue that http
should not have been designed the way it
had been designed but um but like i
think you know for trying to if we're
aiming for aiming for some full so i
think that like
i think like the argument you're
offering that like this is like a pain
in the ass like i think someone has a
merit but i think the argument that like
you know um that it's that that like
philosophically it should be that i
think
i no i i agree with you uh i mainly care
because it was a pain to implement
at the end of the day that's what i'm
trying to minimize for i'm an
implementer the conceptual aspects of
http are not my personal
main concern
ben
waiting for audio okay
uh
so
just to remind people uh uri templates
uh mandate full unicode support so
uh a uri template can contain any
unicode code point which then has to be
uh escaped and normalized down to the
uri car set
um
that happens
after substitution so you can have
supremely weird
uh interactions here like a you know
like a rtl reversal unicode code point
that like sometimes appears depending on
the template contents or like there's
unlimited weirdness there
also ui templates can template any part
of the uri you can like template the
scheme you could have like template the
port number you could have like the
connect udp port target port port number
actually be the origin port number or
you could have be a sub domain of the or
even part of a domain you could register
all 65 000 domains like
anything is possible with uri templates
um
it's just a little bit of a warning
i'll just note that there is an
intermediary there's a middle ground
option here where
we say that that everything has to go in
the uri and we actually specify the uri
structure a little bit
rather than just templating it
cool
thanks uh tommy
waiting for audio cool
um
yeah so
i think i agree with what people are
saying um
implementations that support dough
already need to support uri templates um
people who are doing mask probably also
support dough
so it shouldn't be too much of a new
lift um
to ben's point about weird uri template
types i mean i think we you know
if it hurts to do that don't put your
things in the scheme we should probably
have some constraints here to say like
hey we're already using the scheme we're
already using the authority in the port
so like you can't put
your target there sorry
for connect udp i could i can see where
you're coming from here but when we go
into connect ip as you alluded to and
how we want to kind of align these
i think it's a stronger argument for why
these properties are part of
the resource
because you know in something like
connect udp i could very well have a
generic vpn that doesn't have any
constraints
on what i'm connecting to it's totally
open-ended and i have one that only
forwards sctp packets or whatever and
like those
are very
reasonably different resources than i'm
accessing
and so i do think
the logic
is clearer there but then you can kind
of back apply it into connect udp and
say
yeah this really is
the resource you're connecting to and
if you wanted to split up
your server to
think of it as different resources that
you're accessing have different access
control that way it it would make sense
so i think we should leave it in the uri
and maybe just add some constraints to
the crazy things you could do with a
template that are just wrong
okay
uh thank you yeah sounds like from the
folks in the mic line there's some
interesting keeping this in your eye
templates
all right moving on to
our next and final issue for today
um in so in connect udp since now we are
uh
so for for h2 and h3 we use extended
connect uh with uh the pro the colon
protocol uh pseudo header
uh the method is connect the protocol is
connect udp
what do we do for http one um right now
for http one we use uh
the upgrade mechanism
and we so at the end of the day this
mimics websocket which is the only
standardized use of extended connect
that i'm aware of
and so we say okay
same as what socket you can
do connect udp over h1 by using upgrade
but the question is what method do you
use because when you're using upgrade
conceptually you don't look at the
method you just look at what you're
upgrading the only kind of purpose is to
say
oh
what happens if you accidentally hit a
server maybe who doesn't support upgrade
like
what flavor of failure would you prefer
to have in that scenario
um
and so right now the connect udp draft
says you use connect with upgrade
websocket says you use get with upgrade
um
which one should we use here
i personally don't have an opinion uh
do folks have thoughts
all right well if uh no one cares we can
uh keep it as we have it today in the
draft and we can always uh change that
later uh martin
so if i understand correctly um
if if we ran into a server didn't that
didn't
uh
understand upgrade then we would just
end up
sending datagrams that would become
random bits somewhere and a tcp
connection coming out the proxy whereas
with get it would just sort of return a
404 or something correct
um
let's see well with get you would end up
sending a get with a body which is
technically not allowed uh so
yeah i guess that that would probably be
it where with get you would end up well
not necessarily a 4-4 because someone
could sure yeah
yeah
some error code
i mean that seems strictly better than
like this
undefined behavior with connect not
undefined but just the sort of spewing
random bits out
yeah well i mean uh from uh and actually
uh so connect uh you send a uh
http one connect you send an authority
without a path
whereas here you would send connect
with there would be a flash in there uh
and
now you know
it's it's always hard to imagine what
kinds of bugs exist but someone would
probably sending what's with this flash
to get at her info or something
so i'd expect that it would fail
spectacularly at the dns resolution or
trying to parse the ip stage as opposed
to
trying to create an an outbound tcp
connection
um
just to that something well i i don't
know we need to like analyze the failure
path here but um and you know
other people written more hp departures
than me but like i mean i would just say
just whatever has a more deterministic
and less goofy failure path would be the
way to go here thanks i
totally agree because
what we the new thing we build will work
whatever the connect the method we use
it's just if we hit right so maybe maybe
we just need to do some homework and hit
a bunch of existing servers with what it
was this would look like
and see in what way
things things fail uh eric
it seems like if we're going to be using
extended connect for a bunch of things
and we may want to be
going to figure out what we're going to
be happy with living with
long term there and pick something and
be consistent i guess another option
here would be a
new method like connectx
um
agreed i think we should be consistent
between connect udp and connect ip and
other things uh i would prefer not to
create a new method because that's
always work and
um but
yeah let's let's definitely be
consistent uh empty
so one option here is to ask http biz
what the answer is because
this is a
they currently are examining
in some part
when with the http 3 integration
or extended connect
maybe this is a generic problem for http
and not one that mask needs to
preempt
that sounds great to me uh okay uh
unless someone dislikes that idea i'm
gonna take the action item to email the
http
list
asking them what they think
um and i see some plus ones in there
perfect all right um and this
brings us to the end of this
presentation uh thanks everyone for
listening
and uh
good uh good luck until dawn for
everyone who's with me on the west coast
all right thanks everyone and
over to you tommy
all right
okay hello everyone um
i will be presenting uh
a new unified draft for
ip um ip proxy support for http
all right so
uh connect ip i think we've heard this
many times bounced around the working
group before
why why is this different
and mainly the difference is that we
have had
many different
versions of the proposals from different
authors
and over the past couple months those
different authors and myself have tried
to join forces and come up with a single
proposal for what connect ip should look
like
so
yay for unification
just to recap
the motivation for all of the connect ip
work in general
we want to be allowing
you know truly generic ip proxy through
an http proxy
not just what we get from connect and
connect udp
which is limited to tcp proxy and udp
proxy
and this
if we look at the requirements document
which was adopted and worked on by this
group
a lot of these use cases are what we
traditionally think of as vpns
whether those are
kind of just a user using a vpn for
privacy or remote access into an
enterprise
site to site vpn
that's a lot of the driving use cases
that constrain the space
but you can also think of this as just a
connect-like proxy for an arbitrary ip
protocol
and to that end you can have a lot of
similarities to connect
and i think as the authors looked at
collectively a lot of the differences
in perspectives were because
we had
some perspectives coming from the purely
vpn side and some coming from the
uh side of saying this should be a
connect
protocol for arbitrary ip so i think
we've tried to reconcile those two
worlds and
end up with something that is fairly
simple and straightforward
so as we discussed um with the authors
as we were coming together here
we um
agreed on a couple things as the scope
of this
so
you know right now it's defined as an
extended connect protocol mirroring
connect udp
we believe that if connect udp changes
its approach
this should also change its approach so
we just want to keep those things
aligned as much as possible we want to
follow the best practice there
for
kind of simplicity getting the base of
what connect ip is the proxy always is
dealing with entire ip packets
that are contained within the content of
http datagrams
compression could be done in some future
draft but the base definition is always
entire ip packets
then another key thing
that the authors agreed upon was the
fact that
it sounds quite simple when you think
about it
the connect ip document should be
concerned only with things that exist in
an ip header itself
and that's the kind of the unit that
they are operating on
so
the different endpoints can request and
assign and route
based on fields that exist in the ip
header so that's the source address
that's the destination address
and that's the next protocol
we could also add other things
in if people decided it was necessary
but these are kind of the core elements
that make sense
what is out of scope is
trying to do any ip header compression
now that should be an extension
things like icmp signaling we agreed
should probably be another document
um
that would be useful extension to have
both for ip and udp
connect methods
and there are also fancy things we could
do in which we could get a bit more
next protocol aware and understand what
we do for different port allow
lists for different vpns but that should
also be an extension
okay so what actually is defined in this
document and it's not too much
thankfully
first there's the um the upgrade or
protocol token connect ip which mirrors
the stuff that david was just talking
about as connect utp
so that's really just a lift and rename
currently it's also using a uri template
to be able to scope
things down if necessary
now
in this case it doesn't make sense to
talk about
a target
name and a target or a target host in a
target port because there are no ports
instead you have essentially the target
host that you want if you have one or
you can have none
and a target next protocol if there is
one or it can just be generic and get
anything
there are
a couple different capsules defined
this is using capsules uh really as just
a negotiation
mechanism so that you can
after the time of request
over the stream be able to add and
remove addresses and routes
and so there are three capsules defined
only there's an address assign which
allows one endpoint to tell the other
side
you can send from this address when you
want to generate a packet
you can also have an address request
which is i would like to send from this
address or this
subnet
and then
in the same way that address assign can
define
the source address for packets a route
advertisement capsule defines the
destination that a site is allowed to
send so you can say you are allowed to
send to anything essentially that falls
within this routing table i'm going to
give you
and then the last thing that's defined
in the document is
currently it's called the datagram
format because
the http datagrams document still has
these um but
essentially it's just saying the thing
that goes within a datagram
is a full ip packet
that's it
extensions can do something else if they
need to
um one one of the concepts in here that
we discussed a lot that isn't
necessarily um
immediately obvious is that
there are uses for limiting the routing
and being able to communicate that you
aren't able to route a full tunnel
so a lot of the the simplest vpn use
cases that we think about are
essentially when a
client device receives
a single address or a prefix to send
from and then it can send to everything
in the world
however there are a number of different
use cases where
that can be more restricted maybe you
have a split tunnel vpn or you're just
only trying to reach something very
limited on the other end on the other
side
so
there are different ways you can limit
the scope of a tunnel
you can
in the request specify that you only
care about a specific
target and protocol
either endpoint can also limit what the
other can send from
with its address assign and then the
route advertisement capsule itself can
limit the set of destination addresses
that an endpoint can send to
and besides being a good mechanism for
access control and being very clear
about what's going to be allowed
this also allows a proxy
um that's operating a bit more like a
normal connect or connect connect udp
proxy to be able to share source ip
addresses between multiple clients
so if
one client really only is trying to talk
to a specific host
or a specific subnet um maybe it's
it's not trying to open up
a completely
uh full tunnel scenario then you don't
need the same type of
ip address provisioning requirements
that you would as a normal vpn
so that's essentially the protocol as it
stands i have a couple examples here so
we can just see how this looks so the
traditional vpn setup
i have a client behind my proxy my vpn
server
it has some ip address ipc
that can go out to the world and talk to
any arbitrary address so the way this
would look is
the client starts at connect ip
currently it registers this datagram
context
that
may and hopefully will change
then the other side can just send back
to 200
and say hey you can send from this
address and you can send to
pretty much anything um you want for
that address family
and then at that point
the two sides can send datagrams back
and forth to each other and those are
full ip packets so this is quite simple
you could also have a case where the
client
is only interested in talking to a
single host on the other end maybe it's
just trying to open up a sctp flow for
some reason
and in this case
the protocol works exactly the same
except you can get back
um a very limited
route um that only is the thing that you
requested to connect to
and at that point the payloads are still
full ip packets but they're only going
to be ip packets that are going to that
one particular host
and then the last example we have here
is just showing um
how
you could use this even if you're
connecting to a specific
host
that you can receive different address
families
to send from because we like supporting
both v4 and v6 and you can get a routing
table that supports both
anyway so that's the protocol um
sorry
no not all that is supposed to be proxy
not server right just making sure that
no no
yes
trying to keep things less confusing i'm
confirming that you mean proxy there
it should yeah we can change it to proxy
it's it's the server
from the for the
master connection i understand that but
really yes yeah i mean i think proxy's
probably the terminology i've seen in
current gdp it might be good to unify
that as well to make sure we're not
going
yep that's a good point
thanks
all right so that's essentially the
scope of this
we've tried to keep it very simple
so i think the questions to the group
now are is this the right starting place
for doing connect ip
and if so is this ready to adopt
or do we have other
questions that we think need addressing
echo yeah i think this is a this is a
pretty good pretty good starting point
uh i think it's uh uh probably good
enough to adopt um uh i sent some
testimonial comments in email um last
night thank you for using them
completely because there's not like
midnight but um or something but um
actually i think it was more like you
know three but um anyway um yeah i i
think you know uh uh um you know these
are all things we could hash out in some
later discussions so i i think this is a
good starting point
great yeah and yeah and i did see your
comments thank you for them i think
there's stuff we can discuss um
i think we can go either way on a lot of
them yeah i'm not proposing to discuss
it now unless for some reason the chairs
are like in time primitive
any other comments
david
um i just wanted to
say like i'm i really
i wanted to thank tommy for all the work
he's been spending as editor to unify
the two connect ip proposals here um i'm
very happy we've that we've landed on
something that like works for everyone
so just wanted to thank tommy for all
the hard work here i'd love to see this
get adopted now that we have like kind
of one proposal with the backing of a
lot of folks as opposed to
like two separate ones pulling in
different directions like we had at the
last atf
awesome thank you
all right and
yep it sounds like in the chat people
are generally supportive of this so i
guess chairs do you want to do something
now or later
yeah so
uh thank you tommy for the presentation
and we're gonna use the show of hands
tool so everybody find this tab and
go
find where this is but effectively the
question we're going to ask is is this a
suitable starting point for working
group adoption and you're going to be
able to raise your hand if you think
that it is or you can actively choose to
not raise your hand if you think that it
is not so we're just going to do one
show of hands where you can choose up or
down
and that should be open now
give it a couple of seconds for people
to find the buttons
all right
so we seem to have pretty strong support
for using this as a starting point would
anybody who chose to not raise their
hand like to join the queue and
potentially give any thoughts or
reasoning as to why they
made that choice
and we'll take that as a no so we will
take this to the list and confirm on the
list
but thank you all for raising your hands
next up
we have
ben are you ready
alright if you requested
it's the one immediately to the right of
the cue button
we do not yet have audio for you either
yeah ben you're muted okay how are we
managing slides
uh you can share them yourself if you
click the little share preloaded slides
button
uh
looks like a piece of paper
yeah the button is called ask to share
slides for us non-chairs
indeed
uh okay can somebody tell me where that
might be
the joint
up left just to the right of that
okay ask to share slides
all right you should now be able to pick
your slide deck and then you can advance
at will okay
great thank you
okay lovely we see
so uh this
is about this presentation is about an
individual non-adopted draft
uh
that that i wrote in response to some
previous discussions about path mtu
discovery
and it's it's very much premised or
phrased in terms of the
in terms of the current
uh
datagram format and capsule system
so to the extent that the design team
decides to make changes there
this also would need to change
so
ping is an http datagram format type
and pings flow between a client and an
origin
or we can also call it a proxy
intermediaries if they exist
don't care about ping they are
again in the terminology of the h3
datagrams draft these are opaque
datagrams
and they look like this
each datagram contains a an event number
and some padding and the response
contains the next number and no padding
very very simple
they can go either way once you've
established a context for them they can
be sent and echoed in either direction
okay why
the main purpose of this is
inspired by connect ip connect ip in
order to be a fully compliant
implementation of ip needs to be able to
supply some
minimum mtu
and so this gets tricky if you're
running over a link that's already at or
close to the mtu with any of the links
on the chain between the client and and
the back end have have low mtu
then
what uh currently the way this
needs to uh the way you can solve this
is
by
by sending that datagram reliably well
okay so we can get to that in a second
but
uh
but basically endpoints need to
be able to detect that there's some
datagram that like
the ip layer is is officially able to
rely on so like this datagram is less
than 1280 in ipv6 so it is guaranteed to
be deliverable
but actually it's not because when you
wrap it in all of the mask overhead it
exceeds the underlying wire mtu
so we need to do something we need to
change what we're doing but in order to
do that the endpoints need to know
something about the path mtu and because
of the presence of intermediaries
using for example the mtu estimated by
the underlying quick session
is not going to be good enough and there
are even more complicated intermediary
arrangements like
when the the back end is actually
speaking to an intermediary over http2
uh so
there isn't even really a
there isn't really a relevant transport
mtu at that's on that hop
but this is a very general
anything that uses datagrams
needs
in general to know something about the
mtu of that datagram path
and
also it's very very common to need to
know something about the round trip
times and
packet loss rates
and so it's a very general problem and
so it seems appropriate to have a
general solution
so
this draft
is seeking work group adoption in mask
although
i don't think it's ready to ready for
that especially given the given the sort
of turmoil and the underlying draft i
think we're going to have to
revisit this
i think it's
it's most valuable as a as a test case
so
you know these are
problems and this is a this is the
solution that kind of falls out from
from one set of design choices about how
datagrams and formats work
and i think that hopefully that can help
inform the design team as as they
consider that design space you know try
to figure out well what what are you
going to do about these mtu issues
do you want a solution that looks like
this datagram ping or do you want
something else
and another thing that's important to
note here is that in the design
as considered here
it's
it's important for clients and servers
to be able to
identify when a datagram needs this kind
of protection it needs this extra
special end-to-end
reliability because it's too large for
the path mtu and be able to send it that
way and right now we don't have
actually a mechanism in the current
drafts that that really allows that
and so we've had some discussion on the
mailing list about do we need a
mechanism like this or do we need to
require intermediaries to
adopt some more sophisticated behavior
in order to
in order to make it more make it
possible to deliver those reliably or or
indeed do we need intermediaries to to
adopt a less sophisticated behavior that
would enable
that
that end-to-end property
so yeah that's all i have for
slides magnus
yes so i i think it's an interesting
mechanism i don't think it really solves
the
the toughest case at all of the
perfect discovery especially
if you're going to run the plpd of your
math tunnel you get the
oh before i can tell if the actual flow
is supported or not
you're going to have a delay because
first you need a probe what is the empty
you supported
and then you can make a decision about
it so it's i think it has some
significant downside to try to solve
that issue but
it may be
solving it faster of course means more
complexities in the intermediary so
yeah so there's there's this
learning mtu is always asynchronous
um you know it always takes you never
know it before you start you always have
to wait for it and the question is how
long do you have to wait
yeah but it's one cr cracks i think in
this which is particularly the mask or
any tunnel protocol in some sense in
that
you will know what empty you are for the
first hop for the first quick cop in
something yes
you can quick on that on that first half
yeah
but
not intermediate and forward until the
end of the the peers let's say the mask
appear
that's the that's where you run into the
trouble when you have intermediaries
on the http layer so
yeah but i guess it's for continued
discussion of this i mean how we solve
it and and i think it's one of these
requirements that should be considered
in the design team this quest is to
include that mtu question there
yeah and one thing that i would want to
emphasize is i think this illuminates
one of the questions that's um that's
come up a lot with the design team like
why can't we just use settings frames
for everything
um if you try to use for example if you
try to use settings frames to
communicate the
the
mtu
of the h3 datagram so the setting says
this this proxy supports datagrams up to
this size
then uh
that
implies knowledge of all of the paths to
all of the back ends of that proxy
so it's not just about compatibility
with all the proxies it's actually also
about all of the network elements that
stand between them
okay
ben we still have martin in the queue
sorry martin yeah oh
and um thanks for
thinking this through i think if nothing
else has been a useful exercise to
exercise this as you said but um
i guess it
what i'm wondering is
if you have been under if you have a
protocol running over a mask
yeah
i mean typically these off-the-shelf uh
protocols will presumably have their own
plp mtud
uh mechanism and they also have the
advantage of not only probing the the
mask mtu but also all the way to the
origin server so
um
what is the actual utility of having
this utility
in mask itself
sure so the fundamental problem here is
that
the iprfcs say that in order to be a
compliant ip implementation you must
have
an effective mtu of at least 1280 for
ipv6
and while
transport protocols running over it are
allowed or encouraged to use path mtu
discovery they are also
allowed explicitly to simply cap their
datagram output sizes at 1280. if you
never produce output greater than 1280
the ip specs say that you do not have to
do any path mtu discovery
and so if we want to be a compliant
implementation of ip
then we need to always provide
functional delivery of packets of size
1280.
that's a that's an actual if right we
have the option of saying this is an
almost complete implementation of ip
and one thing that it doesn't quite give
you is the mtu guarantees and so you
actually need to do some some pmtud for
smaller sizes
all right
thank you ben
and lucas is five slash four minutes
useful or do you want to punt to next
time
i think i think i could squeeze in 15
slides in two minutes
go for it
cool
oh no i'll push the wrong button
uh
i don't want to do that
here we go
uh okay um so this is about data ground
priorities which is probably a low
priority given what the mask working
group wants to work on uh this was
originally uh intended to be presented
at the last meeting but got uh pushed
off because we ran out of time hence why
i just wanted to disease any time here
to mention it and to see if anyone's
really interested or if we don't care
right now i have a draft an id um it
didn't take much work to write up
and it's going to expire soon so if no
one's interested we can just leave it
and maybe mothball it and pick it back
up when when the time's right if that
time ever occurs um so briefly there's a
lot of background here we won't go into
that but
uh quick doesn't specify anything about
prioritization of anything it says you
probably should do it but uh it doesn't
specify how the datagram draft that's
now opposed to the uh w g lc is uh
defines the frames but doesn't talk
about priorities of them uh hp3 doesn't
define any priority signals either and
that's post working group let's call um
and the the new mask http 3 datagram
draft that we have
also doesn't say anything
so so we're kind of bouncing around we
have different issues raising a
different draft that have all been
closed to say well you know
the princess is in another castle kind
of thing go go look somewhere else
you've got people like pointing at each
other and saying well you know maybe we
should but i think with all the drafts
we have today we're fine actually we're
not saying anything about priorities
and so that raises some problems for
anyone who's tried to implement
something based on datagrams where
they're being multiplexed with streams
as well or even
logical flows of datagrams might need
different priorities and uh you know
they have different needs and they need
to be scheduled differently otherwise
you know certain kinds of problems might
happen
so i wrote this draft just to get the
idea out of my head this is based on the
extendable priority scheme i don't
necessarily think it's the only way to
do things or the right one
but it is a way
um to do things uh we'll skip the the
recap here
the philosophy of this design is that
datagrams may have a different priority
than the stream that they're related to
and this is only at the http layer
nothing else
so there's some flexibility here but uh
sensible defaults there's no per context
prioritization which kind of skips some
of those problems that came up earlier
um
yeah the proposal is just a new
parameter
that gets defined a similar scale to
this urgency parameter that's already in
priority kind of decorates things and
inherits from it this is all in the
specification
uh
the question i was going to pose last
time is should we adopt this but i'm
thinking right now
the question is who cares uh
you know we could have an adoption
discussion later on when people have
actually read this um maybe mask isn't
even the correct venue i'm happy if
you know with whatever people might
think if they've had any time to look at
it so
that's it
thank you very much for your time
uh i see tommy in the queue
yeah i have time for a clarifying
question um
you mentioned how you know explicitly
this is a different priority than the
one
on the stream data
just what is the rationale for not just
letting this stream
priority be the priority here because
like for connect udp it's almost all
going to be datagrams anyway
uh it is if effectively allowed if if
you say that you support this scheme as
like a a server for instance and the
client doesn't send anything the default
is to inherit the stream's priority so
this effectively just makes that
abundantly clear that that people would
go with that kind of flow you could
equally say that without putting it in
any specification
okay
all right um
sorry to abruptly shut the queue but
we're at the top of the hour at the end
of the meeting and folks have to get to
the next one so
thanks everyone for your time comments
so we'll follow up on the list with
actions regarding the design team and
um
uh adoption of connect ip and uh we'll
see you at the interim
next
meeting and on the list
thanks all and thanks for notetakers