anyone testing
okay
[Music]
it's funny i can't hear any of you
all right while we wait do we have a
volunteer
for
um to be a note taker
who wants to be the note
log out log back in
uh
i'd be happy to take notes except during
my slot again if you
if you
don't have another volunteer you like
better
jake you got the job
um
and does anyone want to take notes while
jake is
presenting
kyle
you
you up to the task
yeah i'll i'll do it awesome thank you
all right here you go
cool we hear you greg
thanks kyle
i do see my slides are you uh
are you not able to see them in the
in the uh
meeting uh
okay let me give you the link i'm
looking at
the i do see them in the meeting manager
jake um okay but where i don't see them
is
you know the uh the little button next
to join the queue
um
slot it's the uh
share slides
uh okay
do you see that button
yeah
for some reason your deck didn't make
that list
that's exciting
only your deck though
so
um are you cool to present yourself uh
just share your screen
yeah yeah that should be fine
okay
all right
we can wait
greg how much longer you want to wait
here
give it another minute or so
yeah another minute i mean agenda's
pretty small so
this is uh really the jake show
it's a head count now
it's gonna be way shorter than my slot
there uh i think so
we should have
plenty of time left over i hope
and you guys can see the the note well
right now
noted
great
i'll mute that
all right i think we're a couple minutes
in so i think we could get probably get
started here
we've got
that all-important 18th person
so
um
all right well welcome to uh mbondy for
those on the west coast thank you for
waking up so early
um
here is the notewell
please note it well
here's our agenda for today
uh didn't render as nicely as it
did in powerpoint
um
any have anyone have anything to add or
bashing to be done to this agenda
okay
all right so we'll get started with um
here's the list of currently active uh
working group docs
um
the
wi-fi multicast problems draft after uh
a long long journey has finally um made
it to its fine final resting place as
our published as rfc 9119
congratulations
um thank you for to mike
for getting us across the finish line
with all those final discuss items
covered and that whole team
warren and
others who
other authors congrats
the
yang models draft
sandy do you want to have anything to
add here sounds like you said um
you updated it based on the yang doctors
and a couple other reviews um you'd like
more one more review any um before uh
a working group last call anything else
sandy you want to add to that
all right
we'll assume sandy's good with that
update
we have the
multicast of the browser drafts
jake is going to cover these uh today
the telemetry draft
how you mentioned that um there's a plan
it's it's related to the um iom draft
doc that's soon to be at rfc
and he planned there's a plan to update
the draft after that and resume we'll
have more discussion on that next ietf
and there's another doc
redundant ingress failover
and
yisong will
provide an update on that one today and
we'll probably
unless there's major objections
begin a working group adoption call
after that
so that's um
everything so far uh that was all the
drafts we have
um first up
let me stop here
tommy uh you are up
um
you can share your screen or you can
share pre-loaded slides the share
pre-loaded scroll slides button which is
next to the
join q button works reasonably well
requesting i'm okay here we go thank you
all right so we invited tommy
yeah so let me um just give up um a
little intro here so um we invited tommy
from uh apple uh to join us um
uh ios announced um
recently
uh a new entitlement program for
s applications that want to
um
utilize multicast um and uh
there were some folks in the working
group who are kind of curious about this
process so we invited
um tommy on to basically describe the
the process and you know what uh what
led to it and um
uh any experiences they've been having
um at apple
with uh support of multicast so with
that tommy i'll turn it over to you
all right thank you um and this should
be a
pretty quick
update here
but
you know we do have time in the agenda
so i'd be happy to have
discussion questions around this and
suggestions of what you'd like to see
going forward
all right so what are we talking about
so
specifically uh
this new entitlement
um
when an entitlement for people who are
not familiar with it on at least mac os
and ios is
essentially a
privilege that has to be signed into the
binary of the application when it's
before it can be released on the app
store
and
some entitlements you can just kind of
check a box this is one that you have to
request
so it's a little bit heavier weight
anyway this is part of a
general
suite of changes that we did to add
restrictions around what you could do on
the local network um
and
these are all aimed at trying to improve
user privacy from various types of
attacks
and so this was introduced in ios 14 so
that means um we announced this
in um our developers conference which
occurred in
june of 2020 so
a year a year and a half ago
and the release came out over a year ago
at this point so this has kind of been
the reality for
the last little bit
and
there are several different changes
that were part of this uh
local network privacy feature overall
first
all apps that are communicating with
hosts on their local network whether
that's unicast multicast
using apis that will trigger
local network interactions
they all must get user permission before
communicating
so you know it's assumed that if i'm
using an app
sure maybe it's talking to the internet
into the wide area network but before it
can start you know poking into my
tv and my printers around me and trying
to do stuff
the user just has to give permission
this really makes
a lot of local network interactions more
consistent with other
kind of nearby device interactions that
required a similar privacy permission
such as connecting to a bluetooth device
etc
so a lot of this is about
consistency and user awareness
the next category of change is that
you know most
of the multicast discovery
that occurs
on ios devices
is using system apis for multicast dns
using dns service discovery on apple
platforms that's branded as bonjour
and
any app that's using that
must
declare kind of at compile time the
static list
of all of the different
service types that they plan to use so
they can't
use any service type that's outside of
that list they can't just start doing
wild card discovery
and then the third category which is the
one that we're talking about here
is
specifically for
multicast and broadcast
um
that's not using any
system api like what we have for
multicast dns
an app must have an entitlement because
this is a
kind of even more privileged and
powerful operation
so that's what was restricted but you
know why
why was this done
um a lot of this was done in reaction to
a growing trend that we saw
in which
very
surprising apps
were doing some arbitrary scanning
of the local network
that
seems really to be
a kind of a user tracking device that
was becoming more common so we wanted to
make sure that that did not grow further
often times
functionality like this can be embedded
within sdks that apps link in
to get some sort of functionality
and so this is not always code that the
developers of apps even realize is being
run within their apps but instead
some third-party library that they had
linked in
that you know maybe in return for being
free was collecting some data about
users in user location
um
and so in general
you would see
when we turn this on first
uh
and just to say hey what lights up what
starts uh scanning your network on
different ports and on different
addresses
it was quite a lot
of apps doing it uh very frequently
and you know some of these can be
legitimate use cases but
a lot of them also could be efforts to
detect
what devices were around what types of
things would respond on the local
network
to create a signature of the local
that the user is on currently
we had
for years before
uh prevented apps from getting directly
at some of the ssid or bssid
information to know oh the user is
currently
you know in this location as a way to
evade getting location permissions
if they didn't think that the user would
grant location tracking
now in general you know as i mentioned
for bonjour we
kind of started preferring
apis where you could list a specific
service type um so
this
guarantees that the app developer is
aware of what they are doing um so you
know if i have an app that's trying to
talk to a printer or i'm trying to
discover a tv that i can display
something on
indicating
at the
app compile time yes this is the type of
service i'm trying to do or maybe i have
a custom service for my own special
devices or i'm doing some peer-to-peer
game
if if they can specify here's the exact
scope of what i need to do
it's much easier to guarantee that
there's not other code running that's
doing uh nefarious things or trying to
do a full
address and port scan
of all devices around
and then the other
um
aspect here is that
there are uses of multicast that we see
as kind of the most prevalent um as
we've been granting these entitlements
by far the most common is oh yeah i just
want to use
um ssdp
which
is you know pretty old protocol not
standard has a lot of security
vulnerabilities and
this is also an opportunity to tell
people hey if you're just trying to do
this discovery
going and using a system api that is
more audited and using a standard
protocol like multicast dns
is going to be a better route if you're
building a new solution so we're also
trying to have people move
to preferred protocols when it's
possible
um so going forward
you know apps that do have legitimate
reasons to need custom multicast can get
approved they just need to
um fill out a form to say
what are they trying to do and
almost everything does get approved
generally what wouldn't get approved is
um
if you cannot sufficiently explain
like
what address and ports are you trying to
use like what what what is your why does
your app have to do this
um or if they're trying to
get around the
multicast dns
service type restriction by
implementing
a custom stack that will let them scan
all multicast services around them
and
another part of the philosophy going
forward is that
the common sdks you know like what we
have with uh you know there's google's
casting sdk
we worked with them to move to using
system system-supported apis and
implementations of bonjour that don't
require applications to get entitlements
and i'll
point out that
right now the main thing that you can do
with an entitlement that is multicast is
bonjour
multicast dns
that doesn't mean that that has to stay
a fixed
list if there are other things
that become
very relevant for ios apps
that should be kind of built into the
system and saying ah well this multicast
protocol should be supported as kind of
a native
protocol
that's going to be generic for a lot of
different apps that could certainly be
done and that would kind of fit into the
model of making sure that
generic
apps aren't accidentally putting in some
tracking software into their apps
so just some other resources
uh we have our 2020 presentation on
local network privacy in general and
then
probably more interesting is this
separate uh
article we put about out about how to
use multicast
we offered some new apis around doing
multicast that year
that were part of our network framework
and then it also documents how to get
the entitlement
and that is all i have
do you have questions
hey jack
yeah hi tommy thanks for uh thanks for
this um i did have a couple of questions
so uh
the mdns you
you seem to say it was bonjour or dnssd
but does this distinguish between like
just using a dot local name that also
generally uses mdns
right so
if you use a dot local name
that does not require any special
declaration of
what service types you're using
the special declaration is just for
browsing
um since
that was more like okay you know people
are using this to scan and you know
there definitely are
um so you have to also uh apply for the
entitlement
if you want to be able to do wild card
launcher and there are
you know utilities that are just about
scanning every device around you and
reporting this is what your local
network looks like um
but we recognize that those are usually
pretty niche
products
uh so
so there's nothing that prevents
scanning just according to a bunch of
dot local names for example or is that
just a sort of separate
configuration
i mean
yes you could try to brute force like
every possible string in the world um
no note or known devices i guess does
require the user permission so like the
user will get a pop-up of do you want
to scan your local network i see okay
um
but not not separate for each dot local
name right or no no okay
okay yes or no
interesting all right um
my other question
my second question maybe uh are there
any differences between uh ssm and asm
or between uh
globally or locally scoped addresses
uh
no no we're not uh doing any distinction
there
currently okay
uh and then
my last question was um
do you are there any sort of
known changes you anticipate to this
going forward or you think this kind of
covers uh
the the sorts of
uh efforts you've seen and um
and nothing else would be necessary
uh
no no changes
kind of you know we just released ios 15
that stayed the same um
that's pretty stable
i i would love to hear from you or from
people in the group like
you know what kind of what raised this
to your attention and
are there use cases
that you think should be common enough
that they shouldn't require an
entitlement and what is that and how
how how could we create a graceful path
for those
uh sure i can answer for myself at least
there was a an article forwarded where
someone was kind of bemoaning the extra
bureaucracy
uh
for um
for just you know experimenting with
multicast in an app development sense
saying kind of multicast is hard enough
i i think that had some sympathetic ears
on the list when it was forwarded but um
you know
i mean we've been working on the on the
security and and noting the
uh i don't know if you saw the draft
insect dispatch uh right after your slot
but um
uh yeah there are some sort of
potential exposures
and so um
you know yeah i
i didn't think it was necessarily a bad
thing as long as it's not a sort of
onerous process so um
just for my own opinion there yeah
and i think there are some other takes
on it
yeah um
i i know that you know there are
a handful of people who've requested to
have
kind of complained um
for just for doing experimentation you
know our
simulators macs work just fine without
the restriction it's really just ios
devices here and
they specifically
um
you know oftentimes
if there are requests for
just like oh i'm doing experimentation
is it's often just to discover like
peer-to-peer like hey where's the other
iphone around me and for that
i think we try to steer people to saying
hey just use the system apis for
discovering
your app's service nearby
that works just fine why are you trying
to invent
a brand new discovery protocol that's
not dns service discovery it's not ssdp
but you're like rolling your own thing
like that's you're probably
making it harder for yourself and
experimenting
sure
um
uh let's see
i guess i i suppose you're not willing
to name names on uh sdks that were
that had suspicious behavior here yeah
okay just thought i'd ask
thanks
all right any other questions
should we hand it over
so i think um
i understand the entitlement process for
for apps
uh as you're sourcing
so
as just as a user if you want to join a
multicast group there's no entitlement
for that or do you just get a pop-up
that says do you really want to use
multicast or so can can you just explain
what that looks like for not the app
developer but the app user is there
anything on their part that they need to
do or that just works yeah
right so yeah again an entitlement and
the list of bonjour
or multicast dns service types
that's all a developer problem they just
have to bake that into their app
so assuming you have an app
that has permission to use multicast
because they got the entitlement or
they're using multicast dns
or they're just using unicast
on the local network
the only thing the user will see is a
one-time
pop-up to say do you want to let this
app use the local network
and you can say yes or no you can go
back and change that decision in
settings at any point
but
that's it it's pretty
coarse
grained at that point of saying
yeah
is this expected the app does get to
pre-populate that prompt with an
explanation of why they use the local
network so the user can say like oh
they're doing this to
do x
and then
we've encouraged people to have that
show up when you're actually starting to
do something that the user wants not
just like at the time you launched the
app
but that's all the user would see
they generally don't have a way to
kind of manually
you there's no you know terminal console
on these devices so they can't like
manually
do some commands that will trigger
multicast
gotcha and um
did uh
you mentioned this this you
this isn't a um your your act
can you give any kind of um
experience in terms of
you mentioned are there
lots of apps that have applied for this
entitlement did you say you guys haven't
denied anyone uh no
i mean some people
there there have been some we have not
approved
um
the vast majority get approved because
the vast majority are legitimate um
gotcha yeah i mean it's it's a bunch i
mean i
i think it's thousands
great ask a question there too and so
the i'm not looking for names but those
that you said that were not approved is
this uh in in the general case because
you can point them in the direction of
something already exist rather than
reinventing something exactly exactly
often times they're like oh
the the most common case is
they were trying to
roll something on their own and they
would say oh oh i can just use this api
to discover
the thing around me great i'll use that
that's that's the most common reason
that they don't end up getting the full
entitlement because they don't need it
any other questions for tommy
all right well tommy thanks for joining
us and thanks for sharing this
information very very helpful
thanks everyone
um next up is jake
let's see i think this is my first time
sharing
the screen so let me
see if i've got this figured out
properly
okay
uh
i think i can
let's just say
yeah okay that's fine
curious was that your compliance
uh button you used
yes that is
that is uh actually no that's that's the
request screen share
okay
told me at the beginning there that uh
that for whatever reason my particular
slides
were not in the pre-loaded list
for some reason i was probably late
um
right so uh thanks i have just a short
update this time um
in the notes i added a link to
my uh last presentation
uh at 111 um if you do need any
background on these drafts and kind of
what they're doing i'll refer you to to
take a look at that one instead i don't
want to run through the overview of them
each time so i'm just going to skip that
um
mostly what i'm going to cover is the
sort of progress in
that's relevant to this work that's been
happening uh externally uh though i will
touch on the um
relatively small amount of
uh
forward progress on these docs and um
and
discuss that a little bit
and then i'll go over kind of what my
next steps are in this direction
so the first thing is that
the multicast community group has been
meeting regularly um we did some some
stuff at tpac
uh actually i probably should have
posted the um
the link to the demo video that we put
up but that's that's there in the list
of demo videos that they had for the for
the tpack meeting uh
under the web and networks interest
group
uh the web networks interest group in
particular
had some nice things to say about about
the multicast community group and the
multicast use case
that they presented during their tpac
meeting
i like the slides there uh there's a
good
uh there's some
[Music]
sort of uh
openness to this in the web community um
the most compelling
part of that seemed to be about
the
or at least the one that got the most
discussion was its impact on some of the
sustainability efforts that are getting
started
um
and uh
it's it's relevance to that
uh to that point um
which i i also highlighted in some of
the stuff that i talked about there
um
and i also had a presentation with the
web transport working group
uh it was a sort of
minor part of their of their overall
meeting
um but uh i've opened an issue
requesting uh that they add multicast as
a
as a use case that they would consider
valuable uh which would be uh relevant
feedback to bring to the ietf
web transport working group um
and and other relevant parties that is
under discussion uh i've had a follow-up
meeting with the chairs and and they'll
be uh discussing it in the working group
uh to see what they think about that but
um
that is uh sort of
necessary steps toward moving it to a
browser use case
um
i also presented yesterday insect
dispatch
about uh
so the background on this uh as i think
i went over before but i'll i'll
recap it here
we
submitted an intent to experiment to
chromium
their feedback was it's not ready
in particular that it needs
confidentiality uh
as well as the integrity and
authenticity that that
was part of the design
um
in addition to uh implementation
weaknesses that are going to need to be
addressed before it can be part of the
browser even behind a command line flag
totally reasonable um but that's that's
going to be some work
but
but really the the sticking point was
more about the design
uh before even getting to that point and
uh
so confidentiality with multicast comes
with um
some complexity uh we tried to capture
the complexity in this uh in in the uh
draft k rose sex dispatch multicast
security
uh and we are looking for a home for it
so insect dispatch their uh the
recommendation for dispatch was that we
uh start a mailing list it's to be
determined whether that's going to be
the msec mailing list for the previously
existing
but uh closed multicast security working
group
um
or whether that'll be a new mailing list
and that uh i'm supposed to follow up on
and we'll be sending an email today to
kick that off
hopefully that mailing list will be
like in place uh by the end of the week
i i
i hope but uh we'll see and we'll see if
we can get any security experts on it to
really dig in on this we did get some
discussion from ecker on the list he's
sort of
against the general idea
and is making the case that nobody's
particularly interested
uh and so there's no reason to look at
it um
but uh
the objections he raised to it were
at on the technical side were not
particularly compelling
i was not able to give him uh
compelling evidence that anybody is
interested either so
there might be more such objections if
we kind of get to that stage
but i thought the discussion overall was
pretty good i think he had some
some good points of feedback that we've
started incorporating into the draft
to cover it but
this is uh
this this security draft is
not just about the web uh
safety model the web security model as
it relates to multicast it's uh you know
we we intend to do both web and non-web
traffic
uh at akamai um
assuming this you know
actually reaches a deployment stage
uh and you know
at the moment it's looking likely that
it will start with the non-web traffic
um
where we have uh
you know we'd be relying on on receivers
that have some deployment footprint and
this would include uh potentially
uh some of the gaming platforms for the
game downloads and also some of the um
sort of uh
smart tv on a stick uh platforms that uh
that some of our potential partners
have some deployment footprint with
um
and
and that doesn't have to be web traffic
although being a part of a web api and
doing
the same thing in all the cases might
actually be kind of handy
but not strictly necessary so
we might be able to continue moving
forward with some of that and i think
the target still has to include the
browser
at least from our point of view for this
to be worthwhile in the end because
there's such a
uh you know some of the peaks that we
the peak traffic days that we hope to
address with this work
uh come from web video traffic and we we
do need we do think we need to address
it
um
but uh the the sort of next steps on the
mailing list front with a security
question
uh would
i mean the the target i'm i'm aiming
towards ultimately is
well ultimately is uh rfc is with
consensus behind them but uh to get
there it would take a buff to open a
working group uh again either the
existing mtech or
a new uh you know
maybe
broadcast media
multicast security or some such i don't
know but um
because it's a slightly different uh
security model than the previous msec
work did so it would either have to come
with a recharger or it would have to
be a new working group i'm not sure what
the what the right answer will be there
and that'll be up for discussion
i'm not sure it'll even happen it's
going to depend on
security people agreeing that this is
worth looking at
um
and that they'd be willing to
to contribute but we'll try to get that
discussion going uh between
now and march or
uh whenever however long it takes
and uh
and hopefully get somewhere but that's
kind of the
uh what it's going to take to get uh
into browsers it looks like because um
the the sort of
not encrypted at the
at the level that the browser
would be maintaining the encryption
uh is sort of a non-starter
according to the the web security review
that we saw
um
[Music]
the the sort of
uh the apis we're looking at are listed
in the
multicast community group charter in the
w3c thing i think i had a
link to the github there which has a
link to the page anybody can join that
group by the way it's not restricted to
uh to people whose companies are paying
w3c membership fees and whatnot um
i i should say anybody whose company
permits them there is a contributor
license agreement
but you can as an individual if your
company allows it make a
make a free w3c account and join the
group so please do if you're willing and
able uh if your company is a member of
w3c then you might have to get uh
approval from somebody who's who's sort
of
heading up your
participation with w3c but uh for most
participants that hasn't been too big an
issue uh i'd love to have uh
anyone who was interested enough to come
to this meeting might be interested
enough to follow this too um i'm
particularly interested in people who
would be uh interested in doing the
testing and uh implementation work as
that as that progresses
uh but that'll be a slightly faster
cadence for updates than the
then the
mbondi updates
so please do participate if you're
interested there and
willing to look at the browser work
let's see the uh some of the early
feedback that we saw from the chat
insect dispatches uh is suggesting that
we're probably going to need to have the
uh the actual protocol proposal
um so for that we're uh i'm intending to
start those experiments uh
you know towards the end of this week
and uh and to get these uh rolling in
the in the coming months
um i'm aiming to do a sort of uh
something inside quick to fit into web
transport
so this would
very likely be something based on the uh
on the on the pardo http over quick
draft
um
but uh
there
are likely to be some differences with
that because i want to make sure to
support datagrams to make it
such that existing multicast apps can be
deployed with just the sort of web
transport shim around them at the at the
sending side and then received by the
browser
that's what i'd i'd like to aim for
so the doc status
for
the mbondiwork i've been
uh engaged on some uh some internal
stuff
uh in my in my day job and on uh
some of this uh
some of this uh you know w3c and and uh
working out the security stuff
uh so i've been kind of low activity on
the drafts that are active here but i
did do some updates in dorms
um
i i
uh
when i checked it against the reviews
i'd had seen uh particularly
particularly rashad's
uh as young doctor there was an
unaddressed comment that i'd left out so
i added some text to address that
so i think as of now it's got all the
um all the updates that people have
recommended
if anything
has been left out that somebody
mentioned then please do
let me know if you see it
it probably would make sense to get at
least another review if possible um but
uh
you know i would love to move this to
last call uh at some
point and have that uh
you know get the
uh the forward motion that would
that would uh make the other two that
build on it uh more
considered more stable
um
likewise the mnat
uh i got a few comments but nothing
really um
telling me to change things i think
uh and so i would love to get
uh reviews on that one in particular as
well
uh ambi i think i'm gonna be um
i'm gonna be messing with as i work on
the security stuff so uh
so if you're looking to hold off on
something you can hold off on that one
uh once storms is done then then see
back would be uh certainly
a useful one to do as well but
my priority order
on reviews if you're willing to do them
would be dorms and m-net and then uh see
back and then ambi at this at this stage
um
let's see uh the in in m i'll highlight
dnssd
uh in particular the um
the uh
the search domain portion of that as the
as the part of the architecture that
worries me the most
um because
it proposes to have a
a
mnat server
that's discoverable by clients inside
their home networks and
uh via dns sd
and this requires
um
probably passing the search domain as a
as a dhcp option into the home network
which
i i am not seeing
uh currently i mean i haven't done a
wide review but uh currently it
anecdotally does not seem
super common that home routers are are
implementing that functionality today
um it might be because the service
providers aren't aren't
advertising in their dhcp offerings but
this is a space that that i don't think
has been
necessarily that
that well explored and
and would bear some um
some investigation
uh
and and possibly alternatives the other
the main alternative i've been thinking
about is uh is
making a dns rr type
that would describe an sg
i haven't tried this i haven't started
writing that draft yet but that might be
a reasonable way to
to allow a local isp to
manage the mapping from
what a client app tries to join
to a
a locally addressed
sg so
that might be a draft that will be
coming to along this work
it's more drafts than i was expecting
when i started
uh anyway um
in terms of next steps
i'd like to consider
dorm's last call so i'd like to open
that up for discussion
now um the other thing i'm going to ask
for is to put dormancy back and ambi
into a cluster
um
the cluster being so that they can refer
to one another and would would become
rfc's together or in the order
and order determined by by their lack of
loops
um
and then
there are some
new docs that are going to be relevant
to this that seem likely to to be on the
way
due to the security feedback we've
received
and it's going to depend on sufficient
interest
being demonstrated
so if you know anybody who is willing to
talk about this stuff then make sure to
get them on the list when i send out the
invitation to join the msec
or whatever it will be
uh so with that do please um
give me any questions or comments that
you cut
sandy
hi hi
i don't hear you yet
uh sandy you're muted right now
hello can you hear me now
yeah no i can hear you great
okay thank you i i forgot to mute myself
and i have a question
about the security multicast
i'd like to know if the multicast
multicast security will have some
affection on the
transport protocol
like mrd or pim or
other things
uh i wouldn't expect so
mld and pin
and beer
i would expect to be unaffected
in fact
i would i would hope that we could even
consider so the trans the the
security considerations
the sort of initial direction that i
have not yet written down
uh and is highly subject to change is
that um
going to be trying to make a
a quick version of this that uses a
symmetric key
for encryption
um and maintains the same kind of uh
out of band the unicast
based uh secure
transfer of hashes to do the um
uh
to do the
authentication of the data channel of
the multicast data channel
um
and uh
and the main difference with what it was
before which was just authenticating
generic udp packets which may or may not
be encrypted
is that the udp packets for this part
would be uh sort of specified as being
uh quick encoded with a with a
with a symmetric encryption key that is
passed over an associated quick channel
um
these
uh
the intent is to make it so that um
so that
existing udp payloads from outside
uh from like existing uh
multicast applications would be possible
to translate into these uh udp
uh packets as
as quick datagrams and be transported
with multicast that way
so that the applications themselves even
legacy applications would not have to
change at all we'd have to do is run a
receiver sort of
inside the sender that would pump out
the quick packets and the authentication
hashes and the authentication hashes
would have to be distributed to the
to the receivers
in a much smaller channel than than the
data channel
in the same way that ambi works but uh
in terms of the the transport under udp
um
under the the quick layer of udp uh
there would be no change um and so
anything that that works today uh mpls
beer
pim uh all these things would be
unaffected
okay
i see thank you
thanks
one of the pieces of feedback was um
or a gating factor was
um and i forget who you mentioned which
group
that know that there is a lack of demand
for this
um
is that
is that pertinent from a technical
standpoint and that seems like a
subjective discussion uh and and also
one that would fly in the face of the
existence theorem that you indeed have
enough interest to be doing all of this
um
so can you so so
is that a thing can you just say nobody
wants this so we're not going to do it
yeah if you can't get enough interest
then they won't open a working group for
you in general um
but uh with that said um the specific
case
here was with regard to the multicast
security um
for
browsers in particular the main question
was like well what browsers are going to
take this they came from ecker he asked
that both on the list and in the in the
cube insect dispatch
and
made the point that
i mean yeah i've been talking to some
chromium people but they're not eager
for this
uh and
seem pretty lukewarm on it
um
you know i i would i would like to get
some uh counter examples
to speak up and
uh
and and say that
i mean i think you know
my response
to his uh
to what he said was that well they think
it's probably not going to work they are
skeptical of this and and
this is
perhaps a justified position based on
multicast history
um they want to see
uh
you know
more people engaged on this before
they're willing to
to dive in
i assume um
and that's some feedback i've gotten
from others in the in the multicast
community group
um so i think increasing engagement
would really show something worthwhile
here i i should also maybe mention uh
you know
i'm starting to get a little bit more
traction in this like virgin media
previously had given us permission to to
say their name is having been involved
in our our trials and evaluated the tech
and uh
supportive of moving it forward
um
since then uh or since last time i've
gotten
uh so comcast said
that they would uh they think this makes
sense for the future
um
you know i i rate them
like they haven't looked at it as deeply
but they do think that this uh as far as
i can tell looks promising and they
would like to see it happen
um
likewise uh
i've i've gotten
so dizone sent an email to the list but
wasn't uh it wasn't forwarded to the
sexist patch list but i do feel
comfortable saying
i i think i will probably be forwarding
it
uh but they they also said that they're
supportive of multicast standardization
um amazon also said did give permission
to say that we'd talk to them and that
that they would like to see
uh multicast capabilities happen
in
uh
news that may or may not be related
design and amazon uh each individually
have signed major
uh major sports
delivery deals
uh for the upcoming years in the like
um you know
10 billion and 2.7 billion uh dollars in
euros respectively uh that they've
publicly announced um
and uh
you know
and suddenly they're interested in
multicast for some reason or at least
tentatively interested uh so i mean
you know will it happen
who knows right but
um but but these are names that
that are not nothing
uh i did not get a chance to say that in
sex dispatch my time was pretty short
but um
but we'll probably be discussing it a
little more
i mean you know people can have an
opinion and have it be wrong
but also there's not it's true that
there's not
perhaps sufficient demonstrated interest
and that's going to have to change in
order for the working group to really
happen for the multicast security i
think
um you mentioned one of the other um
concerns was integrity um
does that mean
is that where you need this you need to
spin up a
new working group or is that just
another draft that
uh so ambi actually
addresses the integrity and i don't
think anybody said that it wouldn't work
um i do think that uh if we do open the
a multicast security focused
uh working group that it would make
sense to move ambi into that working
group instead of here
uh
basically just for the um
for the sort of security expertise that
would be bringing to bear on it
um the original
uh
claim when when we
you know when i talked to a security ad
and asked whether it would be reasonable
to to work on it in mbf or whether it
would require
another working group in the first place
uh was that well it's not using any
you know novel
uh crypto or authentication approaches
these are all well proven in other
contexts
um and so as long as we and it's not
something that that has like
uh tricky trade-offs on crypto agility
we just have a very uh
you know extensible sort of
framework for for how to identify which
algorithms we're talking about via the
yang model
um and so the
you know it's it's
there's not many concerns on the
security side with the with what was
proposed
but i think having worked on it since
then um there might be some subtleties
in like the way the the course model
works that um
i'd like to get some more security
expert eyeballs on really before before
i'm comfortable with it
um
so
you know and you know that that was also
part of the advice that we're gonna need
to have a security uh review of it but i
do think it it would make better sense
if there was an existing
msec
uh working group to live inside the msec
work uh working group
uh once it's there so so i i might
propose moving it if possible at that
time
um but you know ju that's just a heads
up for the future there's nothing
actionable i'm
suggesting at the moment
besides like making a group
so
the integrity stuff that's needed is in
ambi it's just a matter of getting more
eyeballs on it
uh yeah it's an ambi uh
and there might be something very
similar that would go into the quick
protocol itself that would be a
a little more integrated instead of
purely out of band
um but i think i'm
gonna do it by just referring to ambi i
just i need to
to experiment with that part and
actually write it and
and write it up
so that's that's kind of tbd but yes the
the integrity approach outlined in andy
as far as i know is
is looking like it's going to do the job
for integrity
great thanks any other questions for
jake
well thank you very much should i get
back to notes
okay frederick and
uh saba and frederick um you guys are up
so you can choose to
um
you can choose to share your screen or
you can click this button of share
preloaded slides
uh we would like to share the screen
okay i see that you are
seeing the screen do you see that
presentation
yes
thanks
frederick it's your part
i'm frederick
you're me
i'm sorry so thanks for um
for the invitation
my name is frederick louis and uh i'm
here with uh mate who are working on
behalf of uh
association which is the pan-european
company
managing the pan-european network so
we are here today to talk about an
exciting project we have started
in 2019
which is related to implement a
routine stack based on
various data
next
so this is the the agenda uh
very uh quickly
we will explain what is the rar free
router project
um
the lessons learned
um regarding brfc
implementation
the the first br experiment that has
been launched in
and that has been completed in 2021
um
the next point is the amt
relay implementation based on rfc 7450
and
since today we have a we have a very
very
exciting br combined to int
implementation experiment that you you
can
that you can test by yourself
and listen uh the the
the hunger and harvard music and a bit
of conclusion next
so basically what is the the r project
um it's essentially uh combining three
uh components which is the control plane
uh multiple data planes
and create a specific interface between
each data plane and the control plane so
so the goal is to have one familiar
platform that is able to propose
multiple solutions and each solution
will address
specific
research and education use case
and
the
the the fun part is that uh multicast is
one of this use case next
so for now we we we have multiple data
planes based on p4 we have the vm v2
target which is the virtual p4 switch
where you can train yourself and look at
the r free router code we have an
implementation for tofino which is
basically essentially the same uh the
same code base
except the fact that you you will see
more um uh pragma
uh restraining uh features because the
the ace the tofino asic is of course not
unlimited in terms of resource compared
to a virtual switch
we are looking at fpgas
and which will come
soon next year
we have
a backup tcp damper library and also a
dpdk
we have some discussion with um
in order to pro to provide the npa
letterplane
next
so how do we test the the the code uh
essentially we we have deployed uh for a
set of four nodes in in in europe
amsterdam frankfurt budapest and poison
and um so far we
we attracted some attention to various
organizations from around the world and
now we we are pleased to welcome more
nodes in
north america and south america we'll
have some new nerds in um in indonesia
in korea for example
but uh and all of this corresponds to a
beer uh an entire beer domain that that
is spread
onto the the p4 lab
now i think uh it's about the floors is
yours
ah okay so uh what we have
so first of all
we introduced beer in mpnshank
observation that is this rfc
um
basically in software mode that was the
first that happened and then i started
to experiment with my whole network uh
with the beer be
how can it transmit my my frequently
broadcast music sessions
and uh
this is this is what we mentioned that
the the building started in
in
2017 or or about about the time then
when this refc became public
um for for this to happen uh we did
obviously the interior gateway protocols
to to have the the beer
load index and the b mpls labor base um
flooded within the domains so this is
via b right size extension and b ospf
extension as a
started to appear in inframatter this is
uh again the same 2017
when it happened
this is the point where i would
call you if if you if you uh implement
a networking operating system and uh and
you would like to and and you have beer
and would like to do some
interoperability testings then uh
feel free to
contact us we are we are very happy to
do some hacking with you um the thing is
that beerus spf extension have already
uh interrupt tested
uh with isis extensions uh
fortunately the viral shark
decoded it
very well
but uh not yet
tested in interrupt
times
uh regarding the beer bgp draft it is
also supported uh since the beginning
when it when it started to appear it is
uh it is basically when you when you
send the prefix then uh you cannot touch
a beer attribute to it then that
prefix will behave as as it's
s as it saw in the in the igp domains
with uh with the b index that is uh you
can uh
and you can
send multicast
pockets to that uh
that prefix or or parts of the prefix
and uh
and
that
that will happen in beer and
constellation in this case
also we support the um the requisite
version of this that is you get a prefix
without would be uh attribute but uh but
the underling uh root have a beer index
then
the pockets uh also we sent in in the
rank of selection
and and the last thing that we we
support with beer
things that is a appear at this p in a
in a b rank of session it is uh needed
for me just because
this is how i i am with cast my uh my
music in the so-called global table
and last but not least this year we we
as we started discussing with uh with
andy and and and the guys from uh
juniper then he added the empty
functionality
that is uh we have two
different parts and we have the amtv and
also the anti-gateway
which also tested for interrupt with the
video rank you know the erc
and uh and also with the
public
amt rays that are provided by uh
provided by various universities in the
states and as far as i know they are
running uh
here that we have
are tested regularly
over ipv4 and ipv6 addresses
expirement
so basically as i said
i am running a small home network with
some
25 or so nodes and
and then all are
participating in the beer domain
which is now uh since last year
connected to the
b4 test that frederick mentioned before
and the main difference between the two
is that my local
whole network is mostly running on tpd
credit appearance uh
via the
p4 test but the adjunct is running on
hardware-based switches
and
since there are still it is
cross-connected uh with uh
cross-connected
and we are doing uh inter uh
entry as uh
beer set up between them
since that time
other other prefixes are also exchanged
but there are some
at least one prefix that have been
indexed sent from my network and this is
how at the moment the p4 tests that have
a constant multicast rule
uh you can you can check various
states of my home network links on this
page
and uh
directly
one of the regular uh
broadcasts of my office music is is
recorded on this
video on this demo link which which is
uh basically
a unique hosted video at the moment but
it is showing you that uh when i when i
press the play button then then what
happens is in the network so
i show you that uh the end nodes start
the igmp this is a triggered by the vrc
startup then it it get
sent through the
beer core within a beam uh anc
observation this is the
pier beam this is the pmb
interrupt and uh and all these multicast
pockets within the core are transmitted
in in a beer
at the moment
and
and since we have uh the dpdk data plane
i think it is it is two years old now
then since then
all this happens within the dpdk
replication here
and uh
this uh whole network is connected to um
to
public accessible uh
amtv uh this is uh the last line uh how
you can start vrc to uh to use that am
tv and then you can listen through the
integrated uh
my my alcohol music which is streaming
uh
basically
always
and
that's it
um
guys do you see the terminal yes yes
so two things that i would like to show
you here is uh one part that is the emt
uh
gateway at the moment
uh i have started it uh with the roka
router that uh
that i spawn up and when the meeting
started it's basically uh
at the moment this very very stupid
configuration it points a default
multicast through to
to to a random address which is on the
tunnel interface
and tries to join that multicast group
which is sent out obviously through the
through this next hope which is on the
tunnel interface basically it points to
the
just interviews
and the triangle this
this is where the amt pockets are sent
this is weaving at the moment and the
forwarding vrf this is where the deck
oscillated multicasts are handled this
is the v2 vrf at the moment
and
the things that i would like to show you
here that is interesting
when i when i showed the multicast
routine v to vrf for the given group
then
the pockets and and the bytes are
increasing
uh slowly
and this is uh this is a constant
stream here
not too much on this node to show you
because this is just an empty uh
gateway a local gateway that can
decapsulate an amt stream and uh
um basically it can it can handle the
multicast pockets to the local lawn
receivers if there are any
moment
it is just
receiving the pockets and then discards
them
so not too much
to show here this is the server part
[Music]
and this is how an amt
an amt relay that is
configured in free router some basic
security things that we added uh
just today
uh to other only eight clients from a
subnet a total of
256 listeners at all
and
some access some creative meetings on
the new terminals and and loads dropped
to drop the attempts
finally an interface to bind to and uh
and the vr have to bind to and an
interface that you can uh that that will
be cloned for all the clients
this interface is the points toward the
integrands that are
[Music]
the starting emt sessions at the same tv
uh dummy app address here and access
group to only accept
igmp pockets viva stream multicast igmp
here and the same for v6
the same for v6
and
after after all these things
at the moment this client is connected
here so this is why i have an amt
access interface cloned from the
template here
so
and also the multicast group operate
here with the
with one interface is uh
on on the outgoing interface list
and also the pockets and the bytes are
increasing on the group
it have it have an ingress interface
here which is uh um which is a beer in a
bird interface
sorry
but i can show you the
and the npr's forwarding
counters
so this is uh this is how it looks like
and you can spot that it is extras in
bites and it increases
if we if we take a closer look on this
river then
it is uh it's basically an ospf v4pr
label
uh it did not sent out at all um
and it is a beer local b string which is
our
beer index expressed in in the in the
beer b string here
and
we have some peels on this uh on this
beer
label basically they are the same
they are the they are the different
nodes in the in the igp domain
and they are expressed
with these b strings uh as you can see
we we have two routing interfaces here
and also the pockets and the bytes are
increasing
okay i think that's that's from the demo
part let's see what else we have
um
yes sir
sorry again i was muted
so just to
let you know that
in terms of status we we are in a very
good position
knowing that we started in 2019
we are now in the in the
in the situation where we we need to to
calibrate all profiles so uh if we want
to have a pure p router uh we have to
calibrate it in order to fit uh most of
the uh to find a baseline that would fit
off the most of the use case in the in
in our research institution customer or
organization
and uh of course br is a multicast
profile and beer profile is a must-have
because we have some users who have a
multicast enable application
and and this is um
why we think that it's it's really great
because this uh this p4 lab is giving us
a way to to be ahead in terms of
innovation and new implementation and uh
just to let you know that you are free
to test this amt relay that is public uh
you have
uh club amateur showed you the the link
and we can of course
share the link with the
domain list
um
the good news is that uh we are we are
we are we can use this uh fifa app to to
validate two things uh the first
solution of the program was to to
provide a way to link users to multicast
feed which is the role of the interior
but
we think we think that we can solve the
other problem which is
tying new source adding new source to
this multicast platform so that
we can solve the other part of the
program which we which is also which
will provide an end-to-end path to the
uh source toward the the the receivers
and that's that would be great because
um
we really think that this
i wouldn't say a cost effective solution
for multicast but
just to know that this runs in in an
overlay in an overlay
on top of a real network is a very great
asset to to provide
maybe a new way to provide multicast
services that is totally independent and
safe in terms of operation operational
point of view
and this is uh also i think back in the
time when i was working in the
engineering team it was a
kind of scary to activate multicast
because at some point you you you don't
know if you can geoparadise some
resources from your backbone and not in
this case this is totally not the case
we are free to to exploit uh to explore
new to new um new solution and uh
feel free to to to reach us and i'm not
sure sub i should have the link to the
to the current uh
world map
yes i have
can you can you hear
so here this is the the the lab
that is a spawn in
in europe of course
but if you look at the west part we have
we start we have start we are starting
to have new nerds in the uh in the us on
the west coast and
north america and in latin america and
we will leverage a new submarines cable
in an entrepreneurial capacity but just
to let you know that all of this is a br
domain that
that can be used for testing
and also one very good point is that um
if you are implementing a client
um
we have this br domain is ipv6 enabled
so this means that you can
implement your ipv6
int client
and test it against this before lab if
you don't have a specific value to test
it
and i think that's pretty much about it
thank you any questions
any questions
jake
yeah that is uh very cool guys uh nice
work
um
so these there's a couple of mailing
lists you mentioned i think are these
for uh
is there a
what a charter or purpose for these
mailing lists like i'm not i'm not clear
i'm interested in following this work
i'm not clear which is exactly the right
one
that i should sign up for
uh i think i'm i think i'm on at least
one already uh but i'm not sure if if
that's uh for uh
but i'm not sure
yeah sorry i wasn't clear you are
already on the on the multicast
that is between
us but um
i i was mentioning the
the mbondio
mailing list
so people can freely test it
get used to it and approach it discuss
with us how we can improve things
because for sure there are things to
improve uh security encryption or
new
number of
parallel client
and the good news is that we this mt
really has a 10 gig connection toward
the follow
and we should we hope that soon we'll uh
move to 100 gig so we can have a very
tremendous uh
toy
to play with and uh and the good news is
that the more client we test
the more interoperable it will be
and even for you it's a
it's a win-win situation so if you are a
pure vlc developer i would like to
create an ipv6 vlc client
feel free to reach us it's for you
just let us know sometimes there will be
breakage and so on but
uh
it's um it's here for
to for everyone to um to progress
on the contrary we can add new we can
think about how to to bind new source
into this platform
even if it is an experimental platform
but in the end
the idea would be to solve this problem
where we we
we bind the source and the receivers
and
after that we will give you all the
recipes to create your own platform
in your own company whatever
with your favorite hardware
and
that's pretty much about it
that's that's outstanding uh do you have
a sort of timeline in mind for um
for when you'll be ingesting external
traffic
and uh and is that is that gonna be
using the uh the sort of amt and uh
and dryad solution or is that going to
be or did you have something else in
mind
and for the empty
the second empty in the p4 that was just
started but as as i showcased in the
demo uh we have the empty gateway
functionality that can uh pull traffic
from uh from an existing gmt relay
and uh
as i saw and uh on the
m2m uh
i cannot recall so there is a public
list where
there are some uh some interesting feeds
uh i think a a nasa video with 8k and
and some other universities from the
states which are accessible through ent
i i played a bit back in time with them
and noticed that internet2 has shut down
its um services so basically
we have three today's
uh behind the the
domain that that is the amtv
and and some sources are reachable
through one gateway and i'm sorry one
really and the other source is behind
otherwise but i uh
so this urgent entv is just started
today but i i have plans to to populate
some some static tumors to these uh
these uh public other emt rays and and
they have a constant uh constant feed
feed from them and and make them
available in into the giant multicast
network because the more more streams
then we are we are more happy
so so in summary yes we have we have
plans but uh i think it will happen in
in the upcoming days
okay great uh um i i may
uh open a throat on the mailing list to
talk a little bit about the the dns
based discovery mechanism and whether
that would be feasible for you as well
uh thank you
that that that perfect uh one thing that
we would also like to to to focus on is
of course there is a technology aspect
where
you of course all of us
are technical people and we can
find and understand things but the real
uh idea that would like to achieve in
the end is to
achieve something really brain dead
simple i would say that receivers and
source
should not know all of these
complexities or should work instantly
and uh
and this is the difficulty
technically complex but make things
simple for users so that they just don't
think about using anything else i will
just go this way because it's simple and
it works and this is the the idea of
this whole
entropy that is that we are trying to to
to buy
that's exactly what i want to talk about
yeah so uh we'll we'll take that up uh
offline but i'll just say uh take a look
at rfc 8777
and uh
we'll talk we'll talk some more thank
you
i think maybe you wanted to say
something
yeah i got my
hand up um
yeah it's it comes it does come back to
content you're absolutely right at the
moment there's very little multicast
content in the research and education
networks there's a project called eu
metsat
um which is
meteorological related
data that's
multicast we looked on our uk
network janet and it's pretty much only
you met sat traffic that's multicast
um that's pretty much it there's
nothing else really
and as you said internet too have taken
a didn't want to take the decision but
at the moment they don't have a
multicast service because of the way
they're transitioning to new
a new platform they'll reinstate it
later
so it's it's currently multicast is a
bit of a
second class citizen for most things so
anything we can do as you say to make it
easier uh would be great so i think what
we're looking to probably do with rare
in this multicast work is to find ways
of allowing people just to stream even
from
you know bandwidth challenged areas so
they can stream out and reach multiple
people
by automatically um multicasting from
that single stream that they're sending
out and making it transparent to them as
far as possible
um so yeah but yeah multicast is is not
in a particularly happy state in rna
networks which is unfortunate
any other uh any other questions
um
uh saba i have a question for you um
what was your experience uh
in
implementing
amt
um
how much did you know about it before
did you just pick up the spec was it
really easy was it clear
did it take months or weeks or hours
um so basically um i i i first heard i
think from you
about the ant
this d-spring then i i did a lot of
other things and
the first the first reading and and the
first impression
was not uh wasn't too positive here
because i
whereas i am i am thinking about end of
sedations and tuning like
like pokemon so catching them all is is
always good but uh
uh but this uh this kind uh to tune a
multicast
didn't
get too much laugh here but then we had
some chats with freak and
and mentioned that okay that we should
catch this book cable also
so afterwards i started reading the
recipe
uh initially i i also didn't found the
the needed parts for me so i i started
doing the whole one which is very rare
here i usually
have the idea
and and uh i only see for the pocket
headers in the rfc
but then we pointed out that okay they
are also there but i have to scroll down
a lot
at this point at that point uh
so about two or three days passed with
with reading the refse and and cast the
the the idea behind it afterwards uh it
it was uh some hours because uh adding a
new general language is not too hard
here
then i
at that point i i was able to um to see
the multicast streams from from internet
to i mean from the universities of in
states
and then
holding the empty also again
some hours having them in data players
uh was about
another three or two so basically a week
was
after i
i could
i got
the motivation to read diversity
and
it
i didn't found any any uh
issues i mean
it was easy business of the reverses
it's uh very helpful feedback from this
group since uh
it's good it's good to know that um
um that this doc was uh
that the spec was useful for you so
um thank you
and this is really great great stuff um
uh frederick
um just to um
to to come to um
to conclude i i just would like to to um
to hammer the fact that this this lab is
uh
is open to anyone uh who want to improve
their imt client
v4 v6 so
we are now in the situation where we we
we need very good clients so we can
demonstrate things so whether into uh
using a browser or vlc or whatever
whatever um
really if you are really i'm comfortable
with a empty client software development
uh feel free to to really um
to to join to contact us and we we can
open this uh of course uh it's already
open but we where we can make sure that
it's available for you
i think the other thing we did discuss
before this meeting was whether we might
have some form of hackathon and we had
some ideas that we discussed with jake
and
many and others so maybe we can try and
focus on some useful hackathon
4113 that focuses on these things
great any other questions for um saba
and frederick
cool
well thank you very much guys this is
really really interesting stuff and uh
the combination of beer and amt is is um
you know potentially really powerful so
um
very very neat very useful stuff and
um for the
next section i'm actually going to do a
demo that hopefully addresses
well it's it's it's an attempt in the
direction of making
of improving
source content
so
let me share my screen
yes
let's try this again here
all right
can everyone see
powerpoint
um
i need to swap displays how about now
often it's sourcing for multicast
streams is this what you can say
yep you can see it all right cool
all right so um this is a project um
that
we had some um some interns this summer
work on um so what is off net sourcing
so um today
uh there's native sourcing and it's been
around for you know more than two
decades on the mbo and the multicast
enabled part of the internet
um and we can call that you know onnet
um but you know the mbone is a very
small fraction of the internet what and
and and
um you know what amt does is it allows
off net receiving so
if you're not on the multicast enabled
network you can access multicast content
through an amt tunnel you can receive
but what if you wanted to do the same
what if you wanted to source um and and
the fact is most sources could
potentially be on
unicast only networks
um
so we have a you know an interesting
portal for discovering and launching um
off net receiving and that is the
multicast menu
um
often at sourcing uh
this is where um
users on unicast only numbers can stream
uh some type of
stream say video
to a translator
that's sitting on the m bone and that
converts the stream from unicast to
multicast
then it can be accessed the idea is to
access it
natively for on-net receivers as well as
amt for off net receivers
this is kind of how it would work how it
would look we have the the big-i
internet
um that's you know mostly unicast only
we have the m-bone the multicast enabled
part of it um
mostly rna networks uh and you have a
multicast source and a multicast
receiver that works the way it's always
worked now what if you have an off net
receiver somebody on a unicast only
network who wants to receive well we
have these amt relays send it natively
to the relay and then the relay will
send it over amt to receivers
on unicast only networks
but what if you have an off net source
and
now we're introducing this unicast
multicast translator
which will take a unicast stream in
uh
turn it into multicast and spit it out
to um native or off net receivers
um so this translator was developed it's
essentially a python script
that translates just very simply
translates um a unicast stream to
multicast it was written by um
uh
uh one of our interns named giannis
it and it all does just rewrites the
source and destination address it picks
a random ssm address
out of 232
and it also
posts and creates a new entry on the
multicast menu
um giannis developed this uh in
conjunction with um larry and maki um
kind of working together on a project
and it's this um this translator is
deployed at george washington university
um thanks to andrew gallo
in terms of you know what are the goals
here we're just kind of
um working our way through functionality
what would be awesome is if we could
stream from an iphone or android camera
uh to stream video to the unica to the
translator
right now we're just using uh vlc from
uh from a desktop um
but uh
getting that working would be really
interesting the translator which just
translates the
source and destination um that's already
done um you know next would be you know
if it could index the stream say for
search um right now there's not a lot of
streams there's currently zero and i'm
going to create one
um but you know if this takes off there
could be zillions and you know creating
a directory service so that you could
subscribe to different types of streams
say
you know nature cam slash zoo cam slash
panda cam
um and then people could join
that particular channel and be alerted
every time there's a new panda cam that
pops up um so that's kind of the the
long term vision um also potentially you
know recording for for look back
purposes since obviously multicast is a
simultaneous you know live
by nature um
technology
and then receiver apps right now we're
using vlc um but would be nice um
would be nice if we could use you know
something a little easier something um
an app
uh on for ios and android um as well as
something that you know
if we could get this in the browser this
would be really really wonderful um but
for now we're using vlc and you know
we'd love some other ideas just to make
this easier i think you know frederick
said it well
if if we could could make these things
easier so that any user um on the
internet could do it that'd be great um
here's some references um to see the
code this is an open source project um
and if anybody's interested and get
involved um just shoot me an email we'd
love to you know we have a slack group
of um co-conspirators or uh i think jake
has called it a a cabal uh if you want
to join arca ball please um just shoot
me an email we'll add you to the slack
group
um and with that let me um
let me kind of show give a
um
uh
show a demo
um so first can you see my
um
can you guys see my command line here
yeah that looks good a little bit small
if you could do a plus plus maybe but uh
we can see it
yeah
sorry especially those in the morning
just you have to squint really
[Music]
make hard text bigger
okay all right so here's the one command
line uh it's just um runs vlc uh
launches a um a video an mpeg4 and it's
sending it to this magical ip address
here which is the address of the
translator and which is looking on this
certain port
so this is just a standard uh vlc
vlc command for sourcing um
let me
say this so folks in the audience this
is uh there is audience participation
please check the um
uh please check the uh
chat window i just sent
a link to the multicast menu
for anybody who does have vlc4
be great to give it a shot so this is
currently the multicast menu and you can
launch click on any of these things and
it will launch one of the
video streams on the mbone um
so i'm i'm about to hit return here on
this
which will
create that next one
uh that new stream um when if i reload
the multicast menu you'll see
we just created a new stream
uh if
someone is able
uh would be great if you could join this
stream
um
and
i'm gonna join
does anybody i saw jake he does um one
so one of the things you can click on
this and just to see how it works
we can rename this to uh
cute puppy
cam
all right and we will upvote it a few
times because this is the internet and
it's all about shelf
self-promotion um
and is anybody out there
able to join this stream
just shout out if you are
i'm getting something it's not quite
playing yet the plc is thinking about it
um so here's the amt relay um you can
actually see the relay we can see some
multicast
so the so the group address is 232 66 90
70.
that is this
so you can see the
incoming interface
and here's the downstream interface this
is there are two
uh this means there's two tunnels so we
can do a show amt
tunnel
detail
and you can see these tunnels um this
one is one amt
gateway
uh this happens to be a second laptop
that's next to me um and here is another
and here's a third so it looks like we
have uh three receivers
jake i'm guessing one of you are one of
these two addresses
um
anyway uh
are you seeing any video
yet
uh
no it looks like it's crashed my dlc but
i'll try it again one sec
i assure you it's working it's working
on my vlc so i'm gonna i'm gonna blame
your i got an old version of four that's
not working but i i connected
okay
um
i tried to
i tried the url on the
vlc from yesterday and
i have a
message saying that of course i i'm
unable to open the
the mrl so i'm not sure if you can see
me coming but uh
at least i i can't show the stream
i can't see the stream sorry what's the
v4 address of the relay
um
so
the relay is amt
dash
relay dot m2 icast
dot net
[Music]
let me see here
um
[Music]
and
if you're using vlc for a recently
downloaded version of vlc4 it has
um
by default this is the relay that is uh
that is the it's just the default relay
um
but i did i did get some video uh after
restarting but it's a
a bit choppy and it's it's hanging again
it looks like it's dropping some frames
or
uh
yeah or something
but uh
well for what it's worth
what resolution are you sending what bit
rate
i think it's
it's not that big it's only like eight
megs um
but uh i am oh actually here let's sit
here
uh show multicast
route detail
um
this is
yeah about eight megs
eight megabytes per second
well that's my problem then
yeah you're still on dial up
all right oh no it's a soup cannon wire
gotcha
um anyway uh
um
as as uh
anybody interested in working on this uh
as you can see this is you know this is
the idea um
the multicast menu by the way uh
lauren who developed it is working on
enhancing it to uh she is close to
releasing a 2.0
for the multicast menu um and uh all
right so frederick you you're seeing
something is it is it cute
okay cool um
if you want i can just share my screen a
little bit so you can see what's what
i'm seeing but uh
what is that
well that makes you realize in frederick
yes share my screen and i think it's
this one
can you see it
yes there you go
it's great
that is the video it was a little bit
choppy at some point but you you see
that this is in sync with the message on
the left
yeah
but it's yes
we've come to discover vlc as a vlc4
it's you know a beta version and it is a
little fragile
but
anyway it does work
excellent
thanks
all right with that um
uh we do have one last presentation so
um
the song uh if you want to get things
teed up um if you'd like to share your
preloaded slides um but with that uh as
he does that anybody have any questions
about this project and you know the idea
and the vision for this is anybody can
start streaming and sourcing something
that anybody can start receiving and
it should lower the bar for uh
generating
multi-gas sources
that's great
and this is an open source simple python
script so if anybody wants to uh launch
a translator themselves please let us
know we'd love to we'd love to add you
to the global translator pool which
currently consists of one
but
we'd like to do more it's proof of
concept um but you know you can see the
vision here
any other questions about uh off net
sourcing and the multicast translator
jake
uh yeah lenny if i if i stood up uh one
of your translators
with uh
with a
uh with a dns based uh relay instead of
a fixed relay
um
would you
uh would you be
so we we've talked about in i2 running
uh that's that's like next on the agenda
right is gonna be running the um
uh
the ingest
using dryad
to find the relays from external
and pull it in um
i'm just wondering if that's a
that's that's potentially interesting
so
uh the injection so the translator just
uh gets the source onto a multicast
network
um with dryad you could
use that
to hide from i'll have to think about
that i'm saying uh i'm saying i would
perhaps run your open source translator
uh
externally just in in my usual uh aws
uh multicast
oh yes yes yes
instances
yeah yeah definitely that would work and
that could be pulled in
uh wherever it could go directly from
from those relays to uh
you know your network or other networks
as well um but also could could go uh
natively to uh
to various i2 receivers so
um that that does look interesting and a
useful source of traffic the streams i'm
running are um
i mean we've we've run some some
customer streams but they usually want
those a little more controlled um
so if this
if this uh
works okay it might be interesting to
run i'll i'll
see if i can fit it in and take it yeah
i might have to wait till after some
other stuff first
yes but if you if you would like
somebody to to run it on an instance
like that then let me know and i can see
if i can help them
yeah i definitely think that could work
and that could be a good test of um of
dryad and for what it's worth uh the
next multicast menu will have the
ability to uh specify a different relay
um so right now it just uses the default
relay in vlc but
which like for example if you could plug
in a different relay then it could
launch that from a different relay so
that would work in conjunction with what
you know saba and you know his his
uh his test stream so um so yeah that
could uh
all these pieces can all work nicely
together but with that it's uh i have to
cut myself off and hand things over to
you song um
frederick yes
very quickly just as a side note and
very quickly we will try to to play with
uh this uh at least and see how we can
use it in in the p4 lab
great
awesome
all right you song you are up
uh just share your preloaded slides um
where the join cue button is
there we go
or share your screen
and
we hear you
okay thank you
uh
today i will
present the multicultural redundant
ingress router failover and
this is the second presentation in itf
uh so firstly i will
give the quick very quickly review of
this chart
uh for this uh
brief introduction another two ir and
the in-grass routers are used to avoid a
single node failure for the multicast
the two irs are the
umh the
upstream multicast hub candidates for
the ers the er means the egress router
so for
the pim or beer or rcpt p2mp or mmdp
whatever
the
specific multicast technologies
different functions
can be used
for for the
deployment uh so
there are three uh stand
by modes can be deployed for the ir
switchover in case of the irs failure
that the
code standby and the wall standby and
the
heart standby and the details uh you can
find in the draft
and the cost and the influence of the
three uh modes are different and uh
now uh
no one of these uh three modes are the
best choice as depends on the uh
actual network
deployment so the network administrator
should select the appropriate network
mode
so that's the brief introduction
of the draft
and this slide shows a minor update of
the room
one
so the update is that
in some deployments of the warm standby
mode and the irs the irs
made
in charge of different multicast flows
for example uh if we have a 10 um
multicast video flow so we can divide
for the five five for
each of the irs
uh
order is made charge of the different
ers for one specific flow
for example robust for one flow uh ir1
in charge of uh
er2 and er1 under the ir2 charge of er3
the ios can can be backup devices uh
for the for each other and in case uh
one ir fails
and
the other ir may
notify
uh
do not
the arc may notify the other ir to
forward the flow to the ers for example
for one specific flow
uh
i1 is in charge of er1 er2 and the r2 is
in charge of er3 and the if while l1
fails
r1 fails and
it will notify uh the r2 and r2 will uh
forward the multicast flow
uh to the er two yes er one year two and
yeah three
so that's the uh
update of this version
uh that's of the uh
uh draft and any comments are kind of
webcam for this draft and
uh we quarters uh uh think it's ready to
requesting the working group adoption
that's all thank you
jake you're up
yeah thanks so
um
in the
draft i i didn't see how it detects
failure and uh and how it
uh
how it's
doing the signaling from from one to the
other that it needs to uh
that it needs to be in charge of the
of the ingest
there's a
sorry go ahead yeah
so uh
for this chapter we we we just give the
uh a general way for the
uh
multicast root root router
failure
not not
involved the specific technology
in that
uh
okay so
um i guess
i i i think that this is a really
valuable uh
space to develop
but i'd like to um
i'd like to see
um
uh
i i guess
what
some more specific i'd like to see some
some recommended mechanisms at least
like if some exist then i'd like to see
references to them uh or
um
uh
you know
some some guidance on how to do the
detection that
that a failover
uh
is right because it seems like
that's a
uh
i i thought that was necessary in the
for this draft to be um
uh to be
uh
headed the right direction uh to me but
um
yeah but thanks i think this is a this
is a good space to to to work in and i'm
glad somebody is writing it writing it
up thank you
thank you thank you for coming
um
sandy was there something you
had to add
about
sorry memory
yes
okay i would like to say
i think
text suggestion is very useful we can
add some description about the detection
and the other functions
and the other details in the draft in
the future version
thank you
so um
for those who noticed uh
there was a we had two polls uh who was
read the draft and who would like to see
it adopted as a working group draft um
we had seven people who have read it
so it's a good sign so a third of the
number of people on
um and uh looks like um if you could
just
uh
put your hand up uh show of hands uh
who's who thinks that this this is be a
a draft that would who would like to
adopt this
from the work um as a working group
document
um so far we've got six anybody else
no objections
so i think we'll take this to the list
for an official um
working group adoption call this was by
the way presented back in 09
um and uh
figured we'd represent it again to get
it fresh on people's minds first
before the adoption call so
um looks like there's support um
to uh to adopt so we'll take this
officially to the list
uh for an official adoption call um
please speak up on the list um both if
you want to see it adopted or not
adopted and
also you know any any suggestions that
you see for the document are of course
always welcome at all times
and it looks like i'm about to end that
poll uh there we have seven who say yay
and one person who did not raise a hand
um so
let the record show that
and
any other questions or comments
for
um
for this draft
any other questions or comments for
anything in general before we close down
the session
okay with that thanks for thanks for
coming um and we'll see
folks uh virtually or physically
uh in ietf 13 113
thanks everybody thank you lenny
appreciate this thanks everybody for
your work this is actually a really good
session good work all the way around
yes lots of lots of really cool stuff
about real stuff that's you know
actually happening in the network so
this was fun
thanks all
thanks guys see you next time
pure jake
chance bye
you