so we start us we
wait
a minute or so
i guess you can start
okay then let's start um this is tcpm
tcp maintenance
um
my name is michael dixon i'm one of
three coaches the other ones are yoshi
and michael
um
and
this is the note well
you should have seen it if you attended
another meeting so
please read it and
do what it says
um we already have a note taker thanks
to gary who
um volunteered again
um and michael is a java scribe so um if
you
want anything reflected at the mic i'll
put in a prefix mic and i think yoshi
will
do the job in case
michael is presenting
if you are submitting a draft to the
ietf and
you want that the tcpm working group
is aware of it um put tcpm in the name
of the id that makes it much easier for
us to find it and
to be aware of it
this is the agenda
a working up status
then we have a couple of presentations
for
working good documents
one is on proportional rate reduction
which is uh from yuchang which is proxy
or who's proxy by me today um cubic an
update an update on yang two
presentations on tcp
ao um one about the
draft and one about an interrupt test
and uh finally on the working group
documents on tcp edo and eos um
where we have a slide from joe and um we
are also proxying it
after that we have um
two three more presentations um two
about
upcoming biz documents
and one about
an
implementation
[Music]
um feature
provided the talk is provided by neil
anyone wants to bash the agenda
if that's not the case then um
this is
the
are the status of the documents we have
um
rfc is 793 bis and um
that is uh after isj last call um
a revised id is needed and wes is
i think there and
can give us an update
yes uh the isg did a really good job
reviewing it and there are a lot of
comments
i've worked through some of them but
i've looked at all of them i've actually
made edits for a good number of them
but there are a few that i had put off
because they involved more
research or homework
a good example is
there was a question about how we treat
uh
source route options
and uh whether
what this document says is is uh totally
consistent with what other rfc is not
about tcp but about ip options say
and so uh i wanted to make sure that we
did the right thing there and also do
something consistent with what
uh real stacks do
so
i've been sort of dragging my feet and
taking more time
to get around to doing the right thing
and looking up a lot more information on
that one and there are a couple of other
issues like that but for the most part
uh the isg comments are pretty clear and
uh
i think it just
needs my attention to get through them
okay do you have a rough timeline
uh
no so
uh i would i would uh
hope to get around to it uh really soon
like within the next week or two but uh
i've hoped that for a few weeks already
okay so uh but in case you need help um
from others um
reach out to the mailing list
i was going to do that on some of these
questions uh i think that will be much
quicker and lead to better results so
i will do that
okay
any questions regarding 793 abyss
if that's not the case we can go through
the list of documents
um
they are in the order of the milestones
which are
um
often in tcpm not taken
that precisely
so we have prr um i have a status update
on that
in the first presentation
um
we have
eight three
twelve bis
um
uh where we where we have also a
presentation
um
said that he wants to do so he has
implemented what is in the current
document
and
um
microsoft is
wants to do some more measurements and
um
present that the next ietf and
based on the outcome of the measurements
the document should be in a
in a pretty good shape
or not but that depends on the um
on the outcome of the measurements so
that's why we
um
don't see any
new information or and
we don't see a presentation here
accurate ecn and generalized ecm um
are both
in the same state as last time because
the frs work going on in tsv
is
not finished yet
we have a presentation on the tcp
yang document
in this meeting we have actually two
presentations regarding
the tcpao
regarding tcpao one is about
the document describing tests and one is
about
an interrupt test
and finally we have
a slide from joe regarding tcp edo
any questions regarding
the documents
if that's not the case um
any additional statement from any of the
coaches
here this is michael speaking can you
hear me
this may be a good opportunity for a
personal
announcement that this meeting is most
likely
my last meeting at the chair desk
so i've decided to offer to step down
to open room for um the next generation
of tcp researchers so that they can get
management experience
the transit that transition will not
immediately take place because uh
since i still want to wrap up some work
uh the most important one is the top one
on this list here
but once 793 bis
has passed isg evaluation um and maybe
some other things are done then
i'll step down
and as i said i'll open room
for
somebody else to gain management
experience i will stay still stay around
so
i will just go to quinoa to work in tcpm
but not on the chair desk
so this might also be an opportunity for
best to speed up to work on seven i3
this because this is actually a
showstopper so thanks
yeah thank you
and thank you for all the work you did
for tcpm and um
i hope we
um will still
um have you in the working group as a
contributor and reviewer and
a person that can
share his
knowledgeable tcp
thank you
okay um
[Music]
the first
presentation should be
um
let me see
so this is uh
um
regarding um propulsion rate reduction
the draft is
i think um not active anymore
we contacted the
the authors and
basically they are
um
pretty busy with
other things but
they um
they stated that they will
um
provide a new version
on
in the time scale of the next ietf
and
this is the list of
changes
they
currently have in mind which need to be
addressed before
the next version which is two bug fixes
and
[Music]
some clarifications
especially on
interactions between
prr and reg
because at the point of time where
prr was written rec didn't exist so
there are some
some adoptions also
based on newer developments on the
documents
um uh
are there any comments are there any
additional things the author should
address so um
they
said they will read the notes
and
any feedback will be addressed
yoshi
ah hello i just curious about
implementation status of this one it is
already main running in the corner why
not
because now i see you know the beast
version is slightly different from
original version so there are some
logic updates so i just would like to
know the status of this implementation
i'm not sure if any of the um
draft authors are on the uh call but
um i'm in close communication with them
and the um i believe the
this is going to basically
um reflect the latest linux tcp uh prr
there have been a number of um
minor changes and fixes uh i guess
changes really not fixes over the years
and we wanted to update the
documents or reflect the experience in
the linux tcp stack so it will cover
logic that's implemented in linux tcp
richard
so i just wanted to add on this that
i've provided some of the feedback based
on my
experience of prr in the freebsd stack
so this has not yet been fully committed
especially the one that is running
without a selective acknowledgement
but
it
happens where
or will be addressed in an upcoming
revision hopefully
but uh you provided the comments to the
authors already
that is correct yes
okay so the authors are aware of it
any other comments
okay if that's not the case then i would
say um the next focus is cubic and um
videos up um you can run the slides on
your own
they have been uploaded
yeah am i am i audible
yes you are audible
thank you um
so i actually forgot how to do the slice
thing
on the on the
below your name you have uh
to to next to your next to the hand icon
there is a document icon and if you
click on that
yep
you should see a list of documents and
you can select your
so do you see the slides or
not yet i think you have to select it
and then
i selected it but it just opens on
another tab
well done so
yeah i just
i am not sure how to share this with you
guys
okay and then i can do that it's okay if
it's okay if you want to um
take over i i will
let you know yeah thank you very much
i'm sorry i couldn't
no problem
okay uh thank you um hi everyone
uh so you know in in the past year we
have been making some updates to cubic
and we are trying to adapt it to the
recent
based on the recent
deployment experience in in tcp and
quick stacks
and a lot of folks have contributed to
this effort and we're really grateful
for that
um next slide please
so um
i think around two months ago when you
know the chairs were concluding the work
group last call
we
received a final final
review from marco and
this was quite an extensive review and
i'm really
glad that it raised some profound issues
that we probably missed
so big thanks to marco and everyone who
has helped with
you know writing peers or providing
solution solutions
and all the discussion that is happening
on github so i can cover these issues
briefly just that everyone's aware was
changing in cubic base
the first one is because cubic is more
aggressive
than reno so we have um mentioned that
in the changes we have added
that cubic
uh basically updates rfc 5681 and this
is because of this
the the beta factor which is 0.7 instead
of 0.5
uh next point is about um when we have a
slow start overshoot
cubic only reduces condition window to
70 percent instead of 50
in case of reno and this
means that cubic's window is 40 higher
than reno so this could cause high
packet loss during recovery but could
take multiple rounds
and so we have recommended
uh the implementations or implementers
to
implement high start plus plus with
their cubic
implementations and and that's the
experience that we have from the
deployment as most of the
implementations are ready to that
and um
as i was saying it could take a bit more
than one you know recovery cycle to
compensate for the two times overshoot
in the slow start we are advising the
implementers to you know evaluate their
choice of the first multiplicative
decrease
after you know whether
they receive a packet loss or they
receive an ec yak so
this is something
they should be evaluating and we have
mentioned that specifically in the draft
um the next bullet is about
using prr to reduce the sending rate
slowly um you know during loss recovery
and uh as marco pointed out the the
draft uh you know when he reviewed it it
incorrectly mentioned
um
employing a fast recovery for all
congestion events so this should only be
done for packet loss and not for easy
and related condition events and now we
have updated that
um last point on the slide
similar to reno the performance of cubic
you know as a loss-based congestion
control it does suffer in wireless
networks
because the packet loss is not
necessarily you know giving us a good
signaling of the bottleneck capacity so
we have added some text around that
um next slide please
um
so
these are also some
important design changes so cubic has um
[Music]
you know lower window reduction and it
also reaches w max faster than reno so
it really
it effectively means that it has
a shallower salty than reno
and uh we have added some guidance
regarding you know buffer bloat and
queue management
where the new aqms the new
implementations of eqm's probably could
mitigate some buffer blood by for
example setting
lower thresholds for the queue size
um
next point is uh
very important and it is about
how the draft uh
the sorry how the base strap
originally had a lower limit of 2 for
congestion window
and
there is a crucial distinction between a
congestion event due to a packet loss
versus due to ec ack
i mean we do need a window of two
packets in case of packet loss to
perform loss recovery but for
ece markings we need to keep reducing
even beyond a congestion window of one
by using a retransmit timer type backs
off exponentially so i think this is
some
something that implementations need to
be
doing i don't think linux does this or
um other implementations take care of
this
behavior this is clearly mentioned in
the roc 3168 and i think
we should implement this
um
so another important point that has been
discussed in
in detail on github is better to use
flight size
or congestion window in the reduction
equation
um
the rfc series
you know the standards rfcs they
all have
they all use flight size and not save
wind
but there could be an issue of
there could be an issue that the flight
size sometimes is very low especially
for the rate limited apps when the loss
occurs so
uh the best way to mitigate this issue
uh is to implement rxc7661
so we have recommended that and
and some implementations you know for
example the next currently used event
we have left that as an option as well
next slide please
these are some of the editorial changes
um there was a bug in the average cubic
window equation that neil had found uh
thanks neil so we have fixed that
the next point is about
rearranging the algorithms for spurious
events detection um we now recommend the
standard star track
forward rto recovery rfc first and then
we provide some examples or references
for experimental rfcs
um
then we have added cubic's response to
certain events like sudden increase or
decrease in capacity and cubic is more
aggressive than reno in both the cases
last three are some simple editorial
changes
[Music]
next slide please
uh
this one is kind of a duplicate of the
next one so we can skip to the next one
thank you
so this is an open issue that um
i would and we would like some feedback
from the working group we have some
feedback already on the github issue but
if you have not had a chance to look
um i can describe this issue so marco
has raised
some objections about the spurious
detection and the conditions response to
those events
and to provide some context so there are
two types of spurious events um
at least for tcp uh there's
rtos
which is for
applicable for tcp and there are
spurious retransmits detected by
acknowledgments and that's applicable
for both tcp and quick
so the first issue is
that cubic is modifying a standards
track rfc
which um you know defines our response
to spurious rtos
um
the rfc port event 4015 it sets the
condition window to you know flight size
plus minimum of bisect plus initial
window
and this
but in cubic we are recommending to
restore the condition window to its
previous state before the reduction was
applied
so this is the issue um i will come back
to the solution in the next slide
second uh issue is
cubic is currently specifying a response
to both types of spurious events
and uh marco said in smoke in certain
networks for example in mobile networks
a path change could
increase reordering and thus it can
result in spurious fast retransmit
and at the same time
the bottleneck capacity might get
reduced
so if that happens then
um you know restoring to the previous
condition window might not be such a
good idea
and
that's why he said
there is no previous
rfc that talks about restoring state
due to
spurious fast retransmit events
the third one is currently we don't
exclude the cases when the ack detecting
spurs event has ece set on it so this is
a simple one i think we can fix this one
and
the last one is we don't specify or
cubic doesn't specify any mechanism to
adjust rtos
acknowledgement thresholds you know time
thresholds etc to avoid any future
spurious events
next slide please
so um as i was saying the first point
about violating the standards track rc
is a bit tricky
as um the response defined in rfc 4015
is
uh is a bit conservative
uh because the condition window is set
to uh
not to the previous value but to flight
size plus a minimum of bite sac plus
initial window most likely
it will end up to be flight size plus
initial window um in my opinion so this
is too low
um and i think some pro folks
won't be happy with it so if you have an
opinion about this and how do we proceed
or deal with this problem um we really
like to hear back from you
second one uh spurious factory transmits
so these are much more common
for tcp and these are the only events
more quick so
i think um if there is no previous rfc
that provides any guidance
um
perhaps we can record cubic's response
to these events um
and again this is the another topic that
um
you know
any input would be very
any any input on this would be
appreciated um the third one we can fix
uh in the draft that's not that's an
easy fix
and for the last point um i think
a lot of us agreed that
we would need a separate draft to cover
this as we want to keep the loss
recovery changes separate from the
congestion control
um
next slide please
so we will continue to fix any open
issues these are um you know as next
steps
and once uh
whatever issues are open right now are
resolved we will again
request the chairs to conclude the work
group last call
so if you haven't read the draft please
read it if you plan to read it
um
we would like to take care of the issues
as soon as possible thank you
thank you for the presentation and
update
comments
questions
hi vinnie
good job presenting
i just had a very quick comment
about something you said verbally i
don't think it was actually on the
slides
um
you talked about the problems with
wireless networks
losing packets
i think actually the big problem
is not packet loss because wi-fi link
player acknowledgement and
retransmission is pretty good
the bigger problem is the huge
variability because wi-fi can vary from
a gigabit or more
to a megabit per second
and
that happens if you just walk around the
house with your phone or if someone else
walks around and gets between your
computer and the access point so i think
the bigger problem
uh and i don't know whether the draft
talks about this uh but since you
mentioned it i just wanted to bring it
up
the bigger problem is that if your wi-fi
rate instantly drops from 500 megabits
to 50 megabits
when cubic is only reducing 30 percent
each time
it takes multiple round trips
to bring c winds down by a factor of 10
and of course during that time it's
sending too fast the queue is building
up so the round trip time is going up
so the time
for the round trip time is going up
so it is true you see lots of loss on
wireless
but it's not
random packet loss it is q overflow
because the center is sending 10 times
faster than the link
can now carry
right so it's more like a transient
congestion loss
yep
thank you yeah
thank
you praveen
so i have a question um
so as we make these changes right
some of these changes are coming in from
review feedback
i'm wondering if the some combination of
all the uh diffs from the previous rfc
would be representative of a
implementation that has implemented all
of these changes or would it be
sort of a mix and match so my worry is
that as we make these changes we might
not have had implementation experience
of the entire
uh new rfc so that that's just one
concern i had so any comments on that
it's a great point and um
the changes that have been made
you know before this review were mainly
to reflect what the implementations are
doing today
with this new review
um it it's it's a it's being a little
more careful
i would say a little bit conservative in
the sense
um and
we but we have left the options open uh
with respect to the
um things that implementations are doing
today so it's not like we are completely
closed those gates for example you know
using sieven instead of light size
that's one of sorry using flight size
instead of seaweed that's one of the
things but we have still um left
options for implementations which is
like using rfc 7661 and if you're not
using that
some implementations are still using
cvent and not flight size so it's not
like we have completely changed what
implementations are doing the only
change that i can remember which
implementations are not doing is the ecn
change
and i think that's a good change because
ecnc markings are representative of
congestion directly and we should keep
backing off so
so yeah so i would say um we're not too
going too far away or too too way off
from what implementations are doing
so it should be okay
a quick follow-up so so this is no
longer representative of the say the
linux pcp implementation as such right
it's more of a
representation of all the different
implementations is that is that the
current stance
sure yeah we can say that
okay thank you
i just had a
couple
quick comments oh one um
i wanted to encourage uh the draft
authors to
to keep the discussion of the undo logic
in the draft i know there was some
discussion about whether to keep it or
not but i wanted to emphasize that
undoing loss recovery events is really
important for performance in practice
in the real world
and the cubic algorithm has enough state
variables that it's non-trivial to know
exactly what variables are
need to be reverted or to be at least
reminded that there are many different
state variables and not just see when
then access thresh uh to undo so i think
that's important to keep in um
there was also in some of the
github threads some question of whether
it's okay to
to undo lost recovery if there's been
reordering due to a path change
and um i tried to
respond in the thread but wanted to
emphasize again that
um
i i would argue strongly that it's okay
to go ahead and undo um if you detect
that there was reordering um and this
various retransmit because if there was
actual packet loss in that round
then the loss detection machinery will
detect that there was also loss
and will then
um
you know
invoke the congestion control response
and slow down appropriately
so i think that's fine to undo
in that kind of scenario that was raised
um
and uh yeah and then also just to echo
stewart on the question of loss in
wireless networks i definitely agree
from all the packet traces i've seen
from from youtube and google.com that
cellular and wi-fi links these days do a
really great job of link layer
re-transmissions
um and so any losses that are are there
are usually because of the kind of
scenario that's
stuart mentioned or there's a rate
reduction and it takes a couple of uh
rounds for for cubic or whatever to slow
down to match the new delivery rate uh
so thank you for all your nice work on
this this draft
thank
you
virus
yeah some of the things that really
talked about
um especially towards the end right sort
of and then
also the ravine mentioned so if there's
this document started out i mean the the
pre-biz version started out with willing
to document what linux is doing
specifically because that was the you
know canonical implementation
and
the best version started out by wanting
to you know update that because the
links have changed
and also to roll in some of the things
that other implementations of cubic had
in the meantime done
so that is where we started out all the
way pretty much until we got marco's
review
um which uh as we said right raised some
very conservative points that basically
said you know you can't
move this to the standard strike saying
this
um because it's in conflict with for
example five six eighteen or um or sk1
or
and
while that's you know technically
true right we shouldn't publish your
proposed standard that's goes against
the must
in the draft standard
in reality right all the stacks have
been doing it for over a decade and the
internet is fine and so at some point i
think we should sort of give up this um
you know very dogmatic view on on
congestion control and try to accept
that things have moved on since we
published some of those rfcs
um so so some of those changes we made
was because we you know couldn't come to
consensus on the issues on it but i
would sort of really hope that we could
be pragmatic and actually
you know
document what is working in practice
rather than
uh you know
find ourselves in a situation where
unable to move forward because of a must
that was written 15 years ago
thank you
yeah i think i want to echo
kind of wireless point but like kind of
go in a slightly different direction
with it which is
um i i think we should really be
conscientious i mean i think all the
changes like have been discussed sound
like mostly sensible um although the
flight side of steven change is a little
concerning to me because in practice i
think
yeah i don't know i think that's hard to
make right um but but maybe it is okay
with enough caveats um
but but i think we should be really
conscientious of not trying to put
things in a document that no one has
implemented
um and so if we're in a position where
you know we get to work in group last
call and like
there's some recommendations or even
must particularly but even some
recommendations
uh in there that like zero cubic
implementations actually do like i think
we need to like remove them like i think
we need to be like really
conscious of like
not putting things in the document that
no one implements like in production
like i don't mean like a toy
implementation but i mean like a major
deployed operating system or other
environment um
i don't know i mean maybe i'm too like
harsh on this but like
if no one implements it there's probably
a reason and like putting this back is
very silly in my opinion
but that's it
um
yeah one point regarding that so
regarding the implementation point so if
i would make a difference but
i would make a difference between
um
what major implementations explicitly
say that they don't want to do compared
to
they might want to do it or they will do
it but just haven't done it because it
now comes up and it might make sense and
they just haven't implemented it yet
so that might be a difference
um well that that point i'll take it but
you know the flight side and c went
uh issue it really boiled down to
oh there's no roc that uses that and we
are moving to standard tracks so we have
to
i don't know follow the trend and i was
a bit disappointed with that
um
and and uh
like really there is no point of using
flight size
if at all rfc 7661 is probably the way
to go and with that could be a must
um so um i am not very familiar with all
the rfc procedures but that point was
really
like no standard strike rfc has
recommended it by our advice cubic doing
it um so
yeah yeah sorry i didn't mean to latch
onto that one in particular just i only
said it because i'm most familiar with
kind of the ways that i can not work but
um
i think i'm receptive to the idea that
like if they intend to implement it that
might be okay
um but i'm also apprehensive because
like the ietf has standardized a bunch
of stuff that like no one implements and
like
it my experience is it usually works out
pretty poorly if you have no
experimental data because it sometimes
it turns out like these mechanisms have
like gotchas that just don't
like cause them not to work for like
detail oriented reasons that like we
just don't anticipate um
you know and this is just the nature of
the beast like if you've never written
code for it no one's ever deployed it in
production
i mean it probably works but like you
just don't know and simulations don't
really cut it so
um i don't i mean maybe
i'm fine to drop this issue but i just
kind of want to put my two cents in on
that at that point
lars
yeah so as a little preview to the talk
later on updating uh 5681 so one of the
questions i'm actually raising is we if
we should try and roll in some of those
changes specifically the
flight size versus sealant uh discussion
we've had because of cubic at the moment
the cubic draft updates 5681
because it it wants to make it okay for
cubic to do this
which raises the slightly sort of uh
interesting question whether a proposed
standard can update a draft standard um
but we might be able to sidestep that
issue um if we decide to update 5681
any other comments
i have a final question um
to
for the author so you are using uh
hearthstone plus plus as a normative
reference
um i i think it's uh lars could you
answer that bro yeah it is a normative
reference because we wanted to use um
2119 language to say should
so we are basically we're basically
tying ourselves to high style plus
so this means as a message to praveen
the document
uh
needs to progress
uh yes well
it
doesn't need a problem milestone the
milestones are okay but uh and i'm fine
with him saying they want to do
measurements um but
so
he should be aware that there are
dependencies yeah i mean this is yet
another one of those things right where
so high start plus plus is the only
standard strike document we have in this
space
and since we can't
or or the the there's also one of the
points that marco raised right um we
here is that we shouldn't recommend
something that isn't standard strike in
a standard strike document
um and high strike plus it's the only
thing that we intend to publish on
standard strike
right so so either we say you know
you know do whatever or do something
very conservative um
we might wanna uh you know
do that but it's again one of these
things where in in reality people do do
things
but we can't say that in the document
because of stupid silence reasons
i just wanted i mean i just wanted to
so i'm happy if
uh
high start plus plus
matches around the next ietf and
i don't think it's a problem but
it shouldn't move
over and over again
yeah if it does
we have to deal with it in cubic
gary
michael can we just be clear for the
notes whether the reference to high
start is a should or a must
do the authors just want to say so we
can put it in the notes
it's a should
praveen do you want to say something you
just you wearing the queue and just left
the queue
can you hear me
yes we can
hi i was just responding to a question
so i did mention in the chat as well so
we were just waiting for uh other
implementers to also implement the
changes in the latest draft because the
latest rap did have a significant change
right so that's the only reason that's
one of the main reasons we wanted to
wait a bit before we go into working
group last fall um but uh yeah i think
like uh pretty soon we should be able to
get there and then
aim to have uh publish this sometime
around next eight years
perfect thank you
uh neil and i'm closing the queue after
neil
it sounds good uh praveen could you
clarify which other uh stacks are are
implementing i start plus plus and and
you're waiting for feedback on
uh yeah so uh the cloudflare quickstack
uh implements it uh i think uh apple was
experimenting with it and uh freebsd as
well i think netflix was experimenting
with it so there's multiple
implementations out there i'm just
waiting for more feedback to move
forward
okay
so martin uh
states that
he's a bit concerned about the
post-working group last call changes
uh don't actually have consensus so we
will
once once we see the final document i
think we will
we will ask the working group if it's if
the working group is fine with these
changes
anything else
then i think we move on to
uh the next presentation
um tcp yang model i think it's michael
yeah this is michael speaking from the
floor uh i guess you can hear me right
okay
so this is a short update uh um on the
tcpa module other that is trying to work
with mahesh and michelle
um and there have been some recent
updates to this document uh mostly to
ensure that we get closer to a working
group last call to finish
the small piece of work
so
there have been two updates recently
the first one
was basically
some open issues that were left in there
so we
have emphasized now in a much better way
and more prominently that the document
explicitly has a very narrow scope so
this is the consensus in tcpm the
document has a very narrow scope
we have also
[Music]
expanded on the specific game semantics
on the tcp connection table which is
writable so this has caused some
discussions in the past so we added text
on that
and there were some open issues in the
security considerations which got fixed
so
the o3 document was probably first
complete version of the document
and
on that version we then got uh two um
extensive uh sets of video comments both
from tom
catch
um the first email uh the relatively
small minor um edits
which have been fixed in o4 um
so we've changed the reference for tcp
to 793 bis under the assumption that
this document moves forward soonish
and then the result actually bugs in the
yang module which we have fixed
um so this is basically the current
version of
four and then we basically received the
second set of
extensive review comments actually
which are
summarized on slide number four
so these are a lot of good and valid
comments um
most of them are relatively
straightforward so i don't think there's
much discussion needed on it we just
have to implement
the changes so i've listed here that
there are probably missing references
and some of the references need to be
more prominently referenced in the yang
module and a couple of other things so
as i said the references
need to improve um
there are also some
small
changes in the in the yang module that
need to improve some is just yang
semantics
a more
editorial aspect is that the suggestion
is to add more warning signs regarding
md5 so so that is this is a legacy
technology and tcpo is much better than
that so we have such warning signs
already in the document but we could do
so more prominently and that's something
that's easy to change
and uh the examples are also not perfect
so these are all relatively minor things
that will be fixed in the next version
of five hopefully within the next few
weeks
there are only two um
the things that are uh are the bigger
questions actually
and the first
issue is that there is an ongoing
evaluation
in the ops area working group on a
couple of documents actually that work
on
service models
and one of these models specifically the
three network model
also includes yank statements on tcp ao
parameters simply because the layers vpn
site
may need
to implement tcpo to protect the control
plane signaling of the pgp specifically
and that creates
an overlap between these two young
modules
that is nothing specific to this yang
module
the same overlap happens between the l3
and model and a lot of other itf models
simply because it uses
other a lot of other technologies
but
the overlap with
the tcp mdn module was not well
mentioned in the in our draft so far
and this is why we have to do something
about that there is also a technical
difference in the modeling assumption
the
l3 and m model assumes that some of the
tcpao parameters are
modeled in the kitchen k gene
key chain sorry
um
the only issue is that the corresponding
rc which is 8177 doesn't foresee that as
of today
so that is why we actually don't have
that solution as of today and in
the tcpm yang what will be there
therefore i have explicitly added
configuration parameters for the send id
and the receive id we will see later why
these parameters are so relevant for
tcpo
so this is a difference at the moment my
suggestion is to clearly explain
that a difference
and of the reason why the
this model
models those two parameters explicitly
and of course this also implies that we
have to add a reference to the 3m
document
which is still missing
in o4 so this is the first uh
possibly a little bit bigger change and
that requires additional text at least
the last uh bigger request for change
was uh
comprehensive comparison with the tcp
mip
so we got past feedback in tcpm that the
tcp emip is not so interesting for this
young module but now we have a request
to make a comparison
so this is something that's not super
hard because we still model a lot what
is in the tcp mip already with some
slight differences to be future proof
so we could add such a comparison of for
example in a new appendix
so it's something that's doable um but
we haven't done so in the past so and
this is something where
uh i would also look for feedback from
the community um if this is something
considered useful as i said there have
been past statements on the mic on the
tcp map
so as i said as a most of these things
are straightforward we will
come up with a new version of soonish
for the last two ones
any comments from the group would be
particularly appreciated
and um
that's the current status so as i said
there's a new version uh a new version
coming up
that should address or hopefully all
known issues
and we would really look for further
comments from the group
as we have addressed all known issues
the authors believe that the document
would be ready for working group last
call but of course that requires
feedback from the community and that's
my summary for today
comments questions
michael um so what is the what is the um
reasoning behind
wanting to like why did the commenter
want to do the bib comparison
i mean it was just i mean the
i guess the underlying
assumption is that there are
quite a bit of implementations out there
of the t3 mip
so we know that there are
implementations of the mip and if
somebody who implements the mip
wants to transition to this yang module
of course maybe a translation table
could help
in most cases to be honest
it's relatively easy
to see
the mapping the statistics are
very similar we have removed uh i think
one or two aspects from the mip um um
we could reason why we've removed that
although there was a in the middle there
is a setting for the tcp retransmission
calculation timeout so we've removed
that one
i thought that this one is widely
implemented actually
so as i said it would maybe help
implementers but the big question is if
somebody who works on young in a state
shop is really needs a summary in the in
the document
okay well i mean i if you think it's not
a lot of work i i certainly wouldn't
object to like an appendix but um i just
i'm a little skeptical that yang's gonna
become a dominant configuration mode for
like tcpn points uh barring
the special case which you correctly
targeted which is like these bgp um
hosts uh
so i i don't think it's him i don't
think it's important but if if you don't
think it's a lot of effort i think
that's fine
thanks
yeah i mean maybe
i mean that that comment is not the
first time so we all know that the angle
not the um the most important
configuration method for a lot of tcp
stacks but it matters on vouchers
you also see that in the 3nm model which
also targets routers so in that specific
target area the model mattress and
that's also
probably one of the key areas where the
tcp map actually is implemented so at
the end of the day we all know that
on host operating systems this model
will most likely not be widely used
thank you any more comments
so guys we are looking forward to to see
the updated
document
will progress then from there
okay thank you
um
the next is
a presentation on
about
test vector
um the status of the draft
um
so
from my hattie or
i don't know how that thing plants this
up
see there
yeah
hello can you hear hello
yep
you can run your slides by your own
yeah sure
okay can you see the slides
i guess you can see the slice right
okay great excellent
sorry uh i had some technical
difficulties my
laptop just crashed so i had to change
to the
spare one but
there we go
uh my name is johan kulsari so i'm
presenting the tcpa test vectors
draft
and the updates to it
we have been doing that with
show touch
so
let's see the next slide so the
reasoning here is that uh
implementing tcpa is is
quite complex so the test vector should
help to implement it correctly and of
course for interoperability
it needs to be correct otherwise it
won't work at all
so here we have provided test vectors
for the
mandatory options
for ipv4
6 for the mandatory algorithms and for
both
ignoring and including tcp options
and it also discusses some of the
implementation issues that may be tricky
or the implementer
uh
this was presented last time iitf 110
not many changes
uh shortly after itf 110 we were able to
test it in our lab with ipv6 so no
changes there
everything was working fine
then we got good comments from michael
scharf thanks thanks for those
and the version o2 draft was updated
based on them
so there's some clarifications uh
uh
the nut travels or was changed middle
pro
middle box traversal
and
also clarified some parameters that
which one where decimal or hexadecimal
or even binary for the dcs
fields so
these are the changes
so thanks for the feedback uh
so far of course the feedback is always
welcome
we as authors think that i it's ready
for the working group class call
we have been waiting for week feedback
sometime
uh
i guess
i hope it it is looking good so
not more feedback but of course if if
something is noticed
thank you
thank you for the presentation
are there any comments
she has thinking that this is in good
shape and it's getting close
so
if you have any concern or want to
comment no just speak up here or
send a message to on the mailing list
very soon otherwise we are thinking
about proceeding the draft
yeah this is michael speaking also just
as a heads-up this is an informational
document
so um
of the powerful information documents is
maybe a little bit lower than standard
strap so for an informational document i
think that the working group last call
is easier to achieve and we might not be
far away from that
any comments
if that's not the case then we move on
to
um
greg who is presenting on a tcpao
interrupt
greg you can run your slides
herself
oh um
wait a minute
yep now it should be possible
okay hey how's the audio
yeah pretty good
okay hi my name is greg hankins i'm
presenting on behalf of me and also
melchior ailments
who participated and helped facilitate
this interrupt test
i should mention it's not
clear from these slides uh the main use
case that we're looking at in the
operator community is for bgp so
uh this tests focus around pcpao with
bgp and
all the work that we're doing to
evangelize the technology and promote it
in the operator community is around use
for bgp as a replacement for
md5
we conducted an interop test last summer
it was in the middle of the covid
pandemic and the shutdowns so we figured
let's use the time
to do some interrupt testing over the
internet it was uh done remotely using
virtual machines
and it turns out it doesn't really
matter where they're located as long as
there's a tcp connection so we used
multi-hop bgp and established v4 and v6
sessions over the internet
this saved us some time in getting
together in person and lugging routers
around and things like that so it's
really easy just to spin up a vm
and do testing over the internet
we tested with two algorithms there sha
96 and
asc mac 96
the interrupt was pretty easy but we did
learn a couple significant lessons that
um are here in the slides uh lesson
number one
and this is maybe was not obvious to me
as a newcomer to tcp ao i think
for someone that's configuring it for
the first time it could be a little bit
of a learning curve so
the first lesson that we learned is that
send and receive are configured from the
router's perspective so
my initial configuration was to
match the send and receive ids it turns
out you actually have to have them so
that they're opposite so that the send
is configured to the receive and the
corresponding receive is configured to
descend
that was one important thing that we've
learned we provided this feedback to the
yang model to
hopefully clarify that in the
yang model
and we also
updated our respective documentation to
make sure that people understand that's
how you configure it
and the other thing is that since tcpao
supports multiple authentication
algorithms
then or cryptographic algorithms i mean
then you have to make sure that you also
configure the same algorithm or else
that's not going to work
the other lesson that we learned
is that we had a firewall in the path
which we initially did not know about so
the nokia router was connected to the
internet and was was open the juniper
router was behind a firewall
and it turns out that the firewall was
actually modifying the mss option for
some reason
so this caused the calculation to fail
on the receiver and the bgp session did
not come up so this is actually great
because this actually means that tcpa
was working
since the packet was modified
the session did not come up
so once we figured out that there was
indeed a firewall we had to do some
package races on each end and then
we figured out what was going on
relatively quickly
the firewall issue was resolved
and um interop test was successful
there wasn't really much else to say
really once the the tcp sessions came up
we exchanged routes and just as an
extended test and everything worked
great so in terms of implementations
there are currently several commercial
implementations that we're aware of if
anyone knows of other implementations
please let us know and we'll
add them to the list
there are no open source implementations
this is a problem because the community
can't really adopt the technology until
there's a number one open source
implementations and then number two a
tool ecosystem to support the
implementation so
currently there's no open source
implementations and as far as we know
only wireshark supports tcpao
other tools like tcp dump
don't have support for ao yet
so here's uh the exciting news is that
just last week
several
members of the community finalized
a development project that's funded by
the ripe ncc
we have funding to develop a reference
implementation it's done by philip peps
who's
been a longtime freebsd committer
we're going to provide
support
by offering router vm's for interrupt
testing juniper and nokia will support
the testing with vms and the set of
deliverables is first of all a reference
implementation of tcpao for the bsd
kernel and also nc netcat utility
and then a port of that reference
implementation to the linux kernel
we're currently working on more sponsors
to also add extensions to
some popular routing implementations
like open bgp bird
possibly fr
and this work is targeted it's going to
like i said we just finalized this last
week so the work should be starting
relatively soon and release targeted for
early next year hopefully january 21
at 22 though that should be january 22
sorry about that
in terms of resources we have a github
page that has the configuration examples
that were used for the juniper nokia
test we added some cisco examples as
well
we're also developing a much more
comprehensive website tcpao.net
that is intended to be a one-stop
resource for evangelism
resources
why you should use this technology
central location for links to
implementations configuration all that
kind of thing everyone everything that
an operator would need
in order to figure out if their routing
implementation support tcpao how to
configure it
and as well as some of the benefits as i
mentioned
and that's about it
any questions or if you have any
comments or any other tools and
resources or if you'd like to be
involved
in some of the ongoing projects then get
in touch with us
any questions
you mentioned are the um
is the is your team aware of the the
well it looks like a tcp ao
implementation underway by leonard
crestaz for linux
no we did not know about that
yeah it does seem like over the past
uh i guess over the past couple months i
do see patches from leonard prestas
for what looks like tcpao
i think it's underway it looks like he's
revised it a couple times but i just
wanted to mention that
okay i did not know about that um
could you would you mind sending us a
note with uh the name i don't recognize
the name i'm not i'm not a linux
developer familiar with all of them
yeah i'll send you the email
and then pointers to the patches yeah
great thanks a lot
micah
yeah i have one question regarding
actually the previous um configure the
previous talk
have you looked at the test vector
document during that interrupt
no we didn't um
primarily just because we we each had
implementations and we didn't feel like
we needed to
and uh our actually
the nokia implementation was released
many years ago even in the cisco as well
even before the test vector's draft was
even written
so that wasn't useful for us at the time
but i expect it will be useful for the
ongoing work in the freebsd reference
implementation
yeah if as if there's any um if such as
uh
an
observation already
can be posted somewhere for example a
list that this would be excellent so if
yeah
somebody confirms that the test vector
document uh first this correct and
segment has been useful
so this would be a very um strong um
help for tcpm to finish the document
actually
yep
was there someone in the queue before me
um
i just wanted to i mean i
pretty much like the idea of supporting
open source implementations
um regarding the previous d1 do you know
if philip is going to implement this for
the base tcp stack or also for
alternative tcp stacks like for rec or
so
i'm not sure that's a good question i
can
i can ask
ask philip and we can note that in the
project proposal
okay
because i think the base deck supports
uh
the
md5 stuff and the extensions don't right
now
okay
any other comments
if that's not the case then thank you
very much for the thank you
for the interesting information
um
and
[Music]
the next
is
neither wes nor
joe um
but wes is in
his west still there
no idea what's in these charts
yeah so um
my point is um there are two documents
uh so so maybe you can jump in uh there
are two documents one is describing how
to
extend the
option space
for packets
after the initial exchange with soon
segments and another one
which is
an individual submission
about exchange extending the option
space
for packets with this option set
and
[Music]
so he has made
no progress on the implementation
and
things
so things that the document
is
becoming more stable so the tcp edo
document he thinks is ready for working
group last call
and
the the other one which is an individual
document
there are some dvds but he thinks it's
near ready for working with glass call
so that's the status update
um
are there any comments any messages for
wes or joe
a little bit i that is indeed quite
stable and has been for
uh
a while
uh it's just been uh a case of uh
there's a lack of
uh eagerness or urgency in implementing
it anywhere
and so
that's
what has been paused on
however it's not really been changing
at all
and
there are no known issues that i'm aware
of either other than not really being
implemented
yoshi
okay so yeah i think i have a couple of
comment video but i will send a you know
on the list later because i need to
think about a little bit more but other
than that i think i'm really curious
about
uh
some uh middle box interaction or a
hardware optimization interaction of the
edo and then especially if it's in
if someone
you know implementing you know
renaissance others you know always stuck
you know
then i've tried to get some feedback if
this is feasible like this there is no
concerns about it so
i just know
my concise now this is
very best feedback on this document so
but uh this is kind of important
document because you know option space
extension is very important so i just
would like to see more feedback
and then
and also scene extension
i i have some you know one collection
this this is not uh indeed is this is
not adapted working group item so there
is no working with brasco and so it's
not ready for working with rascal i
think
and then
um
and then i basically opposed the idea
that's
submitting this draft as an individual
submission
um
individual streams so if these documents
you know going to publish it should be
adapted back in group item and then star
directly
that's
one thing i want to mention that
but this is as my individual comment
again i also have a want to see a more
feedback on this one as well
yeah the milestones are
um a bit
in the future
martin as an individual or as an id i
don't know
oh as an individual um thanks for the
presentation wes uh can you talk a
little more about implementation so are
there literally no implementations or
just a matter that hasn't been deployed
anymore
actually i believe there was some work
but it was uh
several years ago
i think joe was working with a grad
student who did some
implementation work on edo i don't
think the other one uh
was implemented yet
but um
yeah i think there was some work and
that experience was plowed back into the
draft however it's not uh the case that
that work
resulted in like patches to the linux
kernel that uh
are
deployed or anything like that so
um
i think uh
an interesting way to deal with this
might be to
attempt to last call and see
who responds uh
i i think
i think that might
force people to look at it
because there's really no driving uh
need for this at the moment although
there had been many times in the past
when
people wanted more options space and
didn't have it
and
because of that that's why these drafts
exist
it's only a matter of time before
someone comes up again and wants more
option space
yeah i mean i think i think last call as
a technique to like shake out stuff is
good as long as you only accept knows an
answer um
i i guess my other my other thing would
be uh
i'm a little uncomfortable the idea of
edo being standards track um
it seems to me like
the whole game here is
is deployment experience with the the
whole question here is the middle box
reactions and without any deployment
experience i don't know how we could
possibly recommend this
to people um
experimental would be fine but standards
track seemed really
aggressive to me personally as an
individual
thanks
michael
and i closed the queue after my
yeah just like to echo what wes said um
10 years ago this was really an urgent
problem that showed up every once per
year
and this was the basically when we
started that work um
of course things got more silent on
options recently but as i said there was
a strong need for that document
a couple of years ago
of course situation has changed a bit
but
we don't know the future so i think
there
is it is valid to document some of these
things in one way or another
that's an individual country
okay
but uh yoshi said he had comments so i
suggest that he sends the comments
and
that can get
incorporated in the document
okay so we have uh 40 minutes left and
we have we need 40 minutes for the for
the next three presentations so i'm
i'm running
the timer to
keep
um
the time budgets
reflected so lars you're up next
yeah thanks
uh can you share should i share
uh
i would say you share
you should be able to do that
okay
are you
requested to share
[Music]
i
just
yep now you should be able to do that
i think it's these ones
can you see
yes and sorry for being so super late
with them i actually didn't have them
until earlier today because i thought i
would speak without slides and then i
decided maybe
uh giving people something to look at
other than myself is a nice thing to do
right so
you used a way to submit them which i
don't know how to do that maybe it's
just
so you can you can now upload slides
directly to the data tracker as a
participant
ah okay
which is what i did because i wanted to
try it out but it's a new functionality
that can be advertised a bit more but um
it means that your shares don't have to
like do all the slight handling
uh yourself anymore which is nice
um
anyway so it was
i guess it's good i made slides just
just for that reason um right so so um
this is a sort of initial presentation
on
wanting to raise the question whether we
should revise rfc 5681 which is tcp
congestion control
which is a pretty core um rfc and i
already talked earlier when we had the
cubic presentation on some of the
reasons why i think wouldn't mean we
might want to do that but
let's go ahead
um as a brief history right so 5681 is
the current draft standard um it
obsoleted 2581 which was a proposed
standard which in turn obsoleted 2001
which was also proposed standard and
just based on the rfc number alone you
can see it's been a while since this was
last touched
um so the the main goal here would be to
move this to an internet standard uh
since it isn't already and it kind of
feels like tcp congestion control is
sort of ready for that
um there's one existing errata which has
also been verified um
on 5681 so the minimum goal would be to
roll that into the revision um which is
i think pretty uncontroversial given
that it's already verified
um i reached out to the original authors
and uh ron paxton has said that he has
moved on and has no time to spend on
this but wishes of luck uh mike allman
and ethan blanton said they would
contribute and i've also sort of reached
out to
ridicule neil cargill and jana yengar
for help and
um that is already five so if if those
five want to do it uh you know
full speed ahead to them otherwise i can
sort of volunteer to act as editor but i
felt like i wanted to have some people
on board that know this stuff uh better
than me
um there's a repository um on github
which basically has a markdown version
of the text that was 5681
um and there's sort of just formatting
changes and and some very minor things
are related to that like updating to
reference and so on
um so the the one question i want to
raise is should tcpm even do this right
uh basically open 5681
uh with those goals on the slide and and
there's a another goal on the next slide
that might make that discussion a little
bit more interesting right and that is
um
there's things that have accumulated um
since we uh published 5681 specifically
they're widely deployed for for a decade
or longer
that are in conflict with what 5681 says
and one specific example came up
when we did cubic
uh the quickbiz right 5681 says you set
ss thresh based on flight size
and
cubic as far as i know cubic basically
since its inception and also all major
cubic implementations don't do that and
they update
ss3 based on seawind and not flight test
because it has benefits in app limited
scenarios
um
which is technically not allowed by 5681
right which is why it was raised for
cubic when we wanted to move it to the
standard stack
um gory pointed out there's rfc 7661
which is experimental that already sort
of allows um
ss thresh to be set to something between
flight size and c wind so so cubic would
be sort of
in line with 7661 but 7661 didn't update
5681 and it couldn't because it's
experimental
right um also a quick uh i think this
was uh brought by yusun uh the quick
congestion control document actually
defines updating as a thresh based on
seaweed and so is also not in line with
um and we have sort of this is one
example of something where you know we
are sort of diverging from
the uh the the original
uh
specification in 5681 but there's
probably others like that
um and others might have other examples
so the question is
if we did update 5681 did we want to
move some of these things in
specifically um
for this one the cubic uh bis document
that we're doing is already updating or
proposing to update 5681 specifically to
make cubic's behavior okay
basically saying you know whatever cubic
does is fine too
um and and there might be other things
here that we might want to sort of make
okay based on 5681 um
this does raise the question sort of in
terms of um sort of the the standards
process you know if we move things into
5681 that aren't
uh
baked enough
um you know would that mean we need to
go back to propose standard with it or
or stay at draft center and not go to
full internet center but i think
uh that question of how we're going to
do this we can answer once we know what
we want to do uh to the to the
specification
um and i see i have people in the queue
which is good because that's all i had
thank you
yeah hello everybody um thanks for
bringing this up so i think actually
these changes on this slide are more
important than moving to internet
standards so i think we should do this
for having these changes if we go for
internet standard afterwards or not it's
a different question for me we might
still be able to do it because it's
based on what's actually implemented out
there um
but that's the last important point for
me and i also want to mention another
thing i think gauri started some
document to try to define
something like tcp fairness or whatever
maybe that belongs into the same bucket
not sure
watching
so as an individual i i support this
work um
i i am someone inclined to just roll in
the abc abyss into 3465 as well but i
know that's the next talk so i'll just
leave it at that um
but the um
regarding like the standards level i
don't have a really strong opinion about
it but i i do think
we need to think hard about like maybe
reframing
the language to be a little more
permissive in terms of experiments and
so on um
if the internet standard like it's gonna
be very very hard
for documents to modify it and so um
like i would love to reposition it to
say you know to talk about congestion
control experiments
to explicitly acknowledge the existence
of of things that we know about like
cubic um which i think you're doing here
um
and and you know just
i i just i just don't want to have like
further tinkering
blocked by you can't modify you have a
proposed standard and you can't modify
this internet standard
um and just have that be a line of
objection to further experimentation
thanks
mia
please
be
brief
uh largely support this work i think
this makes sense to me
same sentiment as others are not yet
sure whether we internet standard
congestion control is still evolving uh
we're still finding uh
new ways of doing things so you know
not baking in
would be a better thing to do but this
makes sense to me i had one question so
apart from this particular ss thresh
issue
what are the other changes that we're
thinking about are there like other
uh
issues or updates that we want to do
here
i i don't know frankly so i haven't had
a chance to sort of get together with
the the people i i sort of i got to the
point where i asked them whether they're
interested but i haven't actually sent
an email so what do we want to do um i
think i i basically um
when i contacted them the the goal i
pitched was to move this to another
standard and so by definition we thought
this was going to be a pretty minor
update if um we think we want to make
more changes then um you know we sort of
need to
reconfirm and restate this but i don't
know so i'm
i'm guessing we want to sort of maybe
start a list of some sort i'm hoping it
will be still a short list but this is
the one thing that i have fresh in my
mind because of cubic
gary
you are still muted
can't hear you boy
can you hear me now
yes
excellent
so it's true i started something in
tsvwg to try and catalog all the things
said in rfcs about what was thought good
practice for congestion control
it's a long list and not all of them we
probably now believe in
so where does this really lead us to
i think we can document what new reno is
i'm a bit frightened that we don't
really know the answers to changing it
significantly in other words rewriting
the spec
and i particularly wonder about what
happened in quick because i thought
quick was reno based
and that was what the charter said no
congestion control work and yet we put
cubic's reaction into 9002 which clearly
isn't what the rfc series said
if we make things like this happen how
are we going to write a new 5681 that
covers everything i think this is hard
and we should think carefully about what
we want to achieve
bob
you're very okay
um
the
the changes on this slide is fine moving
to internet standard i think would be
wrong you know
yep
and then um and the the reason
is that i think there's reducing use of
reality
sorry but that wasn't really cool
[Applause]
since we are running out of time i would
say
michael what do you want to say
yeah just have a quick comment from the
chair that's there's also
something that might have editorial
changes um 793 bliss has a congestion
con control consideration section and
that changes the framing for
this 5681
a bit
so because the basic construction
control requirements in 793 bis
and as of today this
was basically 56.81 so um as i said they
changes in 793 bits actually
could result in editorial changes in
this one as well
okay so i would say
we get this um
discussion to the list
since we have to move on
um
so the next one is about abc
vidi should i run the slides again
i can try uh oh you can try okay
ask to share slides or
well you can do it if you want okay
here we go okay and um
you have 15 minutes but if you can do it
in less time i can i'll do this better
can you see this one
yes
oh nice
um so this uh
this is a
discussion on the mailing list about
you know how abc
is currently right now and
youtube neil and i you know we talked
about it and probably we want to
um bring our proposal to the to this
meeting and to the mailing list um so
let's see so
the recap of rc 3465
appropriate by counting
there is a
you know in
earlier in i don't know i wasn't really
working on congestion control in 1999
but there was a paper
um in 1999 and it was about how you know
the receivers could manipulate senders
and
can manipulate the senders to increase
the condition window
uh
by sending acknowledgements for
one bite
instead of for the whole packet and this
means that you would increase the
condition window by a thousand packets
but
the receiver could basically is it could
basically be just acting thousand bytes
and so the rfc 3465 fixes this by
making the increase based on the bytes
acknowledged not per ack
and
the
issue that is discussed in rc 3465 is
about a stretch stack which could
uh sharply increase congestion window
and cause very bursty behavior and for
that it
has a
limit a cap called l to limit the
bursting behavior so this is the recap
of 34.65
uh on the next uh slide we are talking
about the problem statement so the
the
with with you know um so much
involvement and advancements uh the cap
of two
uh packets is not cutting it so we
think that
um
the these days the stretch acts
acknowledge a lot more
significantly more packets than two
packets
and this means that the condition window
increase is going to be limited by two
packets and it's going to be very slow
the increase is going to be very small
uh and other stacks don't implement this
limit um because of you know the
uh low throughput and the low receiving
increase issue
and uh linux has been implementing abc
without l since 2013
and it it basically the the
the way to control bursting it
encourages to use spacing uh to reduce
the bursts
um
the solution uh we're tr we're trying to
propose a solution where you know
we remove this limit l and we say that
the increase in the conduction window is
a separate problem from from bursting so
we use the ack information the total
amount of bytes acknowledged to increase
the condition window and basically
that's based on what we are learning
about the network and what we are
probing
and we will separate out the bursting
issue by using some sort of pacing
um
the rc the pr rfc 6937 um it defines a
new state called delivered data
which is basically you know the amount
of data that has left the network so
we're proposing to use that uh to
increase the condition window and
in the next slide i can describe what
delivered data uh what's the definition
of delivered data
so it's it's it's um in
uh you know in in in just plain english
it is the amount of data that has left
the network
and uh let's say if zach is supported in
in that case um
when we don't have any sac uh blocks
then delver data is basically changing
the uh the old una and the new una
and when sac is supported i'm sorry when
the sorry when when there are sac ranges
which means there are some reordering or
there's some packets are getting
acknowledged before the send una is
increasing
then
the delivered data is changing at the
una and whatever is the delta in the sac
blocks
um when sac is not supported
um then um first case is when there are
no duplicate x it's just same as the
previous case where it will be change in
the same q a and uh when there is some
recovery going on and we have duplicate
acts um then delivered data will be
uh equal to one packet on every single
dupac because one packet is leaving the
network and on subsequent partial or
full ack
it will be updated to whatever is the
change in the send una and we will
subtract
uh one sms
for
one uh packet for each preceding dupac
so you know so that we don't double
count the packets that are cumulatively
acknowledged in the full act
so this this is a simple definition of
delivered data and it reflects exactly
what is leaving the network um at any
with with any act we know how much data
has left on our work
and this is the last slide
this is about this is a simple change um
probably
and can we fold these changes into 56 81
bits instead of doing a 3465 base and
that way we can obsolete probably the
3465 roc
um
that's all i have um open four questions
uh so as i said a minute ago yeah i
think the answer to the last question is
yes um 5681 already has abc but with l
equals one uh if i
characterize it that way
um
so i think just like having fewer
documents would be good uh the other the
other caution i would have is to email
mark allman um
as many of you know i've had like an
extended discussion with him about this
and he is
um some real concerns about
just ramping up l
in the way that you're talking about
here granted it is happening in the
internet and this is but this is
this is an argument we should probably
actually have rather than just kind of
rubber stamp
thanks
ready
uh i just wanted to point it out that um
the windows tcp stack
does use l and it caps it to eight
right now um so that change was done
particularly as stretch checking became
more common
uh and windows tcp stack doesn't do uh
facing either right now by default and i
believe linux doesn't do pacing either
by default so my concern with just
removing the l limit is that then we
should say that facing is mandatory
right so that's what the quick rfc ended
up doing right so quick connection
control rc says
i think pacing is a must if i recall
correctly and then uh it
doesn't have the l limit in the
specification right so yeah if you want
to remove l then you have to make facing
mandatory that may not work for all
implementations on iot devices etc where
you know facing might have overhead so i
think
this is a far more nuanced discussion
than just saying let's remove l in my
opinion
right you're absolutely right without
facing uh there needs to
i mean i'm not in a favor of l but i
think the quick draft um does uh
recommend i don't think it says must my
memory is probably
uh not accurate but uh it does uh
provide an alternative which is kind of
pacing in the transport stack by
distributing how much you're sending uh
in one send during the whole rtt uh
maybe someone can correct me
but you're right um without pacing um
there can be a l but we couldn't reach a
consensus on what this l would be like
you said windows is using eight
um i think we are using ten and uh the
draft says two
uh and mark is going to
based on my uh you know whatever he has
replied on the mailing list he's not
gonna like because then that's just you
know we're just guessing numbers
so
perhaps we can also take this to the
mailing list
yoshi
um
i have one clarification question
so in my understanding abc is used for
slow start phase and then congestion
avoidance space but abc is now used
recovery phase my understanding
so
in the slide you mentioned about deepak
i
it is for the other case not a recovery
case you know the same package does
happen
i just like
no
no you know
if you want to apply this during
recovery phase
[Music]
i think if you read the abc draft um
you know for example if there's a rto
then there's a slow start recovery
and
and in that case it says it recommends l
equals to two in certain scenarios and
other scenarios it recommends l equals
two one
but uh for the fast re-transmit scenario
you're right um because that would be
incongestion
i don't think we use abc in conjunction
avoidance at all because that's
straightforward increased by one mss
um
and and that would apply to the loss
recovery as well during the fast
retransmit but not during the rto
recovery
yeah i just wanted to confirm that uh
the quick rfc 9002 um says either you
must piece
or uh you must limit l to with n
basically
um and the choice of 10 to go back to
the question of whether it's a magic
number or not is it's not i mean it is
short of a magic number um but that
magic number comes from the iw10 draft
which kind of implicitly allows you to
burst 10 packets into the network uh at
once
uh as a direct result of that draft um
and so
you know if you're going to pick a magic
number
you might as well pick one based on an
existing rfc um it also matches and it
coincidentally the initial painting the
fq basin quantum
the initial fq base and quantum of linux
and so there's also experimental
evidence for it um that's not to say i
actually think 10 is the right number
um but it's it's it's something we have
so um
yeah just because thank you for
clarifying yeah i wasn't sure about it
praveen
um i think like uh in uh so we should
recommend pacing i guess and then uh
fallback should be an l value and i'm
perfectly fine with 10 although you're
using eight uh
and seems reasonable to me based on the
initial window
but all the stacks are using
right the issue raised by mark was it's
not really that you're bursting 10
packets you're reversing x plus 10 right
and
x is whatever window you have right now
um
so the point is really not
there is 10 or 2 or whatever it's
it's uh i think the point is
it goes beyond what abc recommends is um
can you burst the whole congestion
window in one cent
um
and
i think the pacing is answered the
answer to that is pacing
we cannot i think we shouldn't be
bursting a whole congestion window uh
wherever we are in the slow start phase
so
okay so i
closed the line
and let's say we
continue the discussion on the mating
list um
in principle i think less documents are
better than more so the rest of the time
uh is neil
can be spent by neil on um
silent clothes
all right so i'm gonna try to uh share
my
share
well you can you can share your
presentation the the sites have been
uploaded so if you click on
the upper left
document i clicked on it
and it
thinks i've got it there it goes
yeah we have to approve it
you can request be approved you do
uh here we go
all right can everybody see that
yep
okay great
so um we wanted to talk today about a um
a an issue that we have seen in
production and a particular solution
that we've been using and wanted to
discuss it with the community
um
and this is about an uh
this feature is called or we call it tcp
silent close
um
so the motivating scenario here is uh if
you imagine a large-scale internet
service
where it has tcp connections to millions
perhaps hundreds of millions of cell
phones
and then um the server machines kernel
pcp stack
closes all of those
tcp connections quickly due to
one of two kinds of situations either
one the server application
exits or restarts cleanly for
updating the executable or updating the
configuration
or there is a server application crash
so the process
uh set faults and dies and the kernel
closes all of those millions of tcp
connections
so in either of these cases the clean
exit or a crash what you have here is
you have tcp
in the kernel bursting millions of fins
to millions of cell phones uh often in
the local region or country
so
obviously that has a problematic impact
um
in particular there's heavy network and
energy resource usage basically to find
in contact and wake up those millions of
dormant cell phone radios
and then there's also a significant
impact because the cell phone network
then has to cue those fins and
repeatedly retry them for the phones
where the radio is powered off or the
phone itself is powered off so it might
be retrying those fins all night in some
cases depending on the
the cell phone
system implementation
and uh that has the potential to cause
um cellular networks to become
overloaded um and in some cases fail uh
and so the concern here is that this
kind of scenario is a potential
scalability or reliability vulnerability
for some cell phone uh networks out
there
so um is this specific to tcp well
in tcp this problem
happens
in particular because the
responsibilities are typically split
between the application and the kernel
and here we have a case where the
application crashes or exits and then
the kernel still has the state for that
socket and it tries to finish the finac
finac handshake at the end
but can do this in a very bursty manner
for millions of connections uh
interestingly you know in in a protocol
like quick that's typically implemented
in user space you probably don't have
this problem uh because the kernel has
no transport state so if the application
exits cleanly or crashes the kernel has
no state so we can't actually
do this you know burst of a million fins
or the equivalent and so there's no
extra network load and so you don't run
into this problem
but in general presumably this problem
could happen for any kernel
transport
so the goal of the tcp silent close
effort uh was to say that upon
application exit or crash instead of
sending those big bursts of millions of
fins we want to basically manifest the
traditional behavior that the internet
has seen for either a kernel crash or a
machine crashing or powering off so
basically in that situation we have uh
all of the connections from the server
that just
crashed or died they go silent
and then any later incoming traffic for
those connections uh that's sent by the
client and then arrives at the
restored or rebooted or powered online
server then triggers a reset because
obviously that server's kernel has no
state for that connection
so
we still want it to be the case though
that upon
the normal or healthy close of a tcp of
an individual server tcp connection
we want to go ahead and use the
traditional
fin act fanatic handshake at the end
and one key design feature of this
approach is that
there's no new network behaviors
introduced in this kind of
silent close approach
because basically applications and tcp
stacks already have to be prepared for
this kind of silence and then a reset if
they try to later contact a remote
endpoint you know obviously before
this could happen with a kernel crash a
machine that's powered off
a cellular or wi-fi link that is no
longer usable because the user is too
far away from
an access point
um but after if we have a silent close
feature in place then obviously the same
symptoms can be manifested with an
application crash or an application exit
so just to clarify what we're talking
about here um if we compare a sort of
server process exit or crash you know
before with the traditional tcp
implementation you know the behavior you
get would be millions of fans going out
to the network uh in a burst to all
these handsets
being retransmitted many times or
retried many times
um and
after if you have a sort of silent close
feature um and there's a server process
extra crash you don't get that storm of
fins
and so what is the precise mechanism
that we're proposing here so the idea is
a boolean uh tcp silent close per socket
option set via set suck ups get via get
succot
and when this feature is enabled and a
tcp connection is closed or shut down
for any reason
then the kernel sends no fan since no
reset and the kernel frees the socket
state immediately
and effectively as said before the goal
is that upon application extra crash the
connection manifests the traditional
behavior for
a kernel crash or machine power off the
connection goes silent any later
incoming traffic just gets a reset
and in particular we've used this option
for years
at our team
for a limited set of very large scale
services
and we plan to send this code upstream
to linux
when netx opens i believe next week
uh and so we wanted to discuss this in
this community um since we wanted to to
start getting this in the open source
world
um
so the usage model is pretty simple uh
you the idea is you enable silent close
on a on a listener or immediately after
a connection is established after except
and thus
if the process crashes or exits at any
time during the normal operation of that
connection you don't get this large
scale burst of fins
however when the process wants to go
ahead and close a single tcp connection
because the work is done or the client
went away the idea is you sort of
disable this silent close feature and
then you do your clothes or your shut
down so that you get a normal fin act
handshake uh when everything is going
that smoothly and cleanly
uh you know the api is very simple set
sock opt pcb sign on close to value one
to enable you know zero to disable etc
uh you know the api details um
we would suggest that this is at least
for now guarded by a system so that the
system administrator has to explicitly
enable this since it's a new feature
we propose that the
child server sockets inherit from the
parent so that you don't need a new
system call to enable this on every new
connection
to reduce overhead uh we would propose
that that it overrides the eso linger
setting
and returns immediately
we looked at some other alternative
semantics um or considered those so for
example
we could say that perhaps if the
application
does a close or shutdown system call
perhaps that always attempts the finac
finic handshake and perhaps you only
would
have a silent close feature upon process
exit
either cleanly or due to crash um but we
decided that that would might prevent
applications from programmatically
deciding to silent close millions of
connections if they realize they need to
to manage memory or handle denial of
service attacks etc
um
usage considerations we do encourage
people before deploying this to really
consider the negative possible negative
impacts obviously if
the server is closing the connection
without the fins that could leave extra
memory usage either in the client side
or in the middle box so we do want
people to consider that so we do want
this to be a feature that's used
carefully and only to prevent outage
prevention
only to prevent outages not just to save
a few packets uh here and there
um
and there has been some related work in
this area that i think helps motivate
this and show that the community does
feel like there has been a long-standing
need for this kind of thing
so there was a paper from connex a
couple years ago
called asylum tcp connection closure and
their their motivating use case was
cellular networks as well although their
angle was reducing energy consumption
and signal load
um
that we thought was kind of a
heavyweight implementation because it
required a new option on the wire it
required you so you have to upgrade
client in the server os and then you
have to upgrade the client in the server
application to agree on this
enabling this so we didn't think that
was a good model
there's also so linger which has been
around for a long time with a similar
motivation like practical motivation of
scalability avoiding time weight state
on servers for millions of connections
um we thought this was similar in spirit
but we didn't want to change this sort
of long-standing api or add a new magic
number to that existing api and risk
compatibility issues
there's also an interesting silent close
implication of the linux tcp repair mode
which is for connection migration
but the semantics don't really
line up with what you want because if
you use tcp repair mode you basically
are serializing your connection state
and
disabling the operation of that
connection in the kernel which is not
exactly what we want to do here
here we want to basically be able to
continue to use this connection and just
say if that
application exits later on then we want
to have that asylum close for that
connection
um so yeah so the effort status we've
used it in years for years and we wanted
to open source this so we wanted to come
discuss with the community
um and uh yeah we wanted to invite a
discussion although i see we're probably
out of time but maybe on the list uh
people can connect with us or now as
well
thank you
thank you for the presentation um
we are basically out of time but maybe
three quick questions maya
and then a question i will be brief so
as you said on this where you talk about
user usage considerations you basically
have a trade-off here right you try to
reduce network load but you increase
load um at the other side and maybe
middle boxes by not sending something so
i'm i'm
not sure what i think about this idea
because i don't know how to rate the
straight up right i don't understand
what the implications are for for all
the involved parties
okay thank you yeah so it's our
estimation and experience that the
the extra amount the extra load that
it's imposing keep in mind is just
memory in the middle box and then the
client and those
pieces of the system already have to
have
logic in place to do garbage collection
and bound that state um so it's our
sense that it's a net safety improvement
to deploy something like this to avoid
accidental you know massively excessive
load on the cell phone network um
since the other
since the players that have to do with
the extra state already have to deal
with this
issue of value in that state
okay so the question i had was i
understand that you do this if you close
the socket or the close of the socket
because the process died but if you shut
down the reader right side i'm not sure
if uh if you do
if when you do that
the tcp connection should go away
um
so i don't think this
changes the shutdown of the read side um
on the right side
i believe
my recollection of how we've implemented
it is that if you enable silent close
and then you do a shutdown of the right
side i believe it omits the fin and
um
i think that's a
detail we could if people think if
people see problems with that we could
obviously discuss that we can discuss
this
yeah stuart last comment
thank you i'll try to make this quick
because we're over time
uh i see the arguments for this and i'm
not saying it's a bad idea
i am saying it needs to be done very
carefully
i think there's a real risk of
unintended consequences here
uh it's very easy like in the research
paper you cited
they don't send the finn to save packets
and as you say this puts a bigger memory
burden on nats and firewalls for that
state
and that also has a consequence
because
uh i'm sure you're aware right now
tcp net mappings tend to have a much
longer lifetime than udp mappings and
the reason that gateways could do that
and firewalls and other metal boxes
is because they can assume they'll see a
tcp pin or recess
that tells them when a tcp connection is
done so merely the lack of traffic does
not mean a connection
uh as has been abandoned
if this socket option is widely
available on linux that makes it very
easy to just abandon connections then
that will force gnats to be much more
aggressive without scavenging apparently
idle tcp mappings just like they do for
udp today
and then you might end up having to send
10 times as much keep live traffic in
this future world so
this apparently well motivated move to
save one fin packet
has the consequence
that we're now sending 10 times as much
keeper live traffic 24 hours a day to
stop these connections
yeah i agree it's something we have to
carefully consider it's i guess my sense
is that
hopefully
these um these not boxes
are using some sort of
lru
[Music]
map you know lre policy for eviction
anyway so hopefully it would work out in
practice
given that the
given the intended usage model but yeah
there's at this point
we have the reality today
that
one of the reasons quick is not suitable
for long-lived mostly idle connections
like push notification connections
is because
udp mappings have to be aggressively
recycled because there's no explicit fin
or reset
and
and if we effectively move tcp in the
direction that it also has no explicit
connection termination
we should expect to see the same
lifetime for tcp mappings as we
currently have the udp mappings
okay
thank you for for the discussion thank
you for attending um
i suggest to move the discussion on the
mailing list um i would say thank you
for attending the meeting and
um
michael yoshi you want to say
a final word or
if that's not the case
then i would say goodbye and see you
next time
and
wherever it is
bye
yeah thanks a lot for learning tcpm5
you