uh
hello
all right i think uh
i think it would be good to get started
uh welcome to the second session on
tuesday
this is sedates
my name's uh mark mcfadden i'm one of
the co-chairs
braun is the handsome one in the video
and um
and what my goal here is is to get the
preliminaries out of the way so that we
can have a good discussion
so good morning good afternoon and good
evening to all of you
um
let's see here if i can do this
uh here's the
ah
here's the note well
um the
the chairs are advised to stress the
note well this time and it's it's good
for you to
remind yourself of what's in here one of
the things that i want to take just a
moment to do
is to uh remind you of
the fact that the i the work in the ietf
is
human collaboration and as a result that
collaboration
works best when people are respectful to
each other understand the fact that they
have different backgrounds
and so
one of the things to know is that we
have guidelines for conduct we have an
anti-harassment policy
and we also have a group of people
who are
both trained up and willing to help
address any harassment issues
so
i put this slide in the slide deck just
as a reminder to all of us i don't think
there's a problem in sedate in fact i
know there's not a problem in sedate but
if you experience this either in sedate
or in any other working group you have
resources to use uh and as a code of
conduct for the rest of us i think this
is particularly important
um uh the agenda here i'll i'll do a
little bit of agenda bashing but not
much
because i really want to focus entirely
on the document that we have and i'm
going to basically turn it over to
carsten to do that
uh i have already talked about the note
well as i said we have a
the working group has a single document
that's the one we're going to talk about
let me just talk a few minutes about
a liaison here's some potentially useful
information
there is a
github repository
where the pull requests are being
collected uh for our our document and uh
of course the charter is in the usual
place can be found on data tracker in
the usual way
um our charter talks about a liaison and
the chairs have had a conversation
back in august with the iab to
request a liaison
to tc-39
the iab agreed in the beginning of
october
to go ahead and do a liaison that
process is a formal uh iab process
uh that basically got kicked off on
october 5th
uh the ieb asked for candidates and on
october 22nd
the iab had a list of candidates
volunteers and has started interviewing
those volunteers
i do have
information that some of those
volunteers have been contacted by the
ieb and the iab is hoping to make
progress on that process um quickly
after ietf112
so unless there are questions here i
think that
what i'll promise to do is i'll promise
to keep the mailing list informed about
the progress uh for this liaison because
as you know we're trying to make
progress on this
document fairly quickly wrap up the
working group fairly quickly and so one
of the things we said to the iab is we
need progress on the liaison
in short order as well
so that's my update on the liaison and
my promise to the working group
basically is that as i hear things from
the ieb i'll continue to
let the mailing list know about the
progress we're making on the liaison
so let me just pause for a second and
see if there any questions
okay well i'm pleased to say that the uh
meat of the agenda is to be turned over
to the discussion of our one document
this was as you know adopted as a
working group item the last time we got
together
uh there's a new version available uh
dasha1
uh carson sent out uh carsten has
actually done a lot of work and i'm not
going to
steal his fire here steal his thunder
i'm gonna just let him talk in a second
you can see the mailing list for the
outline of issues and in the last five
days
there has been a really healthy and i
think really positive discussion on the
mailing list
and
lots of good proposals and so
without any further ado let me turn it
over to carson
to he has some slides
and um i just would like carsten to
manage the discussion
let me stop sharing my screen
okay so you now all
should see
my slides and if somebody enables it
also me
those look good yeah
i look good too but you can't see it
you have to know you need to turn your
video on separately if you want to do
that
yes i did a video request oh no i didn't
uh you've done a screen request
yeah we think it can be so confusing
thank you
sorry about that
okay so um
let's jump right into where we are so on
october 20th we had a new version of the
draft
there are some some eight issues open on
github which
maybe don't cover
the whole ground here
so i propose the structure of discussion
with five points one two five
uh but given what has happened on the
mailing list i inserted a point zero
which we probably have to do before we
go to
uh one two five
um and the point zero is what are we
doing here anyway
um so um the the charter tells us that
we are
extending rfc 33 39
time stamps and
where we could do this to provide
additional information and that's
actually what the charter talks about
um or we could also do this to to
actually change the semantics so the the
timestamp on its own means something
different than
the timestamp with the extensions that
that we have added
so just to remind people what 3339 does
for us
it gives us a utc timestamp and it gives
us
the ability to add an annotation which
is a time zone offset and numeric offset
that
allows you to understand which time zone
this particular time was
meant to be in
but not in the sense of a human readable
time zone but just in the sense of time
zone offset
and
yeah it's a matter of syntax that when
you do that the
time that you actually look at no longer
is utc but is in that offset but that's
just just that's not a semantic thing
it's just the way the way this is
represented
so i
try to summarize what happened on the
the mailing list in particular i'm
referencing this particular mail which
you unfortunately cannot click on but
it's one of the most recent
mails that were
sent
on the mailing list
so on the annotation side where we keep
33 39 unchanged but just add more
information
uh we certainly have the the proposal to
add a human readable time zone
so i can say that sometime actually is
in the your berlin
time zone and not just that it's a plus
0100 or plus 0 depending on
the time of the year
and
of course there are also other
annotations display hints
and so on that can go there and
but the point is this is still a 3339
timestamp just with some additional
helpful information
so any 3339
implementation can be modified to just
ignore
everything that is in this new extension
syntax for instance by ignoring
everything that starts with a
open square bracket and and we have
perfect interability
um but we also have been talking about
other things including modifications
and in particular there is this thing
that that was called b in this
list where we have essentially the same
information you have a 33 39 time stamp
plus a human readable time zone
but we actually mean
that the human readable time zone
overrides the time zone offset if the
semantics of that human readable time
zone changes from the time
the
timestamp is generated to the time the
time storm the time
stamp is consumed
and
there are some
details how you can do this but i think
the the point here really is
this is a kind of time stamp
that is a little bit wobbling around
based on on politic politicians
decisions
uh but after a while it actually
converges to to an actual timestamp
it's just a little bit more
difficult to interpret it because you
have to have access to a current
time zone information database
so that that's
something different from from the
annotation thing that's why i called it
modification thing
and then of course there are other
modifications one can think about for
instance time scales i think that would
be a really useful thing to have but
still it's a modification so again if
we say this looks like an rfc 3339
timestamp but it really is in tai and
not in utc
uh that that's changing the semantics
and finally there have been
new semantics which are not covered
by by the concept of a 33 39 timestamp
at all so not not a fixed point in time
or at least the time where we can
converge to a fixed point
after a while
so for instance a floating time
which is a time stamp that only becomes
one
when you add local context so it's
not
um interpretable without that context
of course the data structure that this
timestamp is
integrated in that might provide the
context so you can still have full
interoperability
on these time steps but the the
timestamp by itself
um is is quite different from
uh what the 3339
timestamp would be
even if it synthetically looks very
similar
uh the question really is
um
should we be doing modifications and uh
completely new semantics so that the
points b and c
on the
previous slides in this working group or
not i'm not talking about what the
charter says about that i can read the
charter
but should we do that
uh so is that something that that is
better done in the context with the
other extensions that are covered by a
and
of course
once we do this one interesting question
is should this still look like a 3339
extension or maybe
should it
prevent
false intervality by by looking
sufficiently different that a 3339
implementation is not going to
misunderstand it for
33.39
um
timestamp
so the argument for
my argument i would use for for doing
one and two is that
we could make sure that these modified
or new semantics
could actually mesh very well with what
we already chartered to do which is a
and yeah just uh to to to remind people
you all have the charters on your
laptops but just in case we need this
for the discussion that sure will start
now
i have put the relevant parts of the
charter on three slides here run
point that i would make with all of this
my life
so the queue is open
uh thanks uh for that introduction
karsten and brian go ahead
yep um so
the only point i would make is that if
the time zone name can override the
offset
then we're already in in the space where
the the time plus offset the the
timestamp or exact point in time is not
fixed in place and as soon as you're
doing that you may as well do all the
floating stuff as well
because at that point
you need to you need to read the context
to resolve exactly the time stamp it
could shift depending on context and
once you once you say it could shift
then we should do all the good shifts
but i'd be happy to also to find
something that doesn't allow the
timezone name to override
the time point if that's what we want to
do
but yeah that one one or the other i
think not half and half
okay neil
um i just wanted to say yeah the the
thing is that some of these things are
just not time stamps they're just date
times um but that's
fine there's
a lot of applications on the web that
need date times with the time zone or
date times that's wall clock time that
does have doesn't have any time zone
associated at all
uh and
defining a standard way of serializing
those is good for interoperability and
that's what i thought the temporal group
looking for when they first came to the
itf with this
proposal um so
i would
say it's fine for it you know
to to not be the same as 3339 we just
don't say it's an extension that we say
it's a separate thing it's just
adding
more uh standard serializations for
common things on the internet just like
3339 did
thanks for watching
lad cloudflare uh
so i would
argue for b1 over b and the reason being
that if you don't know
if you don't see the offset you don't
know how to understand the time zone
an implementation will realize it
doesn't have an offset
but if we have the
the time zone override the offset in
cases where those differ
the implementation that understands the
time zone will
represent we'll think it's a different
time
than the one that's actually specified
and that would be unfortunate
especially in cases where like there's
user entry that can happen
um
i do want to say though that does but
also time zones
time zones
since 1970 more or less
are not going to change retroactively
so if you have a past time let's say in
europe berlin just as an example
the the offset for that time is known
and it's not going to shift although
future times this whole question about
how do you know what time it will be in
the future where you don't
um but that's not
not really a concern that's that's more
calendaring things
yeah i think the the observation about
b
b or b1
is that the time zone info database
content is going to change over
time so the interpretation of that
date time timestamp whatever
is going to change
but as you say it's very unlikely to
change retroactively now
so the interpretation is going to
converge
into something
um at least uh well a small time after
the
timestamp actually happened
so that's still different from a
floating time with which is entirely
unfixed
uh i just want to say the
the semantics are entirely different if
i am living in berlin and i write down
that it is 1pm berlin time
then it is 1 pm berlin time and whether
or not the off you know 20 years later
people are confused about what the
offset was the time i wrote down
is the same
so
saying that you know you can't have the
two
if you actually want to have an
unambiguous utc thing set your clock to
utc and keep your timestamp in utc
you shouldn't have a time zone if you
want your timestamp to be a utc one
uncertainty about offsets looking back
is an intended result of putting in a
time zone
um i think brawn next in the queue
or out of the queue maybe i'll go to
ujjwal
hello am i audible
yes
okay perfect uh i just wanted to first
quickly uh plus one the the point that
was just raised like by watson i i think
you know the the core distinction
can't hear you
maybe i will let you resolve any
audio problems you have i couldn't i can
hear him you can hear him
[Music]
that's weird
maybe yeah
um maybe mark you could try refreshing
or something like that
oh or he cannot hear me he can't hear
you mark you might need to refresh your
audio let me ping him
okay uh can i continue yeah
okay uh i was saying that one of the
sort of promises that we make uh
in in the
uh in the rc or sort of tentative rc uh
is that uh
the implementations that don't
understand any or all extensions would
still resolve the time
uh
you know exactly the same way it would
just uh you know have have difficulty
with other operations and i think that
promise is somewhat broken
if you
if you allow b
but
yeah b1
sort of doesn't have that so so it ties
back into the point carsten made about
yeah do we want them to even
be interoperable with 339 maybe it's uh
you know it's it's not good if they
if you want something else maybe it
should look different so that there's
there's no way that there's a mismatch
or something like that
yeah i still might want to share code so
so some similarity is probably
useful
michael
oh um
yeah i just i just
wondrous emphasis
on
on times just being in the past is is is
misplaced i mean
people are going to publish future times
which are prone to having the um
that the time zone rules change
more than people think i believe
and when you track
time zone
in certain areas the the world time zone
specifications change quite a bit and
at the last minute
so
um
i don't know you can guarantee that any
offset you've put in there is going to
be valid when when you actually come to
the actual point in time
it may be more
true that
they don't change in retrospect but
that's
i don't think we're dealing with that
all the time
let's see
watson again
i think it's important to understand
what people mean when they specify
future times if i say i'm going to meet
you at 12 p.m
or grand central i mean when the hand of
the talk in grand central station both
of them are pointing straight up
and whether or not that is a certain
offset from utc
isn't really the problem
and so a few you know
now what the issue is what happens if
you're specifying
this for a region that that that
suddenly changes the way it keeps its
clock
and that's a very thorny problem because
required
wait a minute though
before we go too far down down that road
yo i i i get your point if you happen to
if it was real meetings real people in
the same time zone the problems occur
when you're trying to set up
a uh
a meeting that cro that's in different
time zones
but what time zone do you want your
meeting to be specified in
you you each want your time to be your
time zone what you agree on what the
contract you make is to meet at the same
instant in time which can be ultimately
expressed as utc there's a correct
there's a thing you said which is
absolutely correct what matters to
people
more than anything else what is the
invariant to people is their local time
not utc
so when you say you want a meeting
at at midday or 2 p.m you mean midday or
2pm local time your time but if you're
meeting with somebody in a different
time zone they are meeting at say 8 a.m
in the morning
now right
for you to meet so utc
we are all pretty familiar with that
problem
so
i think yes
that that problem exists
the the question really is what is this
working group trying to do about
i it
i understand that but expressing say
these times as utc or a fixed offset
doesn't resolve those problems because
if the rules change then the utc has to
change
yes i think everybody in this game is
aware
i i think i think there's i don't think
saying that you're going to have local i
think that prom is inherently insoluble
you don't know whether next year
you know let's say it's a meeting
between say someone in arizona
and or in someone in california you
don't know whether next year one of them
changes time zones
and or it changes the data which the
thing happens so
something has to shift
yep and it's the offset
yeah when you schedule an event
which is why i say the offset is the
wrong thing for future times
i completely agree with that
now there's a use for having the offset
and the timezone id in that you can
detect
that they no longer agree and then you
can actually do something about it and
what you have to do about it is you
can't just automatically fix it you have
to reschedule those things
yeah i think we really have determined
that this use case exists
let me just put out the other use case
so so why
maybe you understand why this is not
quite as simple the other use case is
that i have a certificate i want to be
able to say when that certificate runs
out
and
there it's
usually not useful to factor in
decisions of politicians but you want to
have an absolute time when that goes
away
so you know when you have to install the
new one instead of it
and i think people are pretty pretty
adamant that the times they put into
certificates
actually mean something very specific so
both use cases exist
rfc 3339 is kind of leaning
towards the the let's have an actual
point in time
so that that's the problem itself today
and what we are trying to to find out
here is
uh what are the the additions we can
make and where do we make them
and what we probably don't need to
discuss is whether the problem exists i
think we are all the way out there
apologies i claim to be back
um
and i don't know who's next in the queue
here is it michael
i think most of what i wanted to say is
uh
is is redundant with what you just
mentioned but yeah i just wanted to
point out that we already have agreement
that both
uh use cases are legitimate for
different applications it's just that
we already have a way to to represent a
instant in time if we know exactly
uh you know when the certificate expires
we can already represent that
in a format right but we but we have no
way to represent
let's meet 9am in in melbourne time like
that's not
something that you can do in the
standard space right now and so the
question is not as much as
uh
is is this even useful but
you know like
do we want to do this and if yes where
should we do it
yeah it may be useful to point out that
there are other standards that already
provide that so somebody cited the
icalendar
standard on the mailing list so that
that provides a way to to have a
future
time
in in the sense that that b that's
called b here
yeah so i think we've we've gone around
in circles enough on this to say that we
should
i guess decide whether we want to work
on it or not that's really the question
ahead of us is should should we do that
this question one here should we
do a
time that is not an exact point in time
format
in this working group and i don't know
if we need to do
a poll for that
to decide
um our charter doesn't specifically
allow us to do it though we could
we could do it by not
by basically doing the options that i
proposed which are and not
making any changes to rfc 339 bit but
having things that could
add an additional offset to it basically
that gets calculated by
the time zone rules changing or by
whatever by floating which says resolve
it in your current context whatever that
happens to be
so what do you what do you think mark
should we do a
poll on this or should we just ask
people to speak on it i'm aware we're
already halfway through our time slot
yeah we're halfway through um
um i'm puzzled maybe a poll let's see
here
a poll would be
although i think the important point is
that if we want to do one two we need to
initiate a recharge process quickly
and we need to be very certain
what the scope what extent of that
recharge ring is going to be do we
actually include c for instance or is a
c out of scope and we only do b
um i think that's something that we
should be deciding pretty soon
all of this doesn't have to stop us from
doing a and actually even maybe
finishing and publishing
an rfc that does a
but i think people are so interested in
this other
use case that we need to develop a
position on it even though it's not in
our chart
so i think scoping would be extremely
important if we rechartered um
especially
in in
it'd be very important to make sure that
we are explicit about what is out of
scope
um that's just one person's opinion and
that's without my chair add-on i think
the scoping conversation
while you say would need to happen very
quickly and i agree with that i think
what will be very important is how
how the scope is limited right
uh so
i don't know braun do you have any
thoughts about that
i mean
we would basically
have to say that we we're
creating it the same extension for both
a
a point in time and
floating date time
um and that the floating date time is
not replacing three three three nine
it's but it can be used with the same
same contextual extensions that can be
used to resolve it
the problem is that this is
this is taking even longer and temporal
is is
already
we promised somebody would try and get
something so that they could actually
bake this stuff into web browsers so
yeah
i think what you should speak i was
actually just asking
uh carsten how how much this would delay
us
uh i i
as you pointed out we're we've been
working on temple and we
would like to be shipping out soon and i
i think it would be really sad if we
uh if we have to ship something that's
not standardized i would not prefer that
at all uh so
uh we we should try at least as much as
we can to
to
to take the fastest route
one thing that i was thinking
is that if if recharging
is
is going to take a substantially
long time one thing we could do is that
since a large number of
uh
you know these these different
derived formats so to say are uh you
know useful
mostly in the calendaring space
we could do that sort of reification uh
in
uh in in calyx and then
change the
uh draft that we have here to to not
only
uh you know
like link two to 359 but also to that
and say okay this can extend
all of these formats not just the the
timestamp format what do people think of
that
proposal
so maybe this is the time for for our
esteemed ad francesca to say a few words
sorry for putting you on the spot
no worries um
i do you have more precise question
because i mean accepted saying that
rechartering would in my opinion not be
quick and um
yeah would take some time especially if
you go to the next slide
i think where you had the charter
was by the one after
um
yeah no i don't know what slide it was
that had the the see the current charter
on
uh here you go
um
so
yeah given this
at the current text and and the effort
that it took to get to this charter
um
yeah i would be uh careful about
like if there are time constraints rich
ordering
might not be the best idea but i'm just
listening in to what everybody's
opinions are
or casting did you want me to
no i think
your estimation for for
how how long a recharging would
uh take is is very important in in this
discussion so if this is something where
if we
came up with a very very specific
scope we could make it happen quickly
that would
make it
push the decision into one direction and
if we find out this is going to be
another rattle
uh it would push us okay so
so from a purely process point of view a
rechartering should take around i
believe something like six weeks if
everything is already in place and this
six weeks should start in the beginning
of december
at least so
that's at least
two and a half three months
and that's and that's assuming that you
know everybody can agree on on
recharging text and and scope and
uh motivation and evaluation
um
yeah that is also mentioned in the
current charter so that's
important to to do yeah
[Music]
so i would expect us to take about the
same time to to
fix up the documents
of course we couldn't make one document
a working group document before the
recharger is at least in a
definitive stage
um
again the the the other thing we could
do or maybe we can do both at the same
time
is
write up the
case a here
and make sure all the mechanics for
actually defining extensions are already
in there
so we just have to add this this one
little ingredients that we are actually
doing things beyond 3339
at the time when we are chartered to do
that
i think that's an interesting way
forward because one of the things that
we could potentially do here
is immediately start
working on draft text for rechartering
and then also schedule an interim so
that
being sensitive to temporal
uh that we're making we're making clear
and definitive progress right that we're
not waiting we're not waiting until
march to make more progress here
although i think i want to say again
that you know the
the conversation that's gone on the list
in the last five days has been really
constructive
uh i do think having an interim might be
a way of pushing the work forward a
little more quickly and that's something
i'll bring up at the end of the session
but i can actually see um
three parallel tracks there right is
continuing work on the existing document
and putting putting a into it uh working
in a track where we recharter and then
have an individual submission to
actually deal with for instance b1
um
so that we were making we were making
forward progress
in parallel with rechartering
that's that's one approach anyway i
don't know if people have any comments
about that
that strategy
works for me
i guess the other question for
for
the temporal group is
is this useful to you
in this shape without the ability to do
floating time
or the ability to have the zone override
the offset
i i guess i could speak to that the
uh the idea is that uh
temporal
does
have those semantics
uh
but then because temporal is is in a
special situation where it is a
programming language api so there's more
ways to represent that so so in this
case we
we
of course do not allow the
uh you know this information of saying
okay the the
time zone overrides the
offset be represented in the interchange
format but then you know the programmer
can specify that on their end so
so it's like still doable
uh and therefore we we don't need but we
don't have a pressing need for this
all right in that case i think
definitely pushing ahead with this
document
with
timestamps only makes sense
and also doing the recharging in
parallel because we can publish this one
without recharging
shouldn't i have is that if if he
published this one with with what we
have right now
say
would we need to
say you know push a
new version obsoleting this once we
once we have the the other document
published so that it says okay it can
extend both or can we do that in some
way right now
by saying okay this this applies to
uh
you know any derived formats
and not just that specific format
well i wouldn't write it in such a way
that it has to be obsoleted
i mean if we have a pretty good idea of
where where we are going in the next
step we can make the first step go into
the right direction
so it would just be another document
that is added to it
and
that sounds really good
yeah that sounds really ideal i think
the the way i hear it it doesn't delay
the document we have and it allows us to
to start working on the supplementary
document right away so i think i really
like that idea
so with my chair hat back on i'm hearing
gradual consensus there i i want to make
sure that the mic is open for other
points of view
but uh there is this uh
emerging consensus that we continue to
work on the existing document and move
it forward as quickly as we can
in parallel with a uh
a rechartering pro process that is uh
has a very brisk uh scoping
and then also the beginnings of a
beginnings of the new document for
uh
like i said b and b one here b or b
one so it's it's basically three
parallel tracks that the working group
would proceed on
let me just leave the mic open here and
see if there's anyone else that wants to
talk to that planned path forward
i will say editorially
what's nice about that is that continues
uh
continues to get us towards a work
product relatively quickly
it really addresses the issues that have
come up in the last five days i like
that a lot
and
and i'm not afraid of the rechartering
process i think that
work can be done after ietf112 to move
move reasonably quickly on that
although everything that francesca says
about the recharging process is true all
the
process that it has to go through so let
me just pause here and see if anyone
else wants to
come to the queue
wow i see no one okay
so i'm going to assume that we have
consensus on that path forward
and that someone has very bravely
made a note of what we've decided
uh
let me just make it karsten you're okay
with that as a way forward
yeah i think
we have lots in place that can make
us generate a document for a
and we should simply do that and this
allows us to get for instance the syntax
issues out of the way
before we
actually go into the semantics issues
that may
make b or c a little bit more
complicated than it seems at the moment
okay that's fine maybe it was wrong
that i i wanted to sort of
ask about from the chat
is that uh if the
if publishing this
document that we have right now is not
blocked on rechartering or uh
you know the second document do we have
a pressing reason to to do anything
very quickly
uh because
i i think temple can ship after we we
have this one
published right so
so my understanding of
my understanding here is that we would
move quickly on the existing document
and we have a
in the charter we have a
timeline that suggests that we would get
a
document to the iesg by december
i think that is aspirational at this
point but that's a conversation that i
want to save time to have here at the
end of our session
um i and the reason that i keep
stressing uh parallel development here
is because i am sensitive
to uh
temporals timelines and i'm also
sensitive to the fact that when we were
chartered as a working group we were
chartered as a short-lived working group
we don't want to i i and i don't want to
put words in francesca's mouth but we
don't want to be in a situation where
we're
sort of like barnacles on the side of a
boat sort of adding to the charter over
time right we want a clear and fairly
succinct scope
um that would be my answer to your
to your point
i had um i think i have john next in the
queue
mark i just wanted to make a quick
procedural observation about something
you said
which is that especially given some of
the people who are not participating
in this session possibly because of
conflicts with other working groups
um
uh we don't have consensus on anything
that was confirmed on the mailing list
so john um i completely agree with i was
simply talking about concession in
consensus in the session and we would
obviously
take back any discussions that we had in
the working group meeting back to the
mailing list for
a consensus call i i completely agree
with you i i just wanted to make certain
that was clear and i assumed you knew it
but i want to be sure this could go
anywhere else yeah let me let me be very
clear about my intention and the reason
that i was hoping that braun was making
a note there is that if we have a clear
and succinct understanding of what the
proposed pathway forward is
that i would take the responsibility of
getting that out to the mailing list in
short order and asking for discussion
and potentially consensus around that
path forward
again john knowing that um
i'd like to drive that consensus as
quickly as i can
i i hope we're all in favor of that and
thanks very much
cool we have 13 minutes left to uh
address all the rest of these slides so
we probably should keep moving
yeah i think the the the interim is
really needed
[Music]
um so the the my hope would be that we
actually can get the the document in a
state where where it actually
shows that this working group can
get things done at the time the the
final decision about reset the recharge
ring
needs to be done so this is an incentive
another incentive to do this quickly
so should i go to the other slides
please there
okay
so um i think we have five areas uh
where we need to get work done and
the first of all is uh of course the
overall format
um so we already had some discussion
about ascii this is utf-8 i don't want
to open that discussion right now i just
want to remind people that we have to
have an opinion on that
maybe more important is that we need to
explain what it means to receive an
extension you don't understand
so if all extensions are annotations
that actually simple
once they actually modify the the
meaning that becomes a little bit more
complicated
an annotation may be something that you
really want the recipient to understand
before
using the time so um yeah in many other
protocols we have something like must
understand flags or something like that
so i think that that's an area where we
need to understand what what we
need to do or what we want to do here
um yeah and finally the thing really
needs a name
could somebody please invent a name for
this
um
[Music]
any comments on the quick comments on
this
okay
um yeah the time zone extension i think
is is uh
pretty clear what what that is in
particular if it's uh just an annotation
then i think we we understand that so so
issue number three is is already
answered by the discussion
uh we already had and may we have to
spend a little bit of time thinking
about forward compatibility
uh issues
uh here so what what do you do with the
time zone names that actually are
deleted from the database
and so on
but i think apart from that this this is
uh this should be a slander
now the the next question is naming the
other extensions and the the current
draft has a pretty complicated
mechanism so you don't name any other
extensions
you first of all delegate namespaces to
different organizations that then
run registries for extensions within
that organization
sounds complicated
there's also a
[Music]
consideration that uh names usually
start out as somebody
making an experiment and then this
experiment grows and so on and if we
have
names that that try to reveal that this
is experimental stuff
uh the the x dash
uh will continue to be in that name you
will never get rid of it again so i
think we have to think about how we run
these registries
a little bit
more but my proposal would be to get rid
of the whole delegation thing
because that leads to a complicated
mechanism of making another organization
act in a way that this
document describes
and i think we can just skip all that
and and create a single registry
and make it reasonably easy to actually
register something there or maybe
reasonably hard if we want to but we
have to decide on what's the
threshold we want to uh put in there
there is a concept of a single character
namespace which is currently only
provided for the unicode consortium
and
the text seems to imply
that a single
that any unicode
specification automatically can define
or automatically already defines an
extension mechanism
for the timestamp and i'm not sure that
actually works
so the the u-dash ca that is given as an
example here
that doesn't really tell me enough to to
write software to handle this
so again my proposal would be to
just get rid of this
make sure that we have a good way to
take in
extensions from from
the unicode consortium
maybe require them to spec them out in a
way that they actually are usable
in the
extended format we define
and yeah let's the
last slide here is about the
multi-character
namespaces
i already said this this is more complex
than it
needs to be we could still reserve
extension name prefixes so if we say
u-dash
goes to unicode
that's probably a simple thing to add to
this
registry but apart from that just having
a registry for
information elements that that could be
added by
an organization that writes a
specification which includes the itf
itself of course
sounds much simpler than what we have
now
comments
okay which walk around
i think that i was sort of clarifying on
the on the chat was
that the
the whole
procedure that that i have seems rather
convoluted in hindsight it was something
that i borrowed from bcp-47
so i don't feel strongly in favor of it
or anything and i'd be happy
to
to to take in any uh simplifications
okay that's helpful
i go ahead and comment in the chat about
vanity registrations and so on
um so i think it's pretty clear that we
have to have an expert review
type mechanism here and the the
job the poor designated expert would
have to do is fend off
uh vanity registrations
um so i think that that's standard
material and and we know how to do that
and
i don't think this is particularly more
attractive than other
targets
for people i'm not going to talk about
one particular person who has been very
visible
so
i think we can handle that
yeah and i would say that
my experience with ayanna is they have a
lot of experience in this area
defending against vanity registrations
uh john in the queue
i'm going to respectfully disagree diana
has had problems with that kind of thing
since pastel handed over control to a
committee
uh and uh and they resist
things where they're forced to make
those kinds of decisions and designated
experts do not work with this country
where the serious controversy is
distinct from
uh trying to make things
um
consistent with the setting norms about
how they're described and this meeting
conflicting with the media type
one is a real disaster in stanford
heaviest discussion
i i i would expect that if
um
if you said designated experts going to
make these kinds of decisions among
competing entities who are interested in
registering names
that um uh that you would get resistance
miami and you would probably if they're
on their 12th get resistance to isg
um
this this
this is a tough problem
now i agree the designated expert ought
to be able to project nonsense if i
decide i want to register a thing called
john which is time so wherever i haven't
been standing at the moment i would hope
a designated expert would be able to
beat me when i had enough to discourage
that registration attempt
but uh but if you get two legitimate
attempts to register the same string
with different semantics the system is
not going to deal with that
well at least you will make sure that
only one of these registrations goes
goes through
well then the traditional solution to
that it's going to first come first
serve and that raises its own set of
problems
no
this is not a candidate for comfort
serve um no it's not absolutely
yeah
um
let me see here i want i do uh i know we
have four minutes left and i do want to
reserve a couple minutes to talk about
future actions here
um and i i understand uh john's point
and respectfully disagree in some cases
here um
other uh
let me just leave the queue open one
last time for
any further comments about carsten's
last five slides here
[Music]
okay
what i'd like to do then is chair
is summarize what i've heard
and
just get a thumbs up from braun that
this is the way forward
so what we're going to do is take to the
mailing list commitment to move continue
to move forward
on the existing working group document
and try to do that at pace
the second thing is we're going to
have a conversation on the mailing list
about
rechartering and potentially
asking someone to do an individual
submission that meets
additional requirements that have been
identified both in this meeting and in
the last five days
so that we have a path that has three
tracks
one is the existing document and
continuing to make progress on it
and then two other uh things uh a
working group recharter
and also another document
um
i note uh and as as chair this is
something that concerns me
and braun as well that we have in our uh
in the charter for our timeline we have
a
deadline of delivering uh our first
document to the iesg in december
and what i'd like to do now is sort of
have a reality check about
getting that done in december
and see if anyone has any comments about
whether that's doable or we should
revise that date
well we need two weeks for the regular
school we need one week for
thanksgiving we need one week for
uh the holidays uh and so on and we
probably need a couple of weeks to
actually do the work so that that's a
pretty aspiration i would say
yeah i i'm tempted to say the same thing
um
how
that was going to be exactly my
my contribution
if we make it february of next year
one of the things a working group could
decide to do is have an interim in
january to sort of clean up and and
truly finish the document
prior to working group last call
and so
i like the idea of february of next year
let me see uh if there's anyone that
wants to get in the queue to talk about
that change
okay like the others that's something
that i will take back to the mailing
list and propose
as a change
the last thing that's on my agenda then
and i know i'm at time here
is how do people feel about
the chairs or
organizing an interim meeting in january
i can reply to that i would actually
have one in december
and one in january but
that's maybe just my kind of working
would you also in the queue
go ahead
that i i was wondering if you could do
one sooner
um
well let me do this uh let me talk to
braun offline
about the timing of that
and if uh if he and i can make it work
uh we'll try to have one in december
what i would propose is that if we do
one in december then and that at that
december meeting we would decide whether
or not we need another one in january
rather than scheduling both of them i
think it should be on an as needed basis
while i do agree that in order to make
um you know quick progress on the
existing working group document
i think an interim in december would be
useful i just want to make sure that we
can get the
uh the interested people there
does that seem right to you bro
yeah i think so we'll
sort out a uh
some kind of poll and work out when we
can get the bulk of the bulk of the key
people there
that sounds like a good path forward
okay um uh we are at end time here
uh is there any other issue that someone
wants to bring up
well otherwise uh on behalf of the
chairs thanks to everybody for
another intriguing conversation
i'll be posting uh as i promised to i'll
be posting things to the list probably
try to still get some of that done today
and tomorrow
and then uh braun and i will have a
conversation about how to get started on
uh scheduling an interim in december
with that thanks to everyone
and talk to you soon
see you and gather possibly uh some
people decided we're gonna go chat there
so might catch you over there