all right i think it's time
let's see if i can turn my video on
good morning good afternoon and good
evening everyone
this is our our last day home stretch
welcome to the trusted execution
environment and provisioning working
group
hopefully you can hear me now
let's go ahead and get started um
i think most of you are very familiar
with the note well
with respect to the ipr
um
and how we conduct our business here
one thing that we wanted to call out
is the code of conduct we want to follow
this is based on rfc 7154
and to summarize here it's basically for
us to treat each other with respect
we are all professionals coming in with
our own point of view and diverse
backgrounds
so we should keep our discussions um
more of an impersonal and to the point
um
as we're working to define
solutions that will inter-operate across
the globe okay
so given that i will thank hannes in
advance i've got the links here
um good to see you i've got my co-chair
with me here
um and i've just noted the links here
for
the meeting materials as well as the
note-taking um i forgot to update um
no i think the minutes link is correct
so thank you hannes for being our
notetaker
i encourage everyone else it's a live
document to go to the um
uh
cody md or whatever it's called now
hedgehog um
and help out and
if you can also help us
um recording
that will help
sorry if i got the title slide wrong
hannes what did i do
yeah okay my bad i'll do better next
time
okay so
oh shoot yeah
you're right
okay so
uh agenda for today
um
we've got
akira
providing us the hackathon
we
still have our um
architecture and protocol drafts
have been submitted to
um
publication
uh for today we've just got the
hackathon report um
akira i've got you and i think you've
embedded them in your slides to talk
about the um
the suit and teap i think that was also
part of your hackathon
but there's a github request
for this and then the rest of the time
we'll spend um
talking about the protocol see i'm like
not awake
it should say protocol not not
architecture my bad
uh so barring those updates
any
any other agenda bash
going once going twice
right so
akira
do you want me to share your slides
um
no i think i would like to share my
screen
okay
go for it good
and i could
flip the page
how
how does is my screen showing right now
uh no we just see your video
oh i see
um
yeah i think the chairs
you should accept uh his request to show
you their desktop or the
reloaded slides
ah thank you okay perfect
oh there it is yeah it's interesting i
see two two icons for the share
yes this is because he asked to share uh
desktop and then click on the other icon
you can deny the other request
okay i've tried to accept both
i see your slides now
and
how do i flip it just a minute
so in the lower you should see
this uh oh there it is
i see
wow got it i didn't know
i didn't know the progress from the last
idea i think
yeah and i think the arrow keys on your
keyboard will also work
yeah it definitely depends
oh yeah it does
so i put two things in the slide one is
about the hackathon and another one is
for the uh
adding three suit format examples in
teep
so um i'm going to start from hackathon
talking about hackathon
we
yeah we were
having a hackathon last week with the
jointly with suit working group
yes
um yes received very early email on
tuesday
from hannes
and yes we we jumped in
and also we had we um on the in japan
side in in japanese time we were working
on um
going through our implementation and um
file filing issues on the github and
creating put uh plo requests
and
the so uh
for the first this is for uh explaining
what what is steep first
so t
honestly it's not only about deep
from the beginning from the
when the protocol draft and architecture
draft it was obvious that its
suit and rats was going to be
um used in the deep
and uh
and the in the format
was changed from otr p to t was uh then
it was from json then it was obvious
it's going to be using coset
so um
well there's many things have to be done
in making the deep draft
finishing which is
which which is tough but um which is
also
challenging and good good thing to do
work
try it
so um
from last
um i gifted this idea we focused on i
mean
me and the other people in japan was yes
i would like to call their name
name yeah um
from asd is suzakson from second
takayama
and tragedy
and also
um
from yes we joined on the arm um suit
work suit working group hackathon too so
random harness and and dave was working
on um in
on his time zone too
and coming back so we were uh the main
focus was adding suit
format in the tip draft
yes
and
and we would like to we would like to
finish suit manifest example in the tip
so everybody who is going to use
teep would also understand how to
construct the suit manifest inside the t
protocol
then
and then it will in
then will be much easier
to have the concrete
cdl example with the diagnostic
notation example and the binary
representation with the commented
description with
with
and just the binary
and also we started from the last week
is started to how um
think about how to support the cose
okay
so
for the stamp site we will have a tamp
proto
um this uh as a
implementation as a tam
it's it's open source on the github um i
i forgot to
write it down the
github link here
but it's if you
search on the web browser temp prototam
then it will be you could go to it and
we what we really did was uh
um
try that we we added about three
different way of the having suit
manifest inside the tip um message but
we just
first we um focus on having a trusted
component binary which used to be called
trusted application in
binary inside the suit manifest and that
will be inside the
deep message a deep update message
and also
we from takayama-san we started to have
uh libsy suit it's meant to be a
library to support
to make it easier who wants to implement
it
cheap device or tam
and it's
it's uh
and
so that's was uh adding this um having
suit manifest inside a leap c suit
and also deep device we have an open
source yet but um we we trying to
working hard to finish the
implementation taking very long time by
the way i'm after this ietf119112
i would like to focus on finishing tip
device implementation
publicly available
as soon as possible
i don't know how long it will take but
um yes i will put other work item aside
and i'm going to focus on making team
device
implementation on github
and what we did was we take message
format let's keep updating so finished
supporting draft zero six of the tip
message portion and then adding this
exam um example uh
suit manifest format
and
which is and also uh
it says integrated payload here but um
it means um
in the same same with the on the top
line is adding tc binary inside the soup
manifest super manifest could have only
manifest and could have binary and
separately but um right now we wanted to
have try having a binary inside the suit
manifest and make it workable between
the deep device and time
so um
okay and these are the feedback on the
draft is uh one two three
four five
uh um
issues and put full request
and first one is um from dave
and i think this is uh many of them were
going to be uh going through with the
dave's talk
but um briefly going through is uh
yes
and the tip
tip message yeah where you we're going
to use each token or just the token and
and it's we we need to decide when to
include the token or or not
so uh
that's
dave's
issues
on the github
and
and also
another topic
was i was
participating in a suit working group on
this monday was yes about
cypher suit and honestly if
since we have suit manifest inside the
deep message
we will just like to use
whatever it happens on suit man um suit
a manifest draft
to you for using um cose
exactly the same in the deep then it
will make it much easier for the
implementation we don't have to add any
more
feature in the library or anything else
we're just reusing it and that's but um
to do that we just need to align the
description between the suit and tip and
that's the second one
and and the third one is uh yes
was really uh working on is he went
through reading the suit manifest
um draft and
and proposing
you
there's a in the uh um description then
the suit manifest
for the day for for the usage of the
deleting the
binary or firmware or trusted component
it was
probably using unlink is more preferable
was it was um r or takayamas in our
understanding so we made a um
um
issue listing pull request
and uh and the the fourth is the yes
this is something with
we've been doing from these three months
was
keep updating finalizing the three
way of the example in the deep message
of the suit manifest
and the last is
yes yeah so this is was my quick
one-line
pull request is um since it was the
suit example and the suit manifest was
using um
es-2556 for the corsair yes cwt then
yeah i thought
adding in the cdl uh
effort description might might be better
so it just made a one-line patch
okay
yes so then um
instead of going to
suit manifest example um i would like to
explain how the tip
tip protocol uh draft is describing um
seaboard description
yes
honestly i did suffer a lot when trying
to implement the seaboard so since
i suffered a lot i thought i would put
my knowledge into the deep protocol
draft so everybody else could don't have
to go through uh
entire how to
implement and how to debug it when the
um
when when the negotiation not or uh
point message going back and forth
between the time and deep device
probably whoever going to implement the
seaboard
problem yes i want just wanted to make
it easier for them
so um
this is the left side is c board
diagonal stick not notation
which is uh
derived from reading the cdl
and
in the right side it's in the in the
draft have a binary example but with the
comment in on it so if anything doesn't
work
in with the talking with the other tier
of the
um on the internet
for example deep device and um tam
then
you just go you could see the example
and which line
might be different in the binary if it's
a json it will be much easier to develop
because it's text format and if you do
the ether real i mean like it's not
ethereal right now it's a wireshark
and if you see the
packet dump
then they're pretty much easy for them
if you do the top packet dump on the
seaboard keyboard binary it's all hex
decimal so
if you scan the hex decimal and keep
going through the right side and left
side for about five or ten times you
might started to see on the right side
on this on the
packet dump but started to imagine have
an imagination of the left side
uh
i hope so but um
yeah
yeah i'm trying to make it slightly
easier
so um
and this is suit manifest is also um
similar
i mean
oh yes but we also have a c um seed
um what was the name yes diagnostic
notation and the binary
representation with the comment on it
so if anything you
have something
for example
if the coset
orgasm doesn't match then if it's if you
could see whether it has
minus 16 it's going to be
negam215 is going to be 2f and
hexadecimal and from the beginning from
d86b a3 do you go through and if it's
you need you if you you just
you could check if it's correctly it's
tf and parsing correctly
in the implementation
yep
then i think i'm going to go through the
suit manifest examples
um any question for so far
okay
okay so first example is uh probably the
easiest example
how does it look is
if when the tip update message
is uh
sent from time to tip agent in the tip
device
it has the
um
the suit
manifest
has the uri
pointing to the
where the
trusted component binary is uh hosted
so and then the t um
and then the tip device we're going to
um in the implementation
they're going to
fetch or download the
trusted component binary
right now we still using dot ta
for the convenience for the
understanding
and
and inside the
tc iphone you id dot t is it doesn't
have to be this um
file name you could choose any kind of
the file name
and since
since it's uh in the um
arm implementation for the opti was
using uid and the file name of the ta um
i i added the easier to
parse it in the mine you could use the
uid.ta
and for the example on the um
into sgx and it's any you could use any
kind of the file name so it's dc hyphen
uid.ta which it's going to be it doesn't
have to be using your id or any file
name um pointing to the binary and then
the binary it has any of the um
yeah
um hexismo or any binary inside
and this example
good thing is the
um
yeah the first line is
the um developer who is who create
made the binary of the trusted component
um
is uh could
going to be download from their website
or
https link so you could you could you
will notice the tip device have
downloaded the binaries
and and and the
um
and the time does do not have to
host their uh the dc binary on the temp
side so
you just you just provide a
certain manifest to the deep device
and then the team um the tip device will
get the bioneer binary from a trusted
component developer so it doesn't have
to worry about it
um
and the downside is
um yeah trusted component developer have
to have a
web server or whatever
um
hosting the trusted component binary
and
deep device
need to
download the binary separately after
receiving the suit manifest but um it's
not a
big deal for the second night and first
line
how much it depends on how much the
trusted company developer
have the uh
have the
domain name and have the
bandwidth for the distribute the binary
okay
and the sec and the second example is
also pretty much straight straight
forward
the only difference is uh
inside the
sea suit manifest
instead i have a uri it has the
um
what do you call it in this uh cdo um
yeah
instead of that you are pointing to
other
website you have the dc binary
embedded inside the suit manifest
as as this very simplified written here
detail is
is in the draft but
and this is the simplified
way of the x um description
so good so this one is the more
intuitive so if the tip
deep device requests the dc binary
uh to the time server then the time
server tip update message will contain
the
suit manifest with the tc binary so
you could receive it in one message
and
and yes it's just pretty much the same
what uh opposite from the what i
discussed with example one is the
trusted component developer do not have
to host the binary
yes
um
it's and also it's pretty much the same
what opposite of what i i i have just
this um said
um the trusted component binary
is going to be this
by time so
if yeah you just don't
have one can't you need to trust the
temp and you can't you can't count the
trusted binary download number or
something if you wish but um oh yeah
yeah but
the good thing is you don't have to
worry about it
and uh
and also it's the time message from the
update message from the tam to deep
device will contain the binary so it
stands probably it's going to be tend to
be uh
um
message will be the size will be larger
than um
just having a manifest but um i really
don't think it's a big
big uh
i mean big negative point i think it's
it's uh
that that's that's the
even
even downloading a trusted company
binary separate from team device from
trusted
component uh developer hosted web
website it's it's going to use the same
bandwidth
okay so
and example three is the um
adding the
um
um example of the
um what brandon have
uh
um
talked at i dif one last iedif
when when having the personal data
for the particul for the dc binary
already inside the dc uh
deep device
then you could
um
how you could um this rate the
in this example is the
personal data is the example is having a
config.json file
um the providing to the um
depended tc
binary is in this example is the one
already have in the deep devices dc
uid.suit so if the dc device already
have the tcu id exactly the same
tc already installed and these deep
device then
could receive the
personal data with the suit manifest
inside the deep update message
and yes
okay
yeah i think i pretty much finished my
slide so
[Music]
so yes summary yes
we just started to move on
um adding the suit support
and we started to start the
consider how to support the corsair and
the suit i mean that i'm a tip
and yes
we we now we uh i don't know this suit
manifest for three format it should be
inside the deep draft or it should be in
the suit manifest um
um
um ma'am second draft or external draft
not sure probably it's going to be
discussion with the brandon later with
the dave's talk
and
and yes i just wanted to explain how the
seaboard looks in the tip
yes
and after what i define one line yes the
we would like to go on to
support uh finish the implementation and
having the running code and and so we
could verify first um
we could
uh uh yeah
have the feedback on making the t
protocol draft more concrete
yes
that's it
um questions
yeah
i don't see anybody on the queue
i want to ask something about this horse
well
there were a couple of people on on the
chattic you're feeling your pain
so the the question and i think i saw it
noted from dave um
the the issues that you had listed on
the github i forget the number was it
161.
um i want 62 uh it is
that has now been resolved oh there's a
set of them right yes
161 is still um
pending there
so
okay so
if the if it's okay to have the three
formats in the deep draft it will be
yeah could anybody could uh remember um
dave or
ming could merge it
or if if it's more appropriate to put
put it in the suit manifest
external draft which brandon have split
it
last week
um yeah we could move that to the um to
suit manifest
draft i really don't mind which which is
going
which should go into it because it's
anyway we're going to use the same
format
it does need to get covered um dave you
have a comment
yeah i just uh
first what i put on the chat was it
wasn't uh merged into draft 07 just
because it was merge conflicts whereas
the uh iv deadline was coming up and
then those were resolved shortly after
that
one question that plays into that is how
much of these examples um
suit generic versus teep specific right
so for example if there was a
suit spec that had the thousand examples
that just didn't have teep stuff in it
is that close enough or does steep i
think right now tp has one example in
there for each message type where it's
like the personalization date examples i
think it's the closest to get curious
third example right not the first to the
second one if i remember right um that's
from memory so uh akira please correct
me if i'm wrong but uh if suit had more
examples in some document then would t
need to cover all the examples or just
one of them which is what we're doing
right now and so i think that's the
interesting question that is asking that
i would uh love to hear uh people's
opinions on so
yes
is brandon here
yeah i don't see brendan on
i thought he was going to jump in so
yeah i thought so as well
well hank
honest
honestly these three example is a
very
uh
very s
specific with the t i'm suit manifest
uses
because of the deep um handling between
tam and deep device but it it doesn't it
doesn't mean they have to be in deep
draft um it could be a manifest external
graph
well it could be its own separate draft
as well and then we can argue whether
that work gets done here in teep or
it goes back to suit
um hank you're in the queue
yeah sorry i uh it was hard for me to
press the buttons i don't know why uh
this is hank um so yeah there is so in
principle that is not a problem to pull
that into the
manifest draft or the
uh if it's if it's just the
reintegration um
there's also merits to have that in a
separate draft i think we are happy to
help here uh if it is uncomfortable for
the cheap id to to somehow build their
around the content that's not a problem
we can we can have that in suit and suit
suit-ish um
ids
only only concern to having the uh
example and the suit manifest in the
external draft is it has the like uh in
the example um for in the format it has
the
like
tc hyphen uid.ta which need the
knowledge of the how the ta
works
um but um
yeah yeah that is use case specific
expositional text so i i
you could we can abstract that or we can
we can uh we can ask uh guidance from
some from the area director if it's fine
to have a
specific uh
name here i i think that's that's just a
it is a legwork problem
or or having the three example in
deepdraft
but have the all other a bunch of the
other example in suit manifest as as it
is right now is also fine
yeah that
yeah but then you so so maybe other
people have an opinion but but you i
think i'd like uh to see the examples in
one place to be honest nice yeah so yeah
so hank you're you're kind of
saying you prefer it in the suit
the preference is not so if it's if it's
too uh clunky to have them deep i think
suit is happy to help i would call it
like that so i i don't have a preference
i i have a i have a
the desire to help
okay so i see brendan
brendan is on
and of course he prefers it in the teep
document okay
okay
yeah that's right yes
okay all right so we can continue that
discussion i guess on the main list
could i just briefly say why sorry for
jumping the queue there um
essentially the concern i've got is that
with the refactoring that's been done in
suit
so that there are multiple documents
with multiple different um
sets of of
pieces of the original suit manifest
now it suits already going to have
examples in more than one place
and because of that
i think it would be really sort of uh
incongruous to have teap examples in the
core of the suit document uh when some
of suits examples aren't in the core
document
i see yeah and also if if
if the manifest form
format is in the deep draft
we could say
um we could
how you how to up um
um how to adopt the suit manifest in
a future protocol other than deep yeah
it might give it a little bit of
guidance yes
skipping of the audio exactly when
brandon said the essential sentence when
could you please repeat that
sir sure the the the point is that suit
has examples spread over multiple
documents right now so i'm happy to put
examples in suit where they're
appropriate but the question is if there
isn't an appropriate document in suit
for a teep example to land in i think
it's just a little bit incongruous to to
shoehorn one into a document where it's
not appropriate
so it makes sense to me to put you know
if teep is a profile of suit then it
should have its own examples for suit
does that make sense
yeah that makes sense but that would
remain so the profiling aspect of cheap
would that be its own document then it
isn't the protocol rt
texture so
um
but would that go in cheap then
so so bend up the big if
yeah yeah so so that's why i assumed
suit is the more likely lane but i'm i'm
just guessing now so so maybe other keep
offers have a better editors have a
better opinion
so ben is listing another issue um
on the chat
that if we have a lot of examples that
there may be a desire to have them all
in one place
and so
um
okay i don't think we're going to
resolve this here
go ahead ben
since you're
yeah i think my my note in the jabber
may have been based on a flawed
assumption so i think dave is clarifying
that you know
the idea is
to have a single document that is just
examples and the question is whether to
do that in the teep or the working
groups
and i think
either those are fine and i agree with
you that we're probably not going to get
a clear resolution
in the meeting right now
yeah
okay
well so we'll continue forward then um
thank you akira
yes thank you how do i stop the steering
slide oh there it is oh i i can just
revoke it as well
um okay so up next we have dave with the
main protocol
spec dave do you want me to share slides
or you want to share them
um you can share them but i've been in
queue for uh a curious document uh
brendan was actually not present in the
meeting at the time that a curious
question was first worded so i wanted to
clarify one nuance of the question if
you don't mind
please go ahead i somehow didn't see it
and we don't have to answer it right now
but i want brendan to fully understand
the question so if this is moved to the
list then he can appropriately weigh in
the examples that akira walked through
the part of the question that we would
love you to
weigh in on uh not necessarily the mic
here but at some point right is the
examples of things like um what does it
look like when you take the actual
binary embedded into the suit manifest
what does it look like when you have a
uri that points to it hosted off uh off
the thing are those things that are
inherently teep specific concepts or are
those things that are generic and so
that's the examples he's going through
is those different variations and so
that's why the question is is it really
something in a tea profile or are these
just examples of generic suit things
that should or maybe already are in
in a document in the suit working group
and so if you can do a scan through of
akira's examples and say these things
are actually just illustrating generic
concepts versus no this one is actually
a teach specific concept that would be
very valuable brennan
all so so let's move on to the uh
protocol slides here i gotta
leave the queue and leave my audio on
okay hopefully you can all still see and
hear me all right uh we're gonna be
talking about draft seven of the cheap
protocol next slide
all right
so since 111
there was a long backlog of old issues
that we've been slowly working through
in deep working group meetings and we've
now got to the point that almost all the
old issues have now been resolved and
we're only um talking about new issues
and so i'm going to clear the backlog
today in the discussions here and then
go on to the new ones file but there
really aren't any old ones previously we
kind of picked the most important ones
to talk about in the working group
meeting and we've now kind of cleared
that backlog and so
and most of the spec right has now been
implemented by at least one
implementation right you heard akira
mentioned the last pieces that were kind
of still in progress right integration
of other things but um we think we've uh
fleshed out all of the areas of the spec
that there might be an issue until we
actually implement things but there's uh
no section of the spec that somebody
hasn't at least started on so go ahead
and go on the next slide
all right
so um
here are some of the ones that we
previously discussed at ietf 111 and i'm
not going to go through uh each of these
on slides this is just a list of things
that we covered last ietf meeting
and we had proposed resolutions and
those have now been incorporated into
draft seven and so we added the error
code uh for no freshness mechanism in
common um you can read through the rest
of those but all of those we believe
we've just put in the results from what
was in the minutes from last ietf
meeting okay
go on to the next slide
there are things that people want to
stop and ask about but the point is um
all of these are things we spent some
time discussing last time so these are
the ones that uh were continued this one
we spent quite a bit of time on
um and so this was like all the
discussion of ocsp and capability
discovery that was kind of the main
focus of last meeting and so we've done
the results there right we've removed
all references to ocsp right we said you
just have to have a
update mechanism to update your trust
anchors and that's how you do
replication uh and so all the different
points that were raised during the
meeting we believe we've incorporated
those back into the spec and so i'm not
going to show you the text because my
belief is it just matches what we said
and we would invite you to inspect the
text yourself just to verify that uh if
you had an appointment point you want to
be in there make sure it's in there but
we believe we've collected everything
from last ietf meeting so i want to go
on and discuss new issues and so unless
there's a question on those
um then i'd like to go on let me pause
for a second there's nobody in the queue
right okay let's
go ahead and go on unless there's
questions on any of those so
all right so i'm going to walk through
um other ones that were kind of in the
in the backlog and so
this is one that was one of the one of
the older ones it's finally been merged
and so this one um
uh i think was originally one of the
hackathon uh filed issues from uh maybe
two or three ietfs ago and the text
finally got merged so
after various edits and rebases and
merge conflict resolutions and so
uh remember tokens here is the name for
the nonce-like thing that appears in a
uh that can appear in a deep request
that's echoed back in the deep response
if the tam needs to uh match requests
and responses and so depending on the
freshness mechanism and use and so on
the token is optional depending on use
case it's up to tam
and so when you are using a
token sometimes known as announce right
it now has actual requirements around
there must be random different per
request
only one response is allowed per token
you can't use it for other purposes
other than this particular purpose in
teep and uh when you issue a nonsenate
request there should be some expiration
um such that you can't come back three
months later or something right just the
expectation is you don't keep state
around forever right so that's the kind
of
the guidance that's in there right now
so that one is now merged
next
so this one now i'm getting into the one
that i filed during this hackathon right
this one is ambiguity in the spec
that um in my opinion there's a
straightforward way to address this but
uh here's my presentation about it
the update message allows the token
field and says it's optional but it
actually doesn't have any text that says
when to include it right and so you can
treat that as a couple that you could
read that as a couple different ways
so uh the responses right a success
message or an error message you send
back when processing an update message
does say that you have to echo back the
token if it's present in the update
and uh the update can include a suit
report and if the suit report has
announced um then um
uh
i should say if the update has a uh
token then the suit report if present
must have the suit report nuds in it
okay and so the br and i see russia on
the cube but let me finish the slide
here and then i'll go to urs uh the
proposal that i have is just to clarify
the ambiguity is to explicitly say that
it's up to the tam implementation so in
other words you are allowed to have a
token in
a delete message or an update message or
a query request message it's not a
requirement that you use you know all
three or none of the three you can pick
and choose however you want in other
words we don't explicitly say that but
the post list you say the team gets to
decide when a token in is uh is
appropriate uh so i can do it sometimes
not other times or whatever that's my
proposal because that's one way to read
the wording right now and so i my
opinion is that's the least change from
what the text says right now and leaves
the most freedom for people to
innovate and optimize for their
implementation
and then separately besides explicitly
saying that
to say that uh the teap agent must
ensure that the suit report nonsense
present if the update um contains a
nonce and so um that's already implied
okay but it's not explicitly stated so
we could make that any more explicit so
ross do you have an opinion on this one
go ahead
no i have an opinion on the last one
um
i'm
sorry it took me longer to read your
list than you spent on the slide
nancy yeah
the uh my concern is the tokens must be
different per request
um i hope you don't mean that people
have to keep track of every token they
ever used
um what you mean
is that the probability of reuse is
small
it i think the intent and so i think the
actual wording was authored by one of
our japanese colleagues but i believe
that the intent is that uh it must be
different per outstanding request
and so
uh and there's different ways of doing
that and so i there are ways to not have
to retain state so you could have a
pseudo-random sequence right
that that's my point
is that the probability
of the same value being picked is
so small that you don't have to keep
track
uh you're correct
yeah so we're gonna look for some better
wording there
so i that that's my concern is okay is
some word smithing
okay
good point
make sure that appears in the notes and
we'll pick that up thank you
all right let's go on nancy
if unless there's anybody in the queue
getting up for this one uh unless
there's any uh uh
alternate proposals then i will go
forward with this proposal um unless
somebody has a better idea so
if i see nobody at the queue we'll
assume that that would be okay
all right so the next whole section of
the agenda and since the uh rats working
group is uh up right after teep today i
prioritize the eat stuff in the agenda
to make sure that we have time to go
through this as opposed to the suit
stuff um which does not have uh i think
right after this and so i wanted to have
any input necessary for us to go into
the rats working group after t
so if we were to run out of time i would
rather make sure we cover all the eat
stuff and um not cover all the other
stuff that i have or cover less the
other stuff that i have so i've got eat
and suit then
optimizations in that order so here's
the eat stuff so
um there's been a bunch of threads about
this one started off as the uh rats
meeting on monday and so let me just uh
summarize the discussion uh i've seen so
far if there was anything overnight i am
not up to speed but i i i'm up to speed
as of yesterday so yesterday afternoon
all right so uh there were two issues
related to referencing of each one of
those is already merged one of those is
open to track the remaining things and
so
um on the left is the sets of uh
requirements and i'll go through the the
ones for the second row there and more
uh details in the later slides but this
is the one that summarizes all the other
ones so
uh there's a set of requirements from
the architecture draft okay which is as
nancy said is already in the isg
so we've already got you know working
through consensus on the left column
although i have a question about that
later as we'll see
um the middle column is what draft 07
says right now okay and so there are uh
one two three of those uh requirements
that draft 07 points to the core each
spec as meeting those requirements and
there are five of those that points to
an individual submission hank's document
as meeting the other five in the hopes
that those would be merged into the spec
right that was the status as when draft
07 was posted okay
on the far right side um
is the current proposal for the next
draft other than the yellow one is uh
subject to uh discussion here and so
we'll talk about that another another uh
there's a couple of variations of how
that might be done or not done or
whatever so
the other ones that are currently point
to bar calls the proposal is to point
those to the
latest eat spec because there's been
some uh rewordings of some existing
things in some cases and there's been
some new claims added in other cases
okay so the belief now is that the
vendor of the device can be specified
using an oem id claim and remember that
each has different claim sets you can
have a claim set for each component
right your overall evidence can have
multiple claim sets one for each layer
or one for each component or whatever
and so oem id can appear multiple times
one for each component right so the
vendor of the device if you're talking
about a device claim set then oem id
would be the vendor of the device
similarly the device unique identifier
euit could be used as the unique
identifier in a claim set about
properties of the device okay as opposed
to the properties of you know the
firmware or the t the tpa or whatever
else so eoid we believe could be used
for that one
and then new uh in the latest each spec
they added
the
software identifier as you know
previously it talked about coswoods but
it didn't actually have any uh formal
text in there that was implementable and
now it does right and so now in the
coswood section the software name the
software version um can be used to meet
uh the
what what the architecture document uses
words for firmware type and firmware
version right it uniquely identifies
what's the firmware that's actually on
there
and so the belief is that the 11 spec
draft 11 of eat actually meets um all
but one of the requirements of the um
that's talked about in the teep spec
right now the deep architecture document
right now and that's classic device and
so that's what all the remaining
discussions about is that one remaining
thing um and i see brendan in queue so
is if you're gonna
anything other than class of the device
is in scope for this slide so feel free
to ask questions anything else so
yeah i i guess the the thing that i want
to make sure is that we're not um
constructing a situation where devices
are required to convert between a
variety of different identifiers um
this is this is a moment where we need
to be really careful about how we sync
up between a bunch of drafts that are in
flight at the moment i'm concerned
and and to to be honest with you i i
have not looked through this to to the
extent where i can tell whether oem id
euid and the current uuids specified in
the suit draft are compatible or not i
just want to ensure that we're not
forcing
constrained nodes to convert between
a variety of different identifiers for
the ease of consumption of large-scale
systems because i think that would be a
mistake
so i think the one that you should look
at and form your own opinion i think is
euid
which is specified and eat as being
twice as long as a uuid and so i think
the other ones you'd probably be happy
enough with but that one i would draw
your attention to inform an opinion so
it's like a uuid in the same sense of
properties other than the length is
twice as long
i i think that device identifiers are
probably the id that suit cares about
the least so i suspect i'm not too
worried about that one
okay
all right but yeah those would be
feedback i think for the uh rats working
group which uh i would invite you to the
working group session following this one
so
all right unless there's any other
comments on any of the other ones then
all the rest of these things are about
the classic device discussion which has
been a active discussion this week thank
you to all of those who have weighed in
on it and thank you for coming to this
session if you wouldn't normally be in
teeps so next slide
please okay so let's do some history
here and talk about some background for
class of device because there were some
questions for anybody coming from say
the rats working group that wouldn't
normally be here in teep as to what this
requirement is and what teeps use is so
the first use of this in teep came from
the legacy otrp draft which we don't use
anymore but if you're looking back at
the history you can see uh and i think
um
uh jeremy had posted on the combined
thread that the teep suit thread about
what otrp does and so you see in the
otrp protocol which is now part of uh
global platform specifications it does
have this notion of type of firmware
right which i mentioned the previous
slide that the coswood can cover that
one and the type of tee included in a
device right and so that's one example
wording and otrp does this so next slide
but that's not our spec anymore so it's
just that was a predecessor to what deep
architecture has okay
so a couple places in the deep
architecture document that actually
specified the requirement that we're
talking about now okay one is here
talking about device identifying
information okay
um attestation information maybe may
need you you can identify a device to
the tam right that's more like the the
euid case right
you need it allows uh this hand provides
services a device such as managing
installed tas providing subscriptions to
services locating device specific keying
material to communicate with and
authenticate the device or authenticate
device in some cases it may be
sufficient to identify only the class of
device right if you're managing you know
10 000 things
you have the same policy for all 10 000
of them not on the device by device
basis for scalability right and so
what's the class of the device right not
the serial number but what's the what's
the model number or some other class or
category that applies to the whole uh
set of things not on a per serial number
basis where eoid is like a serial number
okay
next slide
um the other part of the requirement
just to uh verify is in the tee
identifying information and this is the
type of tee
that generated this attestation might be
must be identified right and includes
you know version information for
hardware firmware software and so on
those those other bullets are the other
rows in that table right
t manufacturer information for the uh te
right that's like oem id for the tee
claim set right is required in order to
disambiguate the same te created by
different manufacturers and so as an
example right in the uh arm ecosystem
right you have a uh say a trust zone uh
dee but the actual uh chip manufacturer
is a very it's anybody that licenses the
arm design right so you can imagine a
trust zone with multiple oem ids but
it's the same te type which is trust
zone right so again there's a
there's a classic device there in this
example i think if i'm interpreting if i
understand the arm ecosystem right this
is an example where
there might be a te type that would be
that would span multiple oem ids and
that's an important concept
to keep track of when i get to that
question in another slide here so
all right so hopefully somebody will
correct me if i have something wrong but
this is the text that was that's already
passed working group last call and has
passed on the isg so we already have
consensus on this text
and now let's just uh we have to talk
about how we can effectively meet these
requirements so go ahead and go on to
the next slide nancy
okay
as meeting that claim and so this is
what we want to replace with a a uh
a working group document whether this
document gets adopted is working or
joking but this is really the only thing
left that depends on is this one section
here if we make those other changes that
i mentioned because the eat spec has now
incorporated other things so there's a
cloud
yeah this is not good
no just checking am i back now
yeah you're back
okay yeah i gotta know
i got a notice from mitecho that i was
having glitches so i knew about it so
as long as i'm back now i'm saying uh so
this one it was a proposal that uses a
uuid
to meet the
type claims about the the type of device
type of pe
um this one says you could use a uuid
for those two purposes and that's what
the keep spec references right now and
so whether a t uuid is appropriate or
not is an upcoming question but that's
one that we said that we as referenced
in the last deep spec so
that's one proposal next slide
um i don't see the slide on my screen
can you guys still see the slide on the
screen
okay here we go we see the epr 139 slide
yep it was just delayed it came up for
me
all right so um
lawrence opened a pull request on monday
or tuesday against the eat specs saying
would this meet the requirement okay and
that's what has been generated lots of
discussions so in this example right
it's a uh byte uh
blob okay as opposed to a uid okay
and you can see the various descriptions
and stuff there right set by the
hardware oem vendor again wording is
flexible this is just a pull request
right uh there's no global schema format
for this claim and so it's still opaque
just like a uid is right there's no
format for the claim it's an opaque blob
that you can use but there's no
structure in it okay so again that's a
pull request is another proposal
next slide
okay so here's the set of questions for
discussion here and various individuals
have weighed in on the list on these
questions already but i wanted to
summarize what the questions were that
people have weighed in on and see if we
can get any
way forward or direction here so we know
whether this is going to be a
t profile thing or an
general thing okay so the first one and
these are all interrelated questions
here so feel free to get in the mic in
any one of these four questions here
because there are uh inner relationships
between these okay i know a number of
people have posted their comments to the
list but not everybody here has read
everybody is probably up on that thread
and we want to get some consensus
direction out of the working group here
if possible so
the first one is this notion of a
hardware class identifier right is this
a notion that is specific to teep
or is this a generally applicable notion
okay
that's the first question
is the value of the class identifier is
that something that's globally unique
like a uid is
is it something that's up to the vendor
right because you know if it's a blight
blob or whatever could two different
vendors use the same
value
and the meaning of it is different
or is it up to the profile where two
different vendors can use the same value
and the meaning of it is the same
because it's more like a
identifier of trust zone regardless of
what the vendor is right
is it uh opaque or is there any
structure to it you can see the two
proposals that i mentioned are opaque
if heaven forbid somebody used a text
string somebody might assume some
structure or even if it's a bite blob
somebody might put some structure in
there
where you would not do that with a uid
right now both the proposals are opaque
from my understanding
and then finally is the value a uuid as
in
hank's uh original proposal or a place
uh white blob like it is in lawrence's
one or as was brought up on the email
thread a uh text string which was
mentioned is what otrp does and brendan
said please no
um or is it an oid or is it a url and so
that's kind of all the the of the uh
things people are weighing on the long
thread so um i see brennan in queue so
you get to go first
so uh this this might actually back up
slightly to oem id as well just as a
warning uh but i i think it's important
to consider in this that class
identifiers are not unique for a device
one device could have many class
identifiers and the the reason this is
really important is because it allows
someone to distinguish between the
various different kinds of configuration
that they care about so as you mentioned
you could easily have a class identifier
for a tee
but you might also want to have a class
identifier for all the tees of a
particular kind that also have access to
a specific trusted peripheral like maybe
a particular version of a gpu if you
happen to be building drm um or maybe
you uh care about access to a specific
kind of crypto accelerator in which case
you definitely need a class identifier
for that and that's
probably actually going to have a
different oem id and a different class
id than the tee itself so what you
actually care about in these situations
is aggregations of multiple
oem
and class id pairs and so i i mean
there's a couple of different ways that
you can handle this you can have a
structured class identifier in some kind
of enormous tree or you can have a list
of pairs which is possibly easier to
parse and handle there's a lot of
different options here
and and i think it's important that we
consider that there are a lot of
different use cases here for different
kinds of uh ways of identifying exactly
what a class means to you and your ta
um i will mention the the out of the two
possibilities you mentioned there's a
third possibility i think which is the
one that's most natural and eat which is
multiple claim sets
uh so you have just like you could have
multiple claim sets one for each layer
you could have one more you have
multiple claim sets one for each
component and a composite device you
could have multiple claim sets for other
purposes so if you need to have
different uh you said you know lists of
uh you know pairs of them you could put
those in different claim sets and use
the sub mod relationship to indicate the
relationship that's probably the one
that's the most natural way because then
it's not just this pair you could have
any set of claims that could be varied
uh together right you could have you
know whether it's a time stamp or
anything else that kind of goes along
with that so multiple claim sets is the
most natural way to do that but i see
other people in queue so i i mean i mean
the thing the thing on that is that um
one particular thing can have multiple
claim sets you could have a particular
tee and that t e could have a particular
type of uh of os and and so on and so on
um so what's interesting i i guess i
didn't give you the background here but
for anybody that's not familiar with the
t format there's ah when i say up to the
profile here in the second bullet
there's a separate claim that's the
profile okay and so there's a with the
value of being what that profile would
be and so you could imagine you know
profile value equals uh teep right and
so uh the same component in theory could
also have multiple profiles which would
be multiple claim sets for the same um
for the same component just because that
component happens to be wearing two hats
and have two profiles that is in theory
possible too i don't think that example
is in there but i don't think there's
anything that would preclude it so
okay uh hank
yeah hi um hi dave um so um so my next
words i have to
phrase very carefully i have to tweet
very carefully because
none of my co-authors are here
and
they are all the hardware vendors and
the te builders and the at the station
environment
creators so and this is already hinting
this is coming from rats
and in reds they think i like brent's
comment on you can have
multiple ways to express these uh
let's call them multi-oem multi-parts
things that you have multiple classes
combined and that is especially true
in composite devices and composite
device attestation rats where you also
have the layered attestation maybe on
top of that so you have also the
dependencies which environment reports
on which requirements and so on and so
on so we are very careful and very
complex in describing that from the
supply chain side and we decided on maps
that have classes instances and groups
which are arbitrary subsets of these
can be identified with specific maps
that can have class ids vendor strings
model strings layer identifiers and
other indices of hardware for example
there's the entitymap that can help you
so there's a lot of things that really
can help if you support all of these and
then i think in the github thread about
this uh
thomas just provided a very small subset
that is detect oid detect uuid and
detect integer which is an interesting
choice but from coming from one of the
vendors who just used numbers there and
that is a te
pa component not a complete te
identifier so
and that's not including instances and
groups and such so i think uh looking at
that corresponding work in rats
tentatively
that is a korean might yield a lot of
interesting choices here and also i
think
represents the complexity of how to
um represent uh hierarchies of composite
class things
to have the uh which again would be can
be could be classed by their own then uh
um
how complex that is so so yeah oid uh
all that is possible actually and and
and i don't know if this complexity is
required for etf so that's that's my my
take-home idea i think um maybe you
don't need all of that um but maybe
maybe looking at this and having a
subset of what is required
so again for other people in the queue
here um the thing that is the most
useful is any comments on the top two
comments on the bottom one is probably
the least important because that's
important only once you've agreed on the
answers to the top ones and so
is it team specific or general is it
profile specific vendor specific or
globally unique
and i understand brendan's point is
maybe the answer is multiple if you have
multiple purposes who knows uh but
that's the one i would most likely to
get a consensus on uh so we can get
direction to um
eat versus rats sorry eat versus
teep versus rats
i think a number of the
rats community have argued that it
should be prof up to the profile and
could be done in teep i think previously
tip assumed it would be global and be
done on rats
but that was before this thread and so
that's why i wanted to spend some time
on this so eric you're up next
sure hi eric voigt coming over from rats
uh i definitely think it should be
global uh i do think there are parallels
with profile certainly things like tpm
1.2 and 2.0
are things that are useful to
standardize the behavior of effectively
what an api your behavior is so the idea
of having a union of behaviors sort of
supportable here
is something that is interesting
uh on the text discussion as it should
be a string i don't think we want to
have anything like that but i do think
that there are values in having
standardized
options which people have agreed on on
api type as well as having some vendor
extensibility for new types that are out
there
um
okay
um honest and then i'll uh give an exam
if somebody else doesn't i'll give an
example or two that came up on the list
where i think uh lawrence gave one exam
of things that might be
up to the vendor or up to the profile
and see what people think but hannah's
you're in queue go
ahead hey um i hope you can hear me
um
i i'm trying to write the meeting
minutes and it was difficult to
sort of associate the responses of the
commenters to the questions
uh maybe maybe you could
maybe you could summarize um
like
um
what did you hear like what did you get
out of the the comments so far so i can
capture it in the meeting minutes for
the for the benefit of others who are
not on a call
um i'm with you so that's why i was
going to ask some more specific
questions but uh i i had a hard time
associating comments with specific
questions too other than i think um
uh brendan's i i could where brendan's
point was uh there might be multiple
types of class class identifiers so that
one was pretty clear um the
uh hink is back in queue so i think he's
going to clarify his comments the mic so
go ahead hank yeah apparently as i
understood afterwards i uh replied to
the least interesting one it's the last
question
so so that there's that and also it is a
lot of things and it is a complex
hierarchy tree
okay
all right so uh the i'll i'll mention
the two excel i see eric you're backing
queue if you want to clarify yours go
ahead
well one other and the bolt two
value globally unique but vendor
extensible and there are ways of doing
that
yeah okay so yeah eric's comments
specifically on the second one okay
to support both um which i gather as
something there's many address space
there's many numbering spaces in iana
that do that right that have a vendor
extensible section reserved whether
we're talking about numbers or strings
or any other format there's ways to do
that so
um
so um examples that have come up on the
uh on the list is things that are
vendor-specific and uh i think lawrence
gave an example um where his example was
a generic example that says you know
tesla
and so his was in the argument as to why
a uh byte string is better than uuid
because it's more compact and accessible
for constrained devices because your
class identifiers could be very short
much less than say 16 bytes
such as you know tesla model s 3 x or y
would be an examples of say one byte
things that are what vendor specific
right just translate that into te type
or device type or whatever instead of
tesla but your point is you could have
say one byte um identifiers that is
really within the context of an oem id
the pairing of that plus you know a very
small number of bytes is unique class
identifier that's a vendor specific one
so that was one example that came up on
the list
the example that i gave earlier is
something that might be
not vendor specific but up to a profile
which is if you had a te type that could
span multiple vendors
multiple oems and so i mentioned trust
zone which you could imagine the same
thing could be true for risk five uh tes
or whatever if there's multiple vendors
that have the same te type and you have
tas meant for that te type regardless of
which chip manufacturer built the chip
right just like in tpms right same spec
but many different tpm manufacturers
right and so
um there was examples of why a class
identifier might be
profile specific why it might be vendor
specific and of course uuids are just
globally unique um and so if you think
about do we need a registry of things
that are well known okay or not because
if it's up to the vendor you don't need
a registry right if you have up to the
profile you need a registry right
um whether
so we would need in the uh t profile if
if we have the class identifier values
that are specific to t right if keep
says here's the weight gives us space
you could register you want trust zone
here's the i enter registry to register
a value for trust zone that's vendor
agnostic and so
uh what a people because uh what we want
to know is is this something that needs
to be done purely in teep
and rat and there's no requirement on
rats and rats can just have to eat go
forward without talking about this and
say that's part of a t profile and we
can add claims in there okay rats would
be fine with that right that's something
something we've talked about in teep
hence this discussion
or if we say no no there's really
nothing that's uh type specific here
this is all generalizable and it should
really be in the right in the uh eat
spec or at least in the rats working
group and so that's the most important
that's the top bullet here that's the
most important one because uh in the
next meeting right rats is going to try
to decide should we start working group
last call on eat and kind of ignore this
or have the discussion going on parallel
or just leave it to t right that's the
what we want the feedback to rats to be
for the next meeting so
now that i've clarified that and given
some examples anybody else have opinions
on this because otherwise i'm going to
summarize maybe
a
straw man from what i've heard so far
just to help honest okay
i think
if i were to put out a straw man so far
based on list discussion so far the path
of least resistance might be to say that
at least for now it's specific to type
and a t profile
uh but with a vendor extensible space so
to eric's point okay in which case we
keep would have to define a new claim
we would have to define a new say i
enter registry for the values and a way
for vendors to extend them and then the
bottom bullet becomes a teat question
and not a rat's question okay but that
seems to be the path of least resistance
based on the thread so far but since
this is a different direction from what
type has said so far this is our chance
to either change our minds or to stick
the course or whatever so
um but i think that's what i that when i
saw the last responses from
geary and lawrence i think that was
their conclusion that they did not see
any consensus that there was some
generally applicable thing
but if you think that there is please
come to the mic and say so because
that's probably the default path that
rash where the rats would advise us on
if i'm reading the thread correctly
nancy you're also a co-chair of rats
anything else you want to add that that
would help the rats versus a deep
discussion
no i think you you're stating all of the
issues and i'm
frankly i'm i'm trying to make sense of
of the email thread as well
i'm trying to figure out how we get
consensus
okay if i don't hear everybody come to
mike then i'm going to
say that we don't have any other more
strict guidance to rats other than sure
we'll deal with it in a teep if somebody
else wants to argue that is general feel
free but otherwise because kind of the
the worst case uh danger would just be
we define something that's keep specific
it turns out to be general and now we've
got two claims that do the same thing in
the future right that would be the risk
and maybe that will never happen but uh
all right brendan
okay i'll take them in order it looks to
me like it's a general problem whether
or not there's a this is a general
solution i don't know but there's
definitely a general problem um you can
see that because suit has identified the
problem as well so it's definitely not t
specific
um
i think that class identifiers should be
scoped by vendor or profile i don't
think they need to be globally unique um
because
in general you can't find
something that has a class that's
relevant for security or compatibility
that doesn't come with either a vendor
or a profile
if you have if you can come up with a
counter example then i'll i'll step back
from that one but i don't think that
they can ever be globally unique
i i i plead with you to please make sure
that it's opaque and to enforce somehow
that it's opaque
and my preference is a uuid because you
can turn anything into a uuid by using
the type 5 uuid which just hashes it and
throws away a bunch of the bits
so that's my preference because it ends
up being enforceably opaque because the
content actually just doesn't mean
anything other than allow you to uh
match it to something you already know
thank you um i think that was a very
useful comment and thank you for
explaining the rationale that makes a
lot of sense to me so i'm just going to
repeat back what i heard because i think
i agree with everything that you said
the only one that's i think debatable is
the last one but i tend to agree with
you on it
and so
i think the proposal is that
the
claim id right meaning the the seabor
integer number or label or whatever um
is actually general
and the values of it
are either vendor specific or up to the
profile so in other words the eat spec
could say here is the well-known claim
but the values of it need to be
specified one of the requirements for a
profile is to you know cover how the
values are done but there's still a way
to do it for vendors and a way for the
profile to find well-known values i'm
repeating back what i think your
proposal is right
um and then out of the values right
regardless of whether it's done by the
vendor the profile then it uh
must be opaque okay and uh you like uuid
specifically because it guarantees that
it's opaque well and the other reasons
too even if it's a little bit longer um
if you're trying to bite string or
whatever the danger is somebody would
try to put structure in there and you
wouldn't like that and so uib actually
enforces the annual peakness requirement
did i get all that right
sounds good to me
okay but yeah thank you the thank you
for the technical rationales for all of
those that was very useful
okay
anyone else have an opinion because
otherwise i'm gonna i since i like uh
brendan's uh summary there um i'd like
to uh see other any objections to that
as the teep recommendation as we go into
the rats working group next that the
request for uh rats would be hey can you
define a claim
um but uh leave it up to the vendor and
the profile to define the values to go
with the claim
i i want to make sure we're capturing it
in the notes well as well
yeah
i mean like oem id right the oem id the
the rest working group is not going to
actually define the values of oem id
right it's going to define like a
registry or something or a way or it
does right it defines a way for you to
figure out what goes in there right
remember if it's your your
one of the other id numbering spaces
already exist but the point is that each
spec doesn't enumerate the values right
says here's how to put stuff in there
and this is this case where it could say
the profile needs to do that ayanna
needs to do that whatever so
all right hank
so um yeah i think that t
requires this this uh opaqueness and
everything they can transform to a type
five uuid on the evidence side or at the
station result side of things which is
fine and i think brandon said the
critical words because you know that
so on the other hand you have to know
that
so that is something you that there
where a uu id might not be uh
sufficient but that's not a cheap
problem i think so i would agree with uh
okay
is there any objections to saying that
uh the the
my summary of uh what brendan said is
the
uh
consensus of those in the room i'm not
saying it is yet i'm saying okay would
that be the consensus of the room if you
don't uh think that that is the uh
consensus you have a technical uh
argument against that then please come
to the mic
we're trying to
form a consensus so that is a proposed
consensus do people um
like that or not i don't know if you
want to do a a call of hands on this one
or just a uh since nobody's coming to
the mic if we just say that that seems
to be the sense of the room right now so
up to you nancy
yeah i mean i could take a poll or um
why didn't i do it the reverse if there
are any objections
okay
but now i have to capture
what we're doing consensus for
i'm going to try to pipe um something
into chat here
each should do a claim but leave
values to values to be defined by um
vendors
and profiles okay that's the first piece
okay
um and i think that's separate from the
actual format you can put it into two of
them
okay and then number two um
uh
value should be a uuid
to guarantee
uh
uniqueness now uh previously what keep
had said is the deep working group as a
whole does not actually care which
format it is only that we care that it's
unique and we would leave it to to uh
rest to decide that um and so okay there
we go
i don't know that i stated it well but
um it's close enough
all right i think we have
okay
um okay
i'm gonna give it another minute because
we've got
48 participants but only 13 have voted
and then i'm going to propose that
that's really the only one that you have
to call on because my opinion is based
uh if the opinion of that one is that
the the yes is the consensus then the
actual discussion other ones is not a
teep thing it's a uh it's a uh rat's
thing on the bottom bullet here the only
thing that might be worth uh
doing it is do we agree that the value
needs to be opaque right as opposed to
the value needs to be a uid or whatever
which that should be up to how they meet
the requirement that's just our
preferences right now and that's a rat's
working group discussion but um does the
value need to be opaque would be a fair
way to ask the question
okay
well i agree with you that that first we
need to agree that it should do
yeah the claim
not us
um
okay so we only have one
no vote
so i think we have
a good consensus here because we've got
16 positive votes
okay so i'm going to call it and i think
we have guidance
so do you want to ask the other question
just leave that to the rats working
group and say to take the rest of the
discussion into rats
well let me let me just ask
the second one is the value should be uh
um okay
i'm just gonna say should the value be
[Music]
opaque
okay where uuid is opaque uh a black
blob may or may not be opaque but we're
not asking the question about the format
about this is opaqueness an actual
requirement from keep
okay so i've started a new poll
whether the value should be
opaque
that's that's looking pretty strong
consensus there
yeah i'm gonna give it another minute
though
this may actually help us move forward
on the eat draft too
okay i'm going to give it 10 more
seconds
okay i think we've kind of stabilized so
um
okay
that one you have strong consensus on so
i think we're good to go
okay let's go on to the next slide then
thank you all this has been a very
useful discussion to me so
uh but before we leave the eat uh
section uh
[Music]
uh i recorded for the first question uh
consensus for the second question on
well you should be a big strong
consensus and i don't think you did a
ball on the ua uuid itself right or did
i miss no
i didn't correct i'm saying
based on the results of the other two
this one is a uh rats uh discussion uh
that okay really doesn't care
and that
it should be rats that calls that
question that teep
yeah
thank you for capturing that thomas
next slide um nancy
okay
um
so
uh
trying to finish out the eat stuff the
eat document section seven covers
requirements for an eat profile there's
this long list of requirements there
some of those requirements are covered
in the t document right now like use of
json sieber or both where we say it's
only seabor
like the second one from the bottom
seaboard tags we previously last i have
a discussion and we're not going to use
the seaport tag it's just raw because
you always know that it's uh a uh they
always know that it's um
a
uh
an eat
uh and so on but not all of them so next
slide please you can see that i said
long list of requirements says if you're
going to find a neat profile you got to
cover all those that's what the new
document says okay
so today
um not all of those are covered in the
tea protocol spec how many of those are
right so there's two ways to resolve
this issue one is we just cover the
missing ones by putting those in the t
protocol spec
another possibility is to say we could
separate all the eprofile stuff and put
it into the same spec okay because it's
already in the t protocol the pieces of
it that are answered right now
the default answer is the same spec but
i just wanted to verify is there anybody
that has an argument as to why that
should be separated out into a separate
spec
things that could have been reasons for
b that do not currently apply is if you
had
multiple protocols that were all going
to be using the same eat
profile but that's currently not the
case
it would be a separate spec if say there
was a reason to
implement the eprotocol without the e
protocol without the without the eat
profile that's not the case
or if there is a reason to say we need
the tea protocol spec to go to rfc while
we're still working on it because it's
optional that's also not the case so all
the reasons i can think of for b don't
apply and so right now the proposal is
we're going to address this by putting
all the other requirements there into
the actual heat protocol spec unless
there's any
objections okay
if there's nobody that comes to the mic
we can go on to the next slide
because that will be what's not in draft
07 that would be in draft 08 as we got
to go through the rest of that list
okay
you've got ira agreeing with you
on the chat
all right thank you
next
okay now we're out of the eat section
now we are into uh so thanks to those um
who um oh interesting this one is
actually out of order i meant to go to
the suit ones next but that's okay i'll
still cover this i meant to cover um
let's see we got half hour left let's
skip this one we'll come back to it i
want to get to the suit discussions
yeah you have exactly
30 minutes left
um or a little bit less because you want
to save the last but but i i'll go as
long as you can let's skip this one i
want to get to the suit ones because if
we don't get the optimization ones
that's fine this is the optimization
category yeah
yeah this is what we're going here okay
i'm fine giving you the time dave i mean
the only the only reason why i left the
five minutes was to assess readiness for
this draft okay
okay um yeah okay
uh yeah there's two there's two ones
that are purely optimizations and that
last slide was one of them if we have
time i'll come back to it but uh but the
other category is since we got suit
people here let's go over the suit
discussions okay other than akira
already covered one of those so
uh draft 07 includes brennan's manifest
examples he went through that last ietf
and so uh that's sufficient to answer
issue 41
but uh last iatf brandon also provided
suit reports and we walked through those
last meeting and the suit reports have
not been added into the t protocol spec
right now so that's issue number 170 is
to take brennan's examples that we used
in the ietf 111 meeting and put those in
the appendix of the t protocol spec 2
which is where the manifest examples
already appear
so that's issue number 170 not going to
talk about that because brendan gave
that presentation last time
uh then there are uh two other issues
um one is the one that um actually i
think that's the wrong number on there
oh that's the issue number he had the
pull request number but it's the same
thing that was a curious presentation
about the three types of suit manifests
we've already talked about that in the
meeting but there's another one that he
had in the hackathon slide that i'm
going to talk about now which is um the
one about deleting a trusted component
suit manifest so next slide
okay
so there's two interrelated questions
here in this issue as i read it okay
this has to do with removing or in the
suit working group we call that
unlinking right because it's actually
removed when the last link goes away
right you're dropping a ref count right
um the issue in the t uh
github says removing but we mean
unlinking okay two related questions
here first one for a suit is should a
suit parser
unlink all the dependent manifests when
you uh
all of all the dependencies when you
unlink the dependent manifest right so
if a references b and you say unlink a
does that automatically unlink b
um or presumably i'm guessing the answer
is only when the ref count on a goes to
zero would you unlink b right but that's
the question that's in the issue here
and then the second question is um well
keep is a protocol for doing things but
what happens if you try to run some
alternate thing like running as you know
some admin or whatever outside of t
protocol is there a way to unlink stuff
and what happens if you do that okay
because if you do that um you may be
doing it without having a brand new suit
manifest that says to delete it is it
possible to delete a component that was
added through suit at suit manifest
without having a suit manifest that
updates it okay or do you have to do it
through a suit manifest that's what q2
is okay
and so option number one okay
is you actually require having a new
manifest okay even if you're doing it
locally you have to construct a suit
manifest that bumps the manifest
sequence number um and that's what
actually the suit processor is what
drops the ref count right so the only
way to drop the ref count taken by suit
is to have a new suit manifest higher
verge sequence number or manifest
sequence number that drops the ref count
right that would be option one
option number two point one has
mentioned the issue but i don't think
anybody likes this one which is uh you
could try to have some suit parser that
tries to undo a bait so if you have a
local undo then it tries to look at the
suit manifest and figure out how to how
to unlink and uninstall it according to
all the correct stuff in general this
one just doesn't work with all soup
manifest and that's why it's there for
completeness but uh yeah exactly please
no screams exactly yeah so that one is
really we should cross that one off and
everybody agrees that's not it okay
but then the other possibility is should
there be a uh suit uninstalled so that
the same suit manifest they did the
install said should you need to
uninstall this later without having to
manifest here's what you would do
and so if you tried to do something
locally and you didn't have to create a
new suit manifest so it's really between
option 1 and option 2.2 and this is
really a question for the suit working
group to weigh in on other than um the
tpu's case is you can see the the the
analogy that the filer had is the
equivalent of like apt remove dash y foo
kind of equivalent for like an admin on
the machine does he have to do that by
generating a new suit manifest or can
you do that by uh by some other means
with the actual uninstall commands were
embedded in the last in the actual
install manifest and so uh that's what
issue 168 was filed against um by our
japanese colleagues or at least one of
them
so feedback on this one especially from
suit folks like brendan
right and so the the issue that bothers
me with all of this is a question of
privilege
well actually there's two there's two
issues the first is exactly how do you
obtain the privileges to invoke and
unlink
when you are not the signing author
and
that's out of protocol that's out of
document
um
it's out of manifest the question is
how do you manage that when everything's
done with manifests this is pretty
straightforward because you are
expressing your authority through a
signature
but when you don't have that
this looks to me like exactly the thing
that some attacker wants to be able to
forcibly remove something from your
system
so i can't comment on that and by the
way the default answer is option one and
so the actual pull request tries to put
in some text uh that just clarifies
using option one but it's interesting to
talk about whether option 2.2 is an
option or not so to answer your question
brandon um uh
my view is that option 2.2 is not
completely out of the question whether
it's a good idea or a bad ideas thing
but and that's because in the teep
architecture document okay there is a
trust anchor store okay so the trust
anchor store can have one or more keys
in it that's the keys that are used to
uh like
by the manifest signer for example right
so things that are used to run against
the actual tas okay as opposed to they
say you know the the signing of teap
commands themselves the sign of the suit
manifests and so there's one or more um
uh trust anchors in the trust anchor
store okay and so the question here in
2.2 that you might be worried about is
is it really the case that you have to
have the same trust anchor signing the
uninstall as sign the install do you
have to remember which trust anchor did
it or is it just any trust anchor in
your store is the one that can do that
and if you think about like key rollover
and so on is that really a trust anchor
id of the actual trust anchor but if you
if you took a choice that says any trust
anchor in the trust anchor store was
equally trusted okay then as long as uh
the local install comes from one of
those trust anchors it does it would not
have to be the trust anchor that
actually signed the suit manifest i
think that's the distinction between
option one and option 2.2
yeah so i think the the take that i have
on that is that any equally privileged
trust anchor should be able to
to
unlink a manifest um i just
on that topic i thought we were
originally doing unlink for components
but we now appear to be unlinking
manifests that that
was a somewhat unintended consequence
but i i think it works so i mean that's
all right but we did originally discuss
this as unlinking components rather than
unlinking
manifests uh i did not think of the
distinction when creating the slide so
that may be an error on my part but it's
uh you're right to call it out so
um the the other factor here is that
provide that
the question is where do the links come
from in the first place
uh if you have installed this thing
uh manually then i guess there's a link
that you can unlink
if it hasn't been installed manually if
it's been installed by another manifest
how do you unlink it is that something
you're even permitted to do so there's a
question about link tracking and where
these links come from you can't simply
decrement a reference counter every time
you call on link because otherwise you
could call on link many times and then
leave your system in an unusable state
you can only unlink a link you've
created which means that you can only
say apt remove something that you've apt
installed otherwise you break
dependencies
so i guess the question is if you were
able to locally install a component then
you should be able to locally remove it
in that case you probably want a suit
uninstall
section not command
section
or command sequence rather
because otherwise um
that
i don't see how you would do the unlink
it i'm not sure how that would make
sense i i think you
probably need to have
uh an uninstall command sequence it's
i don't see another way is that
something you think that the suit
working group should actually add into
and by suit working group we mean mostly
you as the editor would actually add
into the uh suit manifest id is that
what you're thinking based on this
discussion
yeah so i think that would have to go
into the trust domains id uh because i
think it's highly relevant to
just
almost entirely
a situation where you have multiple
trust domains uh where
just to be clear teep is exclusively a
multiple trust domain kind of domain uh
yeah i think
it might need to go there and and i
mentioned in the suit working group and
i'll mention it again if anyone else
would like to come on and edit that
document they are welcome
[Music]
so i guess what i'm hearing is that for
now teep should continue to go forward
with option
one
but that uh
uh uh the 2.2 suit will uh consider that
and discuss it
um and i see there's we got a couple of
us uh suit co-chairs here um and so that
would then uh be a new discussion we
would start on the t uh on the suit
mailing list
i think it would have to it's
so i mean the history of suit
meant that uninstall wasn't really a
question it was
really just for install because
uninstall was typically replacement so
the idea of explicitly uninstalling
something was a bit foreign and needs
some additional consideration
yeah and thank you for correcting the
language here as i was constructing the
slide it was
uh
jet lag this week and so yeah that
really should say suit uninstall section
even if the text and the uh issue number
says command right now but this section
yeah say here's the directives to do an
uninstall should you need to do an
uninstall without having any other
information other than the suit manifest
again yep
okay so uh i guess we will push that
option 2.2 discussion to the suit list
and uh currently there's an open pull
request that puts in some clarifying
text assuming that option number one
is the way that you have to do it and so
the clarifying text just says here's uh
here's what happens when you have the
largest to do this you do you do it via
new suit manifest and so it wouldn't
actually
reference the option 2.2 stuff and
unless and until uh suit actually put
something in a document that's
referenceable
era
i presume you wanted to move forward
yeah i see i were in q though
oh true sorry are you actually
uninstalling a component or are you
uninstalling a manifest
ira i i can't hear you i i could hear
him very faintly saying are you actually
i'm selling a component or a manifesto
that was what i was asking yes yes
and i think brendan's comment was it can
either one he thinks would be okay but i
think that's a a question for uh for
pursuit but i think both possibilities
are are
are out there
okay thank you
[Music]
okay
all right um
personalization data scenarios i'm going
to summarize where we're at with this
one
i don't remember if there's a separate
issue number there may be and i didn't
put it on the slide so
personalization data scenarios that are
talked about in
either the architecture document of the
the t protocol document and make sure
we're not missing something here
first scenario for personalization data
is where the
developer provides both the binary and
the personalization data right they're
packaged separately in some way because
the binary is exact is identical that
goes to all the different devices the
personalization data is different that
goes to different devices right but
since that's why they're packaged
separately but the same entity in this
case is the developer and a signs both
of them
case b is where uh doesn't matter what
the developer did right the one that
actually manages the device is the one
that's the actual science of trusted
signer right so
the device doesn't trust arbitrary
developers it trusts its own operator
and owner
uh depending on the use case whether
it's an operator an owner
and so that one provides the binary
maybe gets it from a developer vets it
signs it itself generates
personalization data and puts it on
there as far as the protocol is
concerned this is basically equivalent
to case a right it's a it's a different
organization maybe a different uh human
flow but as far as the code goes a and b
are basically equivalent right it's the
same thing okay they're
indistinguishable to code basically
option c is where they're different
entities so the developer might provide
the binary and the operator owner
provides the personalization data so
like the configuration stuff right
what's the set of keys to use or what's
the what's the names or what's the
website to talk to or whatever it is
right so and
so that's where you have different cases
and so
uh in this exam in this case um the way
shown to do this is that there's a
manifest for the personalization data
that has the tc binary manifest as a
dependency right so
the the operator says you need to
install this personalization data the
personalization data says well in order
to solve this i'm going to also install
the tc binary right and that's so you
can have many manifests that point to
one you couldn't do in the other
direction because you'd have one
manifest that points to many it'd be
very very difficult by comparison and so
this is what's in the appendix e.1
example today
those are all the variations that are
discussed today if there's any
variations missing then please bring up
or file an issue or whatever but i think
that's what's covered in the document
now so
unless there's any comments the mic next
slide please
okay
next one is the cypher suites question
this was filed during the hackathon uh
by i don't remember who um
let's see so today the cipher suites in
the document right now it defines a new
registry that has two values in it
and it says the tam has to support both
of them and the teep agent gets to pick
its choice of either of those okay next
slide
okay uh okay it was a sobe son that uh
filed this okay so uh during
implementation uh it was pointed out
that uh there's this one registry in
deep in a different registry in um
in uh
slash cose and can't we just use the
same one so that we don't have to have
two different spaces and so could
uh
t
just say to use the actual numbering
space and values out of cose and then
that would simplify the code and so this
is an example of what the document might
say this is copied out of sobazon's
proposal which is you know the typecozy
algorithms is the cozy algorithm es256
so those the two that were on the
previous slide and there's various other
ones that are optional but you can see
the way that it specified it it does not
create a new registry and so we would
delete the registry if we went with this
proposal and the point is this would
simplify implementations and so uh
any comments on this
this seems like it's a good idea and
akira briefly touched on this during his
presentation so
uh i'm sure ayanna would like not having
to have two registries and another
expert or something so um unless there's
any comments on this one
um yes uh thank you for clarifying it's
always son uh
optional just means um picking from the
existing coset registry right
uh let's see i see i see people going
say plus one from ira long discussion
from ben but i don't see ben at the mike
so i don't know if there's uh
anything that needs to be discussed with
the mic ben
if you don't come to the michael it
seemed like you just go on but if you
want to say something go ahead
i think he's just clarifying okay next
next slide then
because uh if there's no objections then
i think it's probably a good idea to
simplify so
um
all right so suit
cipher suites
okay now we're into the manifest right
the proposal from the suit meeting just
fyi if you weren't in the suit meeting
was the suit decided that
hss lms
is actually the must um ecdsa is a
should
and you may implement others
okay and those are just examples of
others that there might be but there's
the the boston they should okay
that's fyi from the suit discussion um
early on this week next slide
all right
so the next issue from a
hackathon that's still related to suit
um
is issue 104 okay so here
the uh
the developer creates a suit manifest
that points to the tc binary that the
developer created right so he hosts it
on his own share or wherever he has it
right so the developer creates his own
suit manifest okay so now you have a
case where the tam or you know the owner
or the operator wants to override that
uri okay example okay it wants to host
the binary itself right maybe the tam is
a tan for devices that are not on the
public internet right and so it has a
location that's accessible to the
devices where the public internet that
original uri might not actually be
reachable in that location right think
you know
cruise ship space whatever it is you're
in some disconnected network or some uh
connect network where you don't have
reliable connectivity to the outside
world okay so you want to host that uri
so how do you override that okay
and so one way to do this is the tam
just creates a brand new manifest okay
with the tam is the signer okay and so
it just reconstructs that because the uh
trust anchor is the tams trust anchor
that the device trusts you could create
a brand new manifest that the team can
construct using taking the original
manifest doing a new version copying
most of the fields replacing the uri and
saying brand new one the developer is
actually not in the loop never even
identified doesn't have to be anyway
and so off you go so this is a case that
i think no document changes would be
needed if i understand that scenario
correctly um issue 105 is a way to say
okay is there a way to reduce the effort
to say somehow reference the original
manifest and just override the one field
and say everything else i'm
incorporating by reference okay it's
this other stuff except for i want to
override this one field okay and so here
the binary is still signed by the
original signer right not by the tam the
tam is signing the manifest it says that
original signer is actually okay okay
and i just want to update the uri and so
is this a good idea or a bad idea
or some better way to do this and i've
seen brennan and q to answer this so go
ahead
so i think you may be missing a couple
of other options that are available
which might be more appropriate i'm not
sure
uh so the first one is plain old caching
so
as long as you don't use an https uri
there's nothing to stop you from just
caching the binary on some local system
then you just override it in your
transparent cache and away you go no
problem
uh you're saying push the binary down to
the device and update its http cache to
say go and look here i didn't get it
through http i just pushed it down and
shoved it in the cache right
no no not that uh i mean that's an
option as well that wasn't what i was
aiming for what i meant is that in your
own network infrastructure if you have a
transparent cache sitting around which
i'm sure a lot of network
infrastructures do uh you can
use that instead and then you just
override the http request and serve it
locally i i know you can't do that with
https but there's already
at rest security on your uh
if you're using suit encryption so you
might as well just use a cache uh it's a
much simpler solution and i realize that
we don't talk about it quite so much
these days given that uh https has taken
over but it's still it's a simple viable
option and it's actually kind of the
point of having at rest security on
firmware binaries
uh that's one of the couple of their
options was there others
yeah there's another one um so one of
the changes to the the suit manifest
that came cropped up over this one was
the use of integrated payloads
referenced by a string
and that was specifically so that you
wouldn't have to do conversions from the
uri
to the the key in the integrated payload
but the offshoot of that is that you can
use that as a precaching mechanism you
can then take your
uh your your target binary
download it in advance as your
distribution system move it into the
envelope of your manifest
and make its uh its key in the envelope
the uri that's already in the manifest
and then when the device goes to look
for it it first checks if there are any
string keys and if one of them matches
it takes it there and if not then it uh
then it goes out and attempts to do a
fetch so you can do
transparent pre-caching
so that that might be relevant as well
and as you suggest a device's local http
cache might be relevant too
so uh yeah i'll look through
but
i'm not completely follow the the last
of your three uh the last of your
options here i only followed parts of
that and so uh it would be useful to uh
write it up on the list i see we've got
six minutes left so you're welcome to
try again or to just put the description
on the list that's fine too so
uh all it is is that because you've got
a a string reference
in the suit envelope
for integrated payloads that string can
simply happen to be the uri that's
specified in the manifest
that doesn't require signing authority
to do it doesn't require anything you
can just put it there
so i guess this might overlap with that
uh discussion we had about uh examples
to say
do we want an example we're actually
doing that with the binary uri
that would be helpful yes
yeah
okay any other comments on this one
okay thank you brandon let's go on to
the next slide
all right um
so uh accurate do we do you actually
want to talk through this one right now
or defer and go on to another topic the
question to akira
if if a cure doesn't this is your chance
i see uh
uh can if you want to say if you want to
say something you can also come to the
bike
yeah my mic wasn't working um yeah uh
other topic first yeah it's
yeah this is it doesn't have to be yeah
okay all right then we can we can go on
and it's the same for can if you needed
to say something feel free to come to
the mic otherwise we'll go on all right
so yeah so now we've got to the last two
let's go back to the one slide that i
skipped before that was out of order
that was supposed to be after this one
so go back to right before the use of
suit uh slide there's the first of the
optimization slides
and uh feel free to call time because
this one is just optimizations okay yeah
thank you this one i mean you've got
three minutes left so okay yep i got it
i i i see the clock but uh call time if
you want so all right
this one says um
you know today
um in order to get a query response you
reach out to the tam with an empty
payload the tam responds to the query
response and then you can finally with a
query request and then you can send your
query response you have this extra round
trip
and so this question is this is purely
an optimization but if you already know
the tam key or cert right whatever
you're using to authenticate uh the tam
could you send an unsolicited query
response to avoid the extra round trip
okay
well obviously you can't do this if
there's information that varies in the
response the in the request that you
actually need to put in your response so
like if you have a token like you're
having a not stuff your freshness
mechanism
is uh nonce then of course you cannot do
this okay but given that we have
possibilities of having other freshness
mechanisms right you can use the epic
ide you can use time stamp freshness
mechanism
and so if you had that then there's
nothing that actually appears in the
query request that's different from any
other query request that you've gotten
from it okay
and so um is it possible to send an
unsolicited query response if the query
request would contain no information
that you didn't already have okay
and so here's the proposal to address
this okay
that the teap agent may
send an unsolicited query response to a
tam if all three of the following
conditions are true okay because if any
one of these is false then there's a
potential problem so here's the three
conditions number one
you've gotten a query request already
from that tam and it contained no token
or challenge in other words there's no
fields that actually vary by things
because those are the only standard
fields that vary right there's nothing
in it that would be different from the
one that you got before that right so
there's no no fields that vary
number two
is that um it didn't send you a process
error
since you got that query request because
in other words you if you this one is to
cover the case where you sent an
unsolicited one and something had
changed the tam said up you know there's
some um error and of course the tam just
drops it there's no uh bad response and
so process error is the notification
from the local broker the http returned
that the transport returned an error so
like for return error 400 or 500 http
then the broker sends process error up
to 10 broker up to 10 agents right and
so this says you do not get an error
from trying to do this before that's
number two
number three
is that the tam search or key or
whatever is cached and still valid right
so
you can only do it if you actually have
all the information you need to
authenticate to tam okay so this is the
proposed that if all three of those are
true then it's okay to send an
unsolicited query response because the
extra round trip doesn't actually buy
you anything
okay
any objections because the proposal is
to put that into the next version of the
spec so
and of course we try to implement that
in in the uh
implementations before next ietf so at
least one of them so
all right hearing unless there's any
comments then i think we're out of time
we've got like one minute left but i
don't think we have time to go to the
last to the last one there's only one
more stop
i i was gonna say if you're done with
this slide i can ask the question to you
dave you you've got a bunch of these
comments you now have a way forward with
the eat claims too so i'm presuming
you're gonna continue to resolve these
the question for you is the protocol
spec looks to be maturing
the question is whether um
there would be value in us doing an
early i could ask the iot director to do
an early review if you see value in that
after you you
generate a new revision by the way yeah
if the if you can go to the very very
last lie which is basically asking that
style of questions um
so skip any other content slides just go
to the very last one as you're asking
that um
the i think your question is is it
useful to have an earlier review say
even before a working request call right
and i think you know that might be
perfectly fine right my hope was we
could get to a working group less called
capable state
around iutf 113 that might mean you know
immediately after 113 but sometime
around that time frame um
but starting early review if there's
things i think that would be useful yeah
okay well i mean so my question
now that you've posted to 113 we could
wait till 1 13.
i mean you saw there's still
gaps like uh filling in the rest of the
requirements around the eat profile i
mean hopefully there shouldn't be
anything surprising there but the text
isn't in there right and so there may be
gaps in the text as opposed to
implementation
why not so that's why
yeah
and so right now i'm saying we should
start working group last call once the
number of unresolved issues goes to zero
right and so whether that happens before
or after depends on whether we keep
filing new ones and implementation so
okay
so um
let's shoot for doing the working group
last call in 113 um
and dido and i can keep pulsing
the number of issues that could
get added
i mean best case right the issue number
goes to zero
at the time of uh you know the internet
draft deadline you could start a working
group last call that would terminate at
iutf113 so that would be best case
okay
um honest so we're out of time but
hannes is saying we should maybe do a
hackathon in december
johannes i
encourage you to put that on the mail
list
and um we can
figure out how we can move forward and
making progress so you guys have have
done a great job
in ironing out some of these issues so
thank you for that
okay yeah i see some internet discussion
on hss lms please put that in the list
too
i missed that yes
okay i want to be respectful of people's
time so we i'm two minutes over
thank you everyone
uh
great progress to everyone and until our
next time
thanks again
and thanks thomas for the news thank you
we'll see a number of you at the uh rats
working group session in a half an hour
indeed
akira it's late for you and very early
for me
[Laughter]
but for me it's okay
yeah still
still 11 pm
not bad on friday
yeah i've been waking up at three in the
morning
every morning
yeah
wow
yeah um
for me last i did one was more
difficult because it started from one
two or three a.m
and then in the end
around six
a.m and then
in the regular office
working hours started from eight eight
or something yeah so that's that's
what's happening to me
that's great isn't it because now you
lose nothing from your regular workday
[Laughter]
the fact that i i've been on calls until
5 00 5 30 in the afternoon yeah i don't
know about that
and yesterday was a uh u.s holiday
yeah yeah no conflict
i think your boss will will uh reward
this
well and so to add insult to injury why
am i well i really should not use this
as an excuse for why my slides were skin
slides
no it just it wasn't
because i'm awake
my laptop died
tuesday at around 11 in the morning
so i finally brought it back to life
around midnight tonight so i've only
been taking one or two hour naps so i'm
i'm looking forward to the weekend to
sleep
[Laughter]
one thing i
um i'm i'm i really wasn't noticing but
i started to realize this
having a whole week
of the ietf the last day um improves my
english
your english is very good akita and and
you're right if i recall from when we
started with teep
your english has improved not that it
was bad to begin with
um
uh yeah my english
not always this good it's sometime i
don't know what's the difference in my
brain sometimes it easily comes out
sometimes it doesn't but um
if it's
i don't yeah
somehow just think about how our
japanese improved over the lifetime of
this working group
[Laughter]
yeah
japanese is
um i mean
difficult for me too i mean i i just i
born in japan i grew up in japan but
still
yeah
buddy
yeah i mean
many of the engineers
chose the engineering subject because
they didn't
didn't like
language and literature class i mean
well i i could say that to be true
for me as well
i much preferred the math and sciences
than i did to
uh
yeah
in the us they call them the liberal
arts right so language and history and
yeah
but nancy that maybe explains why our
documents look the way they are and they
will never reach the pulitzer award
stage right
yeah that's true
the truth comes out is that right
all right i'm gonna go get refill my my
bottle of water
see you guys in rats
yeah yeah
see you
later bye guys
bye everyone
you