okay it's the top of the hour
welcome everyone uh this is a session of
the uh that net working group at iedf112
louberger
and myself janusz farkas co-chair uh the
working group
and we are uh thankful to ethan grossman
our secretary for the great minutes and
have uh provided us uh behind the scenes
the uh
agenda details are available at the
usual place
links are provided here as well
on this slide
next slide please
it's a reminder that we operate under
the ietf rules and policies
captured in the ietf note well
so all the rules
apply and by participating here in the
iitf you agree to follow these policies
and procedures please check if you are
not familiar with that as a reminder
this
meeting and the contributions become
part of the
permanent record
so by participating you acknowledge
the recording
there's a list of
bcps
here highlighted that
drive
our operations
and in the next slide we would like to
draw attention uh to to
one of them the code of conduct it has
been there uh before
uh it is uh uh i think it's going well
in in the working group just a reminder
that
we expected
to behave towards our colleagues
respectfully and with courtesy and
professional
next slide please
okay mythical yeah you you have found it
you are here that's that's good and um
we also have the usual uh way of
chat and jumper
uh combined in mythical as well
available and the jabber link is in the
bottom as well
the blue sheets are automatic
in this electronic meeting
no need to bother with that
and please join us for the note taking
in kodi md or hashtag what is the name
at this moment
the link link is here and also available
via the materials
please help me taking and and
make sure that
your points in the discussion have been
captured accurately
uh the agenda also available online
uh
i think that's enough for this slide
maybe the next one
okay the sessions at uh this idea sorry
for the typo it is itf112
uh we had a
joint session
with pass and mpls working group on
monday
this is important for us because mprs is
is one of our data planes
and uh the evolution of mpls is being
discussed in these joint working group
meetings and also
in uh weekly regular
design open design team meetings if you
are interested join them too
there was a a contribution presented
related to that net and we discussed
that one here at the deadnet session as
well please uh check the recording if
you were not able to attend
we are here on wednesday in the main.net
session
next slide and slide please
okay so this is our agenda
after this intro we
will have the om work items on the
agenda
and
after that some data plane uh related
contributions on payoff bracket ordering
and uh the second half is sort of newer
work items
uh first uh discussing continuing the
discussion on on on the requirements on
moving or towards a larger scale
networks
some people were considered in the
beginning and some solution ideas
at towards the end on the achievement
agenda
next slide please
an update on the on our status as a
working group we have a new rfc
published on uh the data plane ib over
mpls
we have two documents for which
publication has been requested uh that
not bounded latency
draft and the newer one is
that that net yang is progressing many
thanks to all the contributors
who have to make this step and we are
looking forward to
finish both of these documents and then
go to the final approval procedure and
get them published
we have two working do group documents
that are not on the agenda uh
they we have the op
oem
package uh there is no specific detail
on ip
uh at this meeting that's a sort of a
bit later stage in the in the queue
uh first we are working on a framework
and an mpls and an ip that was the
discussion and the other one is the
control airplane framework on which
there was an update provided on the list
next slide please
okay we have received the liaison at the
end of july from itot study group 13
on work items related to deterministic
communication
this falls in to our scope and the work
we are conducting here
so this
liaison has been provided
as for information
to us but as it is very closely related
to our work
uh we suggest
to respond to this liaison and discuss
the details on the list
next slide please
okay just a reminder on the ipr
procedures we follow uh
strictly the usual ipr procedures and
there are two
points when we request
ipr call
prior to
so in the beginning at the end prior to
working group adoption and um
towards the working group last call
and also we have a step
that we request uh upgrade statements to
be made clear if there's a new outer in
a draft
next slide please
okay we have been working remote
for a while and
just to to remind people that
our main
forum is the is the list so please
please use the list comment and there
have been good discussions i'm really
glad for for that
and uh we have opportunities for virtual
meetings in addition to the regular ietf
meetings
as as needed we can schedule interview
meetings uh as we just had uh recently
and uh we can also have informal working
meetings to advance our documents
we
used to do this for data plane and then
for yang actually now the young has been
completed and the one
that is ongoing and we we have a
bi-weekly meetings on the progressing
the oem work so these meetings can be
set up by by the chairs and please reach
out to us if
you see
uh other topics that should be discussed
or would be beneficial for the group to
be discussed um
either way in our interim or in informal
working meetings we can we can set up
those meetings
and this was the last slide as the intro
any questions
okay hitting none then let's move to the
first presentation
from greg
yes thank you um
good morning and um so this is an update
on uh
our
framework for
operation administration maintenance
in a dead net
next or at least
so in
111 meeting uh the working group
agreed to uh merge um
part of their
um
draft into this uh document um on
oem requirements for uh that net service
sublayer layer and uh we welcome uh
balash indiana as a coffers
uh we continue discussing uh documents
related to that net oem in our bi-weekly
meetings and uh thanks janice
for leading these discussions
so there are more significant updates as
mentioned so we integrated these
requirements for deadlift subnet
service sub layer
and now are the requirements in the
document structured
in three groups uh general.net oem
requirements
uh
requirements for forwarding sub layer
and for service sub layer
next slide please
so among uh general requirements and
this is not a complete list it's just
the highlights
so the oem sessions are between that net
uh
maintenance
and points
uh
supporting uh and should be you able to
use a proactive and on demand monitoring
and measurement
and uh proactive is uh something that is
uh continuous and
periodic
uh using uh
probe packets
and on demand it's more understanded
it's basically initiated by
an operator and it has a
terminal
lifetime of the test session
um
must support unidirectional oem methods
for example as continuity check and
measure packet delay and packet class
also support uh oem for bi-directional
deadman flows
next slide please
uh for the forwarding sub layer
um
be able to do path uh
mtu uh discovery
be able to use a remote defect indicator
support monitoring levels for resources
allocated for the given that net flow
and for example these resources
are include but not limited to
buffer location and transmit schedule of
calendar
support monitoring any step path
traversed by the particular deadline
flow
next slide please
uh for the service sub layer so that is
the part that we integrated and it's new
to this document it's not new it's been
discussed uh
by the working group but in this
document that's an update
um so oem functions for that net sub uh
service sub layer
and support discovery of the dead net
relay nodes and uh in a service sub
layer these relay nodes are
node that met nodes that
implement support
one of the packet replication
elimination and or the preservation sub
functions
support the collection of that net
service sub layer specific information
and that specific information
is related uh to the pre-op sub
functions and relay nodes
support the ability of exercising
functionality of packet replication
elimination and oil preservation
functions
and
that is
really important because
this is a new mechanism and listed new
mechanism for oem
and it requires
additional special
instrumentation
for
probe
packet and ability to control
uh this
sub functions pre-offset functions
support to use alarm indication signal
between that net relay nodes and so that
is important uh then uh discovering a
defect on um
service layer and indicating uh the
propagating
our medication signal to the
client sub layer
support performance monitoring in a dead
service sub layer with a pre-off
in use
any questions
about their requirements and the
structure
of the document because that is new as
we
added um
there is section on the service sub
layer so we
separate it
[Music]
into the general and the forwarding sub
layer yes
uh lou you have a question a comment
can you hear me
no yes
ah okay i muted that guy yeah he did it
backwards sorry um you're you have a
metric section that seems a little light
my expectations are going to beef that
up um while you're doing that i think
you're it would be good to have um
requirements for each of the metrics
that you're talking about you know
whether the metric is required or not or
you know it must should may
that's it okay
thank you
okay uh next slide please
so while we were
working on
the requirements we found
several open issues that we
consider not to be entirely editorial
and that's why
we are uh highlighting them uh in the
presentation and uh one working group uh
to
uh discuss it
um so the hybrid oem and that's uh using
their classification rfc 7799
and as a
oem measurement method that combines uh
passive active uh measurements
um
is often represented by on path
telemetry methods such as for example in
situ oem and alternate marking method
and telemetry information um
can be collected and transported in
banded out of bank so the example of
invent is one of their
options trace options
documented in oem as
where the information is collected in
packets either hub by hub or and by uh
to end
uh so hop by hub it's a
transit notes uh iom nodes uh add uh
requested telemetry information in the
data packet that serves as a trigger and
end to end as an ingress and igor's only
um
collect information
uh but in addition there are out of band
methods so where their
information is uh
stored locally
either for direct exporting uh
immediately or for
um
aggregation processing and exporting of
some calculated uh performance uh
metrics
and uh so this um
uh out of band methods can be either
using
um
yank data model so they use
in combination with a model driven
telemetry
uh or use
some other methods
well known like grpc
kafka
uh else
so um
what we're asking is that the current
document states that that net oem may
support hybrid performance measurement
methods but in our discussions we agreed
that uh
these methods can provide valuable and
important information especially
uh important for uh streaming telemetry
information that used uh for network
analytics
and uh then in
combination with out-of-band uh
collection entrance um of information uh
provided important and uh valuable uh
operational uh mechanism so the our
proposal is that makes support of the
hybrid measurement methods mandatory so
to change
must
and we understand that this discussion
uh
to be on the mailing list and uh
i would like a working group uh to
discuss it and um
come to some conclusion
uh so further are we proposing to
splitting um the requirement that
combines proactive and on-demand oem
into two requirements
uh that
just the convenience because um
it's much easier to
evaluate the conformance and then uh
when we are talking about
uh if we need the new mechanisms or
we're uh doing a gap analysis
and we're uh
need to do the checklist
uh attribute uh to
two separate requirements rather than
just say okay that's uh this mechanism
can be used for the part of this uh
requirement that is confusing
and uh another is um what we found is
like thought is inconsistency but we uh
discussed it
um
so it's
uh two requirements in the general
session um
are related to unidirectional
performance measurements
and uh they seem as duplicate
so and uh
yeah actually it's like in a second and
it should be ten not in first sentence
and eleven
um so we just uh want to remove the
first sentence
so that's uh probably more editorial
and next slide please
so we'll continue our uh bi-weekly
discussion and uh everyone is welcome uh
to join um so this is our open um
calls
uh please comment uh review the document
and uh we think that we are getting
close to the stable document and uh
probably
uh
at some point uh before the next meeting
will uh be ready for the working dual
bus call
thank you
any comments questions
uh greg i'd like to go back for a moment
to your this hybrid discussion
yes uh
the so uh you made two comments here
about uh um
one is about off path or out of band
um so we have had uh in
um sort of traffic engineering we've
done a lot of out of band um uh for the
response
and
uh response messages or for feedback you
know so on on path or in band for
forward and then
off uh out of band off path for reverse
um
we need bi-directional messaging and
you're doing one-way
oam
that definition is a little different
than rfc 77's 99's definition of
out-of-band
uh for them they use out-of-band to talk
about act uh active and passive
so when they're talking hybrid they're
talking passive monitoring versus active
monitoring
um
well so 77.99 they they they they have
actually the two types of hybrid uh but
um
it's it's
their the title of the
rfc is
active passive in in between
so um
um
itself
uh the
hybrid methods that use
some
that add some information to the data
packet
are
hybrid because uh they need to um
mark packets
uh as in alternate marking methods to
create the flow of uh
marked packets that identify changes in
batches
and uh iam which inserts it as a minimum
inserts the header that indicates and
lists uh
of
informational elements that needs to be
collected um
and a node or requested to be collected
at the node
um so
uh their collection methods out of band
uh here is uh
interpreted as being uh out of band
relative to the monitored uh data flow
yeah i think i think we can have more
discussion on this maybe on the list
but i think for um you know out of band
for responses is something that's you
know well established
and
certainly we're going to want to support
and so the requirement all looks good
actually i think the text in the
document is pretty good it's really just
your characterization here that i had an
issue with okay
the the other thing is that telemetry is
usually about monitoring of oam not the
oem itself
and um you don't use telemetry in the
dock document right now at least i
didn't notice you're using it um
actually you do use it
i'll have to read what you mean by
telemetry uh because um the
the examples you gave are more about
monitoring oem than actual oem right
um
again um so the telemetry um
usually differentiate uh two components
uh so they're uh generating telemetry
information and um
uh
collecting transporting uh such
information
and
their
protocols that used so can be
attributed or characterized as uh on
path telemetry information because uh
the other methods that uh now we
discussed are uh model driven um
telemetry
that is um
based on yank push
right and that's more about getting that
to a central controller or to some
monitoring than to do the oam
on along the data path mm-hmm and i
think
those concepts
in a way that for me at least is quite
confusing
oh i'm sorry um yes i i didn't mention
because i didn't go um
into details of uh what's being
discussed now uh by ippm working group
so uh there is a a
very uh
useful uh proposal of uh iom direct
expert so uh where um
the information indicated in the data
packet that telemetry information to be
uh stored for the local processing so
not to collect in a data packet but uh
just to generate originate this
information and then uh their processing
is uh
determined by the local policy so it
could be either exported directly uh
from the packet to the collector and the
collector can be again uh the collector
can be in the eager ingress node uh or
egress node of uh the monitored floor or
as you said that it could be a some
controller that will use it for uh
network analytics
yeah that that discussion would be great
to bring in here because that's the
context of how you're using telemetry so
if that's how you mean to use it
you know i i think bringing it into the
document making that clear would be
great
okay okay we'll work on that
okay thank you
okay hi uh
vargo is speaking and on behalf of the
counters i will present uh
this draft which is oem for the net
service sub layer
next slide please
so there is this draft is uh
has the intention to to collect uh
the service sub layer specific oem
topics
and
the text is targeted to be moved to
virgo drafts and this is what
greg was in the previous
slot highlighted that some texts were
already
moved from this draft to the oem
framework document
this document is focusing only on the
service sub-layer oem so
forwarding sub-layer oem is out of scope
in this document and we are currently at
version 01
and next slide days
the next slide is showing uh what is the
content of the draft and there were
updates made
so section 4 this is what were already
moved to the oem framework document
section 5
dealing with
that net ping which is describing oem
processing at the.net service sub layer
so what a relay node should do when it
is serving that net oem
packet
the new text is added based on the
weekly discussions
uh uh about uh
the service sub layer oem challenges so
we have added uh illustrator
illustrative example uh just a very uh
simple network uh which is uh which can
be very useful during discussion of oem
related issues and challenges
uh we have also added a subsection
dealing with that net service sub layer
specifics but by it is uh somewhat
specific for for oem
uh there is also a section dealing with
what information
needed when that net oem packet is
processed so this information have to
travel with the oem packet
and there was also a section added about
a possible format of the net ach
next slide please
the this slide is just summarizing this
this new text
and this is as i said
mainly the outcome of the of the weekly
discussion
uh and the discussion on the list about
oem
so the service graph
in case of that net it is segmented in
multiple parts
because the the forwarding sub-layer
parts are terminated at the deathnet
relay nodes
and there are some special
characteristics of a deathmatch cellular
because the prior functionalities they
are acting as a
as a pair pocket protection
and that means that all the parts in a
service sub-layer graph
they are active and they are forwarding
traffic
and they may have a different number of
hops and
as usual it is mandatory to use the
sequence number for for that net series
so the main main challenge is that the
oem packets must follow precisely uh the
same path as the packets of the
corresponding.net data flow
next slide please
this slide is showing a possible format
for the net ach associated channel
header
the associated channel header is is used
for for many years for oem purposes
but its size is limited it is only 32
bits
and if during the discussion of of that
net oem
stuff we have identified
multiple pieces of information which
have to be present in a definite oem
packet
and it would be hard to put all these
information in a 32-bit uh
field
because
some part is already reserved for other
purposes so the first nibble is 0001
and in the vergio version uh
with version 1 we can highlight that it
is about
that net associated
channel
header
there are
in the in the draft some proposals
regarding
what uh type of information should be
there and for what purposes they might
be used this is something up to
discussion uh the the major uh
uh
conclusion that we wanted to to
highlight with this slide is that uh we
need to add additional 32-bit uh to to
the ach and create that net specific ach
so how how many bits for sequence number
node id session id and so on are used
this is up for further discussion
and level and flags fields are also
something to be to be defined in more
detail and discuss
level would be something to to create
oem domains and flags can be used for
example to
to control uh the
service sub-layer functionalities for a
given uh that net oem packet
um
next slide please
so uh with this update we have included
in the in the draft the proposed changes
and clarifications which were on the
list and during the biblically oem
course
uh we are still looking for further
comments discussion as i said this is a
a discussion
draft in order to
to
help to
make text of the virgo documents so the
target is to have a common understanding
inside the group and and consensus on
the that net ach and that net being
functionalities
and these are practically texts these
sections to be moved to the group
document and here we mean the net mpls
oem document
thank you
any questions
okay i think uh you know that last point
about moving into the working group
document is something would be good to
address early
uh if this belongs in the working group
document it should be there rather than
as a separate document
i don't quite understand why it is a
separate document and the flow of the
two documents are not well aligned and
so having it as a separate document to
me is not
not a positive thing if we're going to
merge it we should
get agreement from the working group and
do it quickly
um i know greg is going to present next
on the working group document it'd be
good to hear his opinion on that as well
okay
thanks
yes um okay so um this will be a very
brief uh update
uh on uh oem for um that net and with
mpos data plane next slide please
okay so uh we received uh very good
comments from belarus and we addressed
them uh
so
he is
agreed that
everything is much better now and thank
you polish
and
next slide
so that's it um um
yes we you just uh uh heard and um seen
uh the new proposed for uh that net ach
format
and i absolutely agree and uh we
discussed it with bolas and yanash about
how to proceed and we just
felt that it's uh need to be presented
and discussed by the working group and
the working group will decide uh if it
can be merged into their working group
document
so uh please discuss uh also as yamash
mentioned uh in uh
shares update uh at the top of the
meeting um their
new format for that net
ach format was presented as joint pals
mpls and that networking groups meeting
uh that discuss
advancement or new architecture for uh
mpls
uh data plane and uh
that was uh well received and uh what
was uh the good comments is that saying
that oh guys uh great that you are not
asking for another first nibble but
rather use
uh flexibility of uh versioning of
ach
for your purposes and there were no
concerns that we need in other 32-bit
steps and some comments said that oh
now you have more space and you might
increase their um
sequencing
space so match it to
uh detonate control word um that's
something that uh definitely worth uh
considering
uh but will require some uh more work uh
in general again i would
to um
working group uh to discuss whether it
agrees to changing their uh current
format that is documented in the working
group document
adopting uh effectively importing their
text and new format from the individual
draft
and
so i would like the guidance from
working group chairs on how we can
proceed
with this discussion and
arriving at conclusion
okay thank you
it would be good to hear from the group
if there's any
comments or and particularly objections
to
basically moving the technical content
from bellagio's draft into the working
group track
actually i have a
similar question here and also now
from npr's open design team so i don't
know what what's the procedure of this
sorry at least for me you're breaking up
um uh if someone else heard yeah did you
hear the question
not for me for sure
yes it was breaking for me too
if you type it in if you cannot fix the
audio file
yeah fun if you could just type it in
the question into the uh
um
jabber or i don't know if you want to
try again
okay and am i audible again again
or i will
tap it in the in the chat box
i could hear that
fan you actually sounded good there i
don't know if you want to try one last
time
i'm sorry maybe maybe it's the voice is
not good the quality of the voice is not
good
i my i audiobook again
okay
follow up later
uh fan if you want to try one more time
we could try it
if not yeah please please try
okay um do you remember again
yes
okay so a long latency i think
um my question is was the preceding
procedure um between this new
dent ach format imported
and the mprsd open design team
because i think they are they are
relevant
so
do we need to
first follow the mps open design team
result
and then imported
this then that ach format or we import
it first and then
align with the the discussion
of mpl's open design team
yeah i'm i think there are um there are
three things first is the discussion
from npr's working group and the second
is this the discussion of this new that
net sh format
and the third one is the
is to move this um
new format from individual
uh draft to the uh to the mps working
group shaft
yeah i i think the clarification of to
these questions will be helpful thank
you
um
so stewards probably can answer because
in regard to their open design team
or
stuart were you going to try to respond
yeah i was what i was i was going to
talk to this subject um
so in terms of the the the ownership in
inverted commerce of the structure of
nibble one aches
that probably belongs in pals which is
where we created it in the first place
no one has no one has
found any use for those reserve bits in
the last 20 years so
um we can think about
making them essentially a parameter of
the um channel type which i think is
what was uh what was shown assuming i'm
we're all talking about the same thing
but i think it would be as well to sort
of socialize this in the sort of
pals mpls space um
uh just to make sure that no one in
particular the pal side of it to make
sure that no one can think of any uh
serious
long-term issues for doing that but the
principle of making those reserve bits a
um
a parameter of the channel type is
probably okay which i think is what you
were proposing
so i think
going
to the couple of questions that were
asked about um i think procedure-wise
i'd like to address those and then uh
greg if you want to get back to
technical that would be good afterwards
um
so we have we do have the joint uh
group we are coordinating with them this
was presented there
uh
so that that's happening
uh and that needs to continue to happen
in terms of the documents and what we do
in this working group
i think it is worthwhile
for us to document what we believe is
the working group position and then make
sure we synchronize it right now all we
have is an individual proposal that that
doesn't carry the same weight as this is
the direction that working group would
like to go
so if this is in fact
you know blind document does in fact
represent the direction the working
group like would like to go i think we
should bring it into the working group
document
and continue to socialize it and as the
work progresses uh if it if it gets uh
it could end up getting moved into a
pals document it could get moved into a
joint document and then we work with the
chairs to figure out where it is
but
you know we'd like to keep the process
going at the same time
we're um
you know coordinating so
being able to represent whether or not
this is a working group position or an
individual position i think is an
important step
although i think it would be useful to
get some earlier feedback than that so
that no one is surprised and there is no
and and any corrections can be adopted
earlier i can't see anything wrong with
this but i just think it would be really
useful to have that discussion sooner
rather than later and i don't think it
would be 100 but it was presented in the
joint meeting is that not sufficient
i must have been asleep i was taking
copious notes during that meeting and i
don't remember it but still i must have
been asleep and once i'm losing
i mean it's
one of us has lost whatever is lost i
thought this was presented in the joint
meeting maybe i'm wrong
yeah i was
i was i presented this uh
part of
their
talking so i joined janus and uh
as a buffer of nuclear build craft and i
presented uh their uh
definite hph uh four minutes
and some uh
one of uh good comments
somehow rather it went below the radar
but um
um anyway i think they're probably more
or less in sync anyway
yeah but
your general point is correct and i and
i completely support it which is
independent uh well in parallel with
what we do in this working group and
what we decide in this working group we
must uh socialize coordinate with the
joint
uh activity that joint design team the
and uh and we may we should be aware
that anything we do here it could be
affected by that for example what we
agree may be modified based on the the
joint agreement between the working
groups and in fact we may take the
format out eventually and run it through
the pals working group if that's the end
decision
um but you know having agreement of this
working group
i think is an important step you've seen
mpls making you know doing the same
thing of of putting together positions
that are right for the mpls working
group and then we'll we'll coordinate
between the working groups cross working
groups uh
uh to get make sure we have a uh
an answer that works for all
at least that's how i'm seeing the
process i should mention janos is being
quite because he's a co-author
on the work
so my only concern is that someone in
pals will remember something or other
that that breaks as a result of this i
can't think of anything
yeah that's
needs to weigh in on this i agree with
you a hundred percent thousands of
million
and maybe the right thing is is if we
that net
uh end up last calling the document we
do a joint last call
okay greg you had a comment and we
should uh try to wrap up because yes
it's usually important we are running
over
brief technical comment um so um
we believe i believe that um
uh this is important and um so i would
appreciate the working group uh
discussion on the mailing list and uh
derived conclusion
uh in regard to um updating their
working group document and uh inc
with their new um
that net ach format uh their uh
interaction to the work of open design
team uh one of their documents that uh
working as now its individual document
of group of uh contributors on finally
creating um their registry for the first
nibble after mpls stack
and uh value uh zero for the first uh
value one for the first nibble is
reserved for uh pseudo-wire
ach and now it's
to the wire that net ach
and uh
based on uh direction from mpls working
group or direction of open design team
is uh that any new mechanism should not
uh
impede on existing functionality and uh
it can be used as it can be used is it
used uh currently so uh to minimize
interaction so probably that means that
it will use a different
uh first nibble
value for its header post stack
so with that i can close this
presentation and
let's move the discussion to the mailing
list
greg as author in fact we'll just call
you editor you can change yourself to
editor of the document but as uh editor
of the working group document um would
you conduct a poll on the list to see if
there's objections to bringing in the
technical content of bellagio's document
into the working group document
that's very good idea thank you lou and
i'll shoot an email to the working group
with that question
great thank you
okay so this slide drag is about how to
provide pre-off for the net ip data
plane
and i'm presenting it uh uh
from the code or sienna fergus and
andrew mills
next slide please
uh so uh this document is focusing on
how to add the po functionality to the
that net ipp ip data plane uh it is
listing the requirements
for adding pre-off
and it is also providing
details how we can do that
there are solution basics described
encapsulation are also described in the
document there is a detailed pocket
processing
it is also dealing with the flow
aggregation topic
uh and the defines in detail of the the
pre-op procedures
uh next slide please
we are currently at version uh
or one
and there were
these updates in the document it is
quite stable so there were some
editorial updates typos some grammar
were corrected
and we have received comments on the
list in order to clarify
that this solution is based on uh on
tunneling techniques so this is what was
explicitly added to the document
the solution creates a set of underlay
uh udpip tunnels between an overlay set
of that net relay nodes
uh the text of the document is quite
stable uh so next slide please
uh so just to summarize uh this draft is
really
leveraging the existing data data plane
building blocks there are no new header
fields specified this is a general
solution verbs both for ipv4 and ipv6
and and pre-op defined
for the dotnet service sub-layer
the solution uh is
applicable irrespective what routing
techniques is used
underneath the detonate service sub
layer
so any ip rooting techniques can be
applied
and last but not least it does not
require any additional processing on
transit nodes
the document is quite stable so we are
asking for very loop adoption on on this
draft
thank you
torrelis please go ahead
so um i think we're stuck in the
discussion about the point i raised we
went back and forth and i think it would
be good to have an audio discussion
about that not necessarily here um in in
the meeting but let's find some time
afterwards because i don't uh think that
i saw a you know satisfactory answer to
the
problem i raised with respect to the
need to consider how
the
elimination function and
jitter or buffering that it
necessarily creates can be integrated
into any of the possible
bounded latency uh calculi that we may
use in a way that it doesn't mess up the
calculations for um you know whatever
shaping queuing or other processing is
done for the bounded latency
you were giving some explanations but i
i couldn't make heads or tail a lot of
them
tell us my my understanding is that your
comment was regarding the pocket
ordering functionality draft and not
regarding this draft
no no was the the packet elimination
function
the elimination function which basically
um you know creates the jitter when the
primary uh flow uh you know let's say
you have the a and b flow um
a has the shorter latency b has the
longer latency um and obviously um you
know if all the flows from a come then
the elimination function doesn't really
do anything right it just drops all the
one from b but as soon as something in a
uh is missing you need to forward the
the same packet from b and obviously
there is a lot of um you know jitter
between a and b and kind of the
differential path latency and taking
that into account in a way that um we
can simply drop the elimination function
into the forwarding chain uh and don't
mess up the calculus for the bounded
latency of the queuing in before or
after the the pre-op i think that that
needs to be worked well through and it
might actually you know uh require to
have uh some you know buffering function
in there to avoid pushing off the
increased jitter into the poor calculus
of
the bounded latency shaping yeah
um this is a clarification question what
does that have to do with this document
as opposed to am i confused here um
because i
thought
isn't it isn't your comment just a
general statement on pre-off
as opposed to pre-op and ip i mean this
document scope is oh oh sorry then then
then i may have made uh that uh comment
on the on the wrong document here i i
don't think we actually have an active
document
that's your comment um they based on oh
yeah no this is no i was talking about
a
personal document
yeah so
so is this but this is bringing in
pre-op mechanisms that exist in mpls
into ip
and i think you're talking about the
base mpls ish base pre-off in mpls
and now wait a second so
it applies to you know it's generally
i'm not saying your comment's wrong i'm
saying the comment is generally
applicable to
you know an rfc that we have
and to any data plane
yeah not only the uh
[Music]
comment i think it's a valid comment i
don't think it's a valid comment
on this document because
this document is just taking a mechanism
that we already have defined and
applying it in a different data plane
so i think your comment is a good one
and perhaps warrants its own separate
discussion
given that we have an rfc on it
no i yeah i think it's the right
document i think the uh yeah the
you're right that that
this is not specific of course to the
you know
um just
yeah yeah
to to the it is not specific only to ip
i'm going to
pull my uh joker card that it's a 4 56
a.m in the morning sorry
perfect perfectly fine i think this is a
great discussion i would suggest that if
you run independent of this document
because it's a general point
that's stuart
sorry so i am a bit confused as to why
we need to write this document so we
have
um
mpls
written and that includes prayoff and we
have a document that says how you carry
that
over udpip
so
do we miss something somewhere i mean i
don't understand why inheritance doesn't
mean that this just works and there's
nothing to write but maybe i've missed
something
stuart i i think here the main intention
was to to make it clear and obvious how
it can be done
so so i mean i would have thought that
all wasn't the all that we needed to do
then
it
sounds like maybe it's not obvious from
the original documents is to write a
one-line update to the udp document that
says by the way you can do pre-os
because
surely everything just follows and we
don't normally sort of micro document
things that are already inherited
in the in our existing stacks
i think we've um
gotten
uh
a little bit better about helping people
understand how to use the technology as
building blocks so an informational
document that says how to combine things
you know has we've done those in other
groups so i don't think it's off
completely out of scope
maybe one more thing to add is that the
dotnet ip data plane document claim no
pre-op for ip
explicitly
pre-offer ip
but
there is pre-offer mpls
and that's what it was carrying now so
maybe you need to write a document but
it doesn't i don't think it really needs
to be more than one line to say by the
way you might not realize you can do
this go and read these other documents
uh
even though the queue is closed we'll go
to pascal and david we're way over time
we're gonna just so as a heads up to
other presenters we're going to end up
squeezing your time a little bit
reducing your time pascal you're up
yeah
so i'll try to be quick so we're talking
about encapsulation and as we talk about
encapsulation we and for ip right we
basically uh lose the the visibility of
the inner flow unless we have to dig
deep in the packet
so we end up in the discussion similar
to the one we just had at raw which is
basically how
what basic what identifies
a copy of the packet
um you know the sequence number and and
the flow id or something uh is is
typically what we comes to mind
in that row we kind of make a difference
between the flow identification as being
the upper layer
udp thing versus what goes in ip
and if you if you take that path it
means that you need to have ipad ip
information in the ipad there is an
accentuators and here we are saying hey
we are tunneling and still we don't
change anything we don't add anything to
the to the others and so
question comes to mind how do you find
the flow how do you find the sequence
counter i mean all this is needed
so first of all sequence counters are
needed only on the relay nodes and on
the that not really you know
into the list um just because we're way
over yeah
yeah okay so basically by my bottom line
let's take it to the list i agree my
bottom line is there are different
documents which talk about the data plan
for ip we need to reconcile this as
opposed to just adopt one we need to
understand why this what those different
documents are saying and how that that
needs to be combined or what
right so pascal you're saying it's an
implementation guidance document this is
useful and so you're countering
stewart's point correct
not not uh i'm saying it's probably not
sufficient uh we if we if we really want
to do something in the ap later plane we
probably need more than just a tunnel i
think just a tunnel may lose that
information we care about or it's never
been there like secrets
yeah i think so you're actually making a
different point and i think that's valid
is we should leave room for true ip
solutions in the future all right david
please go ahead
last time
if one is prepared to run the
mpls or udpr or ip uh data plane end to
end and i think stewart's comment is
correct that uh there really isn't much
to say however if one wants to imply
encapsulation over only part of the path
so that we're going to pre-off over part
of the path without running that whole
data plane end-to-end then there's some
interesting stuff to done i think
pascal's been busy uh been been
helpfully exploring some of it
in his comments
okay thank you
uh look forward to a good discussion on
the list on this um clearly there's
interest and uh disagreement so uh
should foster some good discussion uh
the
uh
bellage you're up next uh you originally
scheduled for 10 minutes gonna cut you
down to five please i i will do my best
yeah
okay so this is about pocket ordering
function and uh i have quote or stefan
kerres tobias tobias here and janos
farkas next slide please
so this draft is version 2
and it is dealing with the situation
that replication and elimination
functions may result in out of order
packets
and this is what the packet ordering
function uh
algorithms can correct and restore
the original packet order
next slide please
so
the document is
is quite stable uh we have uh added some
made some editorial updates uh since the
last version
uh
there were discussion uh on the list uh
and it is also related that orless uh
commented in the previous
slot
so we have made it
clear
that
packet ordering function
may cause delay variation however how to
eliminate this delay variation this is
out of scope in this document
and
dealing with the delay variation is a
net forwarding sub layer target and it
can be achieved for example by placing a
digital buffer or a flow regulator like
a shaping function after the probe
functionality
so this is definitely word for
discussion but this is something that is
out of scope in this document because
this document is focusing on what
algorithms you can use in order to
achieve
the pocket ordering functions
and we have also updated the security
consideration part of the document
referring to the security document and
highlighting that these algorithms does
not imply new security concerns
regarding the post
next slide
please
so we have the discussion on the list we
have made some proposed changes updates
uh we feel that regarding the prof
algorithms how it is working this is
something pretty stable
we have received good comments for the
previous version and and updated the
draft according to that
so here again the next step is planned
to ask for very loop adoption
thank you uh dollas
we we can't take
the problem of um
being able to define um
the latency calculus for um the pre-op
function out of scope of when we're
defining the prior function right just
hand waving and saving this forwarding
plane function so i think we should
discuss that so because this was always
the problem with with with the bounded
latency that we need to have a linear
model you know that every component
we're adding to the path you know can be
calculated by itself and you know not
pushing off some unknown uh latency
variation um to to to some undefined
step
yeah i i think this is why we have
separated the sub layers we have defined
the service sub layer dealing with
protection and we have defined the
forwarding sub layer
dealing with the latency and
jitter-related
issues regarding that net flows
no but i mean the the point is about
pushing pushing from
this document this function this
component some undefined uh you know
later engines data off to something else
is architecturally not the correct thing
this is this is basically a you know a
latency that needs to be possible to
calculate for this function and then
there is really the question does it
make sense then to push off um
the
the problem of how to fix these things
so that it becomes linear again to some
other component
yeah but we're running out
i sent you an email let's let's find
some time to discuss this more please
okay um i i think it would be very good
to get a informational document that
talks about how implementation should
manage that issue tourists i don't know
if you want to contribute that or work
with balaj to to do that and whether
it's this document or a separate
document um you know that would be i
think really help the working group
it's a good issue you're bringing up uh
that implementations need to consider i
don't think we're talking about changing
any of the data plane uh behaviors it's
really just the the calculus that the
essentially the controllers have to do
so it's it's a good implementation
uh uh guidance document so that would be
really nice
worst case my contention is that we
should consider that
the elimination ordering function need
to have a shaper um per flow in it like
you know the uh
the
like the shapers we have associated with
the queues and ats for example right the
the cues are what we do on the interface
and then we have the shaper for them and
likewise the same shaper could be
required you know for the elimination
ordering function and that would be part
of the elimination and ordering
architectural component so that's the
worst case
look forward to reading the document
thanks
thank you
uh please proceed you have ten minutes
uh yeah okay um hello this is pony from
channel mobile and it's my pleasure to
talk about the requirements of large
scale deterministic network next slides
please
okay here is the motivations uh in the
last entry meeting which may talk about
if more queuing mechanisms should be
considered the requirements were
presented and would like to work in the
requirement draft first so we submit the
new draft and hopefully it can be used
as the standpoint
compared with the plantation at the
entry meeting the new draft has more uh
analysis about the
large-scale domestic network influence
the
queuing mechanism and based on which we
put up some new requirements
and next slides please
so let's have a recap on the
different levels of application
requirements and obviously of use case
gave the requirements of industrial uh
electricity buildings and so on some of
them
clearly specified the requirement for
lateness let's say a jitter and well
some not for the so far when providing
uh deterministic network service network
network providers always face the
problem of how to
match application demands to the
technology
um um so um the
service can be um clarified one is uh
uh one kind has critical as is
such as remote control or cloud plc or
manufacturing and differential
protection of electricity and there are
also some relatively lower levels of srv
for consumer networks such as cloud
gaming cloud vr
the user of these applications hope to
have a better network experience but
they can tolerate it to a certain extent
if the network quality is not so good
sometimes
moreover uh such users are willing to
spend more money for high quality
network service and they need some
aspects because they have no industry
barriers and can tolerate exceeding the
upper
boundary of latency within small
probability
they have relatively
lower requirements for the network and
may be easier to deploy an excise please
and here are some
deployment and application status of
literary
deterministic network
so we won't
give some much explanation about it um
just want to show that um
[Music]
this draws on both operators and
enterprise users begin to put forward
deterministic requirements for the
large-scale networks
but the
used technologies are not exactly the
same so you can see more work is needed
for network service providers to
successfully sell that net type service
to customers
okay next science please
this is a requirement to a list
according to the
uh
differential um
application requirements um
including the tolerance time uh
synchrony and supports the large signal
hope propagation latency accommodates
the higher
link speed this giveaway tolerates
failures of links and all nodes and
wg chain changes
and the support incremental device
updates
next slides please
quantum one is to tolerate time a
synchrony including four situations
first is to support
asynchronous clocks across domains and
one of dennis objects is to stitch tests
and islands together which may have
different clocks and
are not synchronized so the mechanism
should be able to support the
interaction across time domains the
second is storage data and wonder within
clock synchronized
domain
within a
single time synchronization the main
different
clock accuracy is expected
the large-scale network should be able
to recover or observe
such time variance within a domain and
across multi-domains
third is to provide mechanism not
requiring phone full-time
synchronization
it is really hard to achieve the full
time synchronization in
large scale networks when considering
the diameter of network topology and it
is designed that the same performance
in terms of the boundaries and the data
can be achieved
when full-time synchronization is not
used
such as the frequency
synchronization used in the two
trials and the last one is to support a
synchronization-based
master
method due to the large amount of
traffic in large uh secured network and
some of them are a cyclic and and not
all the networks or device support
synchronizations
such as ats um
use perform based synchron uh
nervous shipper to
achieve boundary latency and the formula
proof shows it
effectiveness
next size please
um quantum 2 is to
support the large single hoop
propagation latency the distance of
transmission transmission transmission
is long enough to generate a larger
latency that line for
cyclic based method the
length of
cycle must be either set long enough
into buffer case or other mechanism
should be provided
and come through is to
accommodate the higher link speed
the large-scale network normally use
higher link speed especially for its
backbone and with increasing of the date
rate the scheduling
cycle can be reduced which requires a
more precise time control and if the
network cycle times remains the same
more data constant
which requires more buffer space which
impose more
complex buffer or
qmag management and larger memory
consumption next size please
the requirement for is to be scalable
[Music]
it's inc
include two aspects
the increase or decrease of the network
device influence topology and discovery
mechanisms
for example the ultra low latency of
application spot network would require
the net extent to
every 5g base station which might be
hundreds of thousands for one operator
and for the massive traffic flows it is
almost impossible to identify individual
rb flow at the net plan because the
larger overhead and resource reservation
for massive number of flows so
flow correlation is required individual
flow may join and exist
the aggregated flow rate rapidly
which will cause dynamic in
identification of aggregate than netflow
and requirement five is to tolerate
failures of links or nodes and tableau
changes
network link failures are more common in
large sql networks
but switching or re-convergence of
routing will cause high length of packet
loss and retransmission which is usually
in seconds before the network is stable
again
and it is necessary to support a certain
mechanism to adapt to figures
of
links or nodes and topology changes
next slides please
requirement 6 is to support incremental
device updates since some applications
that require relatively low level of sle
it will bring acceptable for those
applications to tolerate a
deterministic low
probability to exceed the upper
boundary of latency for those
applications some simple solutions that
may
be realized by update and configure the
ingress and egress device or part of
network service
network device are expected meanwhile
they're critical as if some applications
can be achieved by adding the existing
or other new
mechanisms and updating more service
okay next guys please
and here are some proposed q magazine
besides test and insert
service they are not included in the
boundary latency draft
which is
will be published
soon
we list them and also give some analysis
about the levels of deterministic
uh synchronization or notes the cost
stability and the flow aggregation
the first one is based on as a frequency
synchronization and multiple thick like
cyclic buffers that can be proved to
provide the boundary listening and the
jitter it is used the flow aggregation
and the scalability is also good
um and the second um
uh is micro robust decreasing uh since
it's
interrupted but given the time i think
it's important too um the okay
requirements are really good
but you don't have to discuss the
alternatives out there or do a gap
analysis to do the requirements and
this is going to cause a lot of
discussion and argument
and it really is separate from your
point about uh requirements so i think
adding this having this in the
presentation and the document is uh
actually diminishes from the document
so it may be best to remove it and have
it in a separate document so we can
focus on the requirements if that's okay
and an interesting time to go to your
next slide
okay
thank you
um okay um
next steps uh
wait wait wait more
analysis and discussion about the
requirements i will come and people who
are interested in this work please
contact contact me yeah and any comments
the question uh in terms of the
relationship of this document
uh compared to the one you presented at
the interim
[Music]
with which
so what's the relationship between the
two documents because it's a zero zero
document
uh
yeah um i think this uh question may be
discussed later after this presentation
we we can take it to the left and i mean
the question was to you like is it a
replacement
and so on because in the interim the
takeaway was to develop the requirements
further i got that but uh
yano
let me take it to the list
yeah okay
uh is the person in queue
uh
actually i
answer janos question so it's a quick
answer
very quickly yeah because i'm i'm one of
the courses of this of just now the zero
zero version and the one
presented in the interim actually there
was no
mature um draft
so basically the draft presented just
now is the very first version of that
so that's that's a quick answer for that
what's what's being presented in the
interim actually is a basically a
collection of the information it's slide
it's ppt slide space but there is no
mature draft based on that
that was i mean
yeah
let's take more discussion on this topic
to the list and um
then the requirements related to the
queen mechanisms
and do you consider other
skill networks such as
reducing a macro burst and enhancing
their results and their roots
i i did not hear you yeah so so uh my
suggestion would be if you have
questions comments to the previous
presentation then please take it to the
list and let's get started with this
presentation because we are over time
yes you have eight minutes thank you
start
giving your presentation okay
okay okay
and so uh this draft is also about the
requirements for the wide aerial ip
domestic networking
i do hear me
your slides are already shared can you
start talking to them
i i i could hear you fine in previously
but uh
yeah she may be having a problem please
please uh please proceed with the
president
yes please proceed yes please proceed
okay sorry
unless slide please
is it only me who doesn't hear her
i i see indications that he is speaking
i
first
i can hear her
okay i will proceed first uh
we discussed about the possible problems
with the wide arrow ip deterministical
networking
uh we divided it into two parts of the
work
they are deterministically networking
and wide area network for this mystery
network we should consider two issues
first different services requires
different shaded satellite cues for
example
400 microseconds delay is required for
audio and video but no more than 100 100
micro seconds
delay should be guaranteed by
industrial application
second problems with resource location
rules should be taken into account
account
for example resource should be located
for the deadline
but it will lead to low efficiency
efficiency of resource utilization uh
for the roots uh the strict uh latency
and the jitter commitment peru should be
provided and it must not change due to
the lateral changing it's especially in
pref uh function like the
owners
proposed the latency and the jitter of
the two disjoined rules uh we cannot
have two big difference and cannot be
changing
moreover interdomains root should be
taken into consideration
and the second part for the wide aerial
network the two features are largely
older large-scale network and
multiple dynamic flows
there will be
large scale levels overloads and
long-distance
links and they will
impact on the latency and the
jitter and the multiple capabilities
will be
existed such as flexi and sr turners
and maybe multiple queen mechanisms are
provided and co existed
and finally there are also large number
and multiple types over dynamic flows
coexist
uh so micro bursts may be emerged from
multiple
flows
last slide please
so uh based on the problems
for uh with the white aerial ip
did administer networking uh we listed
the requirements
uh based on the problems first is the
differentiated the network uh
differentiated the battle desolate
queues of the multi multiple services
their deflate flows could be classified
based on their
data cues in the figure show for example
over deterministic service can be
provided such as low latency jitter and
the
low latency just low latency and so on
second is the large scale
network it's a it is required to reduce
the size of the lateral topology and
integrate their multi comp scalability
resource to
achieve the optimal beta data use
third is the high efficiency of the
resource and the rules
resource
classification and modeling is required
along the
explicit path with
the route with the
guarantees such as
bandwides lanterns jitter and the packet
loss should be provided the last one is
the guarantees of multiple dynamic
flows
so shaping and their queen processing
and their
aggregation of multiple flows should be
provided to reduce the micro uh burst
last night
so this is the solutions considerations
for the wider area ip deterministic
networking
we
for the solutions uh we suggest to solve
it from
three direction first step is to uh
locate
deterministic resources second step is
to establish the domestic routes and the
validity to achieve their deterministic
accused
so last night please
so uh the the draft is also about the
requirement or for the large-scale uh or
wide aerial um
net deterministic networking uh we
welcome the comments and this discussion
thank you
comments question
i think it's the right direction to
classify the categories of levels of use
case but
the problem is that whether it is the
right time to be
standardized now uh maybe
in the future
more suitable because in
the previous draft
we also mentioned that but we don't give
the details of of it
and for this draft i think um
some details of analysis are expected
and since it's a little um conceptual i
think
and another question is that we have two
requirements draft
and what
i would ask what's the other i think
about that yeah
yeah thank you uh so for the first
question
brings you
a classification uh over the deafness
service and dirty uh the details
should be provided um
so
we will um
do the
research and
provide the details
for the
um
classification of the data service
not just their
their uh
not
the nancy and the jitter
we will provide the
clarification for the
other requirements in the draft
it looks like there's a good opportunity
to discuss this builder on the list i
think you know if we can
look at having the documents be merged
that would be great
if not if we could figure out where
there's agreement and disagreement
thank you very much
so i believe you're originally scheduled
for 15 minutes uh we only have 10
minutes available for you
[Music]
yes please proceed
okay thank you
china um and this is a
false version of the microphones
decreasing
in this layer 3 network for low limited
traffic dropped
next please
next second
this page will
show some modifications
firstly we
adjust the catalog to clarify the
purpose of the draft
our purpose is to
explore explore the methods to decrease
microbursts in the network and
we add a new session to
analyze the requirement of the method to
decrease
the macro first
and as an example we we
show we introduce a
method
to
decrease the microburst
next page please
okay this is a
simple test
uh from my colleague and
we want to show this page to show that
the
traffic has uh
instinct or positiveness
i i will introduce uh something about it
the traffic passed through a 4g network
and fixed the access network
and
they are between two cpes with gps
a test package will be sent every
60 millisecond
and
the test lasts about 10 hours the
minimal delay between the two
is about seven milliseconds and the
maximum delay is about
700 millisecond and the average delays
is about
26 milliseconds
it can be observed that the ip traffic
has uh instinct or
both he needs because
we can see that some of the packet
experience a long delay in the
between the two cpes
next page please
okay
we introduced three ways to disco
decrease the microburst
this document uh many folks on the micro
bus on the interface
which is different from the the micro
aspects in the previous
page but they show similar
characteristics
the three ways
including
includes uh the traditional ip in a
light
loaded network
this second scenario is very similar to
the
situation of the last page and the
second is the tsm mechanism such as cqf
it means cyclic cueing and folding and
the last method is introduced in
in this chart as an example to decrease
the microburst on the interface
next page please
and this page will introduce the
traditional ip in a light loaded network
a network will be not
will not be
congested for critical traffic
only if that
the criterial traffic has a
higher priority and there is only a
small amount of critical traffic in the
network
uh however in in that night we want to
convey more critical traffic in the
network
so this traditional ip method perhaps
not super for the for our mechanism
being
considered in that net
but uh
the ipod has a good
scalability because most in most cases
only
perpetuate the treatment in the
forwarding node is needed
but in theory
every folding can only provide an
unreliable connection
as shown in the last page we can see
that
some sometimes a long delay is
caused by the person in the network
the next next page please
the second method to decrease uh the
microphones in the network is the tsm
mechanism such as the cqf
uh of course the ctsm mechanism all can
provide a reliable path through the
network
uh in that net network uh the be traffic
will be forwarded by using the
traditional ip forwarding method
and the deadnet traffic will be
forwarded by using the tsa mechanism
however the test mechanisms are much
more complicated than the ip folding so
they cannot have a good scalability as
the traditional ip40 does
but
we think that the scalability is
essential for
a large scale network
next spirit please
so we explore a third method
we are looking for a mechanism that
firstly it it can have a good
scalability
uh it is to say that the intermediate
node should not uh perform a process on
the data plan and it also can provide a
better performance for the critical
traffic
it is to see that
we can provide a different treatment for
the critical traffic and
then we go
get a better
user experience
on the inter intermediate node we
suggest to separate the process or
control plan the data plan
because we think that in a large-scale
network the status on the aggregated
detonate traffic
on the control plane may change
frequently
uh
because uh the the the track the net
flow may contain a lot of subfloors
and they
are aggregated
uh we should not assume that a control
plant on the intermediate node can
interact with the data frequently for
example
to change a shipper parameter frequently
we think that
on the date plan some self-decision
process should be supported
next paid please
so uh we propose a method as an example
in this method
we can do the shipping on at the end
edge and try to keep the traffic shaped
on the intermediate node
we
do the uh
we on the intermediate node
an intermediate node the graduated
critical traffic will be shipped again
as a whole on the interface
uh we suggest some self-decision process
in the shipping
and the purpose is to maintain a
reliable or reasonable buffer death
while shipping the traffic
the first step in our stock is that
not to forward the packet as soon as
possible
as the traditional ip forwarding does
because we think it is one of the reason
causing the microburst on the interface
next page please
it's about the next time or the drop
we will
[Music]
call for comments and continue to modify
the draft and we also call for
contributions from anyone who are
interested in the work
uh i think this is the last one last
page and welcome for comments thank you
any comments
uh thank you for contributing the work
and we look for a discussion on the list
and uh anyone who's interested uh please
uh
you know contact the authors or make
comments on the list uh
thank you
next up
i guess tourists
all right
so this is about the um
uh
oh the title is wrong this is about the
mpls um
tech uh traffic class queueing uh for
cqf next slide
so the the concept of tech cyclic
queueing and forwarding was proposed to
that a long time ago that was in um
i really only get one minute
sorry my counter is at 30 seconds maybe
that hopefully that's wrong i'll there
are too many buttons i just haven't
updated it yet
sure um
right so um
so we introduced that uh in 2018 first
uh
as a concept and you know
got uh you know lost uh running around
in
itf working groups to figure out where
we could standardize this um then we
reintroduced the concept in 2021 with a
new variation of that draft so i think
you know that's that's why we said let's
let's let's
make make something that actually can be
standardized by uh um you know writing
down uh how this would actually work
with the encapsulation that we have
and otherwise complete data plan for
which is mpls
um
and so uh the beauty is also that um it
only requires uh some three to five
values out of uh you know um a qs field
and so in mpls we're using the traffic
class field so we introduce and explain
that work in the interim um so the 01
version added a co-author
and that one
thanks andy had kind of alerted me to
the problems with the yang so i had
longer discussion also with young expert
and i ended up removing the yang
references and text from it and replaced
it with uh something that you know would
allow us to forward to to carry forward
with the specification independent of an
additional yang model to to manage it um
so that we don't get that conflation of
of context in one document uh next slide
okay just a quick summary so
cyclic cueing and forwarding um
is a an old technology from tsn that's
uh available um and used in
campus industrial networks um with
speeds uh
smaller than or maybe even up to 10
gigabits it uses two cycles for the
forwarding uh the main issues is that
when you go to higher speeds
the um
clock synchronization accuracy
requirement goes up linear with speed
which also means that the cost of the
clock synchronization goes up with speed
and it cannot support um you know links
of varying or larger latency because it
is synchronizing packets upon receipt
based on the receive timestamp of the
packet um and not something in the
packet so um you know the latency of the
links has to be very small so something
like a few kilometers so the the
solution and that was even you know
discussed in tsn but obviously adding a
packet header field is always pain so
that's why also a tsn didn't want to do
it
but that is really what is necessary to
reduce the requirement
in clock synchronization
and its cost
and then allow arbitrary long wide area
network links and also links with jitter
that obviously even in you know
high-speed gigabit ethernet and other
links like mobile links come through
forward error correction and uh
re-transmissions at at lincoln lower
layer
um so that
technology is working in hardware so uh
we
we did prove that with um you know proof
of concept hardware implementation just
on fpga
for that cyclic queuing and 100 gigabit
um standard metropolitan and uh wide
area network routers
so at 2 000 kilometer range and less
than 100 microsecond end-to-end jitter
because that was just the cycle time and
i'm not going to go in the details of
how multi more cycles like shown on the
right give you more uh variability in
you know jitter or clock inaccuracy but
that's pretty much the reason to go for
more than three cycles next slide
so why is this important and that goes
back to the two big challenges the
operator we want to have a service
provider class network solution for that
net to be successful even enterprises
want to adapt standard network
operational models from service
providers for anything that is larger
than you know
a building network so
we do not want to have perhaps per flow
shaper state for the bounded latency and
cqf is the only relevant proven
standardized option today and in this
tcqf this tech cqf simply expands it
to you know the tagging in the packet as
opposed to derived from the timestamp
and then of course the challenge number
two and we heard that from the prior two
talks as well
most industrial tsn applications want
and need low jitter for example higher
jitter may incr introduce
the need to run ptp in the network
purely for client devices add ptp stacks
to the client devices to resync control
loops because of the introduced jitter
and
the current uh uh
latency alternatives to cqf have really
the maximum jitter right so zero queuing
latency when there is no competing
traffic and maximum latency under
maximum um
competing traffic so
tech secure is my opinion really the
only short-term option that solves both
challenges um there are some other
options but they would all require new
packet headers because they can't get
away with just a few uh values to
indicate the necessary you know queueing
state that we need to make it work
um
and and you know all of these you know
additional options don't have any um i
think um deployment validation or
standardization uh uh
track record next slide
so yeah so this is this is basically all
the stuff that we could do beyond um
this draft and where it gets interesting
but also difficult um
so
and that gets pretty much to extension
headers um for uh what we want to do um
so we could do one for bounded latency
now um for for for additional proposals
but i think we should be careful not to
do a one-off right so um
and maybe you know in the matter of time
not go through all of this but so there
were other in in the interim there were
other um you know options for uh low
jitter brought up i also um you know
published one particular mechanism last
month so feel free to read up on that
all of these options may have slightly
different parameters mine for example
has one time stem and then a sequence of
priorities to achieve the same calculus
that tsn ats has so that it can be
pushed back but you know there are one
of other things um you know um jack of
stein proposed a stochastical bounded
latency solution so i think all of this
is much further out before we could
successfully deploy it i hope we can and
will work on it
but so i think that that puts it in a
separate bucket from the tcqf which i
think is ready to deploy now if we had a
standard to actually allow
interoperability so
which brings us to the final slide next
slide please
so here are pretty much my two asks
right so you know working group adoption
for uh this
tech cqf
draft
and um you know if if that cannot be
adopted because there may need to be
charter changes uh let's let's try to
figure out how to work through that
process quickly i don't think uh it
really would need to you know be
considered to be any different from the
pre-op work that we're doing which also
deals with algorithms in the routers and
has since we started that net
and then the second ask is to think
about how we can get towards something
like a net us design team with more
regular and informal meetings uh yeah
but thanks for the working group chair
slides that you'll make the with the
webex available so that's great too
pre-off latency um not sure if there's
anything else on the qs side um and then
maybe you know start discussing there
the uh
the current drafts uh that we already
have i want to bring into the working
group for for the round one deliverables
and then the round two um for these you
know new packet header encapsulations
what functionality you want to have
there
all right that's it thank you
thank you dollas so maybe one one
thought on um
the working group adoption that uh
uh perhaps uh so so we are developing
the requirements
and i think that goes before solution
so i guess it would be good to have a
working group document and developed by
a working group agreed on requirements
before diving into solution
well i mean we've been you know on this
for four years this is working we know
the industry needs it
this is this is not necessarily covering
all the operational requirements that we
have
um so i think uh you know any of these
larger scale requirements documents
would be a broader scope then i think
what we do agree to be you know uh the
requirements for a bounded latency
solution
right and and and and remember that you
know
we don't even have anything for the
other bounded latency solutions from the
management plane either so i i think
there is no need to delay um this this
this this can be pretty much done in
parallel and you know if in my working
group the the ads even wanted us to
first work on the solution in parallel
if at all you know uh
work through uh you know the other
aspect so i think that's that's always
in the eye of the beholder how to
sequentialize things
so i i do think we uh have a charter
issue to work um the shares can start
working that with the ad
and
probably
come up with some proposed text maybe
you would get the id at least to agree
with in principle and then bring it to
the working group for review and comment
and run that process
and
in that time it would be great to see
more discussion and input
um into
uh
in this document and we can run those in
parallel
um
as i said right i think that that and i
think that was a little bit the
conclusion uh what you took down at the
end of the interim i i think it mostly
applies to what i had on my slide as the
the second part which was you know uh
looking into all these you know novel
things as opposed to the very short-term
things that we've also been doing with
pre-off and where this air draft would
fall into but yeah fine thanks yeah i
mean we've had the discussion before the
queueing has typically not been done in
the routing area since this is um uh
you know
different for the routing area we want
to make sure that the isg and the ad is
fully on board with it i think just
doing going off and doing it without
their buy-in is just going to cause
problems down the road when we try to
advance it through the isg so
again again
parallel
we can run it in parallel and um
uh certainly uh try to have um a text
that is either uh complete or fairly
mature by the next meeting
well as i said in in one of the
joint meetings i think we we did have
the discussion i think that there were
more people you know pointing to the
fact that the work done on on pre-off
you know is effectively also a qs
function and that had been started
we can have that discussion on the list
uh it's not going to change we're going
to work with the ad on this sure and the
isg so i mean we can keep talking um but
uh we're out of time on this slot
more discussion take it to the list uh
certainly technical discussion we're
hoping does happen on the list
um and with that we're on our last slot
one
this is about the bgp flow specification
for the flat flow mapping next slide
please
so this knight listed the rfcs related
to tsm deadplanes
including display framework ipo for tsm
mps over tsm and tsm vpn over mps
so in the figure show the
satellite may provided the deterministic
service for the tsm and the system and
the deathlet ip and the mps flows may be
carried over tsn sub networks
let's slide please
so
we mainly discussed the
requirements for the flow mapping
there are two parts over
uh requirements for the flow mapping the
first one is the primary primary
requirements of the controller play for
the tsn and desolate flows mapping the
mapping between tsn streams and the data
flows is required for the service proxy
function at data engineers and the
mapping table
can be configured and maintained in the
control plane
second one is the aggregation over
deadlift flows
one two one and the n two one mapping
must be supported
for example aggregating multiple
tsn streams in a single internet flow
must be supported
so based on the
requirements uh were provided in
their listed offices so this document
proposes
extensions in control play to
uh bgp flow specification for their flow
mapping
by using their traffic filtering rules
to identify the packet and they're using
the association associated
action to map the packet to the related
surface
so let's just slide please
so
we
proposed to
extend the bgp
flow specification for the tsn string
mapping to that letter flow
as we were learned the
string identification function are
defined in
archery
and so based on their existing uh
filtering filtering rules
this document proposed proposed earlier
type in l2 components
flows back type for tsm traffic
filtering uh for example the uh
mask in
uh the max
surface data unit unit in mask and the
match screen identification
so uh
moreover for the traffic action of tsn
strings the action is to
uh define to
accept their tests and streams that
matches the rule and the mapped extremes
to the data flows so this document also
proposes proposes the sequence action
extending the community
next slide please
so
and
so forth there
uh that last flow matching map into tsm
string uh this document also proposes a
dcw type in
l3 components flows back uh for that
letter mps flows uh the extended action
for and data traffic filtering is to
accept that flows that matches the death
rule and the mapped flows to the tests
and strings so uh
the document also proposes a test action
uh extended community
uh the test profile can be converted to
the
string related permit parameters and
requirements including ts string id
string handle
sequence number and the traffic scale
scheduling information
let's select list
so a last step
we plan to present and discuss in idr wg
and we want to get more feedback
uh comments and the discussion are very
welcome thank you
any questions comments
two minutes
jeff
thanks luke i'm going to apologize i
actually only caught a portion of the
presentation after i was flagged about
this um
you know
i've read the draft uh very slightly uh
i do see that it is doing much work with
flow spec
a quick word on that um
the
base flow spec
rfc which is the version of the protocol
is
known to not be extensible so there is
work that is starting in idr to do a
flowspec v2 so i think you're going to
find that uh some of your changes will
probably require
the flowspec v2 work in order to become
a
viable protocol component
idr should be holding an interim on
flowspec sometime uh
very likely early december and we'd
invite you to present there
thank you thank you i will
thanks jeff and
uh i will uh change that uh extensions
to flows back or version two last
version
but in this presentation i
i i'd like to get some feedback
for the requirements
of the flow mapping
thank you
now from the uh i think the net side i
think it's important to um qualify the
document that it's really focused on tsn
mapping not uh just generic
net uh so making you know having the
document identify its scope as tsn in
the title the abstract the
the narrative
part that would be important
in terms of the process standpoint i
think we you know i think debt net is
the chairs are happy for it to be run
wherever the ad thinks is is appropriate
whether that be net or idr uh sounds
like it might be best to run it with idr
given where um uh flospec is and what
jeff commented uh i see he's back in
queue so i'd love to hear hear his
opinion on this as well
thanks luke uh so the the first thing i
was going to say is that we do have i'm
having trouble loading my agenda whether
you're on the presentation slot or not
but if you were not
a presenter for idr's session tomorrow
we do actually have some available time
so please consider yourself invited to
present if you not are already there
and jeff after that um if you could let
us know sort of what the opinion is of
the group and uh we can coordinate with
our ad john uh offline
uh to to make sure this ends up in the
right place uh that would be great
okay and last comment for you to give
your time back
um certainly an idea we can help uh look
through the php protocol extensions and
you know much like other plumbing
protocols uh it will be up to you guys
to determine whether this makes sense as
a mechanism for deadnet
thank you gotcha gotcha thank you very
much
um
uh find anything else you want to say
before we end the session
yeah thank you thank you jeff thank you
i will uh contact the jeff and to see if
we if we
would like to present
okay great
thank you all for a good session
uh really appreciate all the
contribution and good work um
uh janosh apologizes for not saying
goodbye he had some audio issues
but
thank you all and
we have a chance of maybe being in
person the next time at least some of us
so hope to see some of you at the next
meeting
bye now
you