we don't have brian haberman but
i think he had a conflict anyway and
he's at the end of this agenda i think
actually right he's at the of the agenda
because he does have a conflict
um
there we go
should we get go onstage
yeah let's do that
okay so yeah here we go um
welcome everyone
itf112
um
here is the note well
you've seen this many times i'm sure um
it's easy to just gloss over this but
it's it's lots of good information here
that i hope people have read
especially the code of conduct
ecp 54 is maybe important
it's talking about how people
should behave in working groups and be
civil and focus on technical discussions
and so on and
thinking we are doing a great job but
you know atf in general there are
sometimes problems with
you know having good civil discussions
and there's other good information here
as well
all right
them for our agenda
uh it's a bit smaller agenda this time
um
so um
yeah
i'm gonna present a draft and
and there's
three other people presenting as well um
any comments on this agenda
so one thing to note here is there's no
um
we have had some presentations recently
on
on multicast and
source routing
uh there's no that on well there's one
draft on this agenda
but there's a side meeting on friday um
to discuss
those topics it's not like an official
ietf session but it's an
open meeting to everyone
so if you go to the main itf page there
is a link to the site meetings where you
can find the
agenda and so on
all right so i want to go on with the
working group status
hey hey hey uh steak it might be just
good if you sent that to that link to
the pim list as well
right
yeah sure uh we can do that yeah
okay thank you
uh yeah
okay for the working group status um
there is uh the
the pym yang model
which has been in the re rfc editor's
queue for a few years it seems like but
that should be published in a few days
now from what i understand it's uh
it's it's like going through the final
review right before publication
this is the igp mld sweeping young model
[Music]
that's in the rfc editors queue as well
let's see did alvaro join the queue
just for a second he backed out
uh alvaro
he sent a link to the chat i think
that's what he wanted to do hey uh no no
i yeah i got on the queue i got off
because i i saw ac you thought i wanted
i thought he wanted to say something
and i think maybe we're going to see the
same thing
uh or hopefully we're going to see the
um yeah the ping yang model is in the
our mosquitoes it has been there for a
while
there was a very late uh bug found
not in the pim module
but in the bfd module
that pim imports and
etc so that affects only pim it affects
ospf and isis which are also in the
editors queue
uh the problem the bigger problem is
that vfd was already published as an rrc
so
we have been
talking to all the authors to see how
well what is the best way to fix this
um right now um
uh rob wilton who's the
op cd is talking to the yang doctors
to figure out what's the best way where
we think the cleanest way is is to
republish
rfc 91
27 i think is what the bfd
module is
and
the
intent would be to you know fast track
that as much as possible because
apparently there are no implementations
and then uh and have the other documents
including the pin module uh your
published um
essays or as they are right with with
with
no changes so that only the only changes
are in the bfd module so in any case uh
that's a long story to say that it may
not be in the next few days uh it may be
hopefully the next few weeks
uh hopefully not it won't go in two
months or anything anything like that
but but uh i think i sent you guys an
email at some point um
maybe the last couple of days i know
it's been busy but yeah just take a look
at that
okay great yeah thank you
yeah so it's not our fault it's all
external references um
all right um
so
uh
we recently requested publication of the
bfd point to multi-point use case
that's being evaluated um well actually
it's it's i guess right before last itf
we requested that um
then um more recently we request
requested publication for rgmp mlb
extensions
uh so there was an ad yeah alvaro
reviewed that and uh
yeah i'm one of the offers and i
submitted a new draft just now
so
we'll see how that goes
um
then we have two working group drafts
now on the
dr improvement or backup vr or sticky vr
behavior
so for this we we really need to make
some progress and
uh we've been thinking about yeah having
you know how to have some good working
with discussion on this um
so
i think for next slide jeff we should
try to
try to make some progress here
find some way to compare the approaches
and have some discussion about how to
proceed in the working group
yeah because we're at the authors are
really driving these efforts if they're
not
driving it then it's going to kind of
fall by the wayside and we agreed at the
beginning that
we don't have to progress both drafts
because they're similar you know we
talked about whether to merge or to
leave them separate and so far as a
working group we decided to adopt them
separately but if there's not a
if there's not progress
on these drafts then um one of them or
both of them are gonna just kind of die
off
and that's a good point alvaro
yeah so ultimately we we want to find
out you know what
what are the right technical solutions
do we need one solution do we need two
solutions
but what what do we think is the best
and then based on that we will decide
you know how to progress with
each draft above drafts or or a new
draft or whatever
the main thing is that to come to
agreement on the technical
the protocol aspects
okay
uh let's see okay yeah we also have um
uh igp mld proxy
young model um it passed working group
last call and uh
i'll learn
oh request publications sometime
next week or so
let's see we also have null register
packing um
we had some issues at first with that
the quality wasn't
it wasn't good enough
it had some shortcomings
so it was returned to the working group
but after that we have a pretty good
review by several work group members
some
discussions and also by the routing
directorate
so um
yeah
mike is driving that well i believe we
are
about request publication for that
um
then there's an assert packing draft um
so uh
[Music]
yeah most worker plus call comments were
addressed i had a few just a few minor
comments that i
think should be addressed before
publication um
so once those are addressed i'll go
ahead and
yeah request publication of that as well
then we have the point-to-point star
point-to-point multi-uh point to
multi-point policy which we will discuss
this meeting and also um
you are doing some work on progressing
igp with 3ml2 to internet standard and
we'll have a presentational discussion
about that
um
the next one actually uh
[Music]
yeah we want to
consider progressing that as well we
discussed at the last meeting but not
this meeting
so we'll get back to that later
and then we have this lisp john poon
extensions that was just adopted and we
also will discuss today
one thing we don't have on here is the
draft that you recently called a uh
adoption call for humans uh
point to multi-point ping
uh right
draft
which um
it looks like we are
good to adopt as far as consensus is
concerned however
we did receive a comment that it would
be helpful in that draft human if you're
hearing this that to
specify whether
this is
focused on
the sr mpls data plane
or the and or the srv6 data plane and to
specify that in the draft
and
it was also requested that before we
adopt it that we ping the mpls working
group just as a cc at least the uh the
chairs
so that they know that we're using their
code point
in this draft so um
does that make sense human
sorry can can you guys hear me now
yeah
okay yeah that makes sense my apologies
i
i forgot to add that comment i i think
we need to
start with srm pls
as
the multi-point policy yeah that that
was something i missed i i will
definitely add that
yeah
that'd be great if you can update that
and then um
and then we will
just uh stick and i will do the thing
that we need to do with the other work
group chairs and then we will uh likely
uh make an adoption
uh yeah we'll send it we'll send you an
email on the list that's saying okay
it's go ahead and clear the
submit as a pin working group document
now
thank you
then we're working on updating the
charter mike do you want to
take that
yeah so
just good segue is that we uh as agreed
with the
spring chairs over the last year or two
we are doing
uh
sr point to multiply work in pim
for a variety of reasons including
springs just very busy and they
prefer to have us do it
so we have adopted a draft and it looks
like we'll be dropping adopting a second
draft
there are
other working groups working on
point-to-multi-point related work as
well including bass and idr
they will likely
keep that work
but
there had been the discussion on whether
we should
take on that work as well
to kind of make it consolidated into one
working group
but for now
that work
appears to be remaining in those other
working groups and
it would be helpful if we at least be
aware of those works and stig and i will
do our best to make this working group
aware of uh point of multiplayer work
going on in other working groups so we
can
add our expertise
and comments to help them to make sure
it jives with our
our protocols
uh any questions so far
comments about that
okay
so
uh
we will be sending we were intending to
have this done by this
this itf but uh because of what i just
described we were not able to to
solidify it but
uh so far we have this
charter update everything's the same
except we did remove the first
bullet with regards to um
management and yang
and we removed that because as far as we
know the yang work is basically done if
that is that does that sound correct to
everybody
okay
so nobody's jumping in and you'll have a
comment to
opportunity to come on the list too um
so we kept the rest that is already in
our charter
and then added this
last bullet so remove that one bullet
and added this one which is to develop
point-to-multipoint protocols
uh this includes sr srv6 point to
multipoint work per agreement with the
spring working group
um
and this may also require other point to
multiply protocols as requested from
other working groups which kind of keeps
it open to if they do want us to take on
that work that we can
do so
so that's really the main thing that we
wanted to make sure that we're all aware
of that it's already been an
understanding that we're taking on this
work
specifically from spring but we wanted
to make it more formal
and then the rest of the charter stands
as is
which is to comment about aligning and
working with other working groups
any
comments about this charter update
yes alvaro
so you already uh you mentioned some of
the other work in other places and that
side meeting that's happening on friday
so you know in general the charter looks
fine to me i think that we're gonna want
to
look at that other work on friday
uh sync with all the other chairs to
make sure that you know we all have uh
all our ducks in a row
we do need um
better coordination across working
groups and you know that's one item that
i think
we are seeing very much right now with
multicast
but that happens in other cases as well
where we see multiple
types of work or multiple work that in
this case uh refers to the architecture
being worked here
we see work in idr we see working best
we see work in pce and other places that
all refer to the architecture but that
are different solutions so we want to
make sure that we coordinate that um so
as far as the charter uh sure i mean we
should probably start discussing that uh
we probably don't won't want to you know
progress it until we have all the other
ducks in mind so that we do this just
once right and not have to maybe do it
twice or whatever so at that time um and
hopefully we can get that done in the
next
few weeks as well so that uh we are all
in in agreement on what's going to
happen and who's going to coordinate and
and all those other things
great
thank you uh
hi june
hello
hi go ahead
yeah
uh for uh for for sr based uh p2mt uh
solution i i think the
the sr based uh multicast solution is
different from the team protocol so
my recommendation is
we can consider with
the side media that will be held in
friday for the msr
side meeting you know uh the other
related all these are released
multicast workers i think it should be
included in my new new working group
okay
okay thank you so we can
discuss that all at that site meeting
thank you
yes alvaro
what stay already said before which is
the site meeting is not an official atf
uh
meeting right
so you can discuss anything you want uh
we still need to agree
uh in the atf
where and how anything's going to be
done right
everyone knows here that we
need to look at charters and you know
everything else
if there is work which hasn't been
presented anywhere in the atf yet
to be done in a new working group sure
we can consider that
um if the work of course overlaps with
other things
uh we can do it in in you know other
places uh just a reminder to everyone uh
this working group is called pim not
because of the protocol
but because of how you know what it says
in the charter here on the slide this is
called protocols for ip multicast
not protocol independent multicast
we chartered this
what four or five years ago
to on purpose
be able to increase the scope if
necessary now that doesn't mean that
everything that has to do with
multitasking has to go here right uh it
just means that that we need to to
discuss that
and uh as with everything you know
things need to be presented in the atf
we need to discuss charters uh yeah et
cetera right it's not just uh
unfortunately not everything is
automatic as as it should be
okay thanks
yeah thank you yeah so there's been many
comments about the side meeting i think
we should regularly do side meetings
that just don't fit within a working
group time period um jake holland had an
interesting one last ietf
and i've already from a side meeting
that i attended this week uh yesterday
uh on addressing i already had an idea
that i think i may want to
present along with dino um on dlts and
an ipa multicast so i think side
meetings hopefully are becoming like a
multicast related side meetings
hopefully become a regular thing that we
do
to kind of just brainstorm on
things like this so
yeah great
any other comments before we move along
to the rest of the agenda
okay
i think stig you are
all right
so um
yeah so uh let's be one with the agenda
uh
so
let's see
yeah so just to remind people this is
the agenda so i'll start out with now
with this and then
uh yeah that will just be just a few
minutes and then
you can go next stop for me
okay let's see the slides here
all right so um
um
this is the drone print attributes for
lisp environments using underlay
multicast
so um there was a draft in the
pin working group some years back uh
defining these attributes
um
the only thing is that
the attributes could be used for to
specify a unicast destination for like
ingress replication
but as defined they couldn't be used for
underlay multicast so
what this draft is doing is basically
saying that you can
also specify a multicast address as a
destination address
um
for lisp and cap
so um
this draft was presented in uh let me go
to the next slide
draft was presented in both pim and lisp
last itf and
it was agreed with this working group
that the work could be done in him
just like last time
but we reviewed by this parking group
so
yeah it has recently been adopted
i'm one of the authors and
it's a very simple document
we offers believe that the main
thing we need to work on is the security
considerations otherwise we feel it's
already fairly complete
but um
okay um yeah so
let's see um looking for
okay yeah i have a couple of slides here
that can remind people what this is
about but i feel like i already said
basically what there is to say
it's about getting this across a
multicast core network we need to
specify the um
online multicast address
and
basically using that existing tlv just
specifying that a multicast group can be
specif can be used
that's all we are doing in this draft
so uh yeah we're hoping to get some
comments review from the working group
and uh
you will work on the security
considerations and uh
hopefully we can do a loss call soon
but yeah i'm hoping by it by the next
itf that we can get some comments and
hopefully be in good good shape by next
item
that's all i have any questions
can you put your pen hat back on so
uh just from a why well while we were
talking about pen rechartering um
do we need to add anything about
lisp related work or do you think this
is just kind of a one-off
we do have
in our charter at the end they we
mentioned working with other working
groups including lisp do you think
that's good enough
for now
right so in this particular case um
uh the reason we're doing it in pim is
that you know it has to do with that pin
joint attribute and that is in our
current charter
so i think you are good there um great
there's been some multicast work done in
the list working group as well
but
it doesn't involve him in any way so
that was done
purely in the list working group
okay
right okay yeah
all right so next step
is uh
multi-point policy
yeah i'll
i'll drive the slides here just tell me
you want to go to the next slide please
if you're talking to him and we can't
hear you
my apologies
so for whatever reason my browser keeps
reloading this webpage um so hopefully
i'm not going to drop off but if i did
that's the reason
so
quickly we wanted to give a quick update
on the point multiplying policy
so i guess we're ready for the next
slide
by the way can can you guys hear me
clearly
yeah
okay
um
so
as of now the replication segment is
obviously adopted by the uh sr
uh and this working group has adopted
the point to multiplying policy i'll
give you a little bit of update what has
changed in that draft
um i'm not going to talk too much about
the end there hasn't been too much churn
on the yang and eventually i think
next itf and
present them to the appropriate working
group based on the
the yang um so that's one thing we have
talked about unfortunately i haven't
done it so far i'll do that for the next
idea
um
when it comes to the
best in vpn evpn sr point to multiply
policy uh so that's the bgp signaling
layer um
for the services
uh that
work is somewhat complete
we can
signal the services over a point to
multiplying policy between two pe's
from the pce
point of view and nailing down the point
to multiple point three
on the on the routers
we went through some changes in the
draft
i'm not going to get into the detail
there was a adoption call
which was had a majority
and they should be it should be adopted
by november 25th unless if there are any
other comments that would come in i
don't foresee that so it should be a
smooth sailing
the next one is the
idr
uh for star point to multiply policy so
basically what this is is
a bgp srte
trying to nail down the the tree
obviously we have bgp into the routers
we try to keep it
just uh
it's not it's not just me
like every minute or so your audio just
uh disappears for like 10 seconds so i
don't know if there's
anything you can do on your end
especially since you're giving another
presentation after this one so just yeah
maybe maybe i'll get to my 5g network if
it's any better than this
um
like right now
it comes and goes
if this is not useful and i and i keep
disappearing
i i suggest to go to the next
presentation i don't know whether
everything is
yeah we didn't just we didn't hear any
of that last uh 20 seconds
okay so i've got the next example
okay
next slide
the next presentation
next presentation okay
yeah bob i
had that same problem with bluetooth i
had i'm using
hardwired just for that very reason
unfortunately
so we're ready when you are coming
but take your time if you're figuring
out your audio
yeah i think maybe he reloaded i don't
see him on the list here right now yeah
yeah
let's give him a second if he doesn't
come back we can uh
go to the next presentation on
extension source management and then
come back to them
yeah let's
let's do that if that's okay
yeah
uh
yeah i think it um
is it pronounced
on
lee for uh
ig pmld yeah extension
you hear me yeah
yes we hear you
hello everyone i am juan ali from china
telecom i am going to introduce our
updates the next page please
in the last discussion a similar draft
is mentioned named multicast source
notification of interest protocol
msnp
msnp is designed around the
premise that you want to minimize source
when no receiver listening
msnip focus focus
primarily on dataflow control or
documents aims at management of
multicast source and related service
including control of multicast source
access which can
improve the security of multicast
control of data flow
which is consist consistent
with the
idea of
ms
nip
management of money casters statistics
with controller
and other uses can be extended based on
source registration
in addition both msnip and our document
is designed for ssm scenario
if these solutions
are to be applied in esm scenario maybe
other multicast protocols such as
protocol independent
multicast
need to be consid
need to be considered together
we will have made some updates to our
document in reference to
comments
in last discussion and the process of
msnip expat thank you
next page thank you
sorry sorry
the first is updates
the first update
is updated for multicast source
registration process
after receiving the
gesture message from the source system
and authenticate authenticating
the router views and multicast source
registration messages
with valid registration status response
to the source system and inform the
source systems that the requests are
approved the router
then the router will trigger a timer and
maintain the
registration status
for the source systems until the timer
expires
the source systems need
pretty
periodically send registration message
to the routers to inform the router that
the multicast source is alive
then routers will refresh the timer
of the registration status
if the router receives multicast data
from the multicast source they will
refresh the timer during the data
delivery the source systems does not
have to send
registration message
periodically
when the timer expires
or the validated
periodical
registration expires
the router will release the registration
states and send a multicast
resource registration message with
invalid states to the source system to
inform it
next page thank you
for multicast
source registration message
and
the update is
the credentials is extended to
16 bits in addition to
earned timestamps
times stamp is replaced by three by the
duration the start time and the duration
are not related to the timer mentioned
in the process
start time
timestamps indicates the start time
when the multicast source can prove
can provide a service for multicast
approves
before this time router don't send the
multicast
data
notification message to the source
system
duration indicates the maximum
duration that the multicast source can
provide service for the multicast
group
you know valid registration request
next page thank you
for all messages defined in this
document the address type field was
removed
if this message are used to ignp message
the corresponding
address are
ipvs addresses if this method are used
to mld messages the corresponding
addresses are ipivalio addresses
next page thank you
we add a new section to introduce use
cases and place multicast source
management for pce based beer solution
in this section
such as in
sdn
to unify the money
management of multicast information
based on the controller
source excise authentication
that float transmission control
and the
receiver information management can be
realized
and the ability of multicast network
service awareness can be
improved
other use case will be added in the in
future updates
and that's the main content
of our presentation any comments on your
work
our work welcome thank you
yeah so thank you very much
are you requesting anything of the
working group at this time
other than comets
stig or anybody
uh
well i can mention that uh
yeah i'm like
i joined as a co-author and i have some
contents that i plan to add on use cases
and uh
yeah
some more work
to be done okay
last uh itf you mentioned uh m snip was
there ever like a
comparison to see if
the work done in the past
[Music]
uh applies to this
um
it's this at least from protocol point
of view i feel
uh
that the main thing is this you know
basically that the source can notify
that it wants to be a
wants to sell multicast and that there's
a way for the
router to respond back to the source
with some information right about
receivers and so on and that's common in
both of these drafts of m snip and this
draft
but the motivation is is different and
um
yeah i think we have several use cases
that are not mentioned back
in the m step draft
there's some differences too like this
job talks about uh i mean there's like
credentials and you can announce like
start time and someone that was not
there in amsterdam
okay
hi june do you have a comment
uh
hello yeah we have compared
with the
msi team
and this software and
their aim is
a similar bosom to control the
the
behavior of yourself not as a source
i think
we can
cooperate
and
under the
that messenger used msnp in the left
update so we also
understood as a closure to put for this
job
and we
in the either
can't update the person we have
also adopted the command from the from
stick for the
encoding of the message and for the
timer
timer control for the register timer
control etc okay
okay ac
cisco systems can you hear me
yes you can we can't now
no yeah it it asked me to allow every
time i turn my audio on i don't know why
uh
the
the primary
motivation for this would be one you can
do credential validation of the sources
and number two you can tell the sources
to quit sending when there are
absolutely no receivers is that what it
is
are those the two main uh two main
advantages why you'd want to go through
this complexity
is that
correct
yeah
yeah uh i i think yeah yeah correct the
main goal of this
result is to
the first thing is to authenticate the
multicultural source we want to
deploy the multicast
in the control manner so not every not
uh
any source can send the mouse password
for the network this is the first uh
first thing the second name we want to
feedback some more information for the
receiver i think this is the popular
multicast application
this is the
main aim of this
quarterback
although we can under other
[Music]
capabilities especially in the msrp
later
yeah
from yeah the way i see this you know we
had
the main complexity in multicast is
often the source discovery and we have
lots of different ways of doing that and
it's usually been like some dynamic
discovery mechanism
but we can simplify discovery
a lot
if we actually
have some signaling other source rather
than having like data driven
signaling
okay okay thank you uh
i guess maybe you could look at things
where you eliminate the rp and go right
to source pacific with this
right
yeah
sorry i didn't get the losses you could
look at flows where you don't rp list
flows where you just go you just have
the registration of the sources and the
receivers and don't even bother with
asm right
right
i think that would yeah that would be
more
deterministic i think
i agree
thanks
all right anything else on this track
[Music]
yes satoshi
i
didn't leave this draft so
um i may miss the point but uh
why
this draft
wants to use igmp or mld for source
discovery
so
um maybe there was a next time
i may clarify the more
uh difference about uh between ms nip
and
this draft because
in fact i couldn't understand the clear
difference between ims and ipad this
draft
but in any case so why uh you need to
use igmp or mle because igpmla is
usually or in general used for the
receiver protocol so why
you need to
extend
ignp mld for source discovery and for
the source discovery if we talk about a
very old
protocol we already have
sap sap
of course sap is not perfect profitable
so that's why
maybe
recently no one has been
using
uh sap but sap itself can become as
something like a source
uh notification so you can extend sap
even if you want to
enhance some credential approach
uh for source discovery so my question
is why you need to use or need to extend
or medley
go ahead and answer that
yeah
i try to answer
uh
i i i i'm not aware with the
the protocol between the horse standard
and its first road router
you know the the allies
responsible i say the main protocol of
the main proposal of reserve is to
authenticate the the multiple source not
not the
firing source really in the network you
know so uh
uh
for authenticated resource it is
a must depend on the protocol at the
layers between the host
and the first router so ignp and ambi is
in the best selection for such control
you know uh we we don't want to solve
the
uh source recovery within uh within the
network
and missing the by finance currently we
focus on the ssn sm ssm scenario so
there is no rp
in the network
okay
money
um yeah it seems like um
this idea of kind of request to send
where the sender actually requests to
send something into the network um it
feels like this is an old idea uh and
i remember it being abandoned a long
time ago
but i
i remember m snip um not getting much
traction um
i i think i'm not old enough to remember
why rts died i think that might have
been
a little bit before my time but i'd be
curious if anybody can remember you know
this isn't the first time that this
concept has come out it you know it was
an idea from a long time ago and does
anybody remember why it was abandoned
and
[Music]
decided not to pursue
or is everybody else too young to
remember
right yeah at least i would say i
i don't remember um
but
at least the main challenge i see is you
know deployment
it's very hard to get hosts upgraded to
support
something like this so even you know
like going from igp with two to three or
seven
two years and years
but i at least i imagine it could be
useful in some special
i don't know some special cases maybe
not like you know like
generic windows through linux but maybe
let's say
cameras with ip support or i don't know
it could be more specialized
use cases perhaps
but at least that's a big challenge is
how do you get something like this into
like host stacks in general
yeah brian haberman probably would
remember um
but
i would i would guess greg shepard where
he here would have an opinion yeah
probably so
yeah go ahead
uh
i
i think uh for
you know because we want to make the
the
smart caster in
one control manner so we think the
source must be authenticated and
controlled so it is different from the
start point of the ms9 here so i think
we can
and the source is the number of
smartphones in limited so i think we can
the update of the
may be acceptable
okay
it is not uh
like the receiver side so
so i think we can put for the
implementation
of the multiple
multiple sources
for such protocol extensions
okay this is our main aim for the
design of this project
great
thank you
i suggest we uh
communicate more on the list and not
wait till the next itf to present this
and let's
see what people think
other comments before we go back to
human
all right
human are you back yes
can you hear me
okay
all right um
so pim light um
if you can go to the next uh slide
please
so the entire idea was born based on the
last call that we had on the beer
signaling um
it's breaking up
yeah but you're back now just well
i'll just say something when you break
up and then just pause
okay sounds good
maybe
are you unwired or
there's construction around so maybe
they cut something or not you know
yeah um
so the
in the beer signaling we
use the pim join and prunes
to signal them
you're breaking up
mike
i don't
i don't think it's working because i
hear my own voice and it keeps breaking
up
right
uh i i apologize i think i'm just gonna
take away
time from working group
i can hear you well most of the time you
just break up a little occasionally
all right i i can't continue yeah just
power through it and we'll just uh
it seems like your first and last
sentences are audible it's all your
middle sentences that aren't so stick
with first and last sentences
okay
so
basically we want join prunes
uh without the pim hello to be accepted
from other routers other peer routers
so
including the assert messages
so this is what we're going to call pim
lite
you don't need to bring up team
adjacency between the routers
directly connected
basically without having the pim hello
you can accept the joins and proven
messages to signal the multicast estates
next slide please
so what becomes the limitation
of this pimlight protocol if you will
so the first thing is that obviously you
cannot discover pym neighbors
dr selection
so there's no ddr priority options
and obviously since there is no pim
hello
you don't create a general purpose state
for your neighboring pim routers on the
local router
i mean these are the main limitations of
this pim light just simply because there
is no pin
hello between adjacent routers
next
perfect um
so
again it's pim with zero calories we all
know that pim is complicated the
protocol
which some networks uh or interface
types might not be able to support or
are not optimized
for the pim protocol
full
pin protocol itself
in in the beer network
where you have
beer packets going between two pim
domain
uh really the beer
encapsulation is not optimized for
sending pim hellos and bringing up
full pim adjacency
between the two
pim domains if you will so this pin
light plays very nicely
with a
of networks
that
are not optimized for pin
as well
which this pin light can be used
next slide please
so
obviously we are looking for comments we
want to make sure that this
draft is bulletproof that we are
covering all cases corner cases
for having a pim light protocols between
for the
comments okay
not sure how much of that you got but
that's it we got a lot thanks for
powering through that
so one thing that we will
oh go ahead
alright let's see let me yeah thanks
mike uh but i haven't read the document
but can we
um
what you're defining here is really a
different type of interface
can we actually call the draft not just
pim lite but pim light interface or
something like that
so that gives the idea of what we're
really specifying in it
so please let's take care of that before
yeah we go further with anything else
thanks and by the way thanks for doing
this this this work
oh well yeah
thank you um
i have no problem calling it team light
interface
the only thing we need to think about is
that
there are logical interfaces or
physical interfaces or even beer um
you got that last comment so what i was
saying is that beer doesn't have a
logical pin interface it's really
we figure out where the source is
and where is the last beer router
on the path to the source
and we send the join
via
the next beer edge router
so i have no problem calling it
interface
so i said i don't have no problem
calling it a pimlight interface
yeah we don't know what you're saying
but it's important
[Laughter]
let me just chime in right now woman and
say that
one thing that is unique about this
draft is being that stig and i are both
on it is that we can't call for adoption
of this draft so we would need to
have a shepherd
um
be as if they're a chair for this
particular draft and do the calling for
adoptions um
and follow this draft throughout
the life of the draft if it were to be
adopted and do the working group last
call and all that
so
um
does
and we can pull the list and see or just
find someone and ask him if they do it
but um right now does anybody
would anybody be willing to to fill that
role for this draft
okay
so we'll find somebody so we can't ask
for an adoption right now any other
comments
human you want to try again anybody
no i'm i'm i'm good
okay
yeah
thank you sandy you're
you're it appreciate your
helping out with that well stig and i
will talk to you more about that uh via
email
all right so we have that volunteer
great
um are we ready for brian now
i don't think he's here though
yeah i
don't see him
it may still be a little bit too early
we're kind of ahead
yeah
uh unleash are you interested and able
to
to present
yeah and there's a lot hearing you
have you been on any of the call stick
enough to
give an overview or not
yeah i was checking with um unleash here
you know if he could do it he has some
audio issues trying to rejoin
[Music]
but yeah if neither he or brian is here
in a couple of minutes i guess we can
sort of discuss it
at least start discussing it without
them
oh am i audible now
yeah hi it's working now great
yeah uh hi uh so
this presentation is for advancing igmp
v3 and mlv2 to internet standard
uh so in last ietf 111 we also presented
this at that time we asked for adoption
and uh now it is a working group draft
so we
uh submitted the first version with some
changes
before the cut off and for both three
three seven six for ignp v3 and three
eight one zero for mlt v2
so i can
briefly talk about some of the changes
which we incorporated
so for 3376
one of the changes which we did like
recently there was a query over the
working group alias regarding the query
election process which was
uh being seen and like one of the
implementations where we don't have a
clear way of
identifying whether
uh
which query should be used for the
election process so uh for more details
we can look at the
emails in the working group and so that
that was one of the issues which got
incorporated in 3376
second thing was the
mld messages being sent with link local
addresses and this is for three eight
one zero
and
one of the erratas which was filed
against three eight one zero uh mld v2
was the right of four seven seven three
where it talks about
the missing
recipe field so that also got
incorporated in version one
and
uh one of the older orders which was
filed against three three seven six is
four three seven five where the older
version query present time of definition
itself has some discrepancy
so this is also being incorporated and i
guess we
there is uh another thing missing so
there is another area which is like kind
of editorial
uh which is five three seven five
against uh
ignpv3376rfc
so that is also got incorporated in
version one of three three seven six
piss
so we are
using github and all these issues could
be tracked here so all these issues
which i just talked about
are they are present in github and
that right now markers closed so
on next slide please
i stick
and next slide
yeah
so some of the open issues which we have
right now is like uh
do we want to move
rfcs1112 with igmp
v1 and mldv1 to historic so this is also
one of the questions which will be asked
in the last atf as well
and
second thing is like rfc four zero
four six zero four uh ssm
for igmp and mlt so do
uh do we want to incorporate that in the
uh this while this while we are moving
with the advancement of
this internet standard so we want to
incorporate 4604 and that
and another question is like uh
how we want to define the relationship
with the new pim igmp mld extension of
this piece this drops
and i guess last one is the errada 675
which is recently being filed
and i brian i think he's already
working on it so i there there is some
email communication happening over the
working group as well
so these are the current open issues
uh
yeah i have a couple of comments on that
so
for the uh
igmpmld extension
at least after pulling the working group
you know i think there's agreement that
we don't need to um
make it an official update of the of the
igp mlb rfcs
so i don't think it should be an issue
for um
to make the right decision on the first
two i think you know we need to have
more details i think and it's probably
good to
send some emails to the working group
mailing list and basically
outline a bit more what uh what
you should consider
like for instance for 4604 like what is
the actual text that
what's the scope of
the work you know what text do we want
to actually
copy from 4604
um
so yeah
it's kind of hard to
without having all those details and
maybe doing some thinking to to answer
these questions right so
getting some discussion on the list of
big rates
guess for second one uh while in the
internal meeting we do identified uh so
what sections we would be borrowing from
uh i think yeah it would be better if we
put all those things in email and
get along on the group
okay great
and regarding the
first one are so uh
uh
is it like
we should be asking this thing over the
group or
moving the rfcs to
the older one started
all right i think it would be good to
send an email to the
to the mailing list for this one as well
so maybe
send you know separate emails for each
bullet points kind of
try to get input
i guess so
this is the pretty much update any
questions or
comments
are welcome
yeah thanks a lot for presenting this
i know you were not that prepared for it
and brian is not here so i'm glad you
could do it
so
i guess that's the last we had on our
agenda
have anything
else we should discuss or
i guess they might be done
thank you that was a good
meeting appreciate your
time
catch you guys throughout the week
thanks yep
thanks so much
see you next time
you