even if it's not virtual
i i missed the big red button the chairs
had in person
and
it is uh
now 15 30 i see so i think we can start
so this is the rmcat
session and i'm anna bristow and i'm
here with
colin and we are perkins and we are the
co-chairs and
let's see if i managed um
so this is the note well i think we are
on friday so you're probably all
familiar with it uh by now if not uh uh
do read it of course because it
does apply to the meeting
and to start with
some administrative so the meeting is
being recorded i think you are aware of
this
by now as well
we do need a note taker for the meeting
do we have someone that can help out
taking notes
now i don't see you guys it's harder to
look at someone suitable
so gory you are in the queue
gory was that you volunteering to take
notes
yeah okay i can't say i cannot do it so
i will enjoy doing it
i'll just bring that up and take notes
um in the hedgehog thank you
and did you want to add something else
or no this was why you you left the
queue now so
um
great so i think we don't need a
separate jabber scribe because we have
the jabber now integrated in mythical so
we will
uh keep an
eye on that
so let's see
so uh
as uh
colleen hinted that we have not uh met
in a while so
this is the agenda we have for the day
we're gonna have an update on
our algorithm so we met last time
for a meeting at itaf 106 and at this
point
we decided we had delivered our
algorithms
and most of our documents
and
we decided that we would go idle for a
while to try and gain experiences with
the algorithms to then come back and see
how we would uh proceed after that and
at that point we were thinking to go
idle for about a year but then of course
the pandemic arrived and
we were hoping to also be able to meet
in person but now of course it's high
time to come back and see what has
happened to the algorithms and what do
we have
left as work in the the working group so
after we finish
this introduction part we will move to
looking at the update on the status of
the rmcap algorithms so first an
overview of it from the shares and then
we will have ingmar presenting uh some
updates with the scream algorithm from
rfc 8298 and we have david
presenting some updates on the shared
bottleneck detection from rfc 8382
and
then we have one active working group
document that has been
left behind on rtcp feedback for
congestion control and colin will give
us the the update on that and then we
will
see where we are on the different
activities uh how to wrap up or what we
have left to
to work on
so to
start with a recap of the working group
activities we have had four algorithms
that we have submitted
as experimental rfcs and they have been
now all published they have been in in
various queues uh some of them waiting
for each other but we have the the
scream algorithm and the nada algorithms
the two congestion controls and then we
have the the coupled congestion control
and the shared bottleneck
detection
and the last of those the nada algorithm
was was published since we last
after our last physical meeting and the
couple congestion control
had the dependency there so it was also
published after we last met but they
were all submitted at this point in time
but now they're also all
rfcs
then we have had a set of requirements
and evaluation documents
and the requirements was actually the
first document that was sent for
publication from the group but that was
in the
in the queue for a long time
because of the the webrtc
bundle and then most of the
evaluation documents had the dependence
on the requirements so uh three of these
four of these documents were
all now published in january of this
year
uh when this whole
sequence of documents were completed and
all published and we already had the
video traffic models
uh published uh before
and then we have one
active working group document on the
feedback side
and this is the draft that colin will
talk about and
when we last met this was waiting for
the
uh
rtp control protocol feedback for
congestion control the feedback message
that was
handled at that time by the avt core
so that is now published in rfc
8888 and
so we should now finish up this this uh
document that was depending on it so we
have that on the agenda
so this was a was a recap of where we
were with the working group we thought
this would be good since we did not need
in a while
any questions or comments on the general
update
otherwise
we will move on to the
algorithms to
have an
update on those
so we have four uh
algorithms and
igmar you're in the queue because you
will be presenting soon i assume
so
is this why or you wanted to ask
something
i'm trying to figure out how to
cancel slice request
yes yes possible before it's impossible
no no it's there i i see it i will just
give the overview first and then i'll
let you share oh
so i i'm on the overview slide so no
worries so we have the four
algorithms so we have scream and ingmar
will give us the the update on that then
we have the the nada congestion control
and uh xiaojing
updated the status on that uh last year
that they had the full implementation
uh completed of nada in the
mozilla browser
and this was kind of the completion for
them on the work so there has as far as
the authors and shares no there has not
been any
ongoing activities after they completed
this
this implementation and
xiaojing and her co-workers have moved
on to other
projects or other employees after that
so i think there is no ongoing work or
nada as far as we know but there is the
open source
implementation
then there is the coupled congestion
control and there there is some
ongoing research
on the topic by the waters so they have
some students working on coupling the
the video and data flows in chromium but
there are no
no results or or
ready things to report but still some
ongoing research
and then we had the shared bottleneck
detection and david will give us the
update on that
so with that i will now uh
stop my sharing
and i will
now i think in my view should be able to
share and i will give the word to you to
give us an update on
scream
okay
and uh
little
i hope you hear me him well
and this is an update what has been done
in terms of experiments the future and
uh
about around screen which was developed
by me and so i had them published or was
it the late 2017 it's been a qui a
couple of years since on
and uh you can skip to the next okay i
need to click on number two here
and there are some to start with where
scream is or isn't used i know
originally
the screen was intended for webrtc and
that was the whole intent to it back
when it was uh the work started on
it was implemented for open webrtc but
it never got traction and it never
really
never really ever
evolved into webrtc and so we don't want
a natural financial reason we don't have
any any much experimentation around that
so uh
but
perhaps something that was a
bit below my radar is that
there was a
can probably look at the avt core
presentation where martin singelbert and
yoriot presented will have integrated
screen with a quick with our go quick
implementation so
they have some results there and
and boundary issues when implementing a
screen there
what has
been more tried more is a cloud rendered
gaming and uh so now we're not talking
about uh one two megabits per second
it's more like uh 30 megabit per second
video with high quality and
then we have done quite a lot of
experimentation and then we also have
for remote driving uh where we have a
hero head or a
remote control call that we have been
driving around in various projects and
that also includes a
high bitrate video with multiple cameras
and
and also a scream has some kind of uh
it's a wrapper around the congestion
control that makes it possible to do
some benchmarking for instance over 5g
networks that has been done quite a lot
and about to clone rendering gaming and
here we have
been much focused around the development
of l4s and the screen was picked
because it's not the perfect algorithm
don't claim that but it's a known
algorithm and it was quite easy to uh
dig up statistics around how it worked
and what kind of latency got on
and
that later on evolved into using
implementing a gear streamer plug-in to
do as a real uh
experiments with a cloud rendering
gaming
and uh where we there we were able to
try out the experiment we'd done without
l4s and uh it was a
uh
we found a couple of issues with the
green algorithms in the process and
mostly related to how video encoders
behave
especially when you frequently update
your target bit rate
and i will come back to that later
and uh
yeah and uh
then we have remote driving where we
have done quite a lot to experimentation
and we have other students who have
integrated uh the screen algorithm with
the remote control core
and uh
we've tried out in various environments
and uh over 4g and party networks
and
it has been a pretty good test platform
to uh benchmark how it really behaves in
pole coverage for instance and
and uh
unfortunately we don't have much data to
show because uh it's a bit
sloppy behavior we run the test and when
then we
drop all the data you know it's a bit
has been a bit of a ad hoc testing
pretty much and for demo purposes and
i hope hopefully we do that better later
on
and then we have this benchmarking table
that is available for for public use and
and
it what it does is that it
it emulates a video encoder where you
can have other you you can pick either a
fixed bit rate or you make it rate
adaptive and you can do the rate
adaptation over quite a large uh
bit rate range
from a cup uh tens of kilobits per
second up to uh more than 500 megabits
per second
the upper limit there is depending on
what kind of laptop you are using or the
virtual machine
that you have in in the other end for
instance however much of the because it
becomes a bit cpu consuming especially
given the packet pacing and that is uh
involved
so it's not ideal for really high
bitrate applications but up to something
like 500 megabit per second you can try
out
i believe though the highest i got was
like almost 900 megabit per second over
one gig gigabit line
and you can also model iframes and
variable frame sizes you get something
that is similar to how a video
encoder in a constant bitrate mode
behaves but it's not i it's not
it's not identical of course
and you can measure rounded time with
the estimated q delay which is a by uh
output from the screen algorithm the
throughput that you get
both the transmitted bit rate and what
is hacked in the other random packet
loss and see marks
and
it's a
it there is
capable
about trying classic easy and
l4s
um
and the finding is uh so far is that
what we'll find is that the window based
congestion control is which is a
scream it is more or less actually tcp
land but but with a
little more bells and whistles that is
probably good at least for cellular
access
because you can have a radar equal
resource configuration that happens and
you can have andover that can pose
transmissions pulses can cause causal
transmission policies on
that if that is not handled you end up
quite easily with a
lot of data in the transmit buffers in
the in the network that is just there
and it's a it's it's uh
it's a causes head of line blocking for
subsequent video for instance
so it's a bet that you have it is a
window-based congestion control and then
you have a lots of zero in cases like
this you have lots of a lot of packets
in the center that you can discard if
they're all deemed too old anyway so
and then you can locally on the center
side of forcing you idr
so you're going to get quite the fast
recovery because of that and that is uh
has been shown in the experimentation
the remote control call for instance
where you can in
a really bad coverage situations you can
end up with a in those situations
and
the feedback rate we have had a lot of
discussion on calling for instance i've
done some uh work around the what is the
applicable
uh feedback rate that is needed
as it is today so something like one
feedback per 16 rtp packets and that is
probably overkill and uh
but uh to be honest i haven't
done so much uh
experimentation what is the pain point
pain limit here it has been more focused
on a stable streaming than optimizing
that core head
so you in
as it is now you end up with something
like the the feedback bit rate is
something like the 150th of the media
bit rate
that's where we end up roughly
and
the video recorder
that is something like 80 of the
development work doing the network
congestion control that has been quite
easy
but the video coders yeah
sometimes they are really strange
animals and
you have a video coder that are sluggish
when you sort of set the target bitrate
it can take a while for it to adapt to
the
new target bitrate on
and sometimes you have
that the video encoders can become
confused by frequent update
dates
and for instance the nvm encoder can be
given
what's called a systematic offset so if
you set it to 20 megabits per second you
will get like 22 megabits per second
on the average
and that has been uh can it's not
it's not a disaster for screen but it's
to give some kind of a
sub-optimal behavior and
that is not always visible if you don't
uh if you use just endpoint based
adaptation but it's more if you use head
for rest and you can you start to see
those anomalies
and also that iframes they are really
problematic in congestive situations
because they can be really larger
so there are companies that transmit
iframes only when needed
and also
gradual decoder refresh
also called
periodic injury refresh
can be useful
uh if that is implemented in decoders
and in the encoders
and another way that is used in a roman
caller remote control car at lower
bitrates you to compress the iframes
even even harder you set the qpmax and
qpmain mean values
to keep control of that
so there are some uh
issues with the video encoder that
even though your congestion control
algorithms works like the sean you have
a video encoders it's a essentially a
black box that can cause a lot of issues
for you
and then you have a what is to be done
in the future and uh
currently for some kind of an lfrs
implementation is in running code that
is not in the in the standard so i
have some plans to do an update
and possibly based on improved alphas
implementation later on but they say
that is not
planned right now
but hopefully later on
i believe that was general presentation
and four minutes left um
do we have questions or
thank you ingmar so let's
open up the queue and see if we have
some questions
so let me ask one question on because
you mentioned that
the code has the easy and
support so the the results that you
showed they were using
easy and feedback or
they were based on
law space
what results we have is that uh so far
they are in sort of in official
or they also what the to the degree that
they are officialized in this demo here
and here is he again if you
probably won't see you know but you can
see that the amount of marked packets
you see in the
sorry
yeah there you can see the amount of
more packets and how it behave how it
controlled the
bitrate of the video
yeah you know that's
so far it's only in that that experiment
that you're using
in this case l4s
we haven't done much experimentation
with eastern
thank you we have mo in the queue go
ahead mo
yes uh the
from what i understand the original um
design in in scream was motivated by
uh wireless clients
um do you think that that uh that
original design is still
uh uh part of the model or do you think
it would be
equally uh optimized for things like
data center to data center traffic
um so i'm really wondering whether or
not it makes sense
to start considering
the full topology when we look at the
congestion controls
and wonder if a one-size-fits-all model
is is maybe not appropriate and we need
you know some tailored for specific
environments
i can tell i believe the most of the
focus was on uh
the last mile uh 4g and 5g access that
was being was quoted driving but i
haven't thought about the data center
the data center for instance if that is
applicable there and i somehow suspect
that the
other algorithms like if we look at the
frog or bb or version 2 or something
like that could be more applicable there
i'm not sure but
it's a pretty tailored to the streaming
of the rtp media in this case and
not sure how useful it is in a wider
context
follow-up do you think that the
direction
matters were you mostly optimizing for
send from
uh from a
client or were you mostly optimizing for
receive
from the clients
uh i'm not sure if honest to the
question
are you trying to optimize uh was screen
mostly trying to optimize the transmit
video of a mobile endpoint or the
receive video of a mobile endpoint or do
you think that you tried to actually
optimize both directions equally
yeah i believe the
the actual scream algorithm
that is
it doesn't really optimize uh if you
look at it and think about
the heater buffers for instance that is
up to the for instance the key streamer
pipeline to handle
and it doesn't do re-transmissions and
that stuff and uh
it just
handles the congestion control without
uh
like it's like tcp without
re-transmissions more or less
but it's another retardation algorithm
that is more sensitive to their delay
increasing
well moe left the queue at least so i
i guess it did do we have any last
questions
no if not thank you very much ingmar for
the update on screen scream and
then
david you're up next
okay we see your slides
okay thank you
well this is an update on the
shared bottleneck detection work and
thanks to michael and simona for
their help putting this together
oops i have to make sure i'm on the
right window i think before the slides
move
okay some work that's happened probably
since the last time
we were here which was quite a while ago
there's been some work putting
um
basically the rsc version of sbd in
multipath tcp and in multi-path quick
and
what we'll be talking about
uh what i'll be talking about
today is
is a thorough comparative study that
we've done
of rfc 8382
and we recently had it published in
ieee acm transactions and networking
now what we do is we compare the vanilla
rfc8382
with
that
with the stat statistics that we collect
but a different type of way of grouping
a dynamic online clustering
method
and then we compare that with what was
one of the most promising ones in the
literature
a different type of method a
cross-correlation method that originally
was an offline method
and also our online adaption of that and
we
in the paper we look at
teacup test bed
experiments
simulations
some experiments over the internet as
well and we can
what we will look at today
is
the time it takes to detect a bottleneck
and to detect the bottleneck's gone away
um the effect of different path delays
on how well you can detect bottlenecks
and
the effect of having lots and lots of
parallel bottlenecks and of course
there's more in the paper if you want to
read it
now the
the rmcat
version is
is based on summary statistics it was
based on summary statistics because
originally
one of the requirements was
um
very
low feedback overhead so with this
method
we send
the summary statistics not very often
and it allows it also allows for us to
detect bottlenecks
on senders or receivers
and work with both
it's a divide and conquer method the one
that's written up in the rfc
where we
and it's very simple very light
where we take
take our flows in our measurements and
first divide them into what's
what flows they're experiencing
congestion and what not
then we take that group and subdivide it
according to an estimate of the
oscillation
then we'll look at the very
sort of variance how they vary as a
summary statistic and then
an estimate of the skew and then
if
if the packet loss is high enough to be
statistically relevant then look at
packet loss as well dividing into
smaller and smaller groups till we
end up with the final
the most common question we were asked
is why don't we use a clustering
algorithm and that tends to be difficult
because we don't know the number of
groups we the number of groups keeps
changing and
the flows in each group can keep
changing
but we
have got a novel iterative one that we
present
and it
it sort of does the closest neighbor by
an inverse square law
now the
other main way of doing this sort of
thing is to correlate the different
flows but because one-way delay is so
noisy if you don't use summary
statistics to help with noise
then you need to filter it some way and
this uses
wavelet filtering techniques which are
easily implementable in an online way as
well
but the original one
takes
the whole delay trace of every flow
puts it into matlab and gets matlab to
work out what the optimal filter
characteristics are for the whole
of everything so you need a crystal ball
for this one
and then filters the trace and then does
pairwise correlation coefficients
okay our version
a a slight modification of that works
out when's a good time to estimate good
filter coefficients and then estimates
them on the fly
okay firstly looking at detection delays
so how long does it take after a
bottleneck starts if we know ground
truth than we did in this experiments
um
before we
can say
there's a shared bottleneck and then
after it goes away how long before
each of these algorithms can say it's
stopped
and
it's not that surprising that the
offline crystal ball method in green
works out the start of bottleneck very
very quickly
it's not so good at detecting the end
because it was never designed
to do
anything but detect bottlenecks not not
stop them um
our online version of that in yellow
also
is similar not quite as good because
it's not optimal i suppose
then we have the rfc based ones the dc
sbd is the clustering dynamic clustering
one and our mcat sbd is a straight rfc
and you can see that
the summary statistic ones introduce
some lag and it takes
you know up to about four seconds
sometimes more to detect or the start or
a stop
of a bottleneck
now what we did here is different paths
have different delays
so if all of the
the paths that the flows are going on
have exactly the same delay then the
source lag difference we say is zero
but if the difference between
the flow with the shortest
um
shortest
transit time propagation delay and the
longest
propagation delay is 1000 seconds then
and here the source lag difference would
be one thousand
and what you see here is as
the difference between
the propagation delays of the different
flows increase
the the summary statistic methods handle
that very well
but the correlation ones
the
the more lag we get
the less well they handle it
and you can see that by them the
efficiency we use the f1 score for
accuracy in this case
um which is sort of a harmonic is uh
harmonic mean of precision and recall
but
they drop off quite sharply
after you get above 100 milliseconds in
this case
now the other thing we looked at is what
happens if we have lots and lots and
lots of parallel bottlenecks at once
how does that affect the efficiency and
we find out that the rfc version
after we get above
four parallel bottom x
um starts to sort of drop off
in its accuracy the
dynamic clustering method that we have
um improves on that with the summary
statistics and
the
cross correlation wavelet filtered
methods
are pretty pretty straight
regardless of how many parallel bolt
necks we have
so in conclusion
rfc8382
performs pretty well as simple it's
light it's really fast compared to all
of the others
it handles path delay as well
summary statistics introduce a lag so
that slows it down in detecting and
undetecting and if you have high numbers
of parallel bottles next then a
different grouping mechanism such as
the one that we proposed here
um
improves on that
now a limitation of all
of these methods
and pretty all shared bottleneck
detection methods is they assume that
bottlenecks have measurable similarities
and all flows
for all flows sharing them a sort of a
bottleneck signature
and a counter example
is that if one
your sending pattern dominates
a bottleneck then what you end up
correlating is sending patterns
rather than a bottleneck signature
and that potentially in some
circumstances can mean that you
group flows together because their
sending patterns matched not that they
were sharing a common bottleneck
so the path forward
we think that
for a proposed standard to be useful
then that limitation should be addressed
first
and addressing it
may be
algorithm-dependent
so it may depend on whether you're using
scream or whatever and you may have to
have that
knowledge a generic algorithm may be
possible using the ideas of sort of a
speakerphone cancelling out
feedback so you may be able to do it
that way as well but that requires a bit
more research
or the other thing you could do is just
note that it's happening and then when
it's happening treat your sbd results
accordingly
and
we're calling on any interested parties
to continue this week
thank you
okay thank you david for the update on
spd
do we have any
quick questions for for david
otherwise it's nice to see that the
standard version still looks to be
performing quite well in your
evaluations
very simple and light comparatively the
once you go to clustering it's a lot
more cpu to do the work
sorry
so david did you look at
um more complex layer 2 bottlenecks
where you've got some sort of um
algorithm going underneath to allocate
bandwidth and
the bottleneck kind of is changeable
maybe not characterizable did you
actually manage to touch any of that
aspect when you were doing your
exploration and thinking
can you just explain a little more
because i'm just trying to picture what
you're sure
so i'm thinking about a radial link
that's actually doing some sort of um
adaptive bottleneck
adaptive bitrate method maybe to counter
rain fade or um movement of the
of the parties
and then your bottleneck doesn't fit any
mold and presumably you have to kind of
reject this one as being difficult to
characterize
but
did you think about these kind of really
odd ones that also appear
um
i can't say that we've thought that much
about that one and that
has the same sort of limitation instead
except in this time instead of the
descending one you're
you have this other pattern being
introduced
so
you have to have some way of filtering
that out so you see
so you're able to compare it and
at the moment
all
detection methods have this
same problem
yeah i i really enjoyed your your
feedback so that was a super
presentation and look forward to hearing
more when other people advance this
thing
okay excellent so thank you very much
david for that
update i don't see anyone else in the
queue and i think we also need to move
on to the next presentation so colin you
are up next
all right
i can make the shot slides
okay is this working
yes yes yes okay so hi i'm colin perkins
i'm going to talk quickly uh about some
of the uh overheads of congestion
control feedback in rtp uh
which is the the final working group
draft we we have in this this group
um so the uh goal of this draft is to
outline some of the overheads of using
the the various congestion control
feedback packets that we we've defined
in this group um so so it's looking at
the rfc 888 method
applying this
along with the other types of feedback
you get
you know the the various compounded
non-compound packets the different
feedback profiles uh the different
reporting extensions and so on
um to try and sort of work through the
calculations and show what sort of
overhead you get from sending congestion
control feedback in in some typical
cases
uh so people can so get get an idea of
um
what's the cost of doing congestion
control and what are the factors that
influence that cost
so it uh looks at two uh relatively
straightforward cases um the first being
that the voice over ap case and the
second one being a simple point-to-point
video case
so in in the voiceover ap case we're
looking at two-part party voice call
sending um frames um you know uh
so so so so many uh voice packets per
second i'm wanting to send congestion
feedback uh um either every frame every
second frame or so on
uh we're trying to set the rtcp
reporting interval so we're sending our
tcp reports every few audio frames maybe
every second frame every fourth every
sixteenth frame or or whatever
uh and obviously we there's different
ways of configuring rtp uh rtp and rtcp
and we we can send the
the reports that the feedback reports
either as um regular compound rtcp
packets or as non-compound packets
uh i mean we can mix and match between
these so so we can either send compound
packets every time or we can send
compound packets with uh non-compound
packets between them
uh so the draft works through uh the
format of a bunch of these packets so it
starts by looking at the format of a
compound rtcp feedback packet
and it sort of looks looks at the size
of the various headers so it says if
we're using udp uh an ipv ipv4 you've
got a certain size of header
you've got a certain size of
header and and overhead for the sender
reports
you know a certain size of source
description packet uh a certain amount
of congestion control feedback packets
so the srt
srtcp authentication tag and so on and
i'm not going to talk through all the
numbers here but the draft works through
sort of counting you know the number of
bytes in each of these to figure out the
the packet sizes
and it does the same for the
non-compound packets which just send the
congestion control feedback report and
don't have the the other uh
rtcp packets stacked in there
[Music]
obviously you get a much smaller packet
because you don't have the source
description packets and the sender
reports and so
um a real system would then send a mix
of these so it has to send occasional
non occasional compound packets in order
to keep rtp working because you need the
occasional sender reports and source
description packets and then in between
that it will send
non-compound packets
that are just sending congestion control
feedback to reduce the overhead
and obviously you can change the balance
between these and what we're seeing on
the slide is something that sends one uh
compound packet followed by a couple of
non-compound packets uh in a repeating
pattern
um and you know in some cases you could
just send the compound packets or you
could have you know one or two or three
or whatever non-compound packets in
between
the draft then sort of looks at how you
do the calculation to figure out the
overheads uh and it take it goes through
the rfc 3550 reporting interval
calculation uh and shows that the the
reporting interval depends on the number
of participants in the session the
average size of the packets uh the rtcp
bandwidth fraction has been allocated
um and that lets you you work out the
the rtcp reporting interval um if we
want to send a congestion control report
every um
a certain number of frames you set the
reporting interval to be you know that
that that number times the um the
framing interval and you you work
through the maths and that gives you a
fraction for the the bandwidth overhead
that you'll get if if you want to send
rtcp reports
at that particular rate in order to get
congestion control feedback
uh and the core of this draft is is a
bunch of charts showing the overhead in
various cases uh and so for for example
in in the case where you're sending um
only compound packets and you're not
using any of the non-compound packets to
reduce the overhead
um
you know that this table shows that if
you have your audio uh being framed into
20 millisecond packets and you're
sending rtcp feedback every second frame
of audio using only compound packets
your rtcp bandwidth is 57 kilobits for
the congestion control feedback
and as you um increase the number of
frames if you report every eighth frame
this drops down to
15 kilobits and if you reduce it if you
increase the audio framing interval then
the overhead drops down more
again this is only sending compound pack
compound packets but it's showing that
you can you can adapt the the overhead
of the rtcp congestion control feedback
by
changing the
how often you send feedback and the size
of the audio packets
if you do the same thing by sending
compound packets in between and this is
sent this is alternating compound and
non-compound packets you see the the
overheads reduce uh
somewhat and if you send more
non-compound packets in between you can
reduce the overheads further
and it's showing the sort of uh example
behavior you get as you play with the
different parameters to illustrate what
what the overhead of these mechanisms is
now it then does the the same sort of
calculation for a
point-to-point video conference uh
assuming we've got two people both
sending audio and video streams uh all
bundled onto a single five-two pulsar
you've got four active ssrc's uh one
audio one video
for each of the two participants
um and we're trying to send um
congestion control feedback every so
many video frames
um
and um the the sort of feedback you get
in this case you've got your
um
your your udpip headers uh and you've
got because there's two ssrcs you've got
the feedback being aggregated into the
packet and you've got one compound rtcp
packet from the reporting source one
from the non-reporting source assuming
you're using the um the reporting groups
and the aggregating feedback mechanisms
and then you've got the the
authentication tag for situ srtp
and again that i'm not going to talk
about it in
in much detail but the draft works
through this uh the non-reporting packet
uh has
assuming wearing extending compound
packets has an empty sender report a
source description c name and and the
reporting group
group source packets in it
the reporting source has a complete
sender report it has the the the sc name
and the reporting group packet and it's
got the congestion control feedback uh
because you're using reporting groups
this is the congestion control feedback
for both ssrcs
since that that they're co-located and
they're seeing the same thing
and the draft works through uh counting
up the size of these various packets and
figuring out what the overhead would be
and
that turns out to be uh quite large in
this case you've got a lot of uh
overheads because of the ssrcs and the
various reporting packets you've got a
couple of hundred bytes overhead plus
the the feedback
um and it works through and it does the
the same sort of calculation plugging in
the numbers into the the rtcp reporting
interval calculation uh from 3550 um and
from that it comes out with a table
showing the the bandwidth overheads
uh and and what we're showing here is if
you've picked a if you look on the left
here the media rate column it it's
making a bunch of assumptions about how
the
video is packetized which are not
entirely realistic but are probably
close enough to give a flavor of how
this would work and make them
abstractable you know if for example
you're picking you're sending media at
200 kilobits per second
um
your
and 16 frames per second video
uh then that gives you um
and you're trying to send a report for
every frame that gives you one on video
packet per reports uh probably free
audio packets per reports depending how
you do the audio packetization
uh leading to an rtcp bandwidth of sort
of 67 kilobits per second which is about
a third of the the
video rate
and as as you see as you go down the
table as the media rate increases uh the
the overheads of the reporting go down
uh and you the table shows how this
varies with the frame rate you're
choosing and so
uh similarly um you can use reduce size
packets uh by playing with the the way
you you can figure out tcp uh and uh i'm
not going to walk through the details
but the draft does that and uh it shows
that the um the the required bandwidth
drops down as you might expect
and reduces the overheads
so that's the this is a very quick
version of what's in this draft um
the the latest version of the draft uh
what what what i've done in this version
is brought the calculations up to date
with the published version of rfc 8888
corrected a couple of minor mistakes in
the way the calculations were being done
and
the previous versions had placeholders
for multi-party and screen sharing uh
scenarios um
i've taken those out because uh when i
tried to work through them i just
realized there were way too many
variables to to easily characterize it
uh and um
if i wanted it if we want something in
there which would uh actually be
representative of the different ways of
configuring it this draft is going to
balloon out to 50 pages long and it it
didn't seem worth the it didn't seem
worth the effort because the scenarios
in there i think illustrate the the
fundamentals of the behavior
now so that's where we're at in this
version um
as i say it illustrates the various
factors that that influence the the
overhead of using this congestion
control feedback uh and um i think
hopefully gives some useful hints to
implements as how you might configure
and use the format
um
from my point of view i i think this is
is done
uh it's got everything i i want to put
in it um i
you know
and i think it illustrates the point um
so my my recommendation would be that if
the group thinks this is useful enough
to publish we should uh take it to last
call
um if there are a few if there are nits
or details to sort out we can do that um
but if to me if the group thinks that
there is a
um
your significant
if the group thinks that it needs
significantly more work to to get this
into a useful state i'm not convinced
it's worth
to me the effort of doing that so
that that that's where i think this is
that
with that uh i think i'm done
okay thank you colin for the
update do we have any
uh questions for colin
yes jonathan
throw the question back at you do you
think it's useful in its current state
for
implementers
no this is something
so sorry you're breaking up and i didn't
hear that
do you think this is useful that's where
it purple matters
uh i i
i i i think it's useful yes i mean uh
yeah it's obviously only covering some
some of the basic cases but i think it
shows shows the point of how to
configure things
but does it and does it give enough
guidance that when you if you have a
specific
you know more complicated case but it
could follow the same
procedure as you did and get an answer
um
i i think it illustrates the general
principles uh and in the more complex
cases there are so many different
parameters to configure that that it's
hard to give specific guidance
yeah but i mean but somebody who knew
what their parameters were could
you know take your follow your procedure
and say okay for my case where it has
this this and this and this is what i
need to do probably
um i
i i think probably i mean obviously it
would depend on their experience with
rtp and congestion control
exactly how familiar they were with the
various things
okay
and this is of course a informational
document
right yeah it's targeting information
do we have any more comments or
questions
if not i think we are also in a sense
this is also moving us into our last
item on the agenda that we have a few
minutes to
to see how to wrap up and what our
outstanding work points are and of
course this
draft that colin just presented is our
last
open
working group document that we had not
concluded
and from from the author's perspective
this this strat is complete so the the
suggestion here i think is to send it
out for for uh
uh working group last call and feedback
from the from the working group
and there of course it's it's uh
very good to get feedback on the the
current status of the document and if
you see that
that this is uh a good good piece of
advice to publish from the working group
uh it now was a while since we talked
about this document and uh
i'm not sure if uh if the participants
have had time to to read it so i think
that
we have to take take it to the list to
to get more feedback on that point
and the other thing that we have done
today of course is to to try and have an
update and summarize the the status of
the different congestion control
algorithms because we had on our shorter
to
move
some of the
one or several of the algorithms
to propose standard after experiences um
but i think
we we have
it's nice to see that there is some work
on some of the algorithms but
i think from the shares perspective the
the conclusion is that we have not
had enough activity and work that it
makes sense to
to
bring any of the algorithms on that path
at the moment
i think what we maybe need to discuss is
is the scream side because i think this
is the algorithm that has seen most use
and as you had on your sliding mark to
to have an update that brings in the
handling of easy and maybe something
that that is useful still as an
experimental
algorithm i would would expect in that
sense
so we are now also open to have have
comments on any of the open points from
the the rest of the participants and and
what your view is
yes ahead
i was just going to repeat some of the
things i
said but
let's hear from you
but
hey sorry um
so i basically think that that um that
last remaining document should be 80
sponsored
and the group should probably close
um
last remaining one being
the
mine or being the screen
that the one that's adopted
okay
am i am i wrong that there's there's
only one adopted right
so so the one i presented which has been
adopted and then there was the potential
update to screen that and i was talking
about
oh yeah um
i would
i would just close the group
i mean i i
if people want to update screen that
that can also be ad sponsored
it can be in transport tswg right it's
i don't see a reason to keep the group
around
but that's me personally
with no dots or anything
so i think for the open document
um hope was that this was very close to
being done
[Music]
i i guess the document can can still
move but
uh
[Music]
i don't expect to do any more work other
than fix some typos people point out
if it's more than that i i'm going to
abandon it
i mean the documents basically been
around for like
eight years or so right and it's
occasionally getting updates which is
great but
um
you know
i would either sort of start working
group last call now or um
make it a sponsor
martin
okay just to add to what lars said um
for scream this uh 8382 bis uh it is
experimental document so we could
actually even do it in iccrg if that's
a um
a better venue for it
corey
i wondered if there were still enough
people around rncap to review colin's
document other people were
willing to give the final version a read
and therefore whether you could do a
working group last call
do you have any sense of how many people
are ready to read it
so that is a
a bit hard to judge but i see that jurg
at least is willing to read it in the
comments in the chat we have about 30
people attending this session
so
and i i think it would be very good also
of course
uh if some of the algorithm authors can
also read it
so that that would be my hope but
it's always hard to to assess of course
ingmar also says he's willing to read it
so i think that would be very good
[Music]
i think we could also check if
i'm not sure if charging is is in the
call i know she's still in the mailing
list even she she has moved from cisco
if she is also willing to read it from
the
from the the nada
side
so i think
if we keep it in the group the idea of
course is to to move it to to working
group last call
and to try to
to finish finish it up
yes sid
i hope you can hear me
yes we hear you
oh i mean
with my eddie hat on
i think
i have not seen any huge activities or
or any activities in the mailing list
and and i have not seen like i mean nada
uh as you reported 2020
uh it has implemented a firefox mozilla
i have no information on whether that is
in use
uh scream uh ingomar is doing
some trials and that's good to have and
we can actually fix uh some updates and
all these things so um that's that's
fine other than that i don't see like
anything happening on somebody i mean
previously in one of the item meeting
there was one proposal coming from um
like somebody asked like
can we can we
make another condition control algorithm
and all this thing i don't think like
they're coming back
so and today from this meeting i get the
view like well there might not be too
much energy to carry the
working group on
so i think uh
for the
this document the lab in that working
role that when we have we can go
directly to the working blast cop
and push it to
iit plastic call very soon
um
other than that i don't i i am
i cannot convince myself like why we
should have this working group and if we
need we can actually keep the mailing
list alive right
so if there is anything
some people want to
come in in future or some updates want
to be discussed this mail even could
still be there
so that's actually what i think
um
and yeah i think this has been working
with a really good document um i have
been
part of this working group from very
beginning
um it was a quite good journey but
i would love to see this work has been
deployed and adopted other than that
i don't see any output from this working
group
now so as i said i mean we had we had
decided to to
have some pause to see if there would be
more deployment and experience from the
from the algorithms but i i
as i said i don't see we don't as shares
also don't see that any of the
algorithms would be you know candidates
to be pushed forward at this point so
that that part of the shorter i think is
yeah it's not relevant at this point in
time so i i think we all
all have the same view on that
um yeah i see one more plus one for for
doing a working group called last call
on the
on the document
[Music]
so we can of course also so coordinate
on
how to
how to wrap up that
that last
document if you have other
uh comments on on that one
side but
otherwise i think the plan is we try to
finish off the the last document and
then we are ready to to close the group
this is my
my understanding of the this the
situation
and the sense of the group as well uh
and we are a little bit over time but
gauri you are in the queue you wanted to
add something
yeah i just wanted to say i put them i
have put the names of the people who
volunteered to contribute last call in
the notes
so that they're now in the notes
okay excellent
yeah then we have an agreement there and
way forward so let's do that
okay
great then thank you everyone
for today and it was still very nice to
see you all
and to also get an update on
what this was ongoing with at least some
of the algorithms
so uh
anything you want to add colleen
mostly i'm going to add that i still
can't work the mute button uh i was just
going to say
thanks everyone for for participating as
you say it was it was good to to get an
update and come to closure on the group
and yeah we we should try and get that
working group last call done very
quickly i think
okay okay thank you okay bye