okay
i think we're top of the hour
good morning good afternoon good evening
wherever you are welcome everyone um
this is the
computing in the network research group
meeting
with jeffrey he uh eve schooler and and
me uh jose mourpitzi uh we are the
chairs of this uh i think exciting uh
research field
that uh i think is is um
more and more important um in the
development of the internet
uh you move the slides eve so can you
hear me by the way
i think everybody is uh aware of this
uh i think
it for this group yes it's important but
also
uh you know that we're recording this
because we are
um
still virtual and i guess even when
we'll go not virtual we'll do it
i think what's also very important is
all the uh disclosures of intellectual
property which is on on the next slide
or something
and uh the code of conduct uh which is
also very important and
i think a few of us have
had
experiences that show us how important
it is
uh eve maybe you want to go to the
agenda very fast
sure can you hear me my audio
and can you hear me am i not on um
on this slide yeah i think we can yes so
this is the oh you can hear me okay
harassment copyrights and everything
uh next one
sure
but maybe they can not hear i think it's
very important okay
we are meeting at the same time as uh
the ietf but the irtf is not there to
do standardizations it's there to
conduct research and you will see from
the agenda
um
um you will see from the agenda that the
um there are important uh
um
research papers that are going to be
presented today and i know there was an
audio issue and i think i fixed it so
thank you for the people who
uh mentioned it
um
uh next slide eve
so uh we have a very
uh packed agenda
uh so you know i'm already
two or three minutes into this so we're
going to go very fast i think we're very
very happy to have scott chanker to
present
the extensible internet which was a ccr
paper
and
essentially raises a lot of interesting
questions about the future of the
internet and also
is is connected to some of the uh
questions that we've had in this group
so we're very lucky with this
then we have the very interesting in
network aggregation paper
then also
the
information-centric data flow for
distributed computing from dirk
and um we we had well it's actually
ideas but actually there's only one
alessandro because it's a holiday uh is
not going to present i'm going to
present this
it's about an operating system for
distributed applications and in
coin we are very big on thinking that
the internet is moving to be more like a
computer board and if we have a computer
board you need an operating system
uh next slide
then we have the drafts update uh
obviously a research group is not too
about doing only drafts but we do have
very interesting work this is happening
in the drafts with this research group
and we would like to give them a chance
to
talk about the ideas so use cases again
uh to show that there you know there's a
way to use these things transport
protocols because the this has
been an issue once you start putting uh
computing in the system
and then uh the security and privacy and
again a big issue we have a new uh draft
that was submitted by china mobile
and then we'll have
uh we would love to have 10 minutes left
to talk about
future groups and future meetings and we
would like this a little bit to evolve
into
but i think uh the main goal is to have
the papers presented so we're going to
do this
the meat deco
uh please uh
you found us you're here this is good
yeah you found you know if you're there
you found the meat deco which is good
um the live minutes uh it's integrated
to meet techo codim uh the mailing list
uh well if you're here you probably know
about our mailing list
uh if you know if you don't well please
do that and you know we have a ton of
documents
um turk your document expired that needs
an update because it's an rg document we
have two rg documents we have again a
new
new drafts i think this needs an update
because we have the new draft from china
mobile also
and and we have a ton of other
um
drafts that you know are a different
level of uh maturity and essentially
this is something that
we will raise on the list
the idea that we need to do something
about it
the milestones um
we've done a lot of it and and we need
uh
i'll go very fast because i know one
minute over
um we'll go very fast to uh the last
thing which is we need a milestone
review and we'll do it and now we have
the presentations
and the first one is scotch anchor from
berkeley and uh the extensible internet
so uh scott thank you very much for
doing this because it's so early in
california
oh well thank you very much let me share
my screen
i don't see oh here no it's coming i
just clicked on share screen
oh okay good
do you see it again
yes here let me give you permission
is it coming up
okay this
could people see this
yes
okay well thank you very much for
inviting me i'm typically up at this
time so this is not a problem
uh this is uh based on
uh
i'll be talking about the extensible
internet and this is based on a
ccr editorial with 18 authors there's a
much smaller group
that is trying to actually bring this
into reality
and
i gave a talk on this at another
research group and so i apologize for
people who saw that talk adrian and
others
but this will be a
large overlap but the goal of this talk
is really to give a very very brief
overview of extensible internet
just enough to initiate a discussion
both about the merits of the proposal
but also how it relates to the the
charter of this research group
um and obviously more details would be
available in follow-up conversations
so the
core subject of the talk is really about
architectural change so
when i say the word architecture i'm
really referring to the arrangement of
the data plate functionality
uh that is the layers and the basic
functions they've been assigned it's not
about specific protocols ipv4 to ipv6
it's not an architectural change in in
my lexicon nor is it about the control
plane
um
now there's been decades of
architectural research trying to make
changes to the the basic architecture
but i i think it's pretty clear that you
know over 20 works of 20 years of clean
slate architectural research there's no
discernible architectural impact
and the public internet at least in the
eyes of certainly the researchers i
talked to
seems doomed to architectural stagnation
that we've tried it just we don't see
any movement
but that's not what the hyperscalers
think um
the cloud and content providers are
building their own large private ip
based networks they've got many points
of presence
and
what's relevant to this working group
these points of presence apply
extensive in-network services flow
termination caching load balancing and
so forth
and
these services have had a very
significant impact on customer latency
and reliability so they put a lot of
money into it because they actually see
very tangible benefits in their user
community
now this is great for applications users
get much better service but it's bad for
the internet
because the internet is becoming
increasingly balkanized these private
networks are defining their own
in-network services
the public internet which can't do this
kind of interposition is lagging behind
so that we're in a situation
where
the the benefits of in-network
processing have been shown but the
public internet can't do it because it's
not part of the architecture
so rather than these ad hoc and
proprietary designs what we need is to
figure out a way to build this coherent
this in-network processing into a
coherent architecture
and you might say at this point but
didn't you start off by saying the
internet is impossible to change so you
know what's the deal
and so we don't think it's impossible to
change even though i've failed
personally many times in the past but
this talk is about why we we think
there's a chance
and so the rest of the talk much like a
seder is going to be organized around
four questions
why is the internet so hard to change
how can we overcome this barrier
what would this new internet look like
and given the failures of the past why
do we think now is different
and so for the first question
you know you know far better than i do
about the architecture but let me just
review one of the critical aspects which
is that layer 3 has two roles
on the one hand it was designed to allow
layer two networks to interconnect
and therefore by definition it must be
in every router
that makes it almost impossible to make
change that is it's in too many places
it's got to be implemented with very
good price per performance uh so it's
typically baked into hardware so
changing that is impossible now and in
the future i don't see that changing
on the other hand
it provides the service model to host
that is this best effort packet delivery
is exactly what anything you want to do
on a host that's the service that you
see and you have to build on
so it has to support all application
requirements
and these requirements are becoming more
stringent
which is a reason to change the
architecture and that's exactly why
the
these hyperscalers have built out their
own networks to extend
the the architecture for their own
purposes so they can meet these
requirements
but it's this dual role
that prevents change because you have
demands coming from above you have
constraints coming from below and they
are meeting in the middle in a single
layer
so
the network must meet additional
application requirements but the only
layer that can address those
requirements is also the only layer in
the architecture
that can't be changed
so that's the the nub of the problem
that they coincide in the single layer
both the demands and the constraints
so the second question is well how can
we overcome this barrier
and there this is where the extensible
internet proposal comes in it's really
very simple you use the current ip
protocol unchanged you don't do anything
but you do introduce a new layer above
it we call it service layer or l 3.5
and the service layer offers new
in-network services
to host so this is the relevance to this
working group is this network services
this is flow termination and caching
um and and beyond which i will discuss
later and the point is this is really
the architecturally coherent version of
what's going on in these private
networks this is really trying to
articulate how to think about it in a
coherent way
so
why does this solve the problem because
it decouples layer three's two roles
currently it's the interface to both l2
which gives it the constraints and l4
which gives us the demands
and in the ei l3 is still the interface
to l2 it does a perfectly good job of
that but l 3.5 is the interface
to the hosts
and there's no reason for l 3.5 to be in
every router it can be much more
sparsely deployed so it's more easily
deployed and changed
and at the same time there's no reason
for it to be narrow so it can meet a
wide range of needs so we've separated
the constraints from the demands
and so now l 3.5 can meet those demands
while l3 is meeting the constraints or
obeying the constraints
so what would this design look like
you have a service layer sl
it's implemented in what we call service
nodes these are racks of servers
deployed at the network edge and here by
edge i just mean somewhere close to
clients it's not at a particular place
in the network
every host is associated with at least
one and typically several service nodes
for reliability
and the typical communication pattern is
packets go from the source
to the service node associated with the
source
destination
to the destination
all the service layer communication is
tunneled over ip
and the source specifies which service
to invoke using the tunneling protocol
when the packet gets to the service node
and it's this ability for clients to
signal
to the service node what service they
want that allows this to go beyond what
the hyperscalers are doing which needs
to be backwards compatible to actually
we're able to offer services like
multicast where the host needs to know
that you've changed the semantics of
what they've asked
so this is the basic outline of the
design this diagram is just telling you
that no matter whether you're at home or
office or a cellular network or in a car
or in the cloud there's a service node
nearby that will mediate your
communication
now the key point here
is that all these services
that these in-network services that i
talk about are in software
so standards are not detailed written
specifications they're open source code
and there are three necessary software
components on the service node
one is the service modules that is for
every service whether it's multicast
whether it's ddos protection
there is a service module that's
implemented that's running on a service
node
it runs in a standardized execution
environment if this execution
environment has a very simple set of
primitives pack it in out ephemeral
storage stable storage
maybe one or two others but it's a write
once run anywhere environment if you
write your service module to run inside
this environment it can run on any
service node
and then of course in the service node
you need some kind of runtime or
orchestration to scale up scale down
recover from failures
this doesn't need to be standardized you
know there'll be open source versions
available whether it's kubernetes or
openstack or whatever comes next
and when i talk about in-network
services this is limited computation
this is not where you run your machine
learning jobs this is basic packet
forwarding payload processing
simple functions like caching so it's
more complicated than just simple ip
forwarding but it's not general
computation it's fairly limited
and
these service nodes
don't just have to be generic processors
they can have secure enclaves they can
have hardware accelerators but
everything you do has to run on a
commodity processor but if there happens
to be an accelerator that can be used to
to get better performance
now choosing the services this is where
you have some kind of governance process
whether it's itf or something else you
know it's way too early but there's some
body that decides what are the set of
public services and and their
implementations
and
all of these public services are run on
all service nodes that is if you're
offering internet service
so you're supplying a service node you
have to download all of the service
modules that are in the service model
that have been approved
and so this is really the biggest change
to ei meaning that ei brings this
deployment model that is because they're
approved software modules they can be
rolled out they can be deployed there's
no per vendor per domain decision
process of is cisco going to support
this is juniper going to support this
that is 18t or deutsche telekom going to
deploy it it just gets rolled out as
part of the standards process
now so
after all this talk about
you know the process what what are the
services that might get offered
you know the basics like flow
termination and caching and load
balancing which you already know
bring a tremendous amount of value
their support for other delivery models
multicast pub sub redirection qos and
qos here not in the inserv
diffserv conduqs but in the
sd-wan kind of qos that you can pick
paths or different delivery vehicles
that meet your needs
support for security and privacy it's
very easy given this architecture to
build a very good ddos prevention but
also if you have secure enclaves you can
have scalable attestation so that a
client when it's accessing google or
some other hyperscaler
can be assured that it's dealing with a
legitimate
node that is running the current google
software
you can have odns like privacy tour like
privacy
you can also incorporate other
frameworks that are becoming quite
popular they can be running on these
service nodes istio and then oppa for
the policies various telemetry kinds of
frameworks
and then support for radical new
architecture something like icn whether
it's the donor style or the ndn style
this now just becomes a service you just
roll it out you're not replacing all the
routers it's just a piece of software
there'll be host support
uh obviously of course for all the
services and
this just gets rolled out like another
standard
um so it really lowers the bar to this
deployment
and that's why we call it the extensible
internet because once you get this
uh framework set up it makes it very
easy to extend the service model in
rather radical ways
this is the last question i have a
question for you would you like to take
questions from the audience now or at
the end
i've only got a few more slides let me
take it let me finish just because
sounds good i
given the failures
why do we think this might succeed and
there are three reasons one backwards
compatibility ip just continues to be
used if you don't want to change
anything you just use ip
you know maybe 20 years from now that
will go away but when we roll ei out
nothing changes about ip
and the kind of resources you need you
just need the service nodes which could
use edge computing or existing pops they
have these facilities out there i mean
we've talked to some carriers and they
say oh you know we could run this
tomorrow that we've got all these
facilities available obviously there's
more involved but this isn't
talking about you know major
capital outlays
the second reason is uh fear is a great
motivator um you know the internet
architecture has resisted change and
mark handles this great essay on you
know why the internet just barely works
and his reasoning is you know sort of
you know basically why should it change
unless it has to but what's implicit in
his essay is
that there's no alternative that the
internet is just there
there's now an alternative
you know if you talk to the clouds they
they basically think that 10 years from
now the internet will just be the last
mile and they'll be
providing all the networking that's
clearly their vision
so
uh there's now an alternative and so the
internet has a simple choice it either
changes or it shrivels to being a last
mile provider
and we think the extensible internet is
one possible change that will preserve
its role
and the third reason
is that ei is based on a simple
conjecture that in network support for
applications
it's important for current and emerging
apps can be done at service nodes rather
than each router can be done in software
not in hardware
and the point is the private networks
have proven every aspect of this
conjecture they're up in the running
they're running at scale they're running
with real traffic at an unimaginable
scale so
ei is really the architecturally
co-version of what of the approach these
private networks have already proven to
work
so that's why we think it might succeed
so my last real slide is you know where
are we we built a prototype really
murphy mccauley who has built the
prototype while teaching four classes a
week so progress has been a little
slower but
you know we want to finish development
which should be in a couple of months
deploy it on fabric and other test beds
engage the community by providing this
test but we say if you have a new
service we can deploy it if you want to
write applications on top of these
services like pub sub or whatever you
can do that too
uh continuing our discussions with
industry and we'd love to have your
participation you here meaning as
individuals as a research group or the
broader community with that
thank you and i'll take your questions
and eve why don't you kick it off
sure um actually i wanted to just give
adrian uh the opportunity to uh
he's first in queue and then there were
some interesting questions in the chat
that um i encourage people who wrote
them to get in line to queue up as well
adrian
thank you eve um and thank you scott for
for this um
as you said the second time i've sort of
heard this and and finally it's sinking
in a little bit um my question which um
draws on some of the the stuff in the
chat is about
um the layering here and in particular
the relationship with with transport
protocols so in in your very simple
example of uh source
snsn dest um
would the would you see the transport
protocol running
um end to end so source to destination
uh or um
would you imagine that those transport
connections are terminated and restarted
at the sn's
so there will definitely be an
end-to-end reliability layer
uh
and
because for reliability we want the
failure of a service node to be no more
serious than the failure
of a router today so they'll definitely
be end to end whether the pipe that goes
we view that ip is providing a pipe uh
whether the the pipe that goes between
these two implement some kind of
reliability is
uh
an open question
but but it's not mandated by the
architecture the essential um
transport is end to end where congestion
control is done there's a much more
complicated question
right because i think i think this sort
of factors into things like uh
um transport layer encryption as well uh
and whether the sms are able to access
the data to do anything unless those
transport sessions um
are terminated and restarted and this is
kind of making me wonder i i don't
dispute at all the uh all your points
about needing to introduce
some additional layering to to get the
development and i'm just wondering
whether this is really go should go in
at layer 4.5 rather than at 3.5 but i'll
let others talk
well i actually can i i mean this is a
very active area of investigation for us
and our current thinking is
that the end to end
first of all all the pipes will be
encrypted at the low level uh but but
that's trivial
but and service node to service node
pipes but at the end-to-end transport
layer
there will be encryption but i we want
to have an option for the endpoints to
say
here are the parts that we are willing
to let the intermediate node see
versus here are the parts that they
can't and so they can decide like they
want to take care of uh
you know take advantage of caching then
they might expose certain aspects but if
they want to keep certain material
private they don't and so we want to
give that leave that flexibility to the
application itself
does that make any sense adrian
i yeah thank you and i i kind of take
that as um this needs to be thought
about more and and nailed down the
details
right but what i would say is i don't
think there's a single answer that is
mandated
but there has to be some flexibility
okay um why don't we uh dirk trossen
you're next in the queue
yes uh thanks thanks scott for for the
presentation um similar to adrian some
things that i heard again
just slowly sang in and there was one
issue that i stumbled across which is
the
sn must implement public services we
need to agree somewhere um
possibly in the itf by governance
isn't that a
barrier to entry though i'm i'm not
really quite understanding the reason
for doing so because also the culture
asks the right question who has the
incentive to really
deploy this but if i'm if i have to ramp
up my sn deployment by really
essentially running any public service
over it
isn't it preventing me for just quickly
roll out my
owner's end where all i want to do is
run my service on it because it's a low
barrier to entry
that our point is that once you support
the execution environment
uh
implementing these other services
is simple it it does require extra
resources but if you don't make it
uniform then the internet
you know the beauty of the growth of the
internet is you knew wherever you
plugged in you had a set of services you
could depend on
if we now go to the space of ip options
which you know is no fun
that's not going to work and so that
really is critical to this that you can
build an application that relies on a
public service
and that will be available wherever the
user is
so that that's critical part of the
proposal
and given that it's
not about changing equipment it's just
about the scaling of your
uh service nodes
we think there's a chance that that's
gonna
take off
so so so maybe i misunderstood your your
slide then so you're saying because of
the um standardized execution
environment
you can run any of the public services
on any of these ends that have been
deployed but i don't so if somebody
comes and wants to run a public service
on my execution environment or my sn
it will just simply run because it's a
standardized execution environment
doesn't mean i have to provide it
as a catalog of possible services i i i
could run on mine
somebody can just load the app onto mys
and then it just runs
no ah no it is
the
let's say it's the itf the iatf decides
what the standard services are every
service node that claims it's supporting
the internet has to run all the services
you know it's like once it's
standardized within two months it must
be up and running that's that's just the
rule so it's not like somebody asks you
to do it
if you're either a cloud who's
supporting this or a carrier who's
supporting this
that's the rule that it just
automatically updates
okay
thanks
dave iran
scott just talk for a second about what
you think the service composition model
is for this
that's the service model composition
bottle
uh what do we have for your attention
no no no what i mean is we we
specifically
do not allow users to arbitrarily
compose services
that there will be
sort of
sets of approved compositions that work
because we
we think it is an impossible
way to provide a general rule for what
can compose with what
um
so yeah that that is one of the things
that if you wanna you can't just say
well i want services 28 and 37
because
you know what if it's some security
measure that's point to point and the
other one is a multicast
so that we we actually sort of
proactively say that kind of
linking
is done at the definition of the
services
level
not at the user
linking them together so there might be
like a
particular stack that says okay you're
going to get an ip-like service and on
top of it you're going to get this kind
of
transport service and on top of that
there's going to be this kind of ddos
prevention
and you know whatever
as a a set of what we might think of
individual features
but it'll be a single service so that
you don't have to
manually compose things and and the
market will show us what
you know how that rolls out but we
really
sort of uh
discretion is the better part of valor
decided that taking on general
composability was going to be a losing
battle so then one quick follow on which
is okay so from the point of view of the
user they see
um
you know a composed service as what what
they talk to the service node about what
about the internal
communication among uh services
is this
some sort of private interconnect is it
part of the architecture is it something
like service chaining or vnfs that we
see today that are
so messy
um
any thoughts
yeah so in our current implementation
what we would do
is we would
say well if this is the composition then
we would have that
ball of code i mean take those several
different pieces of code
merge them together
and then
have them run as a single service module
so that we've actually made sure that
these code that the code bases work
together
and and so we're not doing
enough chaining
it is actually we decide to put it
we won't be using vms probably but if we
were we would put it in a single vm
so that it's a single coherent piece
rather than dealing with the nightmare
of service changing
in these clusters great thanks
king would you like to go
you're next
always and it looks it looks like an
interesting topic to me
and
it also reminded me of two things the
first one is service function channing
sfc and the next one is sd1
so uh i do see that these two uh jose
service has the same or similar uh
model
of this i'll say ei
network
so what's the difference or any relation
between the sfc and s8 and sd1
and ei
yeah
so i i think
for
uh
both of them it is the extensibility
um
so for service chaining
you tell it to go through various boxes
but it's not the network is not making
you a promise of i will deliver
multicast packets for you
it is go through this box this box can
do something but but um
service chaining doesn't give you any
global service definition
that that's your job you have to sort of
you know if you say you go through a
firewall and then go to this and go
through that
you're the one figuring out eventually
what what that's giving you so i think
that's the difference
so something like ddos prevention
um
that
you know we're architecting it
to provide it's a service-wide thing
it's not just a single box it's not just
a scrubbing box so that's what i think
that the key difference is i don't know
whether that helps
so so yeah i may need to read more of
the details yep
and there's a pointer to the paper um i
think it's it's got uh
could confirm i think it's an is it an
april uh ccr paper yeah
yeah and uh but we have a pointer in the
agenda
um and slides and um i see there's one
other person who's joined the queue tng
oh yes uh hey scott it's a good
presentation here ever one thing to ask
about your ei here you know it's running
on the ip and the ip normally has some
protocols to communicate among all the
entities
so for your ei as a 3.5 so how does one
ei node in your term
to communicate with others or will you
configure or were you
through some random no not run some
centralized controller
those type of things in that case well
i don't know whether what the difference
from the like uh icn model something
like that thank you
ah so yes we will have some kind of
discovery
um
process for service nodes to discover
each other but
if you want to have an sdn like control
for a domain
to have the service nodes know about
each other that would be fine so the
control plane we i was completely silent
on the control plane for this we're open
to
a wide variety of how you're going to
manage your domain
obviously a
sdn like approach
you know for
knowing where all the service nodes are
and
telling them how to reach each other
would be very easy to do and probably
the right approach
thank you
it's everybody in the queue but i wonder
i know there's a very um
uh thriving uh conversation going on
back and forth on the chat is there
anybody from there who would like to um
introduce i think i think we we're
getting so late eve uh
we're we need to send this to to the to
the chat
and uh offline to the list um because
we're already
sounds fine scott thank you so much for
coming in and um initiating the
discussion about this no doubt there
will be further conversation
so thank you very much okay thank you
all and and please feel free to contact
me if uh you know whatever is going on
in the chat let me know if there's
anything i can help with
thanks very much and you have access to
the chat so you can peruse what's been
stated there and the and the chat
actually gets posted after the fact okay
when say um
over to you
you're our next presenter
here we
we viewed our working data center so we
have the flexibility to customize
everything
and it's different from the internet
i'm happy to introduce our work in
network application for multi-tenant
learning so this is a joint work from
colleagues from chiang mai university
and the university of wisconsin medicine
[Music]
machine learning algorithms is used in
various scenarios such as uh natural
light reprocessing uh computer reading
so with the increasing size of the data
set and the model so the algorithm is
implemented as a as a distributed system
so the ps architecture is a typical
architecture that can support this kind
of distributed
system
in the ps architecture the data set is
partitioned and put on multiple workers
so in in the iteration
initiation of the algorithm
each worker would compute the gradients
all workers gradients
are aggregated and
used to update the model random
algorithm get into the next study
iteration
in the ps architecture
all workers gradients
are sent to us to a parameter server get
aggregated and the result is sent back
to each worker
so
this kind of or many-to-one transmission
could possibly
cause put on that in the transmission so
they are studying showing that the
performance degradation of such kind
of uh such kind of bottleneck
so recently the chain or network
competition provide an opportunity to
solve this problem
the programmable switches offer in
intrinsic packet processing so the
switch pipeline has registers which can
store the network states and the user
specified programs can be loaded to
customize the packet processing
so there is opportunity to move the
gradient
aggregation into the network which can
reduce the communication and
consequently the overall chain time
there exists there is an existing work
that applies in network of
aggregation to uh to distributed chain
html
this work target a single chart a single
rack setting so there is a wrap connect
multiple workers so the switch is
offload the ps is offloaded to the
switch
so the workers gradients are aggregated
in the switch
to support micro jobs the switch
resource is statically partitioned and
assigned to each job
so we think this uh network aggregation
can be further improved
uh because in
in much in in motor training the
algorithm takes uh takes efforts to
compute and communicate each iteration
so for static allocation when the job is
in um is in competition time this switch
memory would be a email would be a list
and
this design assumes the topology is a
star topology with a switch in the
middle connecting multiple workers so
it should be extended to multi
multi-rack setting
um for example in bird training there
are tens or hundreds of nodes which
cannot be put into a single rack
and in addition uh static partition add
complexity to integrate the
switch memory
allocation with the control plane
so we propose our solution with three
key goals uh the first goal is we should
uh
maximumly uh
you use the network condition for
performance gain on targeting the
production network
we should the solution should support
multiple simultaneous job change
efficiently and it should also support a
multi-rack quality
we designed our solution
atp
short for aggregation transmission
protocol
with the multi-tenant and multi-rack
as the requirements and we additionally
saw extra problems with which can
further improve the performance
so in adp the switch memory is organized
as a real-world details
then each job has a job id with multiple
workers and each worker has a sequence
each worker's gradient is organized as a
sequence of packets
so
to support multiple tenants we do not
uh statically partition the switch
memory instead we organize it as a whole
array as a as a shared resource pool
then
therefore for aggregation uh each packet
is randomly hashed to a unit aggregator
so
the
assignment use a hash function to hash
the job id and sequence number so for
four packets from one job with the same
sequence number but from different
workers they would be hashed to the same
position and get a repeated there
so the the vision result is sent to the
ps then the ps uh return the result to
the switch
it would do two things
first it would de-allocate the switch
memory
then the packets are
is multicast back to
all the workers
so we also overcome to or overcome two
challenges first
because the switch the aggregator
assignment is decentralized it's
possible to to have hash clearance
uh for example um
job tools gradient uh packet is a is a
assigned uh it's hashtag keeper which is
occupied by another job job three in
this case uh all the packets would pass
through the switch and arrive at the on
the ps the ps do the aggregation and
send the result back to the switch
the aggregator is not the allocated part
of the result is sent back to the
workers
so the switch service agreement service
is the best ever and the ps provides a
fallback
to handle the corner cases
there is another case
of inconsistency
or
membership inconsistency it causes
incomplete aggregation
for example
the first packet is sent to a aggregator
which is reserved by drop three
then
this packet it passes through passes
through to the ps
but at this time job3 completes its
application and deallocated the switch
memory the grid guitar the remaining
package
is sent to the
aggregator and the aggregated there so
both the switch and the ps uh have a
partial result they are waiting for each
other this
is a deadlock and uh they are
what's worse is that there is no return
packet of results to dialogue this
switch memory
causing a memory leak problem
so we design a re-transmission antenna
and host with the duplication
in the switch
so for for packet a uh it has that uh it
is a stock under the switch and the ps
but it's
uh it's a following package uh may be
maybe successfully aggregated and
returned so
if the sender observed reduplicated the
ack the result packet
it would re-transmit the missing
the packet that is missing the result
it will all workers would retransmit a
so um
the the regulator is a has a bitmap to
track which worker has already
participated the aggregation so a2 to a
n would not be aggregated twice it would
be
duplicated and the a1 is added to the
partial results so we get a complete
result which is sent to the ps and the
reply back
so with this design we have a uh correct
protocol
that can guarantee the um the
correctness
uh to support microreact aggregation uh
we need a aggregation hierarchy in the
topology
ideally this
aggregation hierarchy can be uh can be
of many levels um we consider the data
center topology
in the data center topology the core
network has multiple passes and it uses
non-deterministic locking so we
it's not easy for us to pre-compute the
hierarchy in the topology so we only
implement the objection in the course
torque switches because there are we
points that the
uh gradient packets
must pass
must pass must traverse
currently we have a two level
aggregation design
so uh all the packets would aggregate at
the walkers tour first then they are
sent to the ps4 and the second level
aggregation is happening at the ps4 the
final result is send it to the ps
um
so in this uh in this
multiple racks part we also overcome
another challenge because uh um
the higher level switch this is the
hierarch aggregation hierarchy or the
previous uh in the paris page so uh in
each of the guitar we have a big map
which uh where each b that he knows uh i
always children um but so there is one
bit of four in the switch two which
indicated the uh switch to zero but the
one meter here cannot denote the all the
possible aggregations these always
work because there are two workers there
are four possible agreements these
um so we overcome this challenge uh that
by falling back to the ps we use the one
in the higher level switch to denote the
successful
aggregation of the whole
sub tree
and in all other cases we regard it as a
feeder and send it to the ps for back to
the ps processing
um
so uh the previous design also overcome
other challenge
other challenges on our reliability
when the the re-transmission with the
duplication can also handle the packet
loss correctly and uh one pack loss
happens in the host of the
re-transmitter and
the bitmap in the switch can guarantee
there is exactly wax application
and we also redesigned the congestion
control uh the essential problem is
what should be the congestion signal
because some many packets are consumed
in the switch so they do not have round
sweep time so there is no rtt we use the
ecl as the congestion signal use eimd
for congestion control
and
on the in the host the switch can only
compute on integrals uh
it does not support floating point
arithmetic so we do compensation uh we
scale with scale the float point block
points two integers bioscanning factor
and uh
this because we skills uh the floating
numbers it's possible to have overflow
at the switch uh to handle this problem
we just use the fallback mechanism we
reuse the fallback magnesium when switch
detect
detects uh
our flow
overflow
the then host will fall back to the ps
aggregation with the floating part of
arithmetic
so we implemented the uh user space
networking stack
on hosts and we implemented a network of
rehab services in a switch
so in the evaluation we have nice
servers so uh little automatic workers
and one and the ps we compare atp with
other piece like pictures such as ps
architecture with different networking
stack and the ring or reduced
architecture with different steps
we use things rupert and time accuracy
as the method
we run workloads of
models in image imagenet contest
for a single job we showed our
performance of a single drop
so we run different models and measure
the chinese rupees we compare different
architectures
in each group
we have three observations
first
atp in all model trim etpr performs
other approaches
sometimes it's the performance skin is
very significant
atp can benefit the network intensive uh
workloads more than the
competition intensive workloads
and comparing atp
with the ring or reduce with hardware
acceleration
atp
is slightly better than ring or reduce
but more importantly it only uses half
of the batteries that we already use
then we show the performance of multiple
jobs uh we compare atp with the static
memory allocation in a static approach
we evenly partition the solution
are you close to conclusion
yes so thank you
thank you yeah
okay so we tune the switch memory for
three jobs and uh get that
throughput the peak throughput then we
reduce the memory to cause contentions
we can see dynamic allocation
degrees more greasefully than statical
approach
okay
there are more evaluations
so in atp we co-designed the host and
the switch logic the switch to service
security service is best effort it has
dynamic resource allocation
the host networking stack
has fallback mechanisms for correctness
guarantee and also reliability and
congestion control
to ml jobs such a design can provide
performance skill and correctness and we
achieve our goal of multi-tenant but to
draw support
um so there is takeaway so usually when
we
do a network competition usually we can
get a very significant performance scan
switch computes much faster than a
server
but correctness guarantee is very
difficult because the network
competition introduces new schematic
into the network for example practice
can be consumed
instead of lost then hosts need to
distinguish these cases
and usually we do switch and host the
co-design
so we can get both credits and perform
skin so for different applications we
can
we can make different designs
that's all about my thought i'm happy
for questions
thank you very much for this um
i think we um
are you know we're
it was great the first discussions were
great so we're losing a little bit on
time uh maybe we can send all the
questions to your paper uh either on the
chat or on the mailing list
thank you very much for this uh and dirk
you're next
yeah uh i need to stop
okay let me see how i can
get to my slides so i'm
trying to use to show the slides that
are uploaded to the data tracker
[Music]
do you have to put them up or how does
it work again
all right it says no slides available
you know what in the case let me do
screen sharing
here you go
thank you
you see my slice okay great
okay yeah thanks for inviting me it's uh
great being with you again um if only
ritual but um
let
me um tell you about some some recent
work um
on a system that we call information
centric data flow that
is a product of our
picollo research project that
investigates
there are new ways for
integrating computing and networking
so in some sense this could be seen as a
customer to a system like i'm the one
that that's got um talked about
um
so let's see and this is john worked
with my students laura alvardani and tm
reindeers
so in coin
so far um
in my view we have mainly been
discussing like two strengths of
of work so like one is coming from like
data plane probability
and then seeing how this could be put to
you know a useful purpose for um you
know having distributed applications and
improving their performance and so on
maybe also
evolving some protocols to support
certain use cases better
um the other strand
you could say is coming but from the
distributed computing um where we say
okay what can we learn from this will be
computing and how does it
affect our view on networking and maybe
then re-imagine the relationship and
in the end have more programmable
systems also like the ones that um scott
talked about
and so i think the the like the thesis
of this group in in general is
maybe is there some confluence at the
end
of these two strains
so this work here is more on the on the
lower strand here and so this is a paper
that we presented
at the
acm icn conference this year and there's
also an associated demo um
and so i hope to
get you interested in this and then you
can i invite you to check out the paper
and the demo video um after this
so in distributed computing um we know
that there are many different types of
interactions so like
simple message passing remote method
indication data sets implementation key
radio stores and so on
and
so
i think some itfs ago
we presented
a system that we called compute first
networking
that was essentially
a um yeah too incomplete really general
distributed computing system um
based on an icn
um today i want to talk about a
like competitively simple abstraction so
data flow which is really a
structured um
direct direct and basically graph based
uh
data processing approach
where you have a system um say nodes in
the in the network
and um like
data objects that are sourced um at some
some endpoint or in some node
trigger computation and other nodes
which then you know
leads to new designs that trigger
computation somewhere else
and so this deck here
can
be implemented in different ways
so you could say because this model is
so simple um
and so if your application semantics
allow it you could also say you want to
parallelize the execution by opening up
a second
subgraph here
and um then just run everything faster
if you have the resources for example
so what you have is um something like a
um like the the
data flow specification
um that could be um you know laid out in
the network in in different ways uh
different levels of parallelism and so
on so that so the semantics in this case
here in this like word count example
would be that um you split the input
here in this text-to-lines box
but you can also have other use cases
where you
you know reuse the same
input
for different types of computation of
course
so some some concepts so data flow can
this fundamental paradigm can be used to
implement batch as well as um stream
processing
so in steam processing you you
like conceptually you look at each data
object independently in an unbounded
stream of data
in batch processing you group data and
typically the systems allow you to um
you know implement groupings
dynamically so based on some predicate
or some
time window specification and so on
so um windowing is a
common concept here that
allows this grouping and
slicing
and this can also lead to situations
where you have something like a
predicate
that allows you to
um
put like one
data object into like multiple windows
for like consumption by by different
functions for example
but you can also
split this up in in different ways
time is an important concept
so you can imagine that the whole system
is has to be kind of elastic so you have
often asynchronous
data production
you can't really predict
the processing transport delays and so
on
and typically what you try to achieve is
that you match
the production rate with
the input rate
and
so the task of a data flow system then
is to
adjust the processing
graph to
the application
requirements and the data production
rate and you can you can see there's all
like
some kind of variable uh performance and
systems can be compared how well they
maybe keep up with the offered load
perhaps
there are a couple of really
widely used implementations so apache
beam is
basically the unified programming model
that many
data from invitations use um so
sometimes they're called
runners so you may have heard about
apache flink um spark of course um
google cloud dataflow is a product
and so on
and the picture here on the right hand
side
um depicts the architecture of a system
i think it's probably inspired by flink
um where you
um on the bottom here you you see the
the notes so these this uh what is
called task manager here so this could
be something like a
a compute node in your network which is
offering
several slots for computation and um
this like the job manager on the top
right here
is kind of orchestrating this whole
system so it's kind of
having an overview
about the available slots
and is responsible for allocating
um tasks for for certain jobs
and then also managing the connectivity
between those those jobs
and
so in flink in particular of course
performance is is also an important
topic
so flink just had their annual flink
forward conference recently and there
was quite a bit of
work on you know trying to reduce buffer
upload and improving in elasticity and
so on
so
fundamentally this is not so easy
because for example flink
is
really using a connection based approach
to connect these uh task managers and so
it's not going into the tasks but really
the the nodes if you like
and so these are like tunnels and so the
flink
task manager is basically tunneling all
the um or configuring the tunneling of
all the task communication inside um
these connections
and of course this needs um some some um
yeah control um so like credit based
schemes for example uh to reduce um
buffer load or our
queue sizes and so on
um so fundamentally um this is not a
trivial task so
you've been looking at this we find that
well these overlays do not match the
inherent logic of
like processing immutable data objects
very well so as i um
presented the data is really locked into
connections and these are like virtual
channels between hosts
and you always need this orchestrator
checking the resources and making the
task relationships and so on
and
so you treat the network as a black box
and then you tunnel the the task
communication inside
virtual channels
and this makes it um yeah difficult to
have a really agile
you know matching of
like your compute performance with the
network performance
and
having also really responsive systems in
the end you don't you have you don't
have this full visibility of both the
computing and the networking resources
now in the system i wanted to um talk
about today and so we call this ice flow
information senior data flow um we
assume that we have a
network of nodes and in in icn we we
name everything
so the assumption here that is that we
have a
network of named nodes
and there would be some routing
infrastructure
that allows us to
discover them and
forward forward
interest packets and data packets in the
system
and um so on top of this of these nodes
we would instantiate functions also with
a certain
naming convention
they would also be announced in this
routing system and so we'll be able to
construct compute graphs and
what we do in this system here is that
we are kind of not establishing
connections to
functions or to to nodes
we are actually just asking for input
data and so when there is new input data
we this triggers computation at the like
downstream function and so on in this
system we are able to for example you
know split up the computation as i
showed before but also um have something
like like like a multicast um system
where you can have reuse the same data
item
in like icn
idiomatic way
quite efficiently
so in ice flows we just talk about names
for the infrastructure and for for the
actors in the system
and the computation of the actors
they return name data object with the
usual icn properties so they are
immutable they can be cached and they
can be authenticated
encrypted and so on
and um so the interesting challenge is
here is that we have asynchronous data
production so we have to know when data
is available so like push semantics
which is typically not idiomatic in icn
and um then you have to think about flow
control so how do you couple consumers
and producers um
and then
in the icn system typically you you
publish data that means you make data
available
um so one challenge here is that you
also have to know when the data has been
consumed which normally you you don't
really know
um
because requests can be answered by
caches and and so on so there needs to
be a system like basically implementing
a bit of tighter coupling um as well
so
the system yeah has a certain naming
convention um where we named the
application the data flow actors and
then the
produce data objects um
um that the functions produce and with
that we are able to to set up the system
and um so this this um tasks of um you
know making data available and learning
about new data
we are using an icn technology called
dataset synchronization for that
where
so logically the producers produce data
under a known prefix and consumers can
subscribe to that prefix and then they
would learn
um when there is new data under that
prefix and then they can decide okay i'm
interested in text to lines object one
and then i can fetch that
so um there are implementations of this
concept like psync in in icn uh which in
the end which you may have heard about
um
and
so
that means um so in the on the like very
low layer this that means consumers
have to um kind of send update
interests uh to learn about new names uh
perfectly
and then um from an application
perspective it's quite a convenient
interface so it's a bit like reactive
programming so you just get notified
when something um you know
shows up that you are interested in
um
we implemented a few additions to make
the system yeah a bit more scalable
like to have like less updates so we
have a grouping concept
where we group data objects into windows
and we're actually just publishing
these windows so uh and so we're using
icn manifests uh um for that
and so there's like a like a a two level
inter indirection um scheme scheme here
um
that
makes that makes the whole system more
efficient and a bit more scalable
um
i'm almost done and so in addition to
the
data flow communication we also need to
share some
you know runtime information and
configuration information so what is the
static flow graph what is the actual
dynamic flow graph
um what are
available compute slots in the system
and so on
but also
implementing this loose coupling between
consumers and producers so we have
um conceived something that like what we
call consumer reports where basically we
publish
what windows have been processed by each
consumer
and so this is um also a um like a
organized data structure in in icn way
and we also use this
data set synchronization scheme
to share this information
okay
just very quickly
so this approach allows us to
deal with
congestion control and um
yeah
like a proper receive window
configuration in a different way so we
can really adapt
like the interest rate for example to
our actual processing speed so avoiding
that we asked for too much data we
cannot
process in in real time
and observing the performance of my
downstream
consumers um could be a trigger for an
upstream producer to initiate
scaling out and so by creating a new
subgraph so if i'm constantly realizing
that my
downstream cannot keep up
so this is the the trigger that we can
scale the system
so there's a demo on this
please check it out
and yeah wrapping up
so
these data flow systems are really
important they're driving many many data
science applications
today and
you can see also more coming up
so in the itf this week there
was a buff on a project called ppm
that is also using similar similar
concepts
the current systems are quite limited
because of their say overlay approach so
centralized orchestration limited data
sharing and we found this icn approach
quite promising
so
this uh data sensing synchronization
approach
um
works reasonably well um but um to be
honest we are currently looking um a lot
into performance
optimizations for that so there's a lot
to do in reducing the overhead
and so on
um
this system would basically need
additional infrastructure so like a
name-based routing infrastructure for
example and there are solutions for that
that
in principally principal work
but
maybe in terms of research
this system could also be supported
perhaps better by a routing system that
gives you more information so
for example
[Music]
resource education information directly
and not only reachability information
and so for coin we think this could be
an example for
like new protocol work so i'm not saying
that this is the the best way of doing
this so this is has to be something that
you know ends up in a protocol spec but
it's it's an interesting example so how
you can break up overlays and leverage
systems like icn to do that
and so today i talked about data flow
but
you can imagine that other
interaction classes could be promising
as well so other systems may be like
kafka like published broker systems and
so on
with that thanks for your attention
are there any questions
thank you so much dirk um
that was super interesting and um i just
want to point people to there's the you
know icn
paper and demo and um i also wanted to
kind of go back to one
um presentation and remind people that
his uh presentation and paper are
available from nsdi21
um so uh i think in the interest of time
we will um go forward in the program we
had segmented the program into
you know papers that have been published
elsewhere and that's been really
fruitful thank you all
uh for your presentations uh the next
section is gonna be brief uh it's sort
of new ideas section
um and then we're gonna get to the
drafts
um and
draft updates and then then a new draft
so with that i think i'll hand over the
floor to marie jose
who's going to introduce the moda ideas
on behalf of her
colleagues
um yeah um i hope my screen oh my god
what is this
and i'm gonna try the timer
clock yeah but i i have the the great
the great
screen problem of um miteko
yes
if i can fix this
why why am i seeing all this
it's supposed to be just the
powerpoint
uh did you
there you go
if you could put that into the display
uh we did for a moment there
oh okay so let me go back into
powerpoint you can also select a
specific screen
versus the your entire there you go well
i
that's what i can't find
oh um
oh my god
let me stop this it's crazy
um
i i cannot find the thing to choose only
one part of the screen
i see
uh
okay
i'm gonna give it one last shot
and then i can and then i can download
in the interim
yeah can you okay you seem to be better
at this than me uh i i'm sorry i'm sorry
i
i know there's a way of doing only the
part of the slide but i can't find
the button
maybe if i could maybe if i close my oh
my no i can't close all my
my screens
yeah you should try it i'm sorry people
i can start talking anyway so that we
don't spend too much time
um
the presentation is about moda it's it's
a currently a a proposal that's been put
together by a large group of people
um and it's a european wide project and
the idea started from essentially
a lot of us
actually a lot of people on the moda
team or uh will be when we once we see
the slides uh are very familiar to uh
this group because a lot of them are
involved and
one of the ideas oh
my slides are coming thank you thank you
so much eve
um
and the the id and we can go directly to
the first slide if when it's you can go
to the next slide if please
okay just bring it in um presentation
yeah in mode yeah
so the idea started from this uh a lot
of us who work in iot
um
have a big problem is and i think it was
interesting that a little bit of that
the scot presentation touched it a
little bit everything is very
verticalized everything is fragmented
and for essentially in iot what people
do is they put a sensor somewhere they
put a gateway in they connect to the
cloud and they claim that the problem is
solved the problem is not solved because
the minute that you want to start having
uh
applications and services and artificial
intelligence that cover uh more than one
thing you you're in you're in your
agriculture well you may want to take
decisions that are based on the market
but then how does that work when you
need to det you need for that to know or
how much disease do you have in your
farm or maybe
what's the building temperature because
that will increase or decrease depending
on you know the time of year or the time
of day and it will increa increase or
decrease your production which yeah will
go back to your your modeling of
decision and now you would the minute
you do that well you have people
involved you have a ton of different
um
systems that don't talk to one another
next
it's like
let's see if i can
so oops
so
essentially in this fragmented
environment the application development
has very very important pain points so
all these fragmented systems that
require overlays multiple gateways
different cloud applications the
different cloud providers that don't
talk to one another
and
there's issues always of that in
security and privacy because there's
data privacy there's digital sovereignty
there's multiple customers who are
involved and it creates a big problem at
the same time
in this group coin
we started to think that
the internet paradigm is much more than
is much more like a computer board than
a telephone network and if we have a
computer board then we need an operating
system and the extra cloud
view
that we have in moda where there's
computing inside different nodes that
actually collaborate with one another
at different levels in the network is
one
um
realization of this vision and eve
you're the one who said that the data is
the fuel of the 21st century and in such
an environment also for iot and for all
these distributed systems
data valorization is key
i think
scott mentioned that you know you you
use open source approaches and this is
exactly what we want to do because in
fact it is not the algorithms or the
software that's worth and the words a
lot it's actually the data itself and so
we want to make sure that we can
actually
maximize data valorization by acting it
on it inside the network next slide
so what is moda it's the operating
system for a new distributed internet i
hope scott are you still on maybe it's
the operating system for the extensible
internet
it provides an infrastructure that
allows applications to be
um easily developed
and it has a lot of things that were
discussed in
in coin and almost uh we have almost uh
one one draft per each each topics here
discovery services communications and
publish subscribe uh we haven't talked a
lot about semantic integration but our
uh our friends and things to things have
done it a lot um the implementation of
common use functionalities that we need
uh including you know forwarding and and
forwarding to different cpus and
forwarding not across
just uh layer three but for functional
french
implementation of forwarding based on
name and so there's a link there to icn
and
ndn
and also obviously in moda what we want
to have going back to the pain points we
would like to have apis and tools
for writing class across though to
running code across those uh multiple
terrorists oh my god here's a typo
heterogeneous nodes
uh inside the network
next slide
um so
the format didn't work very well here uh
the main mode of functionality i don't
want to go uh i'll go fast because i
don't want to go into everything this
but obviously we want to do some
orchestration there was discussion
about orchestration before but we feel
that we can actually look into this
and um
again on device computing over a trojan
system we want to have
if we can
as much as possible reusability and
that's actually a problem on those
verticalized applications is if you
change vendor or if you change supplier
your system doesn't work anymore because
they use different protocols different
semantics different everything
you would like to have modularity as a
design choice i usually when i teach my
class on distributed systems i talk
about the lego blue brick approach so
that you know we want to have a lot of
lego bricks and we connect them when we
need them and we don't use
them when we can't or when we
uh we won't and actually also in iot
systems it's important because a lot of
times you have limited resources
um
you want to be able to
manage the the network processing units
themselves so the in-network computation
uh that allows uh the packets and the
information i would think i would speak
more of information in this case uh to
be properly managed and properly uh sent
to the right interfaces and the right
end devices and end system
and obviously we want to support data
and intelligence services um
more and more data driven until it is is
actually the basic of a lot of
networking uh last year with andy
schuster we did a study for the nsf on
the future of broadband and actually the
conclusion was that everybody who does
broadband wants data so data driven made
required to have
new new
features inside moda and inside the
network itself and of course
there's there's ai that is not only in
the applications but more and more in
the network in terms of network
management
and even uh management of
loads inside data centers and elsewhere
next slide i think it's almost the last
one
um yeah i think the previous slide is an
overview of of what it looks like but
the picture is not very good so let's we
can skip it
um and um
the link to the coin rg well actually um
again it's not just that there's a lot
of people involved in mode that are also
members of this community is actually
there's a lot of common research topics
i mentioned discovery
uh we would like to discover storage
function from you know functional
functions and and computation
uh so functional discovery storage
discovery computation discovery we would
like more and more i think both and
that's actually since i know i have two
hats here so i can say as i as now as
maybe as a current chair that
distributed distractions uh and
protocols are also very important to
both groups they centralize security and
trust uh obviously important and
there is going to be a
draft update later
in this talk about security but it's
also an important thing when you start
distributed systems federated learning
we haven't really addressed that a lot
in coin
but it is something that we could look
at because federated learning needs
some form of in-network
maybe not pure computation but at least
uh some form of
um
trending and and connections and
orchestration and obviously there's all
the use cases and actually the people
right after me will talk about use cases
so i won't go there so this was this was
a very short presentation this is moda
we know that this is right now being
proposed we've been evaluated we don't
know if it's going to go through but i
think the team
um and i'd like to really acknowledge uh
the architecture team that did this and
a few of them are on the call right now
this was an incredible effort this was
an incredible fun thing to do and we're
thinking that maybe
we want to continue the work inside this
community and outside thank you
thank you so much marie jose um there is
a question on the chat asking if there
are any pointers that you or others uh
can share
um that would help people read more
about or if there's a website for
example so um in the interest of trying
to
take that to the list
or the chat yeah i will yeah i will um
um
i will see what we can share uh i i see
this is from from daniel king um i will
see where we can share i'll ask um the
the
the proposal management which i was not
one of so thank you daniel for this
question and i will ask thank you
okay it looks like um
the use cases uh
presentation is next we're into the um
some draft updates and i'm going to ask
if folks could please uh shorten their
presentations
to uh eight minutes each just to kind of
reclaim a little bit of
try time
so let's see oh and actually you know
what i i see that uh um i did take the
advice of those on the chat window to
uh load things into
um
mid echo which i hadn't done before uh
so i admit user error on my part um it
says okay so do you know how to request
the slides looks like you've already
done that
ask to share the slides perfect
thank you
so that looks good
perfect yes thank you for helping me out
yeah so hi everyone i'm ike and i'm here
on behalf of all the co-authors now for
the use cases draft just giving you a
bit of uh update what we've done since
the last iteration
um so the first thing you can already
see on the on this slide so we've a
couple of new co-authors so xavier david
and miguel have joined us
um apart from that let me first give uh
or remind you again of the purpose of
this draft so the uh in our coin charter
we have this second item where we want
to do research on use case driven
requirements analysis and where we also
want to identify potential benefits to
these networks from in-network compute
functionality
and this is kind of what we're trying to
do with this draft now so until now it
was rather loose collection of use cases
so stemming from the industrial ones uh
right in the beginning
um and yeah now we've quite a few of
them uh and what we're now currently
trying to do is actually go more towards
providing input to the second
charter item that we have there
changes in a nutshell since the last
iteration so first of all we have
regrouped the use cases so from the
historically grown structure to the one
that we have right now so we thought of
four ways how we could think about the
use cases
the first one and our really
kind of new user experiences that can be
enabled using coin uh so the uh arvr
um
stuff that marie jose has uh presented
quite a few times is for example in that
category
uh the second group is
supporting new coin systems so where we
think that the new interaction between
communication and compute
can actually enable
new kinds of systems or so entirely new
systems
the third category um is on improving
existing coin capabilities so we already
have uh networks which use some form of
coin
and uh so for example uh cdns have kind
of already some coin functionality in
there and those use cases are now really
on
how those networks can even be improved
further and then finally we have
entirely new coin capabilities that can
be enabled
as a second aspect we've then also tried
to sharpen and tighten the taxonomy so
it was not that um focused before and
we've tried to do that now i'll come to
that
in a moment again
and finally we've also already started
to prepare the actual analysis that we
want to do later mainly focusing on the
research questions and requirements
so with that let's have a look at the
current draft structure so what you can
see is that we have actually done the
regrouping already
we also have this one new use case
provided by xavier that he has already
presented last time or in our last
meeting
and then also we have already the
analysis in the structure right now
um so we're all only
waiting to get started with that
basically
and then finally the aspect that is at
the top of this slide so the terminology
part
that we've tried to really
start aligning the terminology across
the different drafts and the other
research group documents or the draft by
dirk
which has
been expired already but yeah we've
tried to align it in some way and
that is the following now so everything
in green that you see on this slide is
terminology defined in this draft by
dirk and and the other authors
and we've tried to use that terminology
throughout our draft as well or actually
at least have started to do that
um and we've then also added quite a few
additional
uh terminology um that we thought might
be necessary for our for our draft
and overall our idea would be to sort of
get an an overall technology all across
coin
where then the question obviously would
be where would actually uh
place that terminology um so whether we
have that
in every draft or whether we have one
draft that collects all of that
terminology
then quickly regarding the use case
taxonomy um so not that much that has
changed here so we have basically only
split up
the opportunities and the research
questions so that they are now
more clearly identifiable
we've also tried to
link the description of the different
use cases really to the new grouping
that we have introduced into the draft
and finally we've also tried to um focus
the requirements uh a bit more really
only on the coin capabilities so that we
really
describe or try to describe what the
coin capabilities themselves need to do
rather than what the overall use case
has to
satisfy
and with that i'm already at the end um
so next steps that we are planning to do
is first uh finish aligning the use
cases according to the the new taxonomy
so really pinpointing the requirements
and aligning the descriptions a bit
better um then we're also trying to uh
think about the terminology that we're
currently using whether that's
everything that we need or whether there
are additional terms that we might
require and then also
maybe as a question to the the complete
research group where we would like to
collect that uh terminology as the uh
draft by uh
um and and york i think has been expired
uh some time and yeah that's just a
matter of things where we collect that
and then finally we would also like to
start uh with the analysis so we first
try to condense the opportunities
research questions and requirements and
then afterwards try to identify aspects
similar across all of the use cases so
that we can then uh perhaps give a
collected input into the
second uh
charter item of this research group
and that's it thank you
and i think comments we can take them to
the list
if there's not that much time
um thank you i i cannot really um i'm a
co-author so it's hard for me to be both
co-author and um
and and share on this but i think uh
there will be a discussion
uh
amongst the chairs to to bring this as
an orgy document but we'll
i'll let the other chairs talk about it
since i'm an author
thank you i'll just confirm that that
does seem like an appropriate next step
that we can discuss on the mailing list
okay thank you thanks for moving this
forward this was great
much appreciated
dirk truston you are next
okay
um
we see you
yeah
and there you are good
you can see this lines right
yes
very good still a bit new with the ui
and colin has given a good tutorial
thank you
transfer protocol issues uh even network
computing systems that's another draft
um like clouds and myself have been
working on um it had expired initially
in uh
in the last meeting because of the focus
we had mainly on research presentations
and and and
and
it's not quite as outstanding outdated
as the
um date on the first slide gives it was
obviously presented at the 11th of
november 2021 or not 2020.
the the premise um i highlighted the
main piece i don't intend to read this
so this is about um what if you have
functions of the communication system
i'm sorry if the part of the intent
function may be provided as part of a
communication system that's the network
premise really of coin this is a quote
from the end-to-end paper
from the original indian paper
and and we're looking at the challenges
to the traditional intent transport
protocols um you know trying to outline
opportunities research questions uh for
the design of transport protocols that
may arise
uh from the availability of in-network
computing capabilities that's the the
premise really as a recap so the
intention is to provide insights into
various transport technology areas uh
research question changes already
mentioned ongoing efforts and concepts
that are currently under studies so
we're not
limiting ourselves only to existing rfcs
but we're also looking at ongoing work
research whatever we can find
um outline possible future work
in coin and elsewhere
that's
starting with coin but doesn't
necessarily mean that all of the work
needs to be done in coin obviously
and provide that in a gap analysis
so the goal is to contribute to the
objectives of coin and i mentioned i i
quoted here the coin chart or scope
number four namely the research and
potential new transport protocol
required or enabled by in-network
commute
resources so that's a dedicated item
that's chartered really and we believe
that and hope that the draft contributes
to that
the general structure we made a similar
changes a bit you know aligned uh
in some sort of locks up to to the um
changes we also made in the in the use
case traffic presenters are trying to
sort this a bit more into various areas
of discussion so in this case for the
transport draft we divided the or
collected the uh separate
um
chapters from before into a single
technology areas uh section now that's a
section three so that has been entirely
restructured and everything has been fl
uh was was was integrated under that
section
um and then started with the gap
analysis this is just to present the
technology areas and the gap analysis
more visibly in the structure so there's
edit here for future extensions
um
and in particular with a possible
formation of future needed work so this
is much more gearing the the
i'm the document towards the
charter item that i mentioned before
right
um
so in section three um so everything
that really was before in the various i
think section initially three to seven
are now all found here
um and uh and that also helps us then to
link back from the gap analysis in
section five into the appropriate
technology section later on so it makes
the editing easier
um there were smaller updates here only
apart from the larger structural change
in section 3.1 by linking this to the
ongoing in the area of work on internet
addressing but there's a discussion
going on at the moment and
the section 3 also added ongoing work in
the ic energy and then the working group
um so these were
content changes as well to the
structural changes
um question obviously to the group we
would like to ask here and happy to get
any ideas either in the chat or on the
mailing list is what research question
related concept ongoing efforts our
intention is really to
you know also approach the new community
with that question specifically and
because we're sure that we're missing
concepts simply because we're not aware
of them or we
you know haven't worked through all the
various ones so if you have anything any
research question in a related concept
you want to share with us
please do so
gap analysis i said we edit this with
the same subsection structure so you
will see that the subsection structure
in section three is mirrored um in order
to later really have a clear relation
between technology areas uh the the the
the seven subsection we have to the
actual gap analysis in in these various
areas
at the moment we only added an
introductory paragraph outline the
intentions we have no content in the
individual sections yet um
uh
question obviously also to the list is
or to the community is to be one such uh
such uh section or not for coin so we
believe that it may help us to um
working towards the charter if we don't
want this we can remove it but that was
the suggestion we made and that's a
question we would like to get some
feeling from the community
future plans um
so we mentioned already the last time
and we we haven't really made too many
changes to do that but we want to
because we also made changes to the use
cases and i think now that we structure
the use cases as you could see in ike's
presentation more clearly around the
notion of capabilities we want to also
make clearer linkage to the use cases
and particular with that taxonomy that's
being used now in the use case draft in
a in the next version um of the
transport draft
we want to add more existing work um
we've already uh there was a
communication between the chairs but
unfortunately we're a bit too late to
bring this to the chairs um work that
has been presented at hotnet's 2021 and
bharaji the one of the
co-authors of that piper is actually i
hope he's still online but at least he
was online before
um so we tried to bring more existing
work here even to the point that we may
also
you know have this work that we find
present to the wider community as i said
we were a bit late for the agenda for
this time so it may come in the january
meeting
um also similar to the uh use case draft
to turn the research questions maybe at
a later stage into some sort of
requirements language that would allow
us to uh you know formulate um
research work
around these requirements
um gab analysis to fill this i mean if
the
question i asked before is answered
positively so we would like to have a
gab in ours because it's useful to have
that
we really would need help here would
invite uh contributors to that
uh and and and with the view on the
charter um the question here that was
the bit of the confusion i had wanted to
do because i thought the use case craft
was an rg document already um i think
it's the transport draft that isn't an
rg document yet which is why it's
written on here to maybe adopt that as a
potential key output towards the
scope of the charter as an as an rg
draft as well that at least that was the
memory that i had about this
the issue and again to repeat we would
really welcome contributors gab analysis
related work new work that exists even
if you
just send us links if you can't be
bothered to get it as a course or into
properly written up we're happy to get
any
material that you'll find that you think
is relevant should be listed in the
in the
uh draft
please do contact us to do that if you
want to become a bit more active in
helping us absolutely welcome um
certainly wouldn't that would want that
dirk i think you're spot on in terms of
what the future and next steps are
um you have a question from peng liu
um so pain if you'd like to
jump in
um
just one question
i see the draft mentioned that live for
with doncast so i want to ask that if
the quick could be a
potential way to help the flow affinity
or the service equivalence since it has
fixed the connection id regardless of
the change of address or part
yeah
yes yeah so
so the the linkage to diecast is still
in the draft even though i think the
draft actually have expired
and there are aspects that are mentioned
in the
dyncast work that i think um would need
to be pulled
more properly into the draft it's
correct so it's a little bit um
a loose issue at the moment of the draft
it needs to be it needs to be clarified
yeah
spencer um
okay
yeah i was just asking i'm seeing uh
answer it also in the chat but uh
question about
uh if there was a github repo that we
could contribute to especially in the
gap analysis
i think uh the gap analysis would be
really helpful if uh
you all could provide some uh insight
there
yes absolutely we we uh uh ike thanks
for putting the
um the get up into into the chat i i'd
seen that i couldn't type quickly enough
um yes i i would really welcome um and
and that's certainly a way to contribute
to that we do the same for the use case
draft as a separate one for you yeah
we've uh that's that's really improved
uh
us to get get uh input from contributors
uh in other venues so thank you
thanks yeah appreciate it
thanks so much dirk um
really great progress um i in the
interest of time we're going to um
move forward in the program
um
let's see we have
the enhancing security and privacy draft
and if again if you could condense your
talk i know we've given you ten minutes
originally but if you could cut it down
to seven or eight that would be
wonderful thank you very much
okay i will try and i also try to share
my screen
okay
okay do you see the right screen
we do
okay great so uh yeah thank you um you
didn't hear from me in a while but we
still have the draft on enhancing
security and privacy with in-network
computing ongoing and actually a lot has
been happening in the past month and
year in this field of research
so before i go into the update first a
short recap about the scope and
intention of this draft so the main
focus is to implement security and
privacy mechanisms within the network
and the idea behind is behind this is to
reduce the
latency and also to improve the
scalability and provide a quicker
reaction to security incidents
especially in comparison to middle boxes
which are
typically used to provide security
functionality today
and potential use cases for this are to
retrofit security for resource
restricted or legacy devices which
cannot implement security themselves
and this might be also beneficial for
industrial networks with high
performance requirements or to provide
scalable and transparent anonymization
so the goal of this draft is to provide
an insight into the potential of coin
for security and privacy and to show
research questions and telephone
inspections
[Laughter]
okay
yes
[Laughter]
so first related
um
[Laughter]
sadly aina can you hear us
oh aina can you hear us
we're having
terrible difficulty hearing you you're
completely broken
up um
we don't oh that sounded fine uh i
wonder if it's your headphone usually i
don't have
well when you continue we i don't
uh so i'm just wondering i don't know if
anybody heard anything
unfortunately because your your audio
problems started almost when you
immediately when you started presenting
turned off your video to reclaim some
bandwidth but um
could you
okay so
and let's see if we have a little better
luck i mean really it's been broken up
since the beginning
okay let me hear you now
but now you're showing that
uh we i think we got about one or two
yeah if you could go back
um yeah well
okay so you didn't hear anything that's
that i think we got we were on your
first slide we looking thank you very
very much
this slide we lost entirely and and
again we're sort of pressed for time so
um
okay okay let's make it crazy start
again
yeah sure maybe okay to make it quick
the focus is on implementing security
and privacy mechanisms within the
network
um yeah for better performance and
faster reaction
um and use cases are for example
retrofitting security forces
[Laughter]
um
okay i know
i know i think we're going to we're
going to need to defer your presentation
every time you we we speak it's fine
then as you um
present the audio is really okay i
understand that's amazing sadly um
i'm sorry
yeah
um
really too bad yes i know hannes is
saying he really wants to hear this as
do with the rest of us and now as we
converse it's fine but as you can
presentation mode it's completely broken
up
um
so i think we're gonna
yes it's very strange i wonder if it has
something to do i can't tell whether you
have a headphone or not but yeah there
may be a way that you could just share
the slides for her in case it's the
slideshare i'm gonna have to do somebody
already have it down let's see how do i
display it if i because it really seems
like we can hear a perfectly well as
long as he's not doing slight sharing
okay let me let me
download and um
let's see
where do i go to get the okay so i've
uploaded everything to manage the slides
and then if i want to
show this
button on the left hand side near the um
near where you mute and unmute on the
left
it's right next to the screen share
button
i'm just not
hang on
oh
got it sorry
all right
new user here
uh cher
okay
are you all seeing it now
[Music]
okay
all right let's start this again so you
uh you again missed everything
yes yeah
and we only have five minutes so i think
if you could just
give us the high level we're going to
have to punt on other
uh presentations sadly
go for it we'll give you the last five
minutes and we'll take the and the very
last minute
yeah the next tell me which slide to
start with
oh yes
okay so um yeah very quickly there is um
work which tries to implement um
encryption also secure cryptographic
functions for encryption and hashing in
the data plane so this lays the
foundation for security and privacy
applications such as implementing
security standards for example ipsec or
macseg in the data plane and it might
also allow for onion routing or message
authentication in the future
the next slide
yeah there is also an effort to
implement authentication in the data
plane by offering basic mechanisms like
port knocking or one-time passwords
and this might allow for continuous
authentication without latency overhead
or additional middle boxes
then next
slide
um other work is about allowing scalable
transparent oh obviously yes
no problem
yeah so our work is
available transparent and lightweight
anonymization in the data plane for
example by rewriting source addresses
and hiding path information by using
randomization
or encrypting ipv4 addresses to
obfuscate traffic and the idea behind
this is to address the performance and
usability issues of existing anonymity
tools like tor
okay the next slide
um
yeah we can also use um computing in the
network to improve intrusion detection
um
one one potential here is to allow for
inline detection and a quick reaction to
anomalies but we can also reduce the
load on existing intrusion detection
systems and this is exactly what lewis
and i'll do so here they apply
rule-based pre-filtering in the data
plane and by that they achieve a traffic
reduction of up to 75 percent
at the actual ids
okay next slide
and last we
looked into network monitoring which can
be for example used for network
forensics and here soundcheck i for
example propose flow monitoring on p4
based hardware switches so they
pre-process packets in the data plane
and then very efficiently create floor
records in the control plane and this
offers a high performance and cost
efficient
alternative for accurate flow monitoring
in comparison to
existing
solutions okay the next slide
um yeah so to conclude we see
increasing interest of research
community and that underlines our
intuition
about the possibilities that coin
provides for security and
privacy and also its relevance
and this is confirmed by recent
publications which match the ideas of
our draft and they're published at high
rank values for example usenix security
and existing work also provides first
proofs of concept which show that
implementing security
in the network is actually feasible
so we derived from these observations
that enhancing security and privacy
within network computing actually turned
into a hot research topic and there are
many exciting ideas left to investigate
in the future
therefore this draft underlines the
potential of coin to benefit diverse and
quite significant applications which
also go behind beyond typical networking
and um
yeah to drive this draft forward now we
are strongly looking for your feedback
and also contributions
so if you're curious about this draft or
have any comments just drop me an email
and otherwise i thank you for your
attention
and i'm yeah looking forward to any
inquiries
okay that's it
thank you so much uh really sorry about
yeah that was true the network itself
got in the way of your presentation but
um thank you for that terrific update
yeah
some of the
research that's out there
any questions
the audience in our last minute
i think where was the question in the
chat before but i can um get to this
offline i think
okay
okay that sounds good
um
great
then i will stop the slideshare thank
you so much for persevering everybody uh
in our last minute i think um they're
really two topics
uh one is just that if you have don't
know already that hot nets is going on
in parallel this week and there's some
very interesting work
um and the second point of interest is
that of course we've been threatening to
have um an interim in order to um review
our scope
and i think we really we would like to
do that um halfway between this ietf and
the next
um so stay tuned for that we welcome
your inputs on the um
mailing list and thank you to so many of
you for sticking it out despite the
network errors for arriving at whatever
hour
it is in your time zone many of those
time zones it's an inconvenient hour so
thank you for being here and to all the
presenters uh for the
terrific
presentations i know there's been a
really healthy dialogue in the chat
window so i look forward to um
sharing some of that uh we we all look
forward to sharing some of that in the
minutes um
so thank you once again since we're at
the top of the hour for for being here
any other comments
maurice jose or jeffrey
okay i think thank you very very much
everyone and uh
yes see you on the mailing list
and um and see you in um hopefully in
person soon
and thank you to those who helped hand
hold us through some of the
user interface issues that was greatly
appreciated in real time thank you
have a great day
evening afternoon bye-bye
you