on because i would say that kyle's was
flipping so it may just be local
conditions
i actually figured that you were that
you're you were dropping a little bit
from uh because of your internet
connection that was my assumption
but it's so minor that i wouldn't worry
about it you're perfectly audible
yeah that's let's not discuss ethernet
today
that was that was the other technical
challenge of the morning but
we're just going to say that apple needs
to figure out their usbc
implementation again and leave it at
that
all right
so should we uh shall we get started i
guess
yeah have we succeeded in finding a
volunteer for the um
taking of notes
i do not see anyone yet so i guess we
gotta shake the tree
we can't move forward with the meeting
until we get a minutes taker
uh yeah
dude
thank you jake
except
for speaking oh wait man you're not are
you speaking or no yes or unless you've
found it i am speaking
i i am uh this one is
less involved i hope but yeah actually
if you could cover notes while
if there's any questions that come my
way that would be helpful thank you
and mike says so too
yeah
um
great
yes and everyone is
free to please go in and um work with
the
oops as we go to help fill in the blanks
as useful and necessary and take a
little load off of jake but thank you
jake all right
so um
i guess we should note the node well
well
um
remember reminding everyone not only
about the um patents
and the um
the requirement to declare any
knowledge of um
ipr and encumbered
technologies which you'll
i'd like to end up covering a whole lot
in this discussion but that is still an
iot requirement and any discussions here
can and will be used as part of the ietf
uh proceedings
um
and
uh
in particular i'd like to draw
everyone's attention to the
fact that we do have a code of conduct
um and the url is on the slide for
the code of conduct and how to contact
the ombuds team if you leave that you've
had
if you have if you feel you've had an
issue with improper conduct
uh at the ietf
i think that's a hopefully that's a
reasonable covering of the note well
kyle anything else you'd like to surface
in the
i mean i would yeah i would just say
that regarding the regarding the code of
conduct and and harassment just treat
your fellow participants with respect
and don't be an and
things will probably be fine
so
great
our next slide
yep
so we have a pretty straightforward
agenda this morning um
we've already managed to get through
all of the admin hooray
um
we do have some extra industry updates
from glendeen and sanjay this morning
a couple of updates on the working group
docs and then
some interesting other work going on
within the ietf
and then
it seems a valuable time to take a take
a look back over the last two years of
the mops working group my goodness has
it been two years already
um
and
talk a little bit more about where we
have been and where we might go from
here so um unless anyone would like to
bash that agenda
um
i think we're ready to go
not seeing or hearing any bashes oh
glenn yep no no ben glenn is up
bash free wow
that's awesome
uh are the uh presentations loaded up
into digital or into uh meet echo
yes i did that at like 10 46.
oh i love it just in time uh just entire
presentations perfect uh the question is
how do i do that again
well no i'll uh so i have to stop
sharing i think okay
but uh
yeah so
europe
so it's at the top it's the yeah okay
here we go
and then
let's re-update
share
because sharing is caring
all right
it's been a long itf week i i apologize
for having gone there
um hey uh i'm glendeen and uh i'm here
uh to talk about a presentation that
sanjay misha who also along on the
uh session and jason thibodeau
from the stream video alliance have put
together uh we've done a series of these
and sanjay and i usually hand off back
and forth on who's doing it and this uh
itif was my turn so here i am
and we're going to talk about what's
been going on with the streaming video
alliance also known as the sva
since we last met
and i'll uh feel free if you want to
jump into the cube and take questions um
you know what we'll clarify questions on
particular slides along the way if not
i'll you know we can talk at the end of
this
um so the sva has been uh pumping a lot
of work recently uh you know it's been a
very productive 2021 despite you know
what we've all been facing
and uh
the way the sva is organized is very
much like the ietf we're divided up into
working groups that focus on particular
areas we have focuses on uh you know
security privacy augmented reality
uh vr
live streaming
and caching things like that and so when
i go through this deck a lot of this can
be sort of topic focused uh and then on
to the next topic and it's sort of
organized by a working group
so the first thing i want to highlight
is we have released a a test bed now for
the open caching api so those who are
familiar with open caching from sva
there's a linkage across pollination
here going on with uh the open caching
uh at itf there's our open caching sba
and the cdni working group over at itf
in fact sanjay uh you know is involved
in both uh especially at the itf as one
of the co-chairs uh and so
you know we've been developing these uh
these apis uh at the sva around open
caching for several years now and we've
now put together a test bed uh to allow
people who are trying to adopt those
apis to actually exercise against them
and uh check to see if you know where
they need uh compliance
so
that's a bit up and rolling uh we also
have some configuration apis they were
so awesome we had to split them into
three documents uh so there they are uh
this has actually been a considerable
amount of work going through that group
uh to create these configuration apis
and it's really meant to be sort of um a
companion uh to the rest of this work
we're doing around uh caching and uh
availability
next up uh we had a live streaming plc
and a couple of these slides are going
to talk about plc's that were going on
you know one of the things the sva does
uh above and beyond working on sort of
apis and specs and best practices
is uh you know we're sort of i guess you
could say where the industry meets the
specifications uh because in the room we
have a lot of people who do technical
specifications and architectures and and
product we also have a lot of people in
the room who are actually deployed
uh centric and uh content delivery
centric so uh in the end you know we
have this great opportunity to bring
together the people doing the
specifications with the people doing the
deployments and allowing us to sort of
you know let them do some proof of
concepts and say well does this
architecture we've all put together
across the itf across cinti across other
wars like scudy and
at the sva does all that come together
in a meaningful way and what can we
learn from that to feed back into all
the various organizations that are
contributing and so we put these pocs
together uh we've got a couple that will
come up in the decks here but typically
the live stream plc uh has been uh
active uh they've got some um
links here uh that uh that you can go
off and follow and particularly they've
been working on measuring live our
latency in abr streaming and so that's a
very much a great example of you know
putting together this the specifications
we're all been working on you know abr
has you know been around for a few years
but you know latency reducing that
especially for live streaming uh for
things like sports are huge right now in
the delivery industry and so this plc
brings together that uh exercise and
says well are we at the right
we're the right way are we going the
right direction is there things missing
that we need to take back into our
development work into our specification
work and expand on
another plc we have is
all about latency
in streaming vr
uh so
you're gonna see a theme here a lot of
these things it's latency latency
latency and a big part of that is if you
you know look at the the the content
industry there's been this shift in the
last few years you know when we started
mops even two years ago the big focus
was very much on delivering
of uh pre-word recorded content or you
know stuff that was from files often in
the industry we call the spot video on
demand
and you know that's what we've been
doing when we watch a movie we're
watching video on demand
and
we've got it pretty well done but one of
the things that you can be very tolerant
of in a vaude setting is latency you
don't care if you know the movie is
starting up one you know half a second
later or a second later or two seconds
later uh you you're very taller because
it's a recorded film another if you're
watching live sports you want to make
sure that the the events you're seeing
on the screen are as close to uh live as
possible and this is sort of the new big
challenge in front of the streaming
world it's how do we reduce that latency
so that experience is as close to live
as possible and so that applies to live
streamings applies to vr everything
we're doing is trying to like bridge
that uh that gap between you know what
you end up with on your screen you know
your goggles and what happens in the
real world and so you're gonna see that
sort of a repeating theme in this deck
but also as we go forward with
specifications and work that's a big
focus area in the industry
uh we also have a distributed request
tracing uh this is a another way for us
to tell how well the
uh the system is working end to end as
part of the qoe experience and of course
you know you can make things very fast
and very low latency but you can do it
by shaving off quality and that's not
good especially when we're talking about
things like live sports equality and
sports is something that viewers demand
and so
part of the qe experience work uh in
this distributed tracing framework is
actually start looking at how do we uh
collaborate end-to-end and collect all
that data so we can understand when it's
working when it isn't working and why it
isn't working
and so if you're interested in that
space and i think just real overlap with
some of the itf uh stuff please go check
out this link
and you can see what that project is
doing
and then something that's probably
pretty relevant to the itf
uh quick for video streaming uh you know
now that we have quick publishers with
specification yay um you know there's
been a lot of conversation at the itf
around quick for streaming you know we
have mock which is you know meeting and
discussing uh you know the aspects there
well the sva as well has been taking a
look at quick and you know uh looking
back at some of the notes when we did an
update from the svh the itf uh a couple
its ago one of the comments we made was
you know we're looking at quick but we
didn't have any clear plans to pick up
and start deploying it at scale as a
delivery infrastructure you know as an
industry
and
one of the things we identified in
asking the question why is that was that
you know there's a little big shift
going on here right obviously shifting
to quick udp infrastructure away from
the tcp based infrastructure that the
delivery guys all know and have
instrumented really well
is a big challenge
and it's retraining it's uh developing
some new tools and new ways of looking
at the problem space and it's also
understanding how this all comes
together with expectations of the all
the expectations of the new and what
tools and infrastructure we have to
support it
and so one of these the uh the sva has
decided to do
is to create a poc
that is going to
build both a reference architecture for
testing the environment but try to uh
tease out the details of how do you do
that instrumentation and how do you do
the metrics collection from end to end
so that you can actually evaluate quick
compared to your current delivery
environments evaluate quick you know
what it
looks like compared to that but also how
you can then start exercising some of
the more advanced features of quick that
aren't available in the old world and so
ultimately the goal here is to build a
reference
uh evaluation platform
that the uh the broader industry can
take and make use of uh so they don't
themselves have to sort through things
so in practical terms what have we done
so one of our first things we've been
working on is looking through all the
the myriad of quick server
implementations that are out there and
trying to you know
create a set of criteria well why would
you pick one over the other and what
features are you looking for in a quick
server implementation and how would you
then do instrumentation that connects in
with the tool sets you already have
as part of your delivery environment
likewise we're looking at the player's
side how you connect with a player that
supports quick and how you instrument
properly and then how do all the pieces
in the middle come together in a
coherent way and the idea behind this
plc is it will start publishing at each
of its five phases outputs uh that the
sva members and the broader industry can
take a look at and make use of in their
own evaluation quick so hopefully this
helps bridge that gap between you know i
want to play with it and i now have
touched it played with i now understand
it i can start figuring how it fits in
american picture
and also one of the big goals here is to
be able to bring back to the itf
real life experiences around this to say
well here's what worked here is what
didn't work here's some things we think
we made directions we may want to
suggest going in to improve things
[Music]
and it's bringing together here uh so if
you need to get a hold of any of us uh
i'm glenn dean i'm nbc universal and
comcast here's my email uh we have
sanjay uh
at verizon and we have jt at the
streamingvideolines.org uh and with that
are there any questions
all right uh uh kyle are you guys
bingeing the key or do you want me to
manage the queue
oh we're uh we're managing the queue oh
oh
yes so go ahead jake
all right uh okay good
uh
yeah thanks glenn um i wanted to ask
about uh
so it
some of the documents in the sva look
like they're
available for free download i'm not sure
about the distribution policies like
obviously the ipr
and copyright kind of constraints are
quite different than in the itf and
i was curious
just sort of how much of this work do
you anticipate bringing to the itf and
kind of getting it into the more
you know clear
uh space and how much of it is uh like
do we do we have to ask our lawyers
before we should get involved and
whatnot you know well you know the
official answer as we both know is
always you must ask the lawyers for
everything
because
you know engineers aren't allowed to
make decisions like that um but
you know
so
the work of the sva really can be
divided into a couple categories right
one of them is sort of technical
specifications
those may contain uh ip related stuff
and if you're an sva member part of
joining the organization is of course
agree the ip licensing rules which
really focus on uh providing licenses to
other
uh sva members if they want to negotiate
with you yeah and it's not the sv unlike
the itf
isn't uh essentially you know like
as open a ip policy it's very flexible
if you're a member if you're an outsider
it's it's different right
but that's for the specifications and
the really technical stuff or the things
like plc's
uh best practices
and white papers those are things which
do not typically contain any ip related
assertions or materials because they're
they're looking at the industry level
and they're looking at the technology
level that's available across the open
industry like so quick would be a good
example right we're not building a quick
server at the eye at the sva we're not
putting sda member you know ip into that
quick server we're taking stuff that's
already out there that's available off
the shelf
typically open source and and taking it
in and making use of it and documenting
how we make use of it so that stuff is
all available and will be available when
published to the outside world you can
just go to the sva website
uh click on the download you know it
does the same thing where it asks you to
i think register your email address so
we know who you are
and then you download it and and
right the documents you know copyrighted
by the sva but of course you know you
can go out and read and use it and stuff
like that uh the copyright is to prevent
you from republishing it yourself as
your own work uh but not to consume it
uh so you that's as you know and we're
trying to make it as open as possible
because the goal here is to really help
bridge the world between
the delivery operations environment that
is sort of the sva and then the the
development architecture like the itf
um
i kind of liken it sometimes unto
uh like what analog does right now is
full of people who actually take
the technical specs for networks deploy
them and make them work and the itf
writes those technical specs and that
will feed back to the itf where things
work and where things don't work and ask
for changes and i think that's a very
similar relationship between the sva and
the itf for video
does that sort of cover it
uh that's helpful thanks
um
i i guess i'll have to
check with the lawyers but yeah thank
you well
and and the other thing i should add to
is obviously we have like sanjay and
myself were very active in the itf and
so part of our you know role here i
think is to act as that uh
that bridge where it's appropriate and
and to pull things out of one and bring
them over to the other one and there's
other people at the itf that's you know
engage with the sva on a regular basis
in various written groups and so i think
there's a you know an ongoing
relationship of back and forth here yeah
i want to i want to thank clinton yeah
say that there's a sort of
a meta purpose of
sharing that this work is going on
because it's related to ietf work
uh the the ins and outs of how how
you know people here actually engage in
work there and vice versa
are
a little a little trickier perhaps
and i'll point out that you know
we do the opposite to the two groups
like the sva we take the updates that
happen at the itf in places like mops
and a bunch of us go back to the sva in
their working groups and we talk there
about what's going on in the itf to make
sure that we've got cross-pollination
going on actively and ongoing between
the two organizations
anyways that's my presentation did
sanjay have anything you wanted to add
in
my co-author
i think um you you've covered it pretty
well so i don't really have anything
more to add unless there are any
questions
and you can follow up with either one of
us or both of us um afterwards uh you
know we're obviously here on the ietf
and uh we're around other places so
don't be shy
all right thank you great great thank
you both thank you
all right um so i think jake you are up
next with the follow up from working
group last call on the ops con stock
yeah all right i think i can't click on
the
uh
video while it's trying to wait oh what
happened
there's a modal that pops up okay i
guess i have to beat that up that makes
sense
sorry i think it's my first time trying
to use this particular tool usually i
shared my screen
all right
it's kind of neat though
uh but you you lose the opportunity to
uh you know have embarrassing
notifications show up uh to everyone in
the
in the working group
well i can still do that like on my
screen you can see my uh reflection off
the car out the window there
it's that time in the morning
for me out here on the west coast all
right
uh so i was just going to give an update
on our
our adopted draft
that uh
tell everybody where we all are
uh so
our last call you know
quote passed without uh without
objections uh there was one comment in
support of advancing it uh but this is
not sort of the you know overwhelming
support that we see in the room
uh for
uh some of the
some of the questions we've we've asked
from time to time so um
we wanted to just kind of confirm it and
make sure that
there really is working group consensus
to to move this forward
uh
and i was going to go over kind of the
the
status on our last few
you know
gasps of working on this
we close you know we raised and closed
uh over 40 issues you can see them in
the github link
there's a bunch of good stuff there
we
had to open issues remaining when we
finished and uh i guess i'd characterize
these as like
more running out of steam and and uh
uh having conflicts that necessarily
uh
we decided not to like we we had a
couple of leanings on this in different
directions and some questions as to like
really should we
uh put this in but um
know so uh
there there was a little
comment on it that like
maybe if there's something we can
that the operators can do about it then
we should include it but maybe
not otherwise and so this was the
this was the last thing where i think we
just dropped the ball on kind of getting
it in uh its final state was assigned to
me so this one's my fault um you know
there's there's some reasonable things
that an operator can do if dns is
is coming into play as a potential
performance problem and um
so it's not an unreasonable thing to
include we do not have this listed as
one of our blockers for going ahead with
black with with last call i expect there
are other
things that can affect performance that
we did not really cover in our in the
dock in the end uh so you know this is
uh
perhaps a gap but i'm not sure it's such
an important gap that we should
update it and do another last call
and the other one was kind of
there was an interesting talk
last time about the comparative latency
under load from uh from comcast
um
and we had a little bit of discussion i
think spencer had the idea that uh that
there were a few worthwhile sentences to
to
suggest on this topic and uh um
you know i was a little bit
uh i'm not sure it really fits but uh
you know lawfully and regardless the
sentences never quite got submitted i
guess i'd put this as another one that's
maybe nice to have but not necessary um
but that's really all we had
and i guess my big question is like
are we really ready to move forward can
we i don't know we're on a poll
does anybody have concerns about this
that didn't make it to the list
uh
etc so that that is all i have i guess
really what i wanted is a
discussion
maybe a
confirmation
something like this section on mock yes
thanks ali
uh that'll have to be its own working
group i'm afraid
in my opinion
but please feel free to disagree
flourish floors open i'm inviting cues
eric
yeah no specific
no specific comment on on the draft per
se but more on the group last call
there was only one
review by glenn on the mailing list
that's a little bit short
right so i don't want to be the document
shepherd to say and declare group
consensus when there was only one review
so i really urge
other participants in this working group
that are here or not listening basically
to review the document and saying like
glenn it's okay i support like it is
that's enough right so you don't need to
put a ten thousand issue uh the sort of
the better some specifically for you
jake right
yeah yeah so
i'm slightly concerned if only one
review done by glenn
uh it may cause problem when you go
later in the process
right actually
yeah
i have to review it so part of the
purpose
part of the reasoning putting this on
the agenda for today was was to flesh
out if if there were
issues that were going to come up in itf
wide last call let's let's hear what
they are now rather than
being surprised but i certainly take the
point that a document shepard's gonna
be unimpressed by a single
um
so i see two people in the queue i think
that probably where we want to close out
today's um
activity is to
take names uh who's willing who's
willing to review um or and or just send
a note to the list saying that you know
you read it and support it's going
forward but
i guess sanjay is next
yes i'm i'm next and um i just wanted to
i think eric's point well
and i definitely owe a review and i will
be reviewing the document
so i'm on the record
great thank you sanjay
um so uh i can't uh volunteered review
pieces since apparently i already did a
review
uh but uh i will take this over to the
working groups over the sva and make
them aware of the document as well so
they get some eyeballs from that
organization on it and i'll spread it
around some social contacts i have in
the industry because i think this is
some important stuff um
to eric i want to point out that you
know
because we're now using
github uh for the the editor process uh
for this i will point out that
tremendous amount of conversation
actually took place on that github and
i'm wondering if somehow we it would be
appropriate to make a shepherd aware of
the github conversations that went into
the process because
historically it would have been on the
list but now it's sort of on this other
place so i don't know how to solve that
but suggestions would be welcome
there is indeed a dichotomy somehow
between the github and the mailing list
but until now it's still a mailing list
that counts
and
if you open for instance couple of
issues in the github no things block you
to send in the working group last call
nothing prevents you to say on the
meaningless i have open three four five
a github issue and that counts right
musically
yeah thanks sir
yeah i guess as
as an author i i'd also like to point
out that
contributing to the document by uh
you know commenting and opening issues
does not imply
support for
getting the document to the you know for
advancing the document uh
through last call um this is these are
two separate things and while we are are
very grateful we we need a
i would say we need a separate uh
confirmation of that well what
regardless of the venue
uh but yeah the mailing list
as eric said is the
is the normative one there
uh okay uh renin
uh i would be happy to uh review the
document as well uh i just want to say
the document looks really good
there are good comparing and contrasting
of various options
and section 7 is comprehensive but i'll
i'll definitely review it over the
mailing list as well and thanks to the
authors for putting up putting together
this document
great thanks i guess
i have i have one question also that
occurred to me like in in some other
working groups i've seen like
a request to send like we're not aware
of any ipr for all the authors and maybe
we support advancing this document also
i i didn't do that i kind of forgot
that should i
i guess
i don't know what our process is here
exactly
yeah well i mean welcome you're you're
our first document for this working
group so um i think we're kind of
figuring out what our process is as well
as you know as we'll get into a little
later
dealing with the fact that we're not
actually meeting in person and
um kind of struggling to
the dichotomy is not i don't think the
dichotomy is between github and the
mailing list i think the dichotomy is
between people who come to the meetings
and people who participate on the
mailing list
um
so
uh
i think it would be fine and helpful for
the for the
the authors to do that i think that i
mean i as i said i think we need to take
some names and and already got one
um
i'm i'm
yeah i'm appreciative of
glenn's offer to take this to a wider
audience at the same time as you know
we are in last call right this is not a
what document would you write if you
were writing a document request this is
a is this document in reasonable shape
to meet its objectives
yes no what can we do to fix it um
kind of
call
ali
so to jake's question uh uh at least uh
when i was a working group chair
i you know as the chair i asked the
group whether there was any ipr
considerations from anybody not just
authors obviously anybody from the
working group
and
but beyond that since this is an
informational document
i'm not sure whether the ipr
declarations do apply to this one
maybe they still do i don't know but uh
since
yeah i think the ipr
as in the note well ipr always applies
but what i got out of jake's comment was
the and i support the document
you know explicitly sending the note to
the mailing list to say that
the support for it
well i don't think we will have any
concerns jake anyway i just wanted to
point to that
thank you
all right uh that is it then um i guess
if nobody else has comments i don't know
if you guys
uh
want to run a poll in the room or
we'll just do the list but um
yeah and and i guess um kyle what do you
think i would be happy to to get more
names from people here who are willing
to go through the document and you know
send a thumbs up or questions to the
mailing list
i don't know if you want to do that as a
poll if we want to ask people to
volunteer
in in the
in the chat or
um if we just want to take the mailing
the attendance list and send mail to
everybody i'm not above mail spam i mean
yeah i i think volunteering in the chat
seems fine i'm not sure if the polls are
are anonymous or not and if they're
anonymous they wouldn't that
isn't going to help too much i can't
i don't think i've run a poll
uh through medico so okay
i think we did last time but i could be
wrong about that um all right
i don't remember what you know what i
ate for breakfast this morning so
i just remember the very clicky keyboard
in the last meeting um
the okay so how about this let's see if
we can find all right you've got one i
was aiming for three let's go for five
people in the in the chat who are
willing to
um
review the document and send a thumbs up
or a question to the mailing list for
last working last call within the next
two weeks
go okay great we have
we've got two come on
we can get somebody else here
everyone else is wandered away from the
keyboard and
is consuming suitable beverages for
whatever time zone they're in
all right did you mean five in addition
or because we got five it looks like
yeah i think i think we are i think we
are good to go thanks and i appreciate
everyone's volunteering
great you jake and co-authors and thank
you everyone who has volunteered
all right
uh so now
on to um the media operations use case
for an augmented reality application on
edge computing infrastructure well
leslie i have a question uh before we
move on
so uh
as you will remember we decided to have
a live document
at the end of the
rfc eventually and
we haven't really received anything from
the
rfc editor at this point but uh
if
maybe maybe it needs to be taken care of
during the last call as well maybe ad or
someone else needs to make that clear
uh
at this point we have a tiny url link
that you know links to the google
document uh but eventually we want to
have a
base in the you know somewhere in the
atf domain so
if anybody has any idea how to do it or
maybe whether we should take an action
at this point to to do that uh it might
be good to check as well
yeah that's that's that's a good
question thanks for bringing that back
up um
i suspect it's something that we'll have
to deal with either in working group
last call or ietf wide last call um and
see if it's get us to a point where
everyone is comfortable that we have a
usable answer but um
i don't i don't think we're quite there
today
cool
all right over to you uh raymond
can you hear me
okay so my name is
krishna and i will be presenting an
update to our draft
this is a joint work with akbar rahman
[Music]
so updates to the draft are in section
3.1
we have also added a new section 5 to
the draft we will talk about these
changes in the next few slides
the updates are in the form of
reorganizing section 3.1 around the
notion of ar data processing pipeline
we have also added section 5 where we
summarize the network characteristics of
ar application traffic as well as tcp's
interaction with 4g lte network carrying
ar traffic
so let us look at those updates
in section 3.1 we gave a brief sketch of
an ar data processing pipeline that
consists of three consecutive subtasks
namely tracking followed by an
acquisition of a model of the real world
and finally registration
firstly we need to track the
three-dimensional coordinates and
six-dimensional pose that includes
coordinates and orientation of objects
in the real world
these track natural features are then
used to develop an annotated point
cloud-based model
finally the coordinate systems
brightness and color of virtual and real
objects need to be aligned in a process
called registration
in addition to the requirements for abr
algorithms there are other operational
issues that need to be considered for ar
use cases such as the one described in
this draft
in a study conducted to characterize
multi-user ar or cellular networks the
following issues were identified and
have been added in section 5.
firstly the uploading of data from an ar
device to a remote server for processing
dominates the end-to-end latency
secondly a lack of visual features in
the grid environment can cause increased
latencies as the ar device uploads
additional visual data for processing to
the remote server
finally ar applications tend to have
large bursts that are separated by
significant time gaps
as a result the tcp congestion window
enters slow start before the large
bursts of data arrive increasing the
perceived user latency
the study quoted in the draft shows that
segmentation latency at the rlc layer
impacts tcp's performance during slow
start
we would like to thank spencer dawkins
rohit abhishek and jake holland for
providing very helpful feedback on the
mailing list
we would give our detailed response to
the feedback on the mailing list
we would like to take this opportunity
to invite reviewers and contributors to
improve the draft the draft is now on
good help many thanks to kyle rose for
helping out
as a starting point for our discussion
as spencer has suggested in the mailing
list for future versions of the draft we
could abstract out from just discussing
the particulars of ar applications using
resources on the edge
to the general idea of deploying edge
resources for arvr and 360 degree
streaming type applications
so this is essentially up to the working
group to agree whether that is the
correct scope of the draft
additionally
from our perspective the intended
audience for this draft is network
operators
so with the chair's permission we'd like
to open the floor for a discussion
chris
yeah so um i read the draft um
uh it looks it it's an excellent start
um i think um i agree with a lot of the
feedback that's already been given on
the list and i apologize for not getting
my feedback on the list before the
meeting
i said that i wouldn't i didn't
but i will get you some feedback um
one of the things i did observe is that
the
um
there's a lot of discussion about
generation and processing
on the device itself
and
with the intended audience is you know
network operators
um
to me it was in concretely it was not
concretely tied enough to
what's happening on the network and
where those latencies are coming from
and
time budget being spent in one place
versus another
um
uh uh
it wasn't clear to me
how those things were related
um
and as a network uh
uh person trying to read this
um
uh that was confusing to me
yeah thanks chris for the comments uh
definitely we can uh
add more text to the draft clarifying
uh
in more precise terms what are the
various steps which take the uh which
make up the whole uh time budget uh i'd
also like to add here that uh the
description of the various ar processes
are just a brief sketch
they are not meant to be comprehensive
if someone is interested in a
comprehensive discussion they can look
at the references
so the the discussion of er is is
deliberately kept very
brief
but yeah we are open to more suggestions
there any other immediate questions for
renin
so um
i appreciate that you will go through
the detailed responses on the mailing
list which is
absolutely appropriate because there
were some some good in-depth uh reviews
um but i did think it would be worth it
if the working group would actually um
yeah if the working group would
here discuss a little bit more about one
of the points that jake raised which is
you know whether whether this document
as it stands is
straddling at least two worlds and best
pick which one
um
i don't know reena if you want to
address that at all now or if we should
open the floor to other comments and ask
jake to reiterate that point
no absolutely i think uh i'll give my uh
comments on that and i'll definitely
want to hear what the working group uh
wants to say
uh so i think both spencer and jake have
raised this issue of uh the scope and uh
the intended audience of the document
um so what we
want to do with the document is to
uh make it uh sort of as as
i said
uh abstract out of the particulars of ar
applications and
and discuss what are the implications of
not only air but vr and 360 degree
streaming applications
on the utility of edge computing
resources so as uh spencer put it i
think uh he said that reasons to deploy
edge computing uh with the reasons not
being about specific applications so i
think that would be a
from my perspective that would be a
really nice direction to go to but i
want to hear what the working group
thinks
as would we
does anybody want to wade in
i think uh
yeah go ahead kyle share your thoughts
well yeah so speaking as a participant
rather than
rather than as a
as a chair i just say that it feels like
the
the problems that the ar draft is trying
to address are not specific to
to augmented reality they're much more
general and it seems to be that
it seems it seems to me that there's a
there's a large class of interactive
applications
that need really low latency which
implies things about
where compute is located how quickly
objects can be fetched how you know and
what constraints like physics has on how
close those things need to be to you in
order to achieve a desired level of
latency
um
[Music]
that i i sort of i guess one of my fears
is that the is that by using
by by having the you know the the term
ar in the title and having it be focused
directly on that use case that a lot of
people would be like augmented reality
i'm not doing that even though the
concerns
would be
would be shared by a much larger group
of people anyway i just wanted to throw
that out there that's something that
i've been sitting on for a while
yeah and i i think uh i would agree with
that as the draft progress we have
realized that its
scope should broaden or or more
precisely you should abstract out of
particular er applications into more
general issues
uh which
resources on the edge can can help
mitigate
um jake
right so that that was uh one of the
options so that's good that we're
hearing uh plus ones to that side of it
um
i guess
i would say that there are some
so
uh like
uh like renown was saying i think
there's
uh there are some tighter constraints
for
that come from the head motion kind of
constraints then
basically anything i've heard of yet
including gaming like for that one
you're looking at maybe i think last i
saw a 45 millisecond total budget but
this one's more like 15 at the outside
if i remember right so
um that's a significant difference
that's
that's a scope constraint potentially
but
i just
do you ha you know you said there are
many applications that need it did you
have others in mind here kyle uh so
besides ar we are 360 degrees
streaming there is also
a
certain uh
vehicular use cases that would require
edge computing resources certain iot use
cases as well
and
the one common thread across all of
those applications is
the requirement for low latency and also
the fact that the devices are typically
uh
battery driven and so that
limits the amount of resources that is
available
and that also causes this
heat problem that also causes the
battery drainage problem
so uh so across all of those kinds of
use cases you have these similar
requirements
and
they can be mitigated by uh various
engineering solutions involving edge
resources
so that so that's interesting um
yeah i mean i guess i guess it almost
seems like there are
like there are two levels of docs that
are that are wanted here because there
are
there's a unique combination of problems
uh that augmented reality and and
virtual reality um
uh share
uh
but the individual problems are then
then overlap with other areas so it's
almost like you want
the augmented reality problem statement
and then have that refer to
you know up to two other
to documents and other areas that are
addressing subsets of that problem does
that make sense
uh yeah what i would say is that um the
at the operational level as spencer says
in his mail
uh there are a lot of things like the
choice of the transport protocol that
are not necessarily
uh
decided by the network operators but by
the
by the application developers and that
that that then means that at the network
operator level uh there are these uh
these paired uh sort of uh traffic
patterns
uh that they need to deal with to
provide certain say uh qoe so qci comes
to mind which are provided by
uh
4g and 5g vendors
so uh
so yes there is a set of um
let's say requirements
uh posed by the
by the ar application
which are also then
the requirements for other kinds of
applications like uh certain iot
applications or autonomous cycles etc
etc so i think the fact that um that you
can use
uh engineering solutions load balancing
deciding where to offload when to
offload those sorts of things
uh
in combination with with
the edge devices
is is sort of a common thread across all
these applications i think
thank you karen
my apologies i haven't fully read the
document but i had a curiosity question
you talked about uh dynamically changing
qoe
is there any quantitative way to decide
what is quality of experience are there
any metrics you have in mind for those
um so i have
given a reference to that
and uh
and typically the
metrics that the application designers
come up with have to be tied to actual
network
uh things like latency and bandwidth
uh
so
so yes there are
certain uh metrics that you can you can
use but they need to be translated into
you know the standard network
performance
metrics like latency and memory
okay yeah i'll review the document and
provide you more comments on it thank
you very much
that's great thank you um i've been
putting myself in queue and coming out
of queue and in queueing out of cube um
because the the
around the question of um you know is do
we need to capture sort of the use case
of ar and and and tape it up as the
target
it strikes me that we might want to
articulate that in terms that are
around what what is it what is special
about it that requires edge computing
you've listed a lot of the video related
ones and which is appropriate for
mob's document um but it strikes me too
that it might be worth capturing some of
the other compute challenges that are
make it not possible to address these
issues by traditional
you know video challenge technologies
such as cdns
and in particular i'm thinking about
whether it's ar or vr or the metaverse
the whole notion of synchronization of
objects
um or we or shared reality if you will
um
and
how that impacts you know the fact that
you you really do need to do
local
you know you need to break the problem
down based on where you what you're
competing locally versus what you are
yeah achieving through communication
um
so i don't know if that's useful as a
means of sort of
saying you know
of describing what are the kinds of
problems you think we're talking about
here and why is edge computing important
or if it's a complete red herring
um but
that's where my thinking was running too
uh well for
definitely for ar and vr applications uh
the the latency is important
and
one of the reasons why that's important
is because of synchronization issues
that we have discussing in the draft
also
so uh so definitely whether you talk of
your vr or
multiverse uh you would need to uh
you need to think about a
synchronization
and
a way to to
deal with with the latency issues
uh also because most of these devices
are on on wireless networks uh that that
are very variable in their quality so so
uh so yeah definitely synchronization
and i think part of my point was
it is the nature of the problem space
that
um
there are certain things that you can
split across nodes and there are certain
things you cannot right so i mean it's
the age-old problem of multi-parallel
processor computing and shared memory
and or messaging right when you're
solving a problem what are the things
that actually need to happen locally and
what are the things that can be solved
by synchronized communication elsewhere
um and there are some things that just
cannot be
pushed off
um
again i didn't want a rat hole there but
just in terms of there's a
if we want to talk about the problem
space in a means that is somewhat
agnostic of a particular application
focusing it on
you know the level of
breaking that breaking the problem the
compute problem apart and what needs to
be done locally versus not locally and
therefore what video processing has to
happen locally versus not locally and
one of the implications
might be helpful or as i said it might
be a complete red herring
uh no i think it's a it's a very valid
point and if i just off the top of my
head if i recall the
uh
uh satyanarayan and paper that we have
referenced in the draft they talk about
uh three tires so
you have the
the the actual device you have the
edge and you have the cloud
and the device actually represents the
design considerations of mobility and
sensing whereas the edge
deals with the design consideration of
network proximity
and the cloud deals with the design
consideration of i think compute
elasticity storage permanence and
hardware consolidation and within these
design constraints you
i guess
you need to consider
synchronization
and how it is affected by the
special nature of arvr applications
okay
um
so i think
i don't see anyone else in queue uh so i
think that the next steps are renin
you're planning a more detailed response
to the comments received on the mailing
list on the mailing list um i will take
this opportunity to
observe that the document is now in
github and thanks to you and kyle for
getting that sorted so people who prefer
to do github-based engagement
can now do so
and we've picked up at least one more
person offering to do review it was
karen who had offered to do a review of
the document and please share comments
with mailing list is there anything else
that we should cover here today
on this topic
okay all right thank you very much reena
and um
we'll head to the mailing list kyle you
were gonna say something
no no i was just gonna i was just gonna
say our our our next speaker is spencer
who may need to extricate himself from
his other meeting
thank you everyone thanks
thank you
thanks renen
spencer
sorry for the delay we'll we'll we'll be
with everyone in a moment we're just
trying to get spencer's attention
if not we can move on to the
to the next item
okay so i think that we probably should
do that um we'll tell in the chat we
will tell spencer that we've
reordered the agenda
um
and if you can't join us then i think we
can probably speak from his notes to the
mailing list
um i think there were some good
discussion points there yeah
okay all right
uh lee if you could
give us your update on the packet
differences yes thank you
should i
if if you want to share uh slides you
can click on the share preloaded slides
button at the top left
and then select your your deck
presentation review
which one
okay got it
yes
so can you see my
screen uh yeah we're looking at your
screen as opposed to the slides that
were uh that were in the uh
uh
that we uploaded from the data tracker
but it's fine
you might want to put it into
presentation mode though so we don't see
all of the
okay right now
yep that looks good okay
yeah great um
so um i wanna have a summary of the
feedback that i received from the last
meeting
so the comments were i think in summary
i think the comments are mainly related
to how to review the characteristics of
the microblocks containing the packets
to the network and implement the
selective packet dropping at the packet
level so i want to emphasize on the
packet level so i'm very glad that the
concept is very um well received in my
mind and we think it is beneficial to
improve the quality of experience of
video streaming by reducing the package
dropping
granularity from the current traffic
class level to the individual packet
level which means
inside a flow
each individual packet may have its own
significance level
and the router could treat those
individual packets differently
or even within the within the packet
itself
um
yes and we need such information of
whether this packet is significant or
not to be reviewed network nodes
for example
api could be implemented to
input such information or metadata from
the application which might be mapped to
the you know ipv6 extension header or
ipv4 options or a dedicated metadata
field in the ip header
um you know and i want to thank um
drake about the you know the for the
reply in the email list um we will take
a closer look at your your comments
because we haven't gotten much time in
the morning to read carefully about each
sentence in the email
um and we will reply you later offline
um
but um
for the
for the div serve i want to say is the
traffic management is at the class level
which means the ad router will look into
some
uh fields like source destination
addresses and flow id to map
traffic to map list packet to certain
traffic class which means
that inside of flow
the packets would have the same
significance
if this server is used but yes i will
carry the discussion offline in an email
list
next
i want to talk a bit more on the major
characteristics of video frames that
could affect the significance of a
single packet
the first one is the frame type we all
know pack 4 has you know have
three types of frames iframe is
self-contained
so which means
it will have no references to other
frames and it is encoded by itself and
it is the keyframe that provides
checkpoints for re-synchronized
synchronization or re-entry to support
trig modes and aerial
recovery
um we we can think this is most
important type of frames uh in a whole
stream and p frame
is the predictive frame which means
it can allow macroblocks to be
compressed using temporal prediction in
addition to spatial
prediction so for a motion estimation
keyframes could use frames that have
been previously encoded it could be a
proof p frame it could be iframe
so for a b frame it stands for
bi-directional
uh frames which means i will refer to
the frames that occur both before and
after it
so each macro block of a b frame can be
predicted using backward prediction or
using forward
prediction so accordingly
um
the next characteristic i want to point
out is the whether the packet contains
frame that are referenced by other
frames so according to this prediction
relationship among different frames so
each frame might be referenced by other
frames
um
so for iframe the iframe does not refer
to any other frame so is is at least but
it is at least referenced by a keyframe
after it so the losing the first iframe
in the group of pictures would cause
videos picture even missing a few
seconds
um because p and b frames referencing to
i from it would not be decoded nor
displayed either for a p frame it
because it refers to a picture in the
past
um
however you also might be referenced by
a p frame after it or a b frame before
or after it
and for a b frame
can i it can also act as a reference
in the real case it's not a common case
so if b frame is referenced by others it
is termed as a reference b frame
but in the normal case or you know
common case the b frame is not used as a
reference so it is usually called as
non-reference b frame
another important characteristic of
impact video packets is the movement
level of the video sample contained in
the packet
the video things with the low level
movement or less sensitive to both b
frame and p frame packet loss for
example if right now we are having a
conference call my background or um
my body if i did not move much
it has very low level movement contained
in the video
so the
the video things with you know were not
very sensitive to the b frame or p frame
packet loss but on the other hand if
you're watching football
uh video on live video um it is um
you know the movement level is very high
and you will be very sensitive or more
sensitive to both b frame and p frame
packet loss so for loss the p frame can
impact the remaining part of the gop
um or while a lost b frame has only
local effects you know slowly moving
content or very large stack background
like you know my video right now if i'm
sharing so you know think of dynamically
moving content loose
b frame has more true
magic impact and scale can be as far
reaching as a p frame loss so if we can
have some level of
estimation or indication of the movement
level with of the video sample
containing packets we can
you know combine with other knowledge of
the packet we can
have more
uh information regarding the
significance of the packet
um the last one i want to point out
um is the um is whether the video sample
contained in the packet belongs to
a region of interest or not
um the microblocks that are identified
to represent objects in roi are more
important than other microblocks of
non-roi regions
for example we are watching a video
um you are more you are paying more
attention to certain object or certain
person in the video than other
microblocks that are representing other
objects or background is not are not so
important
compared uh compared to the macroblocks
of the roi
um so based on those characteristics of
the mempac video packets you we probably
could use some
um
some way of calculating the import
importance of those
of those of the individual packets um i
did not show here in the
in the slides but what i can think of
is you know based on the frame type we
think that iframe is the most important
so we probably give more
uh
weight to the eye frame frame and for
those frames that are referenced by
others are would be given more um weight
and for the movement based on the
movement level
you know if the movement level is high
then the b frame and p frame would would
have more
importance or more weight than
uh b frame and p frame with less
movement
and then you know if
would think the the pack leaf has roi uh
object then maybe we have higher weights
so we can combine all those factors
uh into um a
certain calculation method i i
personally i don't have a good answer
but we can think of one light by putting
different
weights on those important things
then maybe we can come up of a
significant level force or individual
packets
so
uh here is the summary of the
requirements of network and applications
uh so we think the application needs to
in order to make this work we need it
needs to reveal some information to
network to enable is selective packet
dropping you know examples could be you
know receiving any users rough
preference on the media quality so what
is your tolerance quality degradation
regarding to the example
uh resolution so if you are watching uh
um
before you know 4k video uh is it is it
okay for you to watch uh um you know 480
uh p video or not if it is okay maybe uh
some of the packets does not need do not
need to be
dropped um but those you know like the
iframes should be
maintained other frames could be dropped
and other things like the characteristic
of the media content i presented earlier
and also um you know
like are for example the ior the frame
type
um whether the pack contains frames that
are referenced by others and
correspondingly the network should be
able to leverage above information
reviewed by the application and then
selectively drop packets or
potentially parts of the packets from
com from competing media stream flows
um and re-transmission we can think in
that way re-transmission could be
maximally eliminated because some of the
packets
that are important have already received
by the receiver and the receiver can
accept this qualitative degree
qualitative degradation
then other parts of the packets do not
to be retransmitted again
so the receiving end user is able to
consume in the uh deliver packets as
many as possible in time with acceptable
quality
and this is the slide i added just now
those are the references to papers we
have published and the very first one
which we will publish in 2018 and the
recent one
that were very relevant to this paper oh
sorry to this
uh contribution is this one the um
the coded communication for emerging
network applications with new iep which
is to be appeared as a invited paper in
proceedings of the um
17th international offers on mobility
sensing and networking
okay that's all for my presentation i
would like to see any comments
jake
um
the uh
i guess i'd like to
to clarify um i think you characterize
the
responses as
positive so far i'm not sure i would
call my view on this positive at this
stage
uh i think there might be potential here
but what i'd be interested to see is um
it so first off i think the the problem
of differential
dropping that you communicate to the
network
is exactly what diffserv can do and
that's a that's a good approach that's a
much better approach in my opinion than
um
uh option header
ideas that you mentioned um but i think
there are
challenges uh and that you you'd have to
be looking at a controlled uh
at a controlled network either way
so
i guess
what i'm interested in is basically
really what do you gain out of this i
think this is a thing that you can do in
experiment already i'd like to see
quantitative
results discussing it
in terms of uh user q08 qoe before i'd
like to see this um
really
given a lot more time
but uh
that's just kind of
my view i think it's it's a potentially
interesting thing
but
like
the the fact that iframes are different
uh does not necessarily imply that
dropping them less often gives you a
better qoe without the sort of
measurement to that effect and i guess
i'd like to
uh
you know there's probably constraints on
that i guess i'd like to see an
exploration of what do you actually get
that's that's my main feedback here but
thank you
yeah um no i i did not regard
regard your email as a
very positive uh feedback but
i do thank you for you know uh replying
me through the email list giving me
comments
um
for deep serve i want to point out it is
a course-grained class-based mechanism
for traffic management
which means at the edge of diffserv
domain
the edge router would look into the
source destination addresses and the
flow id to determine
the you know the dscp value for that
packet so it does not mean
the packet within the flow would have
different significance levels or dsap
assignment
because the router would only look at
the source and destination and the flow
id
we will not look at anything else to
determine this vp value
so within
i agree if you use the router to set the
value however i think you can set the
value at the host and have it
uh come in with the disk serv id which
then would be treated differently by the
router so i guess i'd encourage you to
look at that instead where the sender
sets it according to the sock up there's
the
iptos
api in in linux for example and if you
can set that at the host then i think
you'll be able to perform experiments
that do not depend on
router understanding the class and just
use the class just based on the incoming
diffserv
at the router layer when you try to when
you try to go between different diffserv
domains but just to just declare clarify
that point um but good luck uh that it
sounds
interesting if it uh if it really pans
out so uh you know
yeah i would take a look take a look at
what you mentioned yes okay
thanks jake uh magnus
uh yes so i i definitely have to
support one of these comments here
really about
do you have any video quality of
experience results for this type of work
because i mean i think you presented a
very simplified view of how the latest
video codecs achieve their high
performance
and and you're down to ipm
reference structures etc on macrobot
level and then that's
i mean that's all mixed up so
for getting this to work properly to my
understanding you need to ensure that
you can actually separate out the data
you want to drop
for both that it works through both your
security solutions and your framing
solutions
and formatting yet still get readable by
stream so i mean
uh
i i hope you have some
qe results that you really can show that
because before you can show it that even
get that with the framing in place for
those applications i don't see a point
of doing this because
i think that's usually being when
looking at this this kind of
barrier
so it's it's not worth it
yeah yeah
thank you for your comment yeah yes so
um
be honest i i my background is not uh um
video coding sites i'm more you know
networking side or mostly networking
side
so for uh here we want to point out the
you know there there is um could be
significance differences among package
by using this use case
we did some research
on what are the characteristics could be
could be leveraged but
i think those characteristics could be
you know does do not need to be revealed
to the network uh you want one hand
because you know if we
could have the help
from the codex or application
by saying okay list packet
because it has those uh
kinds of characteristics so i would
um indicate it is more important than
the other packets in the stream so we
will have the application or codecs to
do that instead of you know network try
to tries to understand those
characteristics
yeah
sure but i mean the the the issue here
is that you have a very interactive
system is that if you drop a certain
amount of packets your video quality
will be
subjected to different it will really
get different results and that depends
on how your system so you actually need
to have it do both parts here to figure
out and see what results you actually
can get and that i think is is the kind
of homework you need to go do here and
you also say no there's some properties
here yes you can code those properties
if you can determine which packets etc
and you can actually cut out the data
but i think you need to start from the
application and then come to
what you need from the network i think
you're kind of starting from network
here and going backwards so
uh yeah yeah yeah uh i understand uh yes
um i think your comments are very
legitimate um so um yeah
the application yeah we definitely need
to support front application side
because in order to have this
information
or the significance of the packet
known to the to the you know network
list information needs to be calculated
or some kind of
a revealing uh front application to the
network and as you said
dropping some parts some packets may
result in the quality of quality
degradation
but if the any user is able to tolerate
that
then maybe it is okay
right so um
as i said if you know i'm watching 4k at
certain point i'm only watching 480p
i'm okay with that then the
retransmission of those other frames may
not need it
but um i think what you commented
earlier uh very legitimate that the
application does need
needs to support less kind of operation
in the network
and
okay all right
all right yeah i closed the queue
because we're we're pretty much out of
time but uh
but i want to thank you for doing your
presentation
thank you guys thank you very much jake
and others for comments
follow up from the specific discussion
points as this as outlined
i think the thought people probably want
to be putting
[Music]
putting on the table is um if
if this is going to go forward at the
itf what is the appropriate place for it
to go uh i don't think the mops working
group would be the right place but um
perhaps we can help
shape it up to the point where it is
something that can go to another working
group
that would be helpful definitely great
all right thank you um
all right so
spencer is still
busy elsewhere
um
i don't think we are going to skip right
over the
mock item um
i think that we need to
at least speak a little bit about the
notes that spencer sent to the mailing
list
um
so the media over quick
side meeting
occurred earlier this week
i was not there um i'm probably not the
best person to to present the report out
from it
um i don't know if you want to give it a
go kyle or um
if we want to see how much i can make up
on the fly
um
probably not the i'm probably not the
right person to do that um
was anyone else there who has uh who
feels confident enough about the uh
about their uh their understanding of
the outcome
uh you could give a brief summary
i guess not all right
um
so
um spencer as i said forwarded the
mailing list to point her to his notes
from the meeting
luke is in the uh is in the queue now
okay
luke would you like to take the baton
um so yeah i was uh i joined like 15
minutes late to the the media of a quick
mailing list but also being
kind of responding a bit and
you know even even try to get it formed
um really it comes down to there's a lot
of different media use cases right
there's a lot of different protocols out
there you guys you guys know that
there's um
uh this whole swap and there's this new
uh transport layer um uh quick
and really this is just an exploration
of uh
what we could use quick for um
there are some companies and some
individuals that are using it already to
um to deliver media but most of the
meeting was about
what use cases exist
people speaking up saying like oh we
need seeking support or oh we need you
know i want peer-to-peer or all this is
for real time this is for gaming and try
to trying to explore
what existing standards exist uh at ietf
and and whatnot uh and also what would
be a good use case for for quick and
what changes would be required for quick
but the meeting didn't really cover that
too much so right now it's still in an
exploratory phase it's still trying to
figure out
what working group or groups um
uh could be created to deal with this um
if they're even necessary uh
and uh
yeah it's it's it's it's it's a really
rough state right now just trying to
come up with requirements and kind of
come up with what desired target use
cases there are
okay
thank you for that and thank you for
leaping in the last moment
um my understanding from spencer's notes
is that a large part of the conclusion
is that it's important to sort of stake
out you know what use cases people want
to pursue or at least be clear about
what use cases are in play
um i don't know if glenn you want to
speak to your follow-up on that point
assuming glenn is still here
ben is still here
yeah either yeah so um and i can't
remember which lists my comments ended
up on you last night but i made the
observation that
you know
this is a pretty big ocean and
there's lots of different applications
that something we we
you know
chewed through when we created mops in
the first place right just because
there's so much
there's some stuff that's really well
developed with some stuff that's sort of
in the midpoint development use case
wise and some stuff that's sort of like
well hey this is really cool now that we
have this we can do these new things
let's explore
and
it seemed like you know and i by the way
i should say i'm very supportive of the
mock
stuff so i'm i'm coming from a friendly
voice here
i think there's some cases um in
particular i i suggested things like um
ingest uh median just because we already
have existing
reliable protocols like srt that have
said that they're playing with um you
know going over quick uh and there's
other you know applications and we've
seen postings from parties that are
using quick experimentally for ingest
but the use cases for ingest are fairly
well developed so i suggested hey for
the very well-developed stuff maybe
that's what mock could build a charter
around and expand upon and focus on
um
and then for other things maybe it's
time to come back into other groups like
like mops mock mobs
we name these things badly um
but come back into mops for discussion
because i think what mops is very good
at is allowing things to sort of evolve
to a more mature state and then find the
appropriate home to go to
um and that was sort of my take on on
the two things and again very supportive
of of the mock stuff so
what exists today i can help illuminate
so first off uh my cat's on the mouse
hopefully it doesn't meet me um
uh i'm actually i work at twitch and
we're pushing uh releasing a quick based
video delivery protocol
um using web transport
uh i know facebook is using quick for
ingest already with their player um and
uh
in this case we've got two kind of
production ready implementations and
then people have been experimenting with
um
rtp over quick and also srt as you
mentioned srt is trying to proxy
over quick as well so there's a few
different areas there's a few different
implementations out there it's really
too early to tell what works well
um and what maps will as well too quick
um
because sometimes it's it's like you
mentioned
the space is pretty well developed and
you need to have a compelling reason to
use it like not just using the
technology because it exists
i see jonathan's entered the queue
jonathan
you actually wanted to ask uh uh to luke
because he's mentioned his
implementations what he's found you know
what he's found so far like you know
what what is quick giving him that you
know existing like say tcp or udp based
things wouldn't do for him
um in particular is he taking advantage
of some of the
more complicated reliability and
ordering
because i think that's sort of where the
interesting things happen for media
reading more and more over time on the
the mock mailing list um i already i did
post one thread about uh the problems
that we've seen
we're an hls based um stack and uh
with some modifications um but it really
comes down to um headline blocking like
you're forced to download a single
segment you're downloading it
sequentially and when there's congestion
what do you do
um quick gives you the option to have
things in parallel so kind of uh
coordinate them together
uh to cancel them better and stuff like
that um and that's really what we're
utilizing and we're also in a position
that we have our own cdn so it's very
easy to just push data over web
transport but you could totally do this
with hdb3 as well it's just harder
so i think um
i think that we have achieved the
ambition of raising awareness and doing
some cross-pollination uh between the
mock effort and mops i think there are
some suggestions on the table that mops
might be able to help
um
base some of the discussions going
forward in terms of taking some use
cases but i think that we'll have to see
if that
transpires on the mailing list
um
and apart from that i guess
we would like to see how the mock work
continues going forward i think that's
about as much we can draw from this
absent a strong proponent in the room
okay
all right
um
so also keep your eyes peeled from for
mock yeah keep your eyes peeled for mock
meetings and upcoming ietf meetings join
the mailing list get engaged
all right kyle go for it
all right so can everybody see the
slides
i'll assume that's yes
so uh this is the the mops two-year
retrospective can you believe it's been
slightly over two years since the
working group was formed um you can
almost smell the benzene of the
retrospecticus
that's a simpson's reference if nobody
gets it anyway so
i'm i'm afraid that the that the first
part of this deck is going to be a bit
of a downer but you know it gets better
i promise so uh so here's how it started
um
basically two years ago well up until
two years ago there were some side
meetings the the ggie meetings and then
the video interest group side meetings
that went on for for several years
um in montreal in 2019 uh is when we had
the mops buff
where we got you know we essentially had
a discussion about about whether it was
uh reasonable to make a working group
and what the scope of the charter would
be and what not and so finally in
november it was formed just before the
singapore ietf
um and so we had our first in-person
session at uh in singapore
uh and then in march the uh the
vancouver meeting was cancelled
and so here's how it's going now
um note the the the highlighted virtuals
there
which is kind of uh
it's
so i think it's been it's been
kind of a downer for a lot of working
groups but i think it's especially been
a it it's been a special challenge for
for mops because of the nature of a lot
of the work that we do
right so
um i just
took a screenshot of the milestones
quickly there's a you know like we we've
this is this was a snapshot that i took
earlier this week and i know that we've
bumped some of these dates up or back i
guess um several times
as we have kind of missed milestones we
have you know obviously we have a few
done
but we still have a lot of work that we
intended to do at the beginning that is
not done yet
um
these are the two documents we've
adopted it seems you know it seems a
little meager but you know on the other
hand that you know publishing documents
was not the main purpose of mobs to
begin with it never was
um what is our main purpose well
if you look at
um
damn the uh
this is in the wrong place in the slide
all right anyway there's some
we i'll come back to the slide
so if you look at our charter right i've
highlighted kind of the the verbs the
actions that that mops was chartered to
take on
uh solicit regular updates solicit input
uh solicit discussion and documentation
there are a number of things here and
many of them are rendezvous functions
right they are functions of getting
people in the same room together to
discuss common sets of problems and come
up with either you know classes of
solutions or direct you know figure out
where there are gaps in existing
standards and direct work to to other
working groups within the itf and uh and
outside sdos
and so without those
without those hallway conversations
without the you know like the you know
having a bunch of people in the
hackathon room like working on the same
thing or doing demos um without a lot of
tourists coming to mops because you know
because they just they're they happen to
have a free slot and they're like all
right let me go you know go into this
room it looks interesting um
without the you know a lot of the
cross-pollination of having everyone in
the same physical space talking about
problems and seeing where there are
where there's overlap and where there
are you know potential synergies between
work and seeing the the reduction in new
work overall i mean that's been a real
drag from virtual meetings and i think
it's it's impacted mops more than a lot
of other working groups which had
which had explicit
um work items in progress and moving but
it probably has also impacted working
groups that
uh that have been trying to find new
work as well i'm sure it differs from
group to group but it's just this is
just has been my observation based on
talking to other people so
um that having been said we've uh
we've solicited a bunch of presentations
we've had a bunch of interesting talks
will law talked a few meetings ago
um
new participants have come to us they've
actually sought out mops talked to us
and we've hooked them up with people in
in the working group and have them come
in and give give presentations
and moreover there have been a lot of
intangibles that mobs have provided
right we're responsible for a bunch of
conversations happening even though
they're not having it happening in a
physical hallway they're happening on
the internet in virtual hallways
um and so like i think that a lot of
that things like things like uh like
mock things like uh the the renaissance
multicast
uh work on reducing latency are all
things that mops has assisted in in
helping get more attention uh paid to
these things um and uh assisted in
bootstrapping some of this work and so i
think that's that's you know that's a
lot of what we've done now going back to
to the earlier slide uh some other
things that we've done um
that that mops has done in addition to
the you know in addition to kind of the
the uh the work internal to the working
group is providing external community
engagement right so
uh the smt smpte updates sympty updates
uh streaming video alliance updates
um we have a paper that we submitted to
simpty
earlier this year
that we're going to be presenting on in
uh i think it's in december
uh but don't quote me on that um so
there's
there's a bunch of stuff that we've done
and i'm you know i'm pleased with how
the with how the working group has been
has been going
but i mean there are questions about how
we can increase um the efficacy of the
working group like what can we do to
make ourselves more effective
right i mean meeting in person yeah that
would be great that would
you know solve a lot of the problems
that you know or or at least eliminate
many of the challenges that we see today
but
unfortunately that's not actionable
we're either going to have an in-person
meeting or we're not and we don't have
any control over that that's going to be
a you know that's a kind of a shared uh
decision uh among all the itf
participants
do we just carry on as is are things
going well enough that we think that
we're you know that we're on the right
track um you know we should just make
incremental changes from here on in um
do we broaden draft scope or we talked
before about uh looking at the augmented
reality draft and saying well maybe this
is maybe the the use case is much more
specific than the problems described so
maybe we ought to broaden the scope
there it's another option
um
some things that we probably should do
is figure out how to unblock some of the
unmet milestones right i mean we have
milestones that we added to the data
tracker back at the very beginning and
they haven't you know some of them
haven't been finished yet right so what
can we do to get those moving along
um
should we solicit feedback from
non-participants are there people who
have you know thought about
participating in mops uh and decided not
to or are there people who don't know
about mops and maybe we ought to figure
out maybe why they don't why they don't
know about it
um should we coordinate with in-progress
standards activity uh going on elsewhere
in in the ietf right so uh
so uh we could have uh we could do
something experimental like designate
point participants for interaction with
other with other working groups both
within the ietf and other standards
organizations and get
you know either written reports or or
just you know presentations at meetings
uh so that we can kind of
spread information about these things in
a more efficient manner
um having some forecasts
about where we think the industry is
going
so we can foresee what what areas of
work might need doing and then kind of
bring that information to relevant uh
working groups that's another that's
another uh option
um
do we have uh do we wanna have some sort
of vision or road map for itf
contributions to the media ecosystem
right so the media ecosystem is vast and
confusing ietf participants may only see
a small part of it and not understand
how it fits into sort of the the larger
media ecosystem and so maybe we could
develop some problem statements for
internet media operations to clarify
some of the challenges that we're seeing
um and maybe to use the the challenges
to then suggest uh directions for future
work
um and finally uh you know uh
should we solicit input from other
working groups facing similar challenges
right i i think one of the things i
don't have a good a good beat on is to
what extent other working groups are
seeing engagement challenges
uh resulting from the lack of in-person
meetings and i'd you know and and
whether you know if some other working
groups have seen similar challenges what
have they done
uh over the past you know 20 months to
to uh
to help work on those
so uh now i'm going to throw it open to
to the floor for thoughts suggestions
um looks like glenn wants to make some
comments yeah and probably to peddle
some of the crap that i've just said
before we get there uh before we get
there i think um
we should ask eric to give an update on
the iesg review of the working group
since that was one of our milestones
to request uh
speaking so thank you for inviting me
before i actually request
indeed so you know the mops is a kind of
a
time bomb attached to it right we need
to kind of renew the working group
for me
uh it's okay it's doing uh i was really
concerned the beginning of this meeting
right when i saw
at the top of the hour only 11 people
attending the meeting it was kind of
scary because
mobs is basically to
attract people sharing the same common
interests right so now we we peak at 40
we are 33 so
that's okay i think uh i've also heard a
very interesting discussion in the last
two hours or an hour and a half
so i'm pretty satisfied i know that
warren which is kind of the ops um
area director right so i'm interior
director but not using uh in synopse
is also happy with the
functioning and
how mops works he's unable to join today
because i guess it's a dns office at the
same time it is of course more important
for him than mobs
the
issue of other working group
with these
not in person meetings is everywhere
right
it's more critical here like you said
guy because it was really
met uh mean
as a
place to gather people with the shared
interest but the lack of work
is eating mostly everywhere specifically
the lack of new work
so we have a measure at the isg about
the number of dash zero zero draft
and this one is lower than two years ago
for all the working groups
uh we don't do it per area so maybe some
areas are more
uh impacted than others but it's
everywhere
okay and as leslie we talked also before
when god and myself and and lastly we
were preparing this meeting
that
you think i had no time to investigate
further but you think that
the new zero zero uh
only coming from very interested parties
right so with a kind of a lot of
small party trying to do new work
um
so for me i'm pretty fine uh we already
discussed the mops at the previous iesg
meeting
uh and it was continuing right so
everyone says okay go on
and i remember what i said last time iot
ops
is very similar
to mobs right and more and more when you
do both for creating new work including
sometimes say oh is it ala
right uh is it a mobs like
so
mobs now is a an adjective somehow right
uh in the isg slang so for me yes it is
it's okay
it's a good job and good job summary uh
kind by the way
thanks eric and just to close the loop
my understanding is that the uh
we were reviewed after two years and we
are not dead yet so um
just to be clear
yeah two years it's maybe it's basically
you know right there is a debrief of the
isg and the iab
next week
uh
i will talk about mobs there and say yes
it's two years it's extended one year
okay thank you
everybody
sort of damocles is still there
[Laughter]
ben
i was wrong in that i don't want to
correct anything he said i thought you
did it really well thanks kyle um for
running through that i i just want to
add you know i've been a long-time
proponent for mops you know going way
back
and and you know i think we've done a
lot of good stuff um
you know the core problem that was a lot
of my motivation in the past is that we
have
the number one use the internet by you
know data and scaling and deriving to
add those bigger pipes is video
and we've always had a sort of a
historic slight disconnect with
the representation of voices trying to
do video stuff
when we talked about things at the itf
and being a video guy that was always a
thing well we need to fix this and
you know
the reason why
other groups of the itf you know are
very active i think you produce a lot of
zero zero drafts as eric points out is
that we have a real established
community especially if you look at
transport i mean transport's been core
at the itf for how long and and and
things like dns has been core at the itm
this is the home where those people come
and they talk they have a community
established um you know we have a number
of
parties from different organizations
that all know each other have known each
other for decades that come together and
work on problems
and i think that we're sort of the early
days of reaching that gap between the
itf and these video guys out there which
are producing all these documents
but i'm seeing a very positive you know
developments you know i'm seeing that we
have
um you know
when places like cd and i needed working
group chairs you know sanjay was around
uh to step up and become a co-chair of
cdni uh which connects to like you know
the real world and the real delivery
folks versus just people developing
technology uh you know and we have other
things that are being discussed and
thrown around
that is creating a welcoming home for
the people from that video world that
are doing all these video things on the
internet and driving all the traffic and
all the scalability to come into the itf
and have conversations and i think that
mobs has shown through the parties that
are coming here and i believe the
parties that will still come um that you
know when people ask the question you
know i come from a video world i i need
to engage with the itf i believe i want
to engage back to you how do i do that
but that now that box exists it's the
place to say well you can talk to the
box guys first they may not be the right
final destination
but they're the right first destination
and they can you know help you bring in
they can be a friendly voice a friendly
a friend face
and help things mature to a point where
they're ready then connect with other
itf working groups
and build that bigger community so it's
early days but i see that community
developing nicely and and i'm very
helpful hopeful that we're going to see
you know this continue on and and and
the relationships
grow and so that you know 10 years now
we're gonna have this whole room full of
you know itf video people that have
known each other for 10 years and when
there's a new problem a new thing to
work on this is where they come to do it
so that's just my two cents i want to
throw in
all right thanks glenn
uh sanjay
sanjay did you want to go ahead
yeah yeah i i just wanted to uh echo
what uh glenn just said uh so well i
think there's a lot of issues that
are not necessarily
well defined in terms of that you know i
know i know i need some work on
protocols so i i
itf working groups are the right place
there are many cases operationally where
um mob seems like a good you know first
place to start and bring the question
that
that may not be you know
wanting to change the protocol but maybe
you know
the
making sure that you understand it and
you implement it right so some of those
types of areas really fit well within
you know what this working group can
offer so
i think there's a great deal of value
and
obviously the
as um
kyle was saying that you know we don't
have the luxury right now of meeting in
person so a lot of those hallway
conversations
that may happen and that may lead to
people that are attending a specific you
know working group but they may show up
here because
oh yeah that's really an operational
issue that at least we should bring it
back into the mob's working group so we
we kind of don't have that
uh right now but regardless of that i
think this is a good venue where
um
i know sva can benefit a lot you know
streaming video alliance there are a lot
of different operational issues and best
practices that they are dealing with
some of which might actually lead to
some work in in the um
within the different working groups
within ietf but
at least mops is one place where we can
we think we can bring some of the
discussions
great
thank you sanjay
yeah yeah i agree and i i think it's i
think it's clear that it's it's been
useful to a lot of folks so i'm uh
i'm optimistic um and i'm definitely
supportive of continuing the working
group
um
from the chair standpoint i think the
only thing that's really troubling me in
all of this is how quiet the mailing
list is and as i alluded to earlier the
sort of
bifurcation between the people who come
to meetings and the discussion that
doesn't happen on the mailing list and i
don't entirely know how to address that
i mean i think the reality is a lot of
mailing lists have gotten quiet and just
because mail is so last century
um and
um
it isn't helped by the fact that we
don't have the sort of vibrant
people know each other community thing
going on but i'm i'm saying it here in
my out loud voice just because i think
it is an area that we're going to have
to find answers to
um
if we want to successfully progress
through discussions of
topics and documents and last calls and
whatnot
um as as we go along
glenn are you wanting to say more or are
you just
lounging in queue
scared him out of cue
nope
i'm not the microphone
luke
say from my personal experience i
haven't known when to interact with this
working group like even just a little
blurb about media over quick earlier i i
wasn't sure if it's appropriate to like
say what i've been working on in this
working group or if i should just go
straight to like a more specific one
like media over quick so it kind of
means
at least in my mind i
discussions are
either scoped correctly already uh or
end up in like the catch-all and mops
right well and i think it's it's a good
question and and maybe partly because
even if you review the history of
discussions on the on the mailing list
you're not going to see a lot of
exemplars but i mean
i would say at this point the mailing
list is going to be what we make it
um and
speaking of this one one chair i would
rather see more discussion there more
ideas tossed out there than fewer
so
certainly
please don't feel shy
yeah if something's off topic we'll
we'll let you know
kindly and gently like
in this specific example i can talk
about media over quick and it's fine
even if there is already another mailing
list for it
yeah i think that's a particular area
where you know
the ietf is trying to figure out what
it's doing so uh i wouldn't want to get
in the way of an organized activity of
media over quick but if there are things
that
we can do to help in discussion we'd be
happy to be
see it happen on the mailing list
all right any other
questions comments suggestions
complaints
come on people have to have complaints
all right
uh
oh jake
one last uh not not complaint i think
you guys are doing great uh but uh
regarding the mailing list being last
century it made me wonder there is a
ietf slack uh room should we
i'm not sure it'll be any better but uh
and it's
i'm in a couple of rooms there i think
it's usually pretty quiet but i'm not
sure if
uh if anybody would prefer that and i
thought i'd just ask um instead of
leaving it in chat or i think you got
missed yeah that's
that's a good question and i would
suggest if you don't mind dropping it in
the notes that would be great too
um i think that
we may want to do that
we're still going to wind up with the
same question we had about the working
group last call which is if it doesn't
happen on the mailing list it didn't
happen
um so it maybe we need a slack channel
and
more comments on the mailing list
one observation i wonder if part of you
know part of the the work we're doing
here is to bridge in culturally these
folks that aren't traditionally itf
people but coming from the video world
and i'm wondering if
we need to help uh them uh adapt to
what's appropriate on the itf family
lists you know if i'm new to an area i i
probably want to adapt whatever the
local culture is
and since we're fairly low volume and
fairly new uh we don't have necessarily
like a demonstratable culture that they
can plug right into and i'm not sure how
to solve it other than say you know
we're very welcoming and please post uh
maybe those of us who are here already
just need to take it upon ourselves to
be a little more chatty on the list
um to demonstrate sort of a culture of
openness and engagement
yep
that's a good suggestion thanks
all right well uh unless anybody has any
other other business i think we are at
we are at time and we are done
kyle anything else
i don't have anything else
well then thank you very much jake for
taking the notes and thanks everyone who
helped
thanks to our presenters and thanks to
everyone engaging in discussion here
as always it was i thought a useful
meeting and
great have a great rest of iutf
to see you soon thanks everyone
you