so
okay it is
the right at the top of the hour
and we have a pretty full agenda today
so i think we should get started sound
good
um
all right so
welcome everyone this is ippm ip
performance measurement um
i'm tommy paulie
one of your chairs
marcus here is a
new chair joining us so please welcome
marcus and
thank you marcus for stepping up
ian is stepping down in his chair i
don't see him here
um so we may need to just bid him adieu
uh virtually on the list
but um he's been very helpful for the
past
you're in a bit
okay
this is pretty far into the week so
you've probably seen the note well
before um
if you haven't
if this is your first group of the week
this is
essentially describing all of the
requirements and expectations for
participating in ietf meetings
the various processes we have around
ipr as well as around how you
participate
and one thing we want to highlight
specifically this time
is just uh some of the aspects of the
code of conduct you know this group i
think you know for the entire time i've
been here has been very good at
um interacting well with each other but
it's good to just remember
um and have it at the forefront of our
minds as we're interacting in the group
that
you know this is a group with a lot of
different people from different
backgrounds and
the most important thing we can do here
is to treat each other with respect
and to make sure that we're clear
and making it easy for everyone to
understand and participate
and that we focus on
having you know technical discussions um
that are getting at the details so that
we can help progress the work
not uh
getting into anything uh personal or
just trying to stop work um and we're
trying to find the best solutions for
the whole internet so just keep this in
mind in your contributions at the mic
and on jabber and i'm looking forward to
a great meeting
for the meeting management
you are here you are in meet echo um
just as a note when you want to queue
use the little join queue hand sign
um
that's up by your name on the side of
meet echo
you can turn on your own video and audio
if you are a presenter
all of the slides are pre-loaded
um through meet echo
and there's next to the hand button
there's the file button
that allows you to um share slides that
will you'll be able to request sharing
slides when
someone else is no longer sharing slides
we do have a lot of presentations and a
number of
quick elevator pitches so there are
like 20 slides pre-loaded in here so
make sure to grab the right one
and be ready to do that
the notes can be found
here i guess they're no longer etherpad
um we should update that on the slide
they're in hedge talk but you can find
them here and lucas is helping us take
notes
um
and
yeah and if you see someone in jabber
trying to say something on the mic who
can't get audio
please relate that and uh marcus can and
i can watch that as well
okay so on to our agenda
we're going to start with uh
a good amount of time
um
about an hour going over our primary
documents the things that we currently
have adopted
in the working group we have some new
things we adopted since last time around
iom
that we want to spend a bit of time
going over
and then in the second half of our
meeting we have some new proposed work
specifically we have three documents
that we want to go over with 10 minutes
each and this first one is related to
some work that came out of a recent iab
workshop on network quality so that is
some of the background of the discussion
that happened there
but all of these had
some discussion on the list and interest
from the group
and the remaining time will be
a number of quick elevator pitches we're
trying a new style this time where
rather than trying to limit based on
time we want people to summarize what
they're doing within a single slide so
that we can get all of the information
up front and hopefully save more time
for discussion and feedback
and not just be trying to fill up the
whole time of the lightning talk
with um
just you know a presentation of blasting
information at
people all right so that's all i have
welcome ian
and
we we already mentioned that you will be
stepping down and thank you again for
your service
um
all right
is there any agenda bashing or should we
jump right in
okay i don't see anyone coming up
so our first
presentation will be about some of the
iom data integrity and deployments
and frank if you could uh
ask to share slides
do the session for uh
for us this time on iom i just got my my
third jab yesterday
and i'm
kind of okay but i'm not feeling that
well uh so uh
thanks for that
yeah okay
thank you
so here we go um
this is going to be a quick update i
hope we'll have more discussion time uh
since we have 25 minutes allocated for
these two drafts these were
the two new drafts which
were initiated because of the feedback
that was received on the iom data draft
both these drafts were adopted between
last and the
this just before this itf
um
we had discussed data integrity draft in
the last ippm
last two ippm meetings and
we had a bunch of options to meet the
data integrity requirements for the
um for the iron
protocols carrying iom options
uh the changes uh um just highlighting
the changes that happened
uh post
while we adopted this work here
first change major change was changing
it from informational to standard stack
because we are defining
uh integrity based options uh which are
parallel to the the iom data options
that are defined are i options that
could be defined in
other graphs like the direct direct
export draft
um then
we based on the feedback from uh
multiple folks in in the work group we
uh we adopted method three uh which is a
symmetric key based uh signature
to protect the integrity of the options
as uh the as as the proposed method
and mode
all the other methods that were
discussed earlier were in the appendix
that got removed because
as as part of the adoption and feedback
received
during the adoption call
and there were some editorial changes
done for example we had given examples
specific to the options that are there
in the iom data draft but had not
explicitly mentioned
uh options in the direct export or any
other iom drafts that could come come up
in future but uh
data integrity is quite generic it
should apply to anything any iom options
uh
that are that are defined in
uh beyond the data draft
that that is fixed now and
some terminology fixes we had called the
inter i mean we were not following the
the nomenclature used in the data draft
which is now fixed
uh so we we do have uh additional
feedback and some of the internal
discussions among the authors to improve
the security sections
we definitely want more input on uh yeah
we have as2
as256 and chart56 plus hcsa based uh uh
algorithms that could be used for diff
for carrying out the signature but
uh we appreciate feedback from other
folks more familiar with what would be
other reasonable combination of
hashing and signature algorithms that
could be
that should make it into that list
and more reviews on the integrity
methods that is adopted is
appreciated
and plus if anybody wants to try out the
implementation uh of the data integrity
option
especially in the the kernel or in vpp
where we have the iom data options
implemented
that is appreciated
okay so that was about
the data integrity draft i'll i'll just
cover the deployment draft and then we
could have discussions unless somebody
has questions and we want to stop here
specifically on the integrity draft
okay
actually i just jumped in queue quickly
um a couple of questions on the
integrity draft so yeah thank you
very much for the work on cleaning it up
kind of consolidating down to one option
the
two questions i wanted to check on was
a status of implementing this solution
and testing it um
to see you know how it does this impact
kind of the existing iom code bases and
deployments
and then the other question is
should we
um
as a working group be requesting
early sector review and when do we think
we'd be ready
to do that to get that input from the
security area
on the implementation i i think it's
open for um
looks like we may have lost
sweat
hit the wrong button i don't know um i'm
not aware that anybody is coding the
thing up right now i'm not sure whether
justin is here who is driving most of
the work on the kernel
oh yeah we have just in here maybe he
can go and speak up
from
this perspective on what he's been
covering for either the colonel or
yes colleagues also within the vpp
implementation so i'm not sure where
that work is uh but i'm not aware of
anybody else um being actively coding
this thing up so maybe we can have other
people speak up here
from
perspective i think once we have i i
would not feel comfortable going for a
security review unless we have completed
the security section which is one big
leftover in the draw
so that is something that we want to go
and fill in
um
there was a little bit of a hush-hush
well you know tommy when you kind of
ping me can you get that out yeah i
could get that out and
um but um there is still a little bit of
work to be done on the draft i think
before we want to go and go for a proper
security review
um yeah that's sort of fitting in
section six is mandatory that's what
i've used
great great okay so
essentially our next step on this draft
is filling that in and then once that's
done
we can get a security
yeah along with what what is also asking
right so we have two combinations listed
right now for what people want to go and
do from a signing perspective and the
likes so what algorithms you would
appreciate if there's others that people
see as high priority let's go and speak
up on the list please
so that we have a relatively
comprehensive set of things included
um so that we are at least i think from
a from a working group perspective given
that this document is really a document
that has been
kind of shepherded and requested by the
working group uh that we have a
relatively good representation of what
is in there
right yeah
so please speak up and voice opinions of
what you want to go and see included so
that we're comprehensive
yeah
i i would suggest
the
small set of algorithms like just let's
you know choose kind of the best ones
that we need
but not
too many
uh
in there because that often times is a
bad
right
so it's
symmetric the ones for asymmetric but if
people have strong feelings around other
things then let's go and get that in
and as i said like um
yeah i think we could probably give it
another round for
the next meeting that will hopefully be
in person
and uh then maybe we will
really offer
and hopefully we can also find out from
implementations
you know which algorithms are convenient
for them to use or most conducive to
their code base
all right
thank you that's all i had
thank you sorry for the network glitch
i'll i'll continue with the deployment
draft
again this was adopted
recently and we have
revised it based on
basic feedback that was received some of
the feedbacks uh some feedback is
addressed in in the current zero zero
version of the
group draft
uh we aligned the the limited domains
per rfc 8799 and
again aligned it with the ion data
terminology
which was
which was good feedback that we received
uh we are going to continue keeping uh
this alive uh we want to keep it up to
date with uh the new deployment
experience that we have with
the the
kernel implementation as well as
another open source implementation in
fido vpp
we do have iom support for wireshark
which we we need to update the draft
with
further reviews are appreciated
and before we go into the discussion i
would just i want to go and give a big
hand to to al morton who caught a lot of
nits and so thanks al for for all the
feedback that you've been given until to
improve also the language and the draft
like
show in the queue
um
sherman do you want to speak up
during the
working club adoption poll of this job
i sent my
support and also a suggestion
to include
iom encapsulation over beer
into
this
chopped the scope of this job
but uh
it's not
in the zero zero version working group
draft
[Music]
is there any special reason why uh blm
is not included
i we have not addressed uh sorry good
friend
yeah you can blame me i think i forgot
about that i'm sorry for that
okay thank you
we'll fix that
good point thanks for bringing it up i'm
sorry
okay
yep um
that sounds good and i think we gained
back a lot of time which is very helpful
so all the other
presentations will appreciate it
thank you
so
next up we have iom confistate
and showman do you want to come back up
for that great
is my slide
okay to you
it looks good to me
okay good thank you thank you tommy
uh hello everyone uh it's xiaomi
speaking
this presentation is a accurate request
to apply for enabled institution
capabilities
this is a working group draft and the
latest version is zero one
zero zero version of this chapter has
already been presented at the last itf
this is the summary of the
two main updates in this revision
firstly this revision changes the format
of iom capabilities query
and
response from dlv to container
and the reason is that for icmp v6
and
taking example by rc
iom capabilities query is not
a tov of echo request
but the echo request itself
the same goes to iom capabilities
response
it's also not a tov
but the echo replied itself
secondly this revision changes the
format of response contents
from sub to v to object
and the reason is that
for icmp v6
the extensions contained in echo request
reply
are not to sub-tovs but objects
also note that
in six-man working group
and the zero zero version uh
individual draft
javascript uh six-man icmp v6 iom comp
state
has been posted
before ietf112
and
this new individual draft
has been presented in six-man working
group
on tuesday
my my personal feeling is that uh
i've got positive feedback from there
uh the internet
id and six man chairs
uh have no objection to
extend icmp v6 for iom capabilities
discovery
as long as
the ippm working group
has a rough consensus
is the right way to proceed
this slide is about the first
main update
that
changes query header and the response
header
from type lens to
container header
this figure shows the
instantiation
of container header
for icmp v6 iom echo messages
it can be seen that the container header
of icmpv6
does not include exactly uh type in the
lens
it includes a type code checksum
identifier sequence number and
a number of namespace ids
so this change is
needed also note that for nps lsb ping
f sfc ping and vrp
the container header is also applicable
this slide is about the second main
update
that changes response con contents
header from
sub tube
subtype lens to object header
this figure shows the
instantiation of object header
for icmp v6 iom capabilities object
it can be seen that the object header of
icmpv6
does not include exactly uh subtype and
the lens
it includes a
lens class number and the c type
so this change is needed
also note that for mpls ping
sfc ping and the beer ping
the object header is also applicable
except for them two main updates there
are also some other uh mentionable
updates
the first one that a list of namespace
ids
must be included in an echo request
in last version uh may is used here
we think master is more appropriate
specifically if you know any other
namespace id then a default one
zero x
four zero is provisioned at the iom
encapsulating node
then the default one must be included
if other namespace ids then the default
one are provisioned at the i am
encapsulating node
then the provision the namespace ids
must be
included
and the second dimensionable update
is that for the feature described in
this document to work
more optional pre
conditions are provided
they include the explicit path is used
or only one path can be used
or echo request message experiences
the same ecmp processing
as a data packet
the third mentionable update is that one
new double bit
is borrowed from the result field
of iom pre-allocated tracing
capabilities object
and incremental tracing capabilities
object
it's used to
indicate whether the object carries
a 16-bit egress
interface id or the
object carries a
32-bit egress
interface id
so uh next steps for
this chapter we
also
ask for more reviews and comments
uh we'll
revise this chapter to improve it
and then
we'll ask for working group
classical
and thank you
all right uh thank you frank go ahead
comments um
the first one is if you go back to slide
six
uh what we
seemingly do right now is that we have a
kind of opinionated choice of what we
want to go and get included into one of
these
echo replies that you're
transporting back to the requester
which is kind of a bit field that we
come up with here right and it's
inspired by the data types that we have
in the data draft but it's not the same
rather than coming up with kind of new
definitions here would it make sense
to rather
come up with an encapsulation or a
translation of the yang model that we
have
that describes the various fields
into an encapsulation into your
container that you want to go and carry
in your protocol
i think that would make much more sense
and it would avoid the redefinition of
fields rather than
yeah what we have here so i think
aligning that and coming up with a
mapping from the yang model that would
go and be encapsulated over icmp or
whatever carrier protocol you want
i think it's the cleaner approach
that's at least my suggestion and the
other point that i have is
we are starting to use icmp as a
network management protocol
so we should also go and treat it as a
network management protocol here
in the security section you say yeah
icmp can be
eventually secured with ah or even esp
headers included
um that's fine but i think we want to go
on the top language language that is
similar to what we use say for instance
in the netconf rfc
uh so there should be more
less cans but more shoulds of what you
want to go and use so that we have
proper security in place
because you probably need
at least
some form of integrity checking and even
more right because you can retrieve a
load of configuration information from
the notes this way
between the requester and the responder
that's it thanks
uh thank you
i i think uh
i i i uh know your comments uh
uh from uh previous itf meetings
but uh
i'm not sure uh how can i uh encapsulate
the young model uh
data into the
uh
into this response message
so is is that your uh first suggestion
to include the young model data into the
response
go and build an encoding
for the yang model
uh similar to what we've done for
netconf right
um
into uh what you're transporting here
and that would align that we have in
indeed like the yang model represented
in
the communication that you do between
the notes because end of the day i think
what you have with icmp define a
container and then you just ship
messages over that particular container
back and forth between the node and i
don't really see a reason why we should
go and treat icmp as a different
protocol than any other network
management protocol that you're using
here
right so the reason the wheel for a
specific let's not create a specific
encapsulation of a network management
protocol into icmp rather than
we have something generic for managing
individual um icmp individual iom notes
and let's stay with that and then you
just treat icmp as a carrier or beer as
a carrier or whatever
to my understanding uh if if we use
netconf here then we need to
establish a net kind of connection
between the encapsulated node and
each transition nodes
right
do netconf but i think you given that
you want to go and carry
network management information over a
channel you don't want to use netconf
you you're creating your own transport
protocol using icmp
but i think the
there is no need to go and redefine
what you do from an object's perspective
because that is in the young model
the reason why
we choose
yeah
the reason why
okay tommy
yeah i think
we're a little over time on this item
we're overall ahead on time but um
i think this is a
great discussion um i think this is a
good point to drill into um
and maybe this is something that
frank you know if
we can take this
to the list
and just kind of go
in depth on the different options about
how we can
not end up
uh
reinventing the wheel for the signal i
think that would be a good discussion to
have there
does that work for everyone
all right
any other questions or comments on this
okay it doesn't look like it
okay thank you yeah thank you thank you
very much this is good good update
okay
let's let's hammer out the
details be good
all right next up we have explicit flow
measurements
or
i want more than one spin bit
um
all right tomorrow
hi
hello
hello we can hear you do you want to
share your slides
using the preloaded slides yes you can
share my slide
you can drive it yourself so if next to
the hand icon
okay document
yep
so if you click on that
little file icon
file icon is this
okay yes yep exactly and so now i'm
going to approve you and then you should
be able to select
through all of the slides and find the
ones okay
okay
is
verbs
okay thank you i find
sure okay
there we go okay
we can start
okay
you can hear me
it's good to sound
okay we can start
okay i can summarize in a simple same
sentence
the specific measurement concept
explicit flow measurement techniques
employ a few marking bits inside the
head of each packet for los angeles
measurement protocol independent
evaluable for encryption either import
protocols in particular
the metrics described in this draft are
several the first one is the rtt matrix
that we expand the
first idea of
spin bit with the idea of delay bit and
the new idea of
hidden
rtt
that it can be applied
both for spin bit and for delay b
because it's possible to delay the
signal from a certain amount of time in
order to
give them the real rtt for people that
are not allowed to understand it after
there is the round three packet loss
that is
made using the spin beat and the round
three plus bit the t bit
and finally there are two options for
the one-way packet loss the first one is
the square bit that is
already noun techniques in 83
21 fc
and they lost event beat as a second bit
of in the in alternative the square bit
the same bit with the reflection square
with that reflection
from
the other side the square wave that they
could be to generate
again
there is some implementation both in the
academy and
in the field
in the last academics we experimented
with other companies for example
ericsson huawei and so on
some experiments about this quick
measurement there are some
implementation in the field the first
one that we
displaying this transparency is the
recommendation implementation on android
mobile phones
that is inspired the draft about user
devices uh monitoring that is presented
in the last part of this meeting
there is the ericsson implementation
core network problem that detects the
spin beat
title at marking and make the
measurement
the orange akamai implementation that is
the first one that implement on the
field the packet loss using qubit and
albeit
the arcane university had an
experimental implementation they
presented a paper in an fbw
that compared all the techniques that we
described in this draft albeit
arbit and tibit and they
experimented it and
concluded that they works with various
pros and cons
and finally also by way is starting to
work on the topic and with presenting
next academics or some experimental
trials
okay
some words on the hidden beats that is
the last last bit that we introduced
in this draft in the last the version
that we presented in july
the idea is
is born because the
spin bit is not so much implemented
we using our
devices we spread
some
probes on our
mobile phones that
telecom italia
uses for some experimentation in our
network and we
saw that there isn't uh
market packets inside the quick quick is
quite used for example by google
application but also facebook
application and many others
but no spin bit is marked so it is uh
implementation that is defined as not
mandatory in the standards
in the fc 9000 is not implemented in the
field
uh
in italy
almost
but i think all over the world is the
same so we think that to
add a feature to
that we need that then did i beat but
it's possible so to have the hidden spin
beat in order to
mask the real rtt
and introducing this simple mechanism
that adds some
delay in the reflection so the packets
are reflected
the real traffic works in the same way
there is no delay in the real traffic
but the markings delayed so it's
possible to mask the reality but it's
possible to have some measurement but
knowing the
time that we added
but also not knowing it because if the
measurements are between an observer and
another observer or between a server and
the server
the
the measurement are correct the
end-to-end measurement is not
visible
unless you know the other the additional
delay okay
the main change of this draft dementia
is
the first great news is the eppm working
group adopted this draft some days ago
and we updated the
draft the new version of the draft
adding the new name and introducing a
couple of changes that
are suggested during the last during the
working group adoption call
in the introduction paragraph we
underlined the beneficial approach of
the methodology described described
inside the document as per the lfc 1965
thanks to the nikola scan suggestion so
it is this kind of methodologies is
beneficial in this case
and we updated all the references using
the new rfc that are
standardized so there are see
90 000
1965 so we updated all the references
that's the slide okay
this is the summary of all the
methodologies that we present in this
draft
the idea is these drafts is not to make
a clear choices over one methodology
instead of another but we we intend to
present all the
possibilities and then we are the
intention to present in specific working
group that are devoted to specific
protocol the right choices for this
protocol because
a kind of marking can be useful for a
protocol and not so useful in another
protocol
a clear example this idea is in the
slide that we presented the lost lost
beats summary because the main two
methodology
bot uses the square bit
as first bit to mark because it's a very
simple technology well known because
already implementing field
using the rfc
8321 as a reference
but
we have to add another
another bit to have end to end
measurement because the square bit for
this nature is not a 20 measurement but
is
origin to observer measurement we can
measure only the loss between the origin
the client and or the server and the
measurement point
because we mark the blocks of 64 packets
and if the number of
packets marked with the same
color 0 and 1 is less than 64. there is
a loss between the origin trying to
serve and the measurement point so to
have and to animation we have to add the
other another bit the loss event bit as
proposed by akamai and orange in the
their airdraft that we joined with
in
this draft
or the
team recom italia proposal to add the
reflection square bit
the lost event bit generates a market
packet every every loss detected by the
protocol
the reflection square bit reflects the
square wave on the other side so it's
possible to measure
the round trip
loss
using this reflection
all the two methods are quite good as
the
arcane paper
demonstrates
there are some differences because the
loss beat the l bit is very simple to
implement
is more simple than the reflection
square bit
but it is dependent from the protocol so
if the loss is detective of the in the
protocol the lbt's market is not
detected is not market
so it works well with quick so in our
opinion can be
a
right proposal for quicker
it works less well for less is less good
for tcp because for example the
packet is not
detected as losses
so if i load i'll uh i know
is lost
the protocol the tcp doesn't uh measure
it is lost so it's better to use for tcp
in our opinion probably the uh the r bit
but it is a as i said before this is
only a
general review of all the possible
techniques
there is a next step will be to the will
be to select the best bit to mark for
each protocols
next we can show this slide
so we have many possibilities
if there are only two bits for
a specific
measurement
there are
two possible options in my in our
opinion is the most significant
the spin beat and the t beat
to have the round trip time
and
round three packet loss using only two
beat
but the tbt is uh
is
less precise that uh using a
qubit and albeit or jubitan and
arbit so is a
we propose to use only if we have only
one
only two beats and only one for the loss
the option b is to use uh
the debate or the uh mask the diabetes
and delay beat for rtt
and to use the one-way packet loss they
could be for the loss in this case we
don't have the end-to-end measurement
for the loss but only the origin to a
problem measurement for the loss
so it's a compromise if we have only two
bits if we are we have a three bits that
is uh the best option for uh
monitoring on using a specific
measurement
and for example quick is possible to
have
is not defined in now but it's possible
to have three bits
there are four options in
that we have two choice to have a choice
but the first one is to use for rtt the
spin beat
or the idiom version of the spin beat if
can be useful to mask the rtt
and to use one for the one-way packet
loss qubit and albeit in order to have
origin two
measurement point loss or end-to-end
loss
the other the option d is very similar
there are only the substitution of spin
beat where the more precise but not so
well known the beat
and the option e is the equal to the
previous one but we
uh introduce the r bit in instead of the
l bit
this can be useful if we don't want
a measurement that depends from the
protocol because that'll be the signals
the losses detected by the protocol if
the protocol don't then take doesn't
detect the losses the albeit doesn't
signal the losses that bit is
independent so is more complicated of
the albeit and the rather problem is
that there is a delay in the measurement
because we have to wait
a square wave of the qubit starting from
the client reaching the
the server and converting in the
reflected
square wave and come back so we have a
two round trip time more plus the the
time of the square wave to complete the
first measurement but a little bit
instead a little bit is very
quick because there is a market packet
when the protocol detects
but in this case their bit is totally
independent from the protocol so
if also the protocol done
doesn't detect the loss the arbit can
detect it
uh okay the last slide
i'll spend the time for one minute
okay
so we can conclude uh conclude some
thoughts about that is a draft they
there are some implementation there are
some on feed implementation the eppm
working group adopted the draft
we
presented some
some sibling draft there was
another one in this working group about
the positioning of the probes the idea
is to positioning the probe in the
client
in the
client because so we can
save
hardware using the hardware of the
client to make also the measurement same
advantage that we explained in the
presentation at the end of this meeting
another sibling draft is presented in
this session of the core working group
about the co-op protocol
that was another
protocol client server that can
have some extension to have some
additional bit for marking so we we
think that can be a good idea to present
this in the future if the working group
are interested we can try to present an
implementation for quick
having a choice of the right beats
okay this is all thank you
all right thank you um
we do have some time for questions i've
seen some
comments in the chat
trying to clarify
[Music]
the the hidden
bits and
exactly
what each party can see
and what can still be measured with them
so be good to clarify that maybe
okay the
hidden beat the idea with it in beta can
be applied to every bit that measure the
rtt
because it can be applied
both for the beat and for the
traditional spin beat the idea is to
delay the reflection of the
of the packet
that detect
the
the square wave for the spin beat or the
uh sample delay sample that is the
single market packet that is used by the
light beat
so when for example for the spin bit
when the
square wave
that
is uh the the front of the square wave
that uh signal the starting of the rtt
or any of the rtt
arrived to the client the client don't
reflect the end of this square wave
immediately but he continually continued
to
mark the packets with the same
beat so if we are in the one
period
for example the rtt
is 10 milliseconds
and the additional that we add is
other five milliseconds so
when the square wave reached the client
the client don't change immediately the
front but it weighed other additional
five milliseconds to change the front so
the server don't measure the right rdt
but the right elementary plus 5
millisecond
this
masked only the end to end rtt because
if we measure
using a probe dirty between the observer
and the server for example
the server don't add anything because
it works in the same way that it work
for this enormous pin bit or normal bit
so the measurement observer server
observer the rtt
is
right so it's possible to segment the
network and to have a partial
measurement correct but not end-to-end
measurement the only measurement that is
a masked is the round trip between
client and observer
i see okay and the only extra delay is
added
on the client side not on the server yes
only the client side
perfect okay
and i think that's
roughly what the chat was getting to as
well but that is helpful to have
clarified
right and it's impossible to to choice
to choose that uh it is adding timing
many times in many ways
we propose to choose a fixed amount for
each
client
so the position the client is moved for
exactly the same amount of time so the
same amount of kilometer let me say for
all the time so it's impossible to
detect
if there is the right
distance or a fake distance because they
add all always the same amount of time
that makes sense
all right
thank you
okay next we have
the draft on connectivity monitoring
are you able to find your slides in
there
there we go great
we'll find it thanks
um
yep
i
made the presentation before i updated
the draft so these uh
presentation refers to the older version
i mean while updated the draft on monday
and
it contains a
packet loss based uh specification for a
connectivity
metric which is just announced here in
this i also have changed um
the
status from
standard strike meanwhile to
experimental because i think that's more
suitable i not able to come up with an
implementation
very soon
so i think
that's fair
um don't i
think i moved to the other slide yep
um and that is uh
indicating how the
loss-based connectivity
metric is going to work
the
router
sketch which is uh on the upper part is
already part of the other presentations
and there are three measurement loops
passing each
connection or path to be monitored
and uh
two go to the same direction always per
uh
upstream or downstream
and
there's always a contra
the
direction and uh there's only two
measurement path going per direction
either
upstream or downstream
and the idea then is if
there is no
packet received with within
one measurement interval inc t
on
all of the
measurement
loops per monitored interface
then you decide on
connectivity loss
and the simple definition
of
distance between two packets per
measurement interval to me seemed seemed
to be
to wait for the
measurement loop which is producing the
longest measurement loop delay and then
double that amount and simply send
packets only after that has passed on
each individual
measurement loop that means
you only send a
measurement packet along along the next
loop once you've received that of the
last one which is
maybe not the fastest way of operating
it but it's pretty reliable i think
and then
[Music]
you simply count whether you
have all those passing
the connection which you monitor and
i've used the colors to illustrate that
down there
and once
you did not receive them within the time
when you send the next one and it
doesn't matter in which order you do
that
then
you decide that this connection has
failed
the whole idea is to
overlay all these measurements so what
you see here is the individual
combination of measurement loops passing
this monitored interface and if you are
interested in details
terminology is adapted to try to
illustrate that as good as possible
and
you can read how that works
and i'd of course be
happy for
comments
and i'd like to add that the question
about timing has been put to me several
times so i think
or the intent now here is to to answer
these questions
and come up with a scheme how it works
all right
and that is it
from me
it looks like greg is in the queue
um
still i'm not really
comfortable with the terminology because
traditionally the connectivity is uh
state
uh in a fault management
oem
so and
if
there is a connection um so actually
when we are referring to something as a
connection we understand that it's uh
not only ability
uh to receive test packets but
uh on that connection that belong
to this connection but not receiving
packets from other connections so
basically absence of misconnection uh
state and uh misconnection
uh definition uh
usually
specific um
at itf since well we are dealing
primarily
with the ip and um
mpls if it's a pmp-ls and not traffic
engineered
then
we usually refer to the
laws of path continuity
and
the protocol that used to that
extent is a bidirectional forwarding
detection uh bfd
and
one of the things that property of bfd
is that
uh
their session goes down or path loss
continuity
state uh
declared uh when i lost
three consecutive test packets
and uh even though the protocol supports
uh doing that on
the first
packet on only one last packet
there is a good reason to have three
it's not only similar to how ethernet
oem
works
but it provides certain stability
i'm somewhat concerned that uh in this
proposal
uh the
miscon a loss of connectivity declared
on a very first packet
because
then uh if that's the case then uh so
the next packet what next packet will
mark the connection as up
um
then uh
we'll have probably states bouncing up
and down
interchangeably if uh
we have a flaky uh connection
um
on the other hand the uh packet loss
ratio or some other statistics
uh will indicate that the connection um
the path is not stable
but
uh from the uh fault management
perspective um
bouncing states and generating uh alarms
and clearing our arms and
that would cause a lot of uh confusion
so um
maybe that's something that needs uh
further uh discussion and uh look at
and especially how it relates to default
management oh yeah
um yes adding some text
with a relation to fault management oim
uh
i probably need to do that i'm not a bfd
expert
the state of lost connectivity is
declared after three packets have been
lost
if you look at the illustration below
it's uh that red uh
link lsr2 leri is disconnected that
what the text says also in the draft is
you start with sending packet f2 uh
index one
and then you send f3 index one
and the expectation would be if you send
a packet at t2 it should have been
received at t3
if you send one at t3 it should have
been received at t4 and so on and if you
look at the blue one at time t5 it
should have been received at t6 so these
are three packets
and if they haven't been received until
t8 which when when you would send the
next packet on
f2
then you declare the state to be
disconnected so um
yeah it's three packets
three packets which should have been
received for a long time then or
sometime then
at t8 when you declare it to be uh
disconnected
yeah uh i'll be uh happy uh to discuss
uh with the bfd because
i'm working on it extensively yeah sure
that would be helpful
yeah okay uh we can continue discussion
on the list
thanks yeah i would appreciate
right thank you
get on time
perfect okay and
last of our adopted documents
uh we have the srpm
do you want
sharing your screen just share the
preloaded slides
instead of the screen button you can
press the the document button
try click that again
sorry
yeah you see it yeah
yeah can you can you click the
document button one more time to ask to
share
okay i cancelled it and i'm asking again
here we go yep yeah
you are now granted
you see i'm setting it now
we do
okay great
yeah hi everyone
my name is rakesh gandhi i'm presenting
a very quick update on the
stem extension for sr
on behalf of the authors listed
so uh agenda is a brief update and
revision02
just to highlight the work happening in
other working groups on the stamp
extensions and next steps
so there is very brief minor updates in
revision zero two
mostly editorial changes uh we converted
ni into table format and we have no open
issues at the moment
uh there is uh extensions uh
that's built on the great work done by
ippm with stem
spring has two drops on srpm
and also there is one in mpls with a new
encapsulation
for pseudo wires
so uh welcome your review comments on
those traps as well
so uh just uh we are
seeking more review comments and
suggestions for this draft
and we'll wait for maybe one one more
itf before we request a last call
so that's all i had any comments
suggestions
yeah thank you
okay and now we're going to move on to
[Music]
our proposed work um
actually before we do that before we do
that there is one thing i uh
slides
which is we did we did
uh publish rfc emergency indeed
so i just wanted to say congrats
to those authors and
thanks for getting that work through
all right kristoff i'm going to approve
you here
and get started
okay hello can you hear me
can you hear me fine good it's good good
great
um hello everyone um
i will present our internet draft
responsiveness under working conditions
and uh
as this is uh the first time i'm
presenting and i'm giving a little bit a
start with a little bit of background
first
um so
first my
what is it actually what we are trying
here to solve here what are we trying to
address here um
the first problem is that we realized is
there have been 10 and more years of
buffer bloat
in the sense that it was made very
public more than 10 years ago
solutions quickly um started popping up
and were being standardized and
implemented but still today buffer bloat
is a very common problem
and why is that
one reason we believe that is the reason
is because there is first of all a lack
of awareness
and the lack of tools
the awareness of buffer bloat for the
end user would allow to
use the end user as a forcing function
to drive the solutions to being deployed
and find a tool that allows to measure
it would allow to actually measure the
buffer load and allow operators vendors
and so on to
build benchmarks to
to minimize buffer load
a second problem that we realize exists
is there's not really a clear definition
of what buffer load actually is and if
you ask
different people
um you will get different definitions of
buffer bloat
um
it's also not clear how you can measure
it is an icmp ping while doing the file
transfer good enough do you need to
um
flood the network with udp traffic and
then send tcp request response
dns can you use dns to measure buffer
bloat
right it's not really clear and there
are some tools that exists like dsl
reports fast.com waveform and so on
that are measuring buffer bloat but if
you compare one tool with the other
they have hugely
different methodologies and when you run
the tools they provide completely
different results so it's really a
problem of
we don't really know what is buffer
blown and how does it impact the end
user so we believe it's time to for
standardized metric of what we call
responsiveness under working conditions
which is what is exposes problems like
buffer blood
so first of all
we want to measure responsiveness for
the end user
and that means
that implies a certain set of things
first of all a realization that buffer
bloat while typically you think of
buffer bloat as something that is
a big da a big q in a bottleneck router
that is being filled up
buffer bloat can happen at many
different places right it cannot only be
in the bottlenecks router it can be on
the server it can be on the client it
can be in the service nic it can be in
the server's tcp implementation or even
in the http implementation right and we
have found that in many cases the buffer
bloat and http implementations are way
way higher than whatever you you can
measure on the internet so sometimes the
problem is at a different layer where
you would not expect it
so this implies that if we want to
measure um
buffer bloat between quotes because of
the sudden buffer load is no more just
on the bottleneck router but it can be
anywhere right
if you want to measure bar for load it
means you need to use the modern
protocol that the end users are actually
using which means you need to use for
example http 2 hp 3
you need to use tls and so on
you also want to measure all stages of
the connections right
if you have a good solution to handle
buffer bloat in your tcp stack but your
dns
is still going to
go through a shared queue that is
completely bloated well
your user experience will still be very
bad so you need to measure all stages of
the connections dns tcp tls and so on
and so on
and finally if as if we want to use this
kind of metric as a forcing function we
need it to be user friendly and we
needed to be
expressing the number in a way users can
understand it
so
how do we create what we call working
conditions because in order to measure
buffer bloat
in order to measure the responsiveness
when under working conditions we need to
fill the buffers right
now filling the buffers can be done for
example by flooding the network with udp
that would definitely very reliably fill
the buffers can guarantee that however
it is not a realistic traffic pattern
nobody does that
and so
in order to measure buffer build we need
to create
a balance between a realistic traffic
pattern while at the same time reliably
filling those buffers
um
and so
for example a good choice would be
running
several http 2 bulk data transfers right
now on the other side also with quick
coming along well in the future we
rather would want to probably use quick
instead of http 2 because uh the
buffering can be completely different
for quick
now in order to measure
responsiveness we need to create those
working conditions for an extended
period of time because we need to
measure it repeatedly and get multiple
samples to have a stable number right
and so we need to gradually add flows
and monitor the good put evolution to
create this kind of a stable condition
where the buffers are roughly full
and the good way to do is the way we do
it is for example in as we describe it
in the idea in the draft here is we
start with a certain number of
connections as those connections go
through tcp slow start the good put is
going to ramp up and it's eventually
going to level out
and at that point the only way to
increase the good but is by adding more
connections so we have more connections
again you will be able to see it the
good part increase again and then it
levels out again and then you basically
achieve a state of saturation where your
network is
as full as it can be with a reasonable
um
with a reasonable networking load
so once we have these stable
uh working conditions we can then go and
measure responsiveness right and there
are two ways to measure it the first one
is by using those connections that are
creating the working conditions by using
these bulk data transfer we can send an
additional get request on those
connections
and measure the latency for those get
requests
this is great because it allows to um
expose bad http 2 and tcp
implementations on the client and the
server side and it also exposes bad
buffering in the network
another the second approach and maybe or
orthogonal to it is measure the latency
on separate connections right for
example creating a short-lived http 2
get request which then allows to measure
dns tcp tls and the get request
while the network is is fully loaded
nick is allows to expose flow queueing
in the network which is a good property
right because it allows to work around
some of the
issues around buffer bloat
and then we need to as we gather all of
these latency measurements we need to
aggregate those numbers into a single
result because we want to have it being
a user-friendly number and so we can
take an average a 75th percentile and so
on
so finally
as we are doing all these measurements
we then expose what we call the round
trips per minute and we do this
round trip per minute instead of latency
because it is more user-friendly which
is one of the goals that i mentioned
initially is
we want it to be the higher the better
we want it to range from the low tens to
a few thousand
a few thousands
and we want it to be a nice analogy to
what we call revolutions per minute so
the rpm number is a good way to present
buffer bloat to the users
now this methodology is something um
is currently a work in progress and we
are very much looking forward to
feedback we have currently an
implementation uh in macos monterey and
in ios 15
and we also have published service
server-side implementations for it on on
github that i will show in a minute
so
we are very much looking to uh
collaborations around this effort to
define
um
to properly define a way to measure
buffer load and responsiveness under
working conditions
in our internet draft that we wrote we
are using http 2 and we are very open to
other suggestions on how to measure it
because there are many different ways to
create those working conditions and
there are many different ways to measure
the responsiveness and so this is really
a call for
contributions for people to come and
join this effort to um
to give suggestions on how how to
measure responsiveness
we believe that this would be very um
useful and we are already seeing
how the two can be used to actually
debug
bad http implementations in the wide end
so we believe that this would be very
beneficial for the overall user
experience
so with that i'm very happy to take any
questions
thank you
martin
hi christoph this is uh really
interesting really interesting um um
a couple so it seems like there's two
separate proposals here there's a um
like a methodology and then there's a
metric um so i actually have one
question for each so for the methodology
uh this this background these background
connections racing are they just
downloading an arbitrarily large
resource to fill the pipe
yeah yes that's right um okay it's just
an arbitrary uh it's basically an
infinite file yes right okay and then
the second question is about rpm um so
what what exactly is a uh
round trip
how is a round trip defined so if
they're doing a get does does that imply
that an entire resource
is arriving or is there some packet
coming back
so um
in the draft we specify also the what
what the the
protocol would be and so what we what we
require is that the server is able to
provide
one very large file
one very small file basically just one
byte and allow to upload data and so the
small file is used for latency
measurements and because it's just one
byte it would be one packet
um
so that's
that's basically it so in order to
measure latency if we send a get request
it takes it's just for the time it takes
to get the response back now the
assumption is that um
honest on a cdn implementation the
assumption is that this byte would be
locally generated so the cdn wouldn't
need to go back to the origin to fetch
it so that's that is not this kind of
latency in in the picture
do you want to
share your audio thank you
you guys hear me
ah no you can't
okay okay great yeah this is this is uh
very very interesting
yeah yeah i'm getting
i'm getting an echo
um
hang on yeah no anyway i hope you guys
are not getting an echo but anyway i
think this is very interesting and um i
would be very curious because our pdm
is
a performance and diagnostic metrics for
ipv6
that is installed both at the server and
client end and the idea of pdm
is to separate server time and client
time
because this is a problem that many
large enterprises have and i would be
very interested to see
how um what what kind of measurements we
come out with using your test data so so
as i said i think this is this is a
quite quite interesting
details of
pdm so i will all need to look into it
and learn a bit more about it
sure i'll contact you offline
all right uh lucas
i should probably
cut the cue after this
hello can you hear me okay okay
so just a quick one you mentioned
maybe being able to detect bad http 2 or
quick implementations but i just
a word of caution that there's many ways
to be bad
um you know there's lots of things in
these
specifications that
may be a bit optional and people choose
just not bother implementing them so i
just caveat
or try to caveat what you mean by a good
or this is bad this is for like raw
throughput or
scheduling these kinds of considerations
it's a very minor point but i think for
for
nitpickers like me um or people who are
really into web performance where the
workload's slightly different just
quantifying
good or bad might
mean something
the word bad was probably a bad choice
of words
sorry about that
all right i think we're up time on this
one
um
thank you stuff and
it'd be good to hear more comments on
the list especially from people who
have a lot of deep experience with
existing ippmetrics
and now we have al
wearing a deck
all right
are you able to find your slides in
there al i know i know there's a lot
still i'm still looking for the slides
tommy maybe i should just go with the
uh the screen
let me try to see if i can find them
there um
yeah if you want to share your screen
that's fine too
all right cool
and i think you still have to give me oh
yeah here we go
still yes i do
all right
i'll do the screen
and
uh let's see
screen one i think is this one
yes
okay and allow
and
slides
all right i guess i'll just make this
as big as i can
all right
so um thanks everybody and and uh
uh for um
joining in today and thanks uh tommy for
the congratulations on on the uh
one-way ip capacity measurement uh rc
1997 where uh was a long road longer
than we thought so um last time about
the protocol i gave a uh
let's see here i've got the time covered
that's not going to help
so um
what i wanted to do is is basically
talk about some special features of the
protocol since last time we talked about
security features and didn't get much
traction with that so
it's it's kind of a unique protocol that
we've developed to do this
uh you know what so we're going to talk
about what's new in the protocol
where the functions reside
between like a server and a client
matter
and
first and foremost thanks to the
reviewers
jan that's how he pronounces his name
lincoln rudiger and greg
so on to the next
all right so we've we've seen this in in
various forms the protocol setup and and
phases uh you know we've got a setup
exchange a test activation exchange and
um
the most important point i want to make
about this is that you're you're
actually testing connectivity when
you're uh your client is setting this up
and also um opening ports and and so
forth in the
firewalls and
translators and and so forth so um you
know these are these are important parts
of the exchange
uh and and it's always good to record
when you've lost connectivity uh to your
server or between your client and server
uh those are the kinds of things that
relate directly back to um you know
whether a user has connectivity in
general to the to the internet
specifically to one particular host but
that might be uh you know a sort of a
catastrophic indication as well so
recording failures is is just as
important that's one of my workshop uh
points
um but then we're going to go on mostly
today and talk about the test protocol
on the test protocol is the um
where we send test stream uh pdus
and uh and the most important part is
that we get measurement feedback here so
the measurement feedback is uh is
exactly what we really want to emphasize
and so we're going to carry these colors
through the load use our um
in the uh in black and the uh feedback
pdus are in blue
all right and not showing anything uh
else here other than that um
and uh of course this is uh the protocol
that we're currently using in uh running
code
so
so here's the test phase operation i've
got
two scenarios
side by side
i've got a downlink scenario here where
the server is in the network that's on
the top
it's in the role of the sender and the
test controller always resides with the
server so that's an important
functionality and it doesn't doesn't
swap completely when the
sending and receiving roles change
places so let's look at this quickly
you know the sender's deciding what uh
downlink uh test track traffic rates
it's going to send that for our our
classic uh iplayer capacity measurement
the receiver receives that traffic and
it formulates a reverse path feedback
message uh which includes uh loss delay
and reordering measured on the the scent
rate on uh and it sends it back every 50
milliseconds and i i didn't even include
the fact that it measures the rate here
but that's a fairly obvious thing that's
happening so then um
every 50 milliseconds that feedback
message
arrives at the sender
the test controller acts on it
it runs the load adjustment algorithm
and uh controls the sender rate uh it
can select a rate in the table with our
current logic and um
and that's kind of what you see uh
depicted here down at the bottom so
we're you know we ramp up the rate at
first uh ipgr capacity on the y-axis and
time on x and you can see us searching
for the maximum capacity here in the
typical uh
you know rfc
9097 method and then metric
so um we uh we reverse some things and
change some information that's exchanged
when we do an uplink test
um so now the we've arranged for the
sender to do
the sending from the client side
and so the uplink test traffic arrives
at the receiver
and now the
receiver's test controller function is
to perform the measurements
and it keeps those measurements to
itself it runs the load adjustment
algorithm and it sends the next rate uh
to be used over the uh the next feedback
interval
back to the sender
so the um
the reverse path uh contrary contains
mostly the sending rate structure which
is identified in the protocol and this
contains you know the size of packets
the marking of the packets uh the rate
at which they would be sent and um
and so forth and someone's looking for
me to go full screen which means i won't
be able to see
further comments like that so uh good so
um
what we've what we've basically enabled
here though is that for the the test
controller logic that we've currently
defined uh what we've got in
is the capability to change that logic
and so you could create alternate forms
of
reaction to the network or or simply uh
changing the rates and the and the time
rates over time uh the packet sizes and
their burst composition over time and
and so forth so it's a it's very much a
a a a
a uh
you know a very complete and uh uh easy
control of the um of the the testing
situation i i wanted also to mention
that we we measure round trip time on on
a sample basis and that's on the basis
of these feedback uh messages so we
always have an estimate of a round-trip
time
going on
okay
so
let's see uh i gotta hurry through this
now so we we've the we've got lots of
motivation for the new protocol um you
know it's different from a session
sender in that you um
uh you know or the reflector we're
definitely not sending packets back
every time uh it's different from owamp
in that there's a fetch and sending
results at the end of the session and
the the uh uh the security for uh owamp
and ramp is kind of old and was
described as unusual it was a little bit
challenging way back then
so um
uh
we've we've had some good comments as i
mentioned
and um
uh
one of the things i've decided which
made it kind of easy to just to decide
where we stopped with uh the zero two
update uh we're gonna stop
uh describing uh version eight after
this uh version and so new updates will
result in a version 9 or higher
versions of the protocol
so that's good that frees us up and of
course we've got running code and the
running codes available you can get that
link from the draft
when we see errors during setup there
could be multiple errors
right now we're using a hierarchy
you know where the first bad thing that
happens is what gets reported as an
error
but we could make that a field with
flags
both of those options are described in
the current draft
one of the options that jan asked for uh
was uh options for the payload uh you
know whether it be all ones or all zeros
or alternating or pseudo-random
that helps a pseudo-random helps out
with compression links like on satellite
and then um
then we've got
this last one here which is uh interface
measurements where we're actually in the
in the running code right now we're
actually making diagnostic measurements
on the interface uh that observes all
the traffic so you know way back here in
a downlink
test if we've got test traffic sharing
traffic with user traffic
uh we can measure that at where two and
it's a kind of a hybrid type two
measurement at that point uh before that
it's it's purely active so uh we've
we've got that going now and um you know
you could you could uh you could make
that a make a case for that in the um
uh
earlier two as well and maximize on
where to so um like i said next steps we
we talked about the security features at
uh 111 uh the authors uh welcome
protocols and and revisions to the
security modes of operation um but today
we talked about what i think are the
unique features of this protocol
proposal it can do more than measure
capacity and and um you know we've taken
a look at that uh we'd like others to
take a look and um uh i had a side
conversation with martin last time uh we
uh
with working group adoption we could get
an early uh security director view and
and that would help us uh solve that
aspect for this protocol in a way that
might uh go through the iesg a little
easier so um
thanks for your attention and i hope
there's some questions
well um
any question
all right
i'm sorry if you said this already but
like
how does this relate to rsc 1997
it this is the protocol we're using
currently in the running code for
measuring rfc 1997
and
with the logic that's in let me bring
this back up again martin
with the logic that's
that's currently implemented in here the
load adjustment algorithm
this is what we do
we try to measure
the maximum capacity and we do that
based on on the feedback that we're
currently receiving
and the point i'm making is that you
could change this logic this load
adjustment algorithm to do lots of other
things
for example um
you know a hybrid type 2 measurement
where you're where you're seeking
additional
uh downstream load and you want to
measure uh the performance of the
passive traffic that's alongside of it
you know at full capacity so where you
may be building up your buffers and so
forth
okay sounds like we don't have anyone
else in the queue
thank you al
you're welcome welcome
all right
hopefully we'll have some more follow-up
on list as well
okay and then
next up i think we have
greg talking about epm
about it
i can probably share my screen
you should also be able to share the
pre-loaded slides
yourself
do you want to click that button
[Music]
i don't see the button right
right of the hand button
okay
here we go
okay great thank you
okay so um
this is update on error performance
measurement in packet switch network and
uh let's
go
to the next slide please
okay so the recap
their error performance measurement we
define several metrics for the packet
switch networks that reflect conformance
to set of predefined uh service level
objectives and among this metrics we
have the availability and unavailability
as a sequence of the time intervals
that conforms on do not conform to slo
since our last presentation we have two
new coffers uh leon and joel joining us
welcome
and uh we updated um we edited the
section on um availability of
anything as a service and uh
availability uh as um
used uh in mobile communication and uh
look at
how are these two
uh interpretations
of availability relate to
what we discuss in error performance
measurement next slide please
so what is anything as a service i think
that we are all well familiar it's a
concept of
services related to the cloud computing
and remote access
uh and um
almost everything
anything is a service as a security
platform
uh software
um
so um
sdn um
as the van
um so
network
as a service
next slide
so
as everything uh it doesn't come for
free so it has some benefits but at the
same time it has
challenges and the advantages of
anything as a service is it improves
express model because
um there is a
lower uh capex
and
purchase
a subscribe subscription basis
and as more capacity needed from the
providers
and it allows
uh the enterprise uh to uh faster adopt
new applications and um use its uh
expertise of its it on a specifics of
its uh main business rather than in
support
but at the same time anything is a
service has some potential challenges
so because they depend on more equipment
on the network connectivity and
availability of
computing resources so they might be
constrained by their temporary loss of
connectivity uh
problems with the resilience
low bandwidth and low computing power
next slide please
for
anything is a service um
using a dedicated uh environment
uh the availability average is
understood as a mean time between
failures
uh
it's a
equation between
of a mean time between failures and mean
time to repair and um example of uh
failures that considered its hard drive
malfunction in a data center or
hypervisor reboot uh mean time to repair
is how much time it takes to fix a
broken component uh our application to
come back online
um obviously um so we can if we look at
this equation
we can see that
mean time between failures can be uh
considered as a constant for the
particular environment
and the only uh way to uh improve
availability
is uh to minimize uh mean time to repair
and that can be achieved by introducing
uh redundancy
uh in their
infrastructure is like um
with a web
or database service or
world balancers
uh in epm um
epm reflects uh near real-time
availability by uh measuring the
conformance
uh to uh slos and the ability to
communicate so basically it can it's a
combination of
uh
performance monitoring and
fault management monitoring their
continuity of the path
from the user
uh to their cloud
and um
using uh the epm interpretation of
availability it
provides uh valuable data and more
accurate realistic
information about
mean time between failures and
mean time to repair so
because these are
giving us a theoretical
estimation of availability while
using their
methodology of error performance
measurement gives us a real time or near
real-time
information
next slide please
so another um
domain are where we can see there or
hear about their availability is mobile
communication
so the mobile voice and data services
the definition of service availability
can be uh found in um
baric
communication positioning um
and it's uh oriented uh
for uh operators and consumers so and
it's uses their
percentage of the number of attempts
to their access
given services successful uh
attempt
but
it's only
reflects on
established connection it does not
reflect the quality of connection so
that now uh when we see that uh it's uh
not only a voice but a mobile broadband
so their quality of uh the connection
are
becomes
more important and that's where again
uh the methodology of
error performance management and the
approach of how availability is
uh
determined and measured and expressed
uh allows for a better understanding and
better uh quantifying of availability
for mobile
voice and data communication
next slide please
so what we
we always welcome comments and questions
contribution cooperation
and
we think that
this is something
that working group might be interested
and would like to ask to consider
working group adoption
and uh
i see fan um
yes please
i can't hear you if you're talking
fan all right in the interest of time i
think we're just going to have to take
that list or you can drop your question
or comment in the chat
thank you okay
thanks
okay so now we're on to our quick
elevator pitches these are ones like i
will display
the
oh
sorry yang can you come back on um i can
display the slides now
and we will start with
some of the draftly ones okay
all right
and again for these we just want to
cover them in
like a minute or two and please focus on
you know what should this group be
interested about why did it
uh why should people comment on it or
read your draft
okay
okay i'm yami from china mobile can you
hear me
okay
the title of my talk is one-way delay
moment based on reference delay
so the background is that entrance
one-way delay measurements is very
important
uh for
sla as in this fit and the figure on the
left we need to know the end-to-end one
one-way delay of a video surveillance
service in 5g network
we can see that the and one to one-way
delay is the sum of t1 to t4
we propose a new method to accurately
measure the one-way delay
using reference delay without deploying
clock synchronization
the reference delay
is bounded
and has lower data it can be obtained in
deterministic networking in figure 2 on
the left side the engine end-to-end
one-way delay from the sender to the
receiver
is measured and the intermediate network
device are hidden for simplicity we
assume the cinder
clock and the receiver clock are not
synchronized and has some clock offset
in this figure the delay of the
reference packet is stable and bounded
and deleted as the reference
and the
delay of the
target packet is measured
and the way denoted as the target
we will time step both the reference and
the target packet on the sender and
receiver side respectively
denoted as ts1 ts2
tr1 and tr2
uh for reference we're talking we're
we're out of time
um
i i know you have another slide coming
up right after this okay okay we're
gonna switch to that
people have comments you can get to
those on the list um
all right so your next one is again a
one-way delay
here we go
as quick as yes
okay
uh they we we propose a new one-way
delay environment
uh method also based on deterministic
net networking
uh the the way we can have a centralized
control node as shown
and used to collecting network
information and the link from each
network element to the synchronize the
control node leverages delay
deterministic links
so that the delay are shown in the
figure on the left side denoted at t1 t2
to tn
and can be calculated in advance and
have relatively stable and low jitter
as shown on the right side the network
element m and n are connected to the
centralized node by delay
deterministic network when the track
traffic flows from the network element
m to n they will upload flow information
to the centralizer control load the
transmission delay of flow information
tm and tn respectively
and the arrival time of flow information
at the centralized control load is tm
prime and the tm prime
respectively all right then the delay
can be calculated by this formula
and more details are shown in the
document thank you
great thank you
all right okay up next we have just
yeah hello all right let me just pull up
your this is the enhanced alternate
marking
yeah
all right
the single slide is light four if you
can go on flight four
but you're here yeah pitch it to us
yeah the background is that in a few
words that
we
already presented the alternate marking
data fields for ipv6 and the relevant
document is
an isg evaluation but during the
discussion we
there was some inputs from the sg to
consider whether the flow monitor
identification field can be extended in
order to have more entropy
uh
considering this motivation we propose
this graph to discuss in ippm how to
generalize the
data fields extension
and whether it
is necessary to
extend the
the flow monitor identification field
for example the next header can be
can be used to define this enhanced
capability so this is just a proposal
for
discussion in ippm so
we are looking for more feedback from
the group and to we already have some
discussion with greg on the list and we
hope to
have more feedback okay thank you
all right thank you
anyone
any quick comments while we're switching
slides
we have
tall up next
justin we'll give you an update on the
iom linux kernel implementation
perfect
thanks al so a quick update on the
implementation on the linux kernel so
last release of the kernel which is the
5.15 a few days ago has been released
and uh it comes with the uh support for
the iom prayer located trace
uh next version which is the 5.16 and it
is expected for end of december this
year will provide uh tunneling uh
support for in transit traffic so that
we are compliant with the rfc 8200
and actually everything is configurable
with the ip root 2 tool which most of
you probably know with
the ip command in the linux environment
and so there is a repo so feel free to
have a look at it
we provide some documentation an example
on how you can deploy and configure your
iom domain
so that the floor is yours
right so we have a new draft that
describes an iom profile
which is used by the linux kernel
implementation
and this means that by reading this
draft you can create an implementation
which can interoperate with the linux
kernel implementation
and we'd really be happy to get any
feedback and comments about that
so thanks
thank you is this the type of thing that
i mean
it seems a little out of
of what we normally do in ippm it seems
more like an ops
type thing if you're talking about a
linux specific profile but be curious to
hear that
it's closely related to iom so that's
why we thought this would be the right
place for it but if you think there's a
better working group for this we'll be
happy to hear about that sure okay be
interesting to discuss
all right um
next we've got some in-band flow
learning
all right
um i'm not hearing any audio
fan
any other
authors want to
speak up or present this
all right yeah seems like we're having
some technical issues so let's move on
the next one we have a simple direct
loss
now slide the six uh tell me if you have
it
yep
and if you go to slide six uh there it
is
yeah thank you
so um uh
this is a very uh simple um
straightforward draft that defines um
a packet format a message from it for
the session sender and a reflector to
measure the direct loss it's inline
counter stamping just like inline time
stamping
and it's asic friendly because the
counters are at the fixed location uh
supports the alternate marking method
as well as
32 bit and 64-bit packet and byte
counters as well as if you're doing
measurement for
dhcp scope counters as well
uh so messages are also defined for the
authentication mode as well
uh so it's fairly straightforward draft
and welcome your
comments and
suggestions on this
thank you
all right thank you
all right
next we have self-contained automark
hello everyone i am
i'm zombonzo from mobile
and this is a draft about self-content
automated marking mechanism
and then in the left
is the traditional alternate
marking method
the right is a self-contained alternate
we will introduce each
very quickly
in the live
the container or the ms will connect the
information from the coloring point and
the monitoring point
the non-problem parts may maybe several
many
and they need to
corrected the information by using the
block id and in the right
if we
insert the block id information
into the coloring point also with the
color information
by occupying another specific bit
we can replace the monitor
report at the monitoring point uh
directly uh target environment value
if needed
so we think it's very simple for the
client to join in the environment
environment
thank you everyone
that's how
all right
thank you
except we have some postcard based
telemetry
um this draft has been extensively
discussed the email list and a major
question raised by the chairs and ads
that is that's really worth to
standardize this approach or isn't it
already covered by some existing draft
i think it's worse to clarify this point
in the family of the on pass flow
telemetry techniques
there are two types passport mode and
the passco
postcard mode so the uh for the passport
mode the ios trace is already on the
standard track
and in the branch of postcard mode for
the instruction based telemetry is also
the iom dx is also
on the standard track
and the pvtm covered in this drive is a
standalone method as shown in the left
side figure and so but it's also have
some unique issues need to be
solved um indeed it's actually actually
this approach
has already been used by the srv6 oam
dropped but many uh open issues are
answered as this will be covered by this
drop so uh we hope that this is a word
to
be standardized in this working group
thank you very much all right thank you
i think the main question it's good to
have this formulation the main question
i would have is you know if the other
ones are you know defined as iom
[Music]
methods can
can we define this as a specific iom
protocol as well but we can carry that
on our list
thank you yes it can be yeah stay in the
same family here
all right and we're just going to keep
going i know it's at time if anyone
needs to leave they can but let's
get through these last little
talks delaney please go ahead
yes can you hear me
yes i can
okay perfect yep so we're going to have
a side meeting right after this and
we'll tell you the implementation i'll
just cut it really short is everything
just about everything that i've heard on
this ippm meeting could use
encryption
it's all really sensitive data
and so we want to um you know we'd love
to um work with anybody uh to do that
too and i'll be contacting you um
offline and because we're we're getting
we're getting an implementation
so that's it
great okay so anyone interested go to
the side meeting
thank you
all right
we have some user devices
explicit monitoring
all right
laura are you speaking to this
okay
this is the the draft that is a
sibling of the previous one the idea is
to put the probe on the user devices a
smartphone for example or pc in order to
have a
point that is
uh
where it is possible to make all the
measurements without
dedicated
hardware and the software inside the
network
or it can be also an additional point to
interface to the props in the network we
can have some advantages for example the
scalability
the hardware of the user is not
is very much so it's possible to have
many measurements the
measurements are more precise because
we have the point of measurement that is
on both the directions and it's possible
also the network monitoring
coordinated with with probes in the
network
so this is a about the positioning of
the probes of the species measurement
thank you we can discuss on the mainly
list of this idea
great thank you
okay and then we have our final
elevator pitch alexander
um yes hello yeah this is a brief
elevator pitch for a new draft
concerning high precision service
metrics uh the idea is basically to
define a new set of metrics that capture
whether or not the service that is being
delivered complies with the service
level objective uh for instance for when
you have uh precision services that
require a specific end-to-end latency uh
you would want to basically capture
whether or not uh yeah basically your
your uh your your flow your flows are in
compliance and so forth and multiple
applications for this in accounting
monitoring et cetera
some examples of the types of metrics
that we have in mind are fines you would
want to capture a number of packets that
were violating an objective the number
of time units
that were violated during um
during the duration of a service and
this basically gives you also second
order measures of precision availability
so not availability but available the
uh
during which a
uh service can be accessed with the uh
with agreed on uh pr uh
precision so
anyway so the the the just the elevator
page and the next steps are of course to
refine the steps and so forth and also
we would want to
ask anybody who's interested in this
work to to please reach out thank you
okay uh greg did you have a quick
question on this or comment
i'm just curious how that is different
from error performance measurement
so we can discuss it probably in the
middle because that seems to be
the same idea
okay so so um so i did not
let let's let's put this on the boiling
list
yeah uh i think it was referring to the
earlier presentation
alexander that greg made on the epm
proposal so
it sounds like you know read each
other's drafts and let's uh discuss on
the list how we can kind of combine
efforts here
all right sounds good thank you all
right
okay
um
thank you all it's
as as usual a
full
uh session but i think we made some good
progress today um
thank you to
co-chairs thanks marcus for running the
time
um
thanks ian for all your service
we shall miss you um
and thanks to everyone who came and have
a good rest of your ietf if you're going
to stuff tomorrow and we will see you
next time
bye
you