welcome everyone
it's top of the hour we're slated to get
started soon
i'd suggest we wait just a little while
to make sure our speaker
can get in so bear with me for a few
more minutes
hi everyone i was just troubleshooting
with our first speaker on how to get in
so i'm also going to just message the
meet echo people really quick about this
issue and then we can get started and
i'm sure she'll be here before
we are finished with the intro
thanks for bearing with me
okay brilliant so um
welcome to welcome everyone
to
the hrpc session
of the internet research task force at
the ietf 112 meeting um we have just one
speaker today followed by discussion of
our drafts and so
i'd like to ask for
a note taker but only for the latter
half of the meeting after the talk
would somebody volunteer themselves by
typing in the chat
anybody who can do notes please
well if you prefer i can always ask
again
uh just before we get to that second
half if i remember it'd be really great
though if somebody could help with the
notes because we'll be discussing
updates on drafts and steps forward
chime in anytime in the chat
um
so then let's go over the agenda
i'll give you a chance to revise it if
you'd like the
um after the welcome slides we'll have
andrea esterhoisen come to speak about
the internet governance forum
she's currently trying to get in the
room right now and unfortunately
we had a second top talk scheduled
to be delivered by sasha constanza shock
but will not
be able to come
today because of illness it's that time
of year um
i'm definitely due to get a cold because
everyone in my house is sick
so that's that happened
hopefully we'll see sasha at a later
ietf meeting
yeah
pity yeah because i think it's a anyway
nonetheless we uh might be done
earlier than expected because of that
then we have um from me just an intro or
an update rather on draft feminism which
is a
project we started
as part of this research group wasn't
formally adopted but juliana is here i
see who's the co-author on that um just
wanted to give you some updates and ask
your thoughts on way forward with that
work
and then we have a bunch of updates in
general so this is where i'm going to
rely on colin a lot
about the
status of
at least one draft on draft guidelines
and then i think meals there's a draft
association that might have an update or
two
it's expired but i know you're still
working on it and then lastly i think
we'll maybe get an update on the search
for a co-chair for hrpc because you'll
notice i'm here
alone today although it is really nice
that both aubry and niels are here so
once you've been a co-chair of this
group you never actually leave you just
stop sharing
okay good so i've heard that um
[Music]
andrea is on her way um let me continue
on with the intro because we've got a
few slides that you need to see
so the notewow slides um
these are from the irtf um but also they
comply with the ietf general um
ipr disclosure rules so familiarize
yourselves with these please
but you've probably seen them a few
times already this week um
the code of conduct is an important
piece also of the notewell so um
it's good for me now to remind everyone
that this is being recorded it will be
up on the internet somewhere very
shortly after
um so keep that in mind
um and you know behave yourself
then um
just wanted to give a general intro to
this group and to the irtf so
um
we are
we're not part of the iata we're not
setting standards um we're working on
the long-term issues of the internet and
one of them being certainly
human rights and the impacts
going both directions
that is what
hrpc does
it was chartered to look at how
protocols strengthen
or weaken human rights as defined in
your universal declaration of human
rights um and the
international criminal
court
never remember the acronym so the um the
point i think also happens the other way
whereas that as things change
in um the field of human rights and
other things how does that maybe impact
as well the way that we um design and
develop protocols that's maybe the idea
as well so um we have some explicit
objectives then as part of our charter
um we're obviously talking about this
relationship um of human rights and
protocols in general but in specific we
look at
two
of the human rights the first is
the right to freedom of expression
and the second is the right
to freedom of assembly and association
privacy also sometimes factors in quite
a bit since that's also a human right
but there is another research group for
that um that does i think the bulk of
that work in the irtf
um in addition to just talking about the
relationships
between these two sets of standards
human rights as a standard
and also
then internet protocols and standards
we want to actually develop specific
guidelines
this is kind of
envisioned as how the privacy
considerations of rfc 6973 were were
thought up um and we've worked towards
that um second objective with uh draft
guidelines which we'll be updating you
all about
um
in just a little while
and then the other thing that is key to
note about this group is that it isn't
the work happening here is not totally
just self-contained within the research
group a lot of us are engaged outside
of um
[Music]
this
um
so
that means that the larger human rights
community hopefully is made aware of
some of the things happening in this
technical community
and then vice versa
okay
so
moving on i'm just also chatting with
the um
the issue around henriette coming in so
um yeah so specifically then in the
human rights protocol considerations
research group we are looking beyond
just drafts as well
just internet drafts in the irtf
we also
have done a lot of work to invite
speakers from academic community from
civil society organizations and and
others we had a speaker not too long ago
from erickson talking about 5g you know
we're an equal opportunity
um
group and
we want to have um
you know influence and be influenced by
other other groups so policy and
academic papers
also result from some of the work
happening here
at some point there was a film which is
really cool um there have been
interviews as well so these are other
products of the working group outside of
just
you know
rfcs and ids and that sort of thing um
folks
have suggested use of data analysis for
some of this research um we had at the
last meeting 111
sebastian come and talk about big bang
there's an upcoming iab workshop on the
same
so that can help as well further ideas
around
data-driven research that we could do in
hrpc which is excellent
and
um yeah we want to then through the
guidelines document of rfc 8280 um or
based on a280 to also then review um
um
the
protocols elsewhere in the ietf based on
this so we're actively
a lot of us from hrpc are
consciously and active
consciously active in the ietf
to think about human rights
as we engage in those
groups
um
one moment
thanks okay
continuing so yeah the work to date um
i mentioned some of these already
we were chartered um
you know
some years ago
there's been a film
there has been also then one rfc 8280
that i mentioned um
thanks niels for putting that workshop
in the chat very helpful
and then we've got
some
not all of these are active in the
technical data tracker sense though
they're active because i know they're
being worked on um we have uh guidelines
for human rights protocol considerations
um that's in
the that's just been reviewed actually
by colin the rtf chair
so that's progressing um and then we
have as well um active draft on freedom
of association
on the internet and another one on
feminism and protocols you'll get an
update on
both of them today
and where they're at
though that is um what i have for you
right now as far as an intro we still
don't have henriette in the chat because
apparently there's just been a confusion
about her um registration so if you
allow me to put myself on mute for a
second i'm going to go back to our
agenda
and then ask you if you have
any changes you'd like to make is there
any other business
um
things you want to add
songs you want to sing dances you want
to do
trying to fill time
uh hi mallory does it make sense to
maybe do some of the updates on the
drafts while we're trying to get
henrietta
make sense to me
yeah i appreciate that so let's jump to
item
five
and i can save my presentation on draft
feminism for after henriette so yeah
status updates we can just take these in
turn do you wanna um do we wanna talk is
there anything to say about the co-chair
search
yeah hi uh so for the the co-chair
search uh you
sent me um some really good candidates
and then i failed to get a chance to
talk to them so that is entirely my
fault uh and i i realize i i'm running
behind on that
but yeah i mean that they thought there
looked to be some some really good uh
potential uh co-chairs on that list and
uh i'm hoping to talk to them next week
uh
we will see
but yeah i realize i'm behind on that
it should be fine
uh that got cut off at the beginning i'm
afraid
there was also some feedback but
it's not your result okay cool yeah um
thanks for that colin it's okay we've um
we had this um
this meeting fairly well organized well
in advance and we've got quite a lot of
time until um april and as far as i know
not a whole lot of intervening
um
[Music]
intersectional work so
um
we'll we'll endeavor to have that sorted
by the next meeting for sure um
and so yeah thanks very much for your
support with that
yeah as i say i'm sorry that's taking a
little while and yeah i'm hoping to get
it sorted
well before the next meeting
okay wonderful
yeah go ahead nails
hi all does this mean that there are
several candidates for the new
co-chairship did i just hear that
correctly
yeah so the process was that we did um
outreach to the list and actually to
other places as well this is going with
some of our goals and objectives for the
group we wanted to cast our net wide
into other communities so you
folks who are tuned in to this work
might have seen me put like email a few
different places um after
i didn't really put a deadline on it for
when i wanted folks to email me if they
were interested
but it was clear that interest
sort of flared up and then sort of
petered out so at some point i went
through folks who had emailed me i
looked at their cvs and then i gave
colin a sort of short list of folks that
i thought
fit the criteria that we'd sort of
looked at so we were hoping to get since
i represent civil society we were hoping
to get one or even two additional
co-chairs that would be either coming
from industry coming from academia
and that had complementary
background and skills so sociologists
has always been on our wish list for um
co-chair ships and so based on what i
understood to be the criteria i gave
colin a few options and i think again
like it could be that not just one new
um
one new church could join another one
could as well or even you know since
there's interest and folks um getting
involved in this work which is always
flattering we can also think of other
roles right like please come uh give a
presentation please come you know help
document shepard or edit um this work
that sort of thing so that's we're
hoping that actually everyone who
reached out with interest um can find um
work here in the um hr pc
um that that's my ulterior motive but
it'd be good also to have um at least
one co-chair as well before the next
meeting so
yeah and uh i mean a comment i give to
research groups regularly is is that you
have a lot of flexibility in your
process so
if there are a role roles you can find
to bring in people uh even if they're
not
the sort of traditional role you might
see in an ietf group then you know the
research groups have the flexibility to
do things in a different way if that's
useful
if it helps advance the goals
any other comments on this you can come
to the mic or you can
okay so there's a good question in the
chat about good starting place for
newcomers um well this is a really good
starting place um to be here in this
meeting so thanks for joining we're
gonna go over sort of current work items
and um
and then yeah there's also a website
that we have um that is a little bit
more detailed than the the information
about hpc and the data tracker and the
other thing you might do and this is
maybe some slight change we could add to
that um
website niels just shared which is to
watch
older
um meetings that are now all on youtube
so you can go back
and see what um some of the speakers
we've had come to talk about work it's
it doesn't always it doesn't always
result in a draft
uh necessarily um but i think it
introduces the possibility for um for
collaboration and research and then um
of course you get um sort of the you can
track the different um drafts we've had
um the discussion about those and that
sort of thing
um
right
so i think
um
[Music]
what else could we talk about i think um
actually if we could get an update from
you colin while you're still on camera
and here on uh draft guidelines i saw
and everybody should have seen your
review of that go to the hrpc list i
believe or if it didn't it just went to
authors but it was very thorough of you
i thought your comments really excellent
if you wanted to sign post some of this
uh yes i think i sent it to the hr pc
list so hopefully everyone should have
seen that
um
yeah so i mean this is draft guidelines
dash 10 so it's a draft irt feature pc
guidelines dash 10.
um a a since a really long uh detailed
review um i guess it was over the
weekend i forget possibly the end of
last week um
i actually thought this document was
really interesting it's
a really interesting read
there were a whole bunch of
really interesting questions it raises
and a lot of things to think about when
designing protocols and developing
standards
um so it i think it's it's an important
document uh i think it's something that
the the group needs to finish up uh and
i i can see it being very useful to the
community when it's finished
in terms of the
um
content i i had
five main issues and then
a bunch of details
the the main issues um
i mean the the document is structured
around you using the you're in
declaration of human rights uh
and a bunch of other
similar documents to to signpost the
list of human rights to consider uh and
then builds up a bunch of questions
uh to think about when when bill you're
designing a protocol and how those
relate to those rights
um
and
i mean that that seems to me as
someone who who isn't a
human rights lawyer or uh
you know isn't active in that space as a
plausible
way of starting it
um
i
would have found it more helpful if the
documents had said more about those
rights
um
you know as someone coming in from an
engineering background i i can read the
headline
definitions in there and i can sort of
guess what they mean
but obviously you know different
um you know there will be a body of
experience of interpreting those those
rights a bunch of different people and
perhaps in different countries will have
um
different interpretations of what those
rights and those responsibilities mean
um and i i would expect that the extent
to which they're incorporated into
various national laws would vary and
the way the different national laws
interpret those rights uh and the way
different cultures and different
countries interpret those rights would
vary
um so i think it would help the reader
if the document said
more about what are those rights and um
perhaps how the authors interpret them
but also perhaps
how they're interpreted in in different
bodies of law and in different cultures
in different countries um
and giving some sort of concrete
examples of that which
might make this perhaps somewhat
abstract discussion about rights uh
something quite concrete which people
developing protocols can see how they
directly relate to them
um
and
you know um
[Music]
freedom of speech for example gets
mentioned a lot and i think that's one
thing where um
for example a u.s based interpretation
and a european interpretation might
differ in in ways which would surprise
some people uh i think once we start
getting into the various privacy laws
handling of personal data and how they
relate to the rights um
it seems that the the gdpr for example
is quite different to the the equivalent
laws in the us or in china or in other
places so something that talks about how
these rights get reflected down into
regulations and how those differ around
the world and maybe giving some examples
of
how they turn into concrete regulations
that people
you know have to conform to
might help make this real to the the
engineers actually designing the
protocols and make it clear why this is
a real
you know a real concern they actually
have to pay attention to rather than an
abstract would-be nice concern
um and if nothing else it means that uh
you know it's it's easier to say well
you know you you need to pay attention
to this because you will be subject to
this set of laws and you should be start
paying attention to how they relate to
human rights and how it affects your
products
so i think some of that discussion would
be useful just to set the scene and make
it more concrete
um in terms of the the later bits of the
document um
it's
it talks about development of protocols
and having human rights reviews of
protocols um and i guess that's more of
a historical thing from the way
the group has evolved and the way the
document has involved
i'm hoping this can turn into something
where um
it's more something which critical
design is taking to take on board as
they develop the protocol
uh rather than where a group of people
comes your parachutes into the group and
says hi we're from the human rights
review team we're here to help
um
and i think that yeah i think phrasing
it perhaps in a less
less of a you are being reviewed for
human rights more of a here are a bunch
of questions that you may want to think
about when you're designing your
protocol i think i think would just make
it a slightly less antagonistic
adversarial process and might make
make it a little easier sell to parts of
the community
um the big bit was the
the meat of the dread is a long list of
questions to consider um to illustrate
various human rights choices um
and as i said at the beginning there's a
lot of really good questions there right
and
there are certainly things i hadn't
thought about i'm sure that
most of the people in this community
there will be things that they they
haven't thought about and would deserve
to think more about i'm saying that's a
really nice list of questions
um
i thought the the order wasn't
necessarily the most obvious order in
places there was a moderate amount of
overlap between the questions um
so a um
you know i think there are there are
some ways in which this could be fixed
editorially um
which would make the material easier to
follow
i think in in places the document
was phrased in ways that
advocate particular approaches without
necessarily acknowledging the the
complexity of the the trade-offs
one one example might be there was some
um
there was some discussion of
prioritization um and it it talks about
the network neutrality impacts of it and
the impact on choice and and topics like
that if i'm remembering right
uh and and you know these are all
clearly real issues and like they're
clearly potential problems um
what the
if i'm remembering it right what it
didn't so much to talk about was well
there's also arguments for being able to
prioritize certain types of traffic um
you know if i make an emergency call on
my voiceover ip phone uh i would quite
like the the traffic to be prioritized
uh over the neighbors kids watching um
sort of cartoons and using up all the
local link bandwidth right um
and i think if you look at a bunch of
these issues raised there's
that there's arguments for you for and
against prioritizing certain types of
certain characteristics um
and
in most of the cases there is a
trade-off to be made
we saw something similar i guess with a
quick group and the spin bits where
you know
certain people wanted to to be able to
um
measure the network for various reasons
um some people wanted measurement not to
happen um
and um
obviously there are clearly ways you can
go way too far
in the measurement and collect far too
much information and be very invasive of
privacy
equally going entirely the other
direction not allowing any measurement
makes the network unmanageable
and there is a need for the network
operators to have some information about
the traffic flows just to see that the
network is is correctly being operated
and there was a big discussion about
that and we you know
the group eventually after um
more discussion than i would imagined
would have imagined was possible about
one bit eventually came to some
consensus on
how that should be done
but you know in most of these cases
there's a trade-off and it's
it's balancing different um
different needs and different concerns
and that balance doesn't always come
across in places
um
and i think it would be be useful to
adopt more of a sort of neutral point of
view you know here are the trade-offs if
you are trying to optimize for this then
you need to consider the following
things and emphasize the following
things if you're trying to optimize for
that then you need to
um
rather than necessarily advocating one
approach and giving the impression that
if if you are not fully behind that then
um you know that's
that's that's a problem
uh and you know i don't think that
that's the intent but the way the doc
draft comes across in places it could be
it could be balanced out a little bit
more
um and i i think there are
also a couple of places and i'm
blanking on examples right now where um
it could perhaps be a little bit clearer
on what the
general
what concrete things the protocol
designer can do to emphasize particular
outcomes you know if you want if this is
your goal
then
you know
emphasize this thing and if that's your
goal then emphasize the other thing and
there's a couple of places where it
highlights an issue but doesn't really
suggest which directions to go depending
on what you're trying to optimize for
so i think that was my high level view
um as i say there's a lot of really good
work in here there's a lot of really
good questions in here it's just getting
them structured in a way phrased in a
way and perhaps getting a little more
detail in a bunch of places um
to really highlight the issues so
it's it's you know a bunch of
interesting things but not quite there
yet
also on behalf on uh guru shabbat i'd
like to thank you very much for the uh
for the very much in-depth review which
is which is which was really good and
really helpful and
we already started working on an
approach but uh of course we don't have
uh
don't have it fully fleshed out yet
but please allow me to provide some
preliminary observations
and one thing that is uh
that i think important with draft
guidelines is that we do not want to
redo
rfc 8280
so that we want a really like
practicable document and not
re-establish the whole theory the whole
history of
human rights the interrelation between
human rights and protocols because if we
start to redo that then we'll have
another 80 page document and we'll not
get to the guidelines right but i very
much understand that we need that we
could um
[Music]
that that human rights are implemented
differently but i think we really also
chose this research group to be about
human rights to ensure that we do not
need to compare the 194 different
regulations in all the countries of the
world but use the most widely shared
norm there is and that countries have
subscribed to and therefore focus on
human rights and how they are translated
but we can definitely add a sentence to
make clear that they are explained
differently in different jurisdictions
and uh
i think it needs more than more than a
sentence here
the you know
reading this i i'm not actually
without doing a bunch of further reading
understanding what right the document is
talking about or how they translate into
something concrete
so i agree you can
look at all of the different
um
you know all of the different countries
and how these are interpreted in all the
different countries because yeah
obviously that's a multi-hundred page
sort of uh
legal essay um but i think some you know
being you know going through the right
thing a little bit about what's meant by
each one giving a couple of examples uh
about each one is
important to make it clear to the
readers who are not steeped in the human
rights culture what's being talked about
here
so
we need to explain
the rights
explain how the rights
are connecting to
technology
or
how they connect how they are translated
to different jurisdictions because these
are also three huge different fields
right
um so i mean just just reading the
the the
the documentary it talks about
human
i mean section two sort of lists uh a
bunch of rights uh but it says very very
little about what each of those mean and
um
you know
what their practical impact on on
anything is
um so yeah as you know i i can look at
that list and i i can guess what it
might mean
but i'd have to guess what it might
means and what
because i don't have that background and
i think most people in you know
developing protocols don't have that
background in in understanding what
people mean when they talk about these
various rights and what that actually
means in practice so rather than having
people guess what's intended i think it
needs a some text in here to say okay
this is what it means and for example
it translates into
you know whatever set of laws in this
country i mean obviously not in all
countries because that's that's a
ludicrous amount but
you know if you're talking about the you
know protecting personal data then it
would be useful for example to mention
that that you know that gets uh
interpreted as the gdpr in in europe for
example
so and i'm sure that a bunch of places
or if it doesn't this is just showing
that that you know this needs something
there's some confusion here but you know
it needs just a few words i think to try
and make it a bit more concrete
okay but i think i think what we
really try to do with the work is try to
focus on human rights and once we start
treading
into national regulations and into
policies of different countries
then things become much murkier right
and that that was also the strategic and
the tactical discussion that's also in
the charter so i'm i'm i'm a bit
but i'll definitely try to to hint to
that how
as examples
but
making that part of a structural piece
of the study i think would be uh would
be opening us up for far more work and i
think like to establish the relationship
between different rights
and technologies
we've outlined several cases in rfc 8280
to establish the uh
the relationship
and i'm not sure we would want to do
that again in this document because for
instance draft association which is
another document really goes that into
depth
to
dive into
what one of these rights means and that
would then be a whole document so i'm
also a bit like what do we fit where and
do we have a kitchen sink approach and
what do we try to do in which documents
so
and guidelines are really like what's
the guidelines documents but i would
definitely
say that there can points to other
documents can point to other literature
and point to other things but trying to
do that work in this document might then
distract from the actual
objective of the document yeah okay i
mean that that's fair and and it may be
that what this needs is something
relatively brief and a bunch of pointers
um
but you know all i'm saying is is that
reading this as someone who doesn't have
that human rights background i i got you
know i can guess what's being meant but
i didn't know uh and i think having to
guess what's meant is is not helpful
and that's that's
yeah
just a couple reactions from a broad
overview of the group i think um on the
one hand in figuring out how to sign
posts to different drafts i mean
guidelines definitely should point back
to 80 280 that's where it goes into
depth and guidelines is meant to be sort
of like a a re
uh
it's just it's actually just a rev
a different version of 8280 but in a
more practical way so that's one that we
need but we need to bring out the
salient points and i think we've
actually had that discussion i'm happy
with where it's at on that level but
then specifically to
the question of national laws i think in
the past we've because this came up
actually um not long ago sandra raised
it there was quite a prolonged
discussion on the list and we did i
think determined that it was out of
scope but i think what you're saying
colin which is i think useful feedback
is that for someone who's reading this
document and trying to glean
knowledge from it to do better in making
these trade-offs um around
decision-making it might actually be
helpful to get that guidance um not in
the specific i don't think it would be
helpful actually even to look at you
know the big countries with the big laws
i think we shouldn't do that i think
what we should say then instead is
here's an approach you can take
to just make sure you know if it's and
it's not going to be for all sections
but certainly for like data privacy or
other things there's going to be a need
to suggest to people
um to look at any applicable laws and
since
it's tends to be glo like we're building
global
protocols protocols that are meant to be
rolled out not in any particular country
it's worth i think nodding at that as
part of the process um because also i
think niels and this is maybe a
departure from the discussion we've had
in the past is that there is a path to
achieving compliance with human rights
through national laws because
governments are um accountable and
responsible for doing that they're you
know signed
signatories to the
um human rights declaration so it's not
out of the realm of possibility that
that would actually be a useful thing i
just don't think we need to elaborate on
it because
um of all the reasons we mentioned right
because it you know it's it's slightly
out of scope from our charter that's not
the reason i'm leaning into right now
it's it's just that there's maybe too
many um
countries to consider um we're rolling
out global protocols and also
um they will change over time and so
just baking it into the process i think
is the suggested change maybe that would
be an opportunity to point
um protocol developers in the right
direction as far as
compliance on specifically the kinds of
privacy and other kinds of laws that
would actually matter
yeah it just seems quite abstract the
way it's written and you know i know a
lot of this has gotten reflected in more
concrete terms and it's just i think
probably be useful to to the people
actually building the protocols to make
it a little more concrete
yeah and so for rights
that are going to have
a counterpart in national law it might
be useful to say that it's not going to
be for all of the rights
um
great thank you for the um
overview of your feedback colin and
thanks very much niels for engaging on
that i think actually the bulk of
that work is going to happen on the list
right niels and gershwat are going to
digest all that feedback come out with a
new version ask questions where they
need to clarify your
review and then we'll aim to move that
draft forward so thanks to you both
sure i mean if it's useful to have a
chat with the authors about this
then i'm very happy to arrange that
excellent thanks so much
good um niels i wonder if you wanted to
um stay up here with me in gallery view
for a second because i want to ask you
about what's happening with draft
association or if you wanted to
um any updates or thoughts about what's
next
yeah so i think draft association has
done a lot of the things that the
research group has asked it to
and um
uh once again i went through the whole
list and uh couldn't find any other
things anymore so i think it's currently
in the waiting uh line for a document
shepard
so uh
i hope that once it gets a document
shepard it will uh maybe
receive just such an excellent review as
draft guidelines has gotten and then we
can also move that document forward and
then we hopefully we kind of cleaned up
some space for uh some fresh new
documents
so yeah so if there is a uh
someone who has followed the discussion
on draft association and wants to help
it get to the uh
to the finish line
please uh please make yourself known and
happy to work with you
and to be clear about why we need a
document shepherd because i'm a
co-author and um i'm the only coat i'm
the only chair at the moment so we just
need somebody else to come in um in my
view both as
chair and a co-author it's in a really
good place we had um
now it's been a year and a half i think
since we've completed
a real overhaul um led by
uh stefan couture through um sort of
redoing the literature review coming up
with sub questions coming up with cases
that address the sub questions so
um
and it hasn't
it hasn't become controversial on the
list i think there's actually quite a
lot of support and a lot of um past
discussion that indicates the draft is
in a really solid place so it would be
actually quite straightforward for
somebody who
would like to be a document shepard even
if you're new to doing um
shepherding that would be fine but we
would really appreciate some extra
participation so that we can take the
next step with this draft
go ahead
yeah just just follow up on that the
role of the the shepherd in in the irtf
process is is just is primarily to
document the consensus
of the draft and and to
um help make sure it gets through the
review process
um so so the the primary you know the
primary effect here is is doing a
uh a
review of the draft and the discussion
and writing up you know the extent to
which there has been consensus and
agreement and disagreement on on the
list
and in the group
um and then just working with me and
with the the irst to just make sure that
review happens and chasing people up to
follow up on review comments and things
like that
so it's it's not an especially onerous
role
and it's a it's a draft that's very
explicitly listed in our charter in the
sense that we are you know we've done
the sort of broad human rights work with
8280 and the guidelines draft um but the
human rights to freedom of association
and assembly is listed specifically so
it's a really important i think
cornerstone of our group go ahead niels
i promise i won't need a lot of chasing
so uh just to make
things easier
okay excellent
all right i think that is uh that is all
for our updates um i
um
did exactly what i thought i was gonna
do was just forget to beg somebody to do
note taking on this so we'll probably
just have to watch this
next week and write up the notes
um so this is the only portion of the
meeting i think where we need to have
notes except for maybe after i present
on draft feminism so
anyway with that i think we're at a good
place to
shift
uh let me put the agenda back up again
um
so we've we've taken care of one
and five we don't have any in any other
business and sasha's unable to present
so it's just up to honor yet now who um
can go ahead um put yourself on camera
if you can ae with the um the buttons in
the top
and you can send screen in just a second
and
yeah
thanks so much let me give you
permission
can you see my
slides
not in presentation mode unfortunately
let me try again
i can't page
let's see how's that can you see that
um
okay
um is that the correct slide
does it have the the slide number one
it says q a sorry
that's the wrong one i cancer sorry
about this let me um
do that again
unfortunately i can't move this
i had it in presentation mode is that
better
yeah now that it's in the first slide
okay great
so apologies again everyone but i won't
dwell on it and thanks so much for
inviting me i've been following your
work for many years
um from a distance although i've
attended some of the sessions at icann
meetings
and um i'm just very happy to be here
so i'm andrew esterhosen i'm currently
the chair of the internet governance
forum multi-stakeholder advisory
committee until the end of this year
and i want to talk to you about the igf
so
i'll go a little bit into the background
and mallory is that the correct slide
now is that the one that says outcome of
the world summit
yes that's great right
so so the igf and i know many of you
have been part of the igf in at one
point or another
it's this fairly unique kind of creature
in the sense that it is an outcome of a
formal united nations process
the world summit on the information
society
um in 2005
and but it's not part of a un process in
a very rigid or strict way so it's
connected to the u.n it's bound by some
of the u.n bureaucracy and protocols but
it also has a life of its own because it
has evolved
into
initially an event but now more of a
process that is organized by a
multi-stakeholder advisory group the
group i chair which is appointed by the
un secretary general
and there is a secretariat which is part
of the un they they sit inside the uan
division for economic and social affairs
but really the igf is shaped by the
community by the people that run
sessions that participate in sessions
that submit input on what should be the
agenda of the igf so the bottom-up
approach has actually been very
firmly established in the igf
and sometimes there is tension between
this bottom-up approach and the more
bureaucratic um un system approach but
somehow it kind of works
and it has evolved over time this is the
15th anniversary of the igf 2021
and the renewal of the igf mandate by
member states um will be reconsidered in
2025. and that in itself is actually
quite um significant because the igf
um does not actually control its own
destiny and not entirely anyway
it's very much linked to this definition
of internet governance
which i know avery is in the room with
us she was a member of the working group
on internet governance the wiki a group
which between 2003 and 2005
um
investigated explored internet
governance and how it should be
approached and they came up with this
definition which i find very interesting
because it is so broad and it was in in
a sense a counterpoint
to what at the time
were the prevailing more technical
definitions of internet governance
focused on the coordination and the
technical management of the internet and
this definition i'll just read the last
phrase um looks at norm's rules
decision-making procedures and programs
that shape the evolution and use of the
internet so it's really very soundly um
focusing in on that constantly growing
space um
of people and and the internet being
shaped by people and interacting with
people
and just to talk about human rights just
very briefly because i know this is this
is part of the work that you've been
doing has been trying to put human
rights on the agenda in a space
that
was not necessarily initially designed
or that didn't anticipate that should
prioritize human rights and actually
this also applied to the igf um it's
been quite a long and elaborate struggle
to get human rights recognis recognized
as an important topic at the igf
probably it's taken about 10 years at
least it was covered very broadly under
one of the main themes of the idea of
the historical main themes openness
but it has been difficult to get more
in-depth discussion on human rights
there was a fear um from some of the igf
supporters that if we put human rights
on the igf's agenda some governments
would lose interest or they would they
would withdraw report or even that the
private sector might not be that
interested
and the same applies to gender issues um
it's taken a long time and quite a lot
of assertiveness from the bottom up to
get these issues recognized as
legitimate internet governance topics
and so to tell you a bit about the mag
that's the multi-stakeholder advisory
group
and the context that we've worked with
this year has been um
really the pandemic has been
a major concern in 2020 we had a fully
virtual igf which was much easier to
organize than the hybrid igf we're doing
this year
but it has also heightened awareness of
the internet and the importance of
internet policy frameworks that that
prioritize access particularly access
for those that are excluded from access
and that are impacted on it so
incredibly profoundly in the context of
the pandemic
the other factor that's been a big issue
for us this year is the u.n secretary
general's roadmap for digital
cooperation
and papers and proposals from various
governments that emerge from that the
pending renewal of the mandate and the
fact that internet governance in itself
is is continuously changing and growing
it's no longer a set of processes that
you can you know define as sitting
inside icann the igf
uh maybe the international
telecommunications union and internet
governance has just proliferated and
there are spaces at national global and
regional level that deal with various
internet related um
policy um issues and and we need to
somehow still find a way for the igf to
be the connector the common space that
brings all the all those different
forums together
um just our goals have been to be more
uh inclusive that's always a goal for
the igf to remain relevant to be more
focused and impact oriented and to
integrate all the different activities
that are are now part of the igf
ecosystem and i'll say a bit more about
that
the this year's igf and i invite you all
to participate it's free and it's open
there are more than 200 um sessions
of different nature different kinds of
sessions some are more formal some are
more informal and but what i think is
really interesting you know are the
topics that will be discussed they're
only two main issue areas um economic
and social inclusion and human rights
and universal and meaningful access and
for each of those there are a set of
policy questions which which emerged
from the community input we received
and the workshops and other sessions at
the igf will try to respond to some of
these challenges
and then there are four cross-cutting
areas emerging regulation
from content regulation
to antitrust regulation it's just
increasingly a topic that needs to be
discussed it comes with risks
it needs to be approached with caution
but it also needs to be considered as
something i mean i heard you talk about
data privacy earlier for example
trust security security and stability
environment and climate change and i
actually want to bring that up because
there's a proposal on the table for
environmental impact assessments to
become part of internet governance and
then digital cooperation that's the sort
of bigger picture the whole sort of
metaverse of
of internet governance and digital
cooperation the multi-stakeholder and
the multilateral bits of it
the idea is not just a conference so
that's that's always important it has
these different
components and different modalities
which are all very bottom up and you can
all participate in them there are two
policy networks one on environment one
on universal and meaningful access
there are 20 plus dynamic coalitions
ranging from looking at issues like
platform regulation to gender um to
community connectivity
there are more than 140 national and
regional and youth igfs there's this
newly announced leadership panel in fact
there's a call for nominations that went
out yesterday
and there's the mag and the mag has
working groups and while the mag members
are appointed by the secretary general
the working groups are open to anyone
who's interested the secretariat the
staff the u.n division of economic and
social affairs that's the most
affordable component but then there's
the igf community and and it's really
quite vast you know we had in 2020 we
had nearly 7 000 participants in the igf
process
and that's really the life of the igf
um just quickly to mention you might be
interested they're two best practice
forums this year
these are communities that work together
to do some research and they generate a
report one on norms
in cyber security
and understanding how they work
effectively
to mitigate adverse cybersecurity events
and then one looking at gendered
misinformation and disinformation and
looking at practices and tools and
policies that can help build a less
toxic environment for female and gender
diverse groups in the online space
okay i'm kind of at the end just the
internet governance um is the internet
governance forum is at a bit of a
critical juncture in the sense that the
mandate renewal is coming up it's being
challenged by the un secretary general
um to be more output-oriented
um
and there's also a concern that in fact
maybe the igf shouldn't be so
output-oriented that it should focus on
deliberation and discourse on being a
place for discussion not a place for
negotiation there are also exciting
opportunities in particular there's this
common agenda
published by the united nations
secretary general in september
and it emphasizes the global digital
comments
and this could be an opportunity in fact
for for looking at the internet as such
a digital commons and putting some
principles on the table
along the lines of the internet being
governed and internet governance needing
to be underpinned
by these principles of the internet as a
digital um commons and but that of
course um will take a lot of debate and
there'll be a lot of of
different perspectives on that and then
the igf as a process and institution
also needs to to strengthen um in order
to to continue to evolve
so really i'm i'm looking forward to
your questions i just wanted to to
reflect that i think there'd be value in
some collaboration between yourselves
and the igf
or for you to come in fact as you are to
the idea to share some of your
experiences in fact i think the idea of
impact assessments and how they can work
better how they work well
um so a kind of lessons learning or best
practice good practice gathering
on impact assessments could be very
useful and from the perspective of human
rights impact perspectives but also from
from the perspective of these proposed
environmental um impact assessments
um there's also a discussion about the
human rights based approach to internet
governance and so they're different
modalities we could form a dynamic
coalition we could just have a bilateral
but i i do hope that that your work can
continue to be and become more visible
at the ig event if there any ways in
which you think the igf can support your
work let's talk about it back to you
mallory
thanks henriette um
really it's a great presentation i have
i can talk with you all day about this i
wish that we could do that um
but i want other people from
um
the participants to ask um
if there are questions if um folks are
familiar with the igf if you've been
what your assessment is
um i think yeah andrea is the expert in
the room right now on this
i'm trying to stop sharing
stuff if you'd like to um i don't know
before you had your camera going unreal
but we didn't see anything we just saw
black swear if that's how you like it
that's fine um but just inviting you if
you want to
put your camera i'd be happy here i've
just been kind of switched but it's dark
here i need to switch the light off but
please let's i'll i'll do that but let's
just get the the questions going in the
meantime andrew go ahead
all right uh thank you and uh always
good to get the background on the on the
uh
igf so thanks for the presentation
and yet just turning your your last
point back on its head
um i think it will be fantastic to get
uh more participants from the igf
involved in the
because we could really do with a lot
more input from people with a better
understanding of the policy implications
of standards decisions
i'm sure not everyone in the itf would
agree with me on that but um i think
we'd end up with better better standards
uh if we understood the the real world
impact of some of the choices uh being
made
but other than that i'm really looking
forward to uh in-person participation in
poland in a few weeks time which will be
fantastic
thank you absolutely andrew there is
actually a dynamic coalition on
standards
that is it was initiated by a guy called
de natris i don't know if you followed
that work
it was relatively um
it it operated as a kind of standalone
project at some point
um
but now it's a self-organized community
of practice
i'm not sure if any of the of the itf
people are involved in that but i
absolutely agree with you and i think
that that in fact in the early days of
the igf there was more conversation and
i've read i wonder if you even remember
that
there was more focus on standards in the
early period of the igf and than there
is now
and so and i andrew i think it's very
important to have that kind of cross
virtualization the the bigger picture
perspective
along with the specificity the the
specific technical um
detail that you have to deal with in the
standards process so yeah that's uh it
is important i agree
but for example we have um you know
human rights protocol considerations
group that is um
not working as well you can hear my
audio right um
i can hear you
good
the platform is lying to me um yeah i
the i think the other one you mentioned
too is the best practice forum on cyber
security and i've also been engaged in
that for a while and it i think um a lot
of folks who
helped me with my research projects in
that group
um could could apply those here it's
just
they're not it's not always so very
technical but for example like this year
um i've had a team researching
how um
internet security events could have
maybe been
mitigated differently if
whether or not
um international norms would have
actually made a difference
um so we'll see but it could be similar
to i think um work in in irtf around
um you know could these practices have
been different looking in the past at
different things
um so simon hicks has mentioned in the
chat um that the
the large players from the ietf haven't
been involved i think that's not always
true i don't know about this year but in
the past i know the ietf has
hosted um a forum
an open forum open forum is a
a workshop style or a session style
where um a body this goes to the igf as
being a sort of connector so if you are
representing
you know another sort of internet
governance body you can hold an open
forum in which
people participants come to learn about
your body and then um you can have
questions and answers and i think folks
from the iab have done that in the past
but i don't know actually it's on the
schedule for poland
um
there are lots of open forums i think
there are about 40 different open forums
i'm not sure who is um
i don't think the itf is presenting one
but but that is a modality that you can
use and and in fact there's there's also
what we've tried to do is make the igf
more flexible
and uh
the one of the the
forms of organizing a session during the
igf as a networking session and that
remains open in fact one could apply now
for a networking session on on a
particular topic you could for example
during the igf
organize a networking session on
standards
and you know do during a lunch break and
just invite everyone who's at the igf
who cares about standards um to come
together and and share their reflections
on whether you know the policy people
understand standards or not um for
example
yes and colin is saying um that the ice
the internet society is internet society
is running an open forum
they they're talking uh specifically
about their internet way of net you know
the internet way of networking their
approach
at the moment which they've been working
with which is to apply apply um the
interoperability
um
of internet protocols and how the
internet operates as an interconnected
network to policy making so it's
interesting they had sessions on this
last year as well but they are
definitely running an open forum on that
i can download
there's not one for the iab or the ietf
um i also heard w3c talking about doing
one but i don't see
i don't think wc3 applied in the end
but there is a yeah no i don't think
they did they are participating in the
dynamic coalition on accessibility and
disability so they might be
participating
uh in that session with the standards
with their recently uh released
standards on accessibility
i i'm going to jump into my question
since there's no one else in the queue
so one of my questions um i have two
actually the first is about the
leadership panel that you mentioned has
just been
the open call has gone around um as of
yesterday
because it lists
various criteria for who
uh how there will be um
stakeholder participation so they've
held two slots
for the technical community for a
representative or senior director
position of the technical community do
you know how that's been defined and how
they plan on
i would i would assume there would need
to be outreach to the you know iab or
other people who are in a position of
leadership within different sdos do you
know how they're going to go about that
i think i know what you know which is in
the document um on the igf website which
has the nomination process and the terms
of reference
um but yes i think they are looking for
for
um o c and leadership
two people from each stakeholder groups
uh each stakeholder group and then they
have these two at large uh positions as
well
so you know i think it really is
important that one makes nominations
um and that you motivate you know that
you're looking at people i i mean
personally i think it's not enough just
to be a ceo of an international
technical organization you also need to
be someone that's willing to put in the
time
and and engage with the space because
what would be the role
of technical community leadership on
that igf leadership panel the role would
be to bring the igf community um closer
to to the technical community and vice
versa
um
so um it would be important you know for
it to be people that that actually have
the interest and the capacity and the
time to play that kind of role
one consideration is that there aren't
as far as i know there's not a lot of
mechanisms either in the itf or even
icann or w3c around
appointments on behalf of
a technical community that's why i found
it like an interesting inclusion but if
because the i think the term in the
technical community's liaison right
you're like the liaison
you know icann and the itf or you're the
liaison between the itu and the ietf you
would be the liaison between the ietf
and the igf but not that you're actually
representing not just the body that
you're a leader in you're representing
the whole technical community so if
there are two slots and let's say you
know someone from the itu-t
and then someone from
you know the ieee
are appointed they're actually
responsible for connecting all these
sdos so it's just a bit you know it's
it's actually kind of a tall order and
i'm not sure
it's a very true order
you know i i think it is
there's a rotation the terms are two
years
um
i think i wouldn't even go as far as
calling it a representation i don't
think you can represent the entire
technical community in its diversity
with two people
i think that applies to the other
stakeholders as well you know but i
think that that you know maybe if it's
the iab
you know it and if it's if it's if it's
if it's the iatf maybe that will bring a
particular perspective um um maybe
two years later it can be isoc maybe it
can be someone completely different
somebody who is outside of the
institutional framework but very deeply
embedded in the development of the
internet um i think it is a tour order
but i wouldn't aim for perfect
representativity
i would really aim for someone with the
interest and the commitment and and who
is well networked
within the technical community
um andrew thanks a lot for posting that
link
uh and then just the last question maybe
this will spark others for more
discussion but um i noticed the tension
between whether or not the igf should
continue to be a place for um discussion
um and deliberation or whether it should
have more outputs and i
i feel like output driven can be a lot
it can be very meaningful like it's one
of the reasons why i've engaged more in
intersessional work
over
years i've been in working in the igf
rather than just focusing on the annual
event
um but i think even output is very
different from like
you know consequence or
binding um deliberations it it's a very
different kind of space than the ietf
for example where there's clear outputs
but also not just
that it's an output it's actually it it
then they these outputs go out in the
world and they do something very
specific i mean there's we're not making
sure people are implementing
the standards
but they will be implemented and that's
very important i wonder you know if
there's also a parallel in the igf where
it isn't just about producing outputs
but if there is um a push for or what's
the discussion i guess around making the
igf um
outcomes i guess of consequence to the
internet
i think that
that i think what the the strength of
the ijf is is that it brings very
diverse perspectives and interests
together
and
and it's in a sense a safe space where
where where those those interests can
play themselves out use one example the
topic of regulation for example
um a regulation of platforms let's take
that um as an example
how should that be done
should it be self-regulation should it
be by global agreement um as in further
development
around the international system human
rights standards for example should it
be done by national legislatures
do we need new internet legislation as
some people in civil society want
and the private sector in the sense at
the moment is kind of driving the
process by by putting self-regulation
into the pla into place the facebook
oversight board for example
um is that sufficient um
so the value of the igf is that allows
us to debate
the pros and cons and of those different
approaches
so in a way it's a very um
indirect
way of influencing decision making
sometimes yes sometimes you'll get
consensus
and that can then be channeled as a
consensus position or insight from the
igf into other decision making forums
and take something like spectrum
regulation for example there's been a
consensus that spectrum should be
regulated dynamically rather than as a
scarce resource
and the igf has been sending that
message to the itu and to regulators for
10 years still not really being
implemented
and but sometimes there isn't consensus
and just the fact that there isn't
consensus in itself is quite important i
think
so um
i think mallory the the the you know the
other value of the igf is that it is
very different from from from the itf as
you've said is that
between 50 and 60 of participants in the
annual conference every year
are first-time participants
and i think that's a bit of a challenge
for the igf it's a strength because it's
clear it's a kind of a clearinghouse
it's a space where people that are
interested can come and network
refine their area of interest work out
where they should be more involved
but that also means it's not an expert
space it's not a space like the ietf
where your credentials
and you know it will shape what you are
allowed to do
and it makes it very broad based and
quite rich
but maybe not the ideal space to
negotiate you know concrete policy
recommendations but i think the igf can
more effectively
channel
this diverse
debate
the different perspectives even the ones
you know the areas where there's real
contestation
just by documenting that
and communicating that more effectively
to other decision making forums i think
it can enrich the policy making process
um
yeah if there are no questions telling
the queue last call
please just jump in um
if not we'll thank you andrea for coming
oh colin's here good go ahead colin
yeah
no question but uh just just to echo the
the thanks i i think it's really
important to uh
have this talk i think it's all
important to
for the the itf the irtf and the igf to
understand each other uh perhaps a bit
more and to to try and increase the
in the different groups
uh and i i'm not sure how we do that and
maybe we need a bit more of an education
in both directions so the the iatf
participants know how how to get
involved in practical terms uh as as
well as of them
you know being involved once they're
there so i agree it's it's important
that we start the conversation
thanks colin and and i i really think
the work you are doing with the protocol
and i think that's valuable work i think
that's a methodology
it's a methodology that's being tried
that can be applied
um
in other spaces other policy making
spaces other implementing spaces
um
and as i said you know i really like the
people that are working on environmental
impact assessments
um to also look at how you have done
that to see if there might be uh lessons
um to be learned and then maybe you know
one final you know value that the igf
can bring
is i mean i think you don't work with
governments you're very lucky probably
that you don't have to work with
governments as part of your day-to-day
uh debate but i think particularly when
it comes to
something such as consolidating respect
for for for human rights in the the
future development of the internet
um
uh i think liaison with governments can
actually be useful and i think that can
be something else the igf can provide
because it has a very different makeup
it's more formally constituted as
government civil society business
technical community and there is
actually quite quite extensive
participation from governments and and
at times i think particularly with human
rights
you do want to engage governments uh
because as mallory said right you know
as before before i even spoke there is
this existing framework of
accountability with governments as
duty-bearers
so that might be something else i think
that that could be of value
to you but
thanks very much for inviting me and
i hope to see you at the igf
thanks very much henriette um yeah i
hope we hope to see
more folks from the ietf there
um or the folks that that can go between
the two worlds more links are needed for
sure
um
all right so we just have one final
presentation um and we'll probably be
ending a little bit early depending on
how discussion goes um so thanks
everyone um who's who's still
sticking around for that um
i
can just very quickly put up the agenda
again just to um
remind us all where we've where we're
supposed to be going here um so yeah
we're on item number four
this is an update on a draft um that
actually juliana and i are both uh
co-authors on and juliana is here
so juliana at any point if you'd like to
um go off mike um interrupt me or um add
in your thoughts i would very seriously
welcome them i'm just going to switch
slides now slide decks rather to this so
so this will look familiar to some of
you um
but we haven't discussed this draft for
a while and the reason why i wanted to
discuss it again is because yeah there's
actually speaking of the igf there's an
opportunity to talk about this work at
the internet governance forum as part of
an art
installation actually um
sort of an archival process of
um looking at different ways um in which
um you know feminism and um this draft
in particular has carried on some of its
previous work and it is actually if
you've not um engaged with this draft
for a while
um it is actually very much about the
process and the journey and not so much
about the document itself but we're
hoping to change that by um sort of
refreshing efforts on it
the abstract so the goal of this
document is really to just try to
describe how internet standards and
protocols of course and their
implementations
would impact
diverse groups and communities from an
intersectional feminist perspective so
feminism
is one school of thought intersectional
feminism is a slightly different one
which in which
lots of different issues related to
identity um and oppression are
considered it isn't just about
gender or sexuality or things like that
um
so we sort of took the idea um from rfc
8280 that if you took the universal
declaration of human rights which is
itself sort of set of standards very
clearly laid out
and then started applying them to
you know standards body development what
might be
some of the takeaways from that so it's
similar to that
but instead we'd have to use a sort of
slightly different
framework
for the intersectional feminism side
so
um
we've attempted to do that um through
the history of this so uh one of the
first
um
steps in this journey for this working
group or this research group in
particular was um at iitf 104 we had
asked the association for progressive
communications another tie to today's um
session this is where andrea and i
um used to work and also on avery um the
feminist principles of the internet
seemed like a very good place to start
the discussion because like the
declaration of human rights it was very
clear and it had specific principles
laid out um and that itself is a whole
journey over many years
to develop those principles so that was
presented there was a bit of discussion
um and then juliana and and i put pen to
paper and actually
came up with a with a version so yeah
the presentation i actually ended up
delivering this presentation because
there was a conflict um with the
presenter
um from apc at the time but you know i
took the slide deck and and i i did my
best having at some point been involved
in the work um but yeah the feminist
principles the internet if you're not
familiar you could go to feminist
internet.net or org actually both work
um and you can see sort of how you know
there's they're grouped in terms of um
different
big picture ideas like access to the
internet there's issue of access but
there's also that issue of access to
information
reclaiming technology
and you'll see echoes not just from
human rights such as you know right to
information
but you also see
um holy feminist concepts that have been
integrated from a variety of different
perspectives
and how those um how feminism is really
expressed
around the world so presented that um
then the the sort of um initial version
kind of had two it was trying to do two
things at once um maybe not once was
trying to do two things in the same
draft the first was how to identify um
maybe at the user level
um
issues that might come up with respect
to internet protocols and how they're
designed and then the second thing it
did is it tried to look inward at how
gender
is a function of
the internet governance and the protocol
development that happens in the ietf
and so you can see that reflected here
this was juliana's presentation from the
ietf 105 meeting
where you know at the user level we're
trying to describe some of these
internet threats and how it might
actually you know be improved um by
changing the way some internet protocols
work and then on the other hand also
maybe using some of this data analysis
techniques right looking at actually the
ietf archive to analyze terminology
context discussion and how
gender roles played into the ways in
which decision making was done
um
that was the first version
and then um
you know we also then uh like i said
previously the the focus has been
then on how we actually go about
doing this so again another slide from
julio's presentation
um
you know trying to follow in the
footsteps um
of
the 8280 process you know
going point by point through each of
these uh
principles i think there were 13 or 17.
um
what you know what could you say about
each one what could you point by point
say about internet protocols in each of
those
principles
um and then also um the other process
point was just around um
how do we actually get feedback on this
so we didn't feel so the big focus then
i think on the on the following version
was
how do we get feedback from actual
feminist communities about what we're
writing and saying
because that's actually
the um
i think
an important element to consider is
uh and maybe we can over considered it
we we focused a lot on process on you
know sending this draft to mailing lists
where
um feminists and
technology are combined we did a few
workshops actually at various
conferences
um
julianna and i both just to just to talk
about it so that feminists out there
scholars out there knew that we were
writing it and we wanted um their
feedback so we've actually had a lot of
opportunity for feedback
um
and we focused a lot on process but but
then i think that the text isn't
finished and it's not quite um it's not
full yet there's no full full draft so i
wanted to then so this is the history so
far we we haven't yet got um an o2 in
the data tracker yet it's sitting in
github because the doc freeze we'll get
one up uh soon um we branched out
actually the
github and issue tracker from the irtf
hrpc group and it's now sort of on its
own for a little while we'll maybe merge
it back in as a separate or give control
to the
uh to the repo
to that group depending on how this
discussion in particular goes um
but we wanted to um update you on some
of the just small bits that have changed
since so we've got a bit of a reframe in
the introduction thanks to juliana um
we've had another contributor sophia
selly come in with some suggested tweaks
um and then the suggested changes which
have yet to
be done but wanted everyone's feedback
on it
based on other feedback that we've
gotten is actually
maybe we should not focus so much on the
feminist principles of the internet but
actually do a broader literature review
so this would include other um
sort of derivative works of the fpis it
would include entirely different bodies
of work on
feminism and technology
that are completely outside the fbi's
um
and then um the second proposed thing
would be then to
um maybe shift
the um
idea so so going back to
to where we're talking about version
zero zero right
rather than do both things at the same
time in fact use the document almost
like draft guidelines so skipping the
idea of doing a sort of 8280 similar
similar um format and actually skipping
into a guidelines like format so that
the audience is the ietf
sort of letting go of that you know
internal conversation
as much as possible and then just really
focusing as much as we can in the
substance of the draft on identifying
those user level impacts
i don't know if that shift made sense um
it's a bit subtle and um we're coming
towards the the end of this presentation
so i hope you're still following but but
that's i think where we want to go
um
in the in a new direction with this so
that might mean that we actually then
take the structure down
um
currently which breaks down each sort of
feminist principle
one by one actually erase that sort of
do a really nice sort of literature
review first
and then develop from there
um
so i'll i'll just show one example here
of something that i think is really
compelling maybe for the for the future
of the work which is things like this um
you could go to this is repository
anarchyserver.org
where
these collections have really tried to
almost be an archive of sort of the
history of feminism and technology
um and that is typically what we find
when um
these
sorts of bodies of work appear it is
it's very rare you know we're not we're
not looking to just create a wall of
text we're actually trying to contribute
to sort of a living breathing movement
um of of activists around the world
trying to solve these problems and this
process in the irtf in hrpc today is
actually part of that and that we want
more people
to be able to engage with these ideas
um
so yeah these are the proposed next
steps i think for the research and
juliana this is where i really want your
thoughts and we'll definitely
create some time after this meeting to
to talk just the two of us about this
but i'm thinking that you know we we
might reformat the entire draft to
reflect a different you know different
structure so rather than going principle
by principle we actually
now develop a research question a
clearer one which is how can
intersectional feminism guide the
development of internet standards
protocols and their implementations
we can change that but that would be
part of the first sort of
re reframe
and then based on that being our our
north star or our research question
actually then just do a literature
review um in service that question so we
can really focus on storytelling so some
of our sources are not going to be texts
but they might be media interviews
collections of such um and then to that
end we'll maybe need to create somewhere
somehow a repository of those things
given that they're not just going to be
citable texts they might be a little bit
less tangible
um than that and then i think to
continue
in that vein we might actually think
about either invited talks to this group
workshops in other
conference settings we could even do an
interim meeting or two
as part of hrpc
um and that sort of thing so and then
actually just maybe let it sit for a
while because i don't know actually what
the next step
would be without i think a lot more
convening and introspection about the
things that we would find
in the proposed steps
two or three
so now comes the time where i get to ask
you you know what you think of this
proposal um any thoughts any additions
you have about what i'm proposing um if
you are just simply interested in
following the work or at some point
getting involved please email us email
the
um juliana and i as authors or anyone
else who joins us support for this
document with the email here
and then also i'd love for folks to
either put in the chat or put yourself
in the queue as to whether or not you
think um the hrpc should adopt this
draft um as it has
i think
right now um not a whole lot of work
items
um and so i'd like to get
i'd like to get this group a little bit
more focused on
on something of interest i think this
should be it but that's just a proposal
so please let me know what you think
i'm watching the queue now
go ahead niels
um
i have like draft politics which i think
which which i given quite a lot of
thought and there's quite some work
there but i'm hesitant to restart work
on that before draft guidelines and
draft association
go out of the door so
so so that is a bit my thinking so first
get that those ones done
before the other stuff comes through
and i think
sorry there's the echo i think it wasn't
a
working group document or a research
group document is that right don't go
away just yet
oh
my
[Music]
not sure actually i think it
was because i worked on it extensively
with andrew sullivan who then had to
yeah it was adopted as a research group
document
yeah for sure
yeah actually quite uh for seven
versions already
yeah
yeah i recall and i feel like the last
time you talked about draft politics we
wanted to take it an entirely different
direction
which could be which could be fine we
have a habit of doing that in this
research group we start here and then
hard left and go
so that's fine um i mean that's kind of
what i'm proposing with draft feminism
as well so
um i don't think that they necessarily
have to be um exclusive like we could
still you know adopt the draft feminism
work um with um the aim of getting
also draft politics back on the docket
it's it's oh totally i think that the
approaches would be very different also
yeah for sure for sure for sure
i mean in a way they could be
complimentary because i feel like
with
draft politics you know you're aiming to
basically make a definitive statement
that you know technology's not neutral
uh you know with a lot of
citations and and deeper thought than
that but and i think that you know
obviously feminism or intersectional
feminism is an expression of politics
it's a very specific one um and so i
think rather than making a general
statement it actually kind of accepts
the premise that
um
technology is not neutral and it is
political and quality and then and how
right and how in particular
so i do see them as complimentary i
almost see them they don't necessarily
have to be linear but i think one sort
of assumes the premise of the other
other thoughts on just whether or not
because i don't think it makes sense to
adopt the draft if there's not um sort
of interest from the rest of the group
about that um
and if there isn't then certainly
juliana and i can think
about
how we can change or or or
how we can make progress on this draft
between now and 113 to convince you
otherwise
uh hi mallory uh i'm not sure that
adoption is necessarily the important
point take so obviously people you know
if there's interest in the group then
people
interested in the work then then people
can work on
on a document whether it's been adopted
by by the group or not um
and i think that the main thing i would
i would encourage you and the rest of
the members of the group to do is if
there are topics which are interesting
then to work on the work on the document
work work on getting this described and
building community uh and we we can
figure out whether the right thing to do
is for the group to adopt them or
publish them in some other way at a
later point so
doing interesting work is more important
than
you know the precise process details of
exactly what's adopted when web
and this looks like interesting it looks
highly relevant so
that's what i want to i want people to
get involved and i want
you know
that that's my main um
my main goal is to get to get to have
presented this today to in the hopes of
of getting more people to um
write to us or contribute to the github
um but just to say that you know if part
of our process and let me go back a
slide is to maybe you know focus a lot
more on the storytelling and continue to
um to think about process with respect
to other communities that are actually
active on this topic and connecting it
to them if we go to a workshop for
example like it could just be juliana
juliana and i or or some combination of
the authors or folks that have
contributed presenting this work
but i think it can also be um more
meaningful to folks to locate it within
the internet research task force
specifically hrpc not as necessarily
like an ownership or a stamp or a
sort of
i don't know authority um signal but
um i think it then helps to bring people
back into hrpc right where it's like
this isn't just our idea it's actually
supported by a sort of larger group that
thinks it's a good idea to keep
thinking and talking about this so
that's all at some point i i do think
that that can
really compel folks outside of this body
to understand um the importance of this
work
um
at um the ietf
yeah and i i would agree with that and
if that's a useful thing to do then by
all means you know to bring the work
into the into the group and adopt it it
seems clearly in in your chatter and and
it looks interesting for the
you know sort of
you know it seems there's people
interested in doing the work so
all right i'm gonna leave the queue open
for another beat or so
if anybody anybody'd like to jump in
also happy if you want to throw anything
in the chat if you don't want to get on
mic that's fine
all right
um it doesn't seem like anyone else has
anything to say about that so i think we
have gone through our agenda for the day
um
and so
there's not much there's not much left
um
other than to thank you all for coming
and apologies that we couldn't have
sasha speak today we're wishing her
well
um
and
yeah
thanks niels thanks colin thanks
henriette
and see you um
see you at 1 13
online or wherever it's supposed to be
it's true yeah we we use those extra 15
minutes so thanks again
bye everybody
you