okay we're going to use the meat echo uh
slide sharing tool so uh chairs which
means uh yours truly is going to be
advancing slides i will try to listen
carefully for for next slide and other q
and other cues
i think that's our cue to get started
corey
indeed
um
well
this is the last session of this current
ietf plenary meeting the um tsvwg
is meeting in this session
i'm gauri fergus i'm one of the
co-chairs here
david can you introduce yourself
i'm i'm david black uh another co-chair
other side of the atlantic from gory
and west
and uh i'm wes eddy and i'm on the same
side of the atlantic as david
okay so
in this second session next slide please
we are going to
cover a set of drafts on transport
topics
um if you haven't read the note well
at this point in the ietf it's a good
time to go and read it otherwise i
expect you're familiar with this slide
from other talks this week next side
here's our agenda for session two
and we're going to keep the agenda
review very short
and within it we're going to invite
michael to give a brief update of what
happened in rfc 496 all this
as it passed working group last call and
he's now uh waiting on the iesg
tele chat
then we will look at two sctp drafts
followed by
two drafts relating to udp options
a dccp draft and finally some uh
discussion of the diffser specs
this more or less fills our time but as
ever we're interested in receiving
questions and feedback on the mic
so if you have questions please come and
ask
yeah
please keep your your your question
short so that we can move up
yeah
one note for the ad holding tspwg down
to two hours this meeting week did not
work we needed we needed at least three
to four uh and so everybody everybody
gets squeezed uh also for the sharp-eyed
readers paying attention the there's an
ietf token missing from uh the name of
the very last draft from this slide
we're hoping people can figure out uh
where to follow this draft ietf tsvwg
dscp considerations
okay
yeah here's the organization we have a
note taker
thank you ever so much
um we have just one hour
we expect an interim to come in the next
ietf period
and so um please um help the chairs
prepare for that interim and look out
for it when it's announced
um
and we will discuss support for starting
an adoption
call of this ah
we've already done this um
this is an old slide that got
needs to be updated
and rst 496 or this is on the tele chat
nuts up um past working group last call
then received some external review as we
invited an external reviewer to look at
it it received review comments
there was these were late they were
substantial in that they were talking
about possible other use cases
it was discussed at the interim and it's
currently back with the working group
for a new revision so we'll talk about
that document here
hopefully we'll turn it around the
working group for a short period of time
and then we'll resubmit that to the iesg
for publication that would be our plan
next slide
um
we'll be done here so let's see if we
can get a
this is this is michael tuxen's slide um
on this little head michael
yeah this is about our rfc 4960 biz our
next slide
uh these are the
earlier versions next slide
this is what happened between the last
itf and this one we had two revision or
three revisions basically cleaning up
things and revision 15 went into last
call
and we got
we have the director directorate reviews
and we have ad reviews and
some of them
where the form uh the protocol
could change in a substantial way which
were rejected and some other changes
which were incorporated next slide
so the changes which have been
incorporated is it has been clarified
how to handle the case when an
advertised receiver window is smaller
than 1500 which is required
um
there was a discussion
with the security people
on the cookie so it's
made explicit that the content of the
state
cookie is implementation dependent that
the cookie is not encrypted or at least
that's the specification does not
require it to be encrypted
and that the key used to sign this stuff
should be changed frequently and
frequently is specified as hourly for
example
the limits for outstanding tsns and ssns
well we're using
should not and that is chain has been
changed to must not
um and one
other change was that um
during slow start the condition was only
increased
if the comb egg point has been moved
forward
um this has been this was changed
in
earlier versions of the specification
this applied to slow start and
congestion avoidance this was changed
for congestion's avoidance but not for
slow start this is now also changed for
slow start
and
the ayanna
section has been updated and
it was missing a policy for the ppids
all the other changes are improving
birding
the document i think is on the telechat
from mid-december and i'm expecting some
more comments
during the time the ads read it
thanks michael um if anybody has
questions please ask michael
and if there are
um any people who want to look at that
draft and spot something that needs to
be addressed or tweaked within those
changes then please let us know it's
still changeable
but um we we believe it's finished and
therefore it will be on the telechat
agenda in december
other than that on to michael to talk
about the nuts support document
yeah this document
came back to the working group and i
submitted version
23 just because
to keep it alive there are no changes
made right now we got um two reviews
from
ads
magnus and martin
and
there is an alternative
suggestion from claudio
so
next slide
basically the the major issues except
for wording
clarification
whatever is uh are listed here handing
off ip fragmentation at the net um i
don't know how to address that so
controlling net friendly behavior of an
endpoint so how does an endpoint know
that he's behind an ad and should
behave like this
this is addressable by looking for
example at the local addresses
multi-homing support of internal hosts
can be improved support of multiple
external addresses should be improved
um
remote addresses are not in the nut
binding table they were removed there to
make things simpler this was
it was
requested that this should be put back
at least in the case where restarts are
not disabled
um
it was the point about
the pack the the complexity of packet
processing at the middle box so does the
middle box need to understand chunks or
not
and basically the most uh
substantial in my view comment is that
the stock the current document changes
the definition of an association that
takes the verification tag into account
and has to deal with
the case that this is not supported by
the endpoints so basically these are the
major issues and if you go to the next
slide
then um
these are
potential ways forward
one is to improve the current method
which addresses issue two to five
um
that will make things more complex
and one of the issues also was that the
document is already
complex so another way to move forward
would be
just to use the fallback algorithm so
basically it's like
the endpoints have this understanding of
this
verification tag but it's important for
the association and if this is not
uh possible then they
the document already has a fallback
mechanism and we could just use that for
that mechanism that would address issue
two to seven
um which is basically never disable
restarts don't use verification tags
anymore just do
net as you would do it if you come from
udp or tcp land
and
um it reduces complexity it increases
the change of
chance of collisions
um
the third way would be switch to uh
claudia's draft and drop the current
working document or the fourth solution
would be just drop the work or not at
all
uh basically saying if we go for two
this is
very similar to udp or
udp or tcp so we don't need to specify
it the only way would be how do the
endpoints
behave that wouldn't be specified so
these are the four options
how to move forward and
that's what i need input on before
changing the document
so does anybody
currently um on this call wish to
make contributions
do you want to
comment on any of these methods or
or offer to review them
so i guess the reviews are out magnus
and martin did a very good job in
describing the issues so the issues are
clear
the question is how to address them
marcus
yes i i do think uh i have to think a
bit more about what's the implications
of these examples and but
i think we should be able to
i i am clouded probably work together
and try to see what we think jointly on
these issues from our perspective um but
we see that
but i will i will promise to think about
it and and come back i would say in
within a few weeks
i think that sounds an excellent title
and
get the three groups of people to talk
about it oh claudio do you want to say
something
can you hear me
okay go ahead speaker go ahead i don't
know i i really would like to help in
this area and
this option number three
is
we talked about is more or less a subset
of the the current draft it's not really
a revolution so if
we
could avoid dropping all the work done
i'm not and find a solution i am really
willing to help
yeah this has been the longest work item
we've had
and
that's not been through lack of interest
but maybe because we took on higher
priority things in between so it'd be
nice to see this finish
and i don't want to go for option four
but inevitably that will be the option
we arrive at if we don't get conclusion
quite soon
christian
christine you're in queue
yeah
this reminds me of something we did in a
quick format
and
one of the problem of not traversal is
that
once you start managing not also
actively
you expose yourself to a set of attacks
by forge ip addresses
that is it becomes easy to mount
the man on the side attack or something
like that
in which someone takes an otherwise
packet
changes the source ip address
and sends that to the other point
and that creates all kinds of
stat explosion issues or denial of
service issues etc and i don't see that
in the security consideration of your
draft
so i i think that you should at least
consider what's happening there
could you describe one
attack scenario in particular in an
email
uh you want me to send you an email with
the attack scenario
with one so who's the attacker who how
does he behave and what does he um
yeah i mean yeah okay
i can send you an email but the short
summary is that the attacker
the purpose of the attacker is to
disrupt your communication
so the attacker affects the not
rebinding
and by faking the not rebinding
they
convince the other point
that your ip address has changed
the the way the net binding changes is
done in a specific way here
well basically the change in that
binding to point to something where the
source is something that comes how can
you change it
by because
not rebinding
is something that you
that the other point detect by looking
at incoming packets
if you change incoming packets you
should you can
you can basically drive that detection
so the net
the net binding is not changed
dynamically that binding has not changed
i do not
but
spoof's packet has arrived at the other
points
can you please send an email
and i'll help you
i will send you email because
basically if you if you want to do that
that's the reason why something quick
in when you have a natural binding
you get a set of probes sends to the
previous and the old address
and all the kind of mechanism like that
so we we we
um verify path before we start using
them and this kind of stuff is an scp
i think probably we should take this as
an email uh thread on the list it sounds
like anything that probes into the
security aspects is likely to
help shed a little bit of light whether
we need new text or not i guess we'll
become quite clear as we discuss it
okay
thanks christian
really appreciate it
okay so the next person to talk will be
magnus
i'm talking about the dtls over sctp
document
and here's magnus
there
so
yes um so i i'm
here to talk about the details of stp
this work
uh
so um
yes we have done ericsson has done two
ipr disclosures related to this draft
so i want to remind you about the goal
here that the main goal here was really
to ensure that the dealers can protect
larger than 16
384 bytes large sctp messages
and that this work is done on s on 30
people's request
in this work we kind of
concluded on some of the right
requirements especially in relation to
the 3d vp use case about long linked
fctp associations where we have
association that could potentially for
weeks and months the need for and that
leads to periodic uh mutual
re-authentication is needed it requires
re-keying with
probably if you have monkey exchange to
ensure forward secrecy
to reduce the impact of any key reveal
and we also need to re-key stb auth
even if that algorithm is strong with
shock 256 and has a long
lifetime it's it's not that long so
probably um
and we also want to support both dtls
1.2 and 1.3 for having a upgrade path
ensuring that we actually
can move forward with details versions
so next slide
so uh
in those issues we hadn't discussed slot
meeting emeralds in the new draft we are
proposing
uh parallel dtls connections uh
and there were several issues that led
us here i mean detail is 1.3 lacs mutual
real authentication and has no forward
secrets
providing re-keying
and dts 1.2 renegotiation is unsecured
without neutral authentication and
therefore it's often disabled even if in
this use case it would be with mutual
authentication
and we also struggle with determining
when keys for detailers and ssv oauth
could be retired
so
preferably without requiring draining at
key updates
so
and that be draining i mean getting all
messages flushed out
basic footed connection to idle and then
re-key
so uh solution we propose here is to use
the dls connection spiral so when you
need to re-key or reauthenticate the
pair
you initiate a full detail as handshake
to enable this we use details connection
ids in all details records to multiplex
on
and because we're also saying we don't
need me to have more interview live at
any point a single byte connection id is
fully sufficient for this use case
and they can wrap and that will be many
many hours between
reducing the same connection id
representation
so uh
and
when you're gonna switch
you have to
when all else details record records
protected by the old key has been sent
and acknowledged in a non-renegable way
so you know that you've emptied out the
pipeway you know that all
all
stp packets related to these
sap messages are on on the receiver side
then you go forward and close the
details connection that has these keys
related to
and it becomes the sender's
responsibility for this
[Music]
and you do it in each direction
individually to this indication so when
both has closed you can remove the whole
details connection latest state
so that's basically how it works uh next
slide
so um the benefits you see it's they
have no dependency on detailers for
keying or re-authentication features
there's no functionality changes between
support and detail is 1.2 or 1.3
we think this is a good
property here
we currently see no limitations of the
number of reakings you can perform
which we've before had
we have neutral video authentications
and
and full different helm in exchange for
each
time you rekey
with forward secrecy and the key reveal
basically comes limit to a single key
period so if you're working every hour
the most data leak is one hour basically
and it becomes very hard to attack this
because
then you basically need to be able to
authenticate as the pair
so
yeah
and
yes
so this needs feedback
if there is one that finds any you
should really post to solutions so we
need more eyes reviewing to secure
description etc
uh the target here would be to go
towards working blast call after review
and draft updates and we are sleeping a
bit on the timelines here that we really
thought we could hold but that's with
from the struggle of finding a solution
i think
uh
so
i think that was all the slides
yes martin
martin
uh
maybe i'm confused but
if this is in fact where their ipr
issues can you clarify what those issues
are
i mean we are declared ipr
on that we
we have some
uh ipr that we think relates to this
draft
we have made licensing uh statements
about that we will license it
it
yes i understand from i mean parker's
comments is that certain open source
implementations but
perhaps struggle with
implementing this but yeah
um
and and the comment that i i mean one
thing i can see here if the problem is
that we replace 683 i mean we don't need
to obsolete we need a spec that is a
solution that we can give to provide to
3dpp so if if the problem is that the
obsolete the
so far non-claimed
is where there's no ipr claims
i mean that's fine for us it's from our
perspective yes we need a specification
that solves this
thanks
thank you um i think we will have to
revisit the ipr status
as we progress the work
but
let's take michael tucson's comment as
well michael
yeah it's a bit in the direction of what
martin said so
if you want to seek your http traffic
and
[Music]
limit yourself on what's been
standardized by the ietf then you have
three solutions one is ipsec based one
is tls base which was which is very old
i'm not aware of any deployment and
it was only done because it was needed
and there was no dtls and we couldn't
change http we couldn't change tls and
there's the dtls solution
http wise dtls wise it's implemented in
open source implementation so you can
use open source stacks for http for
dtls and networks
um and i'm concerned about replacing
this with something which is iprs
which we don't know yet and i mean
well we don't know yet what what the
iprs cover
and so right now this can't be
implemented in any open source
um
implementation that's what i'm concerned
about and what i'm not sure if if that's
the direction the working group wants to
go or
i mean
the goals are fine um and i think
the original spec needs an update but
i'm not sure if the working group wants
a version which is ipr protected
i think i would rather take that as a
real question to a future meeting when
we had time to reflect on what we have
and what people feel is the important
way to go forward
we don't have to obsolete the current
spec
and we could progress with this work as
an adopted item it already is adopted or
we could do something and
slightly different but we should tackle
this at a future date and finish this
spec i would encourage magnus to
continue working on it so we can see
what the final spec looks like
would that be okay likeness
yeah yes from my perspective it's it's
fine to let's continue review it etc and
see that it works but and as i said we
have no problem removing the obsolete
683 if if
if that makes the working group more
happy from
because i think there's there's a
significant difference in capabilities
here which
yeah that is certainly one of the things
that we should consider at the next
meeting uh whether we should remove the
obsolete line
uh whether people are happy with this
progress
and i'd also like you to try and talk
about um who might implement this specs
so we can have some experience but who
will review it and implement it as we
get the document finished
is that okay like this
yeah yes
cool i thought you would say that that's
good um at that case any other questions
or we'll move on to the next draft
thank you magnus
so the next topic i think on my list is
udp options
so the udp options what we talked about
to the previous interim
um joel need to go chase slides wait a
minute here
yeah that's fine
joe attended that and he has a slide
deck that reviews some of the key
outcomes of that meeting
and talks about the work that remains
for udp options so
i shall present on behalf of geotouch
that's great
so this is the view from joel tuch's
window the view from my window is
complete darkness
and
yeah we're in different places um
i'm going to present on behalf of joe so
next slide if we can
on here
there we go
so the first
the first slide um here is about an
update from the interim in september
um at which we discussed the ocs option
and
important changes that emerged were
discussed as options on this mailing
list previously
and finally appeared in the text of the
id
one of those is a fixed position for the
ocs option and it's allocated in a place
which is now
visible and easily passable
and the unsafe option was changed
and
really is an option that only exists
behind the frag options so um
this note is quite clear in the
text and please check if that was one of
the concerns that you raised and the
frag option
has been rewritten
re-scoped
and really given a major overhaul which
started at the interim in september
and more about the frag option changes
in the next slides next slide
so the frag option
is the first option after the ocs is
given a
fixed position after the fixed position
of the rcs
um this was largely in response to
comments originally coming from tom
herbert
um which was trying to look at how easy
this would be to offload in the future
so placing it in a fixed position
would likely make that an easier job to
solve
for offload
each fragment includes per fragment
options that are placed before the data
and these options relate to every
datagram in
every ip packet carrying a part of the
datagram that's an ip fragment
and they're things like the ocs which
are always present
there's also the possibility of having
per
reassembled datagram
options and they appear at the end of
the
reassembled datagram in other words in
the same place as any other udp options
data
so it reassembles into the legacy format
next slide
the
idea of an mrss was brought up at the
interim um
and talked about there the i this is a
maximum value
of
payload that can be present in a udp
datagram
it's a number that's just chosen it's
chosen to reflect something larger than
the typical mtu
and
various numbers were speculated about in
the interim a mailing list afterwards
and joe finally chose the value 3000 as
the default expectation that a receiver
could reassemble
a datagram which had a payload of 3 000
bytes
it's designed to be
big enough
so that um you can get a sizeable
benefit but not too large that it claims
lots of memory in the stack
when it's implemented
the
requirement for receivers was discussed
and the current id has a requirement for
all receivers to support reassembly of
two fragments the udp datagram
so a receiver that complies with the
internet draft will be able to take a
datagram
that has been fragmented into two parts
reassemble those into a hall
and this will give you
effectively the ability to traverse a
tunnel or to send um larger than 1500
bytes
the limit of two was added for
simplicity of implementation if you only
had two fragments it was argued that
maybe the receiver could be less
vulnerable to attacks the code would be
simpler and probably more efficient
the actual fragment size that will be
supported is a function of both the size
of
the underlying udp packets you can send
across the path
that's the
that's the ip packet size and the mrss
so if we go to the next slide
you'll see the various calculations
which
basically give mass to say that the
amount you can expect a receiver to
reassemble
without any information extra than the
spec would be for two fragments and the
two fragments
together must be less than 3 000 bytes
of reassembled payload
and of course all of this could be
changed if you negotiate the mrss option
so there's an mrss option as well which
lets you reassemble more fragments and
larger size and
these slides have really gone through
the
expectation of the default behavior of a
receiver that complies with the spec
so next slide i think just says what i
said
this is a a check on whether those
people who were involved in this
discussion or anyone else who wants to
know past comment has opinions about
this design choice of two fragments
and the three thousand bytes total
and otherwise apart from this joe
believes he's answered
all the issues which were previously
haunting the spec as we went through the
various revisions
um wanting lots of different um
topics to be addressed joe believes he's
now
only got consistency to address and is
now willing to take more comments um
from the list so
um
that's the last slide comments please
mike you should go first
um um i would say that there are at
least two more issues that uh
need to be resolved uh
one of them is that we don't have
um
a mechanism uh spelled out in the
specification for uh sending pad
padding packets that are uh
required for a
datagram
p
plm tud
uh it's not something that would require
another option it's uh merely
a means for the uh upper layer protocol
to uh be able to specify that uh
uh a uh packet is inflated
uh up to a certain length with uh zeros
on the end
a second uh major concern that i have is
per fragment options having them at all
i think that is a very significant and
unnecessary and undesirable
uh complication on the spec and i will
take
uh the details about this uh complaint
uh to the list
uh and leave my comments there thank you
yeah please do i i'm not joe um
but i would like to apply a one per
fragment option which is the ocs which
is probably needed for traversal of a
nut
all right
yeah right thanks
so so we should we should take that to
the list i've made enough of those two
issues and on to david please
i'm simply uh want to speak up to
support um the uh conclusion on udp mrss
i think two fragments is a good is a
good design choice because uh it cleanly
addresses the tunnel forces from uh uh
fragmentation case which is one of the
things that this draft's about to solve
okay thanks david
i'm wait um one of the things i was
encouraging with my chair cut on
was really for anybody who expects to
use this please come along and tell us
either tell the chairs or speak up on
the list and say what it is you're
expecting from this draft
and
use cases are really good for testing
whether we've got all the features we
have in the right places
so the next set of slides will be
presented by
tom who's responsible for this little
bit of work go ahead tom
nice try gary you're you're involved too
uh hi i'm i'm tom jones um this is our
document that describes uh dplp m2d for
udp options or i think udpodplpmtud
as we were talking about in transport
earlier
um it's a small document that
adds the necessary features for udp
options um
intended to be an example for how to
write small documents like this
if you have more questions you can ask
magnus he asked for the document
it does a couple of very simple things
it adds cdp options the ability to do
the required features for you for dplp
m2d so you can do confirmation of
connectivity
um we can send probes we can validate
the path and we can do um ptp handling
and it's nice and short it's seven pages
um
since the the last revision the document
was um adopted there are some temporal
ordering issues between the adoption and
the
zero zero because i was on holiday
um and so if i have the next slide
um and so that gives us the the next
steps so we missed one which was text on
generating padding so i think we still
have text saying you can use knocks
and this is
um forbidden by udp options this is fine
because you can create padding by adding
zero bytes to the end of the packet and
we're actually happy with this method
uh we need to do an editorial pass gory
claims there's lots of typos um so i'm
waiting for a pull request but we need
to go through and be very thorough on
this
um we need text now to explain how dplp
m2d works with fragments now that
fragments are starting to settle down
and
because we're getting happier with the
design and then we'd really like to get
more comments from the working group
because it's the way to move the
document we expect this to complete
alongside udp options um and i think
once we've done the the first couple of
things listed here the document will
mostly be a maintenance mode until
um udp options is is is ready in the
working group and we'll just have to
track what joe changes as joe changes
things so that we stay in sync
and that's all
so i'm
willing to give up time for questions on
this because it's been adopted
um relatively recently and we'd like to
ensure that it can also be working group
last cold soon so that it and coincides
with the publication of udp options does
anybody have any
questions about the presentation by tom
i would simply comment that the
underlying mechanism here received quite
a bit of review when it was part of the
original uh dplp mtud so this is not new
material and the algorithm is understood
and stable
yeah and this draft although it's kind
of only just become a working group item
has been around the working group and
presented a number of times in the past
so there have not been major changes in
between these two it's just that we've
now reached the stage of this document
needing review from people
well um when do you think we can make a
new copy tom
in this next week
yeah yeah
in the next month we can have another
copy it's not it's not a problem there's
a small amount of things to do so it
should be quite straightforward
okay
does anybody wish to add
any comment or questions on this before
we close
then i'll say thank you ever so much for
tom coming to speak on our joint draft
right um
sorry for the speed at which we're going
through this meeting but um it's good
that we're keeping to time and the next
talk will be by mike but no
marcus on mpdccp so um without any more
introduction would you like to update us
on version two of your
document
yeah hello everyone for sure i'm happy
to update you on the progress we made on
mpdcp maybe starting with some general
updates so we received a working group
adoption in august this year
so quite recently we are focusing now on
maturity towards working group last call
ideally this is alive with the timeline
in 3gp release 18 because there it is
already discussed as an eight as part of
an anticlockwise and enhancement and the
discussion is currently in the
phase uh
that
they have i think a december to conclude
if this goes for study item
approval
um
we also interfaced uh where we now start
discussions with with industry with
vendors um to go for drawing testbed and
implementation activities
that's going on and we have some quite
interesting discussions around that so i
will you keep posted on that
and we also in the face of
next open source version we still plan
to publish
end of this year
aligned with the latest draft updates
and also provide a much better
performance
the draft development is ongoing at
github with currently eight contributors
we have an established process uh with
issue tracker and pull request uh used
for reviews and and updates next slide
please marcus what what's the timing you
need on this uh to align with 3gpp
release 18.
i think it would be good to
have maybe you're working through plus
call then end of next year maybe that
fits ideally
but that requires that it becomes a
study item approval for sure so that is
the decision which will be made end of
this year
in 3gbp
um
yeah two weeks ago we published
the first version of the
working group adoption in that
we
updated multiple things
though
we defined a reliable exchange of
multi-path options for those options
where it is needed
we have a consistent description of
multi-part reordering so we used uh or
we described multi-parts we were
reordering issues as part of the trough
we use diff we use different terms for
describing reordering reordering
reassembly and so on so they made all of
this consistent
then
we added a very important
section from our review on fallback
strategies so what is going to happen if
a multi-path
cannot be established
so for example then we it could be
trigger to fall back to single path dccp
we introduced the number of authors to
be compliant with the rfc editor style
guide
and we made some minor editorial things
if you're interested you can look into
in the
latest version we published this week uh
we made
a lot of progress on describing a new
hand checking procedure
along with authentication capabilities
um to
guarantee a safe establishment of
subsequent flows i will come to this in
the next slide
also some major work we did on defining
or enhancing the multi-path prior option
for fine granular steering of past
priorities backup and disable part that
goes far beyond the mp prior definition
from mptcp
last but not least we improved
the operational section of the draft
next slide please
yeah now coming to an um interesting
topic which we which i also started to
discuss on the mailing list i shared the
link in the chat now
let me explain how
we defined so far the hand checking
procedure and how we improved it
uh so on the left you see the initial
approach we had in the draft
it's a three-way approach we call it
because first of all we establish
the multipath connection over one link
that you see
from a1 to b1 it's a three by hand track
as i indicated already
in that one we negotiate the multi-pass
capabilities we negotiate key material
for later
uh a subsequent flow establishment
and so on
um
so after the multi-part connection
is established so the three-way
handshake was successful it is safe to
join subsequent flows the issues what
you can see here is the mp join
which is sent from a2 to b1
arrives too early
at the host b and overtakes the final
bccp
acknowledgement from the initial flow
then there's some confusion because the
multi-pass connection
has not been successfully established
the mp joint tries to
join something which is not available
and
in our open source implementation we
then react with the dccp reset on that
flow which means the subsequent flow
cannot be established
that is not what we want
that's why we drive to improve this
in the draft as well as in the open
source implementation we are currently
working now on implementing what we
propose on the right side and what is
already part of the draft so
we extended the three-way handshake by
an additional acknowledgement we
sent from the host b to the host a
with that we know
that the multipath connection has been
initiated successfully and it's safe
then to start the joint procedure
from a2 to b1
uh it's a it's a simple solution it
works we could be happy with that
however we wonder if this can be
optimized because it adds additional
delay and also it has a high dependency
that all the four messages of the
initial flow will arrive
that's why
we come to some proposals on the next
slide
starting again on the left
and what we could do to optimize this we
could again go to a three-way approach
as it was before
however
we do not check
when we send the mp join and the amp
transfer arrives at host b
if the multipath connection is already
established we do it at a later point
with the final dccp economic
acknowledgement of the join process that
gives us more time
or that gives the whole establishment
process more time that the initial flow
is successfully established however
that only works
if there is
not a too big latency difference between
both paths
otherwise we run into the same issue
as i introduced
um in the previous slide
that's why we also do not prefer this
however it's a valid solution and we are
happy to discover this with you
uh the preferred solution or the optimal
solution bc is on the right
uh because that reduce the latency of
the establishment process or the whole
time of the establishment process and it
uses the dependency on the initial flow
so what we propose is more or less to go
for a
two-way a reliable two-way handshake
and what we also do in implementation is
we already create all the necessary
multi-parts structures in the network
stack after the first dccp request
arrives at host b
um
then we reply to this
from host b2 to host a
we have ensured that with this
these two messages all the key material
is exchanged which is required
um to derive the tokens and hmax
for a subsequent flow establishment
that means we are not reliant
anymore on the final dccp
acknowledgement of the initial flow so
this one can even fail and it has no
impact because
the mp joint process
can
a subsequent flow and can even establish
the whole multi-part connection
so that is a
big change
in the
design principle of the of the hand
checking procedure
and
we want to put the question here if this
is a good proposal does it make sense
or do we raise raise issues
like
providing a tech surface for daniel of
service attacks because we create
multi-pass structures already in the
beginning
or
or do we raise security
issues with that
um
yeah that is the point i would like to
discuss today with you uh coming with
that to the last slide
so your review is very very much
appreciated and it would really help us
to move forward
so
yeah with that
i am finished for today and happy now to
get your feedback
thank you for the
update that was very helpful
when do you think
you would have
more information about the options and
the design considerations that you just
spoke about i'm wondering whether a
another meeting focused on
specific points would actually be a
better focus for bringing in other
people into discussing this do you think
that you might have
information about that in the near term
so it depends on on what you expect so
if it is just a presentation to make a
deep dive into the issues then i think
we can go quickly for that
if you expect to have those different
designs implemented somewhere and then
it maybe takes a longer time
or it will not be possible at all
because we do not plan to to implement
them before we have the discussion with
with the itf community
i mean i
i i don't expect you to implement all
the options and then come back and tell
us which one was the most painful
and that's clearly not the right way and
so you might need to take a little bit
of decision yourself about which way you
think might work and see if that is
actually feasible to implement
and then at that point it might be great
to bring in more people and go slowly
through what you think might be the
security questions and the protocol
questions
and we could do that in a interim
meeting perhaps dedicated to this
yeah um but i would prefer and fully
support to go for interim
maybe we can combine it with one of the
other topics like http but up to you
what you think is best or having a
separate interim uh yeah happy to
support this and i think we can go
quickly for that
in the meantime we have a question from
chang
kanji
uh yes checking here um i don't have
solution uh comments for your
your uh strategy here but what i know is
currently in essay 2 3gpp working group
it's talking about atss
for phase 3 for release 18.
so it discussed the
possibility to provide more than two
passes actually like uh two three gtp
passes or two non-switch differences
so here you are talking about only two
passes here so have you ever thought
about like three or more okay that that
is a yeah uh thank you for this question
i'm fully aware of this discussion in
3gpp and i think it's a misunderstanding
when i
presented today the figures of the
handshaking process that are very
generic figures that does not mean that
we are limited to two flows um
it's the opposite uh so we support an
unlimited number of
okay thank flows
thank you right okay um we will talk
more about this on the mailing list
and if a meeting is what's required to
facilitate something we will arrange an
interim meeting for this
and the next one will be greg who um
has already tried once to be on the
agenda and now gets the chance for the
last five minutes of this particular
meeting so greg you have only five
minutes and
do something useful please to tell us
about enqueue
all right um
i'll skip past the first few slides
which are just status um
in fact that one i um is a list of
changes in draft 08 that i sent to the
mailing list so that's already been
shared
i'd like to spend a little bit of time
on this one
so this is a current discussion on the
mailing list about
nqb sender requirements and guidance on
sender rates
the top paragraph in yellow um describes
in informative language what an nqb flow
is and it describes it as sending at
most a few well-spaced packets per rtt
i'm going to give some examples of in
today's network
no more than one relatively large packet
every 10 milliseconds
roughly a megabit per second
the next paragraph then in green
points out that
um just marking your packets as nqb
doesn't get you off the hook in terms of
implementing
all of the
expected features to make your
application safe on the internet
including
some sort of congestion control or
congestion response
um and uh
or circuit breaker um functionalities
that sort of thing
um and then the last paragraph is where
um it provides a specific recommendation
around not marking traffic as nqb
based on
the uh
the sending rate and and the current
text in that kind of blue green uh color
if the traffic exceeds more than a few
packets per rtt or exceeds approximately
one megabit per second on an
instantaneous inner packet basis
um the application should not mark its
traffic
and the next slide then we can go to
that
uh
there's was some discussion on the
mailing list around um that one megabit
per second number in the requirement
statement
and will that stand the test of time um
maybe it would be better to base that on
something that um that evolves over time
and suggestion was
something like 10
of the global average access link
capacity at the time
and then
and then adding an example
at the time of writing
what that might be and a link to
where those numbers came from
and then at the end it does the math for
you uh and it says a very typical server
application
that implies no more than 6.3 megabits
per second at an instantaneous rate
and for a typical client application no
more than 1.3 megabits
and here the
um
because interpretation of a typical
server is
effectively a server or an application
that is
it's not aware whether it's sending
traffic over a mobile access network or
a fixed access network
um and so it's the lower of the two um
but it's pretty certain it's not sending
traffic in the upstream direction on an
access network it's almost really
sending in the downstream direction and
then for the client it takes the uh
the view that it's um almost certainly
sending traffic in the upstream
direction on an access network
and uh but again may not know whether
it's mobile or effect so it takes the
lower of the two
questions working group on that um
are we happy with this with scaling the
recommendation over time based on
statistics that are available um at the
time
um we'll need to take that to the list
um i'm concerned that you're using
average across a distribution that's
non-uniform but this is not the place to
split uh to go to dive into the the
statistics
yeah okay um
uh and then moving on to the next slide
then just quickly um
i think that's been discussed on the
mailing list actually just maybe the
following slide
um
a question from my anna um
what should these nq these dsps be
labeled in the iana registry um should
they both be called non-cue building i
mean we should label them separately
again we can discuss that on the mailing
list and the last slide
yeah we need to fix this
last i once once these edits have been
made and we've settled on those um i'm
hoping we can go to working group last
call and i want to get a sense from the
chairs as to
if that would be
advisable to try to start a working
group last call
in the interim before the next idea
i think it's worth drink trying to work
in robust course shortly after the first
the year the other card i'd make on this
is that your your light blue should text
about should not use for high bandwidth
um
i need to redirect in detail um there's
going to need to be some teeth behind
that something that if the sender does
that um the network that the network is
entitled to uh to to evict the track
evict that flow of mqb
yeah
okay fair enough
i can add that to the list
i see a poll has been started
so my fault i started the poll then i
realized you can't press the mic button
where you press the pull
but at least um
i'd be interested in getting people to
read this
recent version of the spec or the
current version of the spec and see how
near we are um i can't really answer
whether we need
more time or not um
please look at it on the list and tell
us your comments
thank you greg and david
wears do we have anything else that we
should say
i
i have one more presentation cued from
anna castura and i think anna's going to
have been caught by the time
so um we'll take that next meeting
and anything else from my co-chairs as
we finish
a good move here as that
that that that needs some that needs
some discussion about content and
i mean we we know something in the space
is useful how we're going to figure out
exactly what
that's fine and i i pled to place um a
standing offer to anna to present more
data if she has any to the next meeting
and
we will try and clarify what goes in
that document
any of the final comments perhaps from
where's on session one if you're still
there with
uh i don't have anything myself
excellent
martin you should take note of the
multi-path dccp
relationship to 3gpp that will
eventually surface in liaison
discussions
yeah roger that like i mean i think if
if um
if it's not picked up a study i might i
think we need to reevaluate
what we're doing
for sure
sure
and
my final thing is i expect there to be
an interim before the next meeting
so please keep a note out for that if
you have things that you think should
appear on the agenda of that interim
please contact the chairs
otherwise we will hope to see you at the
interim or in person perhaps at the next
ietf meeting
that's all for today
see you in the
in the lobby outside if you wish to join
us there and gather
thank you very much everybody
see you all next time