while we're waiting um would anyone
like to volunteer to be a jabber scribe
and or would anyone like to volunteer to
help robin with the note-taking today
robin will be presenting for
15 minutes
but beyond that uh whoever would like to
dive in um they'll be very welcome see
watson's volunteered thank you watson
for jabba's scribe um
yeah if we could get some d2 to assist
with the note taking that would be very
welcome too
any takers we'll need a note taker to
make sure that uh
we don't miss the notes from the q log
bit um i might have to start asking
people by name
if we don't have any takers
jonathan thank you very much you were
the person i had in mind to to ask so
i'm glad you did it first
uh right then uh let's get started with
the session um hello everybody um this
is the quick working group session if
this is not the session you intended to
join please leave now um
i'm lucas i'm one of the co-chairs matt
who's just putting his video on is is my
fellow co-chair this is the first
session i believe that uh lars hasn't
shared a quick
session so um it's it's breaking new
ground um i'm just trying to see as lars
even in the attendees list maybe yes he
is hello lars i thought you might have
escaped permanently but it seems
you did want to come back um so this is
a quick working group session like i
said uh we we wanted to go through the
usual notewell and and etc which i'll
come on to next but also give a little
bit of an update from the chairs about
you know what has the working group been
up to since the last meeting and uh
maybe
the direction of the group so just to
you know we we've delivered rfc 9000 and
people are a bit fragmented across
different drafts we've lost a little bit
of focus but the working group is still
active so we just wanted to keep people
up to date
um so the first order of business here
is the notewell uh we're halfway through
the week now you should be familiar with
this but if you're not um please go
online and look this up and follow the
links and read things
this covers the itf policies that cover
topics such as patents or code of
conduct and and how you participate in
the ietf so
this is important for understanding your
contributions to this working group and
the ietf in general so please please do
go and attend that
we've also
wanted to give some special attention to
the itf code of conduct this time around
um so the you know the
rc7154 lays out some of the expectations
for participants in the itf um you know
we are
just a diverse set of people from
different parts of the world different
experiences and and different viewpoints
and that's good and we should celebrate
that um but that we you know should have
in personal discussions and try to be
respectful of each other i'd like to say
that the quick working group has got a
good uh track record of being able to
function and have constructive
discussions on things so
it doesn't hurt to remind ourselves that
we should keep that up
and i look forward to a healthy
discussion during this session
in terms of administrative year for this
meeting we've got the notetakers thank
you robin and jonathan
the blue sheets are automatically taken
care of now by meet echo so that saves a
chore
the chat will be by meet echo or java
all integrated again no problem
for av if you would like to present and
or
participate in the queue to
ask questions or clarifying questions or
make comments um
we we're using the echo people should be
familiar with that by this point in the
week but if you're not there's several
icons in the top left hand
corner of the screen um you have the
raised hand
to get in the queue um when it's open
uh we will be closing the queue at some
points depending on how we manage time
we can also unmute your microphone or
your video
for presenters we're going to go with
the screen share tool built into meet
echo today so uh when is this a lot you
can click the page icon to request to
share slides
and it'll be done by me echo which is a
little bit more friendly to people's
streaming bandwidth um
or if you really need to use share
screen or we can have the chairs share
this the slides for you um and the
chairs will be running the cube and so
my glamorous assistant matt will be
helping me on that front
um
but down to the order of business today
just a recap of the agenda
uh like i said we've got some
chair updates after this administrator
section um
we have some working group items on the
agenda so we've got the act frequency
draft then we have q log then version
negotiation
followed by quick ld
and then we're on to like a new work
section
so we're going to focus here on uh
multipath extension uh mary will be
presenting on behalf of a few folks that
have been working on that
and had a side meeting a couple of weeks
ago
and that'll be the bulk of our time in
that section and then and as the time
permits um we'll look at some some of
the things here like receive time stamps
uh
quick v next whatever that might be or
the zero rtt bdp um so before we we get
started on the agenda in earnest is
there any bashing that anyone would like
to do
i don't see anyone in the queue or any
comments
so
okay um we'll just proceed
uh
so i'll take take some some spotlight
for the chairs here um some updates
since the last meeting in terms of the
work that this group has adopted and is
trying to to complete um
hb 3 and q pack in case anyone's
wondering they're still in the rfc
editor queue we're waiting
um the work to happen in the http core
drafts
which effectively a dependency for for
those two in a way
um
and uh they're making progress they're
doing okay there's a whole cluster um if
you're interested you can go and look at
but we're effectively waiting they've
been there a long time um if you go look
they were submitted around february i
believe so um
we
we're getting there slowly uh
in case people aren't too familiar with
the deployment strategy um if you recall
a few months ago um as a group we we
decided that
people now that rsc 9000 was out which
is a quick version one um that the http
alpn which is the labeled h3 um was
allowed to
be deployed on the internet and i
believe we've seen some
decent amount of um
live deployments and interoperability on
the public internet which is great so um
i don't see those the specs um being in
the rsc editor queue is
preventing progress here um
if anyone
was um
watching the mailing list
so my issues have been identified um in
the drafts while those things have been
in the queue um they're kind of minor
things um maybe edge cases but some of
the resolutions were
to normative text so a consensus call is
still live i believe i need to check my
dates um just on those uh for the
working group uh at the request of our
ad to make sure that um the proposals
there that we're all happy with
incorporating as as part of the auth 48
changes that the editors will do so we
we've seen a lot of good feedback on
that if you haven't seen them please do
check them out and let us know
otherwise if we don't hear pushback
we'll we'll direct people
to to incorporate the changes as and
when needed um
the op strats the applicability and
manageability or an ad review um so
thank you for everyone for the the
feedback during the various rounds of
working group last call and the editors
for um
working with people on that to get it
done
that's appreciated
the datagram draft also passed working
group last call and that's also an ad
review
and the grease bit working group last
call is
completed we had some feedback um
there's a few minor changes there so
we're just waiting a new draft um and
then we'll do our shepherd write up and
pass that on to the ad so
uh
thank you and mine's just posted in the
chat hill or having a date inbound
brilliant um
[Music]
some related work uh sometimes it's it's
easy to assume that the work that
relates to crick all happens here and
that's not true now that we are an rfc
people are excited and they want to use
this document all you know to be honest
they've been excited for a long time so
uh one of the things that did come to
our attention around about in the itf
was the dns over quick
specification uh went to working group
last call in for deprived and uh i think
a few of us from this working group
posted some comments um that have been
uh
incorporated um or proposals for
addressing those comments have been
incorporated
so
that's good
at the itf we have the mask working
group who met on monday in the web trans
working group and on tuesday those
things are related
there was a side meeting for media over
quick which is non-working group
that was formed i see in the chat that i
have the dates wrong so i apologize for
that we had a meeting yesterday um
jonathan just jumped in the queue and
then left so i think he was trying to
draw my attention to that um i hope i've
addressed the points um this uh all of
the side meetings uh in the ietf
sidebeings calendar so uh please check
that for the actual correct date and
time and
uh actual joining instructions so
there'll be a link to
it was zoomed yesterday
so
that isn't you know necessarily um
strictly anything on quick we're still
trying to figure out things in that
group that may be you know what are the
requirements for using quick versus
modifying quick and trying to understand
if any work needs to come back here or
not so anyone interested in that
there's some healthy discussion there
it's kind of interesting
oh and robin also mentioned uh there's a
aside meeting today um about openssl and
it's quick
support um for uh doing stuff so um if
if anyone's interested in that again
check out the the side meeting uh
calendar because
all the details will be there um
and then talk about new work uh just to
remind people uh this shouldn't be new
information but when it comes to
adopting new work items um we have a
charter that's up on the data tracker um
and just to kind of summarize that the
working group is the focal point for any
quick related work in the itf um
the focus areas are kind of three of the
maintenance and evolution of the quick
specs as and when we need to to do
things that
you know
improve upon or fix or
iterate upon drafts that have been
adopted items and and been published uh
so that should be fairly obvious um
other things about supporting the
deployability which relates to drafts
like
ops strats or queue log or low balances
those level of things so we can support
non-protocol specific work items too if
they make sense for us to do things
and then new extensions to quick so
datagram's an example of an extension
and
we've got another one coming up later in
this session um
but as i mentioned dns of a quick is an
example of how an application protocol
could use quick and that work was done
outside our working group um it could be
done here if we really need it if that
suitable home couldn't be found but i
would hope that most most of the
discussion in such specifications
relates to the application protocol
and that we have an awareness of the
work that's happening there so we can on
you know people from this working group
can go and
review with a with their quick head on
and maybe give some feedback about um
those aspects of things
and then defining new congestion
controls is outscope so
please don't come with those things
because we'll have to point you
somewhere else uh but specifically to
this session um and
uh yeah we we're going to talk about
multipath quick extensions from the
background here uh without um trying to
preempt too much of what mirror talk
about later is that we had a interim
focused on multi-path like a year ago um
which
you know
multipath was in scope for the initial
charter that this working group had and
we d scoped it um into into the current
form that we have today um and there was
a lot of i think a lot of ideas around
what multipath could be what different
problems they were trying to solve um
and so we had that meeting last year
which i think
helped but didn't get us into the right
position and we still had a lot of work
on z has gone on we we've we've cleared
things from our
our agenda and we have some more time
but we also have a clear idea of the
problems um and people have come
together for a more unified proposal so
um
we'll see how the working group
um think on that and we'll be taking
uh the chairs will be taking an
assessment about whether we think that
work is is worth adopting in its current
form um so i want to
ask people to keep that in mind through
the presentation um because that's a
question we'll be asking at the end of
it
so that's the end of of the quick
chairs session um
next step on the agenda
is
ack frequency um so i penciled in jonah
to present yeah but i guess maybe it
might be ian too um which one of you is
it
let me pull up this no
let me stop sharing my slides
ian are you
you willing and able to present
no no response
all right
okay should we should we skip to another
session and maybe come back to that one
uh let's do that i'll chat with you in
the back um but
if he's not able to run obviously i'm
happy to do it
yeah just a little bit noisy for me oh
there he
here he is uh
i'm sorry about that i did my better
lunch um
uh let me get my headphones on
would you like us to drive the slides
ian or you find to do that yourself yeah
i can actually yeah yeah let me just
i don't know if you're experiencing echo
but usually you do
um
cool
i just asked this year so okay great
um
there we go cool um so uh
yeah we're we're kind of hoping to wrap
up the act frequency draft in a
relatively near future there's one
fairly substantial design issue that's
outstanding that i'm going to highlight
um in these slides but uh first i'm
going to start with kind of an overview
of where
the frame is at and um
you know
and talk through that and if there are
any questions obviously feel free to
interject
um so here's the current frame format um
obviously this a type there's a sequence
number so if you receive them out of
order
this is allowed still to retransmit any
frame you would like verbatim
um is possible that a
sender that does this
uh could receive a frequency that
arrives out of order so that fixes that
problem
the accolading threshold of course is
the number of packets that um
technically it's not the number the
maximum number of active listing packets
that the recipient of this frame can
receive prior or before sending an
acknowledgement
um
so
the the key point is that that makes
zero a valid
um
valid value and such so um just make
sure that you you kind of get the
wording on that correctly um and it's
also the wording's been tweaked around a
little bit
um
relatively recently uh request max sac
delay
um so that's the value you'd like the
peer to delay an acknowled an immediate
acknowledgement for sorry delay an
acknowledgement for upon and perceiving
an app listening packet
um immediate acknowledgements are
totally different
uh
uh yes sorry i need to do something
later thanks sir sir um
the uh the ignorancy field um is
ignoring congestion experience um
this was added both as a result of
conversations about how one might use
ecn in different or ecn marking in
different contexts besides
the the two that are current kind of
currently kind of tcp style and class
and qcn
and then the
ignore order is basically the same
the same concept in both cases you're
you're kind of ignoring a signal that
may or may not be indicative of
congestion
um for a longer period of time in order
to you can have your video or multiple
uh packets
um
so uh
we did add some caveats uh there about
like the safety of these and how you
should really be using these and and um
those are in the draft now
so
uh next slides
um so
the the design issue that came up
recently was the latency detect packet
loss um so kazuo pointed this out and
um this is somewhat related to a
previous issue i felt but i think kazoo
is both freezing and and state problem
statement were much better than mine was
um
and so the issue is that one act is sent
immediately today just like with p1
um but after that the next act will not
be sent uh until the eliciting threshold
of the act layer hit
and there's a lot of situations where
that might uh slow down the packet
threshold
uh lost detection um so
the kind of example is you have a drop
you send an immediate act
um and then you don't send another act
for say 10 or 20 packets
um it's it's pretty easy to hit a
situation where you know if you send
another act
you know two packets later you could
have immediately declared a loss and
moved on but instead you're waiting say
like a quarter rtt
um rtt for the the time threshold to hit
um
in data centers this kind of could be
worse unfortunately because data centers
tend to have alarm granularities which
are not amazing
and commonly the
um the thresholds we're talking about
according to t and eight that are tv are
literally unachievable in like a micro
center
i'm sorry a micro
micro second scale data center
networking environment so this this
probably is actually a worse problem in
a data center than the public internet
but anyway that's kind of the outline
um of the problem and the most important
conclusion is that loss detection
latency has the potential to be worse
than in quick v1 um
so the the proposal here is to
communicate the reordering threshold to
the receiver instead of this ignore
order
that we we have right now
and the algorithm comes down to that the
receiver needs to send an immediate
acknowledgement
uh whenever they're missing packets um
somewhere between the
largest acknowledged value that has been
sent in a previous acknowledgement
mastery ordering threshold and the
largest acknowledged in the
that you know currently has been
received at this moment
um from a more recently received packet
um minus the reordering threshold
um so that guarantees that if they're
basically any packet in that range that
is missing
um assuming that the peer is correctly
communicated their reiterating threshold
to you um that means that they can
immediately declare a loss the moment
they receive your
immediate acknowledgement
um so the result is that it reduces the
number of acts
when people packets are received out of
order when compared to quickv1
uh while also improving uh the loss
detection latency versus quick v1
because there's a number of cases now
before i put feet one because you act
every other packet it was possible they
had a circumstance where
um you you
didn't receive that final packet
threshold act say because the
um you know it was
two packets later not three or you know
you kind of an off by one error um and
it would increase loss detection latency
or slightly uh versus this approach
um so ideally this gives you the best of
both worlds um the major
you know the major negative is it
definitely increases implementation cost
by a slight margin uh because you have
to implement this this algorithm right
here
um
so yeah
so that's
that's the item to discuss um
do people have thoughts this pr has been
kind of out there for a while and as
there's the issue
um
yeah christian christian please go
oh i can't hear you christian
um i still cannot
hear you
should we skip can you hear me now
can you can you hear me now yeah okay
that's a
weirdness with the microphone too many
buttons
um
yeah i'm not sure i mean you're
proposing to add a weirdo in threshold
based on packet counts
and
i am not sure that's the right tool the
the reason i say that is that we have
tried a lot of that
we are doing happens a lot in some kind
of multiplexing scenarios
especially if the network is doing equal
cost multiplexing
equal cost load balancing
and
and in that case it seems much more
efficient to use delays than using
packet counts
so there is that
i would agree there are circumstances
where this is
not actually a helpful mechanism um and
so we did maintain the existing kind of
ignore order functionality
if you send a reordering threshold of
zero basically means the existing order
functionality um
yeah i think it it really depends on the
circumstance
um so this i guess is really about
giving the sender
which as described in
the recovery draft the last detection
congestion total draft
um there there are two essential
mechanisms for declaring loss there
right one is reiterating threshold
impact accounts and one is in time and
so this is giving the sender the
maximum number of tools to express
um sort of those two
mechanisms between the the ipad and the
rendering threshold but but you're right
that this may not always be applicable
well no i i think that you're you you're
using your you're thinking of the act
delay
but the act delay as as two functions
there
one of the aggregate function is the
passing of x
as i said i don't want to receive ads
more than 10 milliseconds
apart if everything is working fine
what you're looking at here is a
secondary mechanism
to say
please fire quickly if something seems
wrong
now something seems wrong for you can be
expressed either as
i am observing losses i am serving holes
in the packet sequence numbers
or
i
there is some
some also mechanism now
the packet sequence number is something
which is very hard to use in practice
because
first i mean the the size of the loss in
the packet sequence number vary with the
conjugation window
and second the
it also depends on things like
numbers keeping by the sender
and so
what you have there you have a primary
arc delay
you might want to have an acquiring
delay or something like that
yeah that's that's an interesting point
um
you are right that i'm mentally kind of
conflating the two as being sufficiently
similar to
to serve both purposes and you're right
that it's possible they're not
sufficiently similar
um
but
yeah
okay okay i don't know johnny do you
want to go next or do you should we let
the queue go and have martin go is your
response directly your response to the
christian or john
if it's all right i mean i i think i
don't i don't quite understand
the issue that christine's having
um
at high level basically packet threshold
is already there
and
the problem with this particular with
with the
with the act delays that
we effectively did not have packet to
show lost detection anymore
and what this proposal does is it brings
it back
so
it's not they were bringing a new new
mechanism here we are simply reinstating
a mechanism that we lost
because of this extension
does that make sense to your christian
i'm not i'm not quite maybe i mean it's
not saying we'll have to discuss this on
the on the issue uh and others just
bringing it up
yeah we should we should have that
discussion on on this on
[Music]
because i mean if we go back and forth i
mean trying to explain that verbally
it's gonna be long yeah and you've got
like four and a half minutes to go here
so
um we're happy to have this discussion
on the issue about how important it is
but please look at 96
and we can talk about it then
okay that makes sense to me especially
given our time martin
okay so
wherever
um
i i think maybe i can understand what
you're trying to do i'm not sure about
the first subtraction here i'd like a
picture
because i'm not smart enough to do this
the purpose of this discussion was so
that people could understand what's
going on
and
i suspect this is probably something
along the lines of the right solution
here but i don't know and
so
um that way
[Music]
martin's voice broke off i suspect
because of your mic being on yeah
oh because of mine
can it be the last part martin sorry
request that you
bring this to the list and provide some
i guess better explanatory material than
just a single slide with text on it
but maybe it's just because it's a very
long day in the middle of a very long
week but i'm not smart enough
yeah once again i think that the issue
has some discussion on it but that's
perfectly reasonable and fair i think
part of our goal here was to bring
attention to this issue because it's the
only design issue that's left and
pending and i think that either ways
we'll be able to come to a decision on
it once we get people's eyes
and minds staring at it so
um yeah i mean i think we'd be happy to
do something on email if that's
necessary um
and you'd be a restating of what's on
the issue already but that's happily
done
yeah yeah sorry i kind of thought i'd
send this to the list but i must have
failed to actually hit send on that
email or something so apologies that's
my dad
uh
oh thanks ian um
i think it's better reordering threshold
is
better than ignore order this gives you
a little bit
more options than you know just true and
false
but as i i think christian what he said
i think i agree with him so
if there's a reordering threshold it can
be either in time or in packets i i
think maybe we can make this field
either two fields or make this
make a way to distinguish whether we are
setting this in time or packets
but the other thing i wanted to say was
this is again the same prob same issue
that i had raised with ignore order or
ignore ce is what is the guidance
somebody could set it very high and that
just becomes the same as
ignore order
even if they're not selling it as zero
they can still set it very high
so i'm not sure if the the guidance and
the
how how the sender is setting this
if that
uh there's guidance for how to set this
in the draft
i i think there's no additional guidance
i thought we added guidance um
recently janna i think wrote a pr to add
guidance for other use cases and this
would apply and so we'd have to make
sure that guidance got kind of applied
to this
yeah i don't think we have i mean the pr
the pr for this is not fully fleshed out
yet i think that's that's definitely
good feedback i think we need to have
something that's more
precise in terms of what does an
endpoint do if they don't have anything
better that they can use up they don't
have
having a a
default in there is going to be very
useful and i i think we can we can
default back to quickv1 defaults
uh but it'll be good to state that
explicitly that people know what to do
okay
thank you
i agree sorry
hi thanks for doing this and i do see it
progressing that's really good um i have
two questions um
the first one i think you've already
touched on which i think there is some
element of safety in here if you get
these numbers wildly wrong
then there is a congestion control
implication so i would really love to
see some sort of um
safety considerations or recommended
maximums or something we can
maybe we can discuss that later on the
issue
does that seem reasonable
yeah yeah
we can we can either discuss it on this
issue
or on on other issues yeah let me
yeah i'm happy it needs to be discussed
i think we all agree i just want to make
sure we get the right text in there and
it applies to all the various mechanisms
we have and it's kind of a global like
recommendation so i think we're all on
the same page it's just a matter of
making sure we actually get the right
tax rate down um so yeah that's kind of
why i asked that because i think it
probably is better handles a separate
thing
uh once we've got the issues pinned down
right yeah i think having one text
section that kind of says like here are
all the ways you could shoot yourself or
the internet in the foot like don't do
these things and here's why um it's kind
of what we're we need to have
and then my second point is is even more
crazy than i think what video raised i
mean i'm not convinced that ignore ce
is in any way what the
people who are designing l4s are
imagining
and i wonder what the impact of actually
deploying
an ignore ce thing without some very
strong guidance would be on the whole
l4s thing
yeah we could we could add some notes
about how that
ignore c is not
necessarily recommended for
l4s specifically um
yeah or we should just formula a little
bit of um a separate issue that they can
jump into perhaps on that one yeah
i i think i might have time oh sorry
yeah
add something that quickly uh to gauri
the this isn't ignore ce is not really
designed to handle l4s it's more of an
escape hatch for those for for for l4s
in the sense that
if you have if you don't have any acts
coming back you don't have any accurate
ecm feedback and so this this sort of
currently defeats any accuracy that you
might want to do so it's an escape hatch
it's not precisely defined as a solution
for l4s just to be clear
we'll just discuss folks
yeah we're at time here so i ask you
politely to keep up this healthy
discussion on the list and the issues um
thank you ian for the presentation your
last slide talked about working group
best call um it seems there's there's
still a few
uh well this design issue and a few more
issues to go um another question the
chair is probably asking is is about
implementation and interoperability of
the act frequency i know there has been
some but um if if other people are doing
that that would help us understand
um
how mature this draft is and and how
good it is
but beyond that i think
we'll need to move on to the next slide
so once again thank you ian
you're welcome thanks
robin's up next with q log uh
do you wanna
there we
go the system works thank you go ahead
robin
yeah
i'm intelligible i hope
since we had a few issues with that on
monday
um so it's short other than kilo because
not that much happened uh for the latest
draft in the past three months the main
thing we did was move to a different
serialization format
and just to give a little bit of context
on that as you know we we use json for
the main format which is very nice it's
well supported the main downside is that
it's quite
not very robust in most of the parsers
for example here if you would forget the
final square bracket in this example
most of the parcels would simply break
they wouldn't even give you a partial
result there this means typical json is
not very usable for streaming cases
because there you often might not have
the option to properly finish the json
file
or let's say if your implementation
crashes before they can finish the full
log
so what we did initially was define a
separate
additional format next to that
for which we chose newline delimited
json which is exactly what it sounds
like
you just instead of having proper json
you just have each json object as a
separate line and you can just use the
new line as a delimiter which is
very simple works quite well the main
downside there is that it has no
official rfc
so if you would use that we would have
to define a lot of this basics in the
queue log drafts
themselves
basically a smaller downside is that you
can't have new lines inside of the json
um itself which is a bit annoying if
you're doing like manual grabbing or
actually eyeballing the q log files
because these these events are typically
very very long if you do them on a
single line
so
that's what we had last time and then i
think it was martin thompson who
suggested how about we move to
rfc 7464 instead
which is if you don't know it's it's
called json text sequences
and this is actually very very similar
in uh in concept to new line delimited
json instead of new lines you're now
using the
existing ascii record separator
character so this is not actually a
string so it's it's just because it's a
binary character it's difficult to
visualize in the slide so the rs
with the brackets is actually just a
single unicode code point
uh indicating the record-separated
character
um
so the nice thing there is this is
properly defined in rc it's properly
defined how to
how to use it how it maps to uh um
to
um scratch that
and we can have
new lines inside of events which is also
quite nice the main downside was this
seems to be relatively esoteric it isn't
as broadly supported as newline
delimited json despite being a standard
and so we decided we first want to get
some practical experience with this
before we uh switch the uh the q log
format over to that which is what we did
and so it turns out it's actually
quite feasible quite doable
if you're already doing nd json it's
very easy to move over to
json text sequences
in practice
and we also tested various existing tool
suites or tools that people were using
for
qlog like jq and
all kinds of
linux based
text processing tools and they all seem
to work just fine with this new format
and so that's the reason why we decided
let's go for it and uh so that's the
main change in draft one we moved from
ndjs onto this with that some fewer
additional
minor changes we have semantic
versioning now
we have a little bit of more information
on using different file extensions for
the different formats and also have some
more information on the media types that
you might use when when say sending
these things over
http
um this was then picked up quite quickly
we have support for this in the qvis
tool suite and we also have several
implementations that have moved to the
newest format and everything seems to
work just fine
so two points i want to make there first
it's not that we're moving everything
over to this we are still supporting
both json and json text sequences so
non-streaming file based and
streaming let's say
but if you were for some reason waiting
for this change to be made to update
your own implementation
i think it's fair to say that we'll
likely
stay with this streaming format so if
you were waiting for this
you can probably go ahead and start
implementing that
so that's since last time what are we
planning for the near future
by itf 113
we're hoping to mainly do some editorial
work
and the main thing there is that in the
current drafts all of our events we've
tried to properly define them which
fields are on which events and which
type
are those fields but for those we are
currently using the typescript
data definition format
and here we have a very similar
situation to nd json it's usable but
it's no it's not really well defined
anywhere and it's not an rfc
and so here again we also want to make
the move to something a bit more itf
centric
which is called the concise data
definition language cddl as you can see
it's it's very similar in concepts it's
just mainly the syntax that changes a
little bit
but the main gain we hope to get from
this
especially down the line is that cdl
should make it easier for us to
automatically extract
event definitions
schema definitions in different
formats and programming languages and
also use those to build automatic
validators for q log files which is
something that we are currently missing
a bit
uh so the goal is there to hopefully
have something like in tools like qvis
that you upload a q log file and then it
can tell you exactly if you have any
errors in there
misspelled fields wrong types or fields
and so on and so forth which is
something we've seen surface a little
bit in the in the past months
for some people
so that's kind of the idea it's both to
make everything a bit more neat itf
style but also be more robust towards
the future when we start adding new
stuff
so this is what i think we have in mind
for next ietf 113 and then after that
our main goals are to
basically flash out what we have
we are a bit lacking in tls and qpec
stuff at this moment
so we want to add those things and then
we have a few events that need to be
extended or touched up to be a bit
clearer and then there are some
proposals to add more high-level
generalized stuff like indicating which
cpu or which tread a certain
event comes from that kind of stuff that
other implementations like microsoft
use in their custom logging format that
might be useful
down the line
and that's basically it like last time
we we had i had in my slides um like a
desire to have like a
a global design guideline or or a design
framework so that people could add new
events and new protocols even to qlog
and so on and so forth and
since we've had a lot of discussion
about that and
i think most people there agree that
this is a
bit of a utopia that it would be quite
difficult to achieve this
and even if we could it's probably not
something we want to do within the
the the quick working group for for the
current k-log
effort
and so the idea here would be to limit
ourselves quite relatively to quick in
http 3
and then look into all these other stuff
later on
which is fine for me but i think that
means that we need a very clear idea of
how to do that later on already now or
at least provide enough extension points
down the line to make this relatively
possible
and that's something that is on this
slide and that especially lucas has been
creating some issues for in the past
weeks
that we need to start thinking about
versioning and versioning of individual
documents individual event
groupings we need to think about how to
indicate which protocols and which
events are in which file
um how to uh make it possible to change
existing events for example add new
transport parameters
into the existing transport parameter
event that we have and so on and so
forth and then we should also have a
discussion about
let's say we want a
q log
log events for rap transport
how do we do that is that a separate
draft is it a fully separate thing where
does that live and so on and so forth so
a few of those practical issues those
are not things that are very pressing at
this moment but it would be nice to have
an idea of what people think about this
or to have
some proposals of this by itf 113 so
that we can start the discussion in
earnest
by then
so that's what i have for you today
please if you have any questions
go ahead kazoo
thank you for the presentation and thank
you for making the changes
uh regarding the file format i prefer
uh choosing one rather than
uh having support for two
because in my opinion you know
supporting two is always more complex
than supporting one and writing a
conversion tool to the other
yeah
but it's even if we have two formats
it's still possible to just implement
one and then convert it to the other if
you uh
if you want right i'm not sure i
understand the question
right i mean
if
if there's only one format defined then
for example i can create a pool that
only supports that format
but if
there are two formats being defined
i i'm
you know i'm forced to write a converter
or write
at least write a test to support both of
those two and that's a complexity i
think
for everyone every other one
so you would propose moving to just a
single defined format um
yes
yep regardless of whichever
thank you oh man thanks hello
now i can hear you yep
all right uh regarding the
uh rs separated
keylog
uh
are they semantics of
aggregating multiple logs into a single
created log
uh
going to be understood by the tools or
is it something
that's undefined behavior
yeah so that's that's one of the main
reasons i would have two different
formats
i didn't want to get too deep into that
with kazuo
but
i don't have a second question so if you
have multiple if you have the normal
json one we can append separate traces
as individual objects that's much more
difficult in streaming format if you
want to do that in streaming format you
would have to indicate for each
individual event to which
sub-trace it
it belongs otherwise it's impossible to
de-multiplex them afterwards
thank you
but uh finalizing on that that is
something that qvis for example also
already does
it's not that it's very complex it's
just a different way of doing things
oh well um it doesn't seem like we've
got anyone else in the queue um
there's some some good progress here and
some good progress to come i did see in
the chat um christine mentioned
multipath support i think you know
sometimes defining these events
takes some thinking but it isn't too
hard it's more the
um
what should what makes sense to put in
and what are people willing to implement
um because you can define everything and
if no one implements them then you you
can end up with some interop issues uh
like like we found in the hackathon last
week uh when we are consuming each
other's um q logs so
uh i think there's there's some some
good work to come up and look forward to
that progress in the future
but if there's nothing more here i think
we could just move on
um for just for multipath i was
intentionally waiting a bit for the
unified proposal
right
um to know what what direction we're
going and once that's settled down i i
think it should be relatively easy to
add at least provisional multi-part
events
and then also have some basic uh
let's say cubist tooling around that
to help with multiple debugging
yeah cool well thank you robin um and
with that we can move on to vision
negotiation so david would you like to
step on up please
good
morning afternoon evening middle of the
night everyone let me find these slides
all right
can someone confirm that you can hear me
and see the slides
i can confirm cool thanks
uh so uh my name is david kanazi and i'm
here to
very very briefly give folks an update
on the version negotiation draft
um
so a
very accelerated history uh we used to
have vn in the core specs we then
decided to remove it and split it to its
own draft this is that draft
we were
went around in circles for a bit on it
because it was too complicated then mt
came around with a simpler design that
folks liked
that's in the draft
today
and then the question is where do we go
from here um
so far the the new simplified design
i've haven't heard anyone said they
dislike it so we're in good shape
uh we still have a lot of
minor issues on the on the document it's
more that um just the
the editors uh haven't been focusing on
it so we haven't made good progress on
those
um but like all the ones i did a quick
pass on those last week and it really
looked like
there was agreement on how to resolve
all of them
uh the question is
kind of
what is the status with implementations
uh for the longest time we didn't have
one i just just on monday i implemented
it in our stack not the compatible part
but the
at least the version downgrade part and
it was very straightforward
and kind of the question for the working
group is where do we want to
go from here
do we want to publish this soon do we
want to wait until we have another
version so we can like test the
compatibility bits at scale before we
ship this
uh we'd kind of like to get a some sort
of a timeline because
you know that if this needs to get
published soon then that it's worth it
for the editors to prioritize like
fixing these editorial things otherwise
we can kind of kick this can down the
road until another version so thoughts
questions what do we do now this is the
end of my presentation
crickets
so if
um
one thing is please interrupt with my
server i put it on the general channel
of the slack um just want to make sure
that
you know we
i implemented it correctly
but apart from that uh given that
there's not too much excitement about
this i
guess maybe we just kind of kicked the
can down the road a bit further uh matt
do you have any thoughts
yeah i was just gonna you know hearing
the the deafening silence from the
working group i think like everyone
agrees this is something we need it but
it doesn't seem like there's a lot of
implementation
appetite at the moment i think for
something like this we do want
implementations and interop before we
like you know kind of shepherd it
through
so um just everyone keep that in mind
that if if you want this in the future
if you see this being something that you
want in the future please implement it
sooner rather than later
um gianna did you want to say something
um hey um
thanks for the presentation dude just
very quickly
it seems to me that it might actually be
useful to get some
implementation deployment experience
along with a different version so i
wonder if the quick v2 discussion that
we are about to have later might play
into how quickly we move on this draft
that that makes sense because if we have
a v2 that is compatible with the first
one that'll help us to
use this at scale also
we won't be able to ship a v2 without a
version negotiation mechanism with v1
so like yeah maybe these become a joint
cluster
and uh i think the quick v2 is on the s
time permits so in that case i'll just
say let's punch for now but let's see
what comes out of the v2 discussion
all right and expect a similar
two-minute presentation at the next atf
then
thanks everyone
all right since i'm already on the mic
uh yeah mark i've as we can see martin's
coming up with quick lb so go ahead
martin
yeah
in the uh
staying in the vein of um
things that people sort of support but
are a little bit can i get a clock reset
please uh that think that people that
things that people support but there
aren't a lot of implementations quick lb
um
so uh at 111 i talked about a lot of uh
technical issues
um
and basically that the draft had
expanded to cover lots of use cases
because we weren't getting a lot of
useful feedback of what the most
important use cases were
um
so uh
the the the upshot of that was people
thought it was too complicated too many
choices and i agreed with that and then
of course the other concerns there
weren't a ton of implementations uh
particularly on the server side
and no interop activity to date that i'm
aware of
so some things have happened here uh
christian uitima has been incredibly
valuable and fixing the now very much
misnamed stream site for algorithm into
something that is a little more secure
um uh we've kind of just cleaned up some
of the nomenclature to kind of make it
less
three completely disjoint algorithms
with just um three
just three different sets of options to
kind of the same core structure so it's
just a simplification
thing um
an ad a couple drafts ago was dynamic uh
server id allocation
not preconfiguring that and um i think
we've
reached consensus that it's a little too
cute and there's there's too many um
difficult mechanisms associated with
that that's gone again uh and then i've
heard some good news about
implementations but i haven't seen
anything concrete yet
again like i know there are a lot of
server implementers in the room and that
is where we are
hurting most um
if you have a quick server
implementation many of you do and you
would like to
create some server some connection
degeneration logic uh we have load
balancers that can interact with you and
that would be helpful
there we go okay so this is kind of my
my dream on how this can move forward um
uh chris and i have asked for a cfrg
review of
the the stream cipher algorithm um since
it's since christian came up with
something was kind of a
variant of effect so we've kind of
rolled our own crypto so we're going
through that process now not sure
exactly what the what the reaction will
be
um if that goes well and it shows that
we have the same or similar
security properties to the block cipher
algorithm
it's not clear to me what the value of
the block cipher algorithm is there's an
issue in the github if you want to weigh
in on this but essentially you'd be
getting longer c ids the only benefit
would be fewer crypto passes
which seems like a not that strong
advantage
um and then that would dramatically
simplify that the document essentially
have a like a plain text version and the
cirtex version of the same thing so that
would be um
that'd be as simple as you could get um
i really would like to split the load
balancer portion of this and the retry
service portion of this i view them as
entirely orthogonal with each other
um the load balancer thing's essentially
version invariant with a few caveats and
then retry service thing really is not
and um i'm getting proposals for things
like stateless uh reset offload and so
on and they all just have like the
common theme of middle box coordination
but i don't know if that's a strong
enough thread to hold these two things
together i've also just kind of become
enamored of the idea that like
smaller drafts are better because people
read them and when there's a lot of
ancillary stuff that
half people don't care about just makes
things worse so i don't know if people's
strong opinions about that i'll be happy
to hear from it then after like if all
this goes according to plan then we do
another editorial pass then it'd be done
as it's going to be done that's just the
question of getting a couple
implementations that are up in them and
then we're done
so let's see do i have another slide yes
uh
i don't know if you want to talk about
the block cid stuff right now
we can get into that if you want so i'll
just open the floor for comments
ian
uh i the only thing i had to share is
that i now that we've
kind of worked our way through our
backlog of idea of quick work
in other areas um we are very excited to
hopefully take this on in the first half
of 2022 um
but
there's still some details to be worked
out in terms of who's going to do the
work and everything um but the use cases
are there and
everything but that to be said to be
clear
that's like the stream cipher protocol
with like the key rotation and all of
those sort of mechanisms
um the key exchange portion and all that
stuff uh i don't we probably will
support at some point in the future but
that's like more of a
a year from now or more probably sort of
thing so i think that probably supports
the idea that at least in our case
you're gonna get a deployment
on one of them
a lot earlier than you're going to get
deployment on the other half but i don't
know
are you talking about the retry service
versus the
the um load balancing
yes sorry that's right okay yeah all
right super thank you yeah i mean like
that's the other thing like if we get
a lot of implications in one i
anticipate the implementations of one of
those components versus the other to be
very asymmetric and if one's ready to go
i'd just like to move it um and at some
point i'll i'll produce a mock-up of
what these book things would look like
when people shoot at it lucas
hey martin um have you i'm just curious
have you had any
feedback to say that the proposed split
is is not desirable has anyone kind of
said that they wouldn't like that
um i i i brought it up uh like a long
time ago and got
like
i think it's like five or six weeks ago
and got some negative uh like a little
bit negative pushback i'm it wasn't
super strong i'm become more convinced
this i'm bringing it up again
uh and you know i don't i don't think i
haven't really discussed this on the
list much recently i will do so but this
is my i'm kind of introducing the topic
now frankly
um to allow people to comment
okay that's cool i think that the list
is a good venue to continue that um
i think i i i'm
trying hat off in personal opinion if
splitting them is going to help make
some progress on on the one thing that
people really do want to implement um
that seems like a benefit but i'm i'm
not fully okay with
with lb to know what the potential
downside might be for that split
i mean they're functionally completely i
mean they can in theory be implemented
on the same device but there there's
there's no real relationship between the
two um
they're together because they were again
under the theme of middlebox
uh cooperation um
which is a pretty weak threat in my view
so there's a comment in the chat about
they missed the cfrg email that's
because we didn't actually go directly
to cfrg upon the advice of the security
ids we contact a couple people directly
um if other people like provide a crypto
review of what of specific specifically
section 5.2 the stream site for cid like
that would be
um
very welcome i i just i received the
advice it would be better to actually
contact people directly
any uh matt are you in the queue or you
just um
i'm mostly hanging out but i was going
to say one thing which is that um
i was curious what you're in from a
chair perspective what what is your
opinion on uh
this
necessity for interop for you know
are you
are we comfortable like
because it seems like there hasn't been
a lot of design issues or things
recently besides the things you
mentioned and so
you know do we wait on
interop do we wait on and do we have to
interrupt everything or what and deploy
it or what i was just curious what your
thoughts are on that
so i i have like two concerns with the
surety i'm beyond beyond just kind of my
ideal path and how this proceeds i to
consider my maturity number one is that
the document is written in a way that
it's implementable because obviously i
knew what i meant when i implemented it
um which it doesn't uh
mean a ton
and then the second thing um
and i hope that especially google's uh
intentions are helpful here like
actually
trying to deploy this thing and
developing some uh
like we have we have sort of a
configuration model that has some
assumptions and it'll be really nice to
like test that against actual production
somehow so i'm really eager to
hear um
to hear like what the what the issues
are with google and like what the rough
edges on sort of the assumptions we make
on how to configure things and like what
what what the pain points are i know
that uh my my co-author nick banks has
like been working with azure uh on this
stuff and it hasn't gone super well in
terms of getting them to to provide good
feedback so
um those are really those are the only
reason other than just like the clean up
in the draft that's those are the
reasons those are the two things where i
just don't want to like hit the wtlc
button right now
uh all right if there's nothing else i'm
going to give back the balance of my
time
thanks thank you martin that's very kind
of you um
okay so mira is jumping in the queue
it's time for
the uh new work
topic um samaria take it away
on the topic of multi-path extension
okay hello everybody um so yeah i'm
amelia i'm presenting um a new draft
here um but effectively this is not new
work um there has been previously uh
three different drafts and as you can
see here on this new draft we have a set
of authors that actually combines
the authors from the previous draft so
that's the content
um so let's move to the next uh i have
to i can just control this myself okay
yeah so what happened so far um lucas
already uh mentioned that we had an
interview meeting about a year ago where
we talked about quick use cases mainly
requirements and since then there was a
lot of work and people have been working
on implementations there were three
different proposals and in order to move
forward from here we somehow needed to
agree what the right way is to move
forward like combining those proposals
and and getting one way out of this um
so um i got in touch with all the
authors from uh from all the draft and
there was already a lot of agreement
about what to do and everybody was like
so um on board for having one unified
solution immediately
um so we had a site meeting only a few
weeks ago where we discussed how um to
move forward here and as a result of
that we recently published this new
draft which does take parts of
the the other three drafts um
so
this presentation will give you an
overview about what's what's the focus
in the new draft and what's in the new
draft
and this is um the most important
outcome from all the discussion we had
is that the new draft is really focusing
on the core components
so in the other three drafts there were
always parts which were like not core
components which were things like um qe
handling um address discovery and this
kind of things
and in order to move forward we really
want to focus on those things that are
needed to establish multipath
usage of
of multiple paths simultaneously
so that means the current draft
as a core component has of course the
negotiation of a new extension it has
a minimal set of path management that is
needed about setting up inclusion close
new path um or old pass in that case
it talks a little bit about scheduling
but that's really minimal at this point
we probably need a few more words but
don't want to talk about it extensively
only what's needed to make it work and
then it talks about how to actually
transmit and retransmit packets so
that's it that's the core everything
else that has been previously um
discussed like more advanced scheduling
mechanisms or unidirectional passes
address disc discovery or any kind of qs
handling and these are things that could
come up later on in additional drafts or
could be additional extensions on top of
that
so the other thing that we had like very
broad agreement on is that
one of the important design principles
here is to use as much as possible from
rfc 9000
and this is also kind of the feedback i
not only got from the authors but from
everybody else i talked like please keep
this as simple as possible and that
means make minimal set of changes here
and we actually try to do that so what
we don't change is past validation we
completely keep it as it is in a quick
version one and uh and as used for pass
migration
uh we don't have to change basically
anything about congestion control
because congestion flow was always per
path so when you had migration you had
to reset your congestion control and now
you have to run multiple congestion
controls in parallel for each path we
didn't change the header format and also
didn't change anything in the in the r0
rtt packet so everything that we do for
multipass is done for one rtt packets
there is another design principle which
is kind of uh important is that
we define a path as a four tuple that
may makes some things some assumptions
easier and it mainly means that you can
only have one path before chapel
so what did we change or what what did
we add i probably have to say
what we add is that we kind of not only
want migration but we actually want
simultaneous use of multiple path so
that means that you can send non-probing
frames on multiple paths at the same
time so this is something that is not
allowed by rsc 9000 and that's something
we want to enable here
um so that's one change and the other
change is that we now that you have like
multiple open paths you also have to
care about clothing those paths so
that's some additional
mechanics that we added here um but it's
also not a lot of stuff i have to say
and there are a few additional
considerations about recovery and for
example rtt estimation and these all
depend a little bit about how you kind
of implement acting and packet number
spaces because you really need to figure
out for rtt estimation and loss recovery
in which packet which packet was sent on
which path and depending on what
solution you choose for your packet
number spaces that might be easier or
harder
before i talk more about packet number
spaces which is like one of the open
points i just um show you on the next
slide
what we are proposing to do in this
draft right now
so what we have in the draft right now
is that you can actually negotiate
um either use of one packet number space
or use of model packer number space or
you can in indicate in the handshake
that you support both if both ends
support both
implementations you will use multiple
packet number space that is actually not
in the currency or zero draft version
but that's a pr we already merged into
the next update because that wasn't
clearly specified
so what does it mean one packet number
or multiple packet number um easy so
with one packet number space
every packet you want to send out gets
the new packet number in order and then
you decide to send it out on one or the
other paths so you might send out packet
one on one pass and pack it on the other
pass if you have multiple packet number
spaces the packet numbers are
independent on each path
uh and you can have packet one on pass
number one and you can have packet one
on pass number two but you have to
identify which path this was sent on
um we have those two options in the
negotiation and in the specification of
the current version of the draft but
this is to able evaluation and
implementation experience
and this is not is there's no intention
to publish this kind of negotiation for
the final version of of this extension
in any rsc
um but we proposed to actually take it
on in a working group like this so we
can get more experience here and make
progress and have more
um discussion about this
so on this slide i try to on a high
level summarize the current discussion
about packet number spaces and why it's
not easy to make a decision right away
we had some discussion about this in the
site meeting there's also a nice slide
set from christian hittimer about this
if you want to learn more but you know
the high level message on this slide is
there are pros and cons for both of the
approaches
um
so i think i'm starting with the cons
for some single number packet number
space here so the cons for the single
packet number space is actually it it's
a kind of easy um
the pro sorry that it's kind of easy to
implement it's it's only a few um lines
of code that you need to add or change
um and and the other pros also that it
does work with
zero length connection id
um the cons are that you can come into a
situation where you actually increase
your ag frame size
um
noticeably so especially if you have two
paths which have very different
latencies you might get a lot of
reordering um you can be smart about how
you schedule the packets or how you
create your ex and try to reduce that
but the problem or the con maybe is that
you have to be smart it's not
straightforward you have to do it right
and maybe there's also more chance for
doing something wrong
on the multiple packet number spaces
um you you don't have that problem so
that's one of the big cons it's very um
clear which packet belongs to which path
there's no ambiguity about you know
where the packet was lost or about when
you calculate the round trip time or
anything like that and your pack your
egg frames are smaller and clearer and
so the the logic that you have to
implement is easier however
you have to have more code
more lines of code and you have to have
code that is specific for this extension
only and might not be used in a single
pass
implementation or setup
the other drawback of the multiple
packet number space is that currently
you we have to require connection ids in
both directions to make this work but
that is actually something that is under
discussion and maybe um we come up with
some smart ideas here as well
um so but um effectively i don't think i
want to discuss
this topic here today i think what we
need and what i said earlier is we need
more implementation experience and
feedback about this and then hopefully
have this discussion further in the
working group instead of making decision
right here
um yeah
we have a few people in the queue um
yes
i was trying to look at this right now
let's uh let's actually break here
and take those questions yeah if you're
okay with that mirror i'd like to keep
this on for clarifying questions for for
what's been said already um we'll have
time for discussion at the end
so um kazuho please
fire away
thanks for the presentation
uh i have one question so one of the
slides says that a path is defined as
faultable being bi-directional
does that mean that if you receive
packets on path x you have to send out
for those packets on pathx
no it it it means that you have to be
able to receive packets on that pat on
that pass and and that's something that
you check during past validation but
where how to schedule packets and how to
schedule their your x is is i think
actually not specified that much in the
draft currently that's left to the
implementation
so there's no requirement to set send
the x on the same path
thank you
uh can you hear me
yes
yeah so i have reading you know the
emergency act so um i just got one
comment so i suggest that maybe we can
add some use quiz
or some um
some paragraph in the introduction to
describe uh explicitly so how do we how
how we can use that
uh and be quick so the reason is so now
you should know that uh the cpr
um r18 has um has the release 18 has
discussed the atss for a long time
and several companies strong support
uh to add the multi-pass
functionalities into the attackers to
achieve um you know the
traffic splitting or
even redundant transmissions so i think
uh so i think one of the the valuable
things here is that uh so perhaps we can
if we can
complete a uh
and a quick work for just before the uh
the completion of the release 18 and
then we can we can
try to uh to adopt this this uh rfc into
the real estate team that's maybe
it's it's it's it's a good way to uh
to
like to you know
uh
to make this drive you need to implement
into the in the
real world case so actually i stopped in
a uh
use case draft before for this meeting
so i'm not sure whether i can share my
screen
uh for sometimes
or i can just just simply describe that
the the the draft
we're sure
we need to focus on the discussion here
um
yeah we need to just keep this to
clarifying questions about the president
okay so uh i just i i okay let me simply
describe so i just have a
point
um
i i agree with you i think this is a
very important use case and i'm
supporting that as well um
and um
we should prob maybe have some more
discussion in future but probably not in
this meeting so i think in this reading
we should figure out what are the basic
concepts that we want to see in a draft
and then move forward and and have this
discussion later if that's okay for you
okay so so perhaps uh yeah once we have
um once we've upgraded on the uh on the
basic setup quick shot maybe for the for
the extension so we can consider to add
some introduction and some descriptions
about
how to
you know how to advertise the uh the
draft into a different organization
okay
thank you yeah i think that might be a
rather separate draft than something in
the introduction yeah but
um yeah something to consider later
yeah thanks
diana
uh thanks a very quick clarifying
question um maria you said that the
decision between these two choices would
require more implementation experience
and matt said on chat that this would be
the first design decision that we would
make if this draft were to be adopted
those two are very different points and
i don't need it right now but it'd be
useful to clarify what exactly the path
forward would be because i would like to
push against something which i'm not
gonna do right now but this is
asking for clarification for what that
would be
um
so
if you ask me um i think for example
people deciding to only decide implement
one or the other
you know is good input for this group if
we have everybody at the end decides to
only implement one of the approaches
then we have a decision we don't need
much discussion about it
but i'm also pretty sure that depending
on the stack you're having your
implementation experience might be
different so more input would be
valuable here because based on the
implementations we have so far
um
we can see that the implementation of a
single number packet space um is easier
but we also didn't um evaluate a lot of
the logic that you have to implement
then if that actually works very well so
more work is needed from my point of
view but maybe matt wants to say more
uh yeah what i was going to say is that
you know it i kind of agree with jonah
that it's a design issue but you know
it's it i think what you're saying is
actually kind of the same which is that
you
wait mario what you're saying is you
want input from implementers about which
design they think works with their
implementation not necessarily that you
think everyone should go implement both
and then be like oh i like this one
better
all
right yep that's totally it
spencer spencer do you want to
uh sorry i was just waiting for somebody
to to
tell me if we were we were finished um i
wanted to thank you all for doing this
work uh a lot
um
maria um
we i've been talking about a strategy of
uh sending acts on different paths
which you're leading leading up to the
implementations for now and i'm not
arguing about that
my clarifying question was is that does
that work with one sequence space
multiple sequence spaces both or neither
sorry does does what work
uh
sending sending acts on a different path
um
[Music]
that should is completely independent
you can you can even if you have a
different packet number space you can
send it to a different path all right as
the act doesn't identify the packet
number and space your your
perfect item
i am clarified thank you
sorry i was trying to read the chat at
the same time which doesn't work so you
have to come to the queue and talk to me
hello
yeah
um
so what i want to ask is does the
multipath quick also cover the data from
extension
yes
these extensions are completely
independent so you can implement both
and use both okay okay so you don't see
special challenges here and the
description of multi-pass quick is
completely agnostic to that um okay
nevertheless um my question is specific
to the
uh
multiple r2 to the packet number spaces
so as you know we are developing the
multi-parts dccp which i think has a
similar
yeah kind of similar characteristics to
the multi-path quick
especially when we think about a
multi-path quick with the data chrome
extension because then we have an
unreliable transmission which has some
challenges to multipath and in that
respect we explicitly decided to use
multiple pn spaces for mpdccp because it
has some positive effect if it comes to
reordering
so it supports us in our in our
reordering approach and i think that's
quite important or that you should
consider if you discuss
the packet number spaces if it should be
a single one or a multiple one so have
in mind that multiples plus data chrome
has some special demands and maybe
multiple pn spaces can support here
yeah i mean i'm not i'm not too familiar
with the details of dccp but i think
it's different here because for datagram
and quick you already still know when a
packet get lost you just don't resubmit
it because you have a packing number
here oh yeah okay
yeah that's the same in dccp so you are
aware of a packet that's lost
nevertheless you maybe wanna reorder
packets without re-transmission without
requiring re-transmission and then
multiple pn spaces can help to to make
fast decisions in the reordering process
if a packet get lost
or it's worth to wait for it
i just gotta interject here's a chat
this is interesting chat we can we can
have this on the list and on issues it's
it's kind of beyond the scope of
clarification so uh thanks marcus but um
yeah we'll we'll follow up on that one
um yep we're
gonna if you want to progress through
the slides mirror um
yes uh let's go through many few slides
and just to tell you what's in the draft
not much left here
so as i said there is something about
path management path initiation um it
works very similar than
pass validation if you take pass
validation as it is from rsc 9000 no
changes the only change is that
afterwards after the validation has
completed you can actually send
non-problem packets on multiple path
um pass validation can also be only
initiated by the client so that's a
restriction that we could further
discuss um in the working group but
that's what's currently in the draft
the thing that we did add was pass
removal because with migration you don't
need to remove the path you move over
you close the old parts immediately uh
with multi-pass support you have
multiple paths so you have to care about
how to close them there is a new frame
here which is called path of button
and but we also reuse the retire
connection id frame to actually signal
the that resources can be released and
we also rely on timeouts as it's done
in rf9000
um
so basically um what we do here is we we
from from a semantics point of view we
have two new frame types one of the past
bend frame this carries past identifier
error code and reason frame
and there is also a pass identifier type
which indicates um if the pass
identifier belongs to uh basically the
source or destination id or to the
current pass if no
connection id
is present so effectively you can send
this frame on any path if you have a
connection id if you don't have a
connection you can only send it over the
past that you want to abandon so if you
have a connection id you have like more
flexibility here in providing this
signal to the other hand
then we also have a new um egg
multi-pass frame this is only used if uh
if you have multiple packet number
spaces but this extension is also
minimal it's really like the old egg
frame it only has one additional field
which identifies the packet number space
um yeah
so that's kind of what's in the draft
again we we really try to focus on the
core components that are needed to use
multiple paths simultaneously
and all the authors have agreed on some
key design principles which is really
try to keep it as simple as possible
just add minimal stuff
and
and we are aligned with that i think
that was also what came out of the site
meeting
we have this option to currently to
negotiate multiple packet numbers space
one or multiple number spaces but this
is really for experimentation and so
please if you go implement the site if
you want to implement one or both of
them and report back so we can make a
decision for one of those approaches at
some point but um i think this is ready
to uh to take on by the working group
and move the discussion back into the
working group at the site meeting there
was a lot of interest there was also
people talking about implementation so i
think uh i think it would be great to
have this in the working group and so we
are we are asking if this is ready for
adoption
yeah and just to add to that you know
we've got some time for discussion now
there's there's a lot of potential
things that people could say about cool
ideas they've got or potential issues
they might see um but we'd like to keep
the discussion here focused on on the
question um about you know viewpoints on
on whether we think
this this brush should be adopted um or
not um
towards the end of the the eight minutes
we have here we'll take a show of hands
as well um before taking any any
question to the list
but yeah if people could keep it on the
topic of adoption um that would greatly
help the chairs so
uh john is first in the queue please
please go
thank you for the presentation maria it
was very helpful um at high level i
would say that
the document that lays out all possible
designs
i would argue is not ready for adoption
simply because it it
it's a superset of all the things that
you might want to do now i haven't read
the draft yet so i'll admit that first
um
but can i interrupt you here for one
second so we're not playing out all
possible designs we really try to
concentrate on the minimum but um it was
and there was a lot of things where the
three different drafts you look at like
we actually found a lot of agreement and
the authors are all aligned on these
points it's really just a packet number
space because as you have seen on the
slide there's no clear good solution
right so rather than trying to take any
kind of choice and now and then maybe
revise it later because we're figuring
out this is not the right thing to do
and we left those two options in there
only for this one issue
understood but it's a pretty fundamental
issue i mean the backend number space
issue drives a lot of questions really
it doesn't it's really a very um
detailed implementation thing it doesn't
change any of the functionality or any
of the principles you want to have in
this graph it's really about
implementation
um so i would have to read the draft i
suppose i mean i'll take that back to
myself that's feedback to me however
i'll say that if we can resolve that
issue before we talk about our option
that would be helpful because to me the
the the
ultimately we are defining a protocol
here it's not rocket science and the
protocol is about the details and
the use of path id or not the use of a
separate packet numbers or not actually
again in it to me it should make a
difference in big difference in how the
protocol is designed
so
uh i would argue that uh
take it for what it's worth but i
haven't read the draft so i won't make
it too strongly i would say that my
point is we should resolve that issue
before we really talk about the adopting
the documents
so point taking but also i think what we
have right now is that and that was also
what was in previous drafts already that
we have two specifications and they can
work together we have identified what
are the things that overlap and have
described them in in the respective way
so if you make a decision for one or the
other at some point we just go ahead and
remove parts of the draft and that's it
it's not it's not like we have to
redesign the rest because we separated
those things nicely
um so i think this is really a a small
part only and rather than trying to um
to kind of get ourselves stuck on this
kind of minor implementation point i
think we should move forward and we
should uh make sure that everything is
is in well shape and incentivize people
to um implement this and and give a
clear thing that we actually want to
work on this and come to a conclusion
um
just based on some of the chat and that
that we're having and jonah's point
there about not having read the draft
i'm just going to take a quick show of
hands for who who has actually read this
already um so we're going to use the
echo tool for this um and the question
is going to be quite simple have you
read the draft
and you can raise your hand
um
to say you have
and i'm going to start that now and
we'll run that
give this like another 20 seconds or so
you can click do not erase
drafts but not this version
like i read the ids before they were
merged
what should i answer
maybe no because i think for this
question it's actually important that
you understand what the difference is
okay i'm gonna i'm gonna close the poll
now uh we have
20 raised hands
and 46 did not raise their hands for a
total of 66 participants in a meeting of
168 people so
uh
thank you
kazuo
please
regarding design support
um is there a design principle regarding
the efficiency of the protocol to give
an example is then principle that
multiple quotes should perform as well
as quickbrilliant i might have missed
that but would hope that that be
clarified because that's what drives the
design choices that we make
um so i don't think we have this
explicitly in the draft the design
principles that we do list in the draft
is what kind of what did lead the the
author team to make the decisions right
now it's not like a comprehensive list
so if you want
make sure this is captured in the draft
then please open an issue
yeah so i mean
before adopting this i think
i hope that we agree on the
design goals i mean the the
performance efficiency requirements that
we want to meet
because
without agreeing on that
it's so much
harder to agree on what the choices that
we have to take
that's my i mean i think this needs more
discussion because i don't even really
understand what such a requirement would
mean because um
of course you have different path
characteristics if you have multiple
paths right so you might have one long
delay and one short delay path and if
you select the short delay pass for a
certain application you have better
experience than the longer past but it
might be different for the other
applications so i don't think this
question is actually that easy i'm happy
to discuss it more
right but it's a fundamental different
behavior so i'm not sure there is like a
clear comparison to a single path
approach
well so what was thinking about a of a
strictly uh inferior case like for
example for fc and also recovery we
might need purpose signal back delays
but that's hard to accomplish with
single packet number space
so that was the case i would think of it
yes
thank you
i mean i'm also not sure if the answer
to that is so clear because you just
have to be smart about where to send
when and where to send your ex so this
is something we need more experience
with
thank you
martin
thanks uh yes i've read the draft i
support this work export adoption
although i'll probably personally not
implement it um i don't think we need to
resolve the pack number space issue
prior to adoption i i will say the
reason i support is i think there's a
lot of um
desire for multi-pass solution but there
are a lot of big experimental questions
and i think of all the transports we
have i think quick is the best suited to
do open internet experience because i'll
actually get through the internet unlike
all the other options um
i would probably argue should be
experimental draft we don't have to
settle that now thanks
tommy
all right
um so i i have read the unified draft
and i definitely support adoption of it
um i think that the work to unify the
draft has greatly improved the proposal
um as it's come together
this is better than any of the
individual drafts i think
it doesn't have a lot of the excess bits
hanging off of it it's focused and it's
minimized and i think a minimal
implementation is exactly the type of
thing that we want
to adopt here because otherwise we're
going to spend a lot of time getting
distracted
so it's the right kind of starting point
so if we think we need to work on
multi-path let's do this and i think
this is the time to start to work on
multi-path
mature implementations
are getting to the point where they need
to use it
our implementation really needs to start
looking at this soon so having something
that the working group is looking at is
good
there is an open question about packing
number spaces i think that should be
better addressed by the working group
rather than having the authors try to
come up with one thing and not listen to
the whole working group so
let's adopt it and figure out that
question together
so we're running on time but ian then
yeah go ahead
yeah i i support
the last two two statements um in our
case we finally finished like connection
migration so i think we finally feel
like we have like the bandwidth to
really take some of this work on and
actually contribute whereas before we
didn't so i feel like now is the right
time um i'd love to get the pack number
space issue result but
um i don't think it needs to be resolved
before adoption but i also don't want to
make everyone implement but um but i
think we can hammer out like that pretty
quickly in the networking group um the
only other commenter that say is
if we do this we may want to consider
having like a separate one-hour meeting
just for multipath or something real
quick
um because i get the impression there
are some people who attend the quick
working group who are distinctly
uninterested in spending their time on
us but i don't know you'd have to ask
through about that
christian
i i definitely support uh
adoption that's not surprising but the
big reason i support adoption is exactly
what tommy said
we want the discussion to happen in
public to the working group
not in a confined mailing list that is
between authors
and if we support adoption if we get
adoption what will happen is that we'll
move
the current github repo
in which we're discussing will move that
to the working group people who already
sees it
and will have change control and things
like that and i think
making the discussions public is a big
reason for adoption
uh chana
so i made the point about
um
not adopting this but i think that i i
perhaps the spirit of the question to me
now is whether we should work on
multipath and if this is
a document we can start from and to that
my answer would be yes because there's
only one document and i think that uh
the work on multipath i think is it's a
good time to start working on it as a
working group so i would like to change
my position that i said earlier to uh
yes let's adopt it and let's hash out
these issues
okay and with that i think uh lucas is
gonna we're gonna run two polls so uh
lucas you want to describe
the polls before you run them
yeah i just want to thank people for
their kind of feedback during this
discussion um and the comments as well
um you know this helps the chairs gauge
get your opinion on on this matter so um
to that end i just want to run a pole to
see
you know gauge interest in in who thinks
that the working group should work on on
any form of the multi-path problem and a
multi-path extension to quick to resolve
that problem so i'm going to start that
poll now um if
if you think if you agree um
then raise your hand and if you don't
agree then do not raise your hand
and
we're getting a bit short time so i'm
going to close this poll soon um
some results already coming in that look
pretty strongly in favor of um that the
working group should work on this
uh
the results are in the poll tool at the
end but we have 52 raised hands and
three raised hands
um
let's end the session there it it for
anyone that that said that they don't
believe we should work on this uh
do they want to make a comment at the
microphone
no
okay um so in that case we'll do another
poll um
about
adopting this specific draft
um
as the solution to this
problem
again raise your hand if you agree
um that this draft should be adopted and
do not raise hand
if you disagree
okay i'm just gonna
close that poll too again i'll ask the
same question we have two people who
didn't raise their hand compared to 46
people that did
if anyone
didn't raise their hand it disagrees
that we should have dropped this draft
did you want to make a comment at the
microphone
i i don't see anyone um
okay
cool um we'll we'll take this away's
chairs and speak to some people on back
channel um and and do our thing um so
stay tuned on the list um we've got
martin duke um now we we've changed the
agenda mid-session based on some
feedback um and the version negotiation
chat that was uh in david's slides so
well it's going to talk about quick v2
or whatever we might want to call it
hello again everyone uh thanks to lucas
from what was maybe a typo typing this
t-o-o i've decided to like really
embrace that because uh there's a bike
shed about what the version number
should be whether it's actually the
numeral two or not so i'll be very brief
um why is there v2 draft number one
when we talk about greasing the version
number people said we should roll up
with v2 as quickly as we can and this is
that uh number two to exercise versus
negotiation framework as david discussed
and then if there's any fixes we need to
make
some emergency patches to quick this
could be a vehicle for that
um
it's a very simple short and simple
draft it is exactly the same as v1
except for um
the version number and the salt and the
hkdf labels and sort of things you're
supposed to roll for every version there
are a couple of bike sheds about a lpn
and what the version number should be uh
though those were discussed pretty
thoroughly in 111 and nothing's happened
since then so i invite i direct you to
that uh
uh
that the records of that discussion if
you are interested in those in those
questions um so i guess you know i i
think it's about as radio dots as it
ever will be um if people are want to
implement this and and uh
and take it to standard um
we can do that so i'm happy to invite
comments on that
eric
a clarifying question is there any
reason that we'd want to include those
couple of bike sheds because it seems
like that it's kind of a no-brainer to
do the first bullet point which is
basically just let's rev the version
number um are we trying to open up the
scope to a bunch more than that or
is it still
in my view these are fundamental
questions about what happens when you
roll a new version uh that we didn't
really decisively resolve in my view in
shipping 9000 um again i i mean i don't
want to spend a ton of time on it i just
refer you to the
the the question just how do we number
things and and and what is the status of
aopn for new versions
uh we have to sell it one way or the
other
david
and there we go uh
thanks for the presentation martin um
i think it's
not a given that we want to ship a quick
version to with minor changes
um
because like that'll break a lot of
things so for example like sure adding
quick v2 support to my code base is
trivial like you know if we assume it's
a you know version that just has
different salts and whatever um but
if i do that then all of our tests will
have to run with another version and
it's like
like the carbon impact of that is like
more than all around the world which is
just terrifying when i think about it
but more importantly if we deploy this
on our servers it means that now we need
to support these things for longer we
need more versions than alt service and
we can end up with like compatibility
problems uh take for example we still
have middle boxes out there that like to
extract the s and i of quick packets
they will break some people will tell
you that's a feature
some people will tell me to roll back my
change because they consider it a bug so
there is a
what i'm trying to say is there is a
non-zero cost to deploying a quick
version to
and therefore is it the right move to do
a quick version two whose sole purpose
is to be version two or do we wanna take
up some more work and fix some things
that we want to fix as part of that
effort uh but then we open ourselves to
like second system syndrome so just
wanted to put that option out there it's
not free to do to do a version with a
few changes
thanks david i think that's a good point
i mean i would say that greasing i mean
that's kind of the nature of greasing
right is that you're deliberately
breaking little boxes that are
improperly um
making improper assumptions about the
the
packet format but uh fair enough yes
absolutely there's a risk of breakage um
if people adopt this
yeah i mean in this specific case uh i i
don't think if the middle box is
properly parsing quickview one packets
and is making the assumption that it can
only speak the version that was
published rfc when they were code
they're not technically doing anything
wrong
but but yeah thanks
becker
okay
thanks for thinking this through um i
guess i'm softly in favor of this um the
um i think it'd be good i i i know i
might as sort of
shape the little box thing as others
might be but i think it has some value i
think increasing i think that getting
some some experience in the machinery of
negotiation would be helpful since we're
actually going to specify it um i i
would be against making any technical
changes at all um really just on
pragmatic grounds um you know we like
opened up um you know we like we like
opened up 84 46 for the purpose of you
know um for the purpose of like removing
the word master and um and making some
technical and making some editorial
changes and i'm still screwing with it
like nine months later
um and not really a position about any
real changes at all so i think like you
know
like you know we get to publish this
tomorrow more or less as it is um but if
we like um you know but anything of my
traditional clarifications just like you
know
like once you open the patient you just
start to be like it starts to be like
really hard hard to stop right so so to
be absolutely clear i'm i'm also not in
favor of like putting any nice to haves
in here in terms of fixes i was talking
about like actual like discovered
security vulnerabilities and that sort
of thing should they arise yeah yeah and
i think like you know i think i i think
we should put like i think what i would
do and i still failed to do this with
846 is like put like a two month limit
on like call for like things and they
have to be like really clear defense of
some kind or another and then we'll just
like fix them and go um i mean like you
know i mean things like where it's
obvious as back as just like you know
like especially incoherent or it's like
contradicts itself or like it's
obviously wrong um but like i think you
know the idea should be
i think that um that like let me put it
this way you're like it should
absolutely be the case that like modulo
these constants your code in the wire
should not change and if color wires
change then we like them like they're
like we're probably like that's like bad
news right um yeah so that'd be by my
point
thank you
mt
i need to preempt this
uh so i'm also
sort of soft on this i
am maybe a little more supportive than
echo
support uh because i don't see us
shipping the version negotiation stuff
without something like this
and so um i think we should do this um
your discussion previously though uh
made me
think that you would you were doing like
a biz document but it doesn't seem to be
like that in its current form and i
prefer its current form i think what
you've done is is almost perfect for it
so
i
think this is something we should adopt
and
try to get it out at the same time as a
first negotiation draft
thank you brian
hello uh yeah so um everything martin
said and everything ecker said i would
add that i would actually go a little
further than that and request that the
chairs schedule a working group last
call at adoption time
um just to basically say there is an
actual deadline to keep that to keep the
um
uh the temptation to stuff things uh
into your uh
down
i i
um
like agree a bit with david's point we
should consider the cost of doing this i
think that the right way to consider the
cost of doing this is publish a document
experiment
thank you
yeah uh like i i'm very intrigued i'm
i i'm very sympathetic to the sentiment
to just like ship it immediately i do
think we have to work out this aopn
issue uh
uh and just decide what we're going to
do will that take more than will that
take more than two or three months i'm
not saying schedule working group call
to start at adoption i'm saying
at adoption time also go ahead and say
working group class call will start at
this time yeah should it no but you know
we've we've done crazy things before so
will it is a different question yeah
tommy
um
yeah i wanna i'll echo
barton and brian i i think this is good
to adopt i think it's good to do and
the reason i came into the queue just
kind of answer to
david's point about it being expensive
um
i don't think we need to see everyone do
this like we just need enough greasing
that the internet
sees the new version going by right and
um there are
there are places where we could do it
like we have
different stacks like we don't have like
the stack that youtube uses doesn't have
to use this um right now you know we're
using quick uh for a ton of traffic
with our
private relay stuff on apple devices we
could you know like we don't care about
sni there we don't care about any of
this stuff we can just like yeah if it
breaks middle boxes let's figure that
out let's find it out and there are
places that could deploy this
first that are safer than changing
google's main stack
so we can volunteer to do that
thank you uh give it back to the chairs
thanks everyone
well thank you um thank you for the
discussion i think uh we'll go away
based on that feedback probably send an
adoption call to the list um so
encourage people to look out for that
and provide further feedback there um
that gives us some time for our as time
permits bucket um we'd like to go with
the first of those items which is ian to
talk about
accuracy timestamps
or is connor presenting
i mean it's going to be conor m um feel
free to ask questions of me as well but
um he's kind of the expert on this in a
lot of ways
let me
share the slides here
yep europe take it away awesome uh so my
name is connor i uh formerly worked at
google developing congestion control
algorithms for real-time interactive
streaming applications such as cloud
gaming in the form of google stadia and
presenting this work in collaboration
with ian
and we're proposing
a quick extension for reporting fine
grain packet receive timestamp
information meaning the
receiver of the packets tells the sender
when exactly each packet was received
and
is all with the overall goal to offer
richer signals to congestion control
algorithms built on top of quick
for some brief context received
timestamps were supported in the
original g-quick implementation
initially to serve webrtc's goog cc
algorithm which requires it and so here
we're wanting to
kind of evolve and standardize that
concept and also for awareness there's
another timestamp related draft worth
looking at which has a kind of similar
purpose but achieves it by slightly
different means and at a little bit
different granularity
there's quite a bit of existing work on
using received timestamps to improve the
precision of a network measurement and
the foundational intuition behind these
methods
is to
measure when packet ingresses and
egresses
the downstream network path model is a
queue
and then
by observing the variation in that
one-way q-reversal delay
you can better estimate various
properties of the underlying network
state
and notably this doesn't require clock
synchronization between the client and
server because the q traversal time
variation
is measured always
relative to other q traversal times
probably the most widely deployed
application of this concept is in webrtc
congestion control which observes
differences between
packet inter-departure and packet inter
arrival times at a frame level to
estimate some state about the underlying
queue and respond to congestion and
there's also research like path chirp
and associated methods
like packet pair and packet train which
similarly observe these send and receive
time stamps
for multiple temporally coherent packets
to estimate at that network queue state
and my team at google also recently
submitted a paper which we hope to get
accepted and published and share with
you all detailing how we use receive
timestamps for these kind of latency
critical real-time media applications
in in production
so let me skip ahead
at a high level we're suggesting
a new
accuracy timestamp frame type to be sent
in the same manner as a normal act frame
in the place of a normal act frame
and it has all the uh
fields of the normal arc frame but also
includes additional fields to encode
uh receive timestamp information in a
efficient variant based format which
we'd love we'd love feedback on
we've defined
two
transport parameters to negotiate the
the use of this frame the first
specifies the maximum number of receipts
stamps the end point would like to have
reported back to it and so zero here
means i don't want to receive
these packet receipt timestamp reports
and the second parameter is the exponent
precision to use when encoding the
timestamp deltas
much like octal exponent currently does
where you can achieve better efficiency
at some precision cost
so that's the the super short version
and maybe i'll hand it over to ian then
at this point to talk about next steps
yeah i mean i
i
i look at that design and it's it's kind
of a logical design if you want to do
fine grain reporting that you have to
include that in a knack format
now uh the um the reason
the current extension doesn't do that
because my puzzle doesn't do that
is because i got the feedback in the
working group
at the time
that we wanted extension to be
composable
that is that we wanted the extension to
be outside
of the arc format for example
so that you people that use the arc
format can go on using it
but if the extension is present they can
compose
the extension with the arc format
and and that's that's one of the subtle
difference that you mentioned and
whether it should be
basically
let's change the arc frame to have an ac
plus timestamp frame
or whether we should have a timestamp
extension
and
parallel to the arc extension the arc
frame
that was really the big design question
yeah thanks for bringing that up
christian um
so
we kind of talked about this a long time
ago
there are definite advantages to
including it in the frame which is to
say that the congestion controller gets
to consume all the acknowledgement
information simultaneously
which kind of just makes it easier to
write a congestion controller
um but but you're right that
there may be use cases for which
this is less suitable because it is not
composable um
and so
it might depend on the use case i don't
know
for example an example of composition is
using these
as part of the past challenges
[Music]
yeah
and you could also use this i would
think
to get the same information but i guess
but
you would have to add
yeah it will be quite it's not quite the
same
because i mean you are not supposed to
act you are you are supposed to
acknowledge the past challenges etc i
mean it's
i'll have to uh about that
thanks
uh
would you
want to go because we have one man
um thank you um i wanted to ask about
the just a clarification question so if
there's an ack timestamp frame
is it going to follow the same frequency
as the act frequency frame or probably
less than that
and when there's you know compressed axe
when you are acting maybe once per rtt
that probably won't work for real-time
transport so um
yeah just something to consider i guess
um
yeah
right
yeah so clearly the the
real-time congestion controller would
have to decide what frequency of
acknowledgement it needed if you used
active frequency um
and so i assume that it would want to
use a value that's you know more
canonically typical like a quarter of an
rtt half an rtt or less
um
but yes and and
i don't know i i guess i i feel like
this is a tool that a congestion
controller can use to get more
information but um it's you know without
each congestion driller probably needs
to decide like exactly how much
information it really needs and when
so totally valid point
no
okay and is the timestamp the only thing
that is useful for the real-time
condition controller or
are there something like rtcp
what packet loss and other
uh signals are used but they're i think
they're not used for bandwidth
estimation per se um
conor might have more like information
but um i think
probably probably that's a um this was
sent out to the list would you mind
posting there since we have zero minutes
left
okay
i think maybe connor can give you a
longer answer
okay thank you
yeah thanks
john you're zero man
um thanks so uh two quick points
first i would strongly argue for
composing the reason being
that the number of times that you want
to repeat this information is different
for an acknowledgement versus for a time
stamp so a timestamp is advisory
typically and you just need to send it
once even if the
peer does not receive it it's fine but
with an acknowledgement information you
may want to keep repeating the
information so there's a lot of
repetition that happens there which you
can avoid entirely when you're doing
time stamps um so having a separate
frame that conveys that information
would allow you to do that whereas it'll
be tricky if you're trying to put that
into the back frame itself
second
um
the the reason that arc ranges exist in
the act frame is because we can
express
a list of acts as a
range it doesn't make sense to me to
express a timestamp range
uh i'm not quite sure what that means
and what that really is
so i would i would have expected to see
a timestamp per packet that is being
acknowledged because that is really what
wants to receive
yeah that's what the format actually
does um it's just that the range is used
because
um typically packets aren't received in
order and there are not a huge number of
gaps and the range it allows you to
express
uh ranges of timestamps more efficiently
but what is the range what what is the
range of timestamp though that's what
i'm asking what does the timestamp range
look like uh and this is going into the
details but basically it's like
you get timestamps for the next seven
packets
and
um instead of
folks we're like yeah
we should go we should get along but yes
yep we'll do it it's a framing thing not
a not uh haven't distracted what the
data is and what the framing is
separately that's right yeah
so so thanks for your time um we need to
wrap this up now let's keep it short and
sweet uh i'd like to thank everyone for
this meeting and behaving well um thank
you to our scribe and uh watson and our
notetakers jonathan and robin um nico
apologies we can get to you as time
permits um we'll follow that up on that
off off list um we have some chair
actions we need to take we'll speak to
the ads and various people in back
channel so keep your eyes on the mailing
list
that's all i have i don't know if you
want to add anything matt
okay
until until next time same time
different place
maybe different time
goodbye