okay
that's
top of the hour i guess we'll give it a
few more minutes for people to trickle
in but
i guess still i don't know if people
could
should probably start doing the question
if anybody like to
volunteer to take dots
i need to be
um
terribly you know detailed just uh
active items and decisions is really all
we need
and you can use the uh
the notetaking tool which is linked from
the web
from this
conference at the top right
do we have a jabra scribe also
um
i'm not positive we need one in this
context but
somebody wants to volunteer for that
i'll probably be good too
uh something said
great thank you james
james grayson
cursing
yes you don't have to use the
note taking total hedge doc if you don't
want to if you want to take notes
yourself and email them to us that would
be fine too
don't volunteer all at once but
yes
yeah we really do need this
well i guess we can
start calling on people hey jonathan
yeah i guess so
uh bo
can we
call upon your services as a notetaker
sure i can take notes
thanks
moe okay
just a few meeting tips this
session is being recorded
you do need a data tracker login and
hopefully that all worked i know it was
problematic earlier in the week
you can join the session dragon room
jabber room via the meeting agenda
although i'm not sure why you'd need to
please use headphones or an echo
canceling speakerphone and state your
full name
before speaking so that we can get it in
the notes
you enter the queue with a hand raising
tool and
leave with it as well you do need to
enable your auto audio to be heard and
unmute yourself
uh you don't have to enable
video if you don't want to
here's the notewell
a reminder of itf policies
by participating you agree to follow
these policies which are listed below
bcp 9 through 79 please read them and
understand them
in addition uh to the ipr policies we do
have a policy on guidelines for conduct
an anti-harassment policy and procedures
if you're having concerns about observed
behavior please talk to the ombuds team
and we do strive to create an
environment which people are treated
with dignity decency
and respect and we expect you to behave
according to professional standards
and demonstrate appropriate workplace
behavior
so if you believe you've been harassed
or noticed that someone else is being
harassed or have any other concerns
please talk to the ombuds persons
right as jonathan mentioned we have the
notes on the note-taking tool at this
link
the agenda has been posted
and we have the job describe and note
takers
and this is the agenda
do we have any additions or subtractions
or modifications
okay hearing none we will move on
to the draft status why don't you want
to cover this jonathan
yeah it's the only
the only new thing is rc 9134 from the
publishers publications yeah right yeah
i think yeah so uh
jpeg xs has been published so
it would work there
let's see yeah uh vp9 is in the rsd
editor queue it's waiting on
um lrr which is waiting on
uh
frame marking uh we did a pub rack on
cryptex
so that should go through the 80s soon
uh frameworking
as of
about an hour ago this noticed
incorrect we needed
we needed an updated draft because we
decided to change it to experimental
uh
well published that this morning so now
um
i will do the write-up on that and
hopefully that should get done
uh we dropped petra a while ago he
probably dropped this from the draft
status too uh
the next as a next time so if anybody
that's in tetra let us know but
in the meantime
we can ignore that
and um
we
adopted a few drafts
and i'm like to know which one's 79
i'm liking which one 7983 is i'm sorry
that's uh quick multiplexing i'll go
multiplexing right right right yes yes
so but we i think
all our other milestones are going to be
discussed
here today so yeah so vvc is
both adopted and in first working group
last call there were a lot of comments
there from mostly from the vc community
itself so it's great that they're
participating here and
we'll just definitely be talking about
that later
all right so now i'm going to talk
briefly hopefully about recent liaison
statements
we have a request from the w3c web
transport working group and yanivar is
here to talk a little bit about that and
then we have a liaison from iso iec jtc
one sc29 working group three
about green metadata so
uh yanivar
all right can you hear me
we can
hello uh yes i'm yanni barbury from
mozilla i co-chair the w3c web transport
working group
where one of our use cases is
bi-directional real-time audio video
communication
over web transport
which is a
javascript api on top of itf web
transport and quick uh
and the problem we're having there is
uh
when sending
video
uh when a client is sending video to a
server
and the problem is the client does not
have enough information to know what it
can when it can reapply
a multiplicative increase in the media
center rate to recover from prime
congestion
so basically
we can reduce
we can reduce send rate in in the face
of congestion
but we don't know how to rapidly
reapply ascend rate a faster send rate
afterwards
when the congestion goes away
so the request is to know if uh so we're
glad to hear that
this working group is uh
considering rtp over quick and we're
concerned we're
we would like to know if rtp over quick
can satisfy this use case and if so what
measurements
could a browser make available to aj's
client to assist this problem
and would it perhaps require uh
some form of selectable replaceable even
congestion control
and if so which algorithms
thank you
yeah i would i would caution uh yanivar
that uh rtp over web transport or uh is
a little bit different from rtp over
quick so maybe we'll get into that in
the in the session to follow
because it's not as tightly coupled but
so uh
i guess can you raise some of these
issues in the discussion that follows
and we'll try to see where to go from
there does that make sense
okay we'll do
okay
uh the second liaison is from iso iec
jtc one sc29 working compo3 do we have a
representative
to talk about this liaison request
all right let's see um
see what cars see i hope i'm pronouncing
that right in the queue um are you
okay
go ahead
hi uh can you hear me so yes we can
yes i can uh speak on that my colleagues
uh worked on this uh
so
uh if it's okay i can
go through please
uh so this uh
three epic systems and they would like
to point an update on the progress of uh
this standard
2301-11 which is energy efficient media
consumption green metadata uh this has
been uh so 2015 19 first and second
editions and now
the third edition is uh
currently in the committee drafts uh
series status
and just as an overview uh in general
this standard uh provides uh various
type of metadata that enable uh
management of uh there are these four
bullets uh management of decoder power
consumption or display power consumption
and
for offline uh applications or for uh
like adaptive streaming or dash
applications it provides media selection
uh
metadata and also
quality recovery for uh video encoding
uh power consumption so different kind
of metadata are provided in this
specification and recently the third
edition of this standard uh which is uh
which is pointed to in this ls provides
a bunch of new features
uh
for example these three bullets say here
there is now interactive signaling for
remote decoder power reduction that
gives better power reductions
and also vvc sci messages uh for
carrying green metadata uh related to
complexity metrics this has been added
and also we will see
seo
that can also carry uh metrics for
quality recovery after low power
encoding so a bunch of new features have
been added
and uh
hope that this information is of
interest to this group and uh we can
consider uh using this
in this group
uh these different metadata have all a
very different uh shape and form some
are for live applications some are for a
stream adaptive streaming applications
um and some are forward direction from
center to receiver some are from
receiver site to the sender side so my
imagination is that the the metadata
that is to be transferred from receiver
to the center side that's something
especially where you know some container
formats and so on might be of interest
that's my take on it so that was just
like a quick one-minute summary on this
ls and if there are questions i can try
to answer them
i see james
reading through this it looks like
you're targeting bbc is there any
interest in porting this to other
potentially older codecs that are more
used today
this is the third edition that now adds
vbc but already there are metrics for
older codecs available so uh
yes they are already in the previous
editions
okay
stephanie
question
question would be have you any real
world deployment of these previous
editions i mean the stuff is around now
for a few years right
that is uh where i don't have any
complete information if there's anybody
else
i'm also fairly new to this
okay maybe we can take it on reflector
and so on so we can have uh somehow
is there any action required of the abt
core working group
other than discussion on the main list
i mean it seeks some feedback
of interest from from the group so
yeah i mean i think you know if
you know in so far it's i guess there's
not one of the elements is the receiver
to send her feedback so
um i think if somebody is you know
interested in
uh submitting a draft on that i think we
could certainly
you know be
you know interested in them you can take
up with the if the work group wants to
do it but
i think yeah certainly i think any sort
of
uh
receiver
to send our feedback over rtcp
is in scope for this group
so somebody wants to do that work
uh i think there would be interest in
that
i mean assuming there's interested in
the community
that probably should be noted in the
minutes
so i would assume then we could do some
email communication on this on the
lecture
absolutely
all right
okay thank you
uh
next topic is rtp
hold on stefan and colin are in the
queue okay
so just uh just one remark that uh if
if someone were interested in this type
of stuff then uh of course the forward
direction is also something i mean a lot
of this gets
as far as i understand a lot of this can
get piggy packed into the codec
uh
into the codec bit stream using sai
messages and such
but uh it could also be multiplexed uh
by simply creating its own payload
format right and
um that way it may be applicable also to
non-epic standards
so it i mean see
what i want to say is the uh
um
chances to work on that are not limited
to
to uh the return direction yeah that's a
lot
done in this in this area
um
whether it's worth doing it
you know
but we'll see yeah thank you veron
yeah hi um so i wanted to return back to
the the first liaison statement just
briefly talking about uh congestion
control um
and um
it would seem that
um you know the issues of congestion
control coming up in a bunch of
different groups
and and the media of a quick side
meeting was talking about this and uh
it's come up in a bunch of different
places
uh and certainly for um congestion
control for rtp
udp i know we had the the rmcat group uh
which tried to do a bunch of algorithms
um
and i'm not sure those algorithms
directly apply to quick so i'm not
suggesting we take the work there but
i'm i was wondering if uh we should
maybe have a broader conversation about
where we do
media congestion control over quick and
whether that's of rtp specific or a more
general conversation
so
maybe we should bring it with the ads at
some point
yeah
well i think the presentation to follow
uh colin will directly
uh bear on that question so maybe we can
we can talk about it uh during the
presentation or in the q a show
sure i think it's more general than um
rtp over quick quick yeah
anyone else in the queue
no that's it seems to be up so it's okay
you wanted
all right so uh we're now going to hand
it over
to the rtp over quick team
yeah hi can you hear me
yes
cool uh yeah thanks for inviting us to
present here again today um in july we
already presented the mapping of rtp
onto quick draft and today we would like
to go a bit more into detail on
congestion control for rtp over quick on
the next slide
i'd like to start with a
short overview on the context of the
draft
there are actually two similar drafts
the other one is from sam hurst from bbc
research and development and both drafts
provide a basic encapsulation for
rtp and rtpc rtcp over quick
both of the drafts use the unreliable
datagram extension with the flow
identifier to demultiplex
different rtp sessions
and our draft focuses a bit more on
congestion control and the interface
requirements for
quick implementations and condition
controlling
and yeah both drafts use sdp for
signaling
um harold did you have a question
or are you just getting in the queue to
talk
i couldn't figure out why he won't
wanted to
to carry
a multiple rtp sessions or one quick
session
and this might be obvious to someone but
it doesn't seem to be in the draft
and it's
it's a few bites of tax
that i would like to avoid if we don't
need it
uh sorry i'm not sure understand this
question
you have a you put the flow idea into
the
into the
into the session
and what do you what you to d multiplex
rtp sessions what do you need to do to
demultiplex rtp sessions
um okay yeah uh that is because in udp
um one would
probably typically use different udp
ports and do different rtp sessions over
different udp ports and identify them by
that
and in quick we can
have the itp sessions in one connection
and then try to
[Music]
use all of the information we have
available in that one connection to you
use for different rtp sessions at the
same time like for example the
congestion control information
i was trying to find i was trying to
figure out the use case where i would
want to have multiple rtp sessions on
between the same entities and i couldn't
find one
so
uh
so i was wondering whether it's
it's
reasonable to drop this requirement and
just say
if you if you need more rtp sessions set
up more quickly quick connections
yep um maybe i'll
take that and
we can expand that on the draft
and explain it further
especially explain the need for it
yeah
con
yeah i mean there was a comment in the
chat about not understanding what rtp
session meant in this context i mean you
know rtp session has a very well defined
meaning in in the rtp spec and we need
to make sure that that what's meant here
is
uh consistent with that meaning and it's
not just being used as a as an
alternative to the ssrc for example for
demonstrating users
um so i think there's a perhaps a deeper
conversation about sessions and
demultiplexing that should happen at
some point
okay then maybe i continue with the
presentation on congestion controlling
first and we keep that on a later
discussion
um
yeah so today we want to focus on the
congestion controlling and um
we
identified a couple of questions which
come up when we do rtp over quick
and first is that um
we have congestion control in quick and
rtp
and quick suggestion to use an algorithm
similar to neurano
uh it does not meditate mandate any
congestion control algorithm and rather
provides a set of connection statistics
that can be used by any congestion
controller and other algorithms than the
arena are currently under investigation
and rtp also provides its own congestion
control
using explicit transition controls
signaling in rtcp
for example there's
rc8888 which provides a feedback format
that can be used for algorithms
for example firearms like scream and
nada and also gcc as proposed by
the rmcud group
um now the two main questions we try to
investigate in our experimentations are
first
how can we do con gesture control for
return media
on top of quick which already has its
own congestion control on another level
and then the second is if we can reduce
rtcp overhead
due to duplicate signaling of
congestion stick living in quick and
rtcp
next slide please
so we did
experiments with a couple of different
options we could use for congestion
control
the first one is that we tried to
relieve congestion control entirely to
quick and only do some trivial rate
adaption in our media application
we will leave that out today because
it's um
we already know that it's probably
better to have a um
congestion control algorithm which is
specified for real time and we would
rather look at these today
the next option is that we disabled
quick internal congestion control and we
only use the real-time congestion
controller like we would use for example
over udp like the algorithms from our
cut
in our experiments we use screen because
the
existing implementation for screen was
quite easy to integrate in our setup
and then in the last um
[Music]
combination we used scream and neurano
together
and
on the next slide i have a
couple of notes on how to reduce rtcp
feedback
um
we would like to use the quick
connection stats which are already
available in the transport protocol to
reduce the rtcp overhead
and in quick we have the datagram draft
which allows an implementation to expose
the datagram acknowledgments to the
application
and we're using this to identify which
rtp packets have arrived at the receiver
um we keep track of the send rtp packets
and in which datagrams they were sent
and at what time they were sent so we
have the timestamp and as soon as an
acknowledgement arrives we know that
this rtp packet has been received
and then we also use the rtt samples
provided by the quick connection
statistics
to
infer a receive timestamp at which the
packet arrived at the receiver by just
adding half of the rtt
the last known rtt to the same timestamp
we kept track of earlier
uh the next slide i have a short
overview of our test implementation
um we integrated
quick go with g streamer and the screen
implementation
um
the
application transmit video data in rtp
packets from one sender to a receiver
um using g streamer to encode and
packetize rtp packets which are then
prepended with the flow identifier we
talked about earlier and sent to the
receiver
um the receiver takes the
um
rtp packet and identifies the itp
session and
forwards the data from the package to
the corresponding rg streamer pipeline
and
then we use a slightly modified version
of quick go to be able to selectively
disable new venue in our experiments and
also to
expose the connection statistics and the
datagram acknowledgements
uh we build a testbed setup on the next
slide please
yes i had a question about the
uh
the time stamp feedback
um from
from what i understand the the purpose
of that in rtcp
is for congestion controls to understand
the one-way delay
to understand variance in one-way delay
and those delay-sensitive algorithms
um can use that high-fidelity
one-way delay inferencing
from that but if you're basing if you're
trying to synthesize that using round
trip times it seems like you've lost the
one-way delay aspect of that which may
be important for some of those
uh
uh some of those congestion control
algorithms
uh yeah i think we will get back to that
in a later slide on the results for this
inferring
and there are drafts um or quite recent
drafts which also try to use the um
receive time stamps directly in
acknowledgements i will reference that
later
yeah next slide please
so we have a test pad set up in which we
run both of the applications in separate
containers on the same host
and we use
the virtual network interfaces in the
containers to
simulate different network conditions
we configured a bandwidth limit of one
megabit per second and we run
the experiments with different one-way
delays and
after 60 seconds of a video run
for video transmission we reduce the
available link capacity to 500 kilobits
per second to see how the algorithms and
the transport react to this
and then our application locks incoming
and outgoing rtp and rtcp packets for
analyzers afterwards and
will to calculate psnr and sm statistics
on the raw video files
uh next slide please
so the first results for
um screen using rtp over
for rtp over quick using stream screen
and comparing this to udp
the left graph shows the quick
implementation and the right one udp and
we can see that the results are quite
similar so it seems to be possible to to
use um
quick data grams to transmit rtp and
we can also see that the
target bit rate of the screen condition
control are slightly below the one in
udp
we're not exactly sure why yet maybe due
to some overhead but we need to
investigate that
further on the next slide
so please hold on
the screen plus quick is just the quick
congestion control replaced by screen
right
yes
okay
uh then on the next slide we
um
leave the quick congestion controller
enabled and we congestion control the
real-time traffic by screen before we
put it too quick
so everything um
goes through the both combustion
controllers and we see that in the first
part of the video transmission
it seems to behave very similar to the
previous slide um
but that probably is due to application
limited transmission so
as long as screen is
sending less data than urinal would
[Music]
then we
are in this
application limited state where um
neurano doesn't really do much yet
but as soon as then the link capacity is
reduced to 500 kilobits per second for
30 seconds we see that both congestion
controllers
try to
adapt to the new link capacity and the
the screen target bitrate drops to
almost zero and the ramp up also does
not happen um
at all in the case of a one millisecond
delay it may be that that happens much
later if we looked into it for a longer
time but this is already not really
usable so we didn't investigate that
further
and in the second case our
one-way delay was 15 milliseconds
it seems to be ramping up but also only
much later after the target spirit rate
already dropped to zero
earlier
then on the next slide we
show some results for
trying to reduce rtcp overhead
on the left side we see the results with
rtp over quick using rtcp feedback and
on the right side rgb over quick using
only the inferred feedback i described
earlier
um
we
can see that the
[Music]
the top two experiments looks pretty
similar so it seems to be possible in
general too
um use the quick statistics for rtcp
feedback but we also see that in the
later experiments especially in the 150
milliseconds one way delay the ramp up
in the beginning um works much
slower or starts much slower
and
we
in our experiments we generate the
feedback at a fixed interval and we
think that the
instability in the last experiments
are due to this fixed generation of
feedback which may lead to
some acknowledgements from quick
arriving after
we generate the next feedback even
though the rtp packet has already been
received by the receiver and
due to the delayed and aggregate x they
only arrive a little bit too late at our
sender so that some feedback is not
included which leads to
feedback which would be less precise
than the one rtcp could provide
there are probably
two drafts which could
improve the situation because there's
one draft for
quick timestamps which would give us
timestamps for um
which would help us to
estimate the one-way delay as we already
talked about earlier and then there's a
very recent draft which gives timestamps
for
received packets and that would also
help to
improve the
generated feedback because we then
didn't have wouldn't have to use the
latest rtt samples anymore and instead
we could just use the feedback which is
directly on what we need from quick
instead of inferring it from the
feedback which is already present and
quick now
um then we have one more slide on
prioritization
we run all the experiments again with
the
second
stream opened and quick this time not
datagrams but the real quick stream
which sends constant data
and um
in this case we see that the um
[Music]
application probably needs some
prioritization between real-time data in
quick data grams and background traffic
within the same connection
as
in our experiments we see that the
target bitrate
quickly degrades and it might even
starve
[Music]
because of the background data
and uh yeah there's done probably some
better scheduling of prioritization
necessary
um
but this is also very artificial setup
in our experiments because we really
send a lot of background data and there
are probably
um
better experiments needed with more
natural forms of background traffic like
on-off http request or something like
that instead of constant sending
data
yep then on the last slide i come to the
conclusion
i think there are many three results we
have here so the first one is that it's
probably problematic to run two separate
congestion control loops at the same
time um like
a real-time congestion control algorithm
like screen
for the real-time data and um something
like neurino and quick at the same time
for all of the outgoing
data on the connection
um and the second is that it's probably
possible to use grid
state information to reduce rtcp
feedback
but that could probably also profit from
some optimizations which would be
provided by the
receive timestamp draft or
something similar which would give more
detailed information than just the rtt
and using this rtt for the
debating pro
and then the last point is that
some prioritization is necessary
as we've seen on the last slide
uh yeah in the future we plan to do some
more experiments on
different congestion control algorithms
and different forms of computing traffic
and different network topologies
and we would also like to um
try to find some way to do better
prioritization than no prioritization at
all to see how we can use one quick
connection for
real-time data and non-return data at
the same time
posted in the queue
hey can you hear me
yep yeah
yeah
this is this is really good work uh i'm
glad to see this kind of moving forward
uh i guess i have three points here that
i think are it would be good for us to
try to limit scope um here
uh one would be you know is there
anything besides receive time spawn we
need to have the same information that
rtp or what we had here as
udp
would have
because if i think if we get there then
we can feel pretty confident that
we have everything at a protocol level
you need to do a good real-time
congestion control
second thing is that uh
you know i think trying to prioritize
real-time and non-real time right now uh
might be i think a lot uh and
we might just say open a different quick
connection
or
non-real-time stuff because that's how
it works today
uh and that's that that's where we stop
but that might be a good milestone of
saying that we just
basically replaced the entire congestion
controller if we do rpp flows today and
get that working over quick and i think
that would be a pretty good
accomplishment
and then last
one thing we haven't really talked about
here
is sort of overhead
of um how many more bytes are we putting
on the wire for each rtb packet you know
and where are we sending redundant rtc
feedback and it'll be good to sort of
dive into that and see you know what
those numbers are and then we start
thinking about is there anything that
can be done to mitigate that
yeah i i i think i agree with all of the
points you say
um
yeah
uh sergio
seriously i don't hear you
seriously i'll see if you can figure out
your audio in anytime soon us
i'm not hearing so fast either
oh
i'm here
yeah now here yes yes i do
okay so i just wanted to echo on some
point and make an observation what
justin made and also clarification
question is uh
what's the main specific reason why uh
rtp
uh was considered for this investigation
is that was it was a reason because
some some sense of interoperability with
existing rpg stacks or or or uh was that
a protocol of choice to pick i just want
to understand the
context behind that
can you hear me now
yes
okay it's stupid
see i had the the headset muted even i
spoke okay
so um i think let's
let mathis respond to us first
sorry i'm not sure i understand the
question was a bit hard to understand
i'm sorry
yeah that
that first is even that's i think that
this is awesome work and if you have the
goal there to replicate the results and
maybe this on our own
uh yeah we have we have the code um it
is on github but it's not pro probably
documented right now but we plan to do
that soon
yeah i i was also interested in how to
replicate the the network application i
think like that so because the code is
typically available but the the
how how to replicate the asphalt test is
could be interesting as well
yeah we can share that differently
okay and the second thing is that i
think that
one thing that it is also related to the
web transport thing is that this kind of
test seems to be very
focused on what a native application can
do by modifying or adding integrating
deeply with the quick stack
or providing or
[Music]
but in if we are using web transfer
and i think that we have to consider
also what will happen if the
if the downward destination is going to
be ruined in javascript because probably
the the browser will not provide a
de facto bandwidth estimation
for the application level
uh how can we
make this work when the the
application that it is using the quick
stack is untrusted for example
we are going to replace the the rtcp
feedback
from
from this quick feedback uh how this
will be exposed to the application
because i think that they will impact
quite a lot what we will be able to do
with west transport
um yeah i think
this is
very much focused on our native
application right now which we built for
testing
and there will probably
be a need for more broader discussion on
api things in the future
yeah because for example i doubt that we
can just disable the
the quick confession control and let the
application
[Music]
run on javascript
just do
behave properly
so we will have to find a way of trying
to have both working simultaneously you
know
i think that it was sometime proposed
that have some good breakers in case the
the bandwidth estimation done by the
application is to is not behaving
properly or things like that
but but anyway i think that it is a very
great work that you have done so far and
just hope to be able to improve it
thanks
i guess bernard you're next up that's
going to do it
uh i guess i had uh
wanted to focus on some of the questions
yanivar asked
which is
i guess your paper has the different
metrics that you've
been using
and i guess most of those are probably
exposable in web transport
including that the time stamp info i
guess the one thing that wouldn't
potentially be exposable is the detailed
act data
because um in a browser basically you
can't assume that
that the acts reflect the application
uh what it got but maybe uh
uh the the timestamp uh and other info
from the acts
uh could be could be provided up
i guess uh
and and originally in web transport we
did have the concept of uh adding a
congestion control selector to the
constructor and i guess to justin's
point that would be on a quick
connection level
um so i guess
one thing to think about would be if you
had
separate quick connections instead of
the prioritization thing operating with
different congestion control algorithms
um what the behavior might be there
uh and also web transport does have uh
prioritization built in but it's
probably of the kind that your research
shows is going to be problematic
uh which is basically right now the
datagrams get get uh absolute priority
um so they will starve out the uh the
reliable streams
um yeah i think we could do more
experiments on that in web transport
especially under prioritization and
i agree that it might be hard to
expose all of the data we use in our
experiments yet
yep
okay thank you
spencer
i wanted to thank you for uh bringing
this work uh
forward and thank the chairs for bring
this uh oregon
navy avt core
the
question i probably have or the suggest
i have is
uh
this draft did not actually flag avt
core in the file name and i've been
having some conversations on the media
of a quick
mailing list which is only available
uh
about about another draft that's
relevant here that doesn't have avt core
in the name
it was focused on
uh
the svp for uh
or keeping over quick
but uh
recognizing that that was going to have
know a lot of
uh a lot was going to have to reflect a
lot of discussions about
uh
what
rtp over quick was actually going to
look like uh
or we
for the chairs are you are we to the
point where we should be putting mvt
core the in the draft beams we get more
visibility within the group here
um
[Music]
i mean i don't know is the short answer
i mean because i mean we don't know if
this is ultimately going to end up in
avt core i mean visibility is good i
understand that yeah i'm thinking mostly
from the standpoint of making sure the
right people are looking at it
um
you all can think about that and yeah
yeah sure
the the discussions we've been having
for
uh my draft in this space and uh the
over in the mock mailing list are i
think they're definitely ready uh to
move into
uh
abc core or a group like that rather
than kind of an ad hoc overall media
over a quick discussion yeah i mean
insofar as things are you know rtp is
feel free to tire them at abd card it's
you know it doesn't hurt anything
thank you thank you so much yeah
uh bernadette
remembers a lot
yeah hi um so i mean there's a bunch of
discussion in the chat about short-term
and long-term approaches and i think
that's important i think
we should make sure we have that broader
architectural conversation about where
we want to go rather than necessarily
just
sleepwalking into into reusing our tp
here
um the the the actual reason i i got up
to the mic was um you know the comments
about using separate connections to
avoid having the the congestion control
prioritization discussion uh i mean
separate connections causes quite a lot
of pain in in the current model um and
um
[Music]
we we should uh have it have a
deliberate discussion about whether we
we think that's acceptable pain or
whether we want to
make conscious effort to reduce that and
try to make everything run over a single
connection even if it means more
congestion control and prioritization
work
okay james
uh thank you thank you for doing this
work uh the question that i have is
you've only looked at doing this in the
uni-directional flow right this is just
a sender of one sender one with the one
flow of media correct
yes true
cool in our experimentations it is
probably possible to build something
else with the draft but that's what we
experimented with yeah
cool i think that when we
get sort of tagging on from uh colin's
last remark around
connections and and just various
thoughts are how
multiplexing might be dealt with in this
space
bi-directional
of flows of media should also be
considered as well
um
we've had an awful lot of discussions
earlier this week in the media of the
moq side meeting and in other sort of
forums
around those use cases and
i think that there may be and this is a
hand wave uh
potential issues when it comes to uh
complex competition between congestion
control depending on which way
we tackle the conductivity and
multiplexing of the sessions
uh yeah that's probably true
we were planning to
or our current test sub setup is kind of
inspired by the test cases evaluation
for congestion control from rmcat but
they don't completely implement all of
it
um and yeah as i said we would like to
do more experimentations with that and
then we should probably also include
bi-directional streams there
justin
uh so i just wanted to add on to
comments point uh where he sort of
mentioned that well maybe we should take
on
uh you know prioritization
know i think that's for any uh specific
work in this area we probably want to
have a good sense of what our goals are
uh you know what would count enough will
we count as like a reasonable v1
uh
what what things do we think we have to
do
uh
i think this author has shown
you can get you know some results uh
even just now just by sort of
encapsulating rtp within quite datagram
but what would be necessary for us to
kind of consider is something that we
want people to play on
whether it's overhead whether it's
packet rate optimization
uh you know this is still an early draft
so this is fine where it is right now
but as this moves forward i think kind
of lining up as a
working group what do we think that you
know they should be trying to solve
i think would help us all kind of get to
a shared picture of where we want to end
up
uh yep
fully agree with all of that
okay and we're
kind of over time but this is dairy with
a lot of interest so i figured we would
let us go
over but thank you all and i guess
discussion
um probably on the abt
list um or the mock list or both
uh probably if you're interested should
be subscribed to both but hopefully we
can try to converge on where we're
having the discussion
um and yes then did the authors please
continue your experiments it's very
helpful
uh sergio
so
please this
yeah we have
hold hold on one second spencer are you
trying to do something with slides or
no you're okay
okay go ahead
yeah and then we have released
what are you trying to say something
no okay i don't know
okay sorry sorry
okay so we have been i put a new draft
for greatness that it is
does to clarification one was the
authentication after encryption
and also how the
what the they mean what's the minute of
the crisis attribute when it is present
with with with bundle
it does not change the
anything
on the draft it's just clarification say
that were needed because it was not
clear at the moment
and regarding the implementation status
we still have only two implementations
currently one is
done by you jonathan and that in the etc
and
the the request that i have for leave
srtp that it is not yet merc but i hope
that it will be soon
and we hear the
uh we have it has been requested for
publication and
we are already also
trying to have a an issue open for for
adding the api for enable and disable it
in webrtc
so
i think that that's all and i think that
there is nothing
for the the review but
we will just
need to do the review but i think that
there is nothing
pending to to be done in in the current
draft
there one more side
okay
all right yes i think that's in good
shape and it's in the hands of our a.d
now so
hopefully that will get moving quickly
uh
and
stefan are you presenting
yes
yeah hi um
no this is uh uh the two payload
formulas for the evc will be a quick
thing next please
thank you um
so we had a working group last call a
few weeks ago
a few months ago actually and uh we got
comments uh from
from this guy from henry and they were
all in all
the the the the
activity
on the mailing list in response to this
working group class called was quite
active uh we had more than 30 emails
there
um
and
the comments were also quite extensive
and uh but over the time
i think
we got to a good understanding of what
the commenters were
asking and i think we addressed most
of them
in this version number 12 which was
posted
just before the deadline
and
uh we have remembered the revision
number 13 in the
in the works um that is currently
uh reviewed by the authors where miska
actually uh put in
uh some additional text uh related to
the remaining issue somewhere deep down
in the alpha answer
um
and that's
i mean i i i can promise it for uh
pretty quickly
um
what's a little bit concerning to me is
that uh our usual suspects here on this
uh in this work group uh didn't comment
at all yeah except belmont
and um but i would
guess that uh
that's perhaps because all these uh
payload formats for
for um null unit based codecs are so
similar nowadays that
that
perhaps most of the bugs have been
ironed out
much earlier but
i
really it it would be good if people
could take one more look at it at some
point
now
i i think the real test will come
when the thing goes out to publication
request and
all these uh
security guys come out of the woods and
and talk about
the newest trend uh that they want to
see in the security sections
uh and similar maybe the congestion
control guys i don't know so um
yeah and well so what we will be doing
is we'll publish one more
uh revision
of the bbc draft
uh pretty soon
i gave you a target date mid of the
month but we will do that earlier i
think
probably as soon as later today
and then
we suggest that maybe another working
group last call is adequate since the
text changes are
not insubstantial
although they are deep down in the
details
where
where the bbc codec maps to the offer
answer mostly
and
then i think we're ready for
after that working plus call for
publication request
um
next slide please
thanks bernard now
this was an issue that's more a generic
uh question
uh
that
was triggered by the banner by a comment
from belmod
where he said there are no complete
examples of the stp of our answer
negotiation
in the draft that was in in the context
i think mostly of the scalability
uh
related
rather complex of answers scenarios that
this draft would allow
um
and
that raises a little bit the
philosophical question of uh what good
do examples do
yeah the um so one thing that i've seen
rather consistently
in implementations by people who are not
say
regular participants of this group is
that they take code snippets from the
uh
from the
um drafts or at least
you know the examples were biting from
the drafts
hack a little bit around them
for the special needs they may have and
think that they have uh
something that ought to work with other
people's um
implementation and typically it does not
very often it does not and
the
the reason for that is i think that
people
uh uh simply take the examples as
shortcuts
of for
um
you know for for the way how things are
to be done
and don't really get a full
understanding of what's going on
um
we had this discussion before a few
years ago uh or decades ago or so um
and in uh
for the hvc payload there we later on
decided not to go for full examples and
i just want to
kind of reconfirm that that's the right
thing to do
um
i mean we we can add more examples if we
absolutely need to
but
for the reasons i stated we are
it's not laziness it's really it's it's
more
um
you know i
i think examples teach you way too much
from uh from
the
the complexity of the problems uh that
are hidden in those
uh in those um
of our answer uh cap exchange uh
options that we have in those drafts
so what i asked this question on the
mailing list there was no response um
what do people think
um
yeah uh thanks stefan
i guess what i was responding to in part
is some of the issues we've seen uh with
implementations and figuring out what
they do
there's a pretty widespread problem now
with people inventing their own
very different implementations of hevc
for example
i had an instance where it was
integrated with webrtc and nobody could
figure out what it was doing
and i know that's not the fault of the
draft because it probably didn't also
implement the payload format either
[Music]
but uh
yeah it just
um i understand your point uh
that
but you know translating these things
into actual implementations
uh has just it has been problematic
because people pick and choose things
and
you never know what they're going to do
until you actually look at it
i completely agree
i think
the
the disagreement if there is any i don't
know the disagreement is what the cure
to this problem is
right i think fever is not to
to put oversimplified examples in a
draft
that will be copy pasted
in that may be known as correct but may
may not be known as applicable for the
particular problem that people have and
that people
go away from you know frankly from
from from specs
for something as comparatively simple as
a payload format when you compare it to
the video codec that's
i mean that's
people take shortcuts they do it all the
time right so yeah unfortunately i'm not
running a standards police otherwise i
could i could do something about it but
i don't
yeah
so
okay let me put this as the proposal or
let me put that not as a question but as
a statement so unless people speak up
pretty darn soon uh
right now
but they want to see more detailed
examples
we are not going to add more examples
and we will be
uh we will be
referring to this discussion if we come
out of the woods later for more examples
yeah i don't think you need
examples to spoon feed people um i don't
think that's necessary but in your view
do you think that the current examples
give the high order bit
of of what um
what the
important part most important parts of
the draft we're trying to convey in
their stp i think that's the useful part
because there's usually a lot of text
and it's usually um you know
drafts that have uh
many parameters and and many rules
um on all the parameters it's it's hard
to lose it's easy to lose high order bit
of functional negotiation
in all of the different nuances of of
the parameters so do you feel like
you've captured
just the high order bits and not
all the full complete
negotiations so okay i i think i think
we are we're good enough um if you take
this and and a little bit of say
common understanding of how of irons are
supposed to work uh we we are good for
the relatively
simple use cases say no scalability
once complex stuff comes into the
picture
people have to dig in people have to
understand that you know because if you
if you if you
if you just try to create recreate a
scalability model without understanding
uh
the the vvc scalability mechanism which
are not that easy to to block right
and that
that
five percent of additional complexity
that's being added by the payload format
if if you don't have an if you don't
have an a good picture of that and just
naively starts implementing then
then you will arrive at something that
just doesn't work so the the uh but for
the for the relatively simple use cases
if you're using uh say
say no scalability or temporal
scalability only you should be fine
then i think it's appropriate to not
include
detailed examples of all the possible
subtleties
implementers should know those
subtleties and know the stp for them
okay
good uh thanks i think that's all i had
on the vvc thing so that's on track um
next slide please
so jumping over to evc uh that's a
really short one
um next slide
we haven't uh wrapped the uh uh or one
working group draft
this
this tradition of keeper life drafts uh
i i consider
you know this is this is just not not a
good thing so unless uh you chairs tell
me that we should
uh run keep a live keeper live drafts uh
um for bookkeeping purposes or something
like that uh we're not going to do it
however the draft is still on our
on our internal agenda and we are
committed to to deal with that
however the the way we want to do that
and that was i think greed
in last summer
is we'll deal with it
once we have
learned the lessons and that's
especially the lessons i'm expecting on
the security side
uh during uh the idf last call so in
other words what we suggest to do is uh
we will produce version two
after we
got
the bbc draft through the last call
and then we'll be ready very very
quickly uh with working group glass curl
of the ebc draft
the alternative would be keeper lives if
you choose uh if you do that i think
that's that's that sounds reasonable to
me i think
which one
sorry the the no no don't keep the live
needed
sorry
just okay
okay that's basically
the other question i had is you so when
you're saying security do you think
there'll be sufficient
you know
specific security issues that might come
up due to something like bbc or just
no no if if there were if there were
specific security issues that i'm
i think that would come up we would have
proactively addressed them
this is this is just uh doing payload
formats for the last 20 years something
always comes up from that crowd so uh
i mean if i would be very pleasantly
surprised if this time nothing comes up
but
something always comes up so
uh and there's always a need to add a
sentence or to
to the security
uh consideration question and frankly in
in the past that was also the truth for
the congestion control
i think this time congestion control is
probably not the big issue anymore
because those people are
watching video payload formats generally
nowadays
but
on the security side it's just
i'm just expecting it without knowing
what it may be
okay
okay thank you very much
see mike faller in the queue uh
annular mike which are your branding
with uh general dynamics i was gonna
have mike do our presentation for us
okay
protect and i'll be certainly here for
questions
as we go along
sounds good
hello can you hear me
yes
okay um
i've been listening to the the
conversations of the others and i'll
i'll augment the presentation based on
some of what i've heard
um
but as far as i know the organization we
are supporting is is new or somewhat new
to the ietf
so i provided a couple slides that
discuss our background
for the draft rfc that was submitted
the particular protocol we support is
called skip skirt communications
interoperability pro call it began in
1994.
i was around for the birth of that
as a combined
department of defense and vendor working
group
the working group was called
interoperably controlled working group
um
this
while the skip protocol began in 1994
there were predecessors to it
we go back to the pstn
days of early communications that the
dod would do over pstns and then into is
the end and migrated into ip
all handled with a
with a community of interest if you want
to call it that
and the community was mostly confined in
the u.s uh for a large part of this but
the goal of this group was to develop
the next generation interoperability
security protocol supporting the us
government and the military
interests later around 2001 to include
nato and nato partners and the name
changed to the skip working group
the skip working group is a functional
standards making test
um
community that meets
one or two times a year depending upon
the needs
we have separate
action items to do we have
demonstrations to provide
we are a functioning body that's been
around them for a while
next slide
one of the problems that's come up is
about the skip information access and
awareness
the skip standards are currently
available to participating government
military communities and select
oems of network equipment and call
management servers that support skip
government business entities must
request access to relevant information
and access to skip standards is based
upon a need to need to know
now devices that implement skip
standards transparently operate over
digital carriers
skip is an application layer
protocol it doesn't function down in the
network layer
the devices
[Music]
most commercial network and security
community personnel are not aware of
skip and this can result in a skip sub
media type skip being removed from the
sdp
of a standard sip message
so the lack of awareness among the
network and security community has
become a larger issue as the use of skip
grows over more commercial carriers and
as network security devices become more
restrictive of unknown media
as a side story to that
my first exposure to to
network security was way back in the
early cisco days of
building a firewall based on ip
addresses
i think we can all agree it's progressed
a lot since then as to what the security
appliances do to your network
so
we
we have come across issues next slide
please
we have come across issues where the sd
stp doesn't contain the transport that
we need
so the draft rfc submitted the ietf is
designed to provide information to
network equipment oems network
administrators security personnel and to
help skip succeed of the commercial
networks
because skip relies on
commercial equipment within the network
infrastructure to operate and as it's
become security policies have changed
devices have changed from being
where you go in and decide what you're
going to not let into your network now
they are more like they're going to deny
all and you have to tell them what you
want into your network and when that
telling gets all the way down into the
contents of the stp
skip can have a problem
so the skip rfc enables network
equipment and manufacturers to provide
an equipment configuration that supports
uh skip as a as a media subtype
so that the network administrators
network security personnel can define
and implement compatible network policy
which permits the skip media subtype to
reverse the network
what the skip
media subtype provides is end-to-end bit
integrity no transcoding on the channel
and in treatment as if the the data is
clear channel data
and there is actually a precedence to us
within the rfc standards of rfc 4040 and
we referenced that in the in the draft
submitted
rfc 4040
while it is a gateway protocol it is it
is meant to take iep traffic and
an isdn bri
network
64k udi channel
and build a
end-to-end bit integrity network for the
users to use whatever they want so rfc
4040 develops a clear channel
it just happens to transverse uh
go from ip to isdn 64k udi
so skip is to be treated like that
on a pure ip network
next slide
there are two sub media types that have
been registered with iana as rtp payload
format media types audio skip and video
skip
this rfc is needed to provide additional
information for those media subtypes
where we include the media type
description
the
payload format rtp header fields payload
format parameters and the stp
declaration as a mapping to the sdp
and provides mapping examples what
you'll see on the next slide i believe
next
slide this is the contents of the stp
declaration to support a skip session
i kind of uh like mo's comment of of
high order bits
this is just simply what will be
included in a sip invite of what would
maybe a normal video call with different
codecs listed
so the skip devices are presently
deployed in the u.s and nato tactical
networks
and many national networks in some
commercial networks using that following
sdp media and submedia type
we have deployed products and have had
for over a decade
using these protocols so the secure
session can be used as audio skip video
skip or both and the mapping is shown
there
presently there
i think within the uh
the global community my knowledge is is
that there are probably about
eight nine nations producing products
using these protocols
next slide
so in summary here's here's our
actual issues have occurred because oems
and network equipment
networks administrators and security
personnel are unaware of skip and sdp
contents necessary to establish scare
session
that unawareness is partially tied to
the fact that this
that the body of uh community that this
serves is one that has a as an already
standing community already has expanding
set of standards in which to operate to
do this
so it operating in that environment
is is one that produces the fact that
while we're defining the end products
but we don't have any way to let the
people in the middle know what we do
so the draft rfc increases the etf
awareness of the skip working group in
its efforts to achieve international
interoperability
actually we'd probably welcome some
involvement of the ietf community if
they choose to participate in our
sessions
the purpose of the rfc is to provide
global access to information necessary
to support skip
and a reference to the rfc provides
context in a single reference point for
the newly defined iana media subtypes
audio skip and video skip
so
we have to look at our problem as not
just being
the end products having interoperability
because everyone else who carries
traffic is responsible for defining
what's on the network is responsible for
building equipment that implements
security plans
they need the knowledge to know how to
do that
it even goes down as far as the
procurement people
if i
as a network designer want to
support this protocol on my network
how do i reference that to a procurement
rep so that they can then write a
a
request for quote to vendors saying this
is what your product needs to support
so
as in the last bullet
the rfc provides information about skip
and the skip working group community
system network architects dr
administrators security personnel oems
risk analyst procurement personnel
necessary for skip to be included in the
system security life cycle
so that's pretty much it in in a
nutshell
um
i can respond to questions
i'm not hearing anything
um basically you said that the actual
content of the skip is
on a is need to know which is just a
um some form of classification right
um it's not
the the
it's basically building a a channel by
which the end devices will negotiate
what they're going to do they're going
to negotiate applications they're going
to negotiate security parameters
so its format itself is not as clearly
defined as if you were
carrying a movie traffic or 729 or
something like that
so basically this is just establishing a
channel over
you know a
you know it's an
opaque application channel over
over the art existing rtb fashion then
you need to integrate this with
you know things that use the ip
telephony that what you're saying yes
okay
yeah
and it has been done in some devices
when we've had direct interaction with
vendors we've been able to
especially those that are aware of the
type of work we do
they're saying oh okay so this is just
kind of the next generation of what was
in the previous in the previous in the
pstn world we'd be talking to telcos
about
what they need to do on their network
but
there is no real telco anymore
yeah so my question is what is the what
can the abt core working group do for
you
so are you
i guess the document is an informational
rfc are you looking for it to be working
with less cold or
what's the ask from us
um
here's here's we have to express some
ignorance of your of how the ifc works
so
um
for for our purposes we we look at this
as
uh
the the adoption of this draft rfc
is not the end of the game um we have
much more work to do because an rfc
doesn't mean anyone's going to implement
anything
into their product it takes work beyond
that but an available global reference
is a big start
i would ask buber what do you
where would something like this go
because it is
in the end
it is the standard that's needed for end
products to communicate and the way that
they were designed um the recognition
that their far end product is a
compatible one and then
working over a clear channel
establish what each of the users are
capable of doing and want to do
yeah so i think we have our area
director here uh murray i don't know
murray if you want to comment on that
[Music]
um i was just reading your tweeting over
the charter because it's been a while
since i've read it and as long as
um this is covered in it which i haven't
i've finished reading it yet and this
working group doesn't have any
objections or the working group supports
the idea of bringing it in since it's
informational
um i
don't think this is a problem to take up
but you know consensus prevails
but i think that's an example
of the discussion
[Music]
as an example we could work a group less
call it uh it could be published i guess
through the independent
submissions process also
there's a variety of ways to to get it
through the publication process which
seems to be the goal
is yeah if you're going for
informational there are there are
several options
well that can be a discussion we can
have offline is to the benefits of one
versus the other because that's um
also something that i don't know
personally so
yeah i think one of the things you're
looking for because of the sdp issues is
to get the attention of the sdp
directorate and some of the people who
make these b2b uas who are torturing you
so that's kind of another consideration
is how to get the most exposure to them
that is true
in a sense they are
uh
participants in how network equipment is
created uh by the rfcs that
they have endorsed or or information
that they have to disposal
okay i think the action item and correct
me jonathan would be to bring this
discussion to the mailing list as to
uh how to get this published
does that make sense to you that
probably makes sense i do some people on
the queue let's give it a quick
over time
yeah carol
yeah i was stuck by struck by the
similarities of what you want i want
intermediate nodes to do with between
this and s frame actually
in both cases the main purpose of this
stp negotiation is to say
to tell other entities on the roots
please let this
this through and don't touch it
it's not unlike right this game i think
that's an accurate description of the of
what you present the escape right
yes it is we've been uh
been building products to this since
about
i want to say 2000
2004 2003.
i was about 2008 for skip for
for this so
yeah
it was yeah there was a lot in the works
before it ever
became uh
product
yep
thank you for confirming
good um the question regret in beginning
of the earlier slides uh for this they
were as i mentioned about the
tsbcis specification
um
it's kind of in the same
ballpark if you will
similar or not but not the same as what
we're doing i was kind of curious
how that was approval for that was
processed through the group
that was a while ago i'm not sure how
many people
here now are the extra member
okay yeah because it was like
in the very beginning of the of the
presentation
um yeah it was on the thomas
list of rrcs that were approved um i
guess since the last meeting or whatever
oh no that one yeah yeah um
so
i would actually suggest talking to the
media type reviewers for that and i know
murray is one that wasn't one
at that time so it might be something
where you need to ask that
um but i actually got in queue to ask a
different question um
which is actually on this slide if i can
if i can point to this uh from my
understanding of your description in
addition to the two media types uh that
you have in there you do have data
streams which you describe in this slide
as uh clear channel data
are you anticipating a media type
request
separate from the video and audio media
type of
requests
for
some sort of application slash skip as
well
um no the the reference to last bullet
in that slide is is that the data
present on the
um audio
or video skip
payload type it will be treated as clear
channel data don't mess with it
whatever is there just let it go
because there's there's negotiations
going on we need to fit the and then bid
integrity to to make the devices work
and
trying to trying to look at the traffic
channels not gonna not gonna help you
much
uh
i think you may want to
uh take another pass through the draft
and in your description of that because
that's not the same impression i got uh
with a quick look at the draft so okay
thanks well that's that's why we're here
comments
stefan
so um
having just gone through this xs thing
where
frankly a perfectly available iso
standard uh that just cost a little bit
of money raised a big big uproar
um i i think you will all have a hard
time to get anything through the
standard itf process where they needs to
be a reference in there to a document
that's not available to the public
and so far
my suggestion would be to target from
the outset
to give this to the independent stream
or whatever it's called so basically
not an itf document but still an rfc
uh and
uh
therefore something which most network
people pay some attention to
yeah and then you only have to go
through a conflict review in the idf and
that's that's
much easier thank you
right and then that sort of goes back
also to my comment about the tsvci spec
is that it also references
documents that were only available
through the government so i guess
again sort of requesting or
understanding how that process worked
for that particular
rfc
and its approval again this sort of
similar
to what work what work path if you will
that we're asking for
okay
car
hi um
we seem to be going a little bit
backwards in terms of the way the itf
handles these sorts of documents uh i i
was very surprised to see that all that
um the controversy about the um the spec
that stefan was just talking about
because we've done lots of payload
formats which have
you know had various degrees of
difficulty in accessing the
specifications over the years
so process wise i don't see that there
should be a problem with this in atf
and i i think the ietf certainly should
be able to
publish open specifications that
describe how to use a closed thing
um so i i would sort of somewhat
disagree with stefan and say that they
should go through the standard itf
process because the itf needs to be able
to do this sort of document and has in
the past
um so i i would encourage the group to
adopt this and take it on as a a a
payload format specification in the
usual way and work with
the chairs to work with the area
directors to to find a way of
your
uh
making making sure this is acceptable
and that that may just mean that uh you
know a small number of people are given
access to check that the specification
makes sense
um because it's accessible to the
community which cares and i think that's
what matters
um if i may speak for a minute the uh
that is possible to to for um request
permission for this
to look at this it's a skip standard
214.2 referenced in the r draft rfc
um and really most of the contents that
of that document of any technical
significance um
are in the draft rfc itself
this
doesn't
not much more than that
i mean i think it probably does need
someone who understands rtp um from this
from the ietf to look at look at the the
the kodak specification and look at
what's being proposed and say yeah this
makes sense
but i don't see that it requires it to
be made available to the entire
community it requires
it to be available to the community who
will be implementing it and you know
someone to to look at the spec and say
yeah that what's being proposed from the
rtv point makes sense uh and i'm pretty
sure we've done this sort of thing
before in itf's
that's fine
right
um yeah just on that point the isg
recently has uh
if you look there's there's a bcp 97 is
under revision for
exactly this reason we had a number of
documents come to us that
um we were not able to evaluate because
the specification to which it referred
was not available to us
i think the proposal is exactly what i
think colin just said as long as the
reviewers the people who need to review
it and approve it can get access to it
to make sure this the wrapping
specification is right then it can go
forward it doesn't need to be you know
permanently open public
but also but it is a problem if the
reviewers can't do their jobs that's all
we just have to uh the reviewers will
just have to contact the uh there's a
contact within the draft rfc at the
bottom
requesting access
we know in advance who they are we can
make sure that they get approved
yeah i think that's probably workable
okay so do we have the action items
identified
yes we have mailing list discussion
uh um i'm not sure yeah
sorry my my question is along the line
of that the action items i guess
um you're suggesting that we uh make the
doc the
background document skip 214.2 available
to certain people
we would need to know
who and will help guide them through the
process of who they need to
talk to
and who would be on the iatf side who
would be contacting us letting us know
who needs to get access to the document
i think i think that's probably a chair
item is that right jonathan
so we will um
try to get back to you with with
feedback
um okay
i mean i can think of some some folks
who who might uh
might be appropriate but we'll have to
discuss it
and we'll revisit the uh draft rfc for
for
making it clear that the uh the last
bullet in this slide referencing
treated as clear channel daily is is
is concise and and exact enough to
specify that it's referencing
just the data that is traveling within
the
uh audio skip
or video skip
traffic channels
okay
well thank you
thank you
okay you're on
go ahead
yeah yes right
cool
next slide please
so yeah i first wanted to
update on the avt co-working group on
s-frame
progress that has been made in various
areas
so first you might already be aware that
uh the ietfs framework you issued a call
for adoption of uh
the
omar s frame draft which is mostly
talking about
the format itself and has some arctic
architecture points as well
so it was a successful call with some uh
feedback that maybe the graph should be
split in a pure
format based spec and a separate um
active architecture draft
in addition to that
on the mailing list or in various place
it was noted that there's interest in
using strain format either at the back
up level or the frame level
but not in between which might be a good
simplification
also it was noted that
the sram format itself is uh has some
interest outside rtp um so for instance
you could you could use web transport or
rtc data channel uh with webcodex and
still use this frame uh in between to do
end-to-end encryption
um
so
that that means that uh we
we want integration with rtp but we also
want a screen to be used uh
outside of rtp
um in addition to that uh on the wp side
so the api level
the webrtc working group adopted the
webrt and curry transform as the first
public working draft
and the functionality
already shipped in chrome since
maybe a
year and it's also enabled by default in
software tech preview
and
it might be also
in
in the queue for other browsers as well
so
progress is being made to add support to
allow webpages to to use s-frame or to
implement engine encryption into
browsers
um
so the webrt and kodi transform is
definitely used for end-to-end
encryption
it's also
being used either for prototype or real
applications for other stuff like app
specific metadata enrichment
of and credit payloads
it was also used for uh
emulating
emulating red
if if it's not available in the browser
um
so
so we are seeing that solutions are in
browsers are more and more
using that
and
we're seeing that solution existing
webrtc solutions are using
uh like google do facetime webex there
all adding progressively support for
energy encryption and they're all doing
that with different test firm like
formats and flavors
uh
so
there's no interpolation it's not the
same kind of technology it's very
related but it's not exactly the same
some workarounds are being used and so
so it's not great uh and it's not great
because it's a security privacy
technology and usually having just one
uh
well identified piece of technology to
do that is better so
next slide
based on that my understanding is really
that we need to make progress uh i think
we already had a similar slide one year
ago about that saying hey things are
starting to evolve and to an encryption
is being shipped and we need to make
progress and it's even more of a case
now
um
so and it's particularly particularly
the case for
s frame within webrtc ecosystem for web
transport and data channel we still have
some time but for webrtc ecosystem it's
it's really uh
getting fat there so that means s frame
rtp integration and s frame sdp
integration
um
my understanding in the past was that uh
avt4 for instance would be responsible
for doing the srm rtp integration but
we are seeing um email threads on the
sframe working mailing list about that
so first question that i have to the avt
core working group uh no
previous slide my first question would
be uh
to
to be clear about
uh where should that work go or where
should it be worked on
could it be all done in this frame
working group the sms integration
or
would it be better to do that in ibt
core because currently i see that uh
there are discussions being done in
parallel and maybe it would be
good to be clear exactly about where
he's going to work and
which working group is responsible for
which part
and your opinion
um
i think that probably anything where
certainly anything where like rtp
architecture is implicated is best in
avt core
because i feel like that for the
expertise is
um
okay so that's that seems reasonable uh
for stp integration i guess that it
should be s frame or a music
correct
probably yeah though certainly
you know insofar as it's
i mean yeah i mean especially because it
probably needs something more
complicated than just
what a payload format would do so
probably that means that music
integration
okay okay um
okay so
it's good we're in a vt core
yeah just on that point the the stp
um i mean obviously music is the home
for sdp the payload formats are usually
defined in avt core and that's but
specifies a lot of the sdp parameters so
it maybe needs to review here as well
okay um so so it's great we're in a ut
core we're discussing that so let's try
to make progress
so at last meeting we we discussed a lot
the packet versus frame issue
and uh
i think that there are common
requirements in both cases so if we put
the packet versus frame issue aside we
can try to focus on uncommon
requirements and that's what we try to
do in the next slides next few slides
um
so yeah the vs frame working
there was a good discussions in base
frame working with making list about
various approaches and
basically i think
we
we know that middleware uh middleware
being like sfus network intermediaries
or browsers cannot inspect encrypted or
transform packet payloads
but they still especially as a fuse they
still need information to root and
complete transform packets separately um
and that's
especially the case in svc simulcat
cases but
it's already the case for instance in
in non-simulcast cases
so
one question was uh
from the main list whether
it should be if possible just from http
inspection to determine that content is
encrypted or transformed and if so
where should the information be located
should it should should it be just a
payload type should it be a dedicated
head extension
should we put that information in rtp
payload
so
that's
feedback i like to get from
ebitda forks
car
uh i'm a little
uh confused about what you mean by this
question because um my understanding is
that the payload type defines what what
is within the rtp payload so i'm not
sure what you mean by the separate
the separate points there
um
so currently in uh
the current and deployed environments
the payload type is defining
the codec so let's say h64 api 8p9
and we need we need at some point this
information anyway
and that's how it's being deployed but
we could also say that you know that's
wrong and the pilot type should say oh
it's encrypted content or it's content
that you you do not need to care
it's opaque
and that's one possibility
so i i don't think that's what the
payload type does
in rtp the payload type defines the
payload format
and the payload format describes what
codec it is and how it is packaged
and so if it specifies what's the
contents of the rtp payload
yeah
i mean the only thing is that it was i
mean it was right there in the in some
discussion of the main disease that
maybe
yeah signaling that in the sdp that the
content was
even if it is yes
and
we don't change the packet decision
of the codec just
increasing the the payload yeah the the
payload of the the of the rtp packet
that it could go from there within the
the same pilot time but for example me i
think that it will have a different
payload type to specify that it is not
the
the normal payload type so this is a
it is not um
we are saying what is the solution is
that some people have claimed that
it could be done in a different way so
yes
we were seeking guidance about
exactly if
if this could be an option or we should
just
er if we see for example shape and
sending
[Music]
an rtp packet with
with payload the payload network for vp8
then the payload must be vp8
and an unless view or whatever it can
expect it in
an exped to have
the the correct
payload in there
um so i think that there's some separate
issue issues here
i mean um
one is how you signal it and one is what
is the payload format um
you know the the the the the question on
the slide about here is this located in
the the payload type or within the itp
pillow that i mean they're the same
thing
so you may are you asking about the way
that
is included into the packet or the way
the data is
the way the contents of the packets are
signaled
[Music]
so yeah i was trying to to to cover the
fact that um
in vs frame uh working mainly so there
was a a proposal and um
usually you could say oh i want to
negotiate vpa because that's really what
i want and i want also to to this frame
um
so then you need to provide that
information the fact that you're using
vp8 and the fact that you're using s
frame uh
to view the party and
this information dp8 plus s frame uh
could go also in the packet or it could
be left elsewhere and so on and that's
uh what what i would like to to hear
about
because we we think that getting both
information like that
yeah it is uh it's ep8 and yeah it's
um it's encrypted it's transformed uh
would be useful
by looking at rtp packets
yeah i mean i think my argument here
would be if you're changing what what is
the payload then that's a different
payload format and maybe that's some
sort of encapsulation payload formats
but
it seems strange to say this is vp8 but
the content isn't actually vp8
yep sounds good
number nine
i think what
uh there's a couple of distinct issues
as colin said
one is the negotiation of specific rtp
header extensions like we've had the
frame marking header extension there's
the dependency descriptor
you know that there's routing
information that's being negotiated
um that really does not tell you
anything about what's in the payload
although people have been using it as a
kind of a hint of what might be in the
payload like it you know it's likely to
be encrypted but it doesn't really tell
you that explicitly
and the thing is that you could
negotiate those rgb header extensions
without encrypting the payload
right so
um and then there's the payload type
which or negotiation of things like the
codec but again that currently doesn't
tell you whether the payload itself is
encrypted so it seems to me like there's
something missing in there
um and i know there's been discussions
on the s frame mailing list about
whether you really want to even tell the
sfu that you're encrypting it or it's
none of the sfu's business
so i know there's there's that
issue because really the
the encrypted payload is really an
end-to-end thing and sdp really isn't
about that it's hot by hop
but i think it's a little bit dangerous
to assume that because you've negotiated
a particular header extension that uh
everything will work end to end with an
encrypted payload uh because there could
be as we just talked about with the b2b
uas right there could be somebody in the
middle who's looking at this and if the
sdp doesn't
tell it that they give it any inkling
that it's encrypted it probably could be
uh could become a problem at some point
so i think there is a piece that's maybe
none of the
some of the information is in none of
these none of the things you described
here it's not right yellow type it's not
a header extension
it's probably something else
oh yes i mean it seems to me like
conceptually what this actually should
be i mean insofar as
everything in the rtp session will be s
frame which i think is what people
probably want because you don't because
i think having this be
mixed is a security and you know
nightmare i think what this actually is
a profile much like savp has a profile
um this is a new transformation like
savpp
um
which uh i mean i don't know if you just
i mean whether you actually negotiate it
that way for backward compatibility
reasons is a separate issue but um
i feel like
you know that might be at least
conceptually the cleanest way to
approach it and if we have to hack
something to get it to work with
browsers or whatever so be it um
but
i know that certainly especially for
you know the problem with having to be a
payload type is a
the payload type
um multiplication issues
and
um also just the i don't know if you
want to be able to negotiate both
you know
s frame and non-s frame in the same
session because that sounds like a good
way to accidentally discover you're not
intending
or not discover it
worse
uh sue us
sfu to make some decisions it's not
they're not
different islands they have to be
combined together in any business logic
that you apply on per packet basis and
stp is the one that sets up some uh kind
of stream level indications and uh and
speaking here just in terms of the
articulator it's a bit kind of not
thinking about what happens in the
setting up there
and uh
i did did uh see some of the discussions
that happening on the streams mailing
list about you know saying uh uh for for
a media stream level or for or for
particular payload type on applicability
that if if this is an uh s frame or on s
packet
that way uh for it's kind of hint to the
an stp offensive can be defined
explicitly to say what the behavior
should be
uh they think it's a hint uh to the sf
utility it's saying that you know you
know don't look into the packet further
because it's entered and created you
don't get anything versus uh something
like if it's if it is not an internet
encrypted thing you can look into the
packet to see for example audio level or
something like that and hence having
some we need to kind of uh look it in
the picture of the signaling and the
media to make a decision just looking at
rtp there would kind of leave a bigger
system set up that's happening here and
we need to consider that as well
um
yeah i think um conceptually i agree
with uh jonathan that the first thing i
thought conceptually was also
profile level things like that savp or
something like that
i was an original i made
the
the right precedent model to use however
uh
not an originalist and i don't believe
that
it decided uh long ago should impact
everything today and i think i would
argue that savp has caused a lot more
damage than
uh than good um
and there's been a lot of problems with
things like
stuff for security
i would i would caution against trying
to do
what logically makes sense
is to make a new profile out of this um
but i think that's
that's probably a mistake that rehashes
a lot of the mistakes that those older
profiles cause
what makes more logical sense to me is
this is just an encapsulation like
like red or effect or anything else it's
an encapsulation of
of some other payload so i think it
makes more logical sense to declare all
the real payloads and then also declare
the encapsulated uh types
and then what you actually send on the
wire is the encapsulated type so it
would be a different payload type number
um and it would just be an encapsulation
of some other payload type that is also
in the stp but won't appear on the wire
because you're not actually sending that
format on the wire
that's what i think makes more logical
sense
um yeah i think i agree with what i just
said that this to me does not make sense
as a profile um i think it's entirely
the wrong level of modifications to be
represented as a profile
it strikes me as a wrapper format much
more like um
you read or the retransmission formats
also
and i think what what you are specifying
here is a wrapper format which says that
the content is for example vp8 but
encrypted
um
and so it's a it
so you know i don't think this is a a
codec agnostic payload format i think
this is a codec specific format which
wraps
you know something which which wraps a
particular set of content so what you're
signaling is is that it's this wrapper
format and what is being wrapped is this
you and you know the the the existing
payload format gets put into the wrapper
perhaps with an additional header uh had
it before the front of it and it's
signaled as a payload type um
wrapping some existing payload type
so i just one response i mean i think
that's
probably a fine solution i think
the sdp part is going to have to be a
little tricky because
if you want to say i'm willing to
receive rap vp8 i do not want to receive
unwrapped vp8 but i think that might be
more music consideration than a
avt core consideration per se
yeah i think it's uh it's a good issue
to tackle as well and to keep track of
yeah i mean i i agree there's probably
some signaling issues i suspect they're
not that different to the ones we use
for some of the retransmission or
redundancy format
i guess we'll need to work that through
okay
okay uh we don't have a lot of time but
maybe this is my yeah we could say it's
my last slide no go above
and previous slide
yeah so
i think from what i hear is consensus is
that
we need an ability to identify whether
it's encrypted and transform and also be
an underlying
codec type
i'm
not sure about whether
it's good
with consensus on uh having a solution
that is independent of the exact
transformation format uh it seems to me
that it would be good to have
um because what we're seeing is being
deployed they are various s frame or
transform being used and so
um
the wrapper format will only be able to
will not
we don't want to have a reference for
each
and exact transformation
transform
and uh yes the scope
is directly
related to whatever skill your video
codex only so there's any known set of
codecs that we want to store and it's a
fully generic solution
in any way
the target is only working on your video
products
um just you're on
here going back to your you know the
first slide of
having different uh systems in uh
implementing s frame versus packet in
different uh
uh
different phase like google facetime
versus webex and those kind of things
i'm going back to if you go with an
alternative payload format or some kind
of wrapping payload format how how would
that uh level of
entropy will be achieved with a two
different implementation of the
s frame or what is the packet
so are we are we
kind of saying that we have to do one
versus the other or or are we saying we
we don't talk about that and somehow the
implementations need to figure it out
um
it's open question i don't think that
there's consensus on uh or
on anything there yet
um
what is known now is that
it's either a packet law or a freight
level yeah we're not interested in
cases
but more than that uh since there are
experimentation
implementations sorting the cat and
implementation support frame level so
just maybe we'll
we'll see from there or maybe we can
some consensus i'm picking just one
in the chat about we want to apply s
frame packetization vp8 packetization
uh and this this perhaps comes to the
heart of what's what's the issue yeah
um i i was my understanding was that
what you wanted to do was take um
vpa content you know in the same way
it's usually packetized encrypt it and
then put it into a new payload format
um which seems to be the model i was
talking about and i thought mo was
talking about
justin's talking about doing something
different then perhaps we need to have a
conversation to make sure we're all
understanding that the same thing about
what's meant here
you know it would seem like a package
the things you would put
you know packetize it for vp8 as if
you're going to put it in the packet
encrypt it and then put it in the packet
possess frame vp8 inside but if that's
not what's being proposed then i think
we've got a bigger discussion to have
yeah i'm
sorry we this discussion that'll cut a
little short by other things running
over time
i feel like this needs more discussion
um
[Music]
uh we should try to figure out what's
the best place to have this discussion
uh would people we tried to do an
interim on this before or didn't really
have the right take up but
if we can get the right people in a room
an interim or
perhaps a more informal side meeting
might be helpful just so we can sort of
get convergence on make sure everybody's
talking about the same things
architecturally
is there any interest in that
quickly hopefully
justin says yes
colin says yes
uh
okay we'll try to sus says yes okay
we'll try to have some put up not
something on the list for that
uh so
um all right that seems reasonable
um
good
i think we've reached the end of the
meeting and we want to thank you for
coming okay the only other thing i
wanted to raise is that spencer
um mentioned earlier on the rtp over
quick discussions
we think uh probably having specifically
rtp over quick discussions on the aut
list
would be best whereas more general media
over click on the macquest
uh so just to keep things somewhat
separable
except someone's separate there that's
probably the best organization for that
and with that thank you all for coming
and uh
we'll see you at uh
uh other sessions here or next time
possibly in person
and we'll
uh arrange for interim on the uh s3
measures i believe we can get some
convergence on that
we'll just go side on the left
thank you everybody
uh