welcome everyone to the second session
in this group today we're going to be
having Kurt Baumgartner come and speak
to us about on the strong pity watering
hole attacks everyone please join me in
welcoming Kurt all right good morning
everyone thanks for attending my talk
I'm Kurt Baumgartner I'm a principal
security researcher with Kaspersky Labs
global research analysis team I've been
with the company about six years most of
it looking at targeted attacks and quite
a bit of other work regarding exploit
kits and Java exploitation and other
things but today I want to talk with you
about a watering hole tactic or an apt
tactic and in particular this one was
carried out fairly recently over the
summer by a publicly undisclosed apt the
the watering hole attack themselves and
watering hole as a tactic is not
altogether new is not altogether fresh
but what's interesting about this set of
attacks in particular is that they were
very focused on users of encryption
technologies in particular Italian and
Belgian users were hit the most but
Turkish and throughout the Middle East
and some in North Africa or hit as well
and so i will talk to you about both the
group and the tactics and sort of what
the problem here is why bother talking
about this in the first place so all in
all i'll be i'll be starting off with
talking about the relevant encryption
tools they were interested in both to
enable their attacks on these users and
and sort of the secondary tools that
they were after once they were on the
system's what they could do with those
technologies and why they were
vulnerable we'll look at previous
watering holes to compare against
probably the most relevant to compare
what strong pity is doing now
is what crouching Yeti or energetic bear
did in 2014 their focus in particular
was on ICS organizations or critical
infrastructure they use trojan eyes
installers and replaced them on on
various sites will look into those and
make that comparison and then i'll look
at the specifics of the strong pity
attacks that lasted two of the sites
were up for about or compromised or at
least redirecting users to poisoned
installers for around a week to two
weeks and then there's a there's a third
site that is much more recent and over
the weekend it was up in serving malware
so please don't visit the site but that
in particular is truecrypt they're going
after users of full disk encryption and
older tool for it we'll look at the
geo-targeting what ends up happening
with these sort of reckless watering
hole attacks and then we can talk a
little bit about what they're what
they're doing once they get on systems
so the encryption technology you can
really categorize into two things that
strong pity is interested in one set of
tools falls under your really data at
rest so winrar and truecrypt work on on
data at rest so winrar you pack pack and
archive but then you can follow it up
with a a password of virtually unlimited
length and the package can be packed or
is encrypted I should say with AES 256
so effectively you can have an
unbreakable archive for all practical
purposes using winrar as it's available
now truecrypt is a little different it's
interesting because it's it's a killed
project it's available on sourceforge
the developers tell you not to use it
there was a lot of drama around auditing
the package and whether or not people
should be using truecrypt and
essentially they offer it now to migrate
data away from truecrypt and onto
say a hardware encryption drive or a
hardware encrypted drive which is
interesting either the defenders are
still using an outdated tool which is
quite possible people are still running
winxp and critical infrastructure but
more likely than not they're looking at
older data that they want to move into a
new environment so that's interesting
too and then the second type of tools or
the second set of tools has to do with
data in motion encrypting data in motion
so whether i am clients like skype or
jabber are being used ssh clients I
believe everybody here knows about
secure shell and what a great tool it is
and then finally moving data and moving
communications with filezilla secure
windows copy client and then and then
RDP clients as well the problem with
people depending on tools like this
isn't necessarily the strength of the
encryption but may have more to do with
how they're being distributed this
continues to be a real problem and this
is what strong pity is taking advantage
of so a truecrypt itself may be may be
distributed through sourceforge and
several mirrors but there's no way to
really verify that a truecrypt side and
sort of the state of the project may be
deployed somewhere else or distributed
from another another site properly there
are PGP keys there are all sorts of md5
but a lot of people just are not are not
as technical as they should be perhaps
the ease of use the ability to identify
whether or not a hash or signatures is
valid some people just are not doing
that very well there are also resellers
and distributors of winrar for example
so what may look like a localized
version of winrar may really be a
poisoned installer and it's just very
hard to see
to understand where it should be coming
from and how it's how it should be
properly distributed we do have
appropriate places like you know the
google google well the apple store the
microsoft store microsoft update they're
using ssl they're using keys to verify
the packages chrome update verifies
software coming across the wire but in a
lot of cases for open source encryption
packages and winrar and other other
packages it's just not easy it's just
not sort of hassle free to identify
you're getting a valid encryption
technology deploy or distributed to your
system so with crouching Yeti again
that's the most relevant watering hole
technique when you're comparing
different actors they poisoned
installers so installers of all sorts
whether it was VPN clients that are
mainly used in critical infrastructure
sort of industrial-strength digital
camera driver installers so energetic
bear would compromise a website or an
FTP site pull down the installer for the
drivers or the software that they're
interested in poison it with a back door
and then put it back on the site for
industrial IT environments or industrial
environment IT staff to download install
within their within their organization
so that was very effective in 2014 and
again strong pity is doing something
very similar this summer so what are we
really seeing well in one case it seems
that strong pity couldn't fully
compromise the distributor site they
were able to get a link on the site you
see here a a button there's a there's a
blue button that recommends oh this is
the version you really want to install
it's either x64 x32 or one of several
languages in the background really what
they were doing is they were they had
set up a site called raúl rob and when
you look at rawr rawr lab the legitimate
site and raúl rob it's kind of it's kind
of hard to tell what's going on
and especially with just a simple
redirect from a button that's going to
download to your system something that
looks very much like an appropriate
installer but instead what they had on
this rel rob site was a set of
installers that would that were poisoned
and would drop their back doors in their
spyware to an individual's systems and
again this is very difficult for most
end-users to identify and verify that
this version of winrar is the one that
they're after if you go to the winrar
dot b ii site now you'll see a nice
little section here that gives you keys
and it tells you or hashes i should say
sha-256 that tell you what the package
you're downloading should match up with
or should be fingerprinted with the
problem with that is if the site was
compromised they could very easily
replace the key as well so there isn't
sort of a two-factor verification of
this software package for users of
encryption we saw something very similar
the attackers had compromised winrar dot
IT this is a localized distributor of
winrar and over https people would end
up downloading from the server itself
these poison packages and they were
localized they were also delivered
appropriately so there were x64 versions
in x32 versions being delivered to the
end user system appropriately since then
these guys have cleaned up the site and
strong pity is not being delivered but
again when you look at the site and
download this stuff it's very difficult
to verify for sort of a typical end user
to verify whether or not the encryption
technology they're downloading is the
appropriate one
at the same time these guys were
interested in truecrypt now the
interesting thing it about when you
about putting winrar and truecrypt
together is that if you're encrypting
with winrar and you're encrypting with
truecrypt and you're using say a file
sharing site you can have a virtual
end-to-end encrypted fully encrypted
solution on the right here on your left
there you can see truecrypt sourceforge
net this is the legitimate source of the
truecrypt package at this point and this
is true crypt true crypt com is what
strong pity set up and again please
don't visit that site what you'd have to
do is there's a very long list of
instructions and warnings about not
using the package and then at the very
bottom there's a link to to a strong
pity malware package that does install
truecrypt the software package and then
alongside you get a little treat you get
the backdoor dropper and it can install
key loggers and and some other spyware
along with it um but again this is very
difficult for sort of the average user
who's interested in privacy and securing
their data to really differentiate
between the two so really what did the
guy what did strong pity hit over the
summer well over here you can see from
the Belgian site the redirects to ral
Rob calm hit mostly all belgium belgian
users in this case they hit almost a
hundred users that we have visibility
into so that means to that means to me
that we're seeing the tip of the iceberg
and this is clearly more than just a
hundred users that are getting hit also
interesting is that northern African
visitors we're getting hit with the same
malware along with Dutch and so on on
the on the winrar dot IT
mostly all Italian users which tells me
this watering hole was a very sloppy
attack and from there you'll also see
Belgian and Algerian users we're getting
hit as well and then finally with the
truecrypt site you see almost all of the
users getting hit are localized the
attacks really are in in Turkey the
method they were using to push users to
the true dash crypt comm site was to
place links and place redirects on to
other sites within turkey itself so
software aggregation sites that are a
collection of freeware and shareware and
other things they basically replace the
links on that site and redirected people
to true true to their true crypt com
site so again a very sloppy method of
targeting a select set of individuals
you're after and all in all this group
they've deployed zero day in the past so
they're technically very capable they've
effectively spear fished entire
organizations and groups and so they can
be very precise with what they do but
apparently that wasn't working so they
shifted their tactics to a very sloppy
method which is this water holing so
once they're on a system some of the
additional components strong pity
components that they download to a
system are interested in these other
encryption tools so it's not just when
we aren't truecrypt they're interested
in SH clients that are secure shell
clients that specifically run on Windows
systems they know exactly what they're
after here they're dealing with IM
clients that maintain strong encryption
so there have they download key loggers
and multiple components specifically
crafted to steal contacts and
communications from these as well so
the focus specifically is on the fact
that these widely available easy to
install two encryption technologies are
being used by their targets and they
can't clearly they can't access the data
once it's encrypted with these solutions
so I don't know if you'd call this a
side channel attack or simply system
compromised but the unusual in this the
sort of extraordinary focus of these
guys is clearly on on users of
encryption technologies all right and
and with that I just like to open up to
some questions thank you for your time
thank you if you have a question please
raise your hand and one of our runners
will bring the microphone to you here
thanks that last slide you showed a
bunch of different tools can you say a
little more about what it is that you
observed them doing with those tools I
thought you said they were installing
those tools are you saying they're
installing compromised versions of those
tools so they can so the okay good
question so can i clarify on really what
they're using to as an attack vector and
what they're collecting data from so
this last this last slide is what
they're interested in collecting data
from they weren't using these as an
attack vector so winrar those the
watering hole sites related to
localization in distributor sites those
were being used as an attack vector
truecrypt was being used as an attack
vector I'm going to guess they're after
the data being hidden by that stuff as
well but that's the attack vector and
then multiple components that were
downloaded two systems later on were
hard coded and specifically looking to
steal data from from these sorts of
tools so clearly they're wrestling with
the encryption problem so oh so this is
my last point so why even talk about
this
well clearly with these tools or with i
should say winrar i should i should say
these tools are very effective
encryption technologies if one was to
access p caps of the data flowing across
these you know communications it's going
the work is going nowhere but what
they're doing is they're going after the
long the low-hanging fruit and right now
the low-hanging fruit is verification
and true validation of installation and
I'd any identity of these encryption
packages and in particular winrar and
truecrypt is what they were using and
that sort of distribution system yeah so
just to make sure I get it taste these
are all interesting tools and I can
understand why the attacker would be
interested in what you're doing with
them are you saying they they're
installing malware that lets them
observe data that's that's manipulated
by these applications that's being
encrypted with these okay but they're
bringing malware that lets them get
visibility before the encryption happens
yes targets these okay yeah okay thank
you any other questions
bueller bueller well not see any other
questions I guess we'll wrap up a little
early everyone please join me in
thanking Kurt for his presentation
[Applause]