morning everyone and welcome to this
first session for virus Bolton the title
of the first presentation is wild
Android collusion presented by Jane
Blasco okay
thank you so well as I said my name is
in Spanish Horace oh but you can call me
your show wherever you want but it's
better for you and I come from City
University in London and I'm going to
present this paper that we did with also
into security at and Swansea University
but before that I would like to mention
where this paper comes from so we were
working for a two years in what we call
the acid project this is a project
funded by the EPS are seen in the UK and
it was a collaborative effort between
City so NC into security as an industry
partner but also a comment to university
they were involved in in this paper but
it's both acknowledged
acknowledging them so and the goal of
this project was to make sure develop a
new methods to attack and track the
possible I could say emerging threat of
of colluding applications so as a small
introduction I mean you would probably
all of you would probably know that but
the main security goals of Android are
well and it has mainly three security
goals first one is obviously protect the
user and it's Annie and his data or her
data then protect the apps that are
installed on the device and the system
resources that are like battery and
obviously finally protect the device
itself and in order to do so it has many
different security features and the ones
that I met you here the ones that are at
the device level so you have most of the
Linux derive security features like
process isolation monitor access control
we have also apps unboxing we are also
the famous or maybe famous permission
system security API is like encryption
credential stories etc and we also have
the depth assignment within in Android
is not like use like in other platforms
such as iOS but it's but do you have it
there also and the main point that I
want to make this is that all these
security features features are meant to
avoid the threads that are caused by
single applications but what happened
when applications start communicating
each other so we have
many different ways of communicating
many different things we can do well
communicating the first thing we can do
is just cooperate like two apps just
simply exchange messages to do something
that is useful for the user so let's say
you want to share your location with a
whatsapp contact or you have to you want
to share the location on Facebook you
just tap the share button on the Google
Maps app and that creates an intent that
sends the location information to
another app you select that location
information goes to the Internet but
it's because you wanted it's not that
they are exchanging that information
without your consent then we have
another kind of communication with
squiggle permissions with litigation
attacks and more general outside the
Android context we call these kind of
attacks that confuse the police attacks
and in this case we have two apps or
more than two apps but one of quar app
is developed by I would say a careless
developer that I created a component
inside the app to access a sensitive
resource let's say for example the
camera of the device but the problem is
that that developer didn't protect
didn't protect that results very well so
other apps can imagine the developer
does it on a service the thing is that
perhaps if the developer doesn't enforce
other apps when requesting the the
access to the service to use specific
permissions other apps will be able to
access a systemic resource without
actually requesting the permission and
that obviously creates risks for the
users but what happens if instead of
having a Curless developer and some apps
exploiting that vulnerability in the
application we have two apps that do
that on purpose we would have something
more or less like this so imagine you
have let's say an app that portraits
itself as an Audi Notes app so you could
use the app to record notes let's say
for example and that obably has access
to the microphone and the user has also
delivered another app in the device
which portraits itself as a weather
application but the point is that these
two apps do more than they say they do
so the first up there
because it has access to the microphone
it also records the user conversations
and it uses any of the available
communication channels in Android to
send those conversations to the full
application that having access to the
Internet is able to export that
information outside so depending on the
communication channel use there's no way
by Android to enforce or to avoid this
kind of behavior the apps and another
point is that the user would do loading
the applications and when applications
are requesting the permissions he
doesn't know if these two apps will
communicate so he is not able or she is
not able to take an informed decision
when he's studying or when granting
access to the different permissions for
the apps so when analyzing this problem
you know profound that the most
important of the most
lesyk key factors of app collusion
actual first the communication channels
which I will reveal later and secondly
the threats that can be enabled by the
collision attack and what are the
threats that can be enabled by clean as
well mostly the same threats the single
application could could see first one
the one that is so information theft
very simple in wannabe steals
information sends it to the other
application and your application sends
it outside but then we can have
colluding upsets that could maybe try to
steal money from the user maybe by still
in his or her credentials also maybe by
by making phone calls or sending SMSs
messages then we could have also clean
apps that do service misuse analysis but
we could have also other kind of threat
or a good sale a kind of attack in which
different applications synchronize
themself to actually achieve like a the
highest possible goal or the highest
possible gain for the malware developer
and and the case we found and has to do
with this attack synchronization so we
know that some applications could be
communicating to execute some threats
but how they can communicate well and
there are many different communication
channels on Android the main problem of
the other communication channels between
applications
that some of them do not really need to
go let's say or to ask for any kind of
permission in Android so if we want to
use intents to apps can communicate
through intents without the user knowing
we could use also content providers for
communication in and the content
providers will prolly you will know that
but I like a small databases with inside
Android and the most common content
provider I would say is the contacts
database but if you want to use the
contact database for up communication
you need to ask for permissions we could
also use external storage but again we
need could need to ask for permissions
and in some versions of Android we could
use the services which are a kind of
communication channel that I will
explain just in a bit and you will see
that intense and server preferences are
involved because those are the channels
we analyzed when we executed or when we
did our research that iodine will
display later and then we could have
also some hidden or covert communication
channels in android probably you are not
aware of this but all applications can
read and modify the other settings of an
android device with other question any
specific permissions so if your
application wants to send information to
another application what they could do
is one of the applications could
modulate the value of the volume setting
and the other application Welman
monitoring that value could read
different bytes obviously this is not a
high bandwidth channel but it is
something you could use and you don't
need to request any kind of permission
obviously again you need obviously to
check if the user is listening to music
or doing some things because the user is
listening to music and the volume starts
going up and down it will be a kind of a
strange behavior there are also many
other hidden covered channels and most
of them are the kind of covered channels
that exist in many other platform or
computer systems so we can use
enumeration of processes and sockets
we can also modulate the free space on
the RAM or all the storage we could also
modulate the usage of the CPU to send
information to to other processes so
regarding the third preferences this is
the channel egg we found that was being
used by applications and I want to
explain it a little bit before going
further so sir preferences is kind of
it's a way of historian key-value person
persistence towards on the device and
it's very simple to use and it's widely
used mostly to store application as the
name says preferences so he just if the
developer wants to create a sir
preference file he has needs to create
an instance of a shared preference
object and call the gate sir preferences
method from the context of the
application the developer only needs to
provide two variables the first one is
the file name where the preference will
be stored and the second one is the mode
and this is the interesting one because
the mode of the sir preference file can
be private meaning that know how no
other apps can access it but it could
also be more readable or work rights at
all and in this case apps could access
that file from obviously outside the
sandbox without requesting any specific
permission the good news is that this
renege writing outside the sandbox only
works on versions of Android that do not
have easy Linux on a forcing mode so up
to date I saw the yesterday how the
different versions of Android are now
and these would affect only 25% of the
devices so if we want to read a value
from the from the shared preferences we
just called from the object we have
called get the kind of data tab we want
specifying the key and a default value
in case that key is not found if we just
want to write a value into the third
preferences we just creates an editor
and we it's more or less the same
instead of calling the gate we call a
put with the different data type the key
and the value we want to store but this
is what we need to do if we want to read
or write into or inside or an
application but what happens if we want
to read the sir personal files from
applications for different applications
so the only thing we need to do is we
need to create a context object we can't
create an account X objects from any
other context and the only thing when
it's provide is the package name
with that we will only need to call from
that context object we will need to call
again the gate server preferences
specifying the file name and in this
case were little
org or writable method and we just need
to again call the get the specific data
type or put specific data type with an
editor you want to save or store
information so and no inter
communication channels no in the
possible threats what we did was to
develop an approach by using static
analysis analysis what we did is we took
a data set from Intel security and we
start analysis to strike mainly the
permissions used by the applications and
then the communication channels and by
communication channels I mean as I said
before the intents mostly broadcast
intents stuck with also the static and
dynamic in broadcast receivers and also
how applications were used we're using
the server preferences files what we did
after that is that we use Prolog I don't
know well maybe some of you don't know
that some of you maybe studied this a
long time ago we use product rules with
cell logic programming language and we
started we first codified all the
features we extracted from the apps as
Prolog facts and then we started in
writing some rules some of them as the
ones you see here were used to qualified
certain actions so for example if an app
was using and the read contact
permission and we would say that data
had access to sensitive information if
an acquisition descending or the send
SMS permission we would say that data
could be used to charge the user some
money and so on with all the permissions
and we also I created some rules to
specify how applications could collude
so for example you see a very simple
rule here it's that if the application
one has access to certain information
if application to has out sex to the
outside and if application one
communicates with application to good
have a possible
collusion between application run an
application shop so with this we use
prologue queries to find potential
including upsets like for example when
you see there we just called like
colluding this is a simplification of
the actual code but I think it's useful
to see how it works we ask all colluding
with package name and it will give us
all the possible application that could
be colluding with the application we
could provide as I said we use a data
set provided by in the security and the
last apk in the desert in that the set
was collected on February 2016 and we
found we found many interesting things
but what we did is we focused on how
applications were using server
preferences because share preferences
are not I would say a standard
communication channel in hundred
applications no one uses cell
preferences because you have many other
better methods to communicate between
hundred applications and we found two
things first there were many many
applications that were using well most
of the things we found were inside
libraries that were being imported by
application some of them advertising
libraries some of them other kind of
libraries and we found that there were
many applications that were generating a
unique device ID and we're sharing that
device ID through shared preferences
with many other applications this
obviously implies it's it's I would say
it's a kind of coalition that put up
with the privacy of the user because
they can track which applications are
installed on the same device and that
can be used for advertisement
advertisement advertisement targeting
and things like that and the other thing
that was interesting that we found is
that there were many applications that
were using a specific SDK that were
storing a specific number inside
different servers files so we
investigated further and what we found
is that all those applications were
embedding what is called the malleus SDK
this is the K is developed and
maintained by Baidu and there was a
Malaysian version that Trend Micro
discovered in November
20:15 the behavior of the malicious
version was actually really interesting
because the the SDK what it did is among
many other things it also was able to
create a command and control will abort
inside the inside the app instance
sitting in a service an HTTP server that
would be able to receive commands from a
command control server it will also
allow the command console server to
request for users asset information if
the app was part of the system image it
will allow the command and control
server to install app silently and it
will also allow the the command go to
server we don't know exactly why but it
could a lot of common observer to gripe
contacts on the contact database this
all these things were found by by do and
what we found is that all the apps
including the Baidu
disorder Mobile SDK we're having this
estranged behavior with the server
purposes at what we found is that well
before that most of the results would I
would say maybe academic research on on
application collusion is based on
sensitive information flows but this is
not the case of of the Maloof SDK and
what they did basically where the
different apps embedding the Mobile SDK
we're using the server preferences as a
communication channel to select a leader
to communicate with the command and
control server so the idea is that this
is the K was embedded into many
different applications with access or
with many different levels of access to
the system and the apps we will will be
talking to each other to see which was
the app with more access to a system so
that could be the app connecting to the
command and control server and receiving
their the commands so how does that work
well so in my team we have three
different apps all under sandbox and
obviously all of them having them up
Lucius decay the first thing all of the
apps do when they execute is they do
some checks and they they save a
priority value on a sarafina's file the
name of the server preferences files is
always the package name plus a suffix
cookies
passing okay and how is that priority
value calculated well this is a method
inside
by the SDK it's a beautiful skated and
basically there were many different
takes depending on how that sag went you
will have a different value added to
Assam that was then saved to that share
preference file the first text where
just manifest tax so the app or by said
the SDK could look into the app manifest
to check for different meta tags inside
the manifest it would check if they have
was developed by Baidu and many other
different things and depending of those
values it could save it could add a
different parity value then and that
would check if it was able to get into
the contacts database and in that case
it would add an additional priority
value and finally the app could check if
it was part of the system image so the
nice thing about all these checks is
that the first checks give the priority
value a little bump but the last ones
make the parity value grow a lot so
depending on the kind of checks that
were true the parity value will increase
a lot depending on obviously the app was
inside the system image the parity good
into is a lot more than if there was
just a matter tag found and so what the
apps did with this so they saved again
the same before that they save the
parity value into a SERP reference file
and after that what they did is all the
apps including the mobile sdk grid with
all the other preference files and only
the service of the app with the highest
priority value would be launched in the
the service including the connection to
the command and control server so in
these great the apps were able to let's
say optimize their attack into using the
app that has most access to the system
resources so this is just how the apps
were iterating
to check the server preference file to
look for the highest priority value and
then an intent could be great
and lastly that they intend could be
launched and interesting thing here is
that all the previous interns that
called that service would be canceled
because we're gonna let the malware
developers or let's say the malicious
developers that embedded that injected
that code into the map loss SDK
only wanted the app with the highest
access to the system to be executed
so yes concluding the first thing how
these things can be fired forth first
probably it would be interesting to
develop collusion detection methods at
market authorized level and in order to
develop this well we think that it would
be interesting to check how apps use the
different communication channels that
they have then it would be interesting
to if Android had a system to enforce or
to check how apps communicate to each
other I know that at some point Android
implemented a kind of intent firewall
but it's not been used so applications
can use intense and broadcast intents
freely and the user doesn't get any kind
of notification when two apps are
communicating and obviously the third
part is it's just an obvious thing just
be careful developers should be careful
when they are embedding through party
libraries because they should be knowing
what they are bearing on their apps not
only because of collusion but because
you can insert into Europe many many
different malicious behaviors signal
inclusions first different interrupt
complications introduced risk has
different risks and the problem in
Android at least right now is that it's
not possible the user is not aware of
how absurd communicating and how apps
are exchanging data and the user is mean
he's aware of the permissions that every
author of the apps has but he's not
aware of how these apps communicate and
sell information we also saw that a
specific kind of collusion is possible
again and bring third-party libraries
and can be dangerous and sometimes it's
dangerous and the good news is that at
the moment we only found this kind of
synchronization attacks we didn't found
any kind of sensitive information or
information theft attacks which in
collusion but we don't know if
there could be more apps having these
kind of behaviors because we haven't
been able to analyze lots a lot of
different apps and that's it thank you
for