alright well thank you everybody for
sticking around first and foremost it's
been a long day but I hope this will be
a great end to the day a great great cap
to the day my name is Jay Jacobs I'm
going to be the moderator of this panel
and I have a list of questions that
we've developed and gave copies to all
three of them so hopefully we won't
catch anybody off guard with anything
but I want to start off here with a
pretty easy question could anyone have
you define risk quickly all right just
agree with that was just a joke no but
seriously that the nollie you talked it
in your keynote this morning about
defining risk and the concept of risk
how is um how important is that working
definition of risk that people agree on
it well it's very important because
there's so much confusion about what
risk me and for selling and definitions
that are commonly used in the industry
and many of them contradict one another
the most important contradiction is
where some people believe risk is high
probability and I loss and others
believe it's low probability high loss
so you can't get anything more
contradictory and that these are two
diametrically opposed views on what risk
is and obviously if you go into meeting
and one group believes it's a and the
other group believes it's be there
talking past each other because they
don't really even understand that
they're talking about completely
different concepts so you start off by
the reason we wanted to do this is to
make people understand it's not a better
right or wrong it's a matter of
understanding there are two different
business problems they're both important
business problems and it's we get
confused by the terminology so let's
agree on terminology and then we can
agree on business problems and we
proposed that the definition of risk of
adverse deviation from the expectation
that's consistent with one of the most
important risk axioms we've all accepted
which is risk represents uncertainty
whether certainty the risk is zero so
building on that foundation
oh right it's on oh it's upside down
maybe I just go back and go see
everything you just have again okay so
this is much better yeah yes under who I
was doing wrong i said but so anyway
where was I yeah again so it's not a
matter of right or wrong it's a matter
of understanding that these are
different concepts and each concept
helps by defining these things in a
particular way each with its own
definition we have a better
understanding the business problems
we're solving so yeah the thing I was
saying is you go into a meeting and
people think they're all on the same
page in terms of risk and so but if one
group believes that high risk is a and
the other group believes high risk is be
there using the same word and meaning
completely different things so even
where they think there's consensus there
actually isn't so that's why definitions
of matter because particularly at risk
because this is one of the most
important definitions important concepts
and it's never being defined yeah and
before we get too far I should have done
introductions and I don't have any sort
of a bi or anything for for all three of
you but Ali obviously we saw your
keynote this morning one of your most
influential works for me was your paper
and operational risk I was a few years
ago and Jack Jones in the middle the
creator of the fair methodology author
of a recent book and the title is
measuring and managing information risk
a fair approach yeah and that just came
out like a month ago month ago yeah and
so that's on amazon and various places
like that and Jack and I know each other
from years ago I went through fair
training things like that but he's he
spent years developing fair
and teaching at training people
certifying people in it talking to
companies about risk specifically
information security risk and then duck
huh Burt on the end you've got three
four four books three books multiple
editions of your first one third edition
is out right now of how to measure
anything and definitely also no heavy
influence on me did I capture and you're
also a consultant you decision
management support I'm really started
struggling here for words am I capturing
most of it yeah that's basically it all
of our clients have in all the different
industries there in all have one thing
in common they're making decisions under
uncertainty yeah that's it we do it yeah
okay so let me jump back into a question
here all of you three actually on the
stage were influential to me and I think
too many people in the room that have
seen your work and I've all seen your
work before I met you personally but
whoo-hoo for each of you who has been
influential in your careers you're being
as you are developing your talents and
your skills who is the person or what
was the thing that really triggered for
you that this is what you wanted to do
how did that how did that come about for
us well I I was just going to say my mo
most influential person was my first
quantitative methods professor in grad
school but I guess I can't say that
because I honestly can't remember his
name well what about that personal
trigger together it may not have been
that influential but I remember the
classes they were there I didn't imagine
them but I all the math I had up to that
point was all about physics and math so
this was a big change you know that
quantitative methods actually applied to
policy decisions and investment
decisions it wasn't just about orbital
mechanics and relativity and stuff right
it it actually applied to other things
and so it wasn't all no decisions under
uncertainty you know we did the game
theory a lot of it was operations
research optimization problems like
linear programming and dynamic
programming transportation algorithms
and so forth and so I i got into how
powerful those could be
I kind of like that people made money
with math because I saw a lot of the
people that went through the physics
programs it would end up with a PhD and
I didn't think they were doing that
really I'm glad they love what they do
I'm sure they did but it seemed like you
can even be more impactful unless you
win a nobel prize in physics or
something it seems like you'd be really
impactful by affecting big on certain
decisions in government agencies around
the world and big corporations it really
seemed like it mattered Jack the person
I'd that comes first to mind to me is a
guy named George McKinnon he was the
executive that when I was a new ciso at
Nationwide Insurance it was his
questions that I couldn't answer that
prompted me to begin working on fair and
without that conversation with him I
wouldn't be sitting here and that the
questions were because I know them I
know them I get to ask so the questions
were you know i just presented my
strategy in my budget request of many
millions of dollars and he said so tell
me Jack how much risk do we have and you
know if he'd asked me to talk about the
threats we face through the
vulnerabilities we had I could have
talked all day his question is how much
risk do we have and I shrugged my
shoulders and said well lots and he said
if we spend this 12 million dollars you
asking for how much lesser of school we
have and I said well less and and I left
that meeting recognizing that those were
not trivial questions but they were
reasonable questions and I needed to
have a reasonable answer so the last 13
years has been spent you know I'm
developing an answer to that le my
answer is a similar to Doug's actually
it was my high school math teacher and I
do remember his name is his the David
Nelson for a couple reasons one somewhat
more humorous but he didn't give partial
credit because his idea was that you
know if you're building a dam and you
get a calculation wrong and that damn
worse you can't go back and get partial
credit for that so it forced me to
much more precise or much more accurate
and what I did but the other thing that
he did which really helped me was it
when I was a junior in high school he
got me to start teaching the freshman
algebra class and his view well he was
lazy he wanted telling us to do it work
but his idea was you can't know
something or you can't claim to know
something until you can teach it and
particularly when your teeth teaching
math even if you find it objective
systematic and logical there are a lot
of people who don't see it that way and
how to explain something that you may
can be convinced is completely logical
to someone who thinks differently and
that's really guided me throughout my
career because very rarely do you run
into people who think exactly the way
you do so being able to try and
understand where they're coming from
from their questions and then tailor
your response so they can have better
understanding I was really fortunate to
get introduced to that way of
approaching explaining problems in high
school yeah and also I'm sure we'll come
around with Mike if anybody has a
question to jump in but I'm just going
to keep down going down my list so
obviously all three of you have
accomplished quite a bit already in your
career is there something in your career
that may not be widely known that you're
very proud of like something that that
came up that you were able to accomplish
and it could be something very public to
it could be you know works that we've
already cited or something that but is
there something that you are most proud
of and and why and how did that have
that come about or let me ask us a
different way I think i stumped you guys
with that question if you guys had to do
over would you do something different or
would you tackle a problem sooner
there's there something that you would
want to shift or change the way you
approached studying what you did in my
second book the failure risk management
you know the reason you write a new book
is to get in all the stuff you didn't
get in
alas Brooke that's always what's
motivated me so in my second book just
after that I was coming across a lot of
new and already existing research about
a placebo effect in analysis that if you
go through a process that seemed
structure informal you're going to feel
better about your estimates you're going
to feel better about managing risk just
because hey what through a procedure was
developed by a big consulting firm and
we rated everything is on a scale of one
to five and it's all how you be below
they all have colors red yellow green
and is your risk management better and
they would say yeah you know I think the
consensus is it's definitely better well
even though I kind of hinted at that in
the book there's really quite a lot more
now I think I'd make that case even
stronger now now I do I added more of
that to the third edition of first book
but it seems like that was a big thing I
could add Jack do you have anything that
you wish you could focus more on or do
differently I would probably so some of
the more recent developments and fair
expanded the view from measuring risk to
understanding being able to measure risk
management you know because at the end
of the day how much risk we have today's
is a lagging indicator of our ability to
manage risk in the past decisions we
made in our ability to execute got us to
where we are right and i had actually
kind of developed the early notions
around that 68 years ago and then put it
on a shelf and really only brought it
out publicly in the book a month ago and
i'm wishing i not weigh it down yeah
i'll lead you only actually what i'm
doing right now the writing this paper
to define risk which is really being my
basis first living for the last few
years it's I'm glad I'm doing it now i
wish i could have solved or find a
solution way i'm thinking about it
earlier it's something that bothered me
from the time I was in graduate school
when it was almost assumed that risk was
volatility or
uncertainty of variance and that just
didn't sit well with me because clearly
you know we all know that risk relates
to the adverse aspect so how everyone
could is just to assume something that
seemed lately wrong concern to me I wish
I could have had time to work on this
earlier but it's taken three and a half
years of almost a full time effort so I
don't think I would have had to had the
opportunity earlier yeah well we're glad
you're doing it now so Doug in the you
mention your second book the failure
risk management and that was written
back in two thousand eight correct two
thousand during the amount of financial
actually manuscript was done just before
the beginning of the whole crisis and
then i got one more shot in the check of
edit to add any new material and so it
came out really early 2000 I ok but you
stayed three reasons that risk
management fails and I'm gonna read them
here so first the failure to measure
invalidate methods as a whole or in part
number to the use of components that are
known not to work and three the lack of
use of components that are known to work
and that was six years ago five six
years ago that you wrote that how have
you seen that change if at all have you
seen that evolve well there certainly at
least seems to be a little bit more
skepticism you know I have a lot of big
pharma clients several and when you look
at how they test a new drug they assume
it's a placebo until they prove
otherwise now if you think about it if
we actually analyze decision-making
methods and risk assessment risk
management methods that way we come up
with completely different methods you
assume it's a placebo and then you try
to prove it's not i was going to add to
that in the second book there's a whole
chapter called the ivory tower of babel
and it's all about different definitions
of risk and i talked about Frank Knights
definition and the pmo p.m. Bach
definition that includes positive
outcomes as risk and there's a couple
bizarre engineering ones where risk is a
binary thing and uncertainties arranged
it's there
bunch of goofy stuff but ultimately I
come right back to raleigh is we're
talking about risk representing a
function of various magnitudes of losses
and probabilities usually expresses the
loss as loss exceedance so we're coming
back to the same place glad to hear that
we have yeah consensus that I think Jack
and I actually both raised our hand at
the beginning of the question when you
were asking which of these are higher
risk you said you died I'm not by myself
anyway all right we both raised their
hand on the one that you said was the
wrong answer but I think it's the wrong
answer for a couple of things we ended
up agreeing on one is we weren't
necessarily assuming that high
probability was near certainty it might
have been thirty percent or something
like that because I define in the book
in my book that if it's a near certainty
it's really a cost like Walmart doesn't
have a risk of shoplifting that's it
cost of doing business there your
companies don't have a risk of your
payroll right that's just a known cost
and in a way when they built the Empire
State Building there wasn't a risk of
death there's proximately you know the
deaths happened was some rate than those
large construction projects the Hoover
Dam and so forth the big risk was having
extraordinarily more than you expected
so it's all about comparing to
expectation the other so it was an issue
the other issue was conflating I think
possibly whether or not you even have
high probability high impact events
versus whether or not if you had one was
would it be worse given our definition
of high probability so but otherwise I
other than that we're on the same page
Jack as I mentioned needs to create our
affair and through the years you've
traveled quite a bit given a lot of
training and certified people on the
fair method how have you seen the
approach to measuring risk evolved
through the years you know because I
know that fair has evolved through the
years how do you see people adopting it
and things like that and where do you
see how important is the the training
and
that you did as part of risk assessment
sure so the evolution has been somewhat
of a surprise to me because you know I
was a CISO and so my world was
information technology and information
security sorts of things but I've had
you know a lot of people use it to
analyze a lot of different types of
types of scenarios and circumstances so
we've had people one bank used it to
determine an optimum overdraft threshold
for checking another another bank used
it to determine how much risk is
associated with providing banking
services to the new marijuana growing
industry in Washington state healthcare
organization used it to understand how
much risk associated with opening a new
bariatric treatment center 11 gentlemen
used it to analyze how much risk was
associated with letting his 16-year old
daughter drive to an event out of town
by herself it was more than he was
willing to live with but but you know so
so so seeing it used outside of the
technology context information security
context has been enlightening for me
because every time I go and work with a
client or someone who's using it in it
in a scope that's not my area of
expertise man I just soak that in
because I just learned from it but it's
gratifying for me to see that it's you
know that flexible and can be used in
that many circumstances as far as
training and certification goes the new
certification that's out there well
training I think is important because
you get people using nomenclature
consistently and concepts consistently
and such so it reduces variability and
how its applied you know the mistakes
and such and in the certification that
the Open Group provides around it to
this point about nomenclature and such
that first certification that's out
there is really all about terminology
concept this really doesn't focus on how
to apply it that's the second
certification that's coming out but we
you need to start with concepts and
terminology so that's then I know Doug
you do a lot of training as well correct
and where do you see the value of that
kind of thing I know you talk a lot
about calibration if you want to talk
about that for a bit yeah so are we
focus on methods like our pharma clients
we focus on methods that have actual
clinical trials of improving performance
so independent academic published
peer-reviewed studies where this kind of
method measurably outperforms an
alternative method well it turns out
that people most people can be taught to
be about as good as a bookie at putting
odds on things takes about a half a day
and our success raised by eighty five
percent about eighty-five percent of
people who go through calibration
training end up at the end of the
training about as good as a booking at
putting odds on things and this is done
in a series of trivia questions right
you take tribute test and you say true
or false a hockey puck will fit in the
golf hole you say true how confident are
you eighty percent right you do this
over over again until we get a large
number of trials of each one and then we
show you how bad you were and then you
take another test we show you a few
techniques there's a few tricks things
like the equivalent bet there's a few
other methods that are already in
literature we've actually this year
we've trained just over a thousand
people so we actually have more data on
calibration training than all the
published academic literature combined
on calibration training which adds up to
five or six hundred data points 500 600
people so there's a lot of great
research on that but we go a little bit
further because the whole point of
getting calibrated is just to use you as
an instrument so most of my clients they
can imagine easily a situation where if
they use an uncalibrated instrument and
some measurement it would cause a lot of
problems clients and nuclear power
clients in the pharma industry clients
in my engineering or big construction
management or any
like that they can easily come up with
situations where using an uncalibrated
instrument causes lots of problems but
when you think about it where does a lot
of the judgment come from regarding
cost-benefit analysis or risk analysis
or assessments of risk they're coming
from a human being and we almost never
know the performance of that human being
when they give us an answer of some kind
and so calibration has to do with
treating that person a little bit more
like how they're being used which is as
a measurement instrument as a
measurement instrument they have about
measurable performance and we know that
if you don't calibrate people they're
off by a lot and some are really bad
doctors are horrible by putting odds on
things for example but most
professionals including people in IT and
cybersecurity are about as overconfident
as Harvard MBAs your that's about where
you are when you start out at the end of
the training but that's just the
calibration training because ultimately
in addition to just being trained to be
a measurement instrument you have to
figure out what to do with those so we
say that's what you initially populate
monte carlo simulations with if you've
got what we call arm's reach data to
populate a monte carlo you use that but
you start with your calibrated estimates
and the reason we do that and this is
another thing the cover is we model your
current state of uncertainty so that we
can compute the value of additional
information now the formula for the
value of information if you don't know
this has been around for over 60 years
it's been part game fearing decision
theory for a lot of time it's not a new
thing but if you start computing the
economic value of information to reduce
uncertainty about where your big bets
are what's your risks car etc it turns
out you probably measure completely
different things and so that those are a
couple of levels of training we go
through so calibrations one but the
other track is for analyst people who
aren't the subject matter experts who
are going to be providing the estimates
but they're the people using the
estimates they're going to be building
models and so forth and there's a couple
levels of it there's an executive
overview where your main takeaways all
these conceptual ideas you know learning
about a loss exceeds curve it's like a
big aha moment like you get that one
done and then you get on to more tech
full stuff here's what you got to do
when you build a Monte Carlo here's how
you compute a value of information etc
and I want to change the topic a little
bit to dealing with skeptics obviously a
risk management risk analysis there's a
lot of opposition to some of the
techniques and maybe their new maybe
they're valid on some level but one of
the criticisms that I've heard at least
in our industry and information security
is this we can't do that because we
don't have lack we have a lack of data
but then they add a qualifier and they
say we have a lack of actuarial quality
data for you Ali what does that even
mean and and how valid is that type of a
criticism when you first suggested this
question and I read it I said you know
I'm reluctant to even answer this
question because it it seems as though
there's a false premise built into it in
that the data doesn't exist but really
this question gets to something more
fundamental which is what i mean by
sufficient data and i was wondering how
to answer that question and i was
thinking do I need to explain how models
work and help you create histograms and
PDFs and CDF's and I realized you know
there's a really simple example similar
to the example I talked about in my
presentation supposing you want to build
a house on the beach and you want to
know how far up Keats you need to build
your house to make sure that your house
doesn't get destroyed by wave and you
have a one in hundred year or one
percent tolerance in any given year
you're willing to tolerate the 100-year
event if you collect data for five years
and you connect all the wind-driven
waves over a five-year period you'll
probably have a million waves you ask a
normal statistician is that enough well
30 yeah if i want to calculate mean and
standard deviation 30 to 35 days so this
is you have a wealth of data would you
rather have that million data points of
wind-driven waves or would you rather
have 10 data points collected over 500
years of the tsunamis that hit that
Beach because if you take that million
data points and fit it to a mathematical
model very sophisticated
it will fit a curve based on the
understanding for the worst-case thing
that would happen would be a win driven
wave but in reality that ninety-nine
percent level event the 100-year event
is not going to be a wind-driven wave
it's going to be a tsunami so all you
need to do is use a very crude technique
10 data points in 500 years the 100-year
event will be the second highest lost it
gives me a much better estimate five
data 10 data points and no model versus
a million data points and a really
sophisticated model if I present to that
question that way how many would have
said 10 potato points in male model so
this Co question about data sufficiency
very often we think of data for
substance e in terms of number of data
points but if we're trying to model it a
certain confidence love when we're
looking at it on an annualized basis so
what's the one in hand your event it's
the number of years in the data
collection period that drives it so when
you look at the say the banking industry
and they want a model operational risk
many organizations believe that the way
you model your risk because you're
unique and I learned the term from Doug
earlier David the what is it the fallacy
of you the Union fouls unique unique
miss fancy the idea is that you believe
that because you're so unique none of
the other data applies to you well you
know if your bank there's certain
characteristics you have the dissimilar
to the other banks why did JP Morgan
have an unauthorized trading event and
suck gin and all these other yeah
they're all unique but they're all
exposed if you're in the trading
business you're exposed to rogue trader
risk what would you rather have if
you've never had a rogue trader event
use some other data and try and
extrapolate from a million data points
or use 10 data points from the industry
knowing that you'll be directionally
correct maybe not precise so I think
that's the fundamental problem here when
people talk about data sufficiency don't
realize there's a ton of data out there
it will help you get a directionally
correct number which in many cases is a
hundred times better than a measured
number
from a model based on data that's not
ideally relevant now one other quick
point I would make yeah the way I
presented this problem if you know that
the 100-year vent is going to be a
tsunami you'll say okay I need a model
tsunami separately the problem is many
times we don't know that our datasets
are categories are heterogeneous we
assume they're homogeneous we assume
there's only one kind of wave and then
everyone sucked how did this Black Swan
event take place our models are great
they model predicted the worst way of
whale ahead in wave all having a
thousand years is a 10-foot wave how did
I have a 30-foot wave in year six that's
fundamentally it sums up one of the
biggest problems about modeling and
whenever I've given a talk on what cause
of financial crisis it's or anything
relating to this its modeling requires
you to understand we have heterogeneous
data sets and we assume homogeneity and
and under those circumstances you
shouldn't be surprised when you have
these models the results that are
completely inconsistent with the models
and that sets up a softball a question
to your dog how do you actually what is
the criteria to measure a good model
what represents a good model well it
kind of is the same response to your
question about how do you answer the
skeptics models have a measurable
performance themselves I've had a bunch
of clients that were big six sigma
followers I can still tell you what
processes they don't measure they don't
measure their portfolio approval process
they don't measure their risk management
process they don't measure the return on
performance metrics so those big apex
things they don't they don't deal with
but the good news is is there really are
large clinical trials in published peer
review journals about the performance of
lots of pieces and we call it component
testing so one way to get the big
picture impact we're dealing with this
right now our client in Kenya so we're
measuring the performance of the global
intervention
model which they're talking about
agricultural interventions for the
developing world so it's not just in
Kenya it's all around and we built this
big mind Carlo simulation for dealing
with all sorts of agricultural
interventions irrigation dams
micro-financing see banks Tara scene and
other farming techniques etc so it's
this huge model and they select
different modules to deal with different
kinds of interventions and now they want
to set up a measurement for that this
was actually a recommendation from our
approach that all models are wrong so is
this one and we're going to set up a
process for measuring and improve in the
models we go ahead so we're continuously
validating it well one the best way to
do it ideally is to have great big
controlled experiments where you've got
a whole bunch of people using the global
intervention decision model to form a
whole portfolio of decisions and then a
bunch of people who aren't you track
them over decades because some of them
are you know very long impact sorts of
things and then you say look the people
who are using the global intervention
decision model were actually better so
it's the year 2080 and you finally
figure it out by the time you're off to
Windows 546 or whatever you figured out
that one is better than the other but
there's also component testing component
testings faster we can test individual
pieces of a whole system just like this
is how you do risk management risk
analysis on a racket that's never flown
before or the design of a nuclear
reactor that no one's ever built before
you still know the failure rates of
individual components of the system and
you can model a system and then you you
setup cascade common mode failures and
you say hey there's this problem that
happens some surprising percentage of
the time when I run these simulations so
you're actually testing components and
component testing gives you very fast
feedback there's already a lot of
literature on the performance of
components we know the performance of
calibrated estimators we know the
performance of naive statistical models
compared to human experts it's really
hard to beat a naive statistical model
by the way and when someone is a skeptic
my answer that because I'm really
answering both questions yeah when they
are skeptic I say hey I'm a sucker for
empirical evidence if you could show
one study that showed that people
actually made better decisions over a
significant number of trials using say
high medium low scale of one to five
putting on a heat map kind of stuff i
would start using it there is no such
thing the only studies that exists is
that they're no better or they're
actually slightly worse they add air in
fact one of the studies was this guy
babyboo desk ooh he actually studied how
people use ordinal scales like very
likely and likely and somewhat likely or
unlikely for for substitutes for
expressions of probabilities and he used
a term that I think actually kind of
directly relates to what Alli was saying
before he called it the illusion of
communication you and I both agree that
something's a medium risk and when you
debrief us you find out we meant
completely different things so that's
David budesh go he did a whole set of
experiments at surveys on this it adds
error it actually can make you worse off
than your unaided intuition alone so why
even adopt a method that makes things
worse you know that that phrase from
medicine first do no harm yeah let's
first do no harm let's not make it worse
above all else yes and that's something
that tony cox had worse than useless
yeah that's how I course than usually so
along the theme of skepticism we often
hear well fine and good but we're
dealing with intelligent adversaries and
consequently there's no way to predict
their behavior and so game off how would
you respond to that can actually respond
to that I mean I'm just a moderate but I
want to respond so actually a Wade Baker
and I did a presentation at RSA last
year where we actually took the actions
of the adversary as classified and the
virus rumor and we looked at how random
was that and it turned out to be
absolutely not random I mean that that's
what we do right a null hypothesis we
say if they're intelligent and apt and
adaptive that means that they if we
cannot predict them they must be random
I mean randomness is a core component of
crypto right let's make makes crypto
well do well is it there's randomness so
we said let's look for randomness or
more specifically that's like for the
lack of randomness and not only was it
there but like we didn't even need math
you know I mean it was there was so much
patterns in there I mean there was it
was so blatantly obvious that there were
patterns and therefore I mean anybody
who says and tells an adaptive therefore
we cannot predict their actions that
would indicate randomest and there
absolutely is no randomness so the other
the empirical side of that too I might
just interject there is that remember
we're comparing miles what's the
alternative model if somebody says well
you know we have these intelligent
actors and so they're really
unpredictable you can't just extrapolate
from historical data therefore I have to
rely on my experience and they say that
with no hint of irony right well you're
only comparing two models if the
alternative bottle is their intuition
how are they dealing with the human
actors what is measurably different now
I won't say the name but I was sitting
next to one of the letters in our essay
at the RSA conference and he made this
same point he said but the problem with
information securities you're dealing
with intelligent actors I said so you
think that differentiates you from
actuarial science or insurance do you
think they they never have to insure
against fraud or kidnapping I mean they
insure lots of things often what happens
is people think of the consumer side of
insurance my automobile in life and
health and so forth but actually
actuaries do with all sorts of risk that
include things exactly like that
including things they don't have
millions of data points for so if I can
jump off of that as well so when I'm
faced with the skeptic around data right
very often I'll include pretty much what
you just said which is any time a
decision is being made there's
comparisons being made based on some
model of some sort it's either the end
of
Jules mental model and Lord knows what
that looks like right yeah and data of
some sort and and so if they're pushing
back on we don't have enough you know
actuarial quality data or what I'm
saying for a quantitative analysis all
right what kind of data are you using
for your mental model that you're doing
you know it's always there's always the
model and there's always data and I
guarantee you that the data they're
drawing out a you know their memory
right is not going to be any better than
what we would get through some sort of
logical rational effort focused effort
and as far as the models go unless
they're you know some people with real
with great experience gathered over
years right they may have a very well
developed mental model right but that
doesn't scale with a dinner right and
and so but most people don't have that
and so if I'm putting if I have to bet
on a mental model versus some model
that's been kicked around right and and
hopefully been vetted and proven over
time that's where my money is going
every time good another question so this
is not a softball question this is
pretty guys oh so all three of you have
are on this panel because you've made
seminal contributions to advancing the
state of the art yet I think we'd all
agree that our risk analysis risk
management information security is not
reached the pinnacle of maturity and has
not achieved the sort of impact and
results that we hope to what do you
think it's going to take what
advancement of practice what advancement
of the state of the art will it take and
how long is going to take to get there
all right everyone just has to read our
stuff
yeah but there's truth to that though
seriously there's truth to that because
because so much of what is out there is
so bad I mean really so when I was
developing fair I literally swore off
reading anything written for the
industry for like four years because two
reasons I I didn't want it to pollute my
thinking right and it just drove me to
madness to see the stuff that was being
published out there that could logically
stand on its own you know in any way
shape or form right and and so I think
you know certainly these guys and I like
to thank the stuff that I'm writing is
contributing to I think that's what's
going to carry the profession forward
and but until there's and frankly I'm
not an optimist in terms of how quickly
it's going to happen because there is so
much inertia out there so much inertia I
mean I I'm in meetings you know and I'm
in industry groups and such where where
the preponderance of people around the
room can't agree on a definition of the
problem we're trying to solve so until
you get past that right it's it's just
painful also I'd like to add you're not
alone you may recall that we had a
financial crisis a few years ago and
banks who claim to be experts in risk
management we're all taken by surprise
when they found out that the risk was
actually a hundred times higher than
their ninety-nine percent level
confidence and predicted you know in the
wrist space I'm actually very frustrated
in particular in operational risk I
don't go to conferences or read other
people's well I didn't say all but
majority is the majority stuff that's
out there is you know you can list the
things that are just conceptually flawed
or illogical or just inefficient so you
know but again one of the reasons we
have this problem is you have a
principal
agent issue this is part of the reason
one of the reasons we have the financial
crisis where you will do what's in your
best interest and even though you're
working for a certain firm sometimes
your interests diverge sometimes your
interests diverge and when they do the
verge you will do what's in your
interest at the expense of what's best
for the company and particularly in what
drove the financial crisis is these guys
knew they were taking too much risk if
you read our paper and the appendix we
talked about the what happened at AIG
with credit default swaps and I can't
remember now but this was all principal
agent issues people were being very well
compensated for doing things that looked
good on paper based on the metrics that
were being observed but actually they
were the wrong metrics so what they were
doing was destroying value but they were
being compensated very well for it among
other things they used methods like
value at risk and they figure out really
fast you can tail load risk right so you
can kind of hide all the risk by putting
it one end of the distribution because
your metric doesn't look at how extreme
the loss can be it just looks at what
your five percent worst case or one
percent worst-case scenario could be so
the metrics themselves actually
incentivized hiding risk so let me
explain what that means is it you know
just not to get too technical but if I
have a model and the model says at the
99 percent level my risk is ten thousand
dollars well that seems like okay it's
not so bad but VAR models only tell you
what happens at that point they don't
give you any indication of what could
happen beyond that what if I tell you
that at the 99 percent level it's 10,000
but beyond ninety-nine percent in that
one percent time I'm going to kill you
that's different now how do you solve
that problem virus is being heavily
criticized but the technical solution to
that is to use what's called t-bar where
you simply take the probability weighted
mean of that space beyond VAR ok but
people can game that as well so this is
the fundamental problem you've got smart
people who understand the metrics
exploit the weaknesses in the metrics
and this will happen again so really
it's you've got to have someone
overseeing this stuff who has the right
incentives because again if you bring in
a consultant to validate the model who
are you going to choose to validate your
model someone who you know will give you
the right answer what happened it you
know the credit rating agencies you want
to get a triple-a credit rating no
problem pass this fee and we'll be happy
to give it to you so all of a sudden
junk got a triple-a rating so here's
that you know until we address this
conflict of interest and the
principal-agent problem we really can't
have confidence in any of the metrics
we're working with so how much time you
have left here Lee said we have because
I know we've just completely gone off
schedule and I I don't care I mean I
love it so but you know maybe we should
do a vote or maybe you should make an
executive decision because let me at
least get one more question and yeah
anybody else has some questions we can
go there okay so around around this
skepticism for this type of thing
obviously with the financial crisis and
all the other there's always a headline
showing the failure of quantitative
analysis and I think Warren Buffett even
said beware of geeks with spreadsheets
right I think all three of you at some
point have been labeled a geek with
spreadsheet in that context right what
is the how dare you well by others
but what who are the big biggest
skeptics like what and you know jack
gonna for you and inference security it
was surprising to hear when years ago
when you talked about the biggest
skeptics that you've come across what
are these skeptics and what are the
objections what are the big objections
to this type of this I've run into two
classes of skeptics those who see the
world strictly through a black and white
lands there is no gray in their world
right there world is binary it is
compliant it's not compliant there's
risk there's no risk right they can't
deal with the gray you run into that not
infrequently but that's but the more
common is the person who took high
school statistics and bull and believes
that they understand probability and
statistics and such and that well if I
don't have 30 data points and I can do
quantitative analysis you know and and
they will sit there and they will argue
to the nail I had private I was doing a
workshop with one client where we were
trying to get subject matter expert
estimates from one of their subject
matter experts using calibrated methods
and such and and I said you know what
would what would your estimate be for
this event and I forget what the event
was and he said I couldn't I couldn't
give you a number i said well you know
here's how it works i reiterated he'd
been through calibration thing right he
didn't do well but using the fifteen
percent that and na said no i couldn't
so i said so you're telling me that this
event i think it was like you know the
frequency of an insider you know trying
to hack your network router on the
inside not the outside of your network
you know I trusted an insider I said you
think it could be I don't know a million
times a year oh yeah it could be a
million times really so how many people
are we talking about in here do they
have jobs and this sort of thing and I
could not get him to actually make an
estimate he would not under any
circumstances give me a range
and we actually asked some data on that
so since we've calibrated about a
thousand people remember it succeeds
about eighty-five percent of time about
another ten percent of the time they
improve significantly but don't quite
reach statistically indistinguishable
from a calibrated instrument and five
percent don't seem to improve all my
wife pointed out my wife's a math
teacher math professor at a local
community college and she pointed out
that you've heard of dyslexia there's
actually something called dyscalculia
and about the same percentage of the
population has dyscalculia as dyslexia
and it's about 5% in other words numbers
are utterly meaningless to them they
don't even understand they don't have a
context for them and I don't know if
that's it was just an observation I
don't want to publish that yet I think
just the interesting observation that
there are five percent that just don't
get it through that you know everybody
else is getting it but at least here's
one thing we have now we have all this
day that says hey everyone else got it
what's wrong with you so at least they
they know then it's not just the
procedure for the training or whatever
they know that other people are actually
exceeding that these things I I guess I
have a more complex variety of skeptics
maybe I just break decompose it more I
have a challenge in my first book it's a
ten-thousand-dollar prize and I'm happy
to write the check anytime for anyone
who could prove that you can prove
anything with statistics it's not even
been attempted to be claimed the book
was first published in 2007 with state
of fries it sounds like a joke I'm
serious about it but people say it all
the time and I said well then you've got
ten thousand dollars coming if you can
prove it I'm serious and it's been out
there no one's even sent me a single
email saying i think i might have you on
something because obviously it's absurd
i can probably take a stab at the
converse but you can prove nothing this
is it or well something more sinister
there's the expression statistics don't
lie but Liars use statistics right I
heard that one too I would
say well it's true I can prove anything
to you a statistics but you can't prove
anything to me was the distance there is
it I mean you have to have some
knowledge about these things so yeah
what they mean is it's easy for people
to get suckered by numbers if that's
what they made sure yeah it's possible I
run into other situations where people
will say I've run into the 30 sample
size they I say well you know that's
just the point where you can use the Z
statistic as opposed to the student T
the student t and the Z statistic
converge at 30 you can just use it
that's what that meant because I
guarantee or that chapter on student T
distributions was for smaller samples of
them 30 right and I was taught telling
this story at lunch that I'm in a room
full at a farm a client where there's
several PhD biostatisticians an
additional pharmacologist and all these
other kind types of people and I asked
them here's a results of a sample of 5 I
showed them a sample of 5 out of their
whole organization is this statistically
significant and a bunch of people shook
their head right away well the only
correct answer is you don't know I
haven't told you my p-value my
significance level I haven't say the
hypothesis yet there's all sorts of
things but certainly you could have a
hypothesis you were testing where sample
of 5 was significant and it was useful
and told you more than you knew before
so people had this pre math judgment
they make about what uncertainty
reduction they can get from the data
they have or how much uncertainty
reduction is justified given the risk
and make me know the magnitude of my
decision and my uncertainty about it
they're just winging it you know when
someone says we don't have sufficient
data to measure this I say show me your
math because that's actually a
mathematical plane when somebody says
they don't have sufficient data to
measure this what they mean or what they
should mean is that I have already
worked out in advance how much
uncertainty reduction I get from my
given data and that uncertainty
reduction doesn't actually reduce
uncertainty for my current state without
looking at the data actually no one's
ever produced their calculation to
demonstrate this it's just simply a
presumption of people throughout and for
reasons like the uniqueness fallacy I
used to call it the fallacy of close
analogy
and that I found out there was a term
for it and I certain calling uniqueness
fallacy but the fallacy of close analogy
is one of the reasons why people think
they have very little data when it
factors quite a lot of we're resourceful
enough right I the anecdote I was using
before was my insurance company has
technically no data on my rate of death
other than I haven't died yet so how do
we work out a life insurance premium for
me aren't I unique there's no one else
exactly like me well of course no one
else is exactly like me but they can
still interpolate from larger
heterogeneous sets so yes you're all
unique as snowflakes just like the
trillions of other snowflakes all right
you're all uniformly you need okay and
we can steal interpolate when someone
says I cannot extrapolate from
dissimilar data they just shot down our
whole claim no expertise what's their
experience based on right I suppose one
category I'll just insert this one
special category of skeptics since this
is the group I think I run into possibly
more skeptics in information security so
I since I have a little bit of crossover
with information security and my other
work I really think people information
security might be a little bit more
likely you know I'll reserve this as a
hypothesis until like collect more data
but anecdotally I'm observing that
they're a little bit more likely to
believe their unique and special but
their risk are actually different from
my risk of my clients who dig mines in
Canada or have no risk of drought in the
Horn of Africa or something like that
well we get that argument all the time
we r you know our risk is different ya
know yeah it's not everybody's responds
only not different I mean everybody's
wrist different subway I suppose but
we're unique uniformly different ratio
believing you would be accommodating you
believe in your review hey I'm all about
like I said I'm a sucker for empirical
evidence and I have simple too small to
be statistically significant trials that
we can set up in spreadsheets where we
can do tests over and over again to
estimate the means or meetings and
populations and if somebody doesn't
believe those simple equations we can
set up a simulation and I can just bet
real money until they run out or until
they give up and say I have another
anecdote to talk about information
security people so I do a lot of
statistical research and stuff like that
and I'll present to security people the
research i do and also present to
statisticians talking about the the code
and the language and all that stuff
talking about how I arrived at things in
my industry and security people say yeah
I came up with this and they're like
we'll wait how'd you do that I think you
know principal component analysis a
hierarchical clustering stuff like
they're like slow down a bit go through
that again you know and then I'm gonna
talk institution statisticians and I'll
say you know principal component
analysis and I'm like oh you know like
that's the under discussion oh but
security people are very very skeptical
they're like I don't really go through
all of that again you know explain how
that works because that that doesn't
match my statistics course from high
school you know another angle that I
think we should take is we should invite
skepticism absolutely be skeptical of
models I just say be equally skeptical
of your expert intuition hold this you
know judge that by the same standards
what's the performance of that method it
is a method that has been measured by
the way it has a measurable performance
and many components many parameters of
that method have been measured we know
that people are statistically
overconfident we know that people are
highly inconsistent no matter how many
decades of experience they have they
can't seem to get the same answer twice
you know you ever had to sit down and
judge a list of things like the cost of
an effort or the risk of a bunch of
different things done judgmental list
should the order of the list matter it
shouldn't and it does it's been tested a
whole bunch of times just the different
orders of the list it's called anchoring
it's a well-established effect now so we
have all of these psychological
weird quirks that we have but here's the
key thing remember no matter what you're
doing it's about a model and all models
are wrong but some models are measurably
more useful than others you know the
story of the guy is getting ready to go
hiking in the woods right one guy sits
down and starts taking off his hiking
boots and puts on his running shoes and
his buddy since what are you doing he
says well I heard you're a bears in the
woods today so I thought I better put
out my running shoes his but he says
well you can't outrun a bear he says I
don't have to outrun the bear i have to
outrun you right that's all we're doing
with the methods I'm sorry if everyone's
heard that a bunch of times but that's
all we're doing with methods we're
talking about measurably better you
don't have to go for perfection it's
just better than it was before yeah
Patrick circus certain species of wolves
that lie there hunting techniques if you
outrun me because they have sent some
runners up ahead you'll just get eaten
before i geti yeah that's that's it
that's true in nature so I'll have to
know the threat right Patrick you have
to know your threats the other thing I'd
like to comment yeah I think everybody
probably knows by now that I worked in
medicine for a long time and one of the
most astonishing things that I learned
early on is the role of expert judgment
in the assessment of clinical outcomes
non-medical people tend to assume that
medicine has all this great data and
depending if it's Pharma if it's medical
therapy maybe but if it's a surgical
modality you know not so much and I
think the big secret information
security people don't get this is that
really every discipline relies rather
heavily at times on the role of expert
judgment physics chemistry everything
so I just want to throw that in but
remember about the Wolves when you start
talking about marriage I you know
there's always a needle exceptions so if
we evaluated a drug based on anecdotal
exceptions homeopathy works great
because then you can always think of an
anecdote where it worked right but so i
think we'll try to wrap it up here but
if we could just go through each of you
and just say sort of a long Russell's
question about where where should people
go like if a lot of the people i think
practitioners are always looking for the
next thing to learn the next thing to
look at what's the resource that's
helped you or you can even say you know
go read my book or something like that
but done or what would you recommend
people go go do to learn more it might
be a loaded question but well a lot of
the things that i would recommend for
that are things actually cited in my
book so yeah go read my blog so so
that's a one one-stop shopping to go
look for all that but I would say one
key thing just look outside your own
discipline yeah it's not new it's been
done before I tell everybody no matter
what you're measuring just assume it's
been measured before assume you've got
more data than you think assuming you
need less date or anything those are
very productive assumptions they almost
always turn out to be true so no matter
what you're assessing just assume that
somebody outside your own has done
something like it that you're really not
unique that's a great place to start to
assume you not unique yeah along those
lines when I said that I had sworn off
for those years anything you know
written by anybody in our profession
what I substituted was materials written
by people outside of our profession
right and I had literally within two
years i read forty some different books
on probability and statistics and
decision making and and just weird stuff
that was really outside of what we might
think of as applicable to this problem
but that that had some little nugget in
there that really fed the development of
the concepts and such and so a big part
of it too is is being open minded and
open to being receptive to things that
might seem tangential but my
not right because that's I think we're
leaps sometimes occur right it's a
mutation event if you will mentally for
you in terms of how you're approaching
or thinking through a tough problem
because these are not trivial problems I
mean even if we get the nomenclature
down straight and we get decent broken
models you know we're still faced with
some really tough challenges and getting
past those because we're not unique
right sometimes takes prodding or some
sort of insider from from an unexpected
source and so you have to be receptive
to those sources when you're walking
through Barnes and Nobles or whatever
you see a title of just what the heck
does that mean right pick it off the
shelf because probably a quarter of the
books that i read that really
substantial in helping me grow my own
understanding and develop fair didn't
come from the statistics shelf or the
business shelf or anything like that it
was something kind of like you know lady
tasting tea or something like that I was
like that's odd and I pick it up and
there'd be something really you know
meaningful in there so just
receptiveness to two things outside of
what you might think I'd like to just
let go the same sentiments because none
of us are omniscient but there's a lot
of there a lot of good nuggets in
virtually everything I for a long time
stopped reading things in the risk
management space because I saw so much I
disagreed with and it was just
fundamentally wrong and that I think one
of the things we need is it why we wrote
the paper is there needs to be an
industry consensus definition of risk
that's a robust theoretically valid
definition and then we can have an
intelligent debate on this on many of
these topics rather than you know people
talking past each other so I by the way
also some of the stuff I've written a
few years ago i'm embarrassed it hit me
too so you know as we grow we learn more
and recognizing the mistakes we've made
alright well thank you everybody thank
for
our panelist for taking the time today