so I apologize in advance for the ICP
theme as I said it amused me greatly at
the time and then I realized that
there's a problem because it's clowns
and as we all know clowns are truly the
biggest the biggest threat facing
America nowadays so who am i and the
disclaimer I'm a security professional
by day x pentester disassembler of
things evaluator of risk now I seem to
be in that management consulting role
where I try to convince people that
security might not be a bad thing but
not in a beat them up kind of way I'm no
longer saying no I say let's figure out
a better way are as my boss likes to
call it solutioning your problem space I
say that with a straight face because I
am this far from getting a consultant as
neck tattoo I'm not speaking for my
employer especially if I still have one
after the end of this talk I'm also a
lawyer I advise my fellow security
professionals I see a lot of contracts
generally people send me employment
contract statements of work master
service agreements of what not it could
be their entry-level pen testers trying
to go r is my company trying to screw me
they can be veterans who are hey I've
been doing this for a while and I want
to license some technology to somebody
are they trying to screw me and I get to
get a really good like mirror I get to
have a really good visibility into our
industry by doing that and there's
nothing as creepy as me saying to
somebody at a conference through there
like the chief count their counsel for
large shop like man like like fire I
let's go yeah read a bunch of your
contracts and like how did you see them
like because I'm the guy who doesn't say
no
I write a lot of contracts even though
my day job is doing security I get the
job of writing statements of work a lot
because well I'm a lawyer I am NOT a
juggalo as i said the stroke was funny
at some point i think we've hit that
point so what our contracts their formal
promises they clarify terms that we're
agreeing to they define satisfaction of
promises and I know that sounds strange
but I promise to do this thing well how
do we know when we're done right simple
contract I will sell you my car for five
thousand dollars well how do I know that
we're done you have my car I have five
thousand dollars were there other
promises entailed in this in this
conversation did I promise something
else did that go away during our
negotiations because if you've ever sold
especially if you sell consulting
services you know how you talk about a
lot of things and then you send them
that you send them a proposal and they
go I really like the proposal except for
one thing it's too expensive can we can
we can we do something different and the
next thing you know you've cut a bunch
of stuff and they still think they're
getting what you originally proposed and
that doesn't work so the point of a
contract is to lock it down and
formalize it and say yeah at one point
we talked about that at one point we
talked about a five course dinner you're
getting half of a Big Mac because we're
paint you're paying one-tenth of what we
originally what we originally talked
about so the purpose of a contract is to
is to base is to lay all that out in
such a way that it's formal so that way
at the end no one's going but I think
you owe me this it's how you assign
risks of unknowns who here has ever
knocked over a system during a pen test
I'm the only person who puts up their
hand and amidst that like oh yeah did
you need bns that shop yeah who's
responsible like who's responsible that
actually causes business damage
in your country you've got some like
while will attend to not break
everything we touch if we do we're not
responsible for it like we're
responsible but we're going to help you
fix it maybe but if we cause you
business losses it's not on us let you
be in your contract it's the intent to
be bound it's a promise that is
enforceable so kinds of contracts
there's unilateral which is a promise
for performance the first person who
gives me ten bucks will get this role of
this roll of tape it's it's one promise
and performance so the first person
asked me ten bucks gets the tape then
there's bilateral which is a promise for
a promise if spiff rogue just says hey
I've got ten bucks i'll give it to you
for that tape well he's now he's not
offering ten bucks he's offering a
promise to give me ten bucks and for
some people that's the same as ten bucks
for other people it's dramatically
different it's substantially less
valuable but and then there's
quasi-contract there are things that
aren't contracts that still kind of bind
people we have promissory estoppel which
is a fancy way of saying I relied on
your promise and then there's
detrimental reliance which is I relied
stupidly on something you said like I
relied on your validation that this
company was handling pci data correctly
and therefore I is a bank and suing even
though i have no contract with a certain
qsa I'm suing them anyway so basic
requirements a contract are questions of
a contract is was there a promise did
someone actually promise to do a thing
exactly what was promised and then was
their consideration
consideration is value I promise you a
thing for a thing both of those promises
may have some value but there has to be
something in value and something of at
least minimal value oftentimes contract
textbooks will talk about one single
peppercorn or a penny or a dollar
doesn't have to have significant value
just has to have some value promised
itself is consideration in a bilateral
contract it's a promise to do something
or not do something is consideration
however what is in consideration is
promising to do something you already oh
now when I said I'll give someone this
roll of tape and I don't they give me
ten bucks like don't give them the tape
and I say well and for another contract
if you're next or two bucks will give
you the tape no I already owed you the
tape so that isn't consideration for
that second contract and then the
questions are was the performance
actually done we promised something did
you get back so breach of contract is
when you didn't get what you expected to
get I failed to perform as agreed and
there's two kinds of breaches there's
material which is the thing that I
haven't done is so core to the agreement
like I'm going to pay you for a
penetration test well the penetration
test is probably material to the
contract and the payment is probably
material to the contract something like
it will get delivered on a certain day
may or may not be material right a late
pentest report may be as good as a not
late pen test report but not getting
paid its material and the importance of
material breach versus in material
breach is what it allows you to do if
it's a material breach the other side
the innocent side gets to say nope I'm
out I don't care if the contract said I
am withdrawing
I'm going to do other things now a non
material breach say for example I
promise in my contract that I will
provide a pen castrum from give you a
report and the report will be
confidently written and instead I
subcontract that out to someone who's
like half littering so it's a pen test
there's a report and it's just badly
written you might if you want to make
that into your like your customer facing
letter you may say I have to rewrite
this it cost me an extra five hundred
dollars or a thousand dollars to rewrite
your your bad performance so while it's
not a material breach I can likely get
some compensation for that screw up so
damages when there is a breach of
contract there's expectation if you had
done what you said you were going to do
I was going to expect this and I can I
can be made whole by saying say for
example i was going to resell this
product on so i buy it from you for five
thousand dollars i have a buyer who's
going to pay seven you don't deliver it
to me so i can't deliver it on to my
buyer i was expecting two thousand
dollars prize two thousand dollars
profit i can sue you for the two
thousand dollars i was expecting that 2
grand had everything gone as planned I
would be 2 grand richer that's
expectation sometimes we might not know
what that value is so we put it in the
contract and say liquidated damages if
this goes wrong you owe me a thousand
bucks because I we can't calculate what
I'm out really so just it will just
write it now as a thousand bucks and
then another concept of breach of
contract is mitigation if I know that
you're not going to uphold your end of
the bargain or you don't uphold your end
of the bargain I have a duty to attempt
to minimize my damages usually this is
often done in employment contracts I
hire you to do a thing
we don't start because reasons and you
go well I was contracted to go do this
work for you for two weeks but nothing
happened and I didn't find any other
work so I pretty much spent two weeks on
reddit eating eating nothing but Cheetos
no you to minimize your losses you
should have done things like go out and
find other work you should have
mitigated your damages as opposed to the
job that didn't materialize and then
there's anticipate Ori breach which
allows me to say you have made no
attempts to perform under this and
because of your ineffective are
non-existent attempts to perform under
this I think you're not going you cannot
finish you cannot actually perform it's
like usually this is often brought in as
things like contracting you said you're
going to paint my house and it was going
to be done by the end of October it's
halfway through October and you haven't
shown up you haven't even asked me what
color paint to use you can't possibly
complete it in time unpacking out
because you I am anticipating that
you're going to breach I'm out and then
there is two other concepts called
waiver and latches which is in the
performance of the contract there are
certain ways that one side does not make
does not fulfill all the needs and the
other side doesn't care enough to call
it out we call that waiver where say for
example you promise something to be done
on a certain date it shows up two days
later if I don't if I don't call that
out if I don't say when I was two days
late that's that's a problem if we keep
on doing it where it's always two days
late eventually i'm not able to say oh
yeah six weeks ago that was two days
late i'm not paying because we've waived
it I've been called it out I haven't
said anything so
before I start talking about actual
kinds of contracts I want to point out
that getting clever with contracts is
not always a good idea a lot of people
ask me to write really just nasty
contracts with ugly penalty clauses and
the like and I try to school them not to
because unfair one-sided contracts don't
help anybody for this reason and i'm
going to give an example like hiding
terms under other headers if you read a
contract it usually has a header for
each section so that way we're going to
talk like non-disclosure you may not
disclose anything you learn under this
because it's important to us thank you
if you hide another clause in that
header like non-disclosure and
assignment of intellectual property
because you're going to breeze through
and go oh yeah non-disclosure
non-disclosures non-disclosure don't
care but if you hide something else
you're being a dick and it means that if
you're willing if you're willing to do
that in the contract first thing you see
when we're actually talking about going
from a sales pitch remember sales
pitches everything is wonderful right
everyone is on their best behavior it's
like dating but you want to have one
hint about what is this person like when
things are more settled are they going
to be a horrible horrible person and the
contract is the first time you can see
what are these people actually going to
be like when things get a little it see
ya over brought assigning of unrelated
rights I've seen this in a bunch of
contracts like all intellectual property
you've ever developed his arse like no I
probably walked in with a cup you know a
couple of inventions that that was that
was made on my time or a previous
employers time not yours cannot has but
you look for that you'll like wait a
minute you want that you're going to be
a pain in the ass to work with and the
takeaway I have is this is the first
time you get to see how the working
relationships going to work if they're
going to be a pain in the ass now
four weeks into this they're going to be
horrible and sometimes you take a look
at their contract and you go this tells
me bad things about you you're going to
be a pain you're going to try to screw
me and I'm thinking of a few friends who
are dealing with this where someone sold
them some you know someone brought them
in to do some work and everything was
cool they did the work and then it was
like yes we'd like to be paid we'd like
to be paid our expenses for this and the
person who brought the men's like uh
yeah about that things and some people
require the threat of a lawsuit to pay
up some people won't pay even after the
suits been settled you know the Donald
Trump argument like yes screw you know I
may provide you may provide the services
I'm not paying you until you make me and
the problem is is that if you know going
in when you see the contract as being
very one-sided means they're planning on
screwing you and it makes sense to say
maybe I should hold off maybe I should
renegotiate the contract or if you are
you know thankfully in our industry
where there might be another contract
just waiting to happy you go nope not
doing business with you maybe you should
try to find someone more desperate so
getting clever the contracts continue
these are ways of being clever with
contracts that are actually helpful and
I call this acceptable cleverness the
brown Eminem clause those of you who are
under the age of 35 there was once a
band called van Halen and what makes
them important is that they were one of
the first big arena rock shows prior to
them even Big Show's might be all their
equipment might fit in two or three
18-wheel trucks Van Halen's show was
like 15 18 wheel trucks and they
required certain engineering
capabilities for the building as they
and it has to hold this much weight we
need this much power we need this much
crew and constant promoters sleazy
creatures that they are we're just
signed whatever contract and there's a
case where that Hale and stage show
actually damaged the property because it
wasn't built to hold the weight so David
Lee Roth the lead singer comes up the
idea of in this contract and the
contract rider is like 85 pages because
it's also all the specs like here's
where the power has to be here's how the
lights have to get set up here's this
this this and this and they put a clause
in that said there will be a bowl of
M&MS in the dressing room there will be
no brown M&MS in that bowl and many
people when first seeing this go oh god
it's just like rock-star pretentiousness
instead it's a very very quick way of
determining whether or not you actually
read the requirements and are producing
something that I can work with right
David Lee Roth can't run you know he
can't have its own crew go and check
power you can't check the engineering of
engineering specs on the building but
it's really easy to go no brown M&MS
they read the contract I'm a fan of the
tech version of that the RFC 1149
requirements for any network gear some
of you laugh some of you should look it
up its IP over avian carrier and there
is nothing like putting that in a
requirement to see what happens because
you get a sales guy was like oh of
course it's RFC 1149 compliant there's a
sales engineer going he's it at you I
the guy who is we're trying to sell this
to is clearly an asshole he's smiling
and I don't like it I don't know why and
you watch the sales engine going I'll
get back to you on that actually did
that parade I was a tape a robot tape
library and it's like is it RFC 1149 and
the sales guy was like
course it is and part of the job no I
would just get back because he's asking
us we had some other requirements we
wanted as well they would ago of course
it's firewire compatible it's cozy sup
firewire so make it make sure
everybody's actually read like if you
have specific weird requirements like
you have a union requirement for for
your prevailing wage or you've got
nationality requirement you can't have
any non-americans on the contract or
something like that you want to make
sure that they've read that weirdo
requirement now instead of going three
weeks then were like oh did you mean
that yeah yeah you did so quickly do
something that should make them laugh
that's common it's very common to see
recycled contract languages especially
in this industry I've read my favorite
is one that i got from someone in the
community was like i'm trying to sell
services to a midsize company in in the
space and i read the contract like are
these guys hooked up with yahoo because
all sometimes the contract specifies
saying the company other times it
specifies y'all I'm like are they yahoo
subsidiary and like we're like I don't
know why why you know yahoo has a
subsidiary in allentown I don't know and
then we finally asked the opposing
counsel and it's like oh yeah we just
took the boilerplate from Yahoo's terms
of service like have you heard of find
and replace I would just recommend that
i found it like he build he built his
clients in like twenty eight thousand
dollars to write that contract like I'm
in the wrong business so other things
you do with contracts is hedging risk
indemnification in the case of say for
example you're doing your operating is
like a qsa or your operating is an
auditor and you audit a system you audit
accompany you audit you audit and
application they may ask you to say if
you certify it as good or you you
identify the flaws and we fix all those
flaws and it still gets breached and it
causes us damage we want you to cover
our costs that's indemnification this
can be dangerous especially if you're a
small shop hold harmless is this is a
slightly less painful version of this
which just says you won't sue me for
this oftentimes I put I try to put this
in pen test contracts that I right where
it's
you will hold us harmless for our
activities in scope if we if we if we
knock over a system that you told us to
test and instead of us getting shell we
just dropped it you can't sue us for it
will do every attempt to you know
usually when I've language it says
something like we we will do everything
we can to not break it but if we do you
can't go after us for it liquidated
damages I don't know what my losses
maybe but let's set them now if this
happens you pay me X instead of how us
having to have later discussions about
it a limitation on damages even if I
break everything let's limit it at five
hundred dollars or ten thousand dollars
or whatever you're willing to whatever
the two sides are willing to agree to
but it's a hedging of the risk I don't
know what the damages may be let's set
them we can just fix them with
liquidated damages we can cap them with
a limitation clause and this snags so
many shops somewhere in that contract
you agree to follow missed 853 or 171
are you you attest to being ISO 27001
and it's always hidden there the amount
of ones I've read that have crazy
requirements like you're both FedRAMP
and PCI requirements for a shop that
writes software that doesn't touch
payment card are federally mandated data
but they'll put that requirement in
there it's a way of me if I'm right in
contract hedging that you may lose my
data you'll fit these that meet these
requirements usually will also pen in an
audit clause that allows me to check to
make sure you're doing that this is more
common in a something as a service
market but it's something there
other clauses you'll see in contracts or
how do we handle an eventual dispute we
may have a choice of law any dispute
under this happens under the laws of
Delaware or some other state you just
pick one that you you think you know how
it's going to go out that way there's no
surprises you can do a choice of venue
to prevent say for example i am a
pennsylvania corporation you ate of a
colorado company hires me I say choices
venue is Pennsylvania so that way I
don't have to go to Colorado if this
goes sour arbitration and mediation
clauses oftentimes you'll see these in
there to essentially require some step
before actual actual court litigation
oftentimes though these are one sided
one side will require arbitration but
not bind themselves to arbitration if
they choose to initiate it other things
like control of information and these
are his concepts you'll see there the
non-disclosure agreement all information
you gain under this stays with you you
don't publish it you don't use it
non-disparagement no matter what happens
during this engagement you will not talk
about us ever restrictions on
internal use how you will be holding our
sensitive information it only stays with
within your practice area it only stays
within named employees I've seen this a
lot when you're talking like large
consulting companies where say like
Deloitte we may you may say well I only
want the following enter the following
practice group to be able to see any of
the information that we're giving you we
don't want this to go to everyone at
deloitte restrictions and reuse and
marketing I should be seeing more of
this where you grant rights about your
marketing persona say
example and I've seen this in the field
where like a network manufacturer says
we've just sold you a million dollars of
equipment to solve a problem we would
like to be able to use your name and
your logo for our next pitch are for
marketing materials the problem is is
that how many people have ever done
really good open source in open source
intelligent using marketing white papers
I know I have there's nothing like
showing someone the network map of their
their SCADA environment by showing a
vendor presentation on it no like that's
that's the only secret information like
no google gave me that because the
vendors die vault that here's a picture
of your network map in a vendor in a
vendor of presentation so it's a way of
controlling information you're giving
assignment of intellectual property if
you develop any intellectual property
under this contract whose is it so you
have like work-for-hire where any
intellectual property you create while
you're working for us is ours we paid
you it's ours so how to interpret
contracts there's ambiguity I don't know
what that term means and you look for
defined terms in me in that or the
related contracts if you have multiple
contracts if you've defined the term you
can use the customary definition in the
trade or business I have seen some shops
that will try to bend this as in a
certain large information security
vendor that believes that a koala scan
plus manual verification is a
penetration test that is in their
language if you actually want someone to
get shell on your system or to pivot
that is the advanced penetration test so
but that's in their contracts and
they're like 60 page contracts so the
only people reading them are lawyers who
might not get the night might not
immediately sneer at that so yep so if
we don't have to find terms in the
contract if we're not clear on the
customary definition the court will
often just say whatever's commercially
reasonable interpretation of what that
term is so that's are they background on
contracts half hour contracts for a
course it's usually a whole year in law
school so contracts that affect us
employment we all like being employed
usually employment contracts while the
non-disclosure clause a nondisclosure
agreement I will not reveal what I have
learned here usually limited to things
like sensitive business information the
plans proposed to technology trade
secrets and other sensitive information
you have obtained during your employment
a non-compete after working from here
you will not attempt to hire people for
a certain amount of time you will not go
to the people you supported if you are
in a consulting field and go try to get
them you will not work for one of our
competitors for a certain amount of time
and the relative enforceability of this
depends what comes what what state
you're in for example California has
fairly it restricts non-competes in ways
that we don't on the East Coast
non-competes had p from the east coast
they don't have as much teeth in
California so that's why you go for the
choice of law choice of venue question
in the original contract ago should I
worry about this non-compete
work-for-hire intervention and sign mins
I've seen some ugly ones of these where
an invention you come up with six months
after you've left is ours unless you can
show that you never thought about it and
like how do you show that like I am not
so I so anal retentive that I take
shower notes
you know what you have that you have
that realization as you're you know you
know as your as you're washing yourself
like wait a minute that might work but
how would I prove to my employer that I
didn't come up with that on their time
so oftentimes when you're starting when
you're when you're negotiating a
negotiating a new new job there'll be a
declarations page these are my
inventions I walk in with them i'm
walking out with them at will employment
means they can fire you for any reason
or no reason even though this is an
employment contract with them the actual
can we end it yeah either side can end
it at any time if it says at will most
contracts usually are so second kind of
employment contract i'll go through is
the termination or exit agreement you've
decided to leave it may be a mutual
decision it may be unilateral maybe your
employer is really tired of looking at
you and as such well they will ask you
to leave and usually especially in this
field they'll ask you like look we would
like you to sign another contract that
by doing so you give up any rights you
had to an employment discrimination
lawsuit any questions we still owe you
money any question about anything else
we owe you an exchange will give you
severance we will extend your health
insurance will give you a thing the last
job i left oddly enough one of the
promises they gave was two monitors I
mean they're nice like 22 inch nails
like hey that's cool and that was a part
of my exit agreement but this is a final
attempt to renegotiate things however
they can add things into the exit
agreement that weren't in your
employment contract
so even though you may have walked in
with your invention assignment the exit
agreement may rescind that because it's
essentially a renegotiation to be
careful oftentimes they'll have
non-disparagement you can't talk
about us we can't talk about you
assistance this is a fairly common 1 i'm
seeing this getting actually used for if
you haven't fully documented your code
or you have some chunk of information
about a client situation or environment
there will often be an assistance clause
that says they can essentially rehire
you as a contractor you agree to this to
get them over that hump I've seen it
often threatened mark because you know
you're getting the hey how does this
work screw you I left three months ago
but you remember there's a trick to it
tell me what it is and you you know they
can threaten with we just rehire you is
we can force you to come back and do the
thing so oftentimes you'll just divulge
ical yeah it's up down up down a be a be
so business contracts so you've gone
from being an employee to maybe you're
negotiating on behalf of your company
are you running a company non-disclosure
agreements usually the first of what I
think of is is the flirting part of the
relationship all you're doing is saying
I'm going to divulge some information we
have no business relationship pass this
it is merely that I want to be able to
talk freely about what I'm trying to do
so non-disclosure second one and this is
for a in a contracting or consulting
role the master service agreement this
establishes all the rules by which we're
going to do business right it doesn't
say what we're going to do but this is
things like
how are you going to get paid if you
choose if we do something are you going
to get paid on invoice is it going to be
net 30 net 90 based on a retainer how so
all that all the rules about every
subsequent contract goes through the MSA
so it's essentially how are we going to
do business it's the first if you want
to think of this is like a networking
thing it's the handshake this
establishes all the rules by which
future business will happen but it
doesn't describe what we're doing it
just says if we do a thing this is the
this is the master so in terms of
payment assigning risks the actual
performance is in another contract the
statement of work those of you are
consultants if you have not learned this
yet this is the first thing you read
when you're told oh yeah you've got a
thing to do I don't talk to the sales
rep who sold it I don't talk to any of
the engineers who are currently working
on it I read the statement of work as I
want to know what did we actually
promised to do and I mean by read it I
mean print it out and circle things that
you're like what does this mean I used
to one shop I work for the person
writing the contracts and selling them
would put in phrases that had no meaning
weevil one of our deliverables was
always a possibilities matrix what's the
possibilities matrix I didn't know
either so every one of my deliverables
had section whatever possibilities
matrix and it was like a four by four
matrix about possibilities and I
realized it was like a way of saying
we're going to sell you all these things
you know like but this is actually if no
value but we promised you a bunch of
things but that's the that's the
statement of work is all the things are
actually promising on doing and all the
things
promising to do for you as in payment or
anything else you might be getting from
them the SLA the service the service
level agreement how quickly will you
respond what is your up time so this is
less about kind of contracting more like
if you're bringing on something as a
service this is essentially your bought
these two though are essentially the if
you have a conflict with the person
you've contracted with this is the first
thing you read and you reread it to
figure out who's out of line so those
are you work in healthcare this is a
scary scary thing business associate
agreement it is not merely a contract
this is now actually by signing a
business associate agreement you are
certifying that you comply with HIPAA
and the amount of times I cbas get
signed by consulting companies who are
doing work that should not be business
associates under HIPAA but they sign it
anyway because you want the sale all the
sudden now you're promising that your
own internal processes are best practice
who here thinks their own internal
processes are best practice right
there's not yeah like I remember this
like clear desk clear screen as a
requirement and I'm like well there is a
there is a desk and a screen under these
piles of paper and equipment because I
remember doing it's like I wouldn't pass
this you know I'm telling you
coming oh yeah you should do that do you
do it no all be you know all the
official business locations of our
company in Seattle may do this I don't
know I'm not there right now my own
office no so this is kind of a scare
because it essentially says I'm agreeing
to follow hit
high-tech security and privacy rules and
you're like yeah but I'm a consulting
firm I'm a freewheeling you know white
hat hacker rules schmules I'm leaked all
your stuff is going to be in a thumb
drive on my desk at least I think it's
on the desk it may have fallen off so
you you're now ascribing to all those
things that you expect someone else to
do you're like oh yeah our it's an often
will be I've seen this especially for
doing work with really really large
healthcare organizations like hospital
chains are health insurers is that not
only do you say that you're going to
follow HIPAA they're going to also
publish their own more rigorous security
rules and you're filling out that the
vendor assessments that you often send
out you're like wait a min i have to
follow this I have to do these things
like a peasant know so those contracts
are dangerous they have to encrypt your
email yep the best one was like you have
to use those and I hate those it sends
you the link that you come back to and
then you're like why doesn't this work
on my browser because reasons you're
like do you have a one you recommended
like s none of them so these are
dangerous be careful I find even though
I've done this where I try to explain to
a client like hey and I information
security client like I'm not signing
this because I'm not touching any of
your healthcare data even four-legged
things like a hip assessment like I'm
not actually looking at your ph I if I
cphi I'm not going to look at it because
I don't want to know what you're doing I
would just call it out and say I could
cphi but I'm not handling ph i I'm not a
subcontractor in that space I'm not that
kind of girl
audit clauses these can these are
threats less so like the amount of time
if if they're going to bother to do an
audit beyond a questionnaire a follow-up
phone call and maybe a site visit if
they're going to look at full on audit
they're thinking of dropping you because
you've there's got to be a competitor to
you somewhere that isn't screwing it up
so you want to be a pen tester we've got
an MSA you sign with the assignment
agreement which is how am I going to get
paid when am I going to get paid what
else do I agree to things they're
dangerous indemnification I've see this
stuck into a bunch of master services
agreements where the client expects you
to indemnify them for any damages you
may cause or you fail to find and it's
caused as in you to a pen Testament
clean bill of health four months later
they get owned they want you to step in
and cover their costs you can I mean if
you've got 20 million dollars in the
bank to indemnify as an indemnification
fun go for it otherwise you're going to
an insurance company who may now require
that they view your stuff to make sure
that you are a worthy risk for that so
be careful about this hold harmless you
won't sue me if this happens I often try
to get those into master services
agreements for in scope stuff statement
of work you include the scope of action
in the statement of work the following
systems applications locations however
you're defining the the the work you
want it to be very very specific if it's
if you're doing a scan and pen test the
following IP addresses are in scope you
want to make it very clear this is what
I'm hitting if that doesn't happen or it
gets changed right oh yeah we put in
these new systems and we toured these
out because
we wrote the statement of work for
months ago we couldn't get an approved
we've changed our infrastructure between
then and now and we didn't want to
change it so there might be some kind of
meat kickoff meeting you'll have where
you essentially renegotiate the scope
get them to sign it if only to say send
it from their email like we agree this
is the new scope or this modifies the
scope and the statement of work because
and keep beating this up you want the
scope of what work you're doing to be
clear often times you'll have the
meeting those who also space stay things
stick say things like when when may I
pen past your systems and why is it
always it's like midnight to 4am why is
it always the rule yeah and then we'll
have a status call at nine that was me
for six weeks on the phone like snoring
alerts if we knock something over yeah
we did this test about it and doesn't
pay anymore it was listening something
like master underscore ad is that
important oops yeah we should let you
know to get at a jail letter those are
you do physical pen test or social
engineering that gets a little
aggressive the get out of jail letter is
essentially a a shortened version of the
scope of work signed by either their
legal counsel client legal counsel of
the client CEO or president saying the
person standing in front of you is a pen
tester they're allowed to do whatever
stupid thing they may have just done
between this date and this date no need
to call the cops if you've hit them
please apologize
you can put the gun down yeah explains
what you're doing the idea is this is
that if cuz you know in every physical
pentest there's always that moment like
I'm gonna do something stupid and next
thing you know you're like it someone's
called me on it and it's not just like
oh I'm sorry I'm leaving now like no you
need to be able to show the letter it
says trust me sometimes you're showing
that to the police this is something now
that everyone's going to the cloud
identify the ownership of the stuff
you're testing view of it if your client
has put a bunch of stuff into AWS you
may not be able to pen test it cuz you
know what Amazon really doesn't like you
pen testing their stuff but they react
badly to this because otherwise it's an
attack sometimes a redirect takes you
over the line I found this during a pen
test something that was in scope was
actually hosted elsewhere I went to its
root directory by doing that you know go
up the web server to hopefully find the
Apache admin page and instead I found
someone else's box which i owned looked
at the IP and went that's not ours that
was Rackspace's I should go explain to
rackspace what I just did sorry um yeah
I got I got chillin this oh I got
shell in someone else's box oops so
that's the story I have for that see
what you want to do is if you have
identified co-located cloud whatever is
the service stuff get them you don't
want to do this because I mean think of
this way think of how Amazon or
Rackspace is going to be able to I'm a
pen tester I'm going to be pen test in
this box they're not in the customer
first go away get them to get all that
stuff in place
our come up with another solution but
that's why scope is so important because
breaking a system that is in scope is
just a bad day for them if you've
written this correctly you're
indemnified if I break into a system
that is out of scope I have now
committed a felony a felony does not
look good on your permanent record
prevents criminal and civil liability if
your scope is good so say for example
now going back to contracts what happens
when there's a conflict they believe you
haven't performed they don't like what
you're saying and it goes from argument
to all the sudden people aren't
accepting meeting invites that's that's
when my blood runs cold like uh-oh I can
no ones on the status call no response
with thank you for my you know status
spreadsheet about what I've done so you
know there's a problem what can you do
you might be able to renegotiate you
talk to the principles involved and say
this project has somehow gone off the
rails how do we keep this going do we
extend scope do we extend time do we
change the amount of money involved do
we do something how do we keep the
business relationship fine might I have
to offer something new on both sides
essentially it's a whole new contract
you want to identify the breach and the
breach is the breaching contract what
did what what did you promise to do that
you didn't do what did they promise to
do that they didn't do because you're
fighting about that you want to figure
out how that is how you can fix that how
you can cure that problem this is now
getting uglier you vas it like they have
breached their side so you can say I
believe that you won't continue
performing we're out anticipatory breach
you will not do what you're supposed to
do at a material fact you're not going
to pay us you're not going to get the
project done on time
you haven't done coke or things to it
we're out like the extreme one of these
is all of a sudden your badges no longer
work at the job site because they have
basically told you we've all you all get
help threaten lawsuit this is now things
have spiraled into stupid after their
spiraling into stupid because you've
gone from we were making them happy
we're making them relatively happy at
this point no one on the technical teams
and other side is talking this is maybe
the prince if you're the principal of
your shop you're talking and you're now
not talking to the technical people
you're likely talking to people in the
business management or maybe legal
you're now fighting over whether or not
you're going to continue at all like
this might be the end of the business
relationship and then you've gone from
threatening a lawsuit you've written a
couple letters or your turnings have
written some letters you actually file
Los someone files a suit about this all
of a sudden now it's you're no longer
really worrying about getting paid
you're worrying about escaping so any
questions on contracts
okay its third parties if if i say i'm
holding hold harmless means we're not
going to sue each other under this
indemnification means that if someone
else Sue's me you're stepping in right
you you promised to do a thing for me
like you're going to test my system and
you certify that it's good if it's a
mere hold harmless it means that if you
break it or I cause you damage no now
now you're standing in and saying yeah
customers sues you you're defending me
yeah right especially if it's not yet
done if you're like working on a project
that is not yet made it to github or
isn't really there yet you would
probably want to name it in your
inventions disclosure because it's like
I'm working on yeah and come up that's
why I often tell my mic lines like come
up with a name just name the thing so
that way instead of a some really is
like a patent declaration like a thing
that does awesomeness wow that's useless
know it's a library that does this thing
and now it's a thing and you can
basically claimed it as I'm walking into
this place with this now in a lot of
cases thinking about inventions if they
are close to related to what you're
doing your day job you want to be
careful lest you use you recycle code
one way or the other now it becomes
where the company can rightfully say
whoa wait a minute which in this code
you write for us which of this code is
now in this open source project this
smells like what we paid you to do
that's a concern
right
yes so the difficulty now is how do you
protect how do you protect the project
if these guys can come in and say all
the code that this person you're like
but then you're like taking out like
individual lines like you're going back
to two commits and going show me show me
on this what's yours i I'm less
concerned about that for open source
because most of the time I don't unless
that open source package becomes
incredibly valuable like in the linux
kernel or something like that it odds
are it's going to be like yeah it's a
wash we don't think there's anything of
enough value to fight you on it yeah
it's one of those like i identified this
as a risk the same i identified that
there is you know meteor or clown risk
involved cool I think we're done thank
you so much