okie dokie class is in session thank you
everyone for coming and spending your
time especially the last talk of the day
here and hopefully we'll wander down one
of the many paths and sharon experience
together of what my mind can do against
everything around us but uh in the vein
of that kind of a crappy opener is that
show up okay ish whatever now Eddie yeah
everything else so my name is Russ
hahndorf I've been around in this plane
of existence for quite some time my
contact information is Russell at hand
or calm or org and my twitter handle is
don't look behind you I volunteer
extensively in the wireless village so
if you see me around at conferences
that's typically where you would have
found me where I run and design some of
the software defined radio challenges
when they work and other than that from
those life experiences I try to move
them over and two other practical
components exploring new technology and
new directions and things that are a
little bit wonky and this is exactly one
of those moments where things get a
little bit wonky for me so I've recently
finished defending my PhD as a so if
anyone ever wants to play doctor I'm
qualified but one of the big problems
that I had while going through that was
that little kind of attention deficit
squirrel moment where there will be
these random projects or random ideas
that just show up out of nowhere that
drove me away from what I was exactly
supposed to be working on and this
turned into one of them so over the last
year I'm I've got about eighty percent
of my carputer rebuilt from scratch I
built a PDP eight out of a raspberry pi
that's done you know I got about an acre
of land I got about eighty percent of an
irrigation and system installed myself
that was awful I'm never done with the
wireless village just can't quit zero
this talk is about one of those tangents
which was building an atomic clock at
home as poorly and quickly as possible
and then there's another project which i
call I gave a talk on last year called
Soho SIGINT where I'm collecting signals
of interest around my house and using
pattern matching to identify people well
tell me when a friend has shown up at my
house or not versus the postman or
someone who's going to proselytize or
prostitute or whatever anyways so I can
gauge the level of nakedness that I'm
going to answer the door and but
regarding Soho SIGINT personal tangent
thanks to drag horn I think he's uh put
around in that project with his new
revamped version of kismet because it
now does everything Soho Sagan was
starting to do so tip of the hat to him
for doing that but anything else that
kept me from having to write my
dissertation was fantastic and I do have
a daughter she was a distraction in that
as well but that's that's a
responsibility I just can't leave her on
her own I can just pick up a soldering
iron and go to town on something else
that's my own self detriment towards
finishing that well finally I'm done so
I have a void of time to fill future
projects our experiments with geophone
some things along those lines about
whatever security haunts us by day you
got to have something by night that
helps you rebalance yourself well in
this particular project I managed to
wrap in one of my friends John krina who
likes to explore these wild random
ventures every once in a while together
we've made a musical Tesla coils nixie
you name it clocks caller ID displays
all that sort of random stuff plasma
speakers just really I think a sub
mission is to see how long I could leave
a project on the kitchen table
unfinished to see how quickly my wife
gets pissed off but he joins me in these
ventures and building
and atomic clock at home was one of the
ones that interested them so rubidium
oscillators 101 this slide pretty much
describes exactly at a high level the
mechanics of how they work so in the you
have this thing that is beautifully
named the physics package and inside
that physics package you have a chamber
that has one isotope of rubidium that's
been gasified and then you have a
rubidium lamp that's another isotope and
of that same isotope of the lamp is a
light detector and when you get your
physics package excited and the rubidium
starts generating to the tempo of a very
specific temperature it oscillates and
it oscillates very very controlled in a
very very predictable predictable manner
whereas to the point where if you use it
as a time source the error in seconds is
measured in hundreds of thousands of
years it's not a cesium clock which
costs a whole lot more to build and
requires a lot more equipment and add
zeros to the the end of the cost for the
build for you to do it at home and is
also not accurate as accurate and this
sorry is far more accurate than a
rubidium one but I'm going to be long
dead and this junk is going to be
something for my kids to have to handle
anyways so a hundred thousand years is
good enough for government work so the
the easiest fastest way to do this is to
purchase this device is called a fe 568
OA and they come if you're going to take
this particular route i'm going to give
you some warnings about this they are
they all have the exact same model
number there are no other distinguishing
characteristics from something that you
can search but they are all very
different from each other all not all of
them are very different from each other
there's families of them that are very
different from each other some of them
it may only output
a pulse per second some of them may be
calibrated for a 10 megahertz sine wave
and nothing else some may have any
combination of those fine features of
being able to set the frequency that is
going to oscillate at on its way out or
be a PPS generator or anything want
along those lines and in addition to
that it may have different interfaces on
it as well so in the leftmost image you
can see that there's a db9 connector on
it but in the right image there's some
SMA connectors off the back so depending
if you're going to go out and purchase
one of these pay very very close
attention to what it looks like and what
the specified description is about it
and you can buy them off of ebay without
any problem and what you are ideally
looking for off of the ones on ebay are
ones that give you a pulse per second
out one that also gives you a 10
megahertz signal out sine wave and then
even more ideally one that has serial
input output on it that way you can do
my new calibration on the rubidium
oscillator itself this picture on the
right that has everything outlined look
for anything that has descriptions for
pens one two four three and seven and if
you see those you are golden on having
to purchase that particular oscillator
so what does that physics package and
what does this mystery device look like
on the inside well once you open it up
you have some discrete electronics but
you can see that there's two pieces well
there's one piece of yellow at the top
which is soft foam that's actually a
really crappy thermal isolation from the
actual physics package which is
underneath that like expandable foam
that you would use for insulation that
is the thing that you absolutely have to
make sure keeps warm and all that sort
of stuff but if it gets too hot it can
create error in one of the other sub
oscillators and the other
component on the board now on the other
ones if they don't have the PPS output
or anything along those lines when you
do open them up you can see that there's
that blue wire that comes down to a uml
connector on the motherboard sometimes
you can just do that yourself and save
yourself the headache or you could open
it up and follow the trace is very very
they're wonderfully labeled but you can
follow the traces to directly connect to
the data out signal out or serial out
off of the the box out of the box itself
now the thing that's I got a little bit
ahead of myself but i'll go ahead and
explain it real quick these things
actually and i'll go back to this slide
to explain that part where these come
from typically are recycled cell phone
tower transmission sites they get sent
over to China dismantled and then they
somehow show up on eBay and then ship
back into the US somehow that southpark
episode of jewelry moving around the
world kind of comes back in my head
brigade but this time regarding
electronics these are typically used to
provide the signal and clock sourcing
for TDMA and cdma-based hours they're
also in GSM as well but that is what
their actual commercial uses for there
are military uses for these as well you
can kind of guess what might require
precision guidance controls directions
that can be disposable so you don't want
to lose something that costs a couple
hundred to low millions of dollars if
it's a one and done sort of thing a
couple hundred bucks is disposable so
that that's another use out of these
things well the but what's more
interesting to me is like going it's not
so much the electronics piece it's like
learning how these suckers work and
inside of them inside that physics
package when you cut off the gold
container this is exactly from that
previous overall diagram I showed you
what is inside on the top there you have
the photo detector in the middle you got
your gas chamber and if you can see it
all right there's a little beat
vidiyum inside of there that's nice and
cool so when it heats up its going to
gasify and and the bottom is the lamp so
that's that's what it looks like on the
inside yes they typically use cesium
based oscillators however you can I'm
going to show you a comparison between
this and GPS in a minute because ntp
made the decision for me so my initial
build objective was to sarcastically be
able to answer the question from my wife
do you know what time it is or at least
that's one of the most sub motivating
goals was but more importantly it's I
just kind of like to have one of these
things at the house and once I
understood how to make it work build
another one and be able to like possibly
do some very simple time experiments and
demonstrations with my kid like you can
leave one at home and then take the
other one with you to the mountains for
a long weekend and then come back and
you show the time is different between
the two because the effect of gravity on
the rubidium oscillator which is a very
measurable thing to be able to
demonstrate and then for anyone who's
ever seen the madness at my house I also
wanted to make this fit inside the rack
and then have rest of my other
components pull off of it so I ordered
one what late one night and it took a
while to get through customs and the
reason why I took a while was because of
the rubidium piece of it but it
eventually made it through and it was
labeled as amateur radio parts and the
reason for that is a lot of amateur
radio operators like to use these things
will like quotations to use these things
primarily because of the the use of the
times the 10 megahertz freak sine wave
frequency that comes out of it 4
gigahertz communication so anything
that's like 12 gigahertz and high oh
sorry one point
giga hertz and higher you really need to
have a good TCO tcxo in order to drive
that to be the oscillator to drive that
radio these are really good cheap
solutions for that well I mentioned on
one the previous slides you have two
voltage inputs one is a 5 volt and the
other ones like a 17 to 19 volt input
well the folks who mailed this over were
kind enough to also send a free power 5
volt regulator with it that you just
solder yourself which is just that one
chip that's there and then they also
gave like this little stuffed bear thing
anyways i'm not sure if it fell in the
box by accident and the the packing
month or not this is how mine showed up
and it was fantastic it had everything
that I needed it had a chopped db9
connector on it which was great had nice
foam padding on the side which told me
it was handled with tender loving care
when it was removed and they were kind
enough to throw in like a really
inexpensive 5 volt regulator and these
things like a few cents but it's the
thought that counts well I mentioned
that Cree know my friend went on this
adventure as well and he bought one from
the exact same supplier his did not show
up as an such good condition if you can
see in the lower right hand image it
looks like they there's grommets and
rivets that they used to put it onto a
heatsink plate and they just like cut
him off angrily and he he contacted the
ebay seller and then they sent him
another one for free nice on them we got
this one working again so we got two for
one so essentially I just wanted to see
what would happen if you know let's just
go ahead and solder it up plug it in
turn it on fingers crossed let's see if
it works and the the things you got to
watch out for is that you got your two
different voltages so you got to apply
the right ones to the right pens
otherwise you're going to have a sad
a moment there is a pen that is high
that goes too low when the physics
package is able to receive a sense that
the 10 megahertz frequency is stable
because what is doing is is constantly
watching itself that sine wave and if
it's more than 10 megahertz it's
starting to cool itself off and if it's
less than 10 megahertz is starting to
warm itself back up so once it's exactly
at 10 megahertz it tries it's best to
keep the temperature under control and
it goes hey I'm locked onto a good
signal source life is peachy and then
once luck is achieved the pulse per
second pen starts firing out a pulse
once every second so I was estatic to
see that I didn't release the purple
smoke there were no funny smells I got a
fantastic perfect 10 megahertz a signal
out of it the pen the lock pin went low
and it totally worked as advertised out
of the box this was going to be easy or
so I thought but that was the good news
and what I did notice out of it was a
few other things this sucker gets hot
the temperature on that meat thermometer
says it's just below 110 degrees I took
that picture when it didn't receive lock
yet so it gets a lot hotter I measured
it at 180 degrees when it got locked
when it locked onto the 10 megahertz
frequency and regarding that I was kind
of curious of can I prove even further
that the temperature heating cooling
mechanism is working correctly by
forcing it to go in and out of loch by
you know just dropping the heat sink on
it and then secondarily to that knowing
that there's some discrete electronics
on the inside that are really really
sensitive to the amount of heat that
this oven can generate inside of it is
there something I can do to control that
because this thing is mounted typically
on a giant sheet of metal and that's its
way to convict the heat off the exit
seat so I just went through the parts
been found
low profile when you heat sink with a
fan plopped it on it within like a few
seconds it went out of lock and then I
just found it moved it to a good spot
where then went back into lock but now
the average temperature of the whole
package externally to the touch is about
a hundred degrees I can live with this
now burn my house down so the next part
of the experiment was alright I i now
have a working physics package I like
saying that and my next thought was
alright well I've got this pen that's
one pulse per second I should just be
able to you know throw some bubble goo
bubble gum & goo & gum and hope and
dreams directly to the GPIO pin of a
Raspberry Pi and start counting those
receiving that pulse per second and life
will be great and that was definitely
not the case so the before you connect
anything up you always got to measure
what you're seeing and what you're
receiving so I measured what my pulse
per second look like out of this thing
and the characteristics were is that the
pulse was one micro second in length so
that's really really really really quick
it typically peaked out at about five
volts for its pulse per second which is
fairly high and then the I took a look
at the specs of what the raspberry pi
can did today can detect on his GPIO
pins and typically it wants a signal to
last it's kind of like a imagine a bell
ringing if it goes tink it might not
hear it but if it goes gong and just
rings out a whole lot longer there's a
higher chance or a higher probability
that the pie is going to pick that
signal up when its internal clock goes
through and goes and what's the status
of me who that tickles and registered a
tickle and so the pen must have received
a pulse the other last part was the
raspberry pi will only take on his data
pens a max voltage of three volts so I
was frustrated this was not going to be
as easy as like take this thing and plug
it in there and life was going to be
great so
I amended my build objective list to not
cook my raspberry pi so that was
injected directly as a new thing but I
needed something to compare it against
so I had another GPS that did work
directly off the GPIO pins of the
Raspberry Pi it had a 3 volt max and it
also did a PPS output so I did a quick
comparison between what my rubidium
clock was generating and what a GPS
generates so the GPS is the image on the
right you'll recognize the one from the
rubidium oscillator on the left and if
you can't read the values at the bottom
each interval here is one microsecond
each interval here is a hundred
milliseconds so significantly longer but
it was exactly at three volts DC it
proved my theory of like it needed to be
about 100 milliseconds in length and but
also at the same time I also looking at
it I was like well it my previous one
was a nice little as square wave as you
can get for a pulse this thing isn't so
that tells me that the Raspberry Pi
isn't picky enough about that for its
signal n for the GPIO pins alright so it
doesn't have to be perfect fine I can
live with this this is going to make
that part at least hopefully easier so
leave it to a blonde to turn a DC signal
back into an AC signal for a pulse per
second and what what was happening was
the pulse would hit the diode and the
diode would resonate up and down up and
down and then slowly get quieter but the
good news was is that I saw that the
diode was resonates trib increasing the
length of that resonation so I was like
okay I was able to draw out that that
pulse to an acceptable window but damn
it I now have an AC signal this isn't
cool
and I was a the other thing that I
noticed eventually after I fixed that
part of the problem was the Raspberry Pi
was now able to detect the PPS but it
was picking it up on these time
intervals like way way way too quickly
so I'm intervals were in milliseconds of
each other so it would the DDD DDD DDD
DDD over and over and over so anyone who
works with radio what do you think I was
getting mmm what happens if you have
power tripping down a line and it hits
the end of that line remember then that
you have to put a terminator yep in
order to keep reflections from coming
back oh it up elections up the pole
second though huzzah I didn't cook the
pie it was picking the signal itals
pickin it up too much so this is the
other hint as to the solution that I
ended up doing to find out really of off
of the pie and not offer the rubidium
oscillator itself their ground
references go through not directly to
the ground pins all the time through the
GPIO bus so in short when I connected
all this up I actually had to throw the
ground reference directly back to the
power supply that was powering the
entire kit as opposed to being lazy
about and saying uh ground is ground I
could just pull it off of the pie or
pull it off of the oscillator nope not
in this case I had to actually just pull
it directly off of the power supply
itself so now I have that nice pulse
within the right voltage and it's
extended into the window where things
were hunky-dory peachy keen instead of
seeing like that massive reflection I it
would pick the signal up twice so I
still had a bit of a reflection issue I
got lazy and just threw it
REM pod on to fix that so once I did
that I was able to sew the reflection
would go down it will come back and then
hit back down to the PI that second one
was a weaker one and the i used the
zener diode to just throw anything below
that voltage level directly to ground
life is peachy so all of a sudden now I
am now getting pulse per second and the
raspberry PI's picking it up I let it
run for weeks on end I didn't get any
blue or purple smoke the GPIO bus on the
pi didn't fry I didn't have to move to
another pin for like whacking it over
and over again because if you want to
think about in some regards don't do
this but if you were to turn to the
person next to you and just thump them
once every second it gets a little
irritating and the way the GPIO bus on
the pies are engineered in some way is
that strong thump it they'll actually I
parallel it to like getting bruised the
electronics wear out from it so this was
still within the tolerances of it and
everything was fine so I had an
intermission at this particular point in
time I lost about three weeks of focus
for this project due to work travel kids
thinking thinking about actually writing
on my PhD which I didn't but the I'll
still kind of like in the back of my
head I got it to extend a close to 100
milliseconds but not exactly there and
I'll still worried that that was going
to be a problem so I threw a tweet out
nasta for some and some friends
responded there's a guy named Tim who
has been a player in our wireless
village he's the guy who's rocked the
dog shock collar challenge anyone who
wants to play that fair game and then
there are some other folks that have
worked in the space that responded back
to me like Rob from New on and drag horn
guy wrote kismet and they they gave me
some suggestions of some other stuff
like one of them was to use a 555 timer
in order to try to get the PPS from the
oscillator to trigger the 555 for it to
then in turn flip the light switch on
for a time interval and then turn it off
so I tried a variety of these things and
they worked but when I started having to
rely on other components in order to do
that time delay the ultimate measure for
this was well I might be ringing a
buzzer or having something else reading
the buzzer for me but what is ntp think
the actual application ntp think of
these sources so i slung it together I
got ntp to receive the PPS and compare
it against what the GPS was giving it so
without the the oscillator the raspberry
PI's internal clock jitter was worse
than the GPS is but the gps is jitter
was at a 15 micro seconds with the
rubidium oscillator the pulse per second
was point 0 1 micro seconds for jitter
so that tell if ntp goes yes this thing
is stable and awesome then that meant
that i now had the functions of an
atomic clock using a Raspberry Pi in
this external oscillator so the other
thing that was interesting was later in
life getting the boot up process to
behave correctly and it turns out that
GPS isn't also always the most reliable
source for getting a pulse per second
because weather phenomena can delay it
your GPS receiver has a firmware in it
that tries to account for that error so
that's like a band-aid to a broader
problem that i experienced solely
because of being able to compare it
against this other source well next
thing was hearing from Kirino and how he
was doing with his he had very similar
success and stabilizing the pulse per
second getting his piety and put it we
we worked in isolation but slightly pink
each other solely because we wanted to
see what the other solutions were
possible and all that sort of stuff so
we
compare notes and it turns out that we
were very very close to the exact same
solution from a circuit standpoint but
software wise we were exactly the same
and we both had ntp pick up on things
wonderfully so we're for me personally
like I I don't I'm aid a kernel hack in
order to fudge some of the razz pies
detection of the PPS i don't really like
doing that ideally i'd like to use some
sort of a circuit to reliably trigger
that for me the ones listed there are
ones that i've built and tested minus
the i still haven't done the
multivibrator yet where's render man
when you need them but the the other
component of it is is I have an external
as to like do I have 10 megahertz signal
or not ideally I want to use the NB 506
internally already on the same bored
that i'm building for this and then the
last stage is to just cram it all in a
1u rack case and ultimately like just a
little bit before this presentation I
was like you know what let's make
another Internet of Things thing and
just quickly hack together something
that gives me like a status what it uses
GPS for is to go what time is it mostly
oh it's 1231 all right pulse per second
directly after 12 31 and then every once
in a while at queries gpsd again in
order to see does my 1231 still match
yours and when I was solely relying on
gps d being the time source for it the
ntp would get angry and start saying
your GPS is not precise enough for me to
use it as a stratum 0 or stratum 1 time
source it wanted to use GPS as stratum 2
or stratum 1 but stratum 2 preferably
because the amount of jitter that it was
picking up an association with it so
just quickly
threw together something that would
visibly render the status of the
appliance yes sir it was about a hundred
and eighty dollar GPS from Garmin so
it's the the no no no it was a it may
have had mostly due to maybe noise from
the cable because it was a serial device
as opposed to USB and passing data that
way but there was something specifically
about it that it just didn't like that I
could replicate on another device as
well may have dropped at one too many
times yes sir rubidium oscillator on
ebay you can find them anywhere between
eighty dollars to two hundred dollars
and it's mostly because some people
don't realize what they have and what
they're selling so you may get lucky
with that that's the $80 end of the
spectrum the ones that really go yeah I
know what I got and it's actually
interesting they'll sell them for about
200 bucks when you buy them brand-new
they can be a little under a thousand
bucks I've seen the manufacturer sells
them I've seen them with the variety of
features that they have under the exact
same part number starts from like 500
bucks and goes up to about a thousand
bucks and these these are the devices
that are and the cell phone towers that
are allowing multiple customers to share
the same frequency because of tdma or
cdma hey I think the TNT DMA means what
anyways so it's fairly important for
those sort of functions and this is just
a fun little reuse of something else
that's out there now the other while
researching this thing I should also
note that there are some other videos
and other people that played with this
device but it's kind of the way I
described some of the write-ups is like
these people bought this thing in the
mail and they just wanted the lazy plug
it in turn it on and everything works
and then they wrote a skating renting
table flipping Rivi
you of the device that they got without
actually trying to understand what it
was or how it worked and so so that's
that information is on the end of the
spectrum of the people that don't like
it and then on the end of the spectrum
are like some of the ham radio operators
that have taken this to use in contests
for gigahertz radio links and it's good
enough for that where they're able to
have multiple transmitters operating
right next to each other without them
stepping on each other with this cheap
little $80 oscillator I've seen other
people use them in their work benches
for radio experiments and there's this
one guy who's actually made this like
really crazy steampunk style atomic
clock that screams at you what the time
is that looks it really looks steampunk
ish but his works just fine and its
really really neat looking but he
enjoyed playing with this device my
personal opinion of reviewing some of
this stuff is that people just weren't
really sinking their teeth in understand
what they got they got a little bit lazy
with some of them or write ups or even
their own research on it it isn't the
that's out there but it works well
enough to be able to do this other stuff
if you can figure out a band-aid to
apply to it if you need to and like I
said they may be they are used you're
getting them off of ebay so your mileage
may vary from it but don't give up or be
frustrated with it the sellers will try
to work with you in order to get that
favorable you know 5 out of 5 star
review but you can repair them you can
experiment that's Alton oh so now that i
got thing at home and i'm starting to do
time sink in my house my my ultimate
goal is to no longer have the mismatched
time settings on devices or the
microwave of the oven and my cell phone
have like wildly different times set on
them but you know the law a regular oven
with a clock on as well but you know
that
devices since they don't take an
external time source I might be
additional warrant a near future so at
this point I can show you through a
interesting rendering of the web page of
what the current status of the system is
otherwise I'll take questions if anyone
has them at the moment yes sir you got
to take time off yeah yes yeah I did see
that on so now you can actually you're
careful you know what you're looking for
you yeah and it's just a little bit
lucky on that yeah this is as close as
easy sort of thing that you can get so
like I I threw some questions on the
time nuts mailing list and even back
from those people and digging on the
history of it you still had widely like
some people really really liked it and
other people really really hated it yeah
yeah if he wants to get rid of 1 i'll be
having these were
he forms the third and so one of the
things that will help you even though
you can't measure it yes take your pack
your box and put it in an environment
where it stays breezy yes absolutely ya
know the temperature since the way the
device you're absolutely right because
of the way the device functions is based
upon an oven that controls the
vibrations of the rubidium inside of it
no temperature stability is absolutely
key all inside of his lab the glass wall
yeah a bunch of custom air conditioner
oh yeah not like a I've an
air-conditioned server room that's on
its own spot I've got that I've got that
covered as well I've got that covered as
well there's one individual in this room
that has seen the walking us of the hand
or household of insanity but actually
that might turn into another talk of the
rabbit hole sort of situation yes sir
these devices are are forgivable so
that's why I like there they are nowhere
near as accurate as like a cesium clock
but they are still accurate enough to
within a second of error within a couple
hundred thousand years so if you go with
like a cesium clock you're going to be
adding some zeros to the end of that
hundred thousand years such a lot of
zeros so regarding the temperature
sensitivity of it the the operational
range for it is for the oven if I
remember correctly it's somewhere
between 185 to 190 degrees is where it
ideally wants to be within so that five
degree temperature drift is more like
way overly forgiving for an environment
that is typically housing one of these
devices so inside inside a cabinet for a
cell phone tower they do have air flow
and some refrigeration that's occurring
inside of it which controls it but it's
also on that giant skid so based upon
the thermal dynamics of the way that
they engineered that cabinet they know
by default they're just going to be
shedding X amount of heat off into the
chassis so that it just runs and sits in
the Sun because of all the thermal
protection between the electronics
inside and the external cabinet I don't
know if you've ever had the opportunity
open up and see inside a cell phone
tower cabinet thick doors they look
really big on the outside but there's
not a lot of electronics on the inside
and it's you have the Nina standard for
ratings of boxes for devices that can be
put outside I'm oversimplifying that but
they are of a standard that can
withstand like a lot of moisture a lot
of temperature a lot of dust and grit
yeah
so the way that those cabinets are built
is that it's occupying a very small spot
inside a broader space that's already
air-conditioned and or doing a bigger
amount of passive heating and cooling
already so that's another discussion
that I'll have with you if you'd like oh
yeah you know it's a it's a part of the
engineering of their actual installation
in use because it's not it's not like
you took a server rack and placed it
outside there's a lot of thermal
protection on those cabinets as they're
sitting in the Sun I've opened one up
and gotten cool air pouring out of it in
the middle of the heat so it's their way
more controlled on the inside than you
would imagine
so what these things are used for for
the towers themselves is being able to
know when how long a second is in order
to support the current load of the
customers off of that individual tower
itself the handoff from one customer to
another tower is an entirely different
protocol but it doesn't matter what the
time pulse is between one to the next
when it does the handoff it only cares
about the pulse per second off of the
active transmitted transceivers off of
that one tower itself in order to be
able to squeeze more customers into
narrower time slots but when you hand
off to another one you're going to have
a brand-new negotiation and new time
slot mechanism a new time source when
you're over there as well cell phone
towers typically pull their time off of
the t1 or t3 or ds3 lines from the
signal from there if the internal clocks
inside those towers fail on that they
also have GPS but because neither of
those mechanisms are good enough for
pulse per second for being able to cram
like a couple hundred subscribers off of
one radio so for that you need to have
something that can give precision error
correction and that's what these are
used for and that it's instance problem
having worked in that industry for a
period of time cool any other questions
queries posers yes
if you can get to step three you
survived the blood loss yes yeah I I
rant about these things on my personal
website every once in a while which is
hand org yeah haan do are fo RG there's
a sub component of it and rhetoric /
code has all the really weird random
home projects some radio some other
stuff as well but yeah that that's where
you'll find my ramblings or just email
me and i'll give you the bill of
materials and here's my schematics and
here's the gerber to send to ash Park
for them to print you a board to solder
some components on all that sort of
that's a fun enjoy yes sir how did that
come to that conclusion ntp just
triggering on that over and over and
over and over again was the symptom and
essentially when I jammed the
oscilloscope on the exact same pen you
would actually see the signal a boop
boop boop boop boop boop boop so that
was in the time period of one pulse
having gone out and then there's
multiple pulses still for that one pulse
going out and I was like that's not
supposed to be like that there's only
supposed to be one of those so that was
the diagnostic process that i was
getting reflection so the reason why is
that i'm cheap and that was the whole
point of this you can see i just used
the original db9 connection and just
sloppily soldered on some extensions and
then just straight wires and to
breadboard so there's like signal noise
and loss out of the breadboard itself
when I got to the point where I was
burning PCBs for this a a lot of that
noise just straight up goes away because
you're no longer dealing with like
alligator clips coming off of a lead
that has maybe like four strands out of
the 24 individual the copper just kind
of braided out waukee like my hair is so
like that that's not a good conduct
conductor point so by building the PCB I
got a whole lot of the background
nonsense well but it's it's a really
stupid simple circuit so far right now
I'm trying to figure out I've got like
five of them and I'm now trying to get
to the last point I'm going I want to
get all of these onto one board as
opposed to having like five different
mount points inside the one you case I
just want it to be one thing and then
nicer cabling and all that sort of stuff
currently right now the way that I'm
detecting the the 10 megahertz signal if
I pull if I throw the oscilloscope
directly on the pen it says 10 megahertz
exactly if I measure it off the lead
that comes off to the microcontroller
that is doing the comparison there is
noise introduced there because that lead
and that run of the wire is also right
next to the pulse per second wire which
is also right next to some of the
voltage wires so it's getting additional
noise right next to it so my ideal
solution with this board is that it
slides directly into the db9 point port
but one of the traces that comes off
goes to an SMA connector or some sort of
radio specific cable that can then go to
anything external on the box if it's
going to be on the board with an SMA
connector or anything along those lines
I haven't finished that part yet am I
had mostly because hey actually it
probably could is I free time but yeah
that's the there is someone who has made
a bit of a daughter board that slides
into it where you give it the 19 volts
DC n and it's got break out for serial
an LED to display the high the lock
state and a two pens one for the pulse
per second one for the
we'll source I wish they made a made the
signal source an actual SMA connector or
some equivalent actual RF connector that
would have made that a nicer board
itself but I think they sell it for like
35 bucks if you it's a very easy google
search to find any other questions
queries posers alrighty well thank you
for your time go out and do weird stuff
stop doing security when you go home do
weird stuff