hi everybody my name is Andy Applebaum
I'm a researcher at the mitre
corporation
you can't really see it but on the lower
right hand corner it says mitre I'm
gonna be presenting something we've been
working at mitre called attack which is
an acronym have you guys are you guys
familiar with mitre by any chance we
love acronyms we got CVE we got sticks
we got tanks do we got Capek Mike
there's like two dozen more those are
kind of the big ones attack is another
one it stands for adversary tactics
techniques and common knowledge it is a
publicly released framework that we have
to kind of model what an adversary does
post exploit if you're on your laptop
and you're on the internet right now you
can go to attack mitre oregon kind of
jump ahead to see what attack is but
first Massaro put a little bit of a
preamble I'm not sure if you guys are
really familiar with the Lockheed
Martin's cyber kill chain but it kind of
walks through these steps an adversary
does and they're breaking into a network
and everything yet reconnaissance
weaponization delivery exploit control
execute and maintain a lot of stuff it's
not very detailed it's kind of like
high-level what the adversary is doing
and traditionally when we talk about you
know cyber security and network defense
we talk about on these these four left
leftmost stages you know reconnaissance
weaponization delivery and exploit
people have a tendency to focus on the
perimeter of a network and how to defend
that as opposed to you know control
execute maintenance which is what the
adversary does once they get into the
network and we like to begin this
presentation with this little quote up
here which is kind of a median number of
days and an adversary will sit inside of
a network after they've broken through
which is a lot the every serious sitting
at around a network for a while after
they break into it and it's kind of
important to recognize that hey if we
can look at those post exploit stages a
little bit more we can detect the
adversary
you know quicker than 146 days so this
is just kind of an overview of how we
developed attack basically we got a
bunch of threat reports threat analysis
we kind of took those throw them into a
notional framework of how we can kind of
taxonomies and represent everything in
attack and then ran that over with into
a red team to kind of test a network to
to double back and try to refine our
model
and jumping ahead I'm going to go into
the model a little bit here on the upper
right hand corner you can see the ten
high-level tactics in attack instead of
just control execute maintained we now
have persistence we have privilege
escalation defense evasion credential
access discovery lateral movement so on
and so forth and this kind of breaks
down those three right of exploit stages
into a time agnostic series of ten
high-level tactics that adversaries tend
to do or attend to try to achieve once
they get into a network so one of the
key points about an attack here is that
the adversary model we have here isn't
necessarily theoretical attacks but
rather we've developed attack bump or
we've developed attack by analyzing
publicly available threat reports so all
of the the references we have an attack
site public threat reports that that
actually say hey this this threat group
was doing this this technique again as I
mentioned a few times attack provides
kind of more hype more fidelity of the
write of exploits stages we're not just
focusing on the perimeter we're trying
to really tech sodomize what the
adversary is doing once they get into a
network and another important point is
that attack really focuses on behaviors
we aren't focusing on tools as much as
we are in kind of what the adversary is
doing we don't have file hashes or
individual URLs indicators of
compromised
we don't necessarily focus on those well
rather we want to talk about behaviors
adversaries are doing and then finally
just a point we're working with a lot of
people to get kind of attack out there
government industry academia everything
we want everyone to use attack you know
so again attack that moderate org so
just a breakdown of attack and I
apologize though my slides are like
extra wide so they're breaking over the
sides a little bit but so what attack
consists first you have the tactics I
just kind of talked about the 10 a high
level tactics and then within each
tactic you have a list of techniques
that adversaries can do to achieve that
tactic along with each technique you
have a little bit about detection and
mitigation that defenders can take and
trying to use attack and mitigate the
techniques and then importantly we also
have documented adversary use of
techniques referring to threat actor
you know publicly although threat
reports as well as citations to software
that that adversaries can use to engage
those techniques then another fun thing
we have is kind of disambiguation of
adversary names if you guys have read
threat reports there's like a million
different write actor names so we've
tried to go and find the ones that are
synonymous with each other so here's an
example tactic and technique the tactic
is persistence an adversary wants to
maintain persistence within the network
the technique is creating a new windows
service we include a description of what
the technique is we include the platform
it applies to here it's windows and in
the model there's a little bit more
granularity Windows XP Windows NT stuff
like that the permissions required for
an adversary to execute this here it's
administrator and administrator or
assistant privileges the effective
permissions after the adversary execute
this technique so here it's system list
of just detection strategies that
defenders can use to try to mitigate
this or rather detect this technique so
you can monitor service creation things
like that some steps for mitigation
limit privileges of user accounts things
like that and then data sources these
are kind of Windows internal components
that as a defender you could monitor to
try to identify whenever an adversary
might be playing with new service so
here it's you know you can monitor the
registry process monitoring and command
line parameters and if you look at these
data sources you can potentially come up
with signatures to identify when an
adversary might be trying to use this
technique we have examples which are the
groups in software that do this so here
you can see carbon ACK Lazarus group
tiny Zbot all the other fun ones we have
a list of actual threat actor groups
that use this new service technique and
then for some of the techniques we have
links to Capek which is another minor
acronym which just provides more of kind
of linkage back to a higher-level model
so here's the eye chart we've recently
expanded attack so it's gotten a lot
bigger I don't know if you guys can
really see it but we have lots of stuff
at the top in blue you can see the
tactics I don't know if you guys can see
it in the back but we have persistence
privilege escalation defensive age
and then under each tactic we have
techniques that that the adversary can
do to achieve the tactics so here part
of discovery as security software
discovery that's an example technique
for discovery tactic some of these apply
to more than one tactic for example DLL
injection we have listed for privilege
escalation as well as defense evasion
legitimate credentials we got
persistence privilege escalation and
defense evasion so a lot of these can be
can be used in other they don't just
apply to one tactic now I also mentioned
we have threat actor groups here here's
an example deep panda we have a
description saying kind of what the
threat actor group is trying to describe
it at a high level we also include
references to where we actually
reference the threat report that talked
about this threat actor group so here
you can see we have the citation there
that intrusion into healthcare company
anthem was attributed to the Panda we
have the citation to the threat
connector research report we have a list
of aliases as you can see we have tons
of fun Alice's here in this case none of
them really seem to relate to each other
but they all have been kind of cited
publicly as being hey this is this
threat actor group we have a list of
techniques that this threat actor group
uses PowerShell thats execution with a
management instrumentation web shell
these are things that we've seen in
public threat reports to say hey this
threat actor group is using this to this
this technique we have a list of
software and I'll go into that one it
more in a minute here you can see that
the Panda uses net and tasks with two
windows built-in internals as well as
these three malware suites that are that
were custom developed so here's another
threat actor group and I've just kind of
tried to visualize it and cut up the
command and control on the right has cut
off a little bit but apt 28 they've used
I think there are six references here of
things that they've that we've that
we've seen publicly reported that
they're actively doing indicator removal
time stomp remote file copy things like
that and we're interestingly we can use
this to kind of compare different groups
in pink you have deep Panda and
orange you have apt 28 and here you can
see that they both have very different
play books in what they're doing deep
and you can see we have citations for
persistence and privilege escalation
where's our apt 28 we don't an apt 28
has active citations for command and
control where it's Rudy panda we don't
really have that as much the next
component of attack is software this is
an example of a built-in or a Windows
built-in that we've included in the
software the software list that we have
an attack this is task list again we
have a description subscribes with task
list is aliases task list it we have a
categorization of type type neither be
tool or a malware we have a kind of a
boolean whether or not it's a built-in
both in tool and in this case yes task
list is the techniques that task was can
be used to achieve our process discovery
security software discovery and system
service discovery we have a list of
groups that that we've actively seen
using this piece of software deep and
iturra and make on and then a reference
to Microsoft this is another type of
software a me vast it's unlike task list
this is malware this is custom malware
used by specific threat actor group in
this case it's deep panda these are the
capabilities that researchers have
identified that this piece of software
can use in public threat reports you
know kind of reverse engineering the
software seeing what it does we have the
techniques it's not Windows built in the
type of malware only it's one alias we
have a description and again we have
citations kind of following the same
format this is a fun I charted just
having fun in PowerPoint coloring
different things um but in pink it's
deep panda in and what I've done here is
kind of the Panda uses three malware
Suites Sekulow me Avast and two ruse be
horrible with these names but you can
see that these different software Suites
have different capabilities in blue
yellow and red is kind of the unique
capabilities to each to each software
suite in green it's a combination of
Sekulow and me vast purp
underoos being so I'm brown is all of
them the only one that they all have in
common is they all have kind of
command-line interface for execution
again this is an eye chart but kind of
the the big takeaway here is that by
looking at the malware we can see a lot
of different things that these
adversaries can do when you kind of
consolidate it together instead of just
having those I think nine different like
real references that the pen has been
doing
we now have 28 that they could have been
doing because we know what their malware
is capable of doing then just for fun
kind of a comparison between apt 28 and
deep panda I've done the same thing
where we kind of enumerate the malware
for apt 28 you can see that there's a
lot more you know as opposed to having
six techniques now apt 28 well there now
there's 22 potential techniques that
beset that this Drecker could be doing
deep panda has 28 and there are 9 that
both can can potentially be doing this
provides a nice visualization and now
instead of seeing the partial coverage
we saw before we see a lot more spread
out for each and interestingly the the
both category spreads out as well there
are a lot of use cases for attack I have
some here I'll go through them but I
invite everybody to try to come up with
their own fun stuff we can do gap
analysis of current defenses I'm gonna
talk about that on the next slide but
you can use attacks that kind of try to
measure your security posture you can
also use attack to prioritize detection
and mitigation strategies based on what
techniques and tactics you want to focus
on talk about that one in a minute too
you can use attack for information
sharing you know if we know that this
threat after group does these techniques
I can send that along to someone else
and say hey this threat actor group is
active right now you know monitor for
these techniques and you can kind of
share what that threat actor group is
doing in time back in the prioritization
you can then prioritize what you want to
look for you also track a specific
adversary
if you know in 2012 that this threat
actor group had this set of set of tools
that was using then saying 2015 what are
they doing now how is that modified how
do those modifications reflect changes
in time things like that adversary
emulation is a big one we will one of
those
we want to do with attack has tried to
you know give attack to a red team and
say hey here are some techniques and
tactics go do these go test the network
engage these techniques and when we tell
a red team to do that we can provide
kind of a structured report to the blue
team saying this is what the red team
was doing this is their report
hey you're not you're not able to detect
this technique it's a nice way to kind
of kind of choose structure a red team
exercise and really measure your
security posture then new technologies
and research lots of fun stuff you can
do here personally III do a little bit
of research trying to like formalize
attack formal methods stuff like that
it's fun I know of a professor who's
doing something similar but lots of fun
stuff you can do with attack so this is
an example use case and here it's kind
of going back to the whole idea of a gap
analysis in green what we've done here
is we've kind of colorized it based on
how confident we are that we're
detecting we're able to detect a certain
technique and in green you have high
confidence you might be very confident
that I can detect the time stamp stomp
technique in red you have no confidence
that you can detect it so I might not be
able to detect indicator removal on the
individual hosts of my network and
yellow you might have something like
medium confidence and so the idea here
is by kind of colorizing this chart you
can measure your security posture again
maybe using red teams or just analyzing
the tools you have on your network you
can colorize the chart you can try to
measure what what you're actually able
to detect instead of just throwing
defensive tools and then after doing
this you can focus on what what you need
to kind of amp up from from a detection
perspective so if I if I don't detect by
passing you a C that's something that I
should probably have because it's
covering two different tactics so it
kind of provides you a way to measure
what your security actually is on your
system as opposed to just kind of just
having a collection of defensive
techniques one of the key points we like
to make with attack is kind of again
cutting off the right side of the table
um one of the key points we like to make
is that adversaries tend to do a lot on
hosts
so what this chart shows is kind of what
you can see if you're just looking at
the network perimeter and if you look
here all you can really see is
exfiltration command and control and a
little bit of defense evasion and and
web shell here you're really missing a
lot of these tactics that that
adversaries are doing and I think this
this goes back to that quote in the
beginning where we say hey once an
adversary gets into the network they're
there for 146 days on average you know
because if we're if we're just looking
at the perimeter there are things we're
missing so the big takeaway here is you
get better coverage if you have host
sensing you know another key takeaway is
that adversary has a lot of variation
they can do at the network level and you
can see kind of the command and control
that's the main category that they're
able to vary and these software or
defensive technologies we have like
firewalls IDs systems NetFlow proxies
mail gateway so on and so forth they
tend to focus on the perimeter and they
really miss all these other tactics that
adversaries are doing in the last key
point we like to make is that a lot of
these tend to focus on very specific now
I just like ip's domains file hashes
things like that and these are all
important things to focus on
but the adversary can change these
things they aren't they aren't very they
aren't static they can be varied
question
yes so there is I'm not the expert on
this one but there are some like
software suites that measure things that
are going on on the host and I think one
good example we like to give is a sis
Microsoft sis Mon or sysinternals am I
getting it right
thank you but this internals is able to
measure certain you know if we go back
to this this technique here we have the
data sources here and the idea is if you
take something like sysinternals and say
hey look at these data sources try to
develop some sort of signature just
notice an anomaly you can actually
detect something on the host as opposed
to doing it at the network level anyway
so I think this sharp might need to be
updated but the basic idea here is that
some of these techniques we have in here
are are kind of like Red Team techniques
we haven't seen them as much in public
threat reports but we've seen them kind
of with with active red teaming we've
done I think a big example is
persistence there's a lot of persistence
techniques that we have in the model we
have 24 but we really only have 13 that
adversaries tend to focus on and this
chart has modified a lot over time
originally a lot of these didn't have as
many citations but now we've kind of
fleshed out the model and you can see
credential access discovery command and
control they collection most of the
other ones to have basically full
coverage that we always see we tend to
see the adversaries doing these
techniques and the idea here is that if
there are techniques we know adversaries
tend to focus on and we can focus our
defensive efforts on those techniques to
increase our likelihood of detecting
those adversaries it's just this just
kind of shows that kind of pictorially
you can see that there's only a few left
and white that are not actually done all
that actively I'm not sure how updated
this chart is I think at the beginning I
mentioned we've been doing attack for a
little while this is the original
version of attack from 2014
I think we only have eight tactics and
we have third as many eyeball on that
techniques it was a very much smaller
model a lot easier to read in a
PowerPoint we updated it this one was
still more readable
we added out a new tactic this was in
2015 a lot more techniques and then
finally we've kind of come across to
this we've really been expanding this
this model is really kind of jumped out
and we've introduced groups software and
we've tried to evolve it as we've
incorporated more and more information
and feedback we have a public website I
mentioned it a few times but I'm gonna
do it again
attack moderate org please go there read
about it we have lots of contact
information and attacked that org attack
app might org we have a Twitter account
you can tweet to the Twitter account
will respond you can contact me yeah so
any questions yeah
right so I can't personally speak to
that but that's a very good kind of
future use of attack would be to kind of
because we've only recently got this
basically list of groups and the groups
themselves are completely unstructured
so be very interesting I think to go
through try to label what each group
does and try to see what the correlation
is between each group and how they
because you might find that you know
nation-state attackers have a very
different TTP kind of bag of tools than
say a criminal based attacker I had two
wildly speculate I guess for more
variability in one or the other but
that's a good question
that I know of using attack not yet
that's something that I think we've kind
of talked about and and it's you know
you when you look at it or when I look
at a slide like like this one you know
my instincts say you know if we have
let's say a bag of tools that we see
kind of a threat actor doing an unknown
threat actor how well do they correlate
with a known threat actor and you could
probably put that in there and try to
come up with a set of scoring yeah yeah
I believe we're working on it
if you could send me an email afterwards
I can try to dig into that a little bit
more I'm not sure it's available yet on
the public website I'm trying to
remember because we've recently released
a whole bunch of things related to
attack there is another tool set out
there called unfetter by the NSA that
they just publicize which and that also
brings attack in and that might have a
built in XML model but if you could send
me an email I can look into that for you
oh so I'm with miter miter is a private
not-for-profit we largely advise the
government where are you from over CVE
we tend to focus on standards things
like that
we tend we manage I think seven
federally funded research and
development centers so we're kind of
hybrid we're not quite pure research
like in like a national lab say but
we're more we do research but it's
mainly in support of the government the
government not quite a Fed
yeah yeah that's that's that's a very
good point it's kind of interesting
because on one hand this this it's all
public you know information out there
but at the same time it's very easy to
access now it would provide not only a
nice toolkit for people to you know used
for deception say but also for detection
but also for deception if if we start
getting in there and then we get some
fun game theory going on so yeah
so I'm sadly on the research end of
things so I'm not very good at answering
that I think one of the most important
ones is legitimate credentials I think
that that was used a lot in public
threat reports where adversaries I mean
a big part of red teaming is you pop a
box and you you dump the credentials I
think that's one of the biggest ones I'd
say Remote Desktop is another big one
interestingly based on you know what
we've seen it exploiting vulnerabilities
as a post exploit Technic isn't as
common as say using built-in windows
tools which is why we have so much
effort dedicated to texana maizing the
built-ins
yes sir so I mean this is a this is
notional it was kind of hyper you know
it's fictional
but the idea is you know you would you
basically take the model you would try
to measure how well you detect something
and then and then color it or score it
based on your your results there so here
you know we might measure some so
exploitation of vulnerability is for
privilege escalation defense evasion and
credential access and that's something
that can apply that that or rather that
you can detect partially you might only
detect some vulnerabilities but there
might be you know zero days that you're
not detecting things like that or as if
someone tries doing security software
discovery on a host you can immediately
say hey you know I know you're doing
that and you can catch them right there
this shirt no I don't think so yet right
right so so I don't have this slide
strip but we also have something called
the cyber analytic repository which is
Carmine org and that provides you know I
had mentioned about using sysinternals
to measure those different data sources
that provides a little bit of that and I
believe using that you can also create
this mapping because now you have
signatures behavior olufsen natures that
apply to that that actually map back to
attack so you can do a little bit of
that measurement but that's definitely
something we want to have is a way for
people to ingest this and just like that
be able to create this coloring because
it provides a fantastic visualization
right and this this is fantastic for
providing that
unless there's any questions I'll just
throw contact info and again public
website but if you guys are interested
feel free to contact us contact me
anything thank you very much