[Music]
thank you so much we're here with Andrew
and Catherine from field-ready and we're
so excited to dive in a little deeper to
some of the details around the
challenges we've developed with them and
I think it'll be useful just to get
started with hopefully an easy question
which is can you tell us a little bit
more about field-ready in the work you
do and you know your organization's
mission
thanks and yeah thank you very much for
including field-ready in the hackaday
challenges here field-ready is a
humanitarian disaster relief
organization which means that the kind
of work we're doing is with people
affected by disaster in refugee
situations working with refugees so
there are refugees in Bangladesh or
internally displaced people who might
have been affected by state the recent
cyclone tropical cyclone herald that is
affected half the population of the
Pacific island nation of Vanuatu and
they does a weak recovery process a
rebuilding process for those for those
communities or longer-term
reconstruction such as in Nepal after
the 2015 earthquakes there was a there
is a response but now five years on
there's more work to be done in terms of
recovering the people's livelihood still
and then in Iraq after the conflict
there in particularly with Isis
occupation in the north of the country
try to create jobs and help to create
jobs for young people so that they can
develop their own businesses create
their own enterprises and
that the those are the sort of
humanitarian purposes that we work for
our mission really is a little bit
different it's we're not an the normal
human and cellphone organization if I'm
if there is such a thing what we try to
do is we try to manufacture eight light
in the field what we try to do is to use
all of the capacities and the
technologies the ideas even make a
movement of digital fabrication maker
spaces and we apply them into
humanitarian relief context
so basically field-ready makes aid
supplies in the field rather than
shipping them in rather than shipping in
supplies to a disaster zone you can
imagine in perhaps often an earthquake
or a cyclone a lot of the transport
infrastructure in stroyed with lots of
problems with that we try to make for
supplies locally and we find the finding
of that can make the supplies cheaper
faster and better in terms of when
they're finally handed over to people
who've been affected by the disaster by
making by making them locally they can
be cheaper faster and better which means
you can help more people more quickly
more effectively and by using some of
the ideas of the maker movement you can
also create local livelihoods jobs and
help with that recovery I talked about
yeah that's that's for your daddy's
mission to transform the way aid is
supplied in the world thank you I think
that's a really great foundation to get
started talking about some of your
current projects and then we'll get into
the challenges more specifically so I
know that there's a lot of stuff you
guys are currently working on some
things that were definitely affected by
recent events as well so if you could
just brief you briefly explain some of
your current work and then we'll get
into the first challenge well there are
three kinds of work here we do one is
the response activities and whether
that's to tropical cyclones or to
volcanoes or conflict or earthquakes
mobilizing to actually make supplies and
provide them to the affected people the
second thing that we do a lot of is
capacity-building and quality assurance
almost so trying to support local
manufacturing companies local maker
spaces local entrepreneurs and startups
to help then make eight supplies to help
put us out of a job and to make sure
that some of those some some of those
communities can be more resilient and
provide the aid that they need for
themselves by themselves in future
disaster responses and then the third
thing we do is we try to change the way
that the humanitarian system is working
so there's quite a bit of activity to
influence the aid sector to say you know
what guys making things in
India or China or turkey warehousing
them in Dubai or Copenhagen or Panama
and then shipping them to Fiji to
Bangladesh to Somalia whatever it might
be that's a bit of a crazy way of doing
things why don't we find new ways of
delivering aid trying to transform the
system something that might help some of
the people involved in the the
challenges were putting forward is that
one of the ways we're trying to change
the system as we have published a book
so I'm going to plug the book called
managing humanitarian innovation and a
lot of the information about the way
that we work and some of the tools that
we used to innovate in the middle of
that disaster response to work on
humanitarian innovation which I really
just included in this book sorry over
the course of the challenges in the in
the coming weeks we might be referring
to some of the content in that awesome
and Katherine do you want to say a
little bit about what you're currently
working on in response to the like ovid
crisis and I guess I don't I'd like to
say if I'm talking about what I'm doing
what I'm doing isn't necessarily
representative I was like what you know
everyone but yeah I was supposed to be
starting a position as a mechanical
engineer with the Pacific team in super
Fiji on April 1st but got stuck in the
States and since has been kind of
splitting my time between helping
coordinate between all our efforts
globally on the technical side of things
and also managing some work that's
happening here in this state we've been
running a partnership with an
organization called Cove in nineteen
shields that started up in the wake of
kovat out of the shuttered scenery
fabrication facility in LA um led by a
woman named Alexandra and so she's
manufacturing and distributing thousands
of shields a day
we are helping her distribute donated
and discounted shields to people who
need them so far we've gotten some
shields to two different hospitals on
two different Native American tribal
lands and then we are going to another
large chunk to an organization that
provides health care for homeless folks
in kind of all over California but
mostly in San Francisco and then we've
had a sprinkling of other smaller
donations to some people providing meals
to on house folks and a harm reduction
organization in Portland Oregon
another harm reduction organization in
holder Vella California I think I was
representative I mean over nineteen has
come along in among all of these other
disasters responsible place around the
world we've been manufacturing PPE we've
been manufacturing face shields we've
been manufacture designing and
manufacturing hand-washing facilities
things like that but you know actually
everybody all over the world is suddenly
needy and they're finding that the
traditional supply chains on supplying
so we're beginning to moment to really
ramp up the manufacture of those locally
as part of Tobit 19 right no that's
great I think that gives some good
context for getting into the challenges
and like you've said it's it's
representative of how you guys need to
respond in situations depending on
what's happening and where it's
happening and you know where your people
are and what you have available to you
and really taking advantage of of the
local resources and local connections
there so I think it's a great great
example to get us started so first off
we're going to get into the one of the
open call challenges which is the fluid
warmer I think that it would be really
helpful to just
start with sort of you know basic
definition of what a fluid warmer is
what it does and why it's important to
the work that you all do in the field
the fluid warmer yeah so a fluid warmer
is a medical device that heats
intravenous fluids up to body
temperature prior to those fluids being
injected into a patient this is really
important because if you inject a fluid
that's colder than body temperature you
can give a patient severe hypothermia
and it can result in death and by
intravenous fluids these are most
commonly either human blood for a blood
transfusion or IV saline for rehydration
and when there's not unlike a proper
medical device fluid warmer facilities
will still warm the fluids typically
through imprecise methods like
submerging the fluid which is enclosed
in like a plastic disposable into like a
warm water bath and this is really
dangerous for blood transfusions because
if you heat cold blood a couple degrees
too much you'll hemolyzed the blood and
this means that the red blood cells
rupture and if you inject hemolyzed
blood into a patient that can also very
easily
kill kill--uhh patient so without access
to proper fluid warmers blood
transfusions become very dangerous so in
some of the documentation we're looking
at as you know we went back and forth
developing this challenge I remember a
heating time being something that was
seemed to be an important factor and
then also something that we've noted in
the challenges that we'd like it to be
cost-effective so I was hoping we could
dive in a little bit more to those two
factors and explain you know why why
effective solutions would take these
things into account
yeah heating time is really important
typically the way a fluid warmer works
is that
and you take the tube of the IV in that
line and wrap it around a heating
element so the warmer is never actually
in contact with the fluid it it's in
contact with a tube and so from the tube
entering your fluid warmer to the tube
exiting your fluid warmer you need to
keep the fluid up to temperature and
medical facilities have standards for
how quickly they will inject IV fluids
and so you just want to make sure that
at the rate the fluid is passing through
the tubing you know that it gets to to
body temperature in time I'm so sorry
heating time comes into play cost yeah
that's important I mean the reason these
facilities don't have fluid warmers to
begin with is generally a lack of
resources so if we're making something
on the ground it has to be affordable
and scalable and to that point also the
the design needs to be made out of like
easily source parts and it also needs to
be designed such that if you find
different parts in different locations
you can easily adapt the design or the
code or the electronics to accommodate
whatever components it is you're able to
source if you're making these in the
field and one thing I'd say more
important than any of the three things I
just mentioned is safety field-ready
doesn't usually delve into medical
devices that can kill a person but a
fluid warm air is a device that if it's
poorly designed and that the safety
features aren't all the way there and
it's not yeah not up to par like it can
kill a person and that is unacceptable
obviously so I chase safety features
should absolutely be so as a for most of
anyone thinking about this one of the
other IDs
turns developed or started to develop a
fluid warmer open-source fluid warmer I
believe and did a whole in-depth report
on it which we're gonna sort of
summarize and make available to the
community and we just wanted to I wanted
to go over sort of on the call what were
some of the findings I know that there
were there's a lot of great research in
there that covers some of the things we
just mentioned the heat time sort of the
process of how it actually works and how
to do accomplish those things and she
also has some great case studies are
sort of benchmark examples but I know
that there were also some some feedback
from field ready team members sort of in
the field of how this could be improved
where there are any specific things you
could highlight one of the lessons about
what could be improved on the machine is
on the blood warmer device is
[Music]
essentially the user aspect of it to
make it a lot more straightforward for
the operators to use because we would be
introducing these into context where
perhaps they haven't had them before and
they haven't used these sorts of devices
so they're not necessarily going to be
very experienced on it the training that
might be available would probably often
be a virtual training and there isn't a
great deal of ways to sort of experiment
one of the one of the you know to
practice rather than experiment I think
actually should say to practice on using
the device before you use it on a real
patient so if there's any sort of
feedback mechanisms that can be relied
upon to help provide that training it
could be built into the design of the
product that is probably worth paying
the extra cost for
from the the work that has already been
done I
what's noted in that thesis of needing
the most work and definitely where the
least work went into the start is the
electronic system and the Arduino
controlling that and that's really where
all the safety features happen to I
think the code as is is is very messy
and hard to follow so I think a deeper
dive improving the electronic system
she clearly put a lot of time into the
kind of mechanical design of how it all
fits together and I'm sure there's room
for improvement there but I think
there's a lot of room for improvement in
the electronic so the the other open
call challenges we've developed with
field-ready
are in the form of some sort of tools
that could really come into play in the
in the field and also in some of the
maker spaces this grew out a
conversation with some of the team
members at a makerspace and I'm really
excited about these because I think
they're gonna really be a relatable for
a lot of our community and also I could
see us wanting them at design lab at all
kinds of places so I I think these have
a lot of like so the first one being
versatile heat sealer and welder and
then the other one being a a UV cure
wand I know that there are some
interesting examples you guys mentioned
when we're developing these challenges
that could currently be addressed with
these sorts of tools so I think that'd
be a great place to start just to cover
I know there was a sealing sanitary bags
for equipment was one and so maybe we
can start with some of those examples
and then get into more of where the
inspiration for this challenge came yeah
I'm the heat sealer front some immediate
thoughts for applications would be
package
so kind of you know we make items and we
have to distribute them and whether
they're healthcare medical device items
or items in other sectors we want them
to be clean when we distribute them so
kind of versatile heat sealer where you
know you could wrap something in plastic
and then and get a seal without
something that's quick and and allows
you to package something in a sterile
way is one really quick idea I know also
thinking about in the wake of a ovid we
were looking at producing medical
isolation gowns and sewing can be slow
if we're talking like maker space scale
production not automated textile factory
I'm sewing each and every gown can be
very slow so we were kind of looking at
some of the DIY stuff where people were
basically using mic hair straighteners
to plastic weld and so I think that it
could be really useful to to be able to
weld soft plastics we also have an
intubation box that was developed in
Fiji that it would be useful to have
something like this for and so something
that's first a towel that has some
adjustability to it where you know you
can dial it up if you're trying to seal
and well thick plastic but if you're
trying to use like a really thin plastic
for packaging you can dial it back
something that can allow you to not
necessarily be doing it at desktop but
standing up basically like we work with
all sorts of different sizes and shapes
and products and materials so
versatility is key so this one is more
of like a pie in the sky idea not so
much coming out of a you know we would
use this tomorrow if we had it where's
the heat sealer is very much it we would
use this tomorrow if we had it but UV
cure is just a really powerful tool for
prototyping and
vacations commonly used in medical
devices aerospace automotive but it
allows you to adhere a lot of different
materials to each other some materials
that are with traditional adhesives very
hard to get to bond to each other so
like metal on plastic for instance and
it allows you to have fluid tight bonds
to which can be really helpful in
medical devices or kind of wash
applications and anytime you're moving
fluid basically just something we have
an interest in sometimes I think that
covers it and I think that again we
wanted to reiterate that user
friendliness and safety and
affordability will be crucial to all of
these entries and to the proposed
solutions in these spaces I think again
as you mentioned this has to do with the
variety of sort of applications the
people that might be using and
implementing these these methods or
tools or or devices whether they're
field-ready stuff or they're people that
are being trained by field ready staff
or people that are you know have picked
up this idea and are taking it to their
local facility to implement so I think
unless there was other things around
those you guys wanted to mention we can
wrap up with the the dream team
challenge what maybe just one quick note
on the safety for these kind of lab
makerspace tools it'd be awesome if this
emissions came with some sort of risk
analysis of you know what might be some
modes of failure and how dangerous is it
to the operator and if and if the
designs of you know something that could
be shared more the intention with
everything that feels that it does is
that we share all of our designs openly
so that anyone can replicate them we put
risk notices
on some of our equipment some of our
designs to say you know if this isn't
made right and it fails that there could
be very severe severe consequences to
life or to help for whatever it might be
so make sure you make it rice and these
are the testing steps and all of that
but in those in that risk analysis when
you're looking at the UV ones or the
heat sealer also think about the health
and safety of the makers making it so
you know at this step what you need to
be doing is making sure that you know
you're wearing glasses because you know
safety goggles because you're going to
be cutting wire or you know wearing to
venue in there well-ventilated space
because you're going to be melting
plastic whatever yeah I think that's
actually a really perfect segue into the
Dream Team challenge the discussion of
sort of risk assessment and quality
control and again getting back to the
complications and challenges around
distributed fabrication and sort of
delivery of these these tools and
devices so so yeah we're gonna get into
the the Dream Team challenge this will
be this is something we put together
with field-ready with a dream team of
three engineers designers makers
thinkers in mind who will dedicate two
months to a of engineering sprint to
come up with a solution for this so what
we've come up with is we're looking for
a means of quality control that remotely
tracks and evaluate solutions protects
consumers and ensures a roadmap for
reporting and repair I think there were
sort of a few different anecdotes and
case study examples that you know again
we'll have listed online but maybe you
guys could share a few of those just to
paint the picture a little more the
inspiration for this challenge right you
know appeared of course with some of the
very first things that we
so one of the first things we ever made
as an organization were these things if
umbilical cord clamps that are to go on
the umbilical cord of newborn babies and
these are this is a 3d printed design it
was developed by one of our co-founders
in Haiti for clinics in 80 and it's
quite small as you can probably tell but
you know it really
a question of you know for us at the
time it was about how do we get our logo
on like so that if more we're needed
people know where to go to get it so
they can go to our website get the
design and make more i logo on it so
that if something goes wrong with this
like a clip doesn't work it doesn't
close properly they can report a fault
to us and we'll send them a new one or
you know I think as we've grown as an
organization that we've devote more and
more product more of these items have
been distributed distributed we share
all that all of our designs openly
online knowing which ones were made by
us using our design knowing which ones
were made by other people using an art
design and knowing which ones
[Music]
modifications of our design so our you
know over time to make that more of a
science and less of an art if you look
at the part of the inspiration is also
the future of the maker movement I mean
the maker movement and maker space is
the beginning to inform thinking about
what a new kind of manufacturing might
be localized manufacturing as a poster
that continually sort of centralizing
globalized manufacturing that we've had
ever since the bless' Industrial
Revolution if we're beginning to do
distributed manufacturing the big issue
is really about distributed quality
control and particularly for some of the
devices that we're making
often safety-critical in low resource
settings where perhaps quality control
or the expertise isn't there because
they're making lots of different things
in a day rather than the same thing over
and over and over again and you get that
experience that way so it's really about
how do we you know in the future where
we have massive
there's a small manufacturers making
lots of different things every day what
kind of system can we have to have
consumer protection so that we can meet
some of the standards that have
developed in the mainstream
manufacturing world a fairly basic form
of consumer protection there's knowing
who the manufacturer is and so labeling
ubiquitous you know on every mug on
every gadget not quite on every spare
part or internal components but close
for labeling serial numbers that allow
you to know which production run that
came off or or also you have some kind
of you know in some cases tracking
capabilities you know that a particular
batch of distribution went to that
location or even you know some tracking
potential you know in the in the device
itself so so we might imagine and I've
got some explained some scenarios you
might imagine you know myself visiting a
refugee camp in northern Iraq and
looking at the supplies you hand out
looking at I don't know this finger
brace a 3d printed finger brace and
trying to work out you know if that
needs to be replaced who can I go to to
replace it well actually there's the
manufacturer detail there I can track
that back to somebody trying to work out
if it's a field-ready design it really
is a question of accountability in
helping to enforce quality quality
assurance it's
quite a so this design challenge is
quite a big challenge for us if if there
was a simple solution we'd be doing it
already but the you know so we're doing
things like yeah spray-painting our logo
on that on the gadgets that we make
there's a big enough to do that with we
often but we might a simple number into
it but then we need the backend system
to track that so that you know we have
some obviously data systems in the
organization that allows us to track
these sorts of things but for the
purposes of this challenge assume a
blank sheet of paper and you know if
it's if there are solutions like spray
paints or barcodes or serial numbers or
QR codes or I had no RFID tags or really
have a think about what might work but
you have to think about things solutions
that could work with small clamps like
this so solutions that might be now an
entire toilet latrine unit that gets
shipped out to earth to a refugee camp
within there's some electronics units
and plastic things you know furniture
made out of wood or old pallets or
something what can we do to kind of
track each of those and give some
accountability for what we made to the
people that were trying to help yeah and
I think that actually that sort of flows
right into the next question of some of
the skills you think might be needed by
applicants to this dream team you've
described a little bit about back-end
systems on and to be integrated and
things like that again I know we don't
want to put too many constraints on it
but I think definitely the biggest thing
I feel like is you know an open problem
saw
kind of thinker who can really try to
wrap their head around this because it's
a like you said sort of a complex
challenge with lots of moving parts and
needs a dynamic solution that might
incorporate some physical hardware or
method or you know process and some data
logging and maybe some documentation or
maybe it's a magical tool that puts that
all into one so but if there are any
skills specifically you wanted to
mention that you think would be useful
throw those out there something that I
think would be really helpful for at
least one team member to have is a
background in quality control somehow
somebody who who's worked somewhere and
has some familiarity with standards
within quality control I think could
give some really good insights into what
we might want to incorporate I don't
think that's a mandatory but I think it
could be a really really powerful thing
on the team I think there could be
something interesting with AI here maybe
not that might be too high-tech but
somebody who maybe has thought about AI
and beyond that yeah I think just kind
of a Renaissance person kind of general
a little bit of a mechanical a little
bit of electrical a little bit of
software yeah luckily I think there's a
lot of those kinds of people in our
community and I think that's a great
point about the experience with quality
quality control Quality Assurance and I
think that that looks a lot of different
ways a lot of different industries so
any sort of standards you're familiar
with you know sort of at least a gateway
into what it takes to set up standards
or a process like that so I think that's
an excellent point
awesome I think we've pretty much
covered a lot of the constraints to this
challenge
I don't know if there was anything else
you wanted to mention there
the constraints are that it's this is
something we need to be able to use a
field ready already
we work in Fiji Vanuatu Philippines
Bangladesh Nepal Iraq Syria Jordan
Turkey Kenya Uganda soon when we've
worked in US Virgin Islands and Haiti
and you know the Columbia you know we
were quite
International which means lots of
different languages which means anything
that means that we don't have to deal
with language might be beneficial we
deal with lots of different types of
access so perhaps not everyone will have
a smartphone to use a qre our teams do
that perhaps some of the makers that we
would work with you know someone else
takes the design or a plight client that
we we've made you know and they produce
that maybe you know they'll have a
laptop and a 3d printer but they might
not have a smartphone or something so
it's almost thinking beyond a constraint
a sort of removal processive kind of you
know I'm not just thinking about kind of
attaching field-ready logo to things but
how would we do this kind of labeling
and tracking and Quality Assurance
customer protection almost within the
maker movement generally where you know
feedback can be can go from a user of
something that should be made in a local
makerspace to the person that made that
thing to the person that originally
designed that thing along along that
path yeah so it's I think
I would say a constraint is that for if
we want lots of organizations to try and
adopt this and filter these in a
position to be able to encourage that to
adopt a similar approach to the solution
that might come out of this we have to
think about the integrity of that data
and how the data is managed if there is
a sort of back-end IT system that
manages it all and and recognize that
you know that will need maintenance ISBN
numbers on you know our book has an ISDN
number no you can scan that on your
phone and it will give you the answer
because as a back-end database that
drives that sort of thing so thinking
about some of the the maintenance of
those systems whether it would
potentially be private information that
can reside in your own Syst internal
company system or whether you want
something much broader that's public
yeah there's a lot to play with in
charge that's why we're looking for a
dream team to work on it I'm so excited
to see sort of you know what the
hackaday community is going to bring
forth and just to get these challenges
out there and get everyone's get
everyone's input and super appreciative
that you all are dedicating your time to
continuing to answer our questions to
put these challenges together we know
that you're very busy so we appreciate
it and excited to have Katherine's on
board as a mentor and Andrew available
throughout to ask questions and things
so I'm sure this will inspire even more
conversation and questions from the
community so thank you and excited to
get to launch now we're very excited too
and we can you know we've been waiting
for these things further for these sorts
of design challenges eat sort of
opportunities it's important to us
because whilst design is part of what we
do it feel ready if we're designing
things if we're trying to solve
difficult technical problems we're not
making things without making things
so you know what this is giving us the
opportunity to develop solutions that we
can use in the field in lots of
different disaster zones the day after
that they're ready we can try those
potentially throughout the design
process as we go with our field teams
and the maker spaces that they operate
trying some of these things but I think
it's you know you know it wouldn't it be
great if the dream teams sort of a
tracking system could go on to the heat
sealers and the UV cure ones and to the
blood warmers into the umbilical cord
clamps in search and rescue air bags and
the latrine slabs and all of the other
things that we make and that we would
use those tools the people are
developing as well to be able to make so
that we can begin to really kind of
compete with the mainstream
manufacturing way of doing things to
help people who are often at the very
very far end of globalized supply chains