hey prize dream team
initial concept presentation today we
have
uh the ucpla united cerebral palsy los
angeles dream team joining us
along with their expert panelists from
the ucpla team
we're going to get started with a brief
introduction to why we're all here today
and then we will launch into
presentations and discussion
my name is magenta strongheart i'm the
head of design and partnerships at
supply frames design lab
for those of you who don't know supply
frame is the parent company for hackaday
attendee and design lab design lab is
our 4 000 square foot design and
fabrication facility right out of
right outside of los angeles california
and
this year for the hackaday prize we're
doing something totally new which is the
dream team program
we essentially recruited top talent to
work with our non-profit partners to
help solve a challenge over the course
of a two-month
engineering sprint so we have three
innovators joining us who are part of
the dream team
for ucpla we can't wait to introduce
them and see
their initial concept presentations
today's gonna work where we're gonna
have
a 20-minute presentation by the dream
team and then 20 minutes for discussion
between the panelists and our dream team
members and then finally 10 minutes for
q a from the audience so if you are
tuning in right now
please drop your questions in the
comments section and we'll be sure to
integrate those into our discussion at
the end um
before we get started i just want to
give a huge thank you to our sponsors
digikey microchip supply frame and arm
without them this would not be possible
so we're so grateful and appreciative
for their support to continue this
amazing work and
to develop incredible open source
solutions for our non-profit partners
with that i'm going to pass it off to
giovanni salinas our product development
engineer who's been project managing
these teams and who will give you an
introduction to the challenge that the
ucpla dream
team put forth
thank you magenta and hello everyone i
am really happy to be here today for the
first abstract
and concept review for the dream team
challenge
the ucpla team includes kelvin
in toronto canada ruben in colorado usa
and natalya in boston usa
so hi guys it's great to see you here
now the ucpla challenge asks the team to
design
a new type of universal remote that
meets the needs of the physical
challenges of people with cerebral palsy
and integrates with modern electronics
like
smart tvs workstations and other digital
devices
in as few steps as possible now while
the
definition of this challenge sounds
narrow in the world of usability
it becomes really broad so additionally
one of the biggest and more
frustrating challenges is cost also for
this kind of
devices so after a lot of research
and trying to understand the user's
challenges the team
reinterpreted it to developing an
affordable
open source platform to democratize
assistive technology
for interacting with the digital world
during the first three weeks of work
the team has done a lot of research in
the field and started brainstorming
potential solutions
the the idea of today's meeting with
stephanie and rania
is to present the results of this
research
and start discussing our first ideas
stephanie and irania we cannot thank you
enough
for for being here today and we are
really looking forward to hearing your
feedback
so uh without further ado i'll pass it
on to the team
hello i'm ruben keckster and i'll start
the presentation
which i believe is this one
there we go can everyone see my screen
very good so
thank you giovanni we're going to start
with a simple overview of the
of the project we're going to go through
a simple introduction
building off of what giovanni has
already said
touch on our design goals and then go
over each of the platforms that we feel
that
as as if we could bring them all
together could solve
the be the ultimate remote to solve all
the problems
our big mission as i said before is to
develop affordable open source platforms
that can bring specific technology to
everyone in the world everyone who needs
it
at an affordable price our potential
users have
such a drastic range of disabilities
that
it was a real challenge to try to figure
out what to focus on in the short time
that we have
and our target devices in this day and
age can range anywhere from
a simple tv controller that was around
50 years ago to
autonomous cars that are coming out
our design goals are centralized around
these few points
we want this again to be a universal
control interface with as many
connected devices as possible at least
those
that our users want to interact with the
most
accessibility it needs to be usually
easily usable by anyone
especially users with disabilities
portable needs to be able to
have a long battery life or be able to
charge easily
and even be mountable on on whatever
mode of transportation our users will
be using we would like it to be
expandable and
integrate with as many different input
methods as possible
as as again the range drastically
is a drastic range between different
usabilities that
whatever we decide needs to be able to
adapt to our
our users and with that it needs to have
functions and actions that are
customizable so the users can
pick and select and lay out whatever
this is to meet their needs as mentioned
before the cost is a big factor
especially in the world of accessibility
and we'll cover that more in the
other concepts and uh durability is a
huge factor too
as as users that have disabilities may
not apply the
may apply too much force and so it needs
to be very durable to
be able to stand up to the users
constant use our platform essentially
wants to be the middle man between two
worlds the the physical world where the
user
interacts with different kind of input
methods and the digital world which is
increasing and growing in a rapid rate
and there's so many
awesome projects out there but how do
you interface with them
that's hopefully we'll find a way to
bridge that gap
um this is a one proposal we came up
with
and it's um adaptive smart remote so
sticking to the name of the remote
what if we can make a remote that could
be truly used by everyone
target users in this case we're hoping
to find
we're targeting users that cannot use
existing devices without lots of effort
um they would need some sort of
accessibility
they it works best with someone that has
a line of sight with the device so they
can see
the the buttons and things they're
touching
and with touching they need to be able
to use some sort of uh digit
a knuckle a hand a fist to toe something
to interact with it
and again we are assuming our users want
to be able to use and operate this
device independently
without be able to get it out and use it
and move it around and
you know be their companion as needed
concept goals for this concept for this
proposal
is a versatile low-power device on
usable right out of the box no issue
no additional device or supporting
platforms required
at its bare minimum we hope to get it
out and be able to control
a tv this kind of interface would be
easiest
and intuitive for users with limited
mobility
the it would have unlimited functions by
using a display to show users what
functions are currently
assigned to each button and then you can
design and customize it to your arts
content
options are infinite we want it to be
integratable again with existing devices
easily expandable so touching on
meeting a lot of our target goals easily
expandable
different physical input methods and in
this case we could even include a
speaker that could be added for
additional
feedback and options one option would be
users could use the device's
assistive communication device where
each button may say or
or say something or a word or phrase
to help them communicate
the an original um concept of this has
existed
and has been tried and the users are
super grateful
the caretaker and the the primary user
absolutely
love the idea while it needs some
improvement they are really grateful to
have
something in their life anything to help
ease the struggle
and now it's time to bring it to the
next level in this case we're trying to
the concept be as simple as here's a
screen it's a tv remote
let's say we want to go to another
screen for more functions if the user
presses the far right button
the button on the display would
highlight and it would bring another
screen
so here the possibility is endless they
can flip through a book or page
like platform and and program it at as
many pages as they need and want
again for customizability and
expandability
the you could orient it in any way that
makes best sense for the user
right-handed left-handed
on the right-hand side we're showing
examples of adding external buttons or
joysticks or other
input methods if the onboard buttons
aren't quite or we would need more
options
uh some variations possibly variation
one would
would help alleviate the issue with
people that don't have
that line of sight required to use a
single system
the display unit could be the main
system mounted somewhere up higher
uh in their line of sight and then the
buttons or other inputs wouldn't have to
be this grid
could be wherever they would like it
another variation too we could thought
of is what if the buttons have the
displays built in
um that option would looks more like a
universal remote and would be
smaller more portable but it comes with
its own challenges
and now i'll turn the time over to
kelvin for the next
proposal hi thank you ruben
for this next proposal i want to build
off of ruben's modular expandable
concept and focus on
focus on developing a joystick based
module for operating computer
workstations
and accessing different computer
programs such as photoshop for
expressing creativity
web browsing for gaining knowledge or
connecting to online communities
or video games for recreation common
input devices
uh are mouse and keyboards and they're
not easy to use for a majority of this
population
so they might prefer something more
familiar such as a joystick
next slide so it seems existing
joysticks are a popular input device for
this community
and many users operate their motorized
wheelchair with the hand operated
joystick
so for our solution we want to present
something that has a familiar intuitive
interface
so it's more likely for users to adopt
and use
so then we ask the question why don't a
lot of users have assistive joysticks
for accessing
computers or tablets right now so when
you look at
looking at existing computer consumer
products
they do exist but it's just often at a
ridiculous price point
so for example the bluetooth joystick
for a tablet and phone that exists costs
about twelve hundred dollars
and if we're trying to identify the
biggest accessibility barrier
that restricts individuals with cerebral
palsy from accessing the digital world
that barrier just might be the cost
itself
next slide so one approach that is
pretty straightforward from our end
is to just focusing focus on overcoming
this cost barrier
to develop a level to develop a low-cost
bluetooth joystick that can
connect to computers tablets or phones
the first step would be to identify
off-the-shelf electronic components to
make a bluetooth joystick
including a joystick handle a bluetooth
micro cook
microcontroller and a few buttons what
we want to focus here is
on low cost aiming for a target of under
fifty dollars something that's easy to
assemble
and something that is easily
reproducible by others
so by the end of this project a very
feasible goal would be to deliver a few
standard
functioning bluetooth joysticks and then
we can take this a step further to
address ergonomics and make unique
joysticks
for each individual user next slide
so after we've identified the main
electronic components to make a diy
joystick the next step is to focusing
on mechanical components that affect
ergonomics
mainly the joystick handle so similar to
how you guys have developed a digital
library of three principle parts for
attaching painting tools for for
painting we could do something similar
for some for the joystick handles with
different designs
that are adjustable for different user
grips also different
hand sizes for so for a lot of these
existing
products first of all they're really
expensive so these handles could be like
200 dollars for
a piece of plastic and they're also
pretty generic
because they're made out of pretty
simple basic shapes and they're all
designed very symmetrically so not very
like uh
tailored toward people individual people
so for each individual user we could
loop them into the process
so that it's more likely for them to
embrace the solution
and use their custom tool you could ask
users to try different joystick handles
and identify which one they can grip
best
ask them for their input on their button
sizes or where their preference would be
for button placement on a joystick
platform then we could use
digital fabrication tools like 3d
printers in your studio
that you can use to create unique
joystick platforms
that is tailored for each person so our
job here is to identify the correct
parts
come out come up with a diy joystick kit
and then come up with an easy to use
instruction
manual for assembly and modifying 3d
printed parts
for this approach the goal isn't to
deliver just the generic joystick model
but rather to teach you guys a simple
process
for reproducing low-cost unique
bluetooth joysticks
next slide
so switching gears a little bit another
approach that we want to explore is
a new type of joystick that senses user
motion that is both durable and user
friendly
the easiest way to explain this concept
is by looking at the wii remote
where you can control actions and play
games by waving the wii remote around
so with this system the goal would be to
control digital devices by detecting
motions of the user
that are within the natural motion of
the user this would be
a joystick in a wireless small package
that can be worn
that is attached to different parts of
users bodies based on their preference
so the three images in the below i've
had uh like a wireless choice they got
attached to my hand
uh my wrist and also my name next slide
so here's one example of how a user
might use this type of joystick to
replicate the four directions
of wheelchair movement forward backward
left and right
so here i have a motion sensor attached
to my wrist and i'm wearing it like a
watch
so if i were sitting in a wheelchair um
my arm and my elbow is pretty much like
like on table which is sort of like on a
armrest of a wheelchair
uh so in this position i'm using my
elbow to as a pivot point for my
joystick
so there's no longer a second physical
joystick device
and in this case the joystick is my arm
as itself
so intuitively if i wanted to move left
or right i would swing my arm
left or right from a neutral resting
position and if i wanted to go
forward or backwards i would similarly
move my arm up or down
next slide
so for more examples of this concept
i've uploaded uh two youtube videos that
are linked into the abstract that we've
attached
in this scenario i'm holding two motion
sensors in both of my hands and i'm
using
these sensors to control mouse and
keyboard commands such as
moving the mouse around or clicking the
mouse for the application of drawing and
paint
so the two images on the right are
drawings that are drawn only using these
motion sensing door sticks so i drew the
supply frame logo with both of my hands
and i drew the happy face by moving my
head to demonstrate the ability to
control with different body parts
so with that i'm going to pass it off to
natalia to present a different concept
thank you kelvin thank you ruben and
finally our final sec proposal is a
platform app
and obviously you might immediately ask
why do we talk about any apps after
these amazing contributions and ideas
are for the hardware but i'm gonna make
a case that
application and software basis uh is
interconnected not only for comments and
ruben's applications but for thousands
of hackers from
hackaday and all around the world next
slide please
so why do we even talk about software
well first of all it's the cheapest
solution for the production once
developed it is the easiest to
distribute
no shipping cost no 3d printing errors
no components may
stay out of stock it is potentially the
easiest to adapt and to test with these
existing devices our users own
as the availability of these devices is
possibly the highest as i are
ubiquitous among existing reports
interviews google forms
uh we have leveraged and collected as
well as feedback from the ucpla team
uh almost all of our users potential
users own a smartphone
a tablet or an assistive vocal
support system next slide
and obviously even going beyond with the
ubiquitous communications and systems
available
all around the clock even if our actual
users do not have a system at place
their caregivers
their homes their centers have an alexa
echo
cortana or smart home appliances that
are already connected
we can leverage all these devices in the
support of our users
next slide
here is one of the supporting codes from
the users and from the ucpla team
members
individual utilizes all of the above
smart phone
tablet etc as they're also consumers of
the times
but what is really lacking is the how
how tools
can they utilize these items to fit
their unique physicality
there are no other examples of these
either through apps or videos
another uh responder from our survey
suggests that he's like watching youtube
but unfortunately it's a bit hard for
him to actually find these videos that
actually can
support his condition as a condition of
other
people as him next slide
so what we have done already preliminary
we have
actually leveraged a first version of
our survey
where we ask very different and broad
questions
sometimes they're very precise and
sometimes not
for example if you can install any dream
app of your choice what this app would
be
what would it do or what applications
are you
using at least once a day like whatsapp
facebook or
instagram and based on these responses
our platform app can leverage a
suggestion for our user next slide
here is an example let's imagine tommy
tommy used our service system within an
app
or a web interface and our battery map
will generate a response for tommy the
best option would be to set up an open
source smart home system from openhab
as the smart appliances control is
requested by tomi
very often he mentions that
his preferred communication method is
voice and the second preferred is
touch tommy can either check for and our
platform will suggest
this offer from amazon echo for 39 with
tutorials excluded
or not available or this amazing
hackaday project from 2020 dream team
with a cost of 50 dollars with three
already available tutorials for the
smartphone systems
and maybe with other users posting the
tutorials on the hackaday
next slide there are several main
features
the versatility and personalization
based
exclusively on the desires and
capabilities of this current user
can they touch can they speak can they
produce
songs based on the existing open source
a commercial product
the user owns or wants to own if they
already have alexa
let's leverage it if they already have a
joystick let's leverage it
checking for tutorials and videos to
help the user in
their condition not just oh start using
ipad tutorial
learning curve could be very short to
non-existent depending how climatized
the users are with the apps and
because they have the devices usually
they are pretty acclimatized
and this system is extremely incremental
potential of easy integration with the
suggestions from sarah
alex ruben kelvin as i as well as other
thousands of hackers researchers and
designers as well as center
team members next slide
in a nutshell in a perfect scenario
there are actually no limitations
this platform can can ultimately enable
access
to any device joystick tablet wheelchair
headband to any modality
voice of touch it can be accommodating
for any budget maybe you already have it
or maybe you have some availabilities
and capabilities to pay
and as well as any system even the ones
that already purchased by the users for
any other needs and potentially going
beyond
a cerebral palsy accommodating other
disabilities at least
similar ones next slide
obviously there are a lot of challenges
to overcome the database should be built
and constantly updated
as it might require some support from a
full-time or part-time person at the
center at least in the beginning
uh but community can also leverage this
easily it might require obviously some
additional generation of the contact in
case of
the user that who cannot feel touch or
cannot speak
or cannot actually hear this content
should be generated in the mentality
they can hear and understand
obviously privacy concerns are also
important next slide
obviously here is a big and honest
vision of how we can see this platform
the best case scenario would be the
creation of the unified platform on
multiple u.s states where ucp exists
to include multiple centers expanding
into the worldwide
use and creating the unified database
with
great stats available in the medium case
we will have our counties
our local centers and also available for
statewide use
and in the worst case even if we have
one tommy
being able to tell me natalie researcher
what he's looking for and what other
options he's looking for i can
just give him a feedback hey maybe you
need to go on hackaday and she exists in
that project
next slide so this is obviously not
a final representation but a potential
reason that
tommy can control his system using like
his voice gestures or even brain he can
watch
read and listen how to acquire some
systems how to
buy them he will know that he already
has some parts of them for example if
you use his voice like alex and cortana
will explicitly tell him this
he can maybe participate in some paid
studies and he will actually be able to
learn about
his condition condition of other people
and connect with them
and finally for example the gesture
system is not supported yet
but a system was readily available for
the ucpa center who has
most of the components or the supply
frame can supply them with some
with a budget that is very very limited
he can actually address
to these centers to help them build the
system
and on this one and everybody can move
to the
final slide we want to thank you for
your attention right now we are taking
uh questions comments and feedback and
of course
do not hesitate to contact us
in offline if you have any any remarks
and questions and
on this note i will pass to magento
wonderful wonderful presentation
thank you so much to the ucpla dream
team natalia rubin and
kelvin that was awesome and i'm so
excited to hear the feedback from our
panelists we have stephanie anderson
stott
director of growth and innovation at
ucpla and aranya kerr adaptive design
manager for ucpla with us today
and they've been given so much of their
time so much generous feedback and
mentorship
to all of our prac hackaday prize
entrants this year and especially our
dream team members so
want to give a huge thank you to them
first off and in just a moment we'll
pass it off to them for their questions
and feedback i do want to remind
our audience members right now that you
can comment any questions you might have
for
our panelists and team members here
today in the youtube comments here and
we'll be sure
to gather those before our q a for the
last 10 minutes of today's event
so without further ado we'll start our
20 minutes of discussion
and then we'll wrap it up with your
audience comments and
questions
go ahead stephanie and irania if you
want to take it away
to start out we want to thank hack day
and supply frame for supporting this
incredible challenge
and uh to the innovative members of our
dream team
you've brought even more than what we
could have imagined um
up to this point so this is a very
exciting day for us as we look through
all of the opportunities
um first of all let me just say that it
it is amazing to see that the spectrum
of solutions that you've proposed
really track and meet the spectrum of
needs
okay you seem to have developed
options and opportunities for such a
diverse group of people
and users and that's extraordinarily
heartening for
rania and i as we have met and seen so
many
um creative and very capable people
who simply need um greater addictivity
in in terms of what's available to them
and uh
i i'm quite blown away by some of the
suggestions already i'm very excited not
only to see
um what you've presented
uh reuben related to the joysticks and
and uh some of the equipment that people
are already most familiar with
but um also to really take a look at the
idea
of utilizing the motion sensors kelvin
so many of the individuals that we work
with
definitely have certain types of range
of motion
that they are very able to control and
manage
and are very natural to them being able
to leverage that
and be able to give them more control
in all sorts of activities in their
everyday life
would be significant um likewise
natalia it's great to look at the
opportunities related to the apps as
that's going to be such a diverse and
accessible platform
i want to start off just with a quick
question with regard to
the motion sensing equipment because
that's something that i know
even less about what's what would the
price point be do you still think that
that's going to be something
that might be uh able to be produced
in that kind of 50 range or something
along those lines
yep so um the initial prototype that i
was using
i i had like two motion sensing units
and also migraine controller
and in total it was about 30 dollars so
that's that's sort of the price point
that we're starting with so it's still
like similar to like the other
like joystick open source joystick that
we might want to look at the building
that's tremendous yeah i mean first of
all i think everything is like pretty
amazing so thank you guys
that was so awesome and for you to
consider
everybody like the spectrum it's you
know i think my wish now is like
i want to see it happen you know i want
to see it made you know so it's like
that's my excitement is knowing that
it's brought to this point now
i want to see like the production and
like have the users use it you know
i'm i'm also quite blown away by the
price point um you can get on and heard
our concerns about the exorbitant costs
of so many
of the devices and and the technology
out there that's without
outside of the reach of of any of us
let alone people who are on a very fixed
income um
and to be able to not only make
things um uh really inexpensive to be
able to obtain but to also replace
is is huge also to not have it caught up
in the um the politics and
and um uh challenges that come with
uh insurance systems and you know things
that have to go through uh many
different doctors and consultants and
whatnot is is huge
as you said democratizing the digital
tech and increasing the accessibility
um it's huge it's a huge step in terms
of that
and also just like individualizing to
any user that uses it you know like
everyone has their own language so
like i think that's like really powerful
that they could create their own
language
in in these controls and then be able to
use it so i think that's like really
important because
at the end of the day it's theirs you
know it's not ours it's
so yeah you guys are amazing
to that end the idea as well that um
the individuals could influence the way
that uh
their unique piece of equipment might be
able to be utilized uh
ruben as you were talking about with the
joystick and the different types of
grips
that's again very exciting to see
because the idea is to be able to
conform to the individual needs
and capabilities of people who have
you know unique uh physicality
each one of the platforms suggested from
the joysticks to the motion sensors
to the apps offer a range of those
options
but it's exciting too because this is
each one is so scalable
i believe um and uh
just as you had suggested in your design
goals expandable
um depending on the different types of
things that people would like to do
with the equipment um let's see
questions i probably have a million but
let me
drill down a bit haranya do you have
anything right away no i mean i
i don't really have any question i just
like i love the idea from like the
physicality to like the app part to like
how the user will use it you know and
that can kind of create like
a discourse amongst other users so i
think that's like really
like innovative it's not just about
having that uh
product but it's also having like the
apps to go with that product and then
having
a multiple conversation or a universal
conversation
yeah the the potential for interfacing
with so many
points of interest in people's lives is
huge let me ask you
um along the lines of the motion sensing
um
would there it would seem that there
might be compatibility also with
eye gaze technology we you know
definitely know
some folks who utilize um calibrated eye
gaze
technology to be able to control um
everything from
their wheelchairs uh to communication
devices
um does that seem something that would
be in line
with with what you're envisioning or
developing as an
option for motion sensing technology
so i believe um like the eye tracking id
solutions are
like oftentimes camera based so
i don't know if it's as easy to
integrate it might be like a separate
solution
okay not having a motion sensor like
attached like somewhere on the head
where you're like moving i think that's
somewhat similar if it's
like slight head movements to sort of
control
like different devices i can
jump in actually um and back it up a bit
because i did develop several
eye tracking systems that are not camera
based so
it's important to mention that there are
camera and non-camera based systems
obviously we do lose some of the
features so features like
capabilities of the system you know
camera based can tell you for example
pupil dilation and usually they're
extremely precise
but there are several drawbacks one very
important
even open source are extremely expensive
i haven't seen a lot like on hackaday i
saw couples that tried to actually nail
it down to cheaper versions
and that's why actually a lot of people
uh
still try to hack just a touch camera
and
i'm due to the glasses just to
sunglasses to any frame like
super cheap one that's one direction the
thing is that obviously at night
uh if the sensor is not fitting well
you're tired
uh the classification outcome like the
precision would be a bit lost
but we have also developed a particular
focus on the privacy and ethical
considerations for
other users are non-camera based
approaches so there will be maybe less
features meaning less
options but it can be like eye brings
for example
moving eyes left right so we can
associate those potentially
and these are very very affordable they
do go
under definitely 200 on top of my head
and i believe that with some maybe
external like research they can
definitely go even
cheaper obviously they cannot go like
canada right away 50 but definitely
i think under 200 and what is more
important a lot of these
systems do have imu and other sensors
already built in and they weighed like
20 grams something like iranian glasses
that i
i see right now i'm pretty sure it's
like 20 30 grams right so that would be
actually very very light yeah
so there is uh options no
precise i would say right away but yeah
there are directions we can also explore
that's that's wonderful to hear just
looking at you know what what some folks
have been able to really
utilize and incorporate into their lives
over time just to see
you know different types of applications
that's that's great thank you
thank you very much um oh
with regard to what can be 3d printed
um as as probably the only person in the
group who isn't
um a very strong 3d printer
myself can you tell us a little bit
about with the
motion sensing equipment as well as with
the joystick
what you see is being able to be easily
reproduced and printed
you know potentially by folks in our
studios
and what would be things that would need
to be supplied
um so for the idea of like a joystick
platform where you have like a
joystick and a bunch of buttons that are
bluetooth connected
um i think the main like ergonomic uh
feature that's most important
is the handle itself so i think it's the
handle that we would
like to have like a library of different
parts
that uh for different users that we want
to develop
and it's also like another part which is
not as important but it's also like the
platform
and where like the buttons would go on
the platform that would suit
each person um so i guess those are like
the
the two uh components that we want like
user input for designing the joystick
platform
so if there was the base um compatible
configured
equipment then you could add on those
pieces and print them directly according
to
each individual and have them available
okay
i mean that would work uh very well with
with
how we're set up currently and and also
to
to just touch on the fact that there are
so many other providers um
as you mentioned across the country um
many of whom that we are
connected with um some are other ucps
which is a national organization and has
affiliates across the country but also
um providers of other independent
nonprofits that we know need
this kind of technology and would enjoy
being able to
um to experiment with some of these
prototypes and be able to give feedback
so um there's a huge number of people
out there and then way beyond even our
own network
i'm sure that this could uh benefit so
thank you
aranya do you have anything else uh yeah
i mean i think the idea of all the
different joysticks are like
again that's very personal and that's
very individualized because
every joystick that's out there you know
you just got that one basic one
but some of them use like their like
wrist to kind of move
the joystick around so that big one was
like really cool
so i mean you know basically you guys
thought about
everyone's physicality and kind of like
the spectrum and then
kind of adapt all these different like
you know
set of things that go to everyone so i
think that's
like really interesting so yeah that's
awesome
it's also interesting i would just um
just a little bit more feedback the
notion that you've got these different
platforms offers a user who has
different capacities to use them based
on how they're feeling we talked a bit
about in some of our conversations about
um
you know just the fact that uh exerting
a lot of physical motion
can be very tiresome and so at the end
of the day
the physicality might decline but
somebody might be able to
rely on blinking as you were saying
natalia or
or just making sounds to control
something so again having these
multi-faceted
options and solutions uh we're just
we're just kind of like
time you know how the kind of the body
kind of like not deteriorates but just
kind of loses some of the functionality
and so these are the different options
as time
you know takes over then they can again
they're not losing their ability they
just need more
adaptation and some of these things will
like fit into that
adaptation absolutely and
one of the things i wanted to to
mention correct me if i'm wrong team
we're still waiting for results of the
survey stride and based on those
findings
the project might go in one direction or
the other
and we had so just to give super quick
our update because
folks from the outside on youtube
obviously do not know but i tried to
mention it real brief
we rolled out a first version of the
survey and the actual very quick
feedback that we got
as i said we work like 60 plus questions
very very very long and
full one and the very first feedback we
got from stephanie and iran is super
useful saying that hey you know
it's amazing but we don't work only with
cerebral palsy like
it's exactly your last point stephanie
and irania
there are other similar and sometimes
not similar to all disabilities and
conditions
is exactly what we are talking about so
ultimately we might
even expand it our survey changing a bit
the language and adapting it actually
more generic disability uh so some links
were provided for the app's eye to
include a generic disability and not
only cp
but it's an excellent point for from you
stefan and irania saying that
uh with time even us we are not as fresh
at 9 00 a.m as like for example at
7 00 a.m or 7 p.m et cetera and
obviously
there are disabilities and conditions
where it is unfortunately
degenerative deterioration like ls and
there are no way back no
come back so definitely if you can also
meet
these users potentially halfway
uh we're not saying that we're gonna
design everything in two months but
definitely this is a big big vision and
direction
which we'll try to shoot for at least
with the help of the fox and the team
well and again um the the incredible
advocacy to be able to empower people to
be independent
in every aspect um any aspect really of
their choosing their lives is
is significant with this project thank
you for taking that on
um thank you on behalf of our
organization and
um i believe so many out there so many
others out there who
who are absolutely yearning to be able
to
leverage their their great knowledge
their capability their ideas
their voice in different ways um this is
this is tremendous
i'm sorry i'm gonna have to cut up uh
cut off
our discussion there and turn to our
questions from the audience we have some
amazing questions coming in so i want to
make sure we allow for enough time
to answer those thank you stephanie and
ronya for your feedback and
insight and i'm excited to see what our
team has to say to some of these
comments so let's get started here and i
will ask
to the dream team members if you could
try to be as concise with your answers
here
maybe leave it up to one one member to
answer each
question just so we can get through them
we have about
six collected here and there might be
more coming in so i want to get to as
many as possible
in the remaining time we have all right
so
first question are there any plans to
integrate haptic feedback to the
wireless joysticks
um so yeah i think before we get into
that i think the first question that we
asked the ucple was um can they sense
touch
um because that that's probably more
important if they can't sense it then
there's no point so
i think uh irania you mentioned that
they they do and for
uh each person that that sense of touch
is either heightened or
compromised so it varies case by case um
so with that
suggestion um we do hope to i'll play
around with uh
like providing some haptic feedback
along with like some vision if they
don't have like visual feedback or any
other
feedback sensations so yes
thank you kelvin another question was
how do you avoid the training bias that
is inherent in these voice assistants
do you have plans on making your own
voice assistant for this application
trained specifically from these users
and so uh once again we will definitely
validate some things
in offline with stephanie and irania
first thing we need to
actually think about privacy as i
mentioned it's very important for
everyone and caregivers included feeling
comfortable
so there might be a way to go around
this second thing
uh some of the assistants and we talked
to the
members of lexi team and others
for the accessibility have a actually
available set of accessibility features
that are that need to be activated and
validated but they're already
available so that's also an option and
we
saw that we might work in this direction
uh with some
additional feedback from stephanie and
iranian about voice and service that we
are collecting
thank you natalia um next question
was there any consideration given to eeg
monitor headsets and leveraging those
with software
for example muse by interaxicon would
that work
yeah totally as actually phd in brand
computer interfaces here
and definitely actually posted two logs
uh on our hackaday web page don't
hesitate to
check it actually talking about using
eeg headsets
as a part of my prior work with ls
patients
and we definitely considered this in our
preliminary surveillance have two
responses people mentioned that they use
eeg
so we don't think that it might be the
thing we will go
for but there is always a lot of prior
work and one of the projects i worked is
on open source and potentially we can
embed it in our app
and system so definitely not excluded uh
check out the logs definitely
awesome thank you um another question
and maybe this would just
need a little more clarification or dive
a little deeper because i do believe you
started to cover it in one of your
slides but this person also may have
joined a little later
how do you plan on connecting the
universal remote to a wide range of
products
maybe you could elaborate on that point
true thing
it kind of goes back to our first
overview slide between the the
physical world and the digital world the
thought was the universal remote would
have an onboard wireless system low
power
similar to like z-wave there's a lot of
popular smart home systems
and then it would communicate with a
smart hub or a smart home system and
then be able to digitize
or connect digitally to the rest of the
different
items in the world
thanks ruben have you considered
developing a standard base that hackers
could then design their own 3d printed
parts that could attach to the base
i think that falls along kelvin's idea
essentially the joystick method where
yeah you would start with a base
set of buttons and joysticks and then
you could build off over there
thank you kelvin did you want to add
anything to that
no problem all right we'll keep going
it seems uh like any technology such as
eye or motion tracking there needs to be
an option for an on
off so that users can still have the
option to move without
something moving so i guess that's more
of a
commoner suggestion but if you guys
would like to
elaborate on if you've considered that
or how you would differentiate maybe
in the different applications of any of
these solutions whether it be the
universal remote the joystick
the app utilizing other devices etc how
do you
differentiate the functions and
applications
being as we're still in the very
preliminary design
we are sure considering a lot of options
there's so many other different options
to go off of what kelvin was showing
with the joint with the wireless choice
the imus there was a project where
someone commented these dots you just
place on your skin
and then some device tracks them for for
amputees there's so many cool projects
out there
and so we haven't nailed down on what
exactly we're going to focus on
so keep the comments coming we'll be
sure to include them in our design
yeah yeah so to just add up on that so
like um we could also have like a
joystick let's see like a button
so maybe your like foot is in a certain
position so by slightly altering your
slit
or like by lifting up your arm off your
armrest that that sort of like is your
on
off that is sort of intuitive to use
awesome thank you reuben and calvin uh
one um one audience member wanted to
highlight to check out
iwriter for another awesome open source
eye tracker they use it with an artist
to project graffiti they drew onto a
building because they couldn't draw
so i love that suggestion
another question we had was
how are you all designing the survey so
that it's accessible
they're suggesting that maybe some
community members might not be able to
fill out the survey so that's a question
totally
yeah we thought about this that's why so
we needed
as you all guys know and for those
youtube who are watching do not really
know
it is two months sprint so we are trying
to cover
all the tracks and to right now actually
make one more accessibility version
available
definitely right now limited and we are
working in this direction
uh but certainly if we will make it um
for the extended period of time august
and even beyond august
we're definitely gonna roll out at least
one more accessibility version
for sure to build off of that
we understand that many users at this
point before they have the tools in hand
will need
their caregivers to help fill out
surveys and get us information and
feedback
and we're relying a lot on the ucpla
team to help us with that
thank you all right and then last
question
was around the privacy again
with voice assistance how do you ensure
that privacy
is remained intact if you're
intending to integrate these other
devices
yes for sure so once again uh
we didn't confirm yet uh will we go with
voice assistant or not that's one of the
suggestions basically
uh built upon the feedback from ucpla
and also this survey uh preliminary
results only on 10
users so far actually indicated that all
of them can use voice and
uh it heavy in amazon aircraft on this
kind of system so once again
we will see how we can if we leverage
this um communication uh how secure
it is and obviously in everything that
we are designing and looking at
uh privacy and what will be collected as
data would be the first thing
and we definitely were thinking actually
so we need
proof of concept not to using voice
assistance that is off the shelf
commercial available but have a
small proof of concept version to being
tested by our users and their caregivers
securely
in full comfort and without actually
going into depth but
showing if this proof of concept even
works so
yeah thank you thank you natalia
so that about is uh gonna wrap it up for
us today we're about time here i want to
give a huge thank you to our awesome
audience members for those wonderful
questions
and to our dream team participants of
course
natalia rubin and calvin for their
incredible proposals that they presented
today
and last but not least our wonderful
mentors and advisors from ucpla
aranya and stephanie thank you for your
generous contributions and your time
that you've continued to give us for the
prize and for the dream teams
we're really excited to see how these
solutions continue to develop
and if you're wondering where you can
find out more about these projects head
to hackaday.io and search for hdp
dream team ucpla you'll be able to
follow along their logs and the logs of
all the other dream team
members and their progress there also
please be sure to follow us on socials
facebook instagram and twitter hackaday
and design lab you'll be able to see
updates on resources content that's
coming out video interviews
articles and more thanks again for
everyone joining in today it was in a
wonderful
session and we're gonna have two more
next week with our other two dream teams
on monday so be sure to check those out
you