sorry morning it's my pleasure to
introduce to you Alyssa Miller for her
talk losing our reality understanding
and combating the deep fake threat
Alyssa Miller is a hacker security
evangelist cyber security professional
and public speaker with almost 15 years
of experience in the security industry
her journey through security was
recently featured in an article by
cybercrime magazine she's also been
raggin recognized in peerless book 50
influential penetration testers alyssa
is a treasurer and member of the board
for women of security woah SEC and an
application security advocate for lender
based sinc limited please join me in
welcoming all right so you guys hearing
me through the headphones were good
awesome that's what I care about awesome
well thank you for coming out good to
see you all here besides Tampa so this
is me the intro kinda said at all I'm a
hacker and a researcher I've been in
this space doing this for 15 years I've
actually been a hacker a lot longer than
that I always tell the story really
quick that at you know the age of 12 I
bought my first computer so for those of
you remember 1989 yeah I'm that old
you know we didn't have computers in
homes typically so yeah I went out and
bought my first computer taught myself
how to program in basic and later taught
myself asynchronous modem communications
did some things to prodigy that may or
may not be beyond the statute of
limitations for the Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act I'm really not sure so we'll
just leave it at that
as was mentioned I work for sneek so we
do application security software for
developers and I say for developers I
mean like we write stuff for developers
to use it's not stuff for security
people security
people use it too I'm also author and a
blogger I'm currently working on a book
for those of you that actually heard my
question for Rachel this morning that
was related to the book I'm writing
trying to find ways to get more people
into our industry and help advocate for
them help them understand how to get
around things like you know the HR
firewall and so forth and then finally
I'm also the co-host of the uncommon
journey podcast and itsp magazine we
just launched that a couple weeks ago so
today I'm taking you on a journey it's a
journey of sight and sound and you'll
have really cool sound today we're
hooked up with the headsets you know we
use our five senses to evaluate our
world around us but what happens when
suddenly those senses become the attack
vector that the cyber criminals the
attackers are using against us so let me
tell you a really quick story when I was
four years old my parents took me to
this place those of you from the Midwest
will recognize that the Wisconsin Dells
and yes I got one thumbs up somebody's
from that area love it it's cold up
there colder than this you know we went
to this place and we do a lot of stuff
you know they got water parks and
everything else but one of the things we
did was went to the place they call a
fun house now I don't understand why
they call this a fun house because there
was anything but fun we get into this
maze and it's got mirrors it's got
optical illusions every time I would go
running up I'd run up to it I said I
thought I was gonna get out and I'd find
out my eyes were deceiving me I don't
run I'd go over here and I see all no
that was just mirror there's nothing
there I couldn't trust my senses and I
started to panic I didn't know how to
deal with that situation I didn't know
it was real or fake I couldn't tell
where the actual useful information was
and I couldn't trust my senses to help
me out this is what attackers are doing
now with what we call deep fakes
now how many in you have heard of deep
fakes before I'm guessing most because
you came to this talk so when I talk
about deep fakes I'm talking about any
media that is artificially generated
using deep learning networks and we'll
talk about what that looks like in a
little bit but it could be audio it
could just be pictures or as I'm sure
many of you have seen it's now also
video and really really impressive video
and we'll see an example of that coming
up here in just a few minutes but where
did it begin where do things always
begin if it's valuable technology where
does it start anybody want to venture a
guess I heard it over here
porn any technology in the last 30 years
that has been worth having has always
ended up launching something new in the
porn industry and this was no different
so people artists producers whatever you
want to call them who are creating porn
videos started to create porn videos
only instead of the actresses that were
in the videos they started putting
actresses faces faces of celebrities on
those bodies we had women like Natalie
Portman gal gadot Natalie Dormer and
Emma Watson Emma Watson finally was like
you know what I'm out y'all this is just
gonna keep happening I can't do nothing
about it she just gave up
talk about apathy and if we can blame
her what can you do about this we're
gonna talk about some of those problems
so it didn't take long you know and this
showed up and porn and started to do its
thing we had researchers who were using
these neural networks to create some
really impressive stuff and as they got
better well it's her to move into
politics we started seeing deep fake
targets obviously our present resident
of the White House was included but
we've seen as some of you may have seen
a really popular video out there done by
Jordan Peele where he impersonates
Barack Obama
and Barack Obama is basically you know
chewing on everybody in the GOP that was
a few years ago the results of that were
incredible and they tricked a lot of
people but it's gotten a lot more
impressive and I'm going to show you an
example here and we're gonna try to get
the audio through the mic long story all
right we're gonna see biking you
anything about that I might not be able
to because unfortunately we're slightly
ostentatious tired debris from Las Vegas
those for my fans have long dismissed
allegiance to Impressionists how many
opportunities passed up and wasted
because he's helped to follow what he
must pity the poor impressionist alright
so I don't know how much of it you heard
because unfortunately we some audio
challenges here this morning but that's
alright what's not important is the
audio the audio is the actors voice but
the video is what's important and if you
watch that if you're not paying really
close attention those faces switch and
they switch so smoothly
and they look so realistic you wouldn't
even realize that wait a minute that
that's not the person I was watching
just a moment ago and indeed I've talked
to people who you know
I have seen that video and didn't even
realize in Tolleson they looked over one
second was Nicolas Cage the next second
it was you know you know somebody else
dr. Phil I think was in there too this
is where things have gotten to so far
but it's only getting better why is it
getting better well it comes down to how
these things are created in the first
place and the design of these deep
learning networks that are creating them
so when we start to talk about how we
create deep fakes we're talking about
this thing we call Gans generative
adversarial networks now break that down
and it kind of explains how these things
work first of all they're generative
they're trying to create something from
nothing
okay that's basically what they do so
they're adversarial well that implies
two parties right competing against each
other that's exactly what happens
there's two deep learning networks
involved here the first is called a
generator the generators job is to as
the name would imply generate content
the second is the discriminator now the
discriminator again as the name would
imply is there to discriminate what
images are real versus what images are
fake now in reality they're all going to
be fake but it is trying to determine
you know it's trying to detect hey
that's a fake image or that's an image
that doesn't match the learning center
that training set that I was given and
so we use still images to train these
neural networks on how to generate and
how to detect those images then we just
take a piece of target media so
oftentimes like you saw in that video
it's going to be an actor who you know
is standing in place of the person that
we're trying to create in the video and
the generator just starts replacing
frames and it starts drawing in new
faces now the discriminator taste those
it looks at it and says okay that's real
it becomes part of the deep fake
here's the trick if it's not that
feedback goes back to the generator so
what you end up with here is a constant
loop of the attacker making the defender
better but then the defender making the
attacker better now we've seen this in
info security for you know the entire
time I've been in it probably all 60
years of it but Ganz accelerate this by
orders of magnitude
so this may seem all ethereal this is
you know these are ganz they exist in
academia and you know we're using
there's a lot of research and my teeth
teaches a whole course on what I just
gave you in about a minute they do a
much better job obviously than I do this
was a little over simplified for you but
the fact the point is this there are
consumer grade options for this so fake
app was kind of the first that was the
first open source one it was thrown out
there pretty hard to find an actual
legit copy of it anymore because
attackers got ahold of it and it was
open source so they just started
inserting you know malware and other
garbage into the libraries and posting
them so if you do a search for fake app
you'll get lots of results and trying to
figure out the one that's genuine it's
probably not worth your time now face
swap on the other hand is more recent
and that one's a little easier to find
so that now brings it down to the level
of your desktop now you're not gonna run
the gang on your desktop no it's tied
into third party networks that it uses
for that what you can create this on a
computer and as if that wasn't enough
we'd like to do everything as a service
these days so now we have deep fakes as
a service there's a website out there
are deep fakes web which will create one
online for you the last one you see
there deep nude thankfully does not
exist anymore that was an app that was
produced last year and it's supposed
goal was to be x-ray glasses so you
could see what a woman looked like
underneath her clothes and yes indeed it
only worked on women and all it really
was was a deep fake app they had
pictures of what
they would whatever your target was it
put her face on top of the woman it
lasted a week as you can imagine
thankfully the the community-at-large
wasn't real thrilled of that one
so the point of all this is how do you
define real we define real by the things
that we observe with our five senses
when those five senses are the thing
that's under attack that's a pretty
inherent attack vector
that leaves us scrambling that can have
strong consequences for our society
everything in our society is based on
trust
whether it's banking we had regional up
here before talking about Morgan Stanley
whether it's the stock market which
right now is all over the map because no
one can trust it imagine now when we
have the ability with deep face to
really mess with your minds so what are
some of the attack vectors were seen how
about social engineering
so I mentioned audio before we kind of
when we talk about deep face we get snow
wrapped up in the video we forget that
audio is one of the major targets here
and indeed last year it came out that
there was a oil company in the UK where
the CEO mistakenly wire transferred 220
euros to our 220 million euros excuse me
to the CEO of their parent company
because he received a phone call from
the CEO telling them to make this wire
transfer my problem was I wasn't the CEO
it was a deep faked audio version of the
CEO telling him to do this and in fact
once wasn't enough for these guys they
actually came back a week later tried to
do it again thankfully he kind of
learned his lesson at that point and
didn't fall for it twice but this is a
significant issue how often do we go off
with the voices we hear as a means of in
our daily lives just authenticating the
person we're talking to so this leads
into an interesting attack factor then
what about extortion now yes this
particular instance when mr. Bies owes
from everything I've read and his own
admissions doesn't sound like there was
anything phony about the pictures and
things they were using against him but
what's to stop that be in the next step
does it have to be something real for to
have an impact on his position in that
company does it have to be something
real to ruin a marriage just the threat
of that is enough to manipulate most
business leaders so let's talk about
business for a minute you all know what
insider trading is right what about the
idea of outsider training
well this I've never heard of outsider
training before what is that I'm going
to tell you because I made it up so
imagine this for a second imagine Tesla
is about to release their newest model
they have a launch tomorrow they're
gonna launch the model Q they've been
you know amping it up for months and
months and months I have no idea if
there's a model Q don't don't run out
and look to invest in that I have no
idea that's again made up here but the
night before they're going to launch a
video surfaces of Elon Musk in a private
conversation with somebody talking about
how there's problems with the vehicle
productions going to be delayed things
of that nature what's gonna happen to
their stock it's gonna do that right but
if there was a deep faked video what's
the smart attacker doing they're
watching that stock crash they're buying
buying buying and then when it comes out
maybe they even put it out into the
world that this was a deep fake video
you know stocks recover test well Tesla
launches fine stocks shoot up sell sell
sell instant profit right so it's the
same thing but if I can do that at a
business level someone the size of Tesla
what can I do with the markets of small
nations whole industries so much of what
we do in the market exists based off of
reports and analysts doing what they do
producing their thoughts on these things
we trust
these earnings reports that come out we
listen to those calls as investors what
happens when suddenly that we can't
trust what we're hearing anymore how
could an attacker potentially manipulate
those markets but there's a flip side to
this too right so it's obvious the
attack vectors here I can create these
deep fakes I can do horrible things with
them but let's think about this current
situation of political affairs in the
u.s. we have somebody who consistently
is claiming everything that shows up in
the media is fake news if it's anything
that he doesn't like it's fake news so
haven't we just further enabled that now
we've got this people in society know
they can't trust the media they're seen
how much easier does that make it now
for politicians across the board to
stand up there and when something comes
out about them that is not complimentary
to them simply claim that it's a deep
fake who's gonna prove you wrong so the
good news is researchers are trying to
help there's a lot of research being
done into technological solutions to
help try to address this first most of
them are looking at the idea of
detection how can we detect deep fakes
early on it was simple or relatively
simple if we analyze the video we could
see different distortions we could see
different characteristics artifacts
things in the video that were pretty
telling you wouldn't always have the
right angle of face to make it fit the
angle that was in the video that was
pretty easy to detect so I'm gonna jump
ahead here because we've got things in
the wrong order so another one that was
more recent was the idea of eye blinking
so for the longest time you could very
easily detect these by simply trying to
hear what the subject was even blinking
at all think about it we train these
gans we
pictures still images how many still
images are there a view out on the web
with your eyes closed not many
so they got better ganz started to
create eye closures they started to
blink more often so we couldn't look at
the rate of blinking anymore instead we
started looking at the speed and some of
the natural movements of eye blinking
and what did the gans do they got better
this is the nature of how this works so
some of the other ways we've been able
to detect it simple warping we look at
video especially something like this
where it's a Hollywood motion picture
from far away it's pretty convincing but
then in this particular scene the video
zooms in on her face or his face or I
don't know whose face and then as you
start to see you can actually I don't
know how all you guys can tell but you
can really see a lot of the pixelation
just because we have resolution issues
there's distortions in the cheekbones
because again we're trying to shape one
face to fit the size and shape of
another and that is a complex thing and
these neural networks are trying to
improve on that but there's still a lot
of work to do one of the more promising
detection methods in fact they're
boasting about 95% detection rate right
now is the idea of modeling behaviors so
moving beyond just the simple
technological portions of video analysis
but actually looking at the subject of
the deep fake so in the case of Barack
Obama as you see here when he's
expressing certain emotions or sharing
certain content what are the facial
expressions he makes how does he turn
his head how does he tilt his head how
often does he blinked as he blink more
or less dude does he Pharrell his
eyebrows things like that where now it's
very context specific and it's doing
really well in fact they they're
expecting to see by about June ish
they're hoping to have 99% accuracy here
what's the problem this works great if
you've already loaded that training data
for the subject so if it's a politician
you
maybe you can detect it pretty quickly
but what if it's a random CEO that no
one's really thinking about are you
going to have a training set all set and
loaded and trained up to detect this no
it's going to take time and when we talk
about disinformation like this time is
of the essence now I mentioned the
opposite right this idea of you know
certifying the original so if someone's
gonna claim that it's a deep fake how do
we detect how can we prove that it's not
how can we prove it's authentic and so
research researchers are working in
creating cameras that generate some form
of hash some form of signatures some
sort of way to digitally sign that video
to authenticate it now what are the
challenges with this one you've got to
find the person has the original to what
happens the minute you start uploading
that original to things like YouTube and
Facebook and all these others hosting
services what's the first thing they do
when you upload a video they reprocess
it they run it through a codec so now
we've got a design codecs that are going
to maintain some form of reputable chain
of custody of that evidence and you've
got to convince all these medias social
media outlets we haven't exactly been
the most cooperative in terms of privacy
and you know detecting fake news and so
forth you have to convince them to buy
into this so all the researchers are
saying what if we could prevent deep
fakes altogether so this is what we're
calling the idea of adversarial / -
Bruce perturbations while that is a
really tough word to say basically what
we're doing here so you don't have to
remember the big horrible words is we're
injecting noise into images that is
completely undetectable to the human eye
but as you can see in the images here it
completely messes with all that facial
recognition stuff that we've been using
and it's that facial recognition
libraries that we need in order to
generate these deep fakes
if they can't detect with the faces in
the training set if they can't detect
where the faces in that source video
they can't produce these videos but how
realistic is it to make sure that every
picture of yours on the entire web that
could ever be used as part of a training
set is treated in such a way it's not
very realistic and that can be
problematic so the problem here is one
of disinformation I said that before and
I'm sorry my slides went awry to order
so I'm going to go back the problem with
this information is it's sticky right
the way disinformation works first of
all is it plays off of a person's
pre-existing biases it tells a story
that fits in to what they already
believe or want to believe so what
happens is when they see that piece of
disinformation it simply gets plugged in
to this logic chain that we form in our
brains so we have these different biases
these different preconceived notions
these values that we want to believe and
it just plays right into that and fits
into this logic chain as a result it
becomes amazingly difficult to dislodge
that information so what do we do about
it if I want to debunk disinformation
first and foremost I have to educate
people that it's there they have to be
aware of the possibility I think where
we've reached that point I think 99% of
this room raised your hand your new deep
fakes existed but then when a deep fake
occurs we have to refute it and we have
to refute it over and over it has to be
repeated over and over and over again
now we get that right I mean we've done
that we've seen that happen a great case
it was not a deep fake but the Nancy the
infamous Nancy Pelosi video where a
couple of your far right-wing folks took
the video slowed it down made it look
like she was drunk they posted it to
Facebook even days after it was talked
about that this was fake and this was
you know just someone had had
manipulated the video you
we still saw rapid rapid expansion in
the shares of this video with posts of
people talking about how she was drunk
at this particular event so the part
that we tend to forget here is remember
that logic chain if I'm gonna pull
something out of that logic chain I have
to replace it with alternative
information something that fits with
reality but also speaks to those biases
those values those preconceived notions
something that will fit into that logic
chain so I can take out the false
information and replace it with reality
this is the difficult part this is the
part we have to plan for so when I talk
about deep fakes the challenge here is
we've got all of these you know these
wonderful different technological ideas
of how we're going to detect them we're
gonna prevent the reality is the problem
here is not technological the problem
here is a human issue and so as
organizations who face this in
particular we have to start thinking
about how we address the human mind how
are we designing countermeasures for
this how are we being able to react to
this so first and foremost if I'm an
organization one of the things I need to
start doing is really controlling how
information about my organization gets
out in the world of social media in the
world of interconnectedness
organizations have gotten sloppy we have
so many methods for how we disseminate
information how people find out
different information how this all gets
released to the public we need to start
consolidating that I'm not suggesting
get out of social media I'm not
suggesting to stop using those channels
but we need to be more methodical and
how we do it a little bit longer term we
need to start thinking about how we
build in a response plan as part of any
other incident response plan we would
have disinformation whether it comes
from deep fakes or some other source is
something we need to start can
sitting as an incident that we have to
respond to that means planning to have
media outlets who we trust who will work
with us to get that information out
there repeat it over and over again when
we have to refute something they will be
receptive to telling the story in a
fashion that does speak to breaking that
logic chain and replacing the false
information with real facts we have to
have that plan for how we're going to
monitor for this type of information and
respond to it quickly longer-term
farsighted view we need to start working
and I hate to say this because I know
when I say this our word everybody
freaks out we need to start thinking
about regulations we need to think about
working with lawmakers on litigate on on
legislation rather that will address
this right now there's there's a split
view on this and I have to admit I'm
torn on it myself on one hand you've got
people's right to not having false
information spread about them on the
other hand you have that First Amendment
right to be able to produce you know
your free speech and to you know share
your commentary on political folks and
so forth
and unfortunately the latter is what's
winning right now in social media when
we saw the Pelosi video Facebook refused
to take it down they say I was protected
by free speech it didn't violate any
other Terms of Service without some form
of intervention and it can't just be
politics it can't just be legislation we
do need to pressure organizations as
well those social media giants to see
that okay this goes beyond just simple
political commentary where we have to
start drawing that line and understand
where can we start to effectively push
change in this now Facebook to their end
they've actually started a competition
right now I was just speaking to some
college students earlier this week about
work they're doing as part of a
competition for detecting feet deep
fakes so Facebook is trying to do
something but I don't think detection is
going to be
enough we've seen it with Facebook
before we've seen it with Twitter before
we've seen it with Instagram they
implement these policies but they never
seem to be implemented in a way that to
you and I makes a lot of sense so I'm
not sure that's the end-all be-all
answer the good news is there are some
positive intentions that you know are
applications for deep fakes first any
Star Wars fans I'm among friends all
right so yeah we had grand moff tarkin
was brought back a young Princess Leia
came back both of these were created
using the same technology to me that's
that's pretty cool now there's still
some questions about how do you you know
how do you control who you know is able
to do what they're and permissions and
stuff but well that Hollywood sort that
out and I think it's really between them
and you know and if an actor dies hey
you know figure it out with their estate
right one really cool and that's showing
a lot of promise right now is in medical
imaging we're finding that using this
technology ganzar becoming better than
doctors at detecting very early stages
of things like cancer in MRIs they're
able to see things that's such a
granular level and detect patterns that
they're starting to work with that
medical imaging to detect these things
sooner there's also work being done in
augmented reality where you call up your
doctor and you can have a conversation
your doctor only it's not your doctor
it's it's a deep faked video and you're
talking to you know some other form of I
hesitate to use the term AI but some
form of pot or whatever that's giving
you health information at least
collecting your information and one that
just came out a few weeks ago in the
news and this one I thought this one is
getting mixed reviews some people think
it's a terrible thing some people think
it's great I thought if nothing else it
was very innovative and that's this
politician in India he's the president
of I believe it's a BJP party if I
recall correctly
and he created a video for his
constituents he created it in English
most people in the more populous areas
of India do speak English but if you
know anything about India there's
something like twenty other dialects
that are spoken he had them create deep
fake versions of that video in all 20
dialects so he could reach over 15
million constituents it was very
effective people responded well to
seeing their politicians speaking to
them in their native tongues and it was
all deep fake so yeah I mean you could
argue either way on that but I in a way
you can't argue it that's at least
pretty dang innovative so before I leave
here today I'm gonna leave you with this
clause and I won't read it to you I know
it's long but this speaks to the heart
of what disinformation is all about so
Yuri was a former KGB agent he actually
lives now in the United States but I
mean this was 1984 and he's commenting
on the brainwashing campaign and
ideological subversion techniques that
the Soviets were using against the
United States do we think this is going
on still today probably and I don't
think we're the only targets and I don't
think that we can claim we're not
targeting other nations too so with that
I'm going to share some references with
you so if you have your cell phones this
is probably gonna I don't know if you
can read that that well this is
unfortunately the Lighting's not the
greatest I can make these slides
available as well after the fact
actually I gave a similar presentation
earlier this week that one for sure will
be recorded I'm not sure how we're doing
over here with recording is it alright
so it'll be in the recordings - you'll
see it but definitely a lot of the
research that's being done around
depicts check out these links I'll also
say I invite each and every one of you
to continue this conversation
feel free to reach out to me on social
media I will share all the information I
can with you I can share some other
information I mentioned MIT does this
you know week-long course well they've
been publishing the videos from that
course so you can actually go out if you
search for MIT and I believe it is
introduction to machine learning you'll
find like I said it's a week-long course
and they cover a lot of the topics we
talked about here today they walk you
through the construction of Ganz they
get very technical so if you want to
know more about the algorithms at hand
very good source for that as well
it's where I've gotten a lot of the
information that I've been able to learn
and gather but definitely check out
those studies get in touch with me I'm
always happy to discuss I actually got
that a little earlier than I had planned
I'd plan to leave some time for
questions but I've got quite a bit of
time so are there questions for me
related to the research we've seen
related to the threats anything of that
nature yeah so the question is what
about fraudsters using deep fakes and is
there more information out there
unfortunately there's not a lot right
now there were literally a few Forbes
articles that I found there's been some
research there is the the one story that
came like I said out of the UK but this
is part of the issue honestly with deep
fakes at the moment and again I just so
I was just out at that that big
three-letter conference in California
earlier this week and what I found there
was everybody when they think deep fakes
everybody's thinking about the political
applications of this no one's really
looking at the other applications right
now my worry is after we get through
this 2020 cycle here in the US where do
we go next
and I've got a feeling we're gonna be in
for a big surprise we have the
opportunity to get it ahead of the
attackers right now and I don't think
we're doing that yes
yeah so that's a good point
so people need them brought up the fact
that what about the attack vector of
just using this for harassment and we
saw what happened already with the porn
industry right and and there is
definitely the case for that especially
as this becomes more consumer eyes the
idea of revenge porn and so forth so is
there space for that research there is
space for that research I don't know
that a lot is being done in terms of
researching specifically deep fakes
applications to it I am familiar with a
number of organizations right now that
have done considerable work in how to
help people defend and recover from
those types of situations revenge porn
being a big one that people are looking
at today one organization in particular
that I'm very familiar with is called
badass army and that's an organization
that is working actively with
legislation to try to get things taken
care of in that sense they also work
with victims in recovering from this and
there's a few other organizations too
who unfortunately at the moment that the
name of them are slipping my head
slipping my mind I saw one at P sites
Las Vegas last year there's actually a
video out there if you search for it but
yes there's definitely more room to be
done there too because again all you
need I didn't mention this before but
when we talk about that training set
most of these games have gotten to the
point that four or five maybe six
pictures at most is all they need in
order to generate amazingly realistic
content so that's a very difficult thing
to defend against
other questions yeah yeah and that's so
that's an interesting point brings up
just kind of the the breadth of what
some of these attack vectors are and
even the capability of people to
intentionally attack themselves so
industry and so forth where it might
actually be advantageous to cause an
issue of some fashion and in those
situations yeah you know it is what it
is is the changing paradigm in attacks
and that and that's a simple matter here
is you know we've we've seen over time
you know we start with very technical
hacks and that that's certainly my
background and background of a lot of us
here we've been slowly over time we've
been talking more and more about the
human element or the human factor we see
that that was the theme out in
California this week this is the next
step on that I mean this is now not only
we just attacking people's consciousness
we've taken it to a level of attacking
their actual senses and how they
evaluate the world around them evaluate
what's real and fake
it's a massive new form of social
engineering yes anything else
one last one
yes yeah there's a lot of research going
right now on the medical imaging side
and that's where it's it's impressive so
right now they're looking at just
medical imaging but they are actually
sending even beyond that's where they're
digitizing other forms of information
coming in and they're leveraging it for
that actually another exciting
development that I've seen research
being done using the same technology is
they're actually using it to analyze
malware so they take malware they're
able to convert it whether it's filelist
whether it's it's you know your more
traditional malware they're able to
convert it there's two researchers from
McAfee doing this and what they're able
to see is even when it's polymorphic and
it's you know it's self morphing code
it's able to detect very specific
patterns in that malware where even as
it morphs it still is able to see those
specific patterns analyzing it the way
they would from a deep fake detection
perspective so a lot of research a lot
of things definitely a lot of technology
to be formed here I certainly again
encourage you guys reach out to me I'm
always happy to discuss this share what
I'm seeing my research on this continues
just because it's a topic that I'm
passionate about it's nothing that my my
employer does or anything else I just
happen to really find it fascinating so