all right everyone the moment you've all
been waiting for Super Tuesday fallout
here it's it's like another Christmas
it's better than Christmas this is
pretty much the best I could have
possibly hoped for
going into this I predicted Joe Biden
would outperform and I said he would
need four states in order to remain
viable he'd probably get a bit over that
I don't think anyone expected him to
actually get possibly nine states on
Super Tuesday so my prediction was right
but I was being too conservative and I
think I have that tendency some time to
underestimate ball swinging number two
Schenk melts down number three Elizabeth
Warren comes in third third in her own
state not only she didn't even come in
second she didn't even come in close
she's like more than ten points behind
the front or Biden manages to win I
figured that that one would probably be
for Sanders because he had been running
a couple points out of Warren and Biden
would be a close third it was it was
fairly packed up but the fact that she
can't even win her own home state send
her packing to all of the Elizabeth
Warren fans I know you're very salty and
yes I am going to troll you to pieces on
Twitter for hours and hours today I mean
have a great time you gotta get her to
drop out she's just gonna get humiliated
if she stays in there's no path to
victory for hell there's barely a path
to victory for Sanders at this point
after this I'm gonna go through this it
might be a long rant here it's gonna be
a funny one too so stay tuned I think
the biggest news of the night though
here the whole this this one warms the
cockles of my heart I've been talking
for months to Bernie Sanders fans and
whenever I talk to them I say look I'm
one of Sanders constituents and I'm
telling you that Bernie Sanders isn't
even universally accepted in his home
state and they always brushed it aside
so why do Vermonters compli electing him
and hit point out there's a difference
but demographically is a huge difference
between Vermonters in the nation number
one so get that out of my face number
two you've got to understand the dynamic
of New England politics
New Englanders tend to vote for the
incumbent Bernie Sanders is not an
incumbent presidential figure he's a
Challenger for the presidency he's not
even the nominee of the Democratic Party
he barely cracked 50% in his home state
so - so
night two people's home states were up
Elizabeth Warren came in third in hers
she should drop out and Bernie Sanders
barely managed to crack 50 in a state
where supposedly he was ahead by 50
points supposedly he was running in the
70s a week ago or a couple of weeks ago
where's your support go Bernie Joe Biden
won two states tonight by a bigger
margin than Sanders won his own fucking
home state he hears Sanders strength he
wins Vermont by 51 percent but let's see
Joe Biden won Alabama with 63 percent
that's I think that's a bigger number Oh
anyone Virginia with 53 Virginia one of
the most important swing states of the
whole United States at this point
probably you know the mean median and
the mode as far as that goes other than
maybe Florida Joe Biden knocks it out of
the park gets over 50 I think by the way
when a candidate does that doesn't it
robbed everyone else of Delegates I
think it does Bernie Sanders only got
that in Vermont and just barely dude but
Bernie Sanders at this point is not
looking too strong now Jake jigger of
The Young Turks network of course does
his live stream I would have but you
know I'm in Amsterdam I'm I'm
handicapped by six hours when it comes
to US political discourse at the moment
come come you know months from now or
something maybe that changes right now I
can't really livestream things that are
gonna be at 3:00 a.m. I don't think that
you would enjoy it I don't think it's
gonna be quite as energetic you'd have
to get me loaded first maybe Jake
Jagger's doing is his live analysis and
I saw a clip this morning because like
five people who sent it to me he had a
meltdown and abandoned his own show
because Bernie Sanders was doing so
poorly but yeah I think I mean the news
of the night is this I'm gonna go
through the states here's a list of
where Bernie won California by 33 which
you know that was pretty much expected
that could rise or fall is only 65
percent reporting Colorado with 36 Utah
with 35 and Vermont with 51 that last
one really must hurt him by the way he
might win Maine there's 81% reporting
there and it hasn't been declared yet
because Biden is only leading by a point
so this could go either way it could be
a fifth state for Bernie or a night stay
for Biden
but I mean this is hilarious oh here's
where Joe Biden won he wins Alabama with
63 Arkansas with 41 Massachusetts with
34 Minnesota with 39 North Carolina with
43 Oklahoma with 39 Tennessee with 42
Texas with 34 in Virginia with 53 now
what does this tell us it tells us that
the Democratic voters have rejected
socialism they have rejected Bernie
Sanders snake oil which I'll give you
lukewarm golfclap their Biden I think
still ends up losing but he probably
doesn't get crippled the same way and
this gives us so many advantages seeing
Biden you know devolve on a debate stage
talking to Trump will be funny
number one Trump will almost certainly
win number two although I'd be more
certain if Bernie Sanders were the
nominee and the Democrats don't go full
dumbass they don't go full socialist
socialism should never be allowed to
represent a mainstream political force
within the United States it's a failed
system we've watched it fail over and
over again and the kind of programs that
Bernie Sanders is arguing for have more
in common with Venezuela than they do
with ma Nordic model he doesn't even
follow that Bernie Sanders is not a
social democrat he is a socialist
he's been proclaiming himself won since
the 1970s I'm tired of Bernie Sanders
fans lying and trying to Gaslight me on
this you're not gonna be able to get
around me of all people it's just not
gonna fucking happen anyway Bernie
Sanders has been crippled he's not out
of the running I think that that most
what this probably leads to is a
contested convention this is another
reason to believe Trump will win I mean
his odds must be rising right now
because it looks like his opponents
gonna be a dude with dementia who
doesn't even technically have a clear
mandate going into the nomination
process if they go there and they have a
contested convention here's what I
imagine will happen Biden will be ahead
he will have a clear majority but he
will be ahead in the delegate count
he will clearly be the one that's going
to be nominated but the Bernie Sanders
fans will raise the biggest godalmighty
stink ever in fact some of Bernie
Sanders own staffers have talked about
committing arson and assault if that
happens if Bernie Sanders is not
nominated and I suspect he won't be this
considerably reduces his odds if we went
into the suit
into Super Tuesday saying Sanders is
technically frontrunner albeit a weak
one
Biden's gotten that back this gives him
quite an edge in the delegate total it's
not insurmountable but you have to
understand the other effect the other
effect here is that if he looks like
he's inevitable Warren will probably
drop out and endorse Joe Biden at that
point he will coast through the
remaining states Bernie Sanders will
still continue to pick up minority
delegates maybe even win a couple of
states probably just enough to keep Joe
Biden from a clear majority by the way
but Biden will get it and then the
Bernie Sanders fans who have been
promised free everything will say oh no
imagine that your promised imagine that
you're crazy relative promises to get
you all sorts of shit at Christmas I'm
gonna give you a sports car and a trend
a house and I'm gonna give you half a
million dollars you do this like a
little kid or something the mentality
will be similar you promised them all
sorts of stuff that you can't really
deliver on but you're promising it to
them to make them happy and then
Christmas comes and then they don't have
any of these things because somebody
else informs them that they couldn't
have them now ultimately it's because
crazy relative couldn't deliver on those
things and everyone around you is
rejecting that premise they know that
he's crazy but unfortunately you
believed it because you know it's just
not quite mentally there the Bernie
Sanders fans right now are having a
nervous breakdown and and partially
that's deserved some of these people
should fucking know better they've been
taken in by a bunch of economic
Scientology and they need to be informed
of what reality really is that is free
shit does not work saying it sounds it
sounds noise that we should give people
free ice cream okay how are you gonna
pay for that all make the billionaires
give you ice cream that's that's fucking
stupid that's not the way it works it's
not the way an economy works it's not
the way sanity works it's not the way
the US apparently has chosen to work if
Bernie Sanders can't even scrape
together a clear consensus among dem
motors this just proves what I've been
saying for months which is that he's
taken the Overton Window of the Dems and
shifted it way off to the side leaving
behind all of the centrist voters in the
fucking country ever Chua Lee every
independent when people see this now
Joe Biden just got his are of
inevitability back there are a lot of
people by the way who will vote for Joe
and hold their nose who aren't really
excited you've got two shitty
possibilities here and you have for
quite some time because none of these
other fruitcakes had been viable
Bloomberg's come in third in a handful
of states you might even pick up a few
delegates but he doesn't matter
he's even admitted the other day he
admitted no there's no path forward for
me to be nominated yeah I mean why are
you in then dude he's more likely to
drop out and run as an independent at
this point which by the way would kill
the Democrats as a party you got Bernie
Sanders who can't win because he's too
old he's too weak and feeble he's just
had got done having a major heart attack
he is a self-proclaimed socialist it
doesn't matter if the Twitter mafia
finds that to be fine it doesn't matter
if tumblr pages agree that that's okay
it doesn't matter how many shit posts I
have to see plastered all over the
internet about how socialism isn't
really the problem it was CIA coos or
it's really capitalism that killed
Venezuela and all of this stupid shit
doesn't work the other alternative is a
dude who's almost as always like two
years younger and he's got dementia
clearly has dementia Joe Biden could
string together a paragraph without
constantly making mistakes 10 years ago
now I know that he suffers with a verbal
tic a stutter I understand that but some
of the things that he has a problem with
lately are not stuttering him him
forgetting the most basic things like
what state he's in or to where his pants
maybe before the staffers run after him
to keep him from going outside
that's not normal dude your candidate I
think about who you're running who your
candidates going to be Democrats think
about the choice that it has boiled down
to you pissed away all the viable ones
nobody ever took Gillibrand seriously
who lien Castro sabotage himself and
then he had bootie judge who was
probably the last sane person in the
field and I used that term very
tenuously he decided to drop out he
endorsed by Dhin much to Biden's a
parent benefit tonight so yeah Super
Tuesday round up again
Elizabeth Warren fails to win her home
say comes at third is humiliated which
is what was going to happen it was clear
that if she won it would be by a slim
margin her most likely opportunity was
to come in a close second behind Sanders
ends up inverting completely Biden
manages to fucking grab the state
partially because she refused to drop
out if she had I have no doubt if she
had dropped out whether she endorsed
Bernie or not he would have grabbed
Massachusetts if you look at these
numbers Biden would have been pulling
5050 anyway even if she did and that's
the funny part
Biden's in such a commanding position
right now that he probably would have
grabbed up almost this he probably would
have gotten five or six states even if
Warren had dropped down endorsed Bernie
Sanders the day before that's the funny
part barely would have counterbalanced
bootie judge of course she's been a
non-existent fixture of the field for a
long time she's at this point she's
broken down into pandering identity
politics and making tweets begging for
money well if she keeps making those
tweets and it's clear she's not gonna
drop out then I don't know what to I
don't know what to tell her fans but at
that point you've really chosen a real
goddamn smelly dead fish as a candidate
because if a person is completely
crushed in this fashion and doesn't
leave the race they're just being
stubborn or trying to grift off money
which which is what she's been doing the
whole time Elizabeth Warren loves money
she took tens of millions in corporate
money and their Senate bid never spent
it and then rolled it over and called
herself grassroots Bloomberg's out of it
he comes in 30 doesn't show up it dude
the top number one and two people in
every single state here is Biden and
Sanders nobody else cracked into the top
three anywhere and for the most part
didn't grab up any delegates at all I
think that this is great I think it's
good for America too it's good to give a
stinging rebuke to the socialist whining
babies number one Elizabeth Warren
fundamentally knocked out number two I
think that's good for the country she is
she's an ignominious old fool
Bloomberg doesn't gain any traction it's
clear that he's not gonna do anything
other than sow chaos possibly and that
would be funny more than anything Biden
will probably be the nominee Sanders has
been rebuked his fans are salty Warren's
fans are salty everyone else is salty
Trump must be celebrating is he's
complaining right now the end it's
reverse psychology when he make
tweets about them stealing things from
Bernie Sanders he's trying to get the
Bernie Sanders fans riled up more and it
works that's why he keeps doing it I'm
gonna have a good day it's gonna be
pretty fun corona virus epidemic
spreading a sigh that's about all he so