[Music]
nt start and the other security in
defending the Delaney system brings
we're defending it is digital exhorting
sonar Vietnam pretty return down for us
separating from reality and there
no no so so yeah just so that we're
clear if you're here here's one I have a
by grant somewhere that's not what this
is about this is how to actually protect
the gets read somewhere they won't let
break they won't let me give you the how
to be good is being at doing ransom
we're talking about at least not on
shore I've heard their rumors that they
want to do one of these conferences
twelve miles offshore and and in that
case off you go to twelve on how to be
good at ransom so so we're going to talk
a little bit about ransom where's the
service and that's a little bit about me
[Music]
before we get into ransom or service
let's talk a little bit about the
current state of ransomware sort all on
the same page there's been a sea change
in ransomware and how ransomware works
you know so 2015 and 16 you saw a big
surge in ransomware but primarily
targeting consumes large scale efficient
campaigns that handlings emails a month
etc the and primarily delivered via
fishing and when they're on vacation
the big ones got together people who
Microsoft Safari applets ever got
together and they took some steps to
block provocative attacks they did a
better job of just sending these
phishing
directly to spam holders isolating
browsers in creating creating say boxes
inside the browser so that the web
exploitation actually less affected etc
and so in 2007 saw huge drop-off from
France more tax starting in 2018 that
started to accelerate by the change in
targets primarily targeting large
organizations medium sized organizations
so move away from consumer businesses
and wait some more attacks are still
among the most profitable forms of
cybercrime
so for one a little-bitty thought that
we're gonna move over to those like a
crypto mining model turns out it's
really hard to make a lot of money
crypto fighting it's really easy to make
a lot of money at ransomware if you're
good at what you do and so feel because
we've gotten more palpable and because
the targets have moved from consumers
business we've also seen in the
acceleration and ransom demands
so rates and then you sneak up on new
bucks then couple thousand dollars down
tens of thousands hundreds of thousands
and just so on the other days were six
million dollars which will jump to
twelve million if they don't pay in the
next six days etc so and we've also seen
a change in the way the attacks happen
phishing is still what we think is the
primary deliberate method but we're
really seeing the growth in we're seeing
the growth in remote exploitation and
especially remote desktop protocol so
remove Desktop Protocol taking advantage
of our abilities that also taking the
damage and password reuse or just using
low-level admin accounts
Desktop Protocol but we're also seeing
exploitation of Citrix MMC VPN
exploitation etc so the attackers are
looking for the attempters are looking
for other ways in access into your
services and one of the things you have
to keep in mind is that some of these
attackers are making millions of dollars
a year
others millions dollars here they're
taking that money in they're developing
next place so you're buying X placing
them in our markets and and I use a
sermon on the dark web scary
I feel like I need to get a shot at a
time I use the term hard well but so
we're seeing them invest in that so
we're seeing sort of this expansion of
model now the basic works right like we
still see a whole lot of attacks and
start with hey you need to go over this
invoice click on it and pay us and we
install the ransomware that way but they
are investing in more sophisticated
methods as well and now we've had an
extortion to that
so we're saying sorry for those big
extortion I'm sure you've seen those
where if you refuse to pay the ransom
because over because we're not pay
ransom they say that's fine we stole
seven hundred gigs of files off your
network preview and publish those on a
website um and you don't pay us money so
you don't have to pay the ransom but not
a distortion so extortion is a big thing
I will tell you that it's been
interesting watching
the bad guys trying to figure out
extortion because the extortionist led
to bringing the courts into it so Mays
Hayes ransomware which is sort of the
most
doing that they created a big
commutative website nice news.com they
also created news maize that topic piece
that we've got taken away this they're
not very creative and they literally
trying to host the site in Ireland turns
out that's a huge TV PR violation they
got sued
obviously they didn't directly get soup
of the hosting Fryeburg option not only
did the site have to come down but the
hosting provider went out of business
because apparently that's a really bad
violation of GDP are the most private
information like that so while the
extortion is an interesting idea they're
going to be legal problems that I don't
think a lot of the rest we're out there
slog through they're currently hosting
the site in China which oddly and I'm
going to find this hard to believe has
an issue to take down border yet there
hasn't been anything in the Chinese
courts to shut that or site down so that
may be one way around it if you're
trying to figure out how to publish
information otherwise like most of the
time so maybe the paper have been
publishing that one when these
underground forums will publish the
nature there which is bad as it gets the
data out there but it doesn't quite have
the same impact because if you can't
find it this is one an onion site
somewhere it's not as you know it
doesn't have as big an impact it's not
as big a coercion to make people pay so
who they're attacking we've seen a lot
of attacks against state local
governments that was a huge story 2019
is continuing in 2020 so we you know
recorded future we identified more than
110 Republican publicly reported attacks
against state local governments in 2019
the numbers probably significantly
higher the next those just the ones that
were publicly recorded I will tell you
that in January
wary of 2019 we had recorded nine of
attacks so far in January and February
of 2024 up to 18 publicly reported
attacks against state local governments
so these attacks are not just continuing
that they're accelerating and yes I
realize the whole extra day to get those
nine mr. Jackson this year but it still
seems like they're celebrating and the
payouts from the state local governments
make the advertisement so state local
government actually less likely pay than
other entities more than like your
health care is or finances what because
it makes the news they use these in the
underground when they're selling their
exploit as a service than underground
market so they'll say hey look you know
this city people hundred thousand the
city paid a hundred thousand the city
think this and of course and then their
forums they read the news about that
other stuff so they're fully aware of
what's happening you know out in the
real world
and so they see that as well so even
though state governments are actually
less likely to pay they make a good
selling tool in Indian drug force public
here's another big one we're seeing a
big reversing like had a big
acceleration 30 or 40 past of 2018 up to
47 in 2019 a lot of these attacks are on
the reported and in fact it's
interesting so Health and Human Services
issued a issued guidance in 2016 saying
that because personally identifiable
information could be temporarily
compromised during a ransomware attacks
so even though we've been it's not
stolen
the fact that you've lost access to it
for any sort of length
time could mean that you should be
considered a compromised and that makes
it a reportable event so it's really
interesting watching some of these
attacks or the aftermath of some of
these attacks the healthcare providers
will bring in forensics companies that
go out of their way to identify that no
personally identifiable information was
actually compromised during the attack
so that way they don't have for rhetoric
the Health and Human Services it's like
a whole cottage industry that has sprung
up around done anything which is not
great I understand why nobody wants to
have to report things but it is
something even mine when you see the
number of attacks again there they're
probably severely unreported the u.s. is
not alone there were 102 publicly
recorded attacks in United Kingdom 118
in Spain 47 single Ford cetera so this
is a worldwide problem oddly not as big
a problem in Russia and that's because a
lot of ransomware actors specifically
configure their ransomware so that it
won't install if you have a Russian
English pack word you're using this
really keyboard Russian Cyrillic not
Ukraine's really great slogan under
small what you want so I'm not saying
these are Russian actors I'm just saying
they don't reveal who's bad side also if
you want to protect yourself romance
aware the number one thing you can do is
change your language pack of
and your keyboard layout to Sevilla we
need the rest of your communication and
everything difficult by pretty much
guarantee you won't get hit the
ransomware so the other thing and again
I don't recommend this as a strategy I
was in the city doing an instant
response about six months ago they had a
hundred machines that were hit with
ransomware I was right ransomware a
hundred machines that were hit the only
two that weren't were running Windows 98
that's because Windows 98 doesn't have
necessarily api's they're crooked guys
that the rents were uses so we were
running all windows 98 to be perfectly
safe again not recommending that as
strategy I'm just saying that it worked
in that particular case so Rex where's
the service those we don't know ransom
is a service or what we call brass
gently work by allowing attackers and
experienced attackers to gain access to
ransom or infrastructure so basically
what you have is you get an executable
so you give the seller money they give
you an executable and a control down you
go ahead and deploy the ransom or
however you're going to deploy it they
take care of processing the ransom
payment they take care of control panel
for the victims and as well as for
yourself and all that other good stuff
and then they take the cut off the top
usually somewhere between 10 and 30
percent of anyone the configuration that
you have set up so if your notice that
you really want to get into ransomware
it's a quick and easy way to do them so
if you run a successful spamming service
or you run a successful boss service you
like you know what I need more money I'm
going to get into ransomware I can use
one of these grants worth of services to
do it you find these and generally for
sale men around Florence and dark level
that we do see some that openly sell
this stuff on Twitter or YouTube and the
growth abroad service has helped to
accelerate ransomware attacks so 2015/16
generally there were a dozen groups that
you needed to worry about now there are
literally hundreds of groups that we
need to worry about there's still only
about it doesn't ransomware did
different rants more variants that you
actually need to worry about but there
are hundreds of groups behind those now
so you have many more people attacking
using many different methods of attack
to deliver their ransomware and so even
though it may be the same dozen that are
still problems you now have a lot of
different angles that they're going
after
so one of the first was Sten pala for 39
bucks you can buy the executable now
this is old-school back doesn't please
you know so there's a little control
panel or anything cool like that all you
got was the executable your deliberative
how we would view encrypted and absolve
email exchange for how to do it so
that's kind of one of the first ones
that we saw doing that ransom 32 is
another one worked roughly the same
model etc not very good it was not very
good and the computer was quickly
released and it wasn't updated beyond
that so your full lifetime license
didn't really mean anything but but they
were successful
probably the most successful there we go
is in track so in grab this one most
successful grasshopper Inc started in
2018 retired in 2019 and they were
retired because the FBI had a ball
seized all their infrastructure so you
know kind of like retired from targets
because you shocked that did 300 big
bells with the stuff and a score to go
out they claimed to have made 250
million from the
we're and that is just their cuts they
claimed over 2 billion overall again
that's dubious but overall based on the
number of submissions so a virus federal
etc there were a lot of attacks that use
successfully used in graft so more than
likely they did make a whole lot of
money and they went to they went from
this so this was their original had back
in January of January of 2018 this was
their original had you know they talk
about their dashboard how you can you
know what what its capabilities are etc
they went from that to an
invitation-only model so they initially
they they they were like hey anybody
come these are service as great as they
got better they realizing is better to
be much more selective and who they
invited into their into their process
and we see more of the better ransomware
tools now going with that invite-only
model as you want to be able to bet the
people that are using your service so
brain suppose the service is basically
multi-level marketing for bad guys right
they use some of the same techniques
they refer to their customers as
affiliates so one of the ways that we
track the different campaigns is every
campaign has a unique affiliate ID so we
keep track with that they they off the
highlights successful grants more
attacks in their ads even if that wasn't
the ransomware that was having to be
used in that particular attack what they
want to do is they want
associate their brand with success and
and how do you think lots of money you
rich it you use that so this is an
example of an ad their text only so
they're kind of boring but this is an
example I did the original Russian and
then translated it something that I read
here it's Russian so this is you know
what it's a but it looks like it's the
stable offline criminal Locker which
means that you don't need people to
connect and control server in order to
do the encryption they offer 24/7
support through their jabber server and
this is a big thing customer support is
really important for these Raz offerings
and actually for a lot of the rants more
actors I've been on incident response
calls where the incident response
company will sit in a jabber with
ransomware actor for five hours
troubleshooting a problem that are
really big into customer support because
they don't want to get a reputation as
oh I need the ransom and I couldn't get
my files recovered so the ones that take
it seriously do offer that sort of level
of professionalism so anyway you know
when they talk about their they talk
about their recruitment video they they
like but between our ABS core definition
stop recruiting you know we're going to
customize this to your particular needs
and we're going to provide you with a
stable income rate so that's basically
the same thing is selling Amway get a
stable income if you buy our service and
uh and use that to attack people and
then I know and I apologize this is hard
to read hopefully it'll show up better
in the video but this is ghostly Locker
and one thing they talk about is the
limited availability
so many people joined our vets where's
the service so when we part of our
downline you got to get it now because
if you wait we're gonna close this out
and we're not going to let you have
access to it so if you don't sign up now
you're gonna miss your chance right so
right it makes you want to sign up baby
so we're going to talk a little bit
about the halves and then we're going to
finish the talk by laughing at the ones
that really sucked because as a vendor
one of the things that my marketing
department never lets me do is talk
about the bad guys that will it suck at
their job because we can't scare you
into buying our stuff if we only if we
ever talked about the bad guys that
suffered their job but they're really
funny so but but there are some that you
actually need to worry about so sort of
maybe is the biggest one that's the one
that you see most often with infections
right now we're pretty sure that the
same is game craft is just this game
drives infrastructure will shut down
last week they were actually shut down
they're very selective who they on board
his clients we know they're at least 13
groups using it there may be more the
reason why there's no ad is they don't
advertise the service they go and they
seek out people that they want to bring
in they don't run ads anywhere they're
also probably the most advanced in terms
of how they're delivered so we see
fishing most of the time but we've also
seen them rely heavily on managed
service providers so what they'll do
this little compromising managed service
provider and then use that managed
service providers access to compromise
the customers that managed service
provider which please please please if
you're using managed service providers
in networks please just inept
authentication with them and segment
your network so that you can't be
corrupted by uh by their attacks we've
also seen others that use the RTE
citrus are abilities
nem team released in August to 19th 2019
initially distributed by open RDP
servers but also protects white district
botnet and a series of big big house X
they really like it out to be they
really like fake PayPal I should say so
and this is another one where we're
seeing how a gap did they are they and
we see this with a lot of the actors
down they very closely read security
blogs and security magazines and so on
like we see a lot of them rarely
communicate with the reportedly P
computer and other security public
nations so for example the first version
of MV they had an encryption tool that
was released on october 19 they then
released a new version on October 10th
so October night somebody announced hey
look we found we need encrypt their
ransom where you don't have to worry
about paying the ransom you can just be
pretty automatically so they came out
with new versions on October 10th they
then tell that in the regular forums
about how fast they respond and will
even link to those security articles hey
you saw this article here don't worry we
have this fix there's new version out
now and the color should get it out they
limit their affiliate program to 25
members so you have to somebody has to
drop out before a new person can join of
course it is the dark web so I guess you
could hire somebody to assassinate one
of the 25 members and then take their
place I don't think they particularly
care how the spot opens up just a spot
opens up so again this is what their ad
looks like let you know the locklear
self-abusive c plus less than it is 132
yeah it was to do Windows XP through
through her incursions a convenient
panel panels are very important
everybody likes the nice designer with
the control animals and they let me know
in traffic where it comes from etcetera
so you can see how successful your
campaigns are and adjust your dish you
can mean to whatever else you're using
for that phobos I counted for almost
time percent of all grants more attacks
in the second half of 2018 which is
weirder this pose doesn't get a lot of
attention in the press but you know to
me you know ten percent of attacks is a
pretty big number again initiative
distributed through open RDP that's
where a lot of raptors currently get
their start before they partner up with
phishing campaigns and Center there's a
lot of shared code base between the dark
dark light crisis ransomware we don't
know that that's because they're
associated with them where they just
straight up stole their code I know it's
hard to believe that bad guys would be
dishonest in that way but he easily
sometimes they are so anyway you know
it's one of us to join so that's your
initial cost to get in and but if your
wounds do large volume of you know
attacks if you want to do large fishing
volumes etc they will give you a
discount to gain access they'll give you
if you want to test it out will give you
a test file they will let you encrypt up
the five things that you cannot actually
test to make sure it works they are very
open and ready to discuss whatever your
needs are so that's good you know they
want to make sure that they're taking
care of you Megan cortex so many cortex
has had a couple of successful hits and
they've made the news they're not very
big overall there has been
take an activity set half of 2019 this
is what the rat looks like it's only 100
bucks to get in or 100 euros although I
don't know why every situation of a
hundred euros over a hundred dollars but
yeah they give you that option and then
it's only a 10% fee so basically they
only take 10% of any ransom then you
collect off of it we see them
distributed through peopie the boats
head loaders and then there's been some
reporting that it's been also
distributed through the risk of floaters
they are very big on the affiliate thing
they think once not only affiliates but
they want you to get more affiliates so
you basically again like multi-level
marketing right you you give it a
percentage of you bring in an affiliate
you get a percentage of whatever they
bring in this ransom so they're trying
to make your trending to this attractive
as possible for their downline so there
there are those within there the forms
were also flooded with a bunch of really
bad ransomware and I want everybody to
enjoy how bad some of these summer but
keep in mind that a lot of renter's
start off really bad and then are very
good so six months from now the ones
that were laughing at make sure not to
be wildly successful and doing really
well has some of them can be very
adaptive and make updates to their code
as quickly as possible so again one of
the challenges I'm a firm believer that
it's good when secure to companies share
information if you find a piece of
ransomware and it does bad things and
you're right about it I think that's a
good thing because it makes everyone
more secure the problem is the bad guys
read that information and they then make
improvements to the ransomware and there
isn't a good way for us to share it so
that everybody has access to it and
indeed more secure and also keep the bad
guys from reading it to make their code
better one of my favorites is
Philadelphia ransomware you can find
discussions with him cuz they've gotten
kicked out of basically every
underground form ever
there's a ransomware sucks so bad it's
only forty five dollars to sign up and
in addition to Twitter they have this
slick little video there's no sound so
you're not missing anything in there
it's just background music probably get
sued by Bri for playing it anyway so
it's but it's the most advanced and
customizable
ransomware Emma so you know they've
obviously put a lot of time and effort
into this five minute sales pitch video
which is great you get to see their
control you know what it looks like how
it works it definitely looks like it was
designed in 1996 but where you know
you'll uh you can see everything that
they in anatomists exactly so I've never
seen a successful infection of them I've
never seen anybody report being infected
by them so I think they pretty much take
their forty five bucks they use it by
beer or something you know they're not
selling a rate somewhere that's actually
going to change in to actually in
anybody so random is another one they've
got a cute little that with dust mite or
dust bowl or whatever as their mascot no
fees you just pay the upfront cost so
when they have different tiers of human
the low tier it's 95 bucks to join if
you want the height here with the 24/7
support the concierge service it's like
500 bucks to join but the good news is
you don't have to ever pay that many
fees when you do it
hundreds of that it's posted an
underground forms all over the place
whenever there's somebody say hey I need
some rats they need be reply underneath
like they're monitoring all these forms
sake hey also new p.m. about our service
and so on so we kind of tracked them the
reviews haven't been great it's a
standard incandescent and dead for a
long time too so and as memory developer
and summer I think Randy Rancic wears
the skin basically we see reviews like
that on every form in every place where
they have absolutely mostly works but
they just are very persistent as posting
everywhere they go
kryptonite's is another one
No Fee is just a front cost may be our
one little excuse being this ransomware
campaigns so I again I apologize it's
hard to see here but like CBS News about
Atlanta MSN about the attacks in Florida
actually so they may provide Lisa them
no this attacks you stipulate Vincent
because that's where wasn't around then
their structure their English structure
keeps going the allemande with that
closely it's up for like an hour or two
at a time that goes down for days I'm
and they bring it back up
they claim to have five hundred
affiliates that have signed up for their
service but again you can play there
once and we cannot buy the seal cases
successful invention
so either the the author again I don't
find this hard to believe the hawkers
lying about the fight with their
affiliates or they're all really really
bad at their job and the other really
bad because he's never had a successful
one clashing you so those are kind of
some of the bed normally I kind of end
this with things you can do to protect
yourself a brand similar but that's not
this kind of conference I think you all
know what you can do to protect yourself
and ransomware so I'll just end it with
questions we have like seven eight
minutes yeah yeah so if you have any
questions I'm happy to answer them
otherwise it's kind of like did what we
lead to maybe this isn't what the
companies reason for that makes it bad
what mistakes that so a lot of SATA Keys
need there's making bad so that you know
basically one key will decrypt all of
them but most of it is bad operational
protocol so the riot keen is one of the
best out there they didn't start off the
best but they're they're currently one
of the best and that's because they're
very they're very into dishes how they
deploy they're very careful
the targets and they sit the network for
a couple weeks Gloria and understanding
that work for you so what makes it that
makes a lot of that that is not not not
really what the what people are
monitoring the networks not knowing what
security protocols are monitoring etc so
they quit your antivirus is looking for
whether you're advanced and what
infection is looking for etcetera and so
for a lot of these the plane but so but
his underground term that means fully
unadaptable they're not the video
because they're not taking the proper
steps things like there ways with
something up in this chair but there are
ways to bypass standard antivirus action
there are even ways to bypass like
advanced and point protection they're
not doing any of that in their master so
they're easily picked off by by most
antivirus programs etc so the
combination of the software's path but
then the operators themselves are also
bad because you've been deploying a
crappy ransomware in a network where
nobody's monitoring their antivirus and
they haven't updated in six months being
good as we're not in that state pick on
Baltimore for a second Baltimore was did
by Robin Hood Robin Hood is just crap
ransomware
it just happened it so happens that it's
even Baltimore might happen to be worse
than the team behind Robin you've been
successfully deployed progress we're in
a crap net we're going to crap your
network but if you're not smart enough
to know where deployed you're not right
reason why I asked a few cases just
recently
well that's right and the superblock
guess it kind of raises some questions
that rivals every sort of proliferating
other groups they just know we've seen a
couple times where the code base is got
slow so that's probably what you saw
there again that does or that guys that
got steal from each other and so if you
take you know if you saw the problem
with writing is if you take their code
base
you can't just the point because it's a
manual code you have to like enter a
password to the point so they don't even
trust themselves stuff off you know fax
definitely not the point
so you have to before you deployed the
Red Square you have to put a passcode in
and then it gets the COI so if you take
that code base and you rewrite in to
avoid all of that nonsense you're going
to get rid of some of the things that
make it as good as they are and that
would be for that kind of sloppy second
you're talking about
listen so just like in the crypto mining
you know you saw the ships go from your
standard operating systems in July I
have a few devices it's not like that
are you guys seeing anything where the
ransomware folks were trying to move
into critical infrastructure say like a
Cisco IOS and Geno's so not those
there's definitely some ways yes stuff
that the ranch marketers are looking in
and will see this every now and then
like I said there's a big excoriated
lesson for a whole week about how Kenyan
cameras were vulnerable to dress and
more attack the day you get on camera
through the water listening crypt that
and it's not quite when you're talking
about that same kind of think the
problem of that is if you turned my
Cisco rather I'm just gonna remove it
and start up again I'm not it maven
notice that you've encrypted anything on
that because I admitted networks where
they haven't posted Cisco routers in two
years I mean just not my babies haven't
walked in in two years to do anything
and same thing you know there's always
concerned
well my home brother
we're ready to come brother so the
wrestler are you ever going to notice it
like I know you and I'm building an
update on our home brothers every time
there's a new firmware update etc most
people get their home out from their ISP
and don't ever touch it again until they
set a new highest a turn so there is B
sends them a new one so ICS but the
critical infrastructure that controls
like the water and electricity we
definitely see some interest in that we
have seen any success what we found is
we don't have definitely advanced
parameters that are trying to collect
royalties stuff and nobody need them
either nobody noticed or they rebooted
in by the background the same thing we
see every now and then WordPress like
will encrypt your WordPress website well
then must be website it reset it up I'm
not going to pay ransom there you know
for small whatever you know furries page
rightfully just because I really like
furry so that's that's a huge thing
that's why I always encourage people
it's not just enough that backups or
backups have to be disconnected from
your network so the first thing the
ransomware after does when they get on
the good ranch back there is it leave
everything in your shadow box idea if
there's all your shadow the files are
simply backups of things and recent work
one so with all that gone and then they
will look for they will look for things
on your network that look like backup
servers and they'll give those first
before they forget everything else
because they want the backup server
encrypted and access
they can encrypt it in fact one of the
things I suggested people looking from a
pot and this is a real suggestion not
one of my usual think one spam if you
are trying to go on a pot in your
network to the program for a rascal
after and you want sort of the early
warning Trinity is the accessible server
called backup one or something like that
the ransom parameters won't go for that
and that will be what they try me very
first so it actually makes it really
interesting but the good ones will
others will just you know encrypt
whatever busted in Devon and go but
they're always looking for backups that
one in critical backups may be that much
harder
the other good news is most time they
don't have to because most people don't
actually check their members to see
whether or not they actually work and so
they don't find out until after the
ransom or attack they haven't backed
anything up in three years they've just
been you know we're facing an empty team
there were three months versus hey I
think you're finished only thing
[Applause]