alright so this is a incorporating
PowerShell into your arsenal with PS
check my name is Jared hey I'm a
security engineer with a company called
Gotham digital science we're a pen
testing firm here in the US when I am
not staring at a computer I enjoy going
out into the woods and getting as far
away from technology as possible I'm the
co-owner of the most adorable dog on
face the earth his name is Eli and he
has no sense personal space and a really
adorable underbite and that is kind of
led to it is he has no concept of what
the words like no or bad mean because he
just likes he with that underbite and
it's like all right whatever you can go
back to eating bunny poop or digging
through the trash or whatever you were
doing speaking of bunny poop i also own
a really adorable bunny his name is
bruiser and he had a really bad night a
couple not a year ago a little bit over
a year ago and now his head stuck like
that he had a medical issue that has
basically led to his head being
permanently tilted so he walks around
looking really adorable and really
curious all the time so let's go ahead
and grab power show for it Herschel's
gotten a ton of attention in the last
you know couple years to to the three
years I really has picked up a lot of
attention a lot about chatter basically
PowerShell is this command line
scripting language that Microsoft came
up with it's just celebrated its 10-year
anniversary it's been around since 2006
and it's a scripting language that
microsoft created to make managing
windows easier and so what they did is
they built it on top of the net
framework which is already this very
robust api framework that developers can
leverage they built it into this and
basically as part of that it gains
access to really all the existing
windows management
in Japan players that you might already
be familiar with wmi calm stuff like
that so it's a very very powerful
language ties in with all Microsoft's
existing api's very well-thought-out
language there is a reason why it's
gotten such positive vibe lately what
makes it really cool is being a
relatively modern language microsoft was
able to kind of look at the existing
scripting languages that were out there
and figure out what worked what could be
improved upon and that led them to make
some really interesting very very good
conventions one of the things which a
lot of people hate about parishes it's
very verbose so all the commands in
PowerShell have a verb noun syntax and
while that is very verbose it also makes
it really easy to understand what you're
working with you know if you're going to
set the content of a file with the set
content content command 'let you can
kind of figure out that get content is
what's going to read the content of a
file so it makes it really easy once you
get used to those verbs kind of makes it
easy to approach PowerShell and really
quickly get up to speed and start doing
some interesting stuff with the language
the other great thing is it's being a
language that was developed whole cloth
by a single entity they were able to
implement conventions as far as
parameters go so all of the hamlets in
PowerShell use similar parameters if you
need to talk to a remote computer that
is always going to be the computer name
parameter no matter what command what
you're actually working with real
different from coming from like bash
where you know said awk creb all have
their own individual oops parameters and
stuff like that you know you have to
really do research on each individual
tool to figure out what you're trying to
do powershell is a lot more intuitive
that way the other great thing is they
have a they from the beginning put a
heavy emphasis on their health system
they have a help system that's run
through its called get help and it's
kind of the equivalent of like Linux man
pages except the get help
documentation was actually written by
like normal sane people as opposed to
like computer doctorates from like 20
years ago that were programming and like
seein assembly and developing Linux
tools from scratch github actually was
written by like normal people who
actually use these tools to administer
systems so in a real change of pace
Microsoft actually made a usable help
system which is greatly appreciated
there's tab completion throughout the
whole thing all the parameters lot of
parameter values all the commandments
everything you can just have complete
super helpful and something that's maybe
not as obvious of a benefit unless maybe
you're you have a development background
is that power shell is an
object-oriented language so instead of
in Linux when you type you know you cat
something out you pipe it to grab you're
taking a string of text and really
whenever your piping commands in Linux
you're always dealing with the string of
texts ultimately with PowerShell you're
actually dealing with objects so you can
take a service from get service and pipe
that to restart service and the restart
service automatically knows what to do
it knows how to handle a service object
so really easy to work with very
powerful really cool stuff there is some
I've gotten some pushback on calling
PowerShell an object oriented language
because I guess it doesn't fit the
minutia details of what makes an object
oriented language my background is I was
a sysadmin for 10-12 years before moving
into infosec I don't have a development
background so looking at PowerShell you
have objects and the language seems to
deal a lot with said objects so as far
as I'm concerned it's an object-oriented
language so like I said right now it's
being used for a lot of administration
if you run exchange management console
since 2008 I think the exchange
management console is basically just a
front end for PowerShell it's
PowerShell commands in the background if
you run the new active directory
administrative center which is the
replacement for a doc users and
computers same thing it's a GUI that
you're interacting with but you can
actually toggle the tab and see all the
PowerShell commands that it's running in
the background so really Microsoft is
pushing all of their management to using
PowerShell it's used for a lot of
automation so if you're familiar with
puppet or chef microsoft recently
started pushing out something called
desired state config which is kind of
their take on systems automation and
it's all powered through powershell and
it's because you have this modern
network of where language that speaks
windows works you know at scale really
well it's an excellent tool for instant
response and blue teams because you have
this you know language that makes it
really easy to query all the computers
in your environment for a specific event
log or for the file contents or a hash
of a specific file so real easy to work
with blue team's really latched onto it
I'm not a blue team ur I'm trying to
learn as much as I can but it's just not
my area of expertise if that's something
that you're into you want to learn more
about PowerShell and I are I definitely
suggest checking out invoke dir comm
that's a site run by this guy named
Jared Addison and really smart dude just
really the last time I checked his blog
he at a entry on like reading raw file
tables using PowerShell and stuff like
that and like reconstructing mb ours and
stuff like that dudes just crazy smart
so I definitely suggest checking out his
site they do taking pictures to my right
it's kind of freaking me out
alright so we're red teamers right like
that's great we can administer stuff but
how do we break things with powershell
and why do we want to use powershell to
break things why is everybody so excited
about this or scared so PowerShell is
actually really hard to block because
it's part of the dotnet framework a lot
of people a lot of CISOs a lot of you
know high tea departments they say like
oh my god PowerShell is being used to
reckon pleat havoc how do we stop
PowerShell and you really you really
can't at least it's not easy because
it's actually a dll with in.net so you
can block access to powershell dot exe
you can blog access to like the script
editor you're still not going to block
the user's ability to run PowerShell
commands as will kind of cover a little
bit later there's also just not a lot of
awareness on the sysadmin side Microsoft
despite you know pushing this for 10
years sysadmin still want to point and
click at stuff windows admins at least
want to point and click add stuff to
configure their windows boxes I know
this because I spent the last like four
years of my career as a sysadmin telling
everybody like guys you need to actually
learn how to type into a console
else you're going to be back at help
desk within the next 10 years and nobody
would listen to me and I would teach
classes and be like look this is how
cool PowerShell it is here's all the
cool stuff I'm doing here with
PowerShell and that would just kind of
lead to me writing PowerShell scripts
for everybody else in the windows I you
know systems admin department so windows
has Edmonds they really really like
Mouse's and they're just not aware of
what powershell can do they're not
looking to block it they're not they are
not aware of how can bite them in the
ass this is also led because of this
kind of environment because PowerShell
is so powerful and it's really hard to
block and there's you know lack of
awareness the info the red team the
offensive security side of the community
is really latched onto power show so a
lot of really great developers have a
kind of latch on cheap our show and
they're doing just incredible stuff
with it and what's great about the guys
are really leading this charge is
they're very mature red teamers so they
have very mature methodologies and a big
focus on being aware of data forensics
and stuff like that so there are tools
they'll make sure they run in memory and
they don't leave a trace behind and you
know stuff like that they also bring
with them a lot of them have a heavy
development background so they bring
with them very mature development
methodologies as well to the point that
I really think a lot of the PowerShell
scripts that the offensive community has
put together they're really like the
gold standard of like how anybody should
write a powershell script get help
totally works with most any offensive
powershell script out there if you guys
are familiar with invoke mimikatz that's
one of the like big powershell offensive
scripts totally has a man dog you know
associated with they get help and see
how to use the command from the way it's
actually structured like it's just a
beautifully written script and it
behaves exactly as you would expect a
powershell script to behave so just a
lot of really good solid work on the red
team PowerShell side but we've been
talking about PowerShell as a community
for years now and there is still a lot
of you know from the offensive side of
things like people they they love their
python and their responder in their
metasploit and they don't know what to
do if they got a PowerShell console you
known on the defensive side you still
have a lot of people that think that the
best way to resolve PowerShell is to try
to block it so there's just a lot of
lack of knowledge to powershell and i
think a large part of that comes from
the fact that it's still development on
windows is not cool windows is not a
platform that people look to to develop
on or use like to us red teamers windows
is a target it's not
something to be productive on like
that's what linux is for Windows is
there so we can get da and then write a
pretty report about how we totally owned
everybody and I think Microsoft has
done a lot recently that has made them a
cooler company but they have definitely
some Croft that people just don't care
about and so unless you're really
following the PowerShell community
unless you're really following like you
know the offensive like you know windows
sides of things you're not aware of even
just how cool all this stuff is that's
coming out like a lot of people are
aware of invoke mimikatz but they're not
aware of like in Bay which is basically
a version of responder that's totally
written in PowerShell it's super cool
but unless you're in the clerk in the
community or you're just not aware it's
just not cool stuff hmm the other
problem is it's it can be low
intimidating you know a lot of pen
testers I talked to like learning python
is still on their list of things to do
they haven't gotten around to it despite
the fact that you know we've been using
Python to hack ship for the past like 15
years to come at them and say like hey
now there's this new language on this
platform you don't respect that you know
you really should learn it's just not
going to click and you know where do you
start like you have this whole new
language learner ultimately you just
want to learn how to hack stuff with it
like you don't care about managing DSC
or like Active Directory or whatever
though you should but we'll get it to
that in a minute you know where do you
start so I wanted to make something that
kind of addressed all this right like
how do we make it easier for people to
get started using PowerShell offensively
so let me create the school called PS
attack and PS attack is a custom console
that allows you to run PowerShell
commands and it's it's designed to
emulate PowerShell dot exe but it
doesn't rely on parish ldx see it has a
real powerful tab completion so just
like PowerShell you know you sit down
you can tap complete commands parameters
file path stuff like that and it's a
single executable you just download it
run PS attack and you
this console ray to go what's cool about
this console is it's fully weaponized so
it contains over 100 commands that cover
the full gamut of like what you would
expect to encounter on a pen test so we
have commands from more popular
frameworks such as power tools and power
supply we have a lesser known tools as
well like inve that I talked about you
know recently or power cat or DNS cat
you know and stuff like that and then
because you end up at the same situation
of okay I got this scary blue box that
was supposed to type stuff into but what
do i type so I wrote a family called get
attack and get attacked kind of
functions as a search engine for
PowerShell attacks with NPS attack so
what you can do is type get attack
passwords and it's going to return back
a list of all the commands in PS attack
that have something to do with passwords
so in this case you can see we have you
know invoke mimikatz and get gpp
password you know so real helpful way to
kind of get you pointed in the right
direction to do whatever it is you're
trying to do and I wanted to create a
tool that wasn't just useful for the lab
so I wanted this be something that
people could actually use on engagements
so one of the things that it does is
when PS attack is built it downloads all
of the tools that it relies on so powers
Floyd and nisha and in Bay and all that
it encrypts them using AES and stores
those encrypted blobs within the actual
console within the actual binary exe and
then when you double-click that exe when
you run it it takes all those encrypted
blobs and it D crypts them straight into
memory so the actual malicious files the
raw payloads never actually touch disk
the computer is not aware that they're
there unless it's actually a scanning
ram which is real rare just doesn't
happen it also doesn't like I said it
before it doesn't rely on PowerShell
DHCS so if you have an environment where
you can't run
shot exe you were probably going to be
able to run PS attack and still be able
to run those PowerShell commands and
it's designed to work on everything from
a brand new windows seven install to the
latest versions of Windows 10 basically
anything that has power shell on it PS
attacks should be able to run and be
able to wrexham shop because it is using
the built-in net PowerShell it's
basically just a PowerShell console it
still includes access to get help so you
can figure out what command you're
trying to run with good attack and then
you can use get help to figure out how
to use that command that you found one
of the great things about it help is it
has an examples parameter so for example
if you run get help invoke mimikatz dash
examples it prints out like four
different examples of what you can do
with invoke mimic cats so let me grab
some water and we will do a little demo
of how great PS jackets
that was real fun
alright so in this case I'm sitting at a
windows 7 box as a low-level user so
maybe I found some rdp creds that you
know I was able to get into somebody's
box or physically on site came across an
unmarked machine and I drop PS attack on
there so we'll go ahead and run PS check
and the first thing I want to do is try
to see what i can do to escalate
privileges Reich's I'm a low-level user
I want to try to get around that so
let's do get attack let me just do prove
see if that works one of the things
about good attack you can see each
command has a type so I tried to group
similar types of commands so primp
didn't actually get me the command that
I wanted for this demo so let's do
escalation there we go so all sorts cool
stuff in here a lot of it is provided by
the powerup package of commands which is
basically suite for fine being typical
privilege escalation issues with windows
box so services that are over privileged
but run commands that are run exe s that
you may have write privileges to or
unattended ml files power up is going to
be able to help you find all this stuff
the command that I really enjoyed
running though is called invoke ms 1603
too and this exploits a recent windows
flaw with the secondary logon service
that basically allows us to get system
creds our system privileges on a windows
box it isn't patched for this so let's
go ahead and just run invoke ms 16 32
and that's going to pop us at a command
prompt and you can see we have system
access
man around that computer so let's go
ahead and run PS attack now as system
now that I have system rights the next
thing I'd want to do is start looking at
mimic cats right because we can use
mimic ads to start getting credentials
off the box how many people in the room
are familiar with mimic cats okay so
mimic cats is really like a Swiss Army
knife like windows credentials
awesomeness what we're going to see here
is it's commonly used to dump
credentials from memory on a windows box
and that's what most people use it for
you can actually leverage mimic cats to
do all sorts of really cool like ticket
based attacks like golden ticket and
stuff like that in this case though
we're just going to keep it simple and
we're going to look at what we can do
with nimma cats so let's run get help
you can see it gives us a synopsis some
links here gives us all these switches
that we could use with the command
description blah blah blah great stuff
let's go ahead and run whoops that's my
supposed map oops let's try that again
that was a bug in PS attack it's open
source you're welcome to figure out what
caused that and try to fix it
alright so let's do get help and vogue
Democrats examples all right so we can
dump certs we could dump creds we can
give it a list or computer names to try
to dump creds against so we can run this
over the network or we can just run
straight commands that mimic at supports
in this case we're just going to dump
creds vogue Democrats breads and
hopefully the creds that I have staged
here will work I think this bombed out
when I did it at dirty tony is very
embarrassing all right
oh cool so we have the local users creds
we are apparently running as be banner
with the password was so angry there's
also a different set of credits
thattekad here a user name called back
or upper with a password of change me
one I think that's all the creds will
have in here so let's uh so we're
running a system on in this window what
I want to do is maybe investigate that
back rubber account and see what we can
do with that account so we'll go back to
my user account because he has domain
access he can start query in the domain
so let's do a good attack will look for
a user saw privilege escalation stuff
find user field find local admin
almost there we go all right so Power
View is a selection of a PowerShell
command lights are used for a recon it's
part of its now part of PS attack but
it's developed by some of the guys out
of Barras harm joy and those guys a lot
of really great stuff what we're going
to use here is a command line called get
net user which is really just kind of a
replacement for the net users domain
command but we're going to use this to
query that backer upper account and see
what we can find out about alright so we
can see that he is a member of the
service count so you and he's a member
of the domain admins group because he's
a backup account so of course we're
gonna put them in the domain admins
group it's too hard to figure out how
not to put him in the domain admins
group so let's go ahead and start a PS
attack as our backer upper account
alright so I don't know how much longer
I'm gonna have access to this box right
like I may be sitting at some dudes cube
or maybe i think is already peak reading
is going to log in again sometime soon
whatever so i want to set up some sort
of persistence right so let's go ahead
and do get attack persist and there is
one command because that's the only
command that i have written so far there
is not a lot of persistence commands in
powershell that worked the way i would
want them to work there's they always
seem very like overly complicated and
for example scheduled tasks my stuff
didn't add support for a scheduled task
man let's in Silla powershell 30 which i
think came out with like vista and won't
necessarily be installed on windows
seven boxes and it to set up a schedule
test using the built-in command lets is
like seven different commands or
something like that it's not like i just
want to be able to say like hey at this
time run this command so what I did is I
went ahead and wrote a new schedule task
Z that way doesn't conflict with the
existing new schedule tasks so if we do
get help new scheduled task we can see
all the crazy parameters we can run here
give it a time we told to run on log on
on boot if we do the examples we can see
I provided three different examples of
just different commands that you could
run just set up a scheduled task but i'm
going to cheap here so a lot of you have
probably seen this right here or
something similar so what this does is
this is a download cradle for powershell
what it does is creates a dot net web
client tells it to download whatever is
at this you are
as a string and then this I X is Elias
for a commandment called invoke
expression so basically what we're
saying is hey go download this ps1 file
and then run it this colon then lets us
run whatever that was in that ps1 file
so in this case it's downloading a
PowerShell pile for invoke metasploit
payload which is a commandment that I
wrote that allows you to use metasploit
web delivery module and powers that's a
PowerShell script that will just go out
download whatever payload you're giving
through the web delivery module and it
will go ahead and execute it so in this
case we're running invoke metasploit
payload and pointing it to the URL of
pwnage example.com / payload then what i
did is this is another real common
PowerShell trick is PowerShell natively
supports commands that are encoded with
base64 they did this to kind of help get
around a lot of the issues you come up
with where like you're trying to use
different quotes or brackets or params
friends in like a command line prompt
and like you have to escape everything
this makes a lot easier because you can
just base64 the entire command you know
it's going to be safe no matter where
you pass it through and powershell would
decode it and run it this also makes it
a lot a real benefit for us as red
teamers because it makes it really easy
to pass these commands over shells or
you know you know just a real basic
obfuscation of the command so what I did
is I took this string right here and
this is the base64 encoded version of
this command alright so what we're going
to do is we're in run new schedule task
we're going to tell it to run a
time-based task this is going to be
called updater it's going to repeat
every 90 minutes it's going to run
powershell as the back rubber account
password changeme one and when it runs
powershell these are the arguments
that's going to present power Schultz
can say it's an honor interactive
session the window is going to be hidden
and here's the encoded command to run so
every 90 minutes it's going to
go ahead and do this going to 90 minutes
it's going to reach out to this URL
download this ps1 file and run in both
metasploit payload before I do that let
me make sure I actually have metasploit
set up
pincode brain doesn't
that's true
two
yes
i'm glad i checked this ok so python a
simple HTTP
new
I'll go ahead and let this start up
for those who haven't played around with
web delivery payload pretty
straightforward so you specify a server
host that's going to spin up a web
server and then you tell it what payload
to get back in this case we're going to
get back a reverse HTTPS and then it
just runs so whenever a box hits this
URL it's going to respond back with that
reverse HTTPS payload
alright
alright so we're going to run that
Earthwise back with some xml so by
default when we do a time-based task
using that new scheduled task command
line it's going to run that task in 30
seconds one of the things I learned from
my Derby common presentation is if
you're on battery power schedule test
doesn't give a and it's not going
to run that scheduled task at all so
yeah the the demo at dirty was a
complete fail it was great so let's go
ahead and cheat her we're going to run
this manually
on this forgot the password have changed
me one that's pathetic all right so
there's our scheduled task let's go
ahead and manually run this there we go
so we see it come across download the
IMS file and it should create a payload
metasploit show their am so web delivery
is delivering the payload and we should
get our meterpreter shell back cool so
we have a mature procession and this
scheduled task yeah that's you know if
you want to cheer and applaud that's
cool yeah the schedule test run every 90
minutes we're running as a main admin
account so pretty successful little you
know 10-minute trip to somebody's
computer all right
good
okay so i think PS attack is really cool
i think it's it's a great way for people
to get started with PowerShell I've
tried to make it so that anything you
learn use aim PS attack will hopefully
translate over to actual just regular
PowerShell prompts but there's definite
areas for improvement one of the
problems that I really wanted to address
is that all it takes is for somebody to
download that PS attack exe binary and
upload it to virustotal and now virus
you know abies across the board are
going to be start flagging on the EPS
check binary because it all uses the
same encrypted strings it doesn't matter
that they are encrypted at this point
they're part of a bio signature
somewhere the other issue is that the
tools themselves are a static so you
know there's such an active development
community in PowerShell that you know
when we download these you know
PowerShell tools we embed them in this
binary you know within a week they're
out of date because be able to push out
fixes or enhancements or you know
whatever so I wanted to come up with a
way to make it easy for people to really
build their own PS attack which is why I
created the build tool so what the build
tool does is it downloads the latest
release of PS attack from github
downloads the actual source code for it
it downloads all of the modules and
everything that PS tag depends on it
then encrypts those modules with the
unique key it goes through and then
obfuscated certain strings within the
source code of PS attack so for example
the actual phrase PS attack and then
take some of the values that AV had
started tripping on encrypts those
sources and basically it's like a CSB
that it's an encrypted CSV that PS
attack is going to open up and start
reading values from when it's compiled
and then it compiles everything for you
super easy like you don't you don't need
to know how to compile stuff this build
tool is going to go ahead and take
of that and at the end you get your own
custom made version of PS attack that
has unique foul signatures it's
completely up to date and hopefully
should ave davie for another day so to
demonstrate this this is basically how
easy it is to run the build tool whoops
that's not it for the life of me I
cannot get that video to play when I'm
actually doing a presentation okay so
all this stuff that I said here this
video goes through that except it was
also really slow cuz i was on hotel
internet when i recorded that so you're
probably better off for not seeing this
video the cool thing i want to reiterate
though is that you don't need to know
how to build software for this to work
it actually leverages a lot of stuff
that's in.net to build these software 4
u.net provides ms build exe which is the
same thing visual studio uses to compile
C sharp applications so I'm just as long
as you have net 35 and 45 on your box
you'll be able to compile PS tag using
this build tool I also want to make it
really easy for people to add their own
tools so the way it loads tools is
through a JSON file that's just in the
root of wherever the bill tool is a real
simple format you just give it a name
tell if we're to download the ps1 file
from and now whenever you run the build
tool that will get pulled in as part of
PS attack automatically so you can add
as many tools as you want you can strip
out stuff if for whatever reason you
don't want to include something real
flexible real easy to use both of these
are available on my github github.com /
jared hey they both come with pre
compiled binaries so if you don't want
to run through the whole build tool
thing you can just go to PS attack
download from the release file the
latest binary exe and run it there are
last I checked there were seven or 14
virus vendors that actually detect PS
attack
github as malicious so probably only
good for lab work but you know if you
want to just get running that's a really
easy way to do it the build tool as well
has a binary precompiled for you can
just download it run it and get your
custom made PS attack so I wanted to
tell a little story so at last year's
besides Charleston I gave my first like
public talk where it wasn't just you
know 20 friends and you know little
hacker meetups that we have at Charlotte
like this was I went through a CFP and
like people I didn't know that I might
actually have something to say and be
worthwhile so I gave a talk on an intro
to powershell and how to use it for evil
and it went really well uh the only
thing that I really felt bad about was
at the end of the talk somebody had
asked me how do you defend against you
know this stuff that you've laid out and
what I meant to say was that you know
look I work primarily an offense you
know defense and forensics hasn't really
been a focus of mine you know so you
know it's kind of something you have to
research on your own own have a lot to
contribute to that what actually came
out of my mouth is I break things I
don't fix them which as those words were
queuing up like I already knew like that
is the most immature like you know that
that's not my approach to infosec like
that's such an immature like shitty
thing to say of course like but I said
it anyway isn't God publish to youtube
but I earn that like it was a super
successful talk like you know for a
first talk I was very proud of it and it
was actually credible because a while
ago a while after the talk it got
published by like security tube or
something like that and Jeffrey's nobre
actually retweeted it and quoted me in
it if you don't know Jeffrey snowbirds
which you probably shouldn't he is the
he's a technical fellow at Microsoft
like one of eight like it's the highest
engineering position you can
at Microsoft Jeffrey's never actually
created PowerShell this is his baby and
now he runs like their entire server
like wine like it's Jeffrey snipers
awesome it's why you see things now like
Server 2016 we're like it's there's no
GUI it's just you know console he is on
record of saying like if a server has a
GUI it you're doing it wrong like it's
up so really cool dude like this
is you know the dude the creative power
shows like talking about me
that's awesome and then shortly after
this tweet this tweet came out if you're
not familiar with manifestation he's
like he's like he's been my role model
for a long time manifestation is like
really dude that late took offensive
powershell to a whole new level like
he's a genius super cool dude like
pushes out so much great stuff and he
was it was nice enough to not call me
out directly on this but like I tweeted
at him I'm like dude you know you're
absolutely right like I screwed up you
know I'm so sorry blah blah blah so we
actually ended up working it out this is
a completely unedited DM that he sent me
and I mean super cool we're actually
we're on pretty friendly terms now we
talk regularly you know things kind of
worked out in the end if you're not
familiar with harm joy or enigma those
are the guys that do Empire which is
another great parish all product and
they are really fun to troll so what I
wanted to do is make up for my b sides
Charleston talk right because it's
important that as security professionals
we're not just here to break like
we're here to actually try to make
things better so I wanted to hit the
right button and let's talk about
actually defending against powershell in
an enterprise environment so the
important thing to know about PowerShell
especially when you're defending against
it is that it's not special powershell
is a post exploitation framework like
nobody's popping zero days
powershell they're using powershell
leverage existing access to either
target other vulnerabilities in the
environment or misuse privileges that
the account already has access to so
para show is really just a programming
language it's not a scripting language
it's not you know super special it's not
it's not mimic cats you know it's just a
scripting language and so really
defending against PowerShell really
comes back to just basic security
hygiene you know talking about like
protecting your privilege tax your
privileged accounts and logging what's
actually happening within your
environment and keeping your systems
patched that really is going to mitigate
like ninety-eight percent of what you
see happening in like offensive
powershell one of the big things that I
see in environments is shared local
admin passwords so you know you have all
these you know and end points throughout
your work straight or your environment
and they're all using the same local
admin password of you know and it could
be like hyper like super leet and 20
characters long but if i can run mimic
cats and you know get that password now
i have local admin privs to every single
box in your environment and if those
local admin privs can be used to log
them remotely to other machines then
like why do I really need to main admin
anymore like I can now just run free
throughout your environment and
administer everything to my heart's
content like as an attacker I'm not out
to do schema upgrades I don't need like
you know domain admin access I just want
to be able to install and run on
your boxes so there's a couple ways you
can address this one is you should be
randomizing your local admin passwords
and Microsoft provides a great solution
for this that they just don't advertise
well enough I think and it's called laps
it is super easy to implement it works
as basically what a-what lapse does is
it installs a client on the local
workstation it extends the Active
Directory schema to
a password field to your computer
objects and then through group policy it
just communicates with that client says
hey it's time to update your password
the client sends password to that field
and Active Directory that active
directory is what's called a protectant
or that Active Directory field is what's
called a protected field so only your
domain admins have access to initially
and you can kind of dole out access as
you see fit and what's great is you can
totally log all of that it's also fully
supported by microsoft they have gone on
record saying like hey if you want to
run this and reset your local admin
passwords every single day like you can
still call us up and we'll support it so
super easy to set up definitely worth
looking into absolutely free there is no
reason this shouldn't be running in your
environment the other great thing is
that should be done is preventing local
admins from logging into other boxes
there's really no reason in an
environment that a local admin should
log into another computer remotely and
that's another real easy fix through
group policy you can just update the
denying access group policy object to
omit local administrators and prevent
that from happening so now with this
configuration if I get a local admin
password it's good for that box and
that's it and it's probably going to
change in 20 days or whatever you have
it configured for it so you greatly
reduce the risk of just you know loose
creds the other interesting thing that
I've kind of seen mentioned recently is
we regularly approach privileged access
protecting privileged access from from a
bottom-up sort of standpoint we don't
want lower user lower level users
performing administrative actions right
so it's also starting to come out that
really this idea that you should be
approaching is from the reverse side as
well you don't want your domain admins
logging into local workstations there's
no reason for that you know your your
domain admin accounts these high
privileged accounts should be used
solely for administering the domain so
many people treat domain admin account
says basically a administrator account
like I need to install software so I'm
going to use the domain admin account
it's like know the the domain admin
account is should be you know extending
schemas and cleaning up ad objects and
like that it shouldn't be used for
installing photoshop on an endpoint so
setting up your domain which is starts
to where you get into privileged access
workstations which microsoft has a lot
of great documentation on that you know
if you go to that link it kind of links
to their documentation on that but
definitely something to look into is you
know administrating boxes from a
dedicated machine a vm or something like
that and using those accounts solely for
administration using a lesser user
account for your day-to-day web browsing
and stuff like that same boat service
accounts never need to main admin access
like they should never need domain admin
access and i know it's really hard when
it comes to things like backups and
stuff like that but you know you come
across so many accounts where it's like
I need the schedule test to like copy
some files from A to B so I'm going to
run them as a domain admin so you know
that's that's completely abusing the
domain admin privileges so these real
basic concepts like it addresses most of
what PowerShell is being used for any
other thing that I definitely want to
talk about and this is just general
Windows security is logging what matters
when I was a sysadmin it was really hard
for me to find resources on okay
Microsoft has you know like
20,000 of nids how do I know which ones
actually matter Jessica pain is a
instant responder for Microsoft and she
put together a great article on login
what matters and using Windows built-in
event log forwarding almost as a cheap
free sim for your environment so
basically she covers how to log things
like your event log is being cleared
which that should raise red welcome you
know alarm bells throughout your
environment there's never a good reason
for event logs to be manually cleared
when
somebody clears event logs that logs an
event that should be instantly forwarded
to your sim to your sock you know tears
this admins whoever's monitoring the
sort of stuff you can also monitor dcs
for stuff like you know domain admins or
enterprise admins groups being changed
this is a very ok thanks a very rare
event that you know should be brought to
your attention when it happens same goes
for local groups local admins how often
is a local account created in your
enterprise you know hon a and users
workstation it should be once a quarter
maybe so definitely something you want
to be aware of if that's happening same
goes for new services not something that
happens super often when a new service
is created on an endpoint you should
probably be aware that that is happening
because that's a great sign of
compromise within your environment now
if we want to talk specifically about
PowerShell and how to secure against
PowerShell power show offers insane
amounts of logging each version para
show creates more and more logs to the
point where with powershell version 5
which is the most recent version but you
can install it on any you know windows 7
and up offers basically over the
shoulder transcription logging where you
can see every single thing that's typed
into the console and it gets logged to
an event log and you can ship that out
the other thing is if you are deploying
newer versions of PowerShell make sure
to remove PowerShell 20 when you do this
a lot of the PowerShell upgrades aren't
an in-place upgrade excuse me so
PowerShell 20 is still going to be
available if you run PS attack on a box
that has both 2 dot 0 and you know four
or five dot 0 PS attack is going to use
two dot 0 by default because none of
that login is there so you know
leverage that but as an example this is
when you run PS attack on a box as an
ant's logging this is the sort of stuff
you see you can see hey we are running
in both mimic cats right now it logs it
after all that encryption and
obfuscation none of that matters to the
event log it's log in it right when it's
right when it's about to run that script
so when you run PS attack with lot of
games totally turned up I think it
generates something like nine hundred
some odd events in the event log like it
is the noisiest like language ever so in
a properly configured environment
powershell is the absolute worst thing
an attacker can use because it is noisy
as like I would much rather go back
to visual basic or Python or something
like that where there isn't that log
game you know its power shell shouldn't
be scary that kind of leads to some of
the last reading they'll leave you guys
off with there's a goatee PFE did a
great summary of the modern state of
PowerShell security you can get to that
at that link there Sean Metcalf if
you're not familiar with him super cool
dude basically the like the voice for
securing active directory in windows
today like just a great guy he wrote a
great article on defending against
PowerShell attack tools and everybody
should just follow jessica pain on
twitter and do whatever she says because
she just treats constant gold as far as
like defending windows and working as an
incident under a lot of great stuff
coming from her alright so we talked
about PS attack that's the tool that i
wrote makes it easy to use Farish all
offensively you should totally use the
build tool it is open source so if you
guys have any suggestions feel free to
submit either issues
or if you don't have a code if you want
to submit a pro request that would be
super appreciated but really I just love
hearing any sort of feedback whatsoever
you know if you used on engagement and
it was great let me know if you tried to
run something it didn't behave the way
you expected I want to hear about that
too so you know whatever you want to
talk to me about like as long as it's
related to PS attack I'll talk to you
about it otherwise I have very small
this stuff I'm interested in so we'll
see if we hit up on that the last thing
I want to leave off on is if you are
working in defense there is no reason to
be afraid of power show any properly
configured environment PowerShell is
useless to offenders it's it's crazy
nosy I want to wrap up with if I'd
mentioned earlier about the PowerShell
click that you know if you're if you're
not following the PowerShell community
then you know you're kind of missing out
on all the cool stuff that's happening
out there this is a great starting point
for that click these guys are really
they are the people that developed all
the cool offensive stuff that went into
PS attack so definitely worth following
them and you know giving them the
attention that they deserve a lot of
great stuff coming out of that group and
that's it for me I am Jared 8 on twitter
if you want to email me j'ai hate at GDS
security com if you're in the Charlotte
area a group of us get together about
once a month for Charlotte hackers
anonymous where we talk about hacking
stuff so totally worth checking that out
and all of the links that i posted
throughout this talk are available at
that website down there Jared hate
key-based pal so yeah I think we have a
little bit of time questions or you guys
can go run and get food question
so yeah the question is how does the
PowerShell login handle base64 encoding
powershell login what it does is it's
going to log everything right before it
hits the scripting knows which is the
actual engine that runs scripting stuff
in Windows so yeah it would totally you
would see the decoded command being
wrong so yeah same goes for encryption
the only thing that can really mess with
it and from what I understand is like
obfuscation because it's still legit
PowerShell that you're running there's
nothing for it to try to like d you know
compress or whatever but you'll still
see at least what the obfuscating
command was that was wrong so any other
questions alright guys well thank you
very much I'm very calm