hi guys so today I'm going to be talking
about xxe and what it is and give you
guys some demos and stuff but first let
me just back up real quick so i didn't
know that this lighting was gonna look
like this so i couldn't pick more worse
colors so i'm gonna do could a pic
purple as i was liquor at purple or
orange um so a little bit about me i'm a
college of charleston grad and i just
graduated like six months ago i'm a
cyber operations officer in a South
Carolina National Guard I'm also in my
civilian job I'm a network security
analyst at spawar and I'm also a
technical mentor program coordinator for
node st which is a local nonprofit here
in Charleston that specializes in
technology cyber security and business
entrepreneurship so you know what I look
like I'm stand in front of you but this
is me as Claude the cougar when got his
ring like a year ago and I've like
scooted my butt across the stage that's
the Philly theater a little fun fact
about me alright so the agenda so today
we're going to cover what is XX XX e
we're going to understand what x XX e is
you have to know what xml and d tds are
and what uses it along with that we're
going to i picked a specific file format
because there's there's many that you
can choose from so one that i picked was
from open office or office open xml
format which is essentially just docx
and powerpoint ex and ex-l x SLX
spreadsheets how we can use an open off
this format file to deliver an xml
payload with that i'm going to show you
a breakdown of the docx file a demo of
will I'm gonna butcher his name but will
van the dancers a xml tool so as we as
we see this is a tool that this
gentleman made at demoed at black hat
USA on 2015 that pretty much takes a lot
of the tediousness tedious work out of
injecting these malicious malicious
entities in
these file formats and kind of stream
Liza's little bit I'm an almost going to
do a simple demo of what xxe is and show
how it can be exploited so um a full
disclosure is it's my first talk for one
and then two I am by no means an expert
at this so this is something that I've
been I came across this topic last last
year when I was a senior here and needed
to have a senior research paper kind of
and I was point in the right direction
kind of this is applies to the topic
that I was studying at the time and I
just found it pretty interesting that
it's really simple um it's pretty high
vulnerable and it's like really easy to
do and understand so with that we're
going to go into what is actually a xxe
so it's from hola so this is straight
from owasp website it's an xml external
entity attack is a type of attack again
it's an application that parses XML
input so when you're inputting a file
that is XML base the thing that's
parsing it going through it line by line
to kind of piece it together to see what
actual file is a reconstructed um that's
that's what is an attack against this
attacker is when I XML input containing
a reference to an external entity is
processed by a weekly configurate XML
processor so you can kind of think of it
like an HTML has a CSS stylesheet that
it's not you can't put it in in a HTML
code but it's an external thing that it
refers to so normally we would cross a
payload that when executed will do
various hacker things so you could do
enumeration of your internal network for
instance you can also do remote code
execution you do lateral movements and
you can do directory um traversals so
these aren't all the things they can do
but these are some possibilities it
could do um xxe is usually caused by
name properly configure an XML parser
and by improperly configured means that
the the external entity
a portion is turned on by default and a
lot of different programming languages
it is in fact turned home by default so
this parser is normally through a file
upload feature in a web site or
application the demo that I'm going to
be using today is a open source business
Facebook called EXO platform as brand
locally and it's going to show how it
can actually be exploited using that so
the next part is bug bounties alright so
this is a pretty pretty hot topic and
it's pretty easy to find and in bug
bounties so the first 10 know if you can
read it but the first one says how I
found a remote code execution flaw
affecting Facebook servers in 2013 this
guy was awarded thirty three thousand
dollars from facebook for finding this
vulnerability like swamp or mobility the
next one was how i hacked facebook with
the word document back in 2014 he was
awarded sixty five hundred dollars the
next one was how we got read access on
google's production servers was awarded
ten thousand dollars from facebook and
then very recently this year there was a
special type of xse attack on uber which
26 domains were were hacked through
responsible disclosure uber gave him
like five hundred dollars so that's like
a huge like gap difference so what is
xml so XML stands for extensible markup
language is derived from a much bigger
beefier language called a standard
generalized markup language the
international center for divining marca
to describe the structure of different
types of electronic documents its
software and hardware independent it is
also extremely lightweight so it takes
the goodness of sgml and being how
flexible it is and strips out the pieces
that don't it doesn't really need that
kind of don't need to use for your type
of type of coding or whatever you're
using and just tains the nuts and bolts
um so one key thing
to pay attention to is that XML just
holds data it requires another program
to take that data in to transfer display
it and or to store it so you'll see that
it looks exactly like HTML a little bit
but hTML is used to display data but the
emphasis is on how it looks whereas XML
is used to store data for the emphasis
is on what the data actually is inside
right so taking a look at some stuff
what uses xml so like I said before
microsoft office products so documents
PowerPoint spreadsheets and then apple
iwork products as well so the pages
keynote and numbers libre office open
office um special SVG images the vector
images there's actually an XHTML and XSL
which is the xml version of HTML and CSS
and you have html5 which is becoming the
new standard that is built directly from
a XHTML RSS and atom feeds are also
xml-based as well as soap for web
services there are many many more that
are also xml-based for these are the
ones that are most commonly used so to
understand XML there's two
classifications to it so xml files must
be there either well-formed or they're
valid if they are valid then they're
also well-formed so the the rules for
well-formed is they must have a root
element there must be a thing that this
whole xml file is on it must have a
closing tag soon start and close tags
are case sensitive and they must match
they must be properly nested and all
attribute values must be quoted but it
doesn't require a document type
definition which we're going to cover in
a couple other sides what that actually
is so essentially if you say that your
xml document is well-formed then it just
follows correct syntax put out by you
know the
standards from the people that set for
standards um then if it's valid Dennis
the rules used to determine if it is
Valis the term about a DTD that is
declared so it you could think of a DTD
is essentially it has to follow the same
syntax but then it has another set of
rules laid on top of it that it must
also follow there are thousands of D tds
out that is either proprietary or open
sores that people can use but because X
because XML is so flexible you can
actually write your own it's a little
bit more advanced but it's you know it's
pretty cool that you can actually write
your own stuff for these things I think
there was something that on that came up
when i worked at setaria came up in
conversation that there was this guy on
github that may had his coffee pot and
had all these automated things that he
essentially automated his entire life so
if he didn't come to work by you know if
he didn't badge in by 9am it
automatically shot out an email to his
boss and hey i'm stuck in traffic i'm on
the way uh-huh if he had it he also had
a coded downs like to the exact second
that he could start is script and by the
time he got up from his desk to the
coffeepot his coffee is already brewed
and ready for him to like just turn
around a wall back so XML is that is
that language that you can use for all
these different things because you're
actually writing the language itself so
that your hardware and software can read
it in all right so this is a well-formed
classification example you kind of can't
read it but it starts up at the top is
you defined xml version 1 point 0 and
then right um we're above it says will
muschamp is says note so you're I'm
establishing a note it's going to will
from the head Ball Coach nice burger
with a heading of reminder and it said
you had one job guy and that's because
carolina lost a day it did say it was
great to be a Gamecock and i had a super
cool photo Muschamp do
this but they might have to take it down
because it today is not a good day to be
a game card so this is well-formed right
so we have it we have open and closing
tags for pretty much everything we got
one full entity that is describing
exactly what it is the note we got to
from heading and the body as well as
properly nested so so this would pass
well form this would just would clear
mini parsers right and it would actually
compile as well alright so next we have
a valid classification example in
there's actually there's actually three
of these but I only put two up here and
I'll explain in a minute so the first
part on public is a has pretty much the
exact same thing the only difference is
is that it now has a doctype so a
doctype is for for the for excuse me for
a public is it contains four fields so
the first field is whether to DTD is
formally standardized meaning that was
is was it standardized by an
organization right so for for here we
have w3c um which is the world not the
robot web consortium I believe they're
not a standardized like they're not
allowed to standardize things in in this
regard however they are able to create
so that's just what that sign if it's a
negative equals yes plus equals no
second field is the name of the owner
who is responsible for maintaining the
the DTD so here w3c all right the third
field is what type of document is being
described so for here I put DTD note um
note 1.0 this is a fake DTD so I can
make it apply to this it's not like if
you try to google that you're not going
to find it but for demonstration
purposes is what it is and then the
force field is the language I mean so
it's the en
Ian you I can't even read then and then
we have the the actual URL link going
straight to to find the DTD so when when
this XML file where it was to get parsed
starts at the top and works its way to
the bottom it'll see doc type it knows
exactly where it needs to go to get it
it's got the URL and it'll go out and
grab it look at this file skin parse it
see what it's supposed to do and say ok
I now understand how to interpret the
rest of this document or the rest of
this file that was uploaded let me
continue with it so the next one is a
private it's essentially the exact same
thing the only difference is is that
it's local to that machine right so here
we have doc type um note so the it's
normally the the second part after doc
type is the tag is the first tag that is
accompanying the entire document so in
this case because we're writing it knows
is actually the name of its note um
system means that its private and then
note DTD is a location of where it's
located at so this means that it would
be in the local directory um if I wanted
to put in if I wanted to point it to a
specific file server folder website
whatever the case may be that's where it
would go alright so this is what
actually look like um so the X in the
xml code I can make it look exactly like
this um it's the Seas for upset cuz
didn't do well in there so this leads me
into the OpenOffice format um so out of
all of them this is the one that's kind
of to me it's the easiest to understand
kind of grass and kind of see so a
little background on a prior 2003
microsoft office is file format was
binary based right it was it was good
for this it was good for what it did at
the time but then as technology advances
we need something more flexible so these
types of files were designated with
the doc give XLS and the ppt right so in
2003 microsoft introduced a new new
format based on XML alongside their
binary based formats called the office
open XML file format these are the same
things except they're annotated with the
ex there as Microsoft smart and then
this new format allows Office documents
we use with any application that uses
xml hints then they open office right so
what's really cool i'll get to that in a
minute so the breakdown so a docx file
is nothing more than a dot zip file
that's all it is it's just a zip file
with a whole bunch of xml files in it
and with folders that howls those um you
can think of them as buckets that is
split splits to xml file apart um so
with that it also includes images and
includes um sounds music videos right so
it breaks it down which we will see here
shortly so what's important understand
is that the file structure itself
doesn't matter the relationship of the
individual files that is defined within
the docx that make up the docx file does
matter so I know it's pretty confusing
it was confusing to me and not writing
when I was writing it and I was trying
to think of a way that I can make that
simpler and the only way I could come up
with is actually showing you so that's
why I included it um so you can rename
and rearrange any part of an XML file so
if you have um if you're let's say you
you have a business and you have a
thousand documents and then your company
says all right we're going through a new
rebranding phase we're going to change
out our logo in the binary form you
would have to go in and open each
document and change the logo whereas XML
you can actually do like a batch portion
of it and say I want you to navigate to
this folder with this file name and I
want you to replace it with this file
and all of all the all the document
files in this folder start
I would run through and do it all for
you that's where the power of XML comes
into play because it doesn't it's it's
it breaks it down to a level that you
can pick apart the things that you don't
need so with that this is how um typical
openoffice format files are broken down
so you got document properties which is
essentially your your metadata this is
the author the date it was last modified
date of this class opened and you have
any custom defined xml so this might be
xmls xml code a specific to that file
format you got any bedded code or macros
this will show up here and you might
have word markup language spreadsheet
markup language PowerPoint markup
language cetera we'll be there any
charts so if you a lot of the you can
add a lot of smart charts or charge you
just created in my chrysanthemums you
can put those in there as well as images
video and sound files and we talked
about earlier and the comments so the
comments and the markup language so you
have like editing or Word documents you
can it'll track oh I deleted this word
and add it this word instead all right
so an OpenOffice format breakdown
there's essentially three core folders
depending on what you include into your
into your file to your in this case our
word document depends on what folders
are going to be there and how big your
file is going to be obviously the more
things you add to it longer your
document is the bigger your more XML
files and the more things you're going
to have in it so the the top one is the
relationship folder and remember the
relationship portion is the is is the
key so it's what ties everything
together right so it contains a dot rels
file that defines root relationships
within the package package being the
docx file itself it's the first place
that parses and you should look at when
parsing through file all right so I say
that because this is where most xxc code
is going to be implement
is in a relationship file because it's
not only the first thing that gets
looked at when it's being parse the next
thing is the application name folder it
contains the XML files and folders that
contain other relevant XML and media
files used within the docx and then a
dot props folder which is the meb data
right so now we're going to go into the
demo phase so we have a docx demo and
explanation about it so you guys can
kind of see it on then we have a
demonstration of this tool some funny
stories that go along with it and then
the x-bow leading xxe demo guys cannot
see them
so I'm Bruce Wayne xubuntu box today
come Batman guys well i'm a huge nerd
all right so this is just some we're
gonna open this up so this is just some
newsletter that i found on the googles
last night I literally type in
newsletter is some Google door its kind
docx and this is the first one that came
up so um they now due to state funding
on common core standards we now have
almost 200 Chromebooks it's cool anyways
I thought this was a good one because it
has multiple colors that has multiple
shapes it has many different pictures
and it's got links and all types of
goodness right so this is essentially a
docx file so it's really cool about this
docx file is that you can go in and
rename it and it's change it to that's
it and if change is now zip and then
from there you can extract it
so we'll extract it and then we now have
we now see the folders and files that
make up this docx file right so we have
the relationship file so because this
file is so important that if this file
is damaged in any way the whole document
becomes unreadable our that's the wrong
terminology the software that is parsing
it we're looking at it can't determine
can't read it we can read it if we open
these individual files but the Dom the
software itself can't read in and
possibly the hardware that's interpreted
as well so they hide it by default so
we'll just go in and show hidden files
and this plant peekaboo there it is so
we open it up um this essentially what
it looks like so xml version 1 it's got
a type of encoding then it's got the
relationships that it's going with so
it's pointing to um these schemas is
pointing to these are and this is
essentially just standard just standard
relationships and schemas saying if you
see if you see this is this is
essentially what the docx file will look
like right these are the rules that is
governing this document
to open a docx the document properties
pretty much the same thing we're seeing
the name is a template so this was made
from a template called newsletter we're
seeing that it's a total two pages at
seven or 69 words it was made for
microsoft office word at Stan paragraphs
36 lines so forth and so forth right
this is where you're going to see all
this cool little when college students
writing papers and they're like it's got
to be 5,000 words right I'm 4947 hey
what little sentence can i add in here
this is where it's pulling that
information from pretty much the same
thing so we're here we are in the core
XML files over seeing that the last time
it was modified class day was printed
which was a 2014 source stuff so but so
from there we actually have and then we
have custom xml so this is actually that
custom set was talking about and you'll
see a relationship as we continue to go
down so as you drill down into you're
going to have a relationship if it needs
to to specify how things are tied
together so this will be the application
specific right here so because we're
doing the docx file its it's going to be
word and then this is where your core
file is going to be alright so these are
your if you have in notes is where
they're going to be your headers and
footers your if you have numbering or
bullets and styles and themes and a
media right so it actually breaks your
pictures down so because you have this
file directory let's say I don't like
this paw print I want a cat print
instead and I want this photo you can
implement that right you could say get
rid of image 1 dot PNG put image 5 dot
PNG in its place and then go go forward
that way right so to document doc X
document xml
it's gonna be huge there's a lot of
stuff in it um but this is essentially
where you have your texts your your
headings your titles your your your body
you pretty much the meat of your of your
document this is where it's going to be
so essentially a breakdown of a doc docx
file right so now as you can see that
that took a lot of work to go into that
folder and then to I have to click on
the xml file and then i have to like
tight my stuff into it it's pretty
tedious so what do we do when we find
things like that he scripted right so
that's exactly what um will did and his
code is on github so at the end of my
slides I'll make sure my slides are
available again there are references
that I used for building this um his is
most definitely in there so has a lot of
good good solid information if you're
finding out you're more interested about
this topic later so I found out last
night that will actually released a
version two of his tool that the id10t
error set in at like two-thirty this
morning and I could not figure it out
why I why I couldn't get it to work
couldn't get it to work um so after any
cups of coffee and some push-ups I was
like okay cool we're going to it's on
github so does commits I can just go
back roll it back and find it that way
um but I didn't want to demo it for you
guys and kind of show you a little bit
about it so um essentially it's you can
create a file right so you say what file
type you want and in the payload type so
for for our instance we're going to do a
remote DTD public check um connect that
protocol you can do HTTP you go fer you
do mail to file ftp whatever you're
trying to exploit that you wanted to eat
it
back to UM the hostname and IP address
and/or port that you're wanting it to
connect back to write on the file to
exfiltrate so if you're doing a blind
openoffice xxe portion you're saying i
want to find this file but i don't know
where this file is that's essentially
where you would kind of put that a
little bit so the standard that what
most people do to kind of do a proof of
concept is the etsy / password file on
the linux box um the description of a
file then you can specify a specific XML
for your file format or you can if you
already have a file that you want to use
you can actually just plug it in there
and it'll inject the code in itself hit
build it downloaded straight to your box
and now you have your many of your docx
file she can use for the life of me I
cannot figure out how to get it to work
I couldn't and and it I wanted to use
this tool to demonstrate how awesome it
was so I didn't just want to copy and
paste it in there so I went back to his
first version and um because I knew that
worked so his first version is not as
pretty but it's most definitely
effective it's essentially a ruby script
so if you guys can
need is a little bit bigger
you guys seen that all right cool all
right so um download from github last
night awesome so it's Ruby um and it's a
ruby file tak be is the flag meaning
that you're going to build a file tak f
means that you're going to force these
changes into the file and then the dot
are the samples and in the sample doc um
this is where you could either upload
your own arm but Wells tool already has
like blank examples of many different
file types that they could use that you
cannot just use that instead so from
there I'm going to ask what what kind of
kind of payload do you want um so for us
we're going to be doing a remote DTD and
then payload requires a connect back IP
so I'm doing it on my local box and then
appeal it requires a remote file to
check for on your server right so excuse
me so all it's going to do is just go to
see if they could find that excuse me
that that file in it if it finds it
she's going to shoot back whatever was
in that file alright so I don't have
anything for it I was trying really hard
to do the etsy / password because i
thought i'd be pretty pretty awesome um
a little bit more time I could have
figured it out but so for here we're
just going to do payload ETD um and then
it's going to ask where do you want to
put it at right so right up here this is
a doctype that it automatically
generated for us where my mouse is
hot corners so right here I have dot
type root AG public um Oh xml x is een
and it's going to call back here and
it's going to look for this so this is
actually what it's going to put in
inject into the stock X file um from
there you can insert in all files you
can insert in all files in the same
excel file and create an entity canary
um what we're going to look for is the
actual relationships because I know for
a fact that the parser is going to find
it and it's going to go through it all
right so pick that it creates it and
we're done we now have an awesome
awesome folder our awesome docx file now
we're going to be leet haxor with
and then here is our output file all
right awesome so from here now that we
has is now that we have this file do a
little concept a little bit we're not
going to upload it so um so this is a
this is like I said before this is EXO
platform it's kind of used for like
internals an internal facebook it allows
you to share files obviously upload
files but also allows you to comment and
see photos and do all the cool project
management collaboration type stuff
right so this is one of their older
editions this is version 3.5 point 5 I
think their own 4.2 maybe 4.3 sounds
we're waiting for this as you guys
didn't day so far dt d stands for
document type declaration i believe
description here it is
there we go
yes so just so you guys can see so
essentially what i set up here I don't
explain this I'm sorry I just set up a
simple HTTP listener that saying listen
is listen for any traffic on this port
and just output whatever it is it's a
simple web server that allows me to spin
it up real quick so it's uploading we
get save and we're getting four four
messages back we're getting four or four
messages back because payload ETD
doesn't do this on the server at this
time but this is an indicator this is a
huge indicator that this um this server
is vulnerable to xxe so you know right
off the RIP that this is something that
can be exploited now the level that you
want to go into it is totally up to you
but um you can do more more things and
what's really what's really awesome
about this from from an attacker
standpoint was really awesome about this
is that there's still a lot of surface
areas that haven't been touched yet that
people haven't really messed with or
tinkered with yet so this allows um it's
kind of lols little exploration it's
also kind of kind of a good and bad
thing is the fact that many parsers are
written in like all the languages from
go to PHP to Python the job to Ruby so
they're all they're all susceptible to
this type of thing um so from a defense
side um like I said in the beginning
this this um this XX e is a I'm going to
strap it XX e is something that can be
easily defended against the easiest way
to do it is to just turn off allowing
external entities in your font and
you're uploading of your documents if
you see an external entity you don't
allow it that could be pros and cons
based on your company's or your
organization's requirements but um
that's that's a
that's a huge recommendation and it's
simple it's not only like one line like
if it's true turn it to false if it's
yes put it to no no restart so um so
that's essentially I sexy so anybody
have any questions or comments yes sir
yes on I apologize yet so the name of
the tool is XML at sexxxy and there's a
link in the references page right here
is essentially on this um on this domain
so just type in this right here and
you'll pull up the github page and it'll
have stuff on there as far as what is
actually you know what that's a that's a
very good question let me let me
actually show you what what it what it
injected
so what it see can't do it so what it
actually injected was this right here so
the doctype root tag public Oh xml so
this is our actual um malicious code
that it's going to parse so so when it
hits it it's saying um so root tag is
pretty much a catch-all so if you don't
know what it is you just save root tag
so it knows to go to exactly what it is
to to the actual root tag um maybe I
public then this right here is
essentially the 00 XML so that's saying
that we're going to we're going to
exploit using using this this this tool
essentially in it HTTP this is our
actual address this is our callback so
this is where we're going to send
whatever we find um back to and then
payload DTD is the file that we were
looking for in the very beginning so
this is where you would put the etsy /
password or if you knew if you knew for
certain that there was a particular file
um on on a on this server right um that
answer your question yes nice anybody
have any other questions yes sir
is this just like to defend against
I'm just saying
yes so from from what I've read and I'm
still doing research on this as well so
from what I've read it it seems like me
back oh when I spoke about when I spoke
earlier where you had the two
classifications if they were valid or
well-formed I said there were three
types of wealth outage you can do both
of those were external entities you can
actually write your own DTD in that
actual xml file so it's not calling out
to to anything it's actually like
referring to itself like it's already
pre-loaded right so it parses from top
to bottom so it'll see that and say okay
I now know how to read this doctype got
it boom and then just just keep it
moving all the way through from what
I've read just not allowing external
entities along the way just just turning
it off right and then from there your
development could come in and say this
was detected this is what you know this
is what we're looking for whatever your
error message should be financed your
question yeah thanks goodbye any other
questions comments yes sir
external that allowed the doc txt to
exploit fishing
containing
the entire yeah yeah and if you're and
again if your filters aren't set up
properly you know that it's zipped says
a zip file anyways it depending on I
guess the level and the depth that your
that your filters are actually doing
these these inspection of these files
you're right it could get past I dunno
there's research going on now talking
about exactly what you're talking about
JavaScript and looking at how JavaScript
parses it and how you could use
JavaScript along with embedding it into
these documents that do x XE that way
answer your question comments concern
yeah
anybody have anything else yes sir yeah
so the fine thing with adobe is that its
proprietary so it does use XML but its
proprietary so it it's not as open out
there I dunno there's stuff on it but I
haven't like really done a deep-dive
into it yeah so I've come to learn and
technology in the many years I've been
doing it there's always a way there's
always a way it's just time effort money
and energy you know you're going to find
a way to accomplish whatever it is that
you're trying to do um but no so doc I
saw are cool they're awesome but if
you're sending you're not going to send
a docx file to a client you know if it's
a final report you're going to send a
PDF or something similar so PDFs are one
of the along with Office documents are
one of the ones that you know from from
what I've seen and what I've experienced
that are the ones that are getting you
know people don't really think about
just like macros inside or a document so
yeah so that's most deadly something on
my list that I really want to learn more
about and dig into any other questions
anything else
well that's all I have so thank you