giving hand for our next week
thank you hello my name is max Harley
I'm gonna be talking about the art of
shell coding shell coding is truly a
dying art people these days sort of tend
to gravitate newer people that come to
security kind of gravitate towards web
exploits because it's much more
approachable than like running through
binaries kind of scary stuff so most
people don't really get to experience
shell coding or binary exploitation so
in this talk I'm going to try to prove
that shell coding isn't as hard as
people make it make it out to be and
it's also still extremely useful it's a
little bit about myself I really enjoy
CTF
that's actually how I got on this topic
that also means I don't do this for a
living so don't take anything I say as
fact but sort of use it to formulate
your own strategies for shell coding so
if you want to follow along you can go
to a presentation max HIO
/l code you can bring it up it has a
really good mobile support this is
actually the master presentation so if
you it'll like follow me throughout this
presentation kind of cool if you want to
do that so in this presentation we're
gonna learn how this string of totally
random looking characters becomes this
and as a security researcher we really
like this because this is this means we
have a shell we get a root shell we can
run whatever we want and that's pretty
awesome so a quick question is anyone
here a C developer or like part-time C
developer so we have one so more than I
thought there would be - and does anyone
like CTFs everyone yay so these are the
groups that this is really going to be
extremely applicable to so for
developers obviously teaching like
secure programming practices
but for CTFs if you look at all the
DEFCON qualifiers there's always at
least a little bit of shellcode that's
required in every problem so kind of a
cool thing I keep throwing this term
around but what is shell coding really
very generally and very typically
referred to shell coding as assembly
instructions that allow us to run
arbitrary code typically in like a C or
C++ program so things built in C++ are
like servers even games a lot of time or
built in C or C++ so that's really where
you're gonna be able to use this why is
shell coding relevant this is kind of a
big one because a lot of the times we
look at web exploits and we kind of
disregard binaries but dirty cow came
out recently that's that was really
topical and it actually this specific
version that I have linked here uses
shell coding to generate a root shell on
whatever device you run it on which is a
really bad so it technically it uses
this tool called MSF venom to generate
the payload but it's still shell code
and it's still cool if you look at any
of the Metasploit modules they all to
get there she'll use shell coding and
you also get like hacker style points
because shell coding is kind of crazy
kind of cool so definitely hacker points
you get those so we need to learn a
couple of things before we start
actually shell coding I'm not going to
spend too much time on this but I'm kind
of gonna overview it the first thing
very seemingly obvious but it gives a
good perspective on what we're gonna be
talking about we have a couple
definitions vulnerability and exploit
vulnerability I'm just going to define a
flaw in the system that leaves it open
to attack and an exploit an attack on a
computer system especially one that
takes advantage of a particular
vulnerability so we see exploit takes
advantage of
ability to do malicious stuff so for
people who do web app pentesting
cross-site scripting is your
vulnerability and then session hijacking
is your exploit very similarly in binary
exploitation our buffer overflow which
we'll talk about in a second is our
vulnerability and getting a shell some
sort of shell through shell coding is
our exploit so buffer overflow in ten
minutes this is a preface kind of what
you have to know beforehand I want to
try to keep it down to ten minutes
but buffer overflow is extremely
practical we see it's good for training
people good for tutorials and stuff and
it's also extremely practical so a lot
of newer developers especially once your
programming and see tend to kind of fall
into this trap of allowing buffer
overflow vulnerability to be used so
here we go first thing we need to know
assembly this is the lowest level
language that can reasonably be
programmed in so actually C is converted
into assembly so IB program c code gets
converted to assembly we have these
things called registers so these are the
things that are highlighted in red EAX
EBX there's an e CX e SP there's a ton
of different names for these and we have
a couple simple commands MOV moves data
so on the first line we move the number
five into EAX second line we move 10
into eb x the third line just like in
whatever language is your favorite the
plus operator will add two things in
this case add adds EAX and EBX and
actually stores it into a X so we get 15
so we add EAX EBX 5 plus 10 15 and then
we print
one specific register I want to talk
about is a IP e IP is our instruction
pointer this one is really necessary to
understand how the buffer overflow
vulnerability works VIP will holds
memory locations and it also tells the
program where to go next I'm going to
get into a kind of a demo to show you
help you understand this so I have this
C program it so we start off in main we
create an integer called 5 or an integer
called a set it equal to 5 we have an
integer called B 7 equal to 9 we say a
is equal to a plus B we call a function
and then we print so we print hello
world and then a new line and then 14
because a is equal to 5 plus 9 and
that's it so we'll compile this run our
program and we see we get hello world
and 14 I'm in at 14 so we're going to
use a tool called objdump what objdump
will do is take our C program and
convert it to assembly this is going to
help us understand how C kind of
converts to assembly so you don't need
to understand all of this right now but
we can see some some things that look
familiar like this emit these numbers
over here 5 and 9 actually may be easier
with some house you can see 5 and 9 over
here getting placed into areas we see
add we're adding two things we call new
function like we saw in the C program so
it calls blah blah blah FB if we scroll
up
we can see this function of blah blah
blah FB and all this does is print
something the rest of it is kind of you
know unnecessary so the first column
over here on the side these are the
locations so these are the locations of
where we are the second column is the
processor what's called op codes and
this is what your processor actually
reads these are the values that your
processor read and then this last column
just converts the op codes into sort of
a more human readable something so that
we can understand it
so next so how is data stored in
assembly so we need to think about how
we can interpret this how sort of some
sort of compiler will convert our C code
into assembly and it actually so we
start off we arrive at main so we need
to do something with main we create an
integer and then we create an another
integer and then we exit so in assembly
there's actually an internal stack
that's that's used and kind of created
and we push and pop things from the
stack to tell us where we are what kind
of values are being inserted so in this
piece of code this is how the stack
would look so we first push the main
return address at the bottom of the
stack and then we push the variable a
then we push the variable B and that's
kind of how it's built if we see if we
lay the stack out horizontally we can
see that the start we start off with the
topmost part and we kind of go on from
there over a equals four and then the
return address for me so functions on
the stack it sort of operates a little
bit differently kind of weird how
functions work so we start off we're in
main we create the return address we
first pushed the return address for for
main and then we create the integer foo
set it equal to two then we call new
function when new function is called we
push the return address on to the stack
so we know where to come back to it
which is kind of important because if we
didn't know where to come back to the
program would just kind of keep
executing and nothing good happens from
that so next we push things onto the
stack
bar and then the variable name
and then this function exits so we
return back to the return pointer return
come back and there's things that were
on the stack got pushed off because we
left this function so that's kind of how
how functions work on on the stack
that's an internal staff that assembly
uses so now that we have sort of that
prerequisite knowledge how do we
actually how do we exploit this buffer
overflow vulnerability so if we can
figure out a way to overwrite the return
address and store figure out where a IP
is going to execute from from that
return address we can actually control
the execution process so for example if
we write more characters into some sort
of buffer so actually I'll get to that
in a second
so here we have source for some program
we made we first create a function
called a new func we create a buffer and
then we use gets so gets is a function
in C that allows us to get from standard
input and then store whatever we get
into a buffer the only problem with gets
is that it allows us to put in however
many characters we want so it doesn't
have this restriction of our buffer
being only five characters long we can
put whatever we want so in this stack we
see that if we were to input hello into
a standard input
we would have a stack that looks like
this we first pushed the return address
for main that's this one zero down here
that's this one and then we go to the
new func we see
to restore the return address for new
funk and then we create a variable a
called hello or that has the value hello
five characters long it works out
perfectly the only problem is if we put
in some sort of character that is longer
than five longer than five characters we
completely overwrite that value that was
once there in this example we're
overriding zero eight zero four two B
which is the second thing in the stack
with 0 8 0 4 8 4 because we push greater
than 5 characters to this under this
buffer so that means we're actually able
to control program execution just by
writing more characters than then what's
allowed so this is really important for
C developers because they need to make
sure that no one is writing more
characters than than what your buffer
size is so I'm going to do a little demo
as I said I really enjoy CTFs and this
was a really good example of let's see
so this was a really good example I
found on one of the CT ups I did of a
make that smaller
the other works there so this is a
really good visual representation of
what we're gonna be what I'm actually
talking about we have this source right
here so you see we go to main we take
one of the arguments and we pass it into
the Volm function we create a character
array called buff that's only 16
characters long and then we use STR copy
which just copies whatever we write to
it or copies our input into that buffer
the only thing just like gets STR copy
will not check for bounds so this means
we're allowed to write however many
characters we want into this into this
function so here's what our actual stack
looks like so you have our buffer that's
a 4x4 so with 16 characters we have 8
characters right here of sort of null
space and then we have EVP which is
pushed don't really need to know about
that but then we have e IP so eventually
we are actually able to rewrite enough
characters in C won't fit into ASCII
mode so we write enough characters we
can actually start writing values into e
IP so that's definitely a problem but we
can see this really cool function over
here called give shell which actually
gives us a slash bin slash SH shell
that's telling me how to do it
so let's look at what we have so we
check out the makefile
so this is saying it's gonna copy or
it's gonna compile that overflow Tutsi
file that we're wait we just looked out
name it overflow too so we're going to
use the objdump tool that we just talked
about and find out where the location
for that gift shell function is so that
we can hopefully call it so we can see
we get a memory address over here 0 4 0
ad something quickly gonna show you that
this works really well
before
and we can see in this saved a I P this
green space up here I just have written
the 0 4 0 0 8 0 4 8 4 ad address in this
so if we run it it runs it prints this
out ads our our location and then let me
get a flag yeah see chips are fun that's
pretty cool so that's that's a really
basic buffer overflow vulnerability it
really takes advantage of overflowing
some sort of buffer to allow us to
execute wherever we want to the last
thing I'm gonna talk about is Linux
system calls these are really important
for learning how to your shell code
because a lot of the time will need to
call kernel functions or things in the
kernel to allow us to do cool stuff
so in assembly the that's the int 0x80
is just means let's call something in
the kernel so you you set up your
registers you call in 280 and then it
executes whatever system call you tell
it to so specifically we're gonna be
talking about system call one and sis
call one is the exit siskel so anytime
of program exits you actually have to
call something in the kernel to tell it
to exit the program cleanly so I'm
actually show an example of this
so we start off we this is just a way
that we can program and assembly we move
one into EAX so we are calling cysts
using system call one we move 0 into e
bx this just means that we're going to
be returning 0 and c this is a kind of a
way to say this program exited cleanly
and then we use this call int 0x80 so
exits already so we created a binary off
of that called exit and if we run exit
it exits so how cool is that we were
able to exit a program so we can
actually use this I don't know if you
guys can see that but this is just
saying it says 0 over here and that just
means that it returns 0 so we it did
exactly what we told it to we'll get a
little bit more complicated here and use
system call for system call for is right
so this system call for will tell your
Colonel - right - whatever buffer you
want it - right - so we'll start off up
here say create a a string called
message msg we allocate it we say we
want it to say hello world and then 10
which is just a new line operator we get
down into the code we use system call
for we move for into EAX just to denote
we're using system call for we move 1
into e bx that just means we were going
to write to standard output you can
specify buffers so if you want to like
write into a buffer you can do that
in ECX we put the pointer to the message
which we declared above EDX we put how
many characters we're gonna write we're
gonna write 12 characters and then we
call and ad so that's gonna execute that
next we exit the program like you would
like our previous example showed so I'll
make this and run it and we see we get
ello world and if we echo this we'd
return zero so again it did exactly what
we wanted it to and everything but
perfectly great good so now for the
actual shell coding how are we gonna
insert our code this is a good question
so calling arbitrary functions is pretty
cool but we really want to get shell
that's kind of kind of really what we
want so here what we're gonna do we're
gonna go back to our previous example so
instead of A's we have this kind of long
string of A's instead of A's what we can
do is actually insert insert the opcodes
that we saw when we did the disassembly
so if we insert opcodes here and then we
set E I P so we overflow into e IP and
set e IP to the beginning of our buffer
our program won't know the difference
between the stack or the calls that it's
trying to make and our buffer so it'll
actually start executing what we say in
our buffer so for this presentation
there are actually tools to mitigate
this where the program will know if the
stack or it'll know the difference
between the stack and our shell code
body but that
so
I can get two here we go so
so if we were to insert instead of those
ages if we were to insert that middle
column the be eight zero one zero zero
zero and then point it to the beginning
of that it'll actually execute execute
exactly
so making shellcode typically I say
typically pretty much always we'll write
our shellcode in assembly we'll use
what's a tool called NASM to compile our
assembly and then use objdump which was
the tool we talked about to disassemble
the binary that we just wrote to figure
out the op codes that we want the reason
why we don't use something like GCC or
any sort of other compiler is because
GCC does like spooky like really spooky
stuff because the code is so optimized
that typically you won't really know
what you're feeding into the buffer or
feeding into this shellcode stack its
GCC is optimized for speed and not size
so we typically really just don't want
to use that this leads us into making
good shell code which is very different
from hacking shell code so a good shell
code is kind of what makes it denotes
the or shows the difference between like
like hackers and security researchers
hackers will try to get the shell code
as small as they can sort of as a game I
mean if you've ever seen people play
code golf it's kind of the same thing
smaller is better and the reason for
this is because if we have smaller shell
code we can fit that same the same code
into a smaller buffer so if some
programmer gives us a buffer size of
like thirty first like 525 we need to
make more efficient shell code to
mitigate their to use that buffer the
next thing
shellcode cannot use two zeros next to
each other and the reason for this is
because strings in c are terminated by
this character so if we have a string
it'll kind of just shut the string off
and kind of cut it where it is it's just
kind of a rule that you have to have
because of because of C so I'm actually
going to do an example
so
this is gonna look really familiar to
you we just did this this is our old
exit shell code or our old exit assembly
we move one into EAX we move 0 into e bx
and we call anti D when we do objdump we
can see how many characters is this we
have 1 2 3 4 5 and we have 12 this is 12
characters long
so I also wrote a new one that does a
little bit of magic we start off by
exhorting EAX with itself what this will
do
if you've ever done like binary
operations XOR puts a 0 in something
that's the same so if you XOR something
with itself it's just gonna set it to 0
and then we increment EAX by 1 and I'll
show you why we do this and then write
for EBX we XOR evx with EBX so that EBX
is set to 0 and then we call it ad so
this is extremely helpful
because look at how much smaller our
shellcode is now we went from 12
characters to 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 from 12
characters to 7 characters just because
we didn't have these kind of crazy
amounts of these crazy amounts of zeros
here so we can see that the easiest way
is not always going to be the most
efficient way to do this
so now we want to insert our shellcode
so we insert a shellcode into the buffer
we point the EIP to the beginning of our
buffer we magic happens and then we get
a shell so that's pretty sweet
so I did have a demo of this but I left
my lab stuff on a USB for hours away so
that sucks
but here's a really good representation
of it so we sure we have our very this
very familiar code now we call get input
we create a character array and size 80
and then we call gets on that buffer so
we have this kind of 80 character long
place that we can throw stuff into if we
assume that 0x be 7 7 6 is the beginning
of our buffer we can insert the shell
code that we previously wrote that that
new the new exit function to the
beginning of that buffer and then we
write a ton of a's or just whatever kind
of we have we run a ton of a's and then
we overwrite a IP to set it to the
beginning of that buffer in this case B
seven six seven six and so what will
happen is it gets obviously this would
be cooler if I like could show you but
it would go to the top it would do gets
we override it and then it just exits
and exits cleanly and nothing happens
kind of pretty pretty cool
so here's a few tricks there's a lot of
tricks to shell coding again it's kind
of it's kind of an art you know you're
trying to make it as small and as a kind
of cool as you can get it so there's a
couple tricks actually for shell coding
and for kind of exploiting buffer
overflows in general that are really
really extremely helpful our first one
is the knob slid so knob is a really
cool command a really cool assembly
thing
it stands for no op it's 0 X or it's a X
90 so at X 90 and all it does is nothing
which is the beautiful thing about it
it'll all it will do is increment the IP
by one and do literally nothing so why
is this useful
the problem with with this is that when
we overwrite a IP we need to set it
exactly equal to the beginning of our
shellcode we need to set it to 0 XB 776
and if we don't set it to that exact
address
we like it'll it'll do whatever it wants
it'll just kind of flail around have no
idea what it's doing but if we put no
ops before the shellcode and then have
our shellcode at the very end then this
gives us a much larger region too to
kind of find put our stuff in too so we
start off our top sled so here we start
off instead of all these A's we replace
it with an OP slip so we can set our AIP
to anywhere between be 776 and the end
of our blank space before E I P and it
will knock not not not not not not find
our shellcode and execute it that's
extremely useful because it's a it's
really hard to figure out where the
beginning of our buffer is so this gives
us a lot of room
there's also another not really a trick
but another kind of tool we have
available to us is a msf venom msf venom
sort of in the same tools packages as
Metasploit and it'll generate shellcode
for us it's not a trick or a tool really
in assembly but it'll help you do your
research or whatever you want to
whatever you're doing it for because you
don't have to go through the process of
writing an exact ve2 like slash bin
slash sh to generate your shell well
it's a good thing to know how to do that
we do have tools that will do it for us
and it'll even do things like Knob sled
for you so you just tell it to like the
shell code that you want to generate how
big your buffer is and then if you want
an OPS light or not and it'll generate
that whole string for you so you don't
have to really do anything now the thing
yeah so it's definitely definitely good
to have so the last thing is recommended
reading so this is a very can get very
uh you can get very deep into this
there's a lot to it
so definitely reading reading and
practicing are the easiest ways to get
better at it shell coders handbook is a
super great book that sort of steps you
through the buffer overflow shows you
how to exploit it to get a shell sets
shows you how to set GUI d20 to get a
root shell which is pretty awesome
talked about other vulnerabilities other
than buffer overflow really just cool
stuff next asm tutorial if you want to
generate your own shell code learning
ASM assembly is gonna be how you do that
so if you can write it really
efficiently you'll get better shellcode
that's just how it's going to work and
then learning about binary exploitation
honestly this link isn't even about
binary exploitation it's more about CTS
find whatever all those technical
CTF time gorg CTF time is has lists of
all CTF that are coming up
honestly this is going to be the best
way to practice is by finding out
whatever CTF is coming up next and just
doing it because doing it is gonna be
how you learn you can read a lot but
doing it is gonna what this is gonna be
how you get better I would definitely
recommend checking out CTF time
recommend participating in as many as
you can because you will benefit greatly
from this so thank you for listening if
you need to contact me here are some
avenues to do that and that's it
does anyone have any questions
Chris yes I have never needed to
obfuscate shellcode okay yeah so a shell
code obfuscation of it'd be useful I
mean I guess for like yeah I mean yeah
detecting like there's there's death
there's programs that will check
like if malicious code is being run so
if you can actually obfuscate that then
you'll bypass a lot about so yeah so
that's actually a very good point if you
want to just write shellcode writing as
smallest is going to be best if you want
to write shellcode that will bypass a
fire a firewall or whatever antivirus
you're gonna want to Optus gate it
pretty much that yeah pros and cons of
different things hey what's up yeah exam
yeah yeah so if you were to yeah you
need to find some way to compile your
arm but yeah if you were trying to
exploit an arm system exact same way you
write your arm shellcode do your objdump
or whatever your tool of preferences and
then throw that shell cut up exit yeah
exactly the same way you just have to
use a different compiler especially with
art yeah yeah yeah
yeah
sänger
yeah I mean it's there's definitely some
stuff that's uh if you're gonna do the
labs on it you need to actually download
an old version of like like Red Hat or
something because there's a lot of a lot
of new like things like stack Canaries
things like aslr are newer ways of
evading like shell coding attempts
so there's definitely it dates it a bit
but the shell coding handbook does
explain a lot of like these new at the
time newer technologies like bypassing
ASL are bypassing stack Canaries so that
you actually do get it still works but
you know using all of your resources so
looking at that book is going to be good
but using like doing CTFs is going to
show you how sort of modern-day or how
we how we do it five years yeah so yeah
so my the lab that I had set up actually
I had disabled a SLR in the kernel
because you have to do some kind of more
advanced techniques to bypass a SLR but
yeah yeah yeah yeah you can bypass just
disable it if you don't want to have to
deal with it yeah hey
actually I really prefer radar - it's a
really awesome tool and it can do a lot
of it's kind of meant for meant for this
kind of stuff like binary exploitation
so I would definitely recommend radar to
recommend checking out that tool but
objdump works you know you can do some
like awk stuff to get it to actually
output the shell code you want but radar
- is definitely a good good tool to
check out for debugging
I mean it's like there's a process to
how you bypass one of each one of them
so I mean learning after you learn the
process I mean they're both as is just a
process yeah to doing that stress so
that's a lizard
it's a gangster lizard who's actually in
space yeah thank you very much