[Music]
all right welcome back everyone I'm
really excited to announce this next
talk you know it's going to be amich I'm
pronouncing that right adversarial
misinformation play books and a little
bit about the speakers so Roger Johnston
is a security analyst at Ubisoft
Montreal where he specializes in
adversary emulation and threat
intelligence enjoy nineteen you are
closely with the credibility coalition
in this InfoSec working group to develop
counters for disinformation and to
provide tooling to the a MIT community
today roger volunteers with the
cognitive security collaborative where
he builds capabilities to bootstrap off
communities provides trainings and
evangelizes the need for greater
awareness of disinformation his recent
work at cognitive security collaborative
includes the launch of an Mis PE sharing
community for influencer operations
through cognitive security collaborative
roger recently joined a CT eileen to
counter kovat 19 disinformation and
Sarah Jane SJ Turk is a data nerd with a
long history of working on the hardest
data problems she can find her
background includes designing unmanned
vehicle systems transport intelligence
and disaster data systems with an
emphasis on humans and autonomous
systems work together developing
crowd-sourced crowd-sourced excuse me
advocacy tools managing innovations
teaching data science to Colombia's
international development students
designing probabilistic Network
algorithms working as a pirate
technician and CTO of the UN's big data
team her current interests are focused
on misinformation mechanisms at counters
she founded but Dasia
light industries to focus on this worked
with the global disinformation index to
create an independent disinformation
rating system and runs a credibility
coalition working group on the
application of information security
principles to misinformation
Esther Dane holds degrees and artificial
intelligence and pattern analysis and
neural networks super excited to welcome
these folks please give them a virtual
round of applause and
yeah let's get started
okay so hello there my name is Roger and
today we're going to be talking to you
about cognitive security and it's a
rapidly growing domain that interacts
with both cyber and physical security
and it includes things like information
operations and disinformation
specifically we want to introduce the
tools techniques and resources for
threat sharing response and practical
applications there are five things we're
going to be talking about today
what disinformation is to threat
intelligence folks how to run
distributed teams for combating
disinformation the standards you'll need
to do so and the tools required to do
that so yes so over to you SJ okay so
next slide I'm gonna have to start
talking about what this thing is so
called negative security is the thing
we're trying to protect their
traditionally of being cyber security
networks wires computers and physical
security has become part of that the
idea you need to protect your physical
domains but there's also sighting of
collective security that you're
protecting not just the computer
networks and the physical domains but
also the mental domains around them now
part of that has all has been within
cyber security for a very long time it's
always been if you look for it this idea
that it's a lot easier to mess with
people's minds to get what you want than
to mess with the system's now we're
seeing it turning up in very large scale
that it's a lot easier to mess with
people's minds to get what you want for
pretty much everything so the thing that
you're seeing a lot of right now is this
information you're seeing a lot of
disinformation campaigns you're seeing
everything from things like health care
disinformation
there and misinformation through to 5g
conspiracy theories and lots lots of
different motivations for it people are
doing this for money they're doing it
for attention
they're doing it for geopolitical Ames
they're doing for political aims lots of
reasons behind but focusing back to what
what it is we're talking about so what
we're talking about is how we deal with
disinformation how we deal with
cognitive security as part of an
embedding insight a CTI team so how did
we do threat intelligence when the thing
we're trying to protect is cognitive and
one of those threats is disinformation
so lots lots of definitions very easy to
get hung up for a very long time on this
infant and disinformation definitions so
we just use one working different
definition for the moment and this this
idea of this deliberate promotion false
misleading misattributed information so
the information that you use in a
disinformation disinformation campaign
doesn't have to be false you can use
real information but you can use false
attribution you can put it in a false
context you can use fake groups to
amplify it in a fake way so we have
disinformation campaigns we are
interested in the creation propagation
consumption of those and we're
interested in large-scale disinformation
we don't care that my grandmother thinks
my favorite color isn't purple we do
care if the intent is to change beliefs
and large amount of people we do care if
the intent is to create confusion we do
care if the intent is to create harm and
we can talk about visual harms for a
very long time as well next slide so
originally we started working on amat
looking at two levels so this was a
geopolitical level
so countries have this is the dye model
are different ways of affecting each
other so diplomatic informational
military economic so these were
traditionally a country had borders you
have to kind of find a way across those
borders now every single one of these
gets influenced by information and
everywhere you have information you can
use this information to influence that
so now countries influence each other
using this information so we've got
these large-scale attacks coming country
to country next slide we also got
interested in what the business
correlation of that was so equally this
dine model for businesses so each of
these things now relies on information
each of these things can be corrupted by
this information so but now we're in a
different world Kovich has shown a lot
of cracks in information societies where
we're all at home we're all relying on
information not all of us are at home
but a large number of people are relying
on online information on what's
happening in the world and there are
unholy alliances forming between crowds
like the anti-vaxxers far right-wing
terrorists let there are people looking
to make money off the back of these that
there's all sorts of motivations going
on there are all sorts of swirls of
things going on and this looks very very
similar to the sorts of storms of
information you get across networks but
just on a human level so next slide so
what we see as people responding to this
are these layers of information so as
somebody creating a disinformation event
quite often you will see these longer
longer scale campaigns so 5g is a very
long term think
people working on anti 5g anti backs is
a very long-term thing but you'll see
inside that incidents the Stafford Act
incident just took a few days there was
a room where the staffer that was going
to get implemented people were going to
be locked at home
5g COBIT 5g causes Kovac came up
appeared went away again and we keep
seeing incident after incident people
generally run on stories so narratives
the stories we tell ourselves about who
we are what's happening in the world
around us who we're not so we have this
idea of in-group so who we belong to and
who we don't belong to and you can use
narratives to strengthen beliefs in
what's happening you can use narratives
to strengthen beliefs and who you are
you can use narratives to confuse people
and you can use that to weaken whole
populations but as a data scientist as a
responder what you tend to see are these
artifacts you don't see the campaign's
the incidents and narratives you have to
work out what those are from the
messages from the texts from the images
from the groups from the accounts from
the social media from websites and to
work your way back up this pyramid so
what we see in practice is we track
incidents we look for narratives that
tie together those incidents but we work
at on out from artifacts so there's a
correlate here again with traditional TI
but this is where we come from so next
slide as with everything else people
process technology culture every system
and this all starts with people
everything starts with people so there
are people generating this they are
using people both as endpoints but also
as carriers and there are people to
respond to this so next slide so we
built the cogset collab
came out of the Mississippi Cosette
groups from last year we spoke about
last year the concept collab is a
nonprofit that was built to bring
together all the different people who
could start building the CTI response so
to create the resources to in need
create the processes create the tools to
start defending this cognitive domain
and do this in the similar way to other
CGI and then covered 19 happened so we
have this great idea to build a American
equivalent to Lithuanian elves which are
groups that do this make this
information response volunteer
disinformation response in Eastern
Europe and we were going to spend a
whole year doing it just setting it all
up and Cove it so we found ourselves
running and supporting community
deployments around the world so next
slide and luckily some of us have been
here before so 10 years ago I was lucky
enough to be part of the crisis mapping
community so I was one of the original
leads who was setting up processes
working out how to build data responses
so that the maps and data sets that
people responding to disasters need it
got into their hands in disasters during
those disasters and it was a very very
similar problem there was data in lots
of different places there was social
media there was this information
information there were flows there were
volunteers who wanted to help there were
people who had tools and it wasn't
joined up so we have a similar thing
happening now so now we have four teams
here that were part of coab in 19
activation which is a team that's
working on information and hazardous
information feed over to us covered 19
disinformation which was set up by
myself and a fellow
former crisis mapper so he's now over at
the Atlantic Council because that was a
search team which also has a
disinformation feed collection cogset
collab providing the back-end process
and tools support and the disinformation
team inside the CTI leak we were lucky
enough to be asked to set this up so
we're going to talk about this and as we
talk about this we're not with two
humans here were two people talking but
we're talking about what a team is doing
or what he is still doing is still
building and I just want to take a
second just say how immensely proud I am
er all the people who've come in brought
their skills and brought themselves and
just stepped up and started building
this thing it's immensely impressive
okay next slide
so that's the people building there's no
point
building a pretty view of what's going
on if you can't actually act my friend
Pablo has a saying for this which I'm
completely forgotten at the moment but
it's basically something like yeah and
and then so you've got to think about
who can actually act at the other side
so you have the ice axe which are the
critical sectors to feed out to so the I
sales I sack system we've been part of
helping set up the cloud native security
I sell one of the reasons we pick the
tools that we did was because the
existing networks already used those
tools so we could feed straight in so we
have set of set of groups over to the
left we can connect over to and being
pile of CTI lets us connect into more
people who can respond so quite often
when you hear talks about this
information there's this assumption that
well you can educate people and the
platform's can take stuff off their
sites and then there's a pause there's
an awful lot more that can be done with
an awful lot more responders and we're
going to talk about that at the end of
this talk but just a sense
more people who can get involved in our
getting involved okay next slide let's
get to the process bit so this is the
text setup that we're using at the
moment and don't get hung up on what's
in it this is just basic tooling tools
that we're using again the the miss
panned the hive matching with tools that
other people are using the slacks
well everyone uses slacks oh hell we're
building slots all over the place but
this idea that we've got alerts coming
through we've got collection coming
through and we analyze in tools that
other people understand within a CTI
world so it's not a surprise to anybody
and we're going from this alert to
action and just next slide and again
this is for reading later it's this
sense of your your flowing through this
you're not just collecting just because
you can do something pretty when we
collect when we decide to start an
instant report we do it in the hope that
we can make some difference so it's like
tell people you're doing this make sure
it's actually going to do something or
has a potential do something useful
start putting it somewhere other people
can find it and make sure it goes
somewhere so this is the plan next slide
so let's look back at that collection
part so that was like alert how you
start this and then look it's how we
actually get stuff into the systems so
next slide
so we spent last year building our Emmet
and I'm sure we bought some of you to
tears talking about how we built a
disinformation version of the attack
framework so adversary misinformation
influence tactics techniques this idea
is that we needed a framework to
understand how the bad guys would
organize a disinformation incident so
it's at the innocent level so that if we
understand and we can map the activities
that they do and a techniques they use
we can then map counters to those
techniques ways to deal with those
techniques so we've got the framework
we've been building out the process
we're building out those counters
building out tools we can use so
originally we built amat as a missive
basic working group under the
credibility coalition we've now moved it
over to Mike we're taking it on which is
wonderful because then they get a mate
and attack but for the moment we're
running it under Cox at colab because
we're using it so next slide this is
what it looks like in practice we built
this by looking at every type of stage
based framework that might be useful so
we looked at the attack framework and
other info SEC frameworks we couldn't
get any of those to quite fit this
information we looked at advertising
technologies so we looked at the funnel
networks the the funnel frameworks that
were used to describe how people move
through AdTech those are really useful
for describing how people get
radicalized and there are parts of those
in in amat the fact that you have things
in fact there's there's a stage missing
off the back of this which is the
monitoring and evaluation stage that you
go through a campaign and then you check
how well it worked
just so there are pieces all the way
through this there's also a task list
behind damage that you don't see on the
front end but these are techniques so
just like attack there's tactic stages
and there are techniques within each
stage that that you see happening and
now I'm going to hand it over to Roger
because he's been quiet for way too long
okay thanks Esther so we have we have
the i'ma framework and we have some
ideas for we're talking about
disinformation in general but we need to
make that practical need to actually
apply that and people did you work with
it so this is an example probably most
people are familiar with planned emic as
a deep pond conspiracy theory video that
recently came out and make some pretty
dubious claims about the nature of Kobe
19 and it's an interesting example to
look at because it doesn't just resonate
with a normal conspiracy crowds but it
really threatened to become mainstream
for a number of reasons in part due to
the high production quality and some of
the specific techniques they used which
we'll get to
and then next slide but when we look at
this example when we look this influence
operation we want to be able to
deconstruct it specifically enumerate
the individual techniques so that we can
go and counter them in this case my
endemic relies very heavily on an appeal
to Authority it uses the attack the
technique used to fake experts so dr. JD
Mike Ovitz is and now disgrace doctor
but the message resonates because it
suspends disbelief with the viewer a
person that would perhaps otherwise not
take a message seriously thinks to
themselves well this is a doctor so
perhaps we should entertain this
thoughts
[Music]
and that's that's pretty interesting you
can then go and counter this technique
by focusing on things like her
credentials individuals involved whether
science debunks this whether there's
previous research that says this is
false but that doesn't necessarily
matter that much the damage is already
done and we see this with fake experts
in other fields such as anti vaccines
climate change or whatever and so this
technique using a using a fake experts
who push to push out a narrative is
effective because it's a human story and
the place into a narrative of a lone
researcher who is out you know trying to
defend herself against the powers that
be the political and scientifically
thought would crush this theory and and
that's you know that's not about the
science that's about that's about the
human story
so moving on each of these techniques
that we're looking at whether it's
planned emic and these appeals will take
it they got experts or the use of bonds
to amplify message we need to be able to
work with these ideas quickly and map
them out so that we can we can model
these behaviors and model them and their
progression over time and so one of the
first tools that we actually turns to
was the mitre attack matrix and the
attack navigator excuse me and we kind
of retrofitted the navigator to work
with Emmet's so now we're able to you
know just click through the UI create
layers for red and blue team planning to
model out what the attacker is doing the
strap our ideas for how to count to them
and then export this into other tools
such as miss or threatened cell reports
or however we wants to use that
mitre recently upgraded or modified the
attack matrix so that it supports sub
techniques which is really interesting
so previously you had something like
it was a very clunky kind of technique
lots of things would be contained in it
the idea we have now is to go the same
route using subject mix and be able to
refine these further so you know a
little more granular than what we're
representing here so that's in the works
okay okay so that was the techniques and
tactics how we represent those we're
also looking at how we fit things like
narratives into Miss specifically and
we've just started looking at how
narratives grow and die because now it
is also appear and disappear and
attached to different groups in
different ways so we've looked at the CM
you listen for covert 19 we're looking
at other lists from other groups we're
also seeing narratives being combined so
covert is interesting because we're
seeing Kovich narratives combining with
conspirator cost burfi narratives male
swear
so there's a whole bunch of interesting
work from storytelling to be to be
brought in here so just pretty this is
placeholder we're unless but there's
work if anyone's interested in playing
with this complain
next fun oh okay dope so I just
really no place to do this um okay so a
lot of the work we did in the last year
was really to bootstrap our set of tools
and putting everything in sticks was a
requirement miss can use sticks most
tips do use sticks and it's a standard
for the ice house and ice axe
importantly so I've added some new
objects we have new SG oohs and AHS
arose in the works to further extended
language that we can use with Emmett's
but one of the major things we recently
concentrated on was was misc I did a lot
of work to get a mitt included and work
natively in this
so that were able to able to tag event
C's in the appropriate Hema techniques
and importantly we recently set up a new
mist sharing community specifically for
disinformation and so we're working with
friends in nato canada RRM other
partners to start sharing and
collaborating on information operations
in a like a dedicated channel so yeah so
I'm in this for me worked in a set of
tags new objects that are specific to
information operations and did you for a
lobster kata me of disinformation is a
set of tags specifically for talking
about the nature of an operation and
it's like relationship to States or
political actors or whatever and this is
this is why we're doing it this is why
this is why we want to use this really
it's about showing though the story
that's happening it's not just it's not
just collecting the indicators I don't
really care to just have a set of URLs
or a set of Twitter handles or posts
what we actually want to do is represent
how those relate to each other how
they're being used so just a certain
Twitter handle cross post see a set of
blogs and how does that relates to you
know domains that are owned by some
party or whatever and as we collaborated
in the mist community hopefully we can
flesh out and begin to enrich these
models and push those out to a wider
wider distribution group okay next slide
analysis next slide so this is about
making sense of what we found so graph
analysis is gaze big in what we do so
super spreaders people who are actively
spreading out disinformation finding the
origins of rumors it seems to be
tracking to money and awful lot
finding new artifacts tracking those
movements over
so this is basically how disinformation
is spreading over time and getting a
handle on that and being able to block
it next slide
image analysis looking for similar we
haven't done much looking at chellah
fakes we haven't seen a lot of that yet
next slide and some early work on
narrative detection next slide again and
to action next slide so this is the last
section
so this is looking at what can actually
do and it breaks down to four different
plants its actions or do we already
exist as take down the botanist educate
people and then tactic level action
technique level actions and then
doctrine doctrine level actions so
doctrine based actions which i think is
actually cutting some of the most
interesting stuff to you Roger okay
so yeah so we spent last year looking at
countermeasures thinking of things that
we could do ultimately the way we
organize those into buckets are based on
JP 313 effects actions that we can
detect or deny you know disrupt agree
destroy we want to have some type of
effect on an adversary escape abilities
so we looked at those we organized them
under that model and then started to put
them into meta categories which means
can we cluster a set of disruption
activities in such a way that you know
it really belongs in its own bucket
maybe adding friction to a platform to
make it harder to use sock puppets for
example and once we have these we can
then start applying them to the
individual techniques in the Amit
framework to the individual tactics and
techniques that are in there what we're
looking at right now is a simply
accounts of our occurrence progress on
which techniques are able to it's a
counter and that's how we started but
it's not really how we finished and
that's not what we're doing anymore
Australian
Pablo and Greg had a conversation at
some points about the nature of
disinformation operation what came out
of that essentially was the idea that
influence operations have some essential
requirements you need resources it's
time media infrastructure and everything
is universally scarce or at least honest
universally scarce so with use like with
these critical elements we can apply
those to our countermeasures or think of
our countermeasures in reference of
those critical elements ask questions
about how we can disrupt those so for
example when we're looking at resource
exhaustion things like money and
audience are there ways that we can
waste an adversary's money or make an
operation so expensive that it's no
longer worth it or or in reference to
execution or time
can we is there time so that they're not
able to achieve their goals in the
required frame example of that meeting
the 2020 election know if you're trying
to meddle in the election it'll only
make sense that you do your actions
prior to people though then afterwards
it doesn't matter so if we can throw a
wrench in that or slow down that's a
specific elements that we can apply
effects to for that purpose but to do
that you kind of need to know a little
bit about who you're dealing with if you
can't just go in and speculate you
actually have to model who your
adversary is or do some research to
figure out how they're resourced what
their limitations are this was a super
interesting example one of my recent
favorites it's double deceit and the
nature of this operation it's
essentially like a dozen kids 12 or so
young young young persons sitting around
a table with smartphones posting all day
long in Indiana so it's a very low
resource operation there's one or two
managers maybe a bunch of kids very
little technology very little at
administrative oversight or or
management as as far as we're aware and
no automation no bought capabilities it
was just people dining posts into their
phone so how do you disrupt that what
looking what can we do well there are
number of ways one of the things that
came to mind that we looked at was
disrupting their ability to understand
their metrics or know whether or not
they're actually being effective if we
can engage the adversary let me bleed
though must alone there must be given
the fact that they're a lone resource
after but not or may not be able to
necessarily see the bigger picture we
might be able to push them in a
direction that's counter to their in
school so we can sort of time waste of
money keep them busy doing whatever but
ultimately you know it in for their
their failure and so we've started to
model this in our playbook or play books
which is what we have all on the screen
right now and we break this down into
individual response actions so a
particular thing we want to do deep
platforming and account and then we
bundle those up into a bigger playbook
that's a situation appropriate or actor
appropriate based on the critical
elements of the effects the critical
elements we want to attack and the
effects we want to to put on that
Parliament so that's the core idea of us
building play books and I think that's
where most of our time is going right
now I know we're short on time and I
wish I could get into this a little more
but yeah I'll hand it over to you and
I'll just say thanks so much for
listening to us today thank you
so uh back to yesterday oh no just thank
you very much oh sorry about that I was
talking while muted great with
technology um so thank you so much folks
this was amazing
it was actually I know that Mis P is a
really popular subject among our
participants and this way of working
with it and its application to you know
the world situation
to pervading so I'm just gonna attempt
to show the questions so let's go right
to it how do you account for an
irrational party or the one that is
strongly biased by beliefs over facts
this is the whole working on emotions
rather than facts think so a lot of
disinformation remember I said that she
doesn't have to be volts does actually
play with emotion
you can play in that space a lot of
really good disinformation works on
network effects so you're looking at
who's connected to a person and how you
get information through those
connections quite often the counters can
be very similar to the problem one thing
that has become very apparent with
ecovillage is that countering
disinformation isn't just about removing
the disinformation it's not just taking
out the problem it's also a twin thing
or if you have to produce better
information sources so part of the
reason this information has become so
good is that there are information
deserts there are not those strong
sources of clear good information that
everybody recognizes and goes to
especially unfortunately there are some
countries where the state would normally
do that and doesn't have that state
representation so yes sir so some of
this is but you produce or amplify
better information sources and the
platform's putting up links to better
information sources every time you look
at Kobey's you'll see the whio marker on
some of them has has been a good counter
I'm not sure if that's enough Roger yeah
so I think one thing to add to that is
that there isn't necessarily so like
what we're looking at with this
information and this information there
isn't all this a counter and that's just
something we need to bear in mind if
somebody has a deeply entrenched
irrational belief like bleach is good
for you that's gonna be really difficult
to to steer them out of and so I I don't
know if attacking that how long is
always the solution rather to try to you
know maybe steer them to other sources
or distract them with something less
that's harmful to other folks yeah well
not awesome all right so the next
question is do you attempt to do
attribution if so how successfully
sometimes we try to track back to source
I have taken back to source where there
being private individuals and not
attributed so sometimes the best thing
to do is to not give attribution
sometimes it's not helpful and you don't
want to be daxing somebody also
attribution is hard there are countries
organizations who work hard to look like
somebody else so sometimes what you're
trying to track is not necessary
attribution but motivation so why is
somebody doing this thing and why is
suddenly somebody getting excited about
MH 14 in the middle of an active acts
conversation oh the bass question is can
we stop this or slow it down it's not
who did this I think the one thing we
can look to in that in that respect
though and sju you're touching on it is
the narrative analysis you know we can
pool the narratives that we suspected
that an actor is producing and and ask
questions who does this benefit write
like does this narrative help actor X
yes or no but I won't necessarily tell
us who that person is but can at least
hinge their motives and that might be as
good as we can get it in some cases so
that make sense
all right next question then you
mentioned money is often behind the
source of a rumor can you trace your way
to an idea of what kind of interests
this money has such as government
corporation mercenary Oh in in kovetz
there's an awful lot of people who are
just selling books or selling talks a
lot of pride essentially private
individuals selling their ways and we've
seen everything up to an including
t-shirts out there there's also some big
money behind some of the the protests
and stuff but more often than not has
been small money it up a large part of
it is just like a bad revenue just
clicks right click some merchandise yeah
yeah that's kind of sad all right
another question do you know if tools
using AI in combination with Hammett to
have a situational big picture or would
there be no way for such things to be
efficient we actually as part of Cox at
Cadillac have a data science subgroup so
I played a scientist we kind of play
with AI so
the narrative stuff we skipped through
we did do some clustering analysis so we
basically scraped EU versus this info
scraped out their text and do cluster
analysis or their text looking for
narratives so yes we can and yes I think
it would be useful it's just on the
to-do list at the moment maybe someone
watching wants to get on it
one of the things all complaining
interest what are the interesting things
I saw it's not really AI it's more NLP
but lighter lighter did a project if it
was called tram for parsing CGI reports
and then like matching out the sentences
or words or whatever to the miter attack
matrix that's something I've been
eyeballing to do but it just requires a
lot of like initial parsing of those
reports manually to build your data set
but if anyone wants to help me then you
know we could make that happen so yeah I
mean I also gave a talk in AI for good
where they wish list in it in the back
of it so well there's a list there if
you want to go play awesome alright I
think we have time for one last one have
you found a way to create a common
operating picture possibly using AI
dashboard that can show real-time events
with possible events that cause them any
thoughts hmm that's not a bad thing to
aim at I mean we've got high for the K
scenes we've got miss with the
situations in there we're not too far
off just dashboard dashboarding it but
it's about making it make sense the
class yeah everyone that go sign up all
right well thanks so much this was
really a pleasure and ya have an
excellent evening everyone who's in the
audience please give a virtual round of
applause for these folks and also a
special shout out to Rogers extremely I
don't know spacecraft kind of battle
station situation
brings around salute thanks so much
thank you
[Music]