hello i'm pierre de genome vice
president stakeholder engagement Africa
working with icon the Internet
Corporation for Assigned Names and
numbers well I can is coming back to
Africa after the successful recovering
you know the bond 2013 I can from tribe
55 make history for so many reasons
number one I will see you for this year
they will be living and then mr. young
might be will be to the community number
two account 55 provides an opportunity
for finalizing all remaining issue
before the proposal for the new of a
side of the inner function is submitted
to the ntia another free morocco itself
and Marrakech we know like to miss the
beauty the pitiless of those places so
well for those reason I welcome you to
our Akash murabba enjoyed