we're here with Demi Casco one of the
new incoming vice chairs of the country
code name supporting organization or the
CC NSO Demi what looking ahead what are
some of the challenges facing the CC NSO
CCNA so is an amazing community very
diverse very with but with people that
well intended and well involve it
through the icon from the very beginning
that they're part of the foundations of
the internet us as a whole then I'm
really proud to be part of this
community and the challenge is now is to
face that the transition of iana
stewardship function we are just
approved go forward for this transition
and we are very optimistic see in New
Times with with the the new institution
the new I can and new iono function
together and responsible to the whole
community and answering to the whole
community let me ask you this one of the
things that organizations like the CC
NSO and many others with within I can
within the i kin community one of the
things they strive for is diversity
geographic and otherwise yet that's the
very thing that makes it hard to reach
consensus right yes consensus is a
difficult thing to reach because of
course you have to be some in some way
you have to have all the members
dissatisfied a little bit to get the
consensus you cannot get all satisfied
with some version we just saw this in
the voting of the of the proposal to go
ahead with the IANA transition but it's
very very regarding it's very grateful
to see at the end of the process that
all are applauding and we all accept the
results talk to me about that so does
that make it worthwhile when you finally
reach that point of consensus as you did
on the stewardship transition proposal
what's that feel like after you've gone
through so much contention it's like
going until the end of the tunnel and
seeing again the light of the other or
denature it's good to be here after
women say more than one year of off
struggle to reach this point and that's
a great feeling for yes for course
that's great Demi thank you very much