I'm sure it's touched every one of us
this probably touched no one more in a
way differently than it's touched most
of us and brought fear and terror into
his heart I'm talking about the man who
has to follow that act
so I'm sure many of you saw the news
stories when we announced a few weeks
ago that you're in Mar be willing
succeed fadi as our next president and
chief executive officer and as you might
imagine the search for fatty successor
was not an easy one the board
interviewed candidates from around the
globe but what impressed us about urine
was not only is 20 plus years of
experience in the IT and telecom world
and his valuable leadership skills but
also the fact that public service is at
the very heart and soul of his being as
the head of sweetness post and telecom
service he has demonstrated a desire to
serve the public and that is the sort of
person that we need to lead I can in
this next stage of evolution so with
that it is my honor to introduce yarn
marby and I've had the pleasure of
getting to know him and I know that you
will too