I mentioned earlier the Fadi done a lot
to transform us into an international
organization part of that work is I cans
increasing presence on this continent
and in turn Africa's increasing
involvement in I can so it's no secret
that to a very large extent Africa will
help write the next chapter of the
Internet's history and in that context
I'm proud to announce that I cans first
engagement Center in Africa will open on
the first of april in kenya in nairobi
kenya
so that's in about three weeks from now
so things are going to happen at a very
rapid pace so be a proud moment for all
of us and with that I want to turn the
microphone back to buy hair