here we go good morning everyone my name
is Casillas toyama of JP nap and today I
would like to talk about an on /
availability model of exchange point and
the JP nap case studies unfortunately Oh
on the web pages and the title is only
an described availability model so maybe
it is very hard for you to imagine what
kind of talk I would like to do but then
today I like to talk about availability
of exchange point okay and first oh I
like to briefly introduce the JP of what
the JP nap is okay the JP nap is the
largest one of the largest exchange
point in Japan and which is provided
since 2001 now currently a three
exchange point in Japan we have the 180
that JP nap tokyo one and JP nap Tokyo
to and draping up osaka and these three
exchange point are not interconnected
between them among them and so I meant
that and they're independent systems and
the tokyo and osaka are approximately a
400 miles away so the if there isn't a
big earthquake in the Tokyo area oh the
providers can back up the traffic to the
Osaka area okay and also we built on one
more site in Tokyo the Tokyo to the
token one and two tokyo to on 10 miles
away alberton Oh as you know the traffic
in internet traffic in Japan is
concentrated in the Tokyo area so oh we
have to hedge the risk oh such a or the
terror or power failure so we built
another site yeah Oh in the Tokyo areas
at Tokyo to ok and the JP nap carries a
lot of traffic our own the current ria
at a peak 140 s 46 gig and this is the
whole
oh the fourth-largest all over the world
the top three is an o the Amazigh x and
day kicks and links those are the three
big guys and the next isn't JP now okay
so let's go on to the availability model
our exchange point so the white
availability 0 because in these days old
as you know the Internet becomes our
infrastructure of that over our society
so oh these days the people and AS
application service provider or content
provider or requires a very high level
availability stability and or or
reliability so availability is important
for also an exchange point okay so first
I would like to propose the very simple
but the strict moral of the availability
about an exchange point oh this
configuration and obstruct configuration
is the typical or one because out so all
there is an exchange point network which
consists of multiple is red switches or
some kind of switches and linked
together so this is Mason all the
switching cloud and ice fees connect
their routers to this switching cloud so
this one this connection is in exchange
point switches and the routers
connection okay so there is a
demarcation point of it when them sweet
exchange point network and a bit and oh
I Swiss routers so between here between
this it's responsible for our exchange
point so from this perspective I would
like to define the simple availability
model
so the definition is the exceeded point
is available if no packet loss and no
link failure in the switching crowd and
old port for the customers are after run
oh I like to define this the normal case
isn't available okay so let's imagine
how not available cases and that one
typical one isn't oh the packet loss or
link down and a switching cloud of
course I'll exchange point should be
regarded as a big pie for all the
customers with enough capacity when that
wave so in this crowd oh we have to the
exchange point provider have to maintain
no packet loss and no link video such
kind of state is very important so okay
so if there isn't some pocket will also
link down and here so this network
defined as not available okay and or
sometimes the 0 is fees Oh push their
traffic into a fitting cloud but then
sometimes they are put too many packets
to this line and this one else isn't
responsible for a provider site so this
one is not not nuttin defined as an
unavailable okay only at this side
and the second part isn't one port it's
down for a customer this case is defined
as an unavailable if the in case that
then the port for is PB is down that is
not affected to a pier with others
button the potentially is Phoebe will
have a bcp collection or in the future
or some kind of things so only a one pot
is down is also not unavailable so the
exchange point provided I should
maintain all the port is up and running
so okay so this is a very I think that
the streak simple but a strict model so
extreme point provided I should maintain
exchange point network itself facing oh
no packet loss or no link failure and
also all the ports up and running in the
next I would like to talk about in deep
enough technology to improve
availability and the first step is using
the network itself either are redundant
okay so not only the switching network
but we add the redundant network and
also we provide the main port and backup
or to our customers all the customers
and inside an network we are using some
kind of redundant particles to to to
maintain that this network is available
and the next technology is an optical
switch for customer port
this optical switch ow chain changes
from main port to back up off
instantaneously instantaneously means
and I'll tens of milliseconds this
optical switch always watching the light
from the eff switch to to the customer n
and if the light is going down the
optical switch soon change the port to
the backup side and it is done in a tens
of milliseconds and this means oh the
most routers do not sense link down and
therefore oh that busy positions are not
down this feature is very important for
the providers I think because if the
link down is sensed and bgp session is
down the road to check out the router
start to recalculate the best route best
path and best route again and if after
that the recover that this one yet the
routers Oh again or recovers to that
this pass is the best so if the busy
position not down so if the visa
physicians not down such an hour
recalculation of the route it's with not
occur so the providers are used this
exchange point network is so very stable
it okay and we also use this optical
switch when we are doing the maintenance
work so when we would like to maintain
me maintenance work on the switch we can
easily backup change we can easily
change to the backup port and the switch
we can easily maintain the switch during
the oh the traffic is backing now after
the maintenance will recover to that
main how ok so i would like to use and
the JP naps real data and this
technology is how effective this
technology is ok oh this list isn't all
our troubles and maintenance works at
the Jaypee neff tokyo one from a june
two thousand seven to make 2008 so Oh
exactly one year so there are 0 18
events during this year and the group
and the green one shows that the
maintenance work and yellow one chosen a
switch trouble switch or switch network
trouble and red one at a human error we
made us some times and made 0 over this
operation yeah so this during this year
we have 18 events of our troubles and
maintenance and miss operations ok so
next I would like to use this data and
how effective that those in technology
is to improve the availability so and
the first focusing on the maintenance
work Oh usually all the maintenance work
is done of 20 for this time period ok
and if we had if we did not have a
redundant network
oh I excerpts would not be available
during the maintenance window so yeah
assuming this and we I calculated the
total hour of the maintenance work was
26 hours and 34 minutes so if we if we
did not have a redundant network this
time are equal to the downtown but then
we have a redundant network so Rihanna
network and our main and backup port or
for all the customers so when we do a
maintenance how the customers connection
to a main support to remove and insert
the back up sweetie it may take an 15
seconds Oh at-at least so first I'll
main to back up and after the midday ass
back up to Maine it will take an hour 30
second I like I estimated it would be a
30 second so during these maintenance
work the impact is approximately a
there's a 10 customer and this time in
the 20 customers so for each customers
are 30 seconds so we have two other
network would be unavailable during the
five minutes and this scale up in this
case 10 minutes okay so well if we if
the switching network was redundant
button there is no optical switches the
down time would be 62 minutes and 30
seconds button as I told we had an
redundant network also a cocktail switch
40 for customers I'm in the for isps
so the down time the optical switches
all changes the main port to back up or
in a tenth of milk second so for this
time approximately mmm at most one
second isn't downtime and that this one
is approximately at to second so
equivalent summarizes some of these
times approximately 15 seconds is the
real down time so how much that
availability differs focusing on this
maintenance work oh the downtime the
first case oh if we had not the
redundant network nor optical network
the downtime is 26 hours approximately
and 0 downtime the ratio is in 0.30
percent from the availability side 99.7
percent but if we had a redundant
network at the time in the case the 16
minutes is it would be the downtime but
uh oh the current leader JP nap using
the redundant network also an optical
switches so the down time is
approximately 30 15 second per year so
the downtime is a 0.0000 47 and
availability would be this one so this
their shows that the redundant network
and the optical switches are very
effective to increase the availability
and as I told the optical switches are
always watching that our light from the
sweet ethernet switches okay so next I
like to focusing on the human error this
case we mistakenly put the power off of
the transmission device between here and
unfortunately the optical switches
detect the failure and instantaneously
will change to the back up porn so the
this trouble does not affect our
customers o Network but then if we take
the best scenario Oh probably it was
about in 30 seconds to notice the
mistake and recover it oh I just in this
case the operator is just in front of
that oh the transmission device so they
soon noticed oh that they're the failure
the mistake so it may recover
approximately 30 seconds but then
actually stolen as I told the optical
switch change to the backup port so
there be an approximately one second
much more less than tens of milliseconds
is affected to the customers so the
total Oh availability of the Tokyo Japan
app tokyo one during this year wasn't
approximately a ninety-nine point nine
seven six percent and downtime is was in
two hour and a seven minute and this
seems to be are too long yeah and and
this is according to the definition of
the of my availability model l which is
very simple but the street
and this case and this case is and it
took a long time because this failure is
and how it was very difficult to
determine that no customer site is wrong
or the JP napped our site is wrong and
also we have we had to negotiate with
our customers to repair our to take some
steps to recover that failure so that
isn't a problem to be solved next time
but then please take a look at these no
impact impacts egg from the impact site
the backbone network of the 0 power
switches the failure is an approximately
64 second per year so almost all the our
customers can be you can be used our
network all the time and it would the
availability is worse than ninety-nine
point ninety nine nine nine nine eight
percent so quite longer I think so to
summarize I presented a very strict but
very simple but to strict a variability
model exchange point and using the model
i calculated FJP nap availability and
aware availability can be a cigarette
country improved by redundant switch
network and optical switches thank you
very much