yes
so
let me introduce myself so i'm currently
working in cyber warfare lab as a red
team security researcher
and i have
sorry
and i have three years of three plus
years of experience in reverse
engineering and mostly i'm interested in
reversing the internals and
malwares
and
right now
i'm currently focusing the
windows internal sandal
so
[Music]
so i hope you guys all have uh
downloaded all the prerequisite that
that that we have mentioned here
yeah okay
so
so uh let me just begin with the
so let's just begin the
session now
so i'm gonna go quick on this p file
format because we have a lot to cover
here you can see we are covering seven
injection technique
now which is which which is lot more to
cover in the in a day so
i'm just going to go quick in the
p
file format
so pp file format is particularly
particularly a file format for the
executable dlls of the code in the
windows operating system
so there are few importance header on
the pe file format
which are the setter and the header and
inside the anti-header there are file
header and optional header
and the last header is the section
header
let me just turn on the laser now
so you can see these are the uh
these are the headers that we that i
just talked about
so those header is the first header of
the pe file format and this is the 64
byte long structure and you can see
there are lots of member here but we are
only interested in e-magic and then
alpha new
the e-magic is the first members and it
hold the signature of the dos file which
is the mz uh we all know that it's the
mz
so uh the another another member is the
alpha nu uh which hold the offset to the
start of the anti-header so let's say
whenever we are parsing the p header uh
in our code
so
if we parse the dos header
and if we add the alpha nu offset to
that dos header we will use to the
anti-heaters that's why the alpha new
header is important to us
so this is the
sorry this is the dos header and all the
members are here
which is which is in the pe view
so the
another header is the anti-header this
is the primary structure for the p
header and it is of type image
anti-headers
so this consists of three members which
are signature file header and optional
header
so signature is a four byte d word and
it holds the value p followed by the two
terminating zero you can see there is a
p and followed by two terminating zero
here
so the next header is the file header uh
file header is a 20 byte long structure
and this header contains basic
information of the pe file
and the one that is important for us is
the number of section for our project
but uh the few other uh informations are
here which are mis these are the machine
architecture
and the time date stamp pointed to the
symbol table table number of symbols
size of optional header and
characteristics
so
let's come to the optional header uh
this is the most crucial this uh the
most visual fields are contained in this
optional header
even though the name of this header is
the optional
so some of the important fields are
image base address of the entry point
subsystem section alignment file
alignment size of the code and the image
data directory so data directory is an
array of the image data directory
structure this is structure holes two
members which are virtual address and
the size
so this is the structure of the optional
header you can see
so the virtual address now points to the
relative version address of the
particular directory and the size holds
the size of that particular directory
so in the data directory array there are
east elements point to some of some
important information such as import
address table export address table
resource table
so here are the list of the directories
so the last header is the section header
which contains the important information
related to the related to the sections
such as name of sections virtual address
virtual size and size of the raw data
pointed to the raw data etc
so these are the common these are the
common section
of the executables
uh text section and the r data section
data section research section and the
relocation section
so now we
we wish the first
injection technique of this video
session
so
let's just get started with this
injection technique so this is the apc
code injection technique
so apc stands for the asynchronous
procedure call
this is a really nice feature of the
windows operating system
that allows us to place a job in a queue
for execution uh
in context of the particular threat so
basically uh in this technique we are
placing our cell code in a pcq
of the process trade and whenever this
process threat enters into the all the
table state our cell code will get
executed
the sum of the routing that might put
the thread in all the table states are
slip ex single object and weight wait
for single lock ctx i'll wait for
multiple object ex and there are few
others
so these are the steps for the apc
injection first we need to find the
target process to inject our pill boot
and after that we need to perform the
relocation sorry we need to perform the
remote allocation
after that we will write our payload
into that newly allocated memory in the
in the target process
so after writing the payload we have to
find all the trades which is present in
that target process
once we find all the threads we will
place our sell code in the queue for all
the threads and whenever the threads
enter into the outlet table state our
cell code will get executed
so this is to note that this uh this
technique is quite unstable so there is
a
there is a different variant of this apc
injection which is also known as the
early bird apc injection
which we will be going to cover in the
lab session so
so these are all the api calls that are
used in this apc injection
so let's move to the lab
okay
so
is my vm visible
yes
okay
okay so
here in the server here in the line
number 300 at
uh i have commented this out so let's
just uncomment this line
and i will comment this line number 236
so uh this is the just the
this is just the variable which will
allows us to switch between early bird
and the normal abc injection
so
i hope you guys have
uh have all the vm ready
to
to go way to go to go with me
so before uh executing this application
i will just
put the breakpoint
so the breakpoint i have already put the
breakpoint here at line number 117
so i'll just execute this
application
so uh the target process for our for our
uh implant is the notepad.exe so
i will just open this 32-bit notepad
which is which is in the cs4 directory
so this is our victim process
yeah so we have the victim process open
so let me just go into this
uh find target process function
so uh here we can see uh using the
of using the api called great tool help
32 snapshot we are taking the snapshot
of the process as well as the snapshot
of the thread
so let me just step over this code
and with the help of this process 32
first we are retrieving the first
process from the snapshot
and after that we are comparing whether
the
whether the
process from the snapshot is equal to
our target process so our target process
is notepad and
and currently it's pointing to the
system process
so once this
is equal to the
process our target process it will enter
this if block
so if it is not equal to our target
process it will just simply
go and call the process 32 next function
which will retrieve the next
process from the snapshot
so this process goes until uh it is
equal to our notepad so i'm just gonna
put the breakpoint at line number 27
and i will continue the execution
so now you can see we are
inside the if block
so we are doing the same thing for the
thread as well
so
we are just getting the first thread and
here
uh
here there is a if lock you can see
so we are checking whether the
the whether the threats owner is whether
the trade owner id is equal to our
target process id so if the trade owner
id is equal to our target process id uh
we will push that trade id into the
uh into into the vector or we or we can
just
add this thread id into the
arrays also
so here basically we are just collecting
all the threads that are uh that are
inside the notepad so let me just go
here and show you so there is only one
thread currently so it will just
uh get that thread for us
so our three donor is for like um
because we want to
get all the threads of the
notepad right this is our target process
so this is checking the trade owner is
checking that whether this
the process id of the trade owner is
equal to our process id which is
one two two zero zero
so
no no not code thread but uh yeah it's
it's the like we have the process you
can see it see it's the notepad.exe
right so the
process id is one two two zero zero and
let's see uh here we are checking
let's say
we have got this straight from the
snapshot
so this is checking that whether this uh
whether this thread owner id is one
zero
or not if it's if it is equal to one two
two
zero zero then
uh then the process then the owner id
processes will be equal to the
on this this target process on id
so here basically we are just collecting
this thread id
from our target process
and putting it into the vector array
so
i will just go over here
so yeah you can see i have put the
breakpoint already here in line number
126 is
so i will just continue this application
so now uh you can see there uh in the
dids the vector array
so we have got the
we have got all the thread ids
so let me just confirm yeah this is it
so once we get all the thread ids for
the uh from the particular process from
our target process uh we will open we
will open the
uh we will open this target process
using the process id and with the
process all access right so we are
trying to get all the access right from
of that process object so basically we
are just getting the handle to this
particular
particular process this target process
here
now once we got the target process we
will allocate the uh memory
so here you can see the base address is
all zeros here so we are allocating the
we are allocating the new memory in the
target process
for our sale code
so you can see the silk the base
addresses of 460 and four zeros let me
just go to the
process hacker and in the memory
okay let me just add
so yeah this is the one that we just
allocated and you can see um
it's all zeros here
so after that using the
api a write process memory we are
writing our payload into that
into this memory so let me just execute
this
code
and i will just read with this
memory here and you can see our cell
code is
successfully written here
now uh you can see
the
protection for the memory is read and
write so we need to change this
protection to
read and execute so that
our payload will be able to execute
so it's in the forces
so you can see we have successfully
changed the
memory protection of this
um of this memory so it's now read and
execute now we are converting our
now we are converting our
cell code to the start routing
so we will look through we will look
through all this thread id that we
collected from the process and we will
put our cell code in its uh in its
apc queue
for the
for the threads
using the queue user apc
function
so let me just execute it
so yeah you can see nothing happened
because uh this technique is not
reliable
so
so our thread might so it is not
it is not confirmed that the thread
might enter into the audio table state
so our shellcode might not get executed
so we have to be really lucky on this
one
so if we try this a few a few different
times then we might able to execute our
self code so
so let let us switch this switch this
application to the early bird
so
uh
pull it first so let me rerun this
application again and this time we will
be going into this
early bird function and you can see i
have already put the big friend at the
line number 59
so here you can see we are
how we are creating the process in the
suspended mode you can see the flag we
have we are using is quite suspended
so if i just step over and you can see
the notepad is created in the suspended
mode
after that we will allocate the memory
for the uh for the payload in the remote
process in this process so let me just
open this one
and if i execute this first law look
7 in 4 0's
so you can see the memory is allocated
here
and it's all zero
now we will write our payload into that
[Music]
so you can see i have executed this
write process memory so
our cell code should be written here
so you can see our cell code is
successfully written here
so after this we are changing the memory
protection from read write to page read
and execute
so at this moment you can see it's rw
so let me just refresh this
box and let's see
see so you can see
uh the
the memory reason is now read and
execute
so now we can just put our cell code in
a cube using the queue user apc and
we can resume the main thread of the
suspended process
so now we can see our cell code is
successfully injected and you can see
the
you can see the processes still in
notepad
and
nothing is changed here
but our circuit is successfully get
executed
so this is it for the
apc injection
so if you have any question you can ask
so let's take a two minute break and
we can start with the another technique
called model stomping
so if you have any question you can just
drop the question in the comments
so
if you have any queries then you can
just drop in the chat box
okay so i'll start the
another technique which is called model
stomping
so now let's start with the
another another technique called module
stomping so in this technique phrase
just get the laser here
so in this technique phrase or lazy
template dll is loaded into the target
process and the cell code will be
injected into that loaded loaded target
dll
and when we create a
new thread uh the cell code will get
executed from the legitimate dll and the
one
and one of the advantage of this
technique is there will
no need to be changed there will no need
to change
memory protection like we did in the um
a pc injection
so these are the steps for the model
stomping first we will get the handle to
the target process
and after that we will load our
target dll into the target process
after that we will write our payload at
the entry point address of the loaded
dll this one this step is really
important
and after that the thread is
created and
the thread will execute our payload
so these are all the api calls that are
using the
module stomping technique
so let's just jump into the lab
so
we are running this application
in a 32-bit mode so
it will require the target process to be
so i'm running the 32-bit notepad here
so the process id is
13520 for this notepad
so i have put the breakpoint in this
at the line number 64.
so i'll just execute this program now
so using the open process we are trying
to get the handle to this uh target
process
and and our process id is 0 sorry 3 4 d
0 in hex which is
which is 1 3 5 to 0 in decimal
so let's let me just execute this code
so we can see we have successfully got
the handle to the target process this
process
now we will uh here you can see at the
line number 72 we are allocating the
memory uh but the target but the
allocation size is the length of the
target target library so which means we
are
going to load uh we are
not going to uh load our
or we are not going to copy our
dll into the
into the remote process
but we but we are
writing our
uh module file path to the target
process memory
so
the the
so before selecting this dll this is the
target dll and this is the
legitimate dll from the microsoft
so before selecting the dll we must be
sure that the uh the dll must not be
loaded already into this uh process
target process so we can see there is
no such dll
called file mgmt dll here and this tll
must be
larger and larger than our cell code
so after that we will allocate the
memory for
uh for writing this file path into the
target memory
so you can see we have allocated the
memory in this address
which is e4 and four zeros
so
uh
if i just execute this line of code
we write process memory
uh we will be right the file file path
to the target process memory
so you can see we have written the
file path for the file management dll
which is our target dll to be loaded
into this process
so uh
using this load library a functions we
are going to uh load this dll into the
remote process memory into the remote
process which is notepad
so uh at this point we are retrieving
this load library from the local address
of the load library function from the
local memory local process local process
but
but most of the time the kernel 32.dll
is loaded in loaded at the same base
address
in many other process as well
so you can see the base address for the
uh load library a function is 7 6 3 4 0
bd 0
and we are assuming that the
load library a
is in the same address is in the same
address space
in the target process as well
so after that we will create the remote
thread
so the function will be the load library
a and the parameter will be the
file path
so
in the model here you can see there is
nothing
there is
there is no dll such as there is no dll
the
there is no file mg and dll here
so if i just uh execute this code
so this quit remote trade will going to
execute the remote thread into the
target process so if i just
create the remote thread here
so you can see the file mgmt.dll is
loaded into this target process memory
now we have loaded our target dll into
the target process
we have to file we have to find the base
address of the dll
because we have to write our cell code
at the entry point
at the entry point of this dll
so
let me just
go into this file module base function
so here we can see using the enum
process modules we are reading all the
we are reading all the modules all the
modules of this target process so here
you can see right now it's all the
all the values are 0x ccc all the zonks
value
so if i just execute this function
you can see we have got all the
all the base address of this uh all
these of these models
so uh using the gate module file name ex
we are looking through each modules and
using this gate module file name ex we
are trying to get the
full path of the
we are trying to get the full path of
this dll and here we are checking
whether whether
it contains the
we are just checking the substring and
we are just checking that whether the
file path contains the
contains our file uh which is
filemgmp.dll
so let me just execute this function and
see here
we can see we have got the
full path for the notepad.exe and it's
checking whether the uh whether the path
contain the file mgmt.dll or not
so i will just continue this
application and
you can see the model name is now
filemgmpdll and it is equal so
we are returning the base address of the
file mgmt dll so
let's just go over here and
so you can see the base address for the
file mgmt.dll is six to f9 on and four
zeros
so if i just execute this line
you can see we have got the base address
of the
of the loaded dll which is six 62f900
let me just put this in the watts
you can see it's 6 to f9 and 4 zeros
and here it's the 60 f9400 so we are
good to go
so after this
after that we have to find the entry
point of the target dll
so using the read process memory we are
reading the 1000 bytes from this
from this base address
so here we are parsing the dos header of
this target dll
and we are retrieving the anti-headers
now from the optional header uh there is
a
there is a member called address of
entry point
so this is the offset of the entry point
so one once we add this value to the
module based address then we will get
the exact entry point of the
loaded dll in in the target process
so here we can see the entry point is to
well before zero
just add this to the ones as well
so uh
we will just add this entry point with
the
model module this
[Music]
so here at the point at at this point we
have cut the entry point of the dll
which is loaded in the
remote process
now we have got the entry point we will
just write our cell code in that entry
point
uh now it looks like the
payload is returned to the entry point
of the
target dl we will just
execute the remote thread now
so you can see our cell code is executed
successfully and to confirm this we can
just go to the thread here
and you can see there is a file ng empty
dll loaded here
and you can see the message box is
in the stack trace
so
this is it for the
module stomping so if you have any
queries you can ask
[Music]
so i will start with the i will start
the process following now
so this is the one of this is one of the
famous technique and this has few
different variants
but the one that we are going to talk
here is the original one
so in this uh
in this technique we are just
in this technique we will just replace
the
executable section of the legitimate
process uh with the with the malicious
executable and all the replacement will
take place in the
memory
so these are the steps for the process
following
so the first the important step is to
create the pros create the process in
the
suspended mode
after that we we have we need to find
the image-based address of the target
process
because we we have to hollow out that
targeted target image
so after we hollow out that target image
we will allocate a new memory into the
same image base address
so for our payload
so after that we will copy all the
payload section and header to the newly
allocated
memory in the target process
then we will sense the context of the
target process
after that we will resume the main
thread
of the target basis process
so these are the api that are used in
this
technique so the one that is important
is this nd on map view of section api
with the help of this api we are going
to unmap the
uh unmapped target image from the
process
so let's jump into the lab
so you can see i have put the breakpoint
at line number 103
so i'll just execute this application
so using the create process api we are
we are going to create the target
process
in a suspended mode
so you can see the target process is
traded in a suspended mode
now using this anti-query information
process uh we are going to read the
uh we are going to read the information
about this process
uh because we need uh one thing here the
we need to get the pay batteries here
and as well as the uh image space
so here uh this is pointing to the pave
of the
our remote process and and in 32 bit at
the offset of the 8 we will find the
image space address of the
particular process so let me just go
here
so you can see the image base address of
the
so the image based address of the
notepad is f
0 and 4 0s
so
we are hollowing this
image so we are just uh
hello we are just hollow outing this
image
so
let me just show you something here
first
so this is the 32-bit baby structure and
at the
opposite eight you can see
uh it's pointing to the image address uh
which is this image address here
so if i just uh if i just execute this
code
i will be pointing at the offset 8 right
now
now using the read process memory we
will read the image base from that
opposite
so right now you can see the target
image base is uh
zero zeros
so if i just execute this one
you can see uh it's a f and all zeros
which is equal to our target image base
so now we will unmap this section from
the process so just look uh look at this
carefully right now uh we can see there
is a f and
five zeros
and you can also notice the type is the
image here
so
from here to here
uh we are just great we are just reading
our
payload buffer from the file and
on writing and putting that
buffer into the heap
and from the payload buffer we are
reading the size of the image of that
payload buffer here by parsing the p
header
so you can see we have uh got the size
of the
size of the image of the of that payload
uh this is important
uh because after unmapping this section
we have to
allocate a new memory
so that's why this is important to
allocate the new memory
so
here you can see uh using the zw on map
view up section we are going to unmap
this section right now you can see f00
is still here
so if i just execute this api
uh you can see the f00 is unmapped and
it's vanished from here
so
so now we can reallocate the
memory in the same image space so we can
see we are
allocating the uh image at this f00
offset now
so if i just execute this first solo px
function
you can see the
fn500 we can we have allocated the new
memory and it's all zeros and the type
is the private you can see
and the protection is memory protection
is read right and execute
so after that we will be calculating the
delta base for
for the relocation
so now we will be writing the header to
this
memory address you can see right now
it's all zeros
so if i just execute this line
uh you can see we have written the
payload header here
now
now uh
from line 7 172 to 177 we are
writing all the sections into this
address into this memory location
so let me just continue continue the
execution
so if i do this
you can see all the sections are written
here now
so after that we need to fix the
uh we need to perform the location
so
uh what is exactly happening is here
so what exactly happening here is
uh there are some constant uh in the
upper
image so uh use
so we are
repatching all those we are we are
fixing all this con constant to
uh
to execute the process
peacefully
so uh if you are really interested to
know what's happening here in this line
of code
so you can uh
comment
so you can just drop the comment
uh because like uh
i have to go through the different tools
to make you understand this
because uh from the
from the code perspective it's really
hard to understand what's going on here
so if you are really interested you can
just drop the comment and at the end of
this video session i'm
going to
i'm going to explain what's really
happening here
so for now just understand that we are
fixing some constant in the uh remote
process memory of uh
in the
uh in the
in the payload which is loaded in the
remote process memory
so once the relocation is done
we will get the entry point of our
payload in the which is in the target
process memory
so here we have got the offset
and we have added the offset to the
uh to the
image base of the payload
so this is the exact entry point of the
of our payload in the target process
memory
now we will get the
context
of that process
so you can see uh here the
here the eax register is holding the
holding the entry point of the previous
uh
previously
holding the entry point of the original
image but we already have replaced that
image with our
payload so we have to replace the entry
point
entry point of the original image base
with our payload image base
with our payload entry point
so
so whenever the process
is created in the suspended mode uh the
eax register holds the
entry point of that particular process
so that's why we need to replace the
entry point here
so we are replacing the
uh
entry point uh we are replacing the
entry point of the original process
which is f21860 with the entry point of
of our payload which is f 0 1 2
6 c
which is in the target process memory
so once the uh
once we
pass the eax register here
we will just apply the patches using
this say trade context
after that we will just resume the
threat
so you can see we have successfully
loaded the
cell code here
so you can see nothing is changed here
the image file is still the notepad.exe
command line is still denotepad.exe
and our cell code is loaded from the
notepad
process
so this is it for the process halloween
so if you have any queries about this
you can just
drop the comment
foreign
okay so
i will start with the persistable link
now
so this technique utilizes the windows
api calls uh which are related to ntfs
transactions
so ntfs transaction brings the concept
of the automatic transaction to the ntfs
file system
so for instance let's say we are
performing some file operation in a
transaction
right so
suppose we are writing 100 bytes of the
buffer in a file
and assume that we have written away we
managed to successfully write all those
hundred byte uh into that file in a
transaction
however that
operation will not be fully successful
until the operation is committed
for the transaction
so this means that the operations should
be committed to
for the operation to be fully successful
so if any
so if any issue arises during
the write operation the transaction will
roll back and entire operation will fail
so
this is to maintain the integrity of the
data on the disk
so process following has four process
halloween is broken down into four step
uh transact load rollback and the
animate
so in the transact section we are going
to
open our file legitimate file for the
transaction
and then we will write our payload into
that transacted file and after that
with the help of that transacted file we
will create a image section
here
and once we created the email section we
do not need that transacted file so as i
mentioned before if we commit the
transaction uh the operation will be
successful so in this case if we
uh commit the transaction our payload
will get written into the sticks uh
which we do not want that to happen
so uh
so in the third step we will just roll
back the transaction uh which will
completely remove the malicious code
from the
ntfs system and there will be nothing
left on the disk
and after that
the last part is to animate the process
so use until now we have the image
section here so using this image section
we are going to create the process
so
we have to fix something
in that process so basically let's
assume that we have to give the
we have to give the life to that process
and
and this
this fine this fourth step is really
important step
and i want every
i want everyone to understand this step
because this is uh literally same in
upcoming techniques like process
hardware dropping and process costing
so uh
we will be going in depth in this step
in process double ganking lab so
so
please save energy for this lab because
we will be spending more
time in this persistable ganking lab as
compared to others
so these are all the apis
so these are all the apis that i use in
the support ganking
some are missing but no ways we will
cover that in the lab
so if you understand the process
hollowing and persistable ganking it
will be really easy to understand all
the upcoming techniques
because all those techniques are
somewhat similar to these two techniques
so
so let's just move to the lab
and this one is little bit complex so
so uh
for this
so for this technique we need to turn
off the windows defender completely
because it will get detected by the
windows defender
okay since i do not have the permission
here let me just go away
so in the admis administrative template
and inside the windows component
there you can see the
microsoft defender antivirus
and
you just have to enable this
this policy
so whether we are just starting off the
microsoft defender
so it will not work in my case because
uh
i'm not running in the administrative
user
so
this will not work
i have to
log into the admin account and then i
have to do that but
but even though let's start this
technique
so once you turn off the uh
policy you can just restart the pc and
then the antivirus will be completely
turned off
but at the end i will be getting some
mirror
because the antivirus is not on not
turned off in my case
so you can see
the
i'm i'm putting this in the debugging
mode and
the architecture is 64 bit so it's
compulsory for if you are using 64-bit
architecture uh you need to
run this application uh in a 64-bit as
well if you run this application in a
32-bit then it will fail
so for the 32-bit application you have
to
you need to have 32-bit operating system
and for the 64-bit you need to have
64-bit operating system for this
technique
so uh
so let me just put the breakpoint at
line number 173
and these are all the apis which are
loaded dynamically so let's not worry
about this
so i'll just execute this
code here
so here uh you can see our target
process is the
mynode.txc which is in the temp
folder in the c directory
here this is the uh this is the target
uh this is the estimate file
so let's just let's
step into this function
so at the line number 43
uh using the antiquate transaction we
are creating the ntfs transaction object
so let me just go over here
into programming and
in the handle
so uh if i uh let me just execute this
code
and you can see we have created the
transaction sorry oh yeah transaction
object
uh and
and use and we will be opening our
target file for the transaction and here
you can see we have passed the handle to
the transaction
and using the create file transacted w
we are just opening the file for the
transaction and the permission we are
requesting the read and write permission
for this
transacted file
so yeah you can see um we have got the
handle to the file
which is uh c8
you can see it's a c8 here
so after that we are just returning this
transaction handle to the transaction
and handle to the transacted file
so now uh
we will write our payload buffer into
the transacted file
so if i just go over it if i just go
here and
open the file and see it's uh there are
kv with
and
because uh nothing is written here
uh because this is because this
transaction is not committed
so
so we need to commit the transaction to
uh to per to uh we need to commit the
transaction for the successful operation
otherwise nothing will be
done to the file
so
the buffer is still in the transacted
file so
so let's enter this create section from
transacted file function
so using the antique section
we
we are creating the
uh image section here
and the flag we are using is sake image
here uh this will uh confirms that the
file that we are
passing here
must have the
valid v header so if the transacted file
doesn't have the valid pe header then it
will fail to
create the section because of the second
image flag
so the this transacted file must have
the valid pe header
so here you can see
if i execute this line of code
you can see the section is created
successfully
and if i just go and
click on read and write you can see our
payload is successfully
written in the section
so we have created the
section out of the transacted file
so now we have the uh image section
we we do not need the transact uh we we
do not need the transact transacted file
so we will just roll back the
transaction using anti-rollback
transaction function
so here you can see we are just we will
be rolling back the transaction using
the anti-rollback transaction
now we will close handle to this
transaction and the transacted file
here you can see our transaction object
is distributed
and the file and the file is also the
string file handle is also destroyed
so using the uh using this section you
can see using these sections we are
creating the uh process body uh with the
help of the anti-create process ex
api uh we are using this api because uh
this api
requires uh requires this section uh
rather than the file path so since we
have this section so we are using this
antiquate process ex
so let's just look at here
if i just execute the
code here
you can see we have got the process body
now
right
so
you can see there is nothing in the
properties of this process
so we have to fix this process
now with the help of the antiquity
information we are reading the process
information
because we want two things here our
first one is the pave itself and the
second one is the
entry point of that particular
process
entry point of our payload
which is in the
in this particular process
so after that we are reading the
wave here
so here after reading the paper we are
just type casting this to the
uh baby structure if i just go over here
uh you can see this is the very large
structure and this is the similar
structure that is just show you
that i saw you before in here
you can see this is the this is
structure so we are typecasting
so we are typecasting this uh
retrieve data
uh with the paper
and in here
we can see we are getting the image base
address
so using the rtl image antihero we will
reach to the anti-header of the payload
and from there
we will try to
get the address of the entry point
so once we get the entry point you can
see we have got the entry point once we
get the entry point we will add this
with the
image base address of our payload
which is loaded in this target process
so as you can see this is our entry
point of our payload
in the target process
so here comes the important part
using the rtl create process parameter
ex
we are creating the process parameter
here so at this point you can see it's
all zeros so and we are passing the
command line argument and i think it's a
current directory path
uh which i am not sure but
you can always fill these null values
with the required argument it's uh it's
not necessary but you can always
uh work on this one
so i'm just giving the command line
argument and the
image file path i'm not sure
so if i just execute this
api
you can see we have created the process
parameter so uh the the second one was
the current directory
and the first one was the
command line
so this was the command line and this
was the current directory so you could
just fill uh all this null with the
parameter as you want
so once we have created the process we
need to
uh we need to transfer this process
parameter
into this remote process newly allocated
a newly created process
so here we can see uh we are allocating
the
uh we are allocating the memory for the
parameter process parameter in the
remote
process so you can see the
uh the address is
addresses 1 cc 960 and 9605 and 4 zeros
so let me just go here and look at that
address
this is one cc yeah this is the one
so in here or at this point you can see
it's all empty so in here we are going
to write the process parameter
so you can see using the right version
memory we are going to write the process
parameter into the remote process so if
i just execute this function
and look into the
memory
so somewhere around here
you can see we have
we have written our
we have written our process parameter in
the remote process
so this is the address where the process
parameter is written
so let me just add this in the watch as
well
so
after this
we will get the pave of that remote
process
now we have to
uh now there in the in the pave
there is a member called process
parameter
so we have to
give the address of the process
parameter to this member
so let me just go over here
let's open this
one the another one this is the 34 64
bit paper
and you can see at the offset there is a
process parameter
so we have to give this
address to the process parameter member
so let me just open the page here
i think this is the one
so at the 20th offset you can see uh
it's empty right now so we will be
writing this
value here
using this right process memory so if i
just execute this code
and we read this
so you can see at the 20th offset we
have written the
address of the process parameter
so now everything is set
so using the anti-grade 3dx we will be
creating a new thread
and the start routing of the thread will
be the entry point of our payload
so yeah you can see we will get the
error now which is c00 c0002
so this is because this we are getting
this error from the windows defender
so we have to turn off the windows
defender to
successfully execute this process
so if we just turn off the windows
defender from the group policy
uh we will be able to execute this code
so
so this is it for the process double
ganging
so if you have any queries you can just
drop the queries in the chat
oh yeah
so yeah you can see it's disabled now
because of the
because i am not the admin right now
i'm not in the admin user right now
that's why
so
you can just disable this you can just
enable this and
the code will work
so now we will look into the
okay so now we will look into the
another technique which is the
transacted halloween sorry it's not the
transacted halloween it's transact
hollowing
sorry for the typo
so this is
this is the combination of the two
technique which is process hollowing and
persistable ganging
the advantage of this technique is this
technique will solve this use of both
the technique
so uh in the process hollowing
when we unmap this section we
we needed to allocate the new memory for
our payload right
so so if you have noticed you might have
noticed that the
memory section that we created is of
type private
so but normally uh if we look into the
process the process has the memory
section of type image for the executable
section
so this looks really suspicious from the
perspective of the
security peoples and security tools
so process the poll ganging will fix
this issue
and on the other hand as we just saw in
the lab it's a little bit complex to
create the process in process double
ganging
so the process following will help on
this one
so from here to here you can see this
flow uh this is literally same
as the persistable ganging
from uh transact to rollback and after
that the process is created using the
process allowing technique
so first we will create a anti-fs
transaction object after that we will
open the target file for the transaction
and we will write our payload into this
transacted file
so once we created the transacted file
with our payload so once we uh once we
write our payload into that transacted
file
uh we will create an image section out
of that transacted file
so
after we created the image section we do
not need the transacted file so we will
just roll back the transaction which
will completely remove the
file from the edx sorry file from the
ntfa system
so after that
after that we we have the email section
so
uh we will create the
target process in a suspended mode
and we will
map that image into that target process
so we will map that image section into
that target process
so uh as i as i mentioned before process
following has quite different variant so
this is the another variant of the
process allowing technique
so in this technique we are not going to
unmap anything so after we on after we
map the image section into that target
process memory now we have to
uh we have to fix the
context of the process so we we just
need to replace the entry point
as we did it before
and after that we after that we have to
update the image base address at the
pave of the target process
and we will resume the threat
so these are all the api calls that i
use in this technique
so let's move into the lab
so
i will put the breakpoint at the line
number 171
and i will execute this program
so let's just step into this function
so
so here i'm just
retrieving the function dynamically
so here you're using the anti-quit
transaction we are creating the ntfs
transaction object
like we did in the persistable hanging
and after that we will uh open the
target file for the transaction using
the create file transacted w and the
transaction and we are requesting the
read and write permission
and we are not waiting or we are just
opening the file so file must be here
uh yeah you can see the file is there
so after that we after we get the handle
to that transacted file
uh we will write our payload to that
transacted file
just go to this process
so we can see we have the transaction of
transaction object and we have opened
the we have open the file
so using the transacted file uh we are
creating this section so again we have
used the sake image so this will
uh this will make sure that the
uh this this will make sure that the
transacted file has the
valid pa header if the transacted file
doesn't have valid p header then
it will fail to create the anti quiz it
will fail to create this section
so we can see uh the section is created
if we just enter if we just hit control
and enter we can see
we have created this section from the
transacted file
and this is our payload
now we will just close the
transacted file because we do not need
that
after that we will
roll back the transaction because we do
not want to save our save the payload in
the dix on the rigs
so after that we will close all the
handles
now
now we are left with this section here
so uh using the anti-process query
sorry antiquary information process
basically we are not using here right
now but we will be using here at line
number 191
but before that uh
here you can see we we are creating the
process in a suspended mode
so if i uh just step into this process
into this function
uh you can see uh we are creating the
calc.exe
uh in the suspended mode
so the calc that exe will be created in
a suspended mode
so you can see the uh processes in the
suspended mode right now
now
you can see we have step into this
map section image map section into
process va function
so using this anti-map view of section
we are going to
map the image that we have
into this target process memory so let's
let's just open this one and
so uh here you can see the section basis
zero zero zero
so if i just uh
execute this function enter my view of
section
we can see our uh our our payload is
mapped into this address in a target
process so let's just refresh this
i think this is the one
so you can see this is our payload here
it's successfully mapped into the
process and it's the image it's the type
is the image here you can see
so uh
so this is the base address for the
payload as well for the
which is in the target process so this
is the base address of the target so we
do not have to go
we didn't have to retrieve this base
address from the
target process from the paper the from
the from reading the tiger process
memory
so we have the base address of the
payload
which is in the target process
so uh using this antiquary information
again we are reading the process
information
because at this point uh we have to
uh we have to
uh i'll tell you later so
let's just get into this
function uh we are getting the entry
point of the
payload in the target process
so we have the base address uh we just
need to calculate the address of the
entry point offset
so you can see the address of the end
offset of the entry point is one to be
it so we just need to add this offset
there with the section base address
which is the base address of the payload
in the remote basis
so now you can see we have got the entry
point here
so after that uh using the gate thread
context we are
getting the process context here
so uh in 32 bit the rax was holding the
entry point but in case of the 64-bit
rcx will hold the entry point
so at this point it is pointing to the
original entry point of the
original
image
which is the calc the offset entry point
of the calc.txt
but we want to replace uh
that entry point with our payload
entry point
so
let's just replace
that r6 with our payload entry point you
can see
912b 8
and it's it it is 912b8
after that we have to apply this
context
which will be done by the setrate
so uh
so now we have to do one thing before
executing before executing the thread
we have to update the
we have to update the image base address
in the page also because right now it's
pointing to the
uh it's pointing to the notepad image
base so we have to replace that with the
we have to replace that with the
payload image base
so here we are just uh
reading the behavior
so uh the image base offset is at the
10th 0x 10th offset
and the hexagonal 10th optic offset in
the hexadecimal
and 64 bit let me just go to the desktop
and
open this figure here
so you can see uh at 10th of seat in
exit decimal uh we have the image base
address
member
so
here we are just adding the
and we are just adding the 10 in the
in the remote
you can see
so you can see it's a
d409 fc 0 and we have just added 10 here
and this this points to the
remote image base
so let me just open the pave here
so right now this is the tenth offset
you can see it's pointing to the
original image base which is seven ff
seven one two ca0
seven f f seven one two ca and four
zeros uh which is pointing to the
character txt
but we want this to point to the uh our
payload base which is seven ff sixty
seven b nine and four zeros
so using the right process memory we are
going to replace this uh address replace
the address of image image based address
of the
payload in the pave here
so
if i just
execute this right process memory api
and reread the
memory you can see it's changed
now it's pointing to the
pointing to our
image base of the payload
so it's seven b9 you can see d7 b9 and
four zeros now it's pointing to our
payload
after that we will just resume the
thread
and you can see our cell code is
executed and it's in the calc.exe
so
you can see nothing is changed
the command line is not changed and the
image file name is also not changed here
so this is the transacted this is the
transact following
so this is it for this lab
so if you have any
queries you can just drop the comment
drop in the comment
so let's start the another technique
which is processor by dripping so in
this technique the file on the dix is
modified after the image has been mapped
into the target process
so let's assume that the file android x
is our payload
so using that payload file we have
created the image section
and using that image section
using that image section and the api
anti-process
ex we we have created the process body
here so let's suppose
uh here we have created the process body
using the
uh image
section and let's come to the second
line
the modification is done before creating
an initial thread which means that
before
before starting the initial thread we
have to modify our payload which is on
the dix
so the question is why do we need to
modify
the file on the dix because we already
have the process body
we could just fix the process parameter
and resume the thread right like we did
in the persistable ranking
so the answer is
whenever so the answer is
uh many security products or register
the cornell callbacks
so
whenever the initial thread is created
the corner callback will get triggered
and it will notify the security products
so then security products go over so so
then secretive product will go and scan
the
image section which is in the memory
and as well as the file which is on the
dix
so if we modify the file which is under
dix before creating an initial thread
what will happen is the file the
antivirus will go and scan the image
section
and as well as the file on the dix and
the security product will
uh
find that the file on the dix is
different than the file
different than the
image section which is executed in the
memory
so this will full and evade the most of
the security products that's why it is
necessary to modify the file on the disk
in this processor docking technique
so uh these are the steps for the
processor production
so uh first we will create the temporary
or decoy file
uh in which we are going to write our
payload after that we will create an
image section using that bigquery file
so
using this implement section we are
going to create a
new process body
so we are going to create a process
which will be just the body process body
at this point
so after creating the process we will
modify the
decoy file which is on the dix
and then we will set up the process
parameter and create the remote thread
as we did in the persistable ganging
and after that we will close the handle
to the degree file
so the query file should be closed only
after the
only after creating the new thread
because uh security products
do not only
[Music]
monitor the process but they do
but they also do monitor the file
changes
in the system
so this is why it is important to close
the file handle after creating the
thread
so this will evade the
most of the security products
so these are all the api calls for the
processor by developing
so let's move into the lab for this one
so you can see
i have put the brakeman at line number
and i will execute this process
sorry execute this program
so
you can see we have created the degree
file uh in this directory
so let me just go to this directory
so
so we we haven't created it but we are
we will be creating now or using this
great file w
and we are get we are
asking the read and write permission as
well
so now we have the handle to this
file
so this is the file
that this is the degree file you can see
std61
so once we get the handle to this
file uh we will just write our payload
into that degree file
so using the right file
so
you can see we have written the
payload buffer into this file
which is now it's 11 kb here
so
after that using the antiquate section
and the
decay file we are creating the
image section here
so you can see we have created the image
section
and this is our payload
so um
so using that image section we are going
to
create the process body using the
antiquate process ex api
as you can see the process is created
here now
so uh using the antiquity information we
are reading this process information
because uh we need the entry point of
this particular process
like we
did in the persistable ganging
so let me just step into this
function
here we can see we are reading the paper
of this target process using the
anti-reversal memory
after that we are typecasting this
this paper buffer with the baby
structure
so
from the
address from the
optional here we have we are retrieving
the address of the entry point of the
payload
you can see it's one to be it and here
we are adding the image base
here we are adding the offset of the
entry point with the image base address
and which will give us the exact entry
point of the payload
which is in the target process
so now we have got the
entry point
so it's time to modify the file on the
dix
so at this point you can see it's a mg
header here
so here we are
placing the cursor at the beginning of
the file
you can see
so
now we are going to write the
buffer which is of size
1000 bytes
in
x now let me just put bitcoin here
and i'll continue this application
so you can see the
uh right file is successfully
right file api has successfully done
it's done it starts
so
let me just go over here and you can see
we have overwritten our file
payload file and you can see we have
written the hello world from cyber
warfare lab which is this buffer
and here we have only uh over it in the
half of the
or
a list in the half of the buffer but
this will be okay
so after this we have to
create the process parameter like we did
in the persistable ganking
after that we will be allocating the
virtual memory for the process parameter
in the remote process
now we will move our process map process
parameter into the remote process
using the right and the right also
memory
after that we will get the wave address
here
so
[Music]
as you can see in process hopper dotting
in the memory
you can see at the opposite
20 there is all zeros so i'll just write
the
address of the process parameter there
so you can see we have
overwritten this value with the process
parameter address
now all we have to do is to
create the remote thread
and the
and the start routing will be our entry
point
payload entry point
so i think this is uh
this is because of the
uh this is uh because of the windows
defender
so let me read on this again
because whenever
whenever we fail
so
whenever we fail to create the remote
thread
in source technique
it's probably some antivirus might be
blocking us from creating the thread
so i'll uncomment all of this
yeah i think it's because of the
uh it's because of the
i think it's because of the
thread i think it's because of the
antivirus let me just print the let me
just put the breakpoint here
so yeah it's the status code is same as
the persistable ganging
so
uh the the thread creation has been
blocked by the windows defender
so i think this
technique is
not working
in the latest version of the windows
because it's getting blocked by the
windows defender
so i
from the group policy if you
disable the
microsoft defender the process will work
that the thread creation will work
this might be uh probably this will this
this issue might be
probably this issue will happen in the
process questing as well
uh because uh in processing gusting it's
the same thing so let's just
try it out in the business questing as
well
so if you see the status code 0xc
and
i think it's six zero and two two uh
that means
the thread creation has been blocked by
the windows defender
so if you have any queries you can just
drop that in the
comment section
also i suggest you to turn off the
defender
to practice all these
injection techniques
because uh
uh there there
there are other ways to create the
thread
so no worries about that part
so
let's begin with the process ghosting
so this technique is literally similar
to the process double ganging the only
different the only difference is that
the
section is created using the delete
pending file instead of the transaction
so whenever we put the file in the
delete bending state
uh it will make antivirus 2
too difficult to scan and delete it
but we just seen that the
defender was blocking us from creating
the thread using this technique using
the uh process
fixing technique
so let's see if this
will uh
let's see if this will bypass
all right let's see this fill
allows us
to execute the thread
so in the process questing uh we will be
creating a dummy file
like we did in the processor harper
derpy
after that using the anti-set
information file and the file disposes
an information class as a parameter we
will be putting our file into the delete
binding state
and after that we will write our buffer
into the delete pending file
so uh
so using the delete pending file we will
create the image section
and once the
image section is created we do not need
the pending file so we will just close
the handle to the delete pending file so
once we close the handle to the delete
pending file the file will be
automatically deleted from the system
and after that um
we will be doing the same thing which we
did in the process of working
creating the image creating the process
using the image section and updating and
updating and fixing the process
parameters
and after that we will be using the
threat so
uh
during the thread uh while resuming the
threat we were facing the issue in
process harper darting
let's see if we face any issue in this
process question
because let's see if
windows defender is going to
block us in this technique as well or
not
so these are all the api that i use for
the process costing
so let's move on to the lab
so you can see we have hit the
breakpoint at line number 220 so we will
just step into this function
so here using the nd open file we are
opening the file
so if there is no file um
if there is an old file then it will
just delete that file and
create a new file because of the
supersede flag here
so we have got the handle to the file
so okay let me just go over here and
so this is the file that we just created
so let me just go over there
so this is the file and you can see it's
um
it's accessed by our application so
we cannot open
so uh here you can see using the
anti-set information file api
and the
and the file disposition information
class as a parameter
we are setting the file into the delete
pending state
now the file is in the delete pending
state now we will write the payload into
that file
so if i first
go over here
so you can see uh we have already
set our file in the delete pending state
that's why we do not have to permission
to open this file
so this will be same thing will happen
to the antivirus as well
so they will not able to
scan the file and or delete the file
now are using the file handle we are
going to create the section here
so here you can see we have created this
section
and you can see
this is our payload
so let me just go to this file you can
see
uh so whenever i
step through step over this code
so whenever i close this handle to the
file
this file this file will get deleted
permanently you can see
the pz6 dd1
so you can see the file has been deleted
successfully from the system
so after that we are just creating the
process with the section
section that we just created
so let's go over here you can see we
have created this section now
now uh everything uh now everything will
be similar to the sustainable ganging
and processor part typing we will we are
just
setting up the process parameters here
so using the anti-query information
process we are reading the process
information
then we are getting the entry point of
our
payload in the target process
here we can see um
we have we are just adding the entry
point offset with the image base address
to get the entry point like we did in
the process double hanging and harper
derping
now we have the entry point
let's just put this into watts
after that we will create the process
parameter
so you can see we have created the
process parameter with the
current directory dll path image path
and the command line
so at this point we are giving the
uh
target path has and file file path as
the svc host
in the process parameter you can see
now now we have to allocate the memory
for the process parameter in the remote
process memory
so now we have allocated the remote
process for the parameter
so we remote process memory for the
parameter
now we will
write our
parameter into that newly allocated
memory in the remote process
so you can see this is the 1dd305
3 of f7 8940
this is the process parameter address
now here
now here we are writing the address of
the process parameter
using the right process memory
so at the
20th offset of the tape
uh we can see
once i click the reddit there will be
the
parameter address written so you can see
after that we can just resume the thread
so yeah the same thing happened
the
windows defender is blocking us from
creating the thread
so this is it for the
uh
for the processed
ghosting
now let me just restart this
vm and i'll try to turn off the windows
defender completely
so i will turn off the windows defender
completely here
and now we start the
pc
sorry the vm
and we can confirm that the
uh the process that the thread creation
was blocked by the windows defender
so let's test this with the process
ghosting now
i think the defender is completely
turned off now
let me just turn up from here as well
so let's
put the breakpoint here
so as you can see our
uh
our cell code is successfully execute
executed
so it was because of the windows
defender we were getting that error
so
uh you could always try this uh you know
try this at home
like you could always try
some new things to bypass this
bypass the defender using the different
technique
so let me just run this again
so let me just feel on this again
so
yeah i just wanted to show you this so
at this point you can see we have our
process parameter is set as the
svchost.exe
so if i just continue you can see
the process is successfully liquid
our circuit is successfully executed
so let's try this with the
harper derping as well
so let me just put the breakpoint here
so you can see
the process is executed successfully
sorry the cell code is executed
successfully
so the window defender was blocking us
to
create a new thread or the remote thread
so uh thank you everyone for
attending attending this webinar and
this is it for the
process injection technique
so if you have any queries you can just
drop drop into this app
you