uh
[Music]
this thing one two yeah yeah
oh it was a normal
me
[Music]
is
for the
zero person on the stream uh you should
go on ctf101.netsec.io
and uh make sure to create an account
and then i'll uh i'll talk with the
people in the audience
be back be right back
i'm sorry i'm not looking at you
i'm gonna actually just stop this thing
and then share my screen
should be good
all right
is there anyone who speaks english
[Music]
is
foreign
[Music]
um
way up
register and work on the challenge
mohan though
and
oh no that's login i need a register
oh yeah that's this
all right so
as i was uh telling in the room uh we
were gonna we're gonna start from the
bottom from system men and then work our
way up this is a million way of forensic
reverse engineering
uh unfortunately i have no way to know
if there's anyone uh online so
uh i might forget about you completely
at which case you should have come on
site i'm sorry about that in advance
uh okay so we're gonna look at ssh first
um
the
the way that we're going to connect with
ssh is using a key so is everyone here
familiar with ssh
or have you never heard about it
familiar so ssh is basically like remote
desktop but for the for a console and
it's usually to administer linux systems
but it is very useful as well because it
can carry arbitrary data across a tunnel
we're not going to do the tunnel part
yet but ssh has an important concept so
instead of relying on passwords you can
use keys
and as an administrator using keys is
very key
but it's the the fact that
you're pretty much guaranteed the
complexity of the what the user uses to
authenticate
uh and it's we're talking like 150 60
bit of complexity
again you know depending on the specific
cryptography used but it is
uh
stronger-ish security so
this is
very simple right you have the host name
you have the port you have the username
and then everything is laid out at the
bottom
for you so we'll try to connect and see
what this leads us to so if
i use this now
you can use a
windows subsystem for linux it has ssh
now so you can use that but uh you you
can also use putty so we put in here the
key in the putty format putty is a very
well known windows ssh client but i'm
gonna for the demonstration i'm gonna
use uh ssh
from linux so
as we what we can see oh i'm gonna just
remove the trust that i established
before
uh
known hosts uh this is a bit uh
whoops
yeah all right
it's because i tested all my challenges
yesterday so that's why i had different
behavior
uh oh i'm also gonna go in this folder
and i'm gonna remove everything to show
you that i'm not cheating
so we're empties a clean slate
now
we're trying to ssh there it's the first
time we connect so ssh is considered a
trust on first use protocol
which means that you there is some
like the host key is exchanged on the
first time so you you could be
man in the middle the first time you
connect to an unknown ssh server but
after you did the first trust usually
you know you just set up the server so
you connect to it right away after
but so once the this first trust is
established then
um
if anything in the cryptography changes
afterwards you'll get a big ass
warning
really scary that says you are being
attacked something eavesdropped in the
middle the secret that you exchange on
the first use is different
so
now for our purposes you know in a ctf
context you basically are trying to
attack the system so you will trust that
whatever key but then here what we have
is that we're asked for a password
so
we know that there is a key pair that
was given
so now let's try to use that so we'll
download it
so i'll uh
you know you started ctf you create a
folder with the name of the ctf and then
you put your stuff at the right spots so
i have the track is called system and
i'll put the key pair there
and then
let's look at the options i want to pass
a key
all right so we have here identity file
right select the file from which the
identity private key for public key
authentication is red so we're gonna try
that
it's a bit directed right so i'm
cheating a little bit here
so we're gonna pass dash i
and then a link to the key
ssh keypair
gonna try to connect
oh i'm getting an error like unprotected
private key
well ssh is trying to teach you how to
do the the things correctly right it
says
you know this stuff shouldn't be
readable by others so it's saying that
the permissions are too broad
and
on linux by default
uh other have read access to your files
and they don't know that this is a
single user system so they're giving me
this warning
so we're gonna change permission on it
so permission
again you know this is ctf 101 we're
going to change permissions and it's
part of the challenge
you know it's it's all good
so we're going to use uh change mod and
i like the symbolic
way of changing permission do we see the
at the bottom yeah
i like the symbolic i i could
i'll pump it up oh i can't actually i'll
clear all right
so i like the symbolic way of changing
permission because it's super easy to
remember as opposed to the octal like
zero six four four or seven seven seven
uh so
the
friendly way you basically have u for
user
j for group
and o for others which is the the
the permission system that you see here
right
so
the the first uh
sequence of three is user
second sequence of three is group and
the last is others or people some people
call it world
so
what
the error messages i got is that
permissions were uh too
broad
it was too permissive so we're gonna get
rid of those readable portion for group
and other
now
with the symbolic way this is
accomplished by saying
user must be equals to read write
comma
group and others
equal nothing
as simple as that don't need to remember
the octal stuff
and then
say i always forget i didn't get into
the directory so and then the file name
so what happened
happens that we remove the read bits by
saying that we want nothing
in
for group or other
now
will it complain
no we got in
we were in the system
let's oh we ls you know we list the
files and there is a flag let's look at
him at it
flag.txt
learning to use ssh and ssh keys is a
very important skills and we got the
flag right there
i'm gonna try it
all right we got it
so
let's check how we're doing
okay okay
so um anyone
has so we're gonna move on to the next
one but anyone has questions or you guys
are are not set up properly or this is
just too easy you haven't attempted
see
[Music]
um
don't leave
all right
so
yeah so i'm gonna look at the challenge
first right because we need to have a
goal oriented
resolve it's good
okay so ssh tunnel
it's very important skill to understand
so
you're going to leverage the machine
that you had you just gain access to
in order to reach another machine behind
that machine
this other machine is not available on
the internet
and and this is what's written here is
that you could try to reach
that other machine
from the first one
so
the goal is to to query a service
on the sysanmin
service machine okay i'm going to do a
little diagram here so
uh let's
so this is pivot box
and
the machine behind is this admin service
okay
this is the internet
and uh
this is us
all right
so
what we did in the previous uh exercise
is access pivot box okay now what we are
asked
is there is a service
running here so a process
running here on port
555.
what we are asked is
to query that service okay
but the problem is that this so the the
host name is called system men service
we're gonna try
from
our my computer
i'm gonna try to access it right but
this is not an internet this is not a
global ip address this is not
uh
something that is reachable from my
computer right now
okay well
what about from the server we just got
access to so from pivot box
can we access that system
so let's try to ping it
oh
i can't there's no ping is not installed
ping is not installed
can we
resolve it
we don't have an s lookup okay can we
is there dig another dns tool no
is there
systemd resolve
no
so basically i don't know how from that
system it's a very restricted system and
it's part of the challenge okay this is
why we have to learn about ssh tunnels
so
again back to our our little diagram
here so we did ssh into
pivot box
all right
so we did ssh into pivot box
but there is nothing here that gives us
the power to reach
the the port 555 that we need to reach
on this other system we're not even sure
that system exists because we have no
tools to query dns that i found
does anyone
here know another dns resolving tool
that i haven't tried
host file the host file let's check take
a look at the host file that's a good uh
good point
so a host file on linux is atc host
oh it's there
all right so we know the ip that's good
we made progress
so now is there okay so we have
so the host file
i didn't even know docker worked that
way
so docker did inject the ip in the host
file so we know now that this
is on a different
subnet it's not an internet accessible
address right we're going to put that in
our diagram here
uh
up that's the ip
of this system
and
since it's not an internet accessible
address we need to find a way to uh
query it
to uh
we need to find a way but we are in
pivot box so here we probably have an ip
in this subnet so i tried to look at rip
it says command that found i'll try i
have config i'm not found is there a way
i can find my own ip and that subnet is
it an etsy host it's not
so
there's probably a couple ways and one
of the things is we have access to
python right so we could
put python code to figure out what's my
ip
or what what are all my ips because
python is basically you know
an interpreter of
a lot of things
but why not go there because it's kind
of out of scope a little bit but still
an important part of the mindset right
of the what do you have at hand that can
help you solve the problem which is i
need to query that service
so
we're gonna try we're gonna forget
what's rip we're gonna assume that we
can connect to this ip
so we're gonna try maybe
you know so i uh so netcat doesn't exist
doesn't exist
uh curl
doesn't exist so nc is basically
low level
tcp it's called the tcp swiss army knife
so it allows you to connect you know to
any ip and a port uh it's very useful
tool for
port exploration and stuff like that
but very manual it's very low level
uh curl is for querying uh http stuff
and it's not there and then there's wget
wget is another it's curl like
so we can see okay can we connect to the
host
and so
by default it will try port 80
4 http stuff and it says connection
refuse but we know that it was on port
5555 so we can do that
and then it says connection reviews
okay
now we tried all our options
to leverage
pivot box so we were we were here right
we tried
tried everything
from here
and
the result is set face
now
we have all the tools that we need on
our attack machine why don't we
have a mechanism to reach this port and
this is why why ssh is so powerful
you can
and so basically what what happens is
that with ssh
you create a tunnel
that will go up to here i'll uh i'll try
to make that more uh clear i guess
and so what we'll do is that we'll we'll
uh send our data here and it will go out
like it's coming from here to go there
okay
that's what we're gonna try to do with
our ssh tunnel
ssh tunnel now
the syntax for ssh tunnel and the and
and you can figure this out on your own
uh with the man page
but uh
if you search for tunnels so searching
in man page you just write slash
and it will search in the man page
search for tunnel
couple words uh maybe it's not super
clear
that's not the type so ssh has basically
a lot of different types of tunnel
it's not helping i know the name of the
option i'm gonna like
reverse figure it out okay
so
dash capital l but so it's here if you
look at the man page it says specifies
that connection to the given tcp port or
your linux socket on the client host
are to be forwarded to the given host
and port
so
what's interesting is that an ssh tunnel
doesn't only allow you
to do
port here which is already in itself
very interesting right you're tunneling
securely getting out and poking the
local system but it allows you
to go from
the system you are connecting to
to another system only available from
that system
so
capital l
and then you have
port
host and host port this is what we're
gonna
build so
port is the port on the client
host is the host
after the original ssh connection
in in our case
this is sysadmin service
this so our original ssh is to pivot box
but from there our tunnel we want it to
be destined to system in service at the
remote end
and then there's host port so if host
this is an n service host port is 555
and so
let's try it okay we had our previous
command we still need the key because
we're still authenticated to that system
we're just adding another feature on top
of it
so dash capital l
port
our port is local
basically
we we invented right as long as we
remember what value we put there this is
local this is for us for later
because
although we're set up in that tunnel
that tunnel
it's not giving us the flag instantly we
still need to query that service but
instead of doing it
from the target system we will do it
from our own system it's all going to
make sense very soon
but this port we can
figure it out on your own one a really
good value is one two three four five
it doesn't matter to be honest
okay then it was host
host will put sis admin service
because pivot box knows what that means
it translates to 172.1.0.8
and then 555.
so what's weird about the first time you
do an ssh tunnel is that you think that
the ssh tunnel is so important that it's
going to change the behavior of ssh from
the the common line perspective but it
doesn't so you press enter and you still
have your shell
but what you don't know or what is not
obvious
is that the tunnel was connected at the
same time so you do have your command
interpreter but the tunnel was created
so if we look at our local machine so
i'm opening a new common line on my
local machine
and you do a net step
to look at what are open services and
let's grab one two three four five
so the flag that i'm using
the p flag is to show the process
associated with a socket this requires
root this is why i added sudo and i need
to type my password
but so uh unfortunate positioning of
zoom okay let's just run it another time
all right
so what you can see from this is that on
my local system now that i did the
tunnel
i have
something on port one two three four
five
that is
listening and it's ssh
so ssh
created that tunnel for me now i wanna
solve the fl i wanna find the flag what
was i requested to do i was requested to
poke the service
so that's what i want to do
but now what's
the thing that we let's go back to our
diagram so now that i have this tunnel
and i'm here
how
can i query it
i can query it by
accessing my local system on port one
two three four five so if i drop
a packet
destined to
localhost one two three four five this
will magically
go
to
sysadmin service port 555.
let's do this
so i'm going to use ncat because it's
the superior alternative to nc which is
uh netcat which is the old
uh venerable at this point
uh tcp swiss army knife so i'm going to
end cap
127.0.0.1 which is localhost and i'm
going to do the port one two three four
five
this will magically
enter the tunnel
go through pivot box encrypted by ssh
get out at the other side of pivot box
and go to port 5555 and i'll get the
flag and this is what happened
congratulations
you pivoted
so imagine
all the firewall bypass capabilities
that you have once you master ssh
tunnels so it's incredible
you can do so much shadow i.t with ssh
tunnels
and there's even a concept in ssh where
it's called proxy command
where you can ssh into a box behind an
ssh tunnel ssh is very very powerful
and so let's try to put that
password in
and we got it
so
let's look at how we're doing
this is you know again
very hard
to
know where everyone is at right so i'm
taking it really slow maybe too slow for
some of you maybe too fast for others
right trying to do my best
trying to be respectful of everyone's
time
so we got six solve for the first one
which is very good
and then the last one we're like oh five
solves okay so we're doing we're doing
great all right so
this the pivot box service
is useful so keep it close
because once you do xss attack
on other people on the internet
you need them to be able to exfiltrate
their secret to a server somewhere
their browser will want to talk to
something and you need something to
listen there so don't forget that system
we're going to use it for the last
uh challenge of the web track
now let's look at the web track
or you know what since it's a beginning
of a new track
we can
uh
we can take a
you know couple minutes
i'll i'll ask the people on how they
feel
be right back
[Music]
okay
um
foreign
uh
yes
okay
all right
foreign
oh
[Music]
okay so
all right
so
for the web
for the for the web one
uh
the the first one is a
true classic of all ctfs that are easy
to have access to
and it's
use the source
so we're going to open it
and then what we have is a web page
and we're like what i don't know admin
and min
login failed
uh user user
login failed okay i don't know what can
i do i can try to look at the source
and if i do this
what do i i have i have oh
okay use the source
not even using my own advice all right
so you know
web pages have html code and that code
is all open
no matter how complicated it can be to
look at it nowadays it's still all there
right it's still instructions given to
the browser that are readily available
so
in that code there can be comments there
often is comments
so when you see an advice or a a joke
around using the source
the uh
power
then it's just look at the at the source
and sometimes
it can be really misleading like for
example a classic
of just
a twist on that use the source trick is
you put a thousand empty lines
and then the the password or the flag is
there right so if there's a thousand
empty lines you don't see it in the
first screen you see nothing but then
you realize oh there is a scroll bar and
then you scroll at the bottom and you
have your flag so you know
baby steps
but so it says if needed
support account is support welcome too
so
we're gonna do support
welcome to
login hey
hidden account activated here's your
flag
now
it's it's really simple right it's 101
but the reason why it needs to be
explained is that sometimes
there's a hint in the source and then
you're you're told
the
you're hinted towards the right
direction so it's always something to
look at and a lot of other places where
people will hide hints include
robots.txt and stuff like that common
uh
http stuff hidden behind web servers
so we got this
all right so the the to to view the
source
uh you can use uh
i think zoom is messing up with my
all right so you can use the view source
like this control u but the end spec
mode is pretty powerful and it's
something we're gonna use more and more
as we
as we go the through the web track
so and spec mode has a source component
but with a nice uh
navigation mechanism
you can and then there's the network
where you'll see a queries from your
browser
so it's all uh good stuff
oh and you can see that i'm i'm using
like a
preset to simulate a phone
okay
all right so
first one quite easy
view source
you have a clear text username password
you can get in
now let's move on to the sql
okay
so sql what's going on here i'm gonna do
test right search for test
now this is a
made-up challenge right but what what is
key in understanding sql injection is
that
it goes into
a database
and sql is a programming language
so it goes
in a something
that is a programming language so sin it
must be syntactically accurate
and you must you must think like the
programmer so now to help us understand
all this
we show the query in this challenge so
basically when i wrote test in the
search here what happened is there was a
select star from items where
name like
and then test is there
so we can say oh okay so this is where
it's going all right i
imagine that the flag will be in the
table
that it's querying already so i'm gonna
try to look for a flag
ah
so someone in the system is making
messing with me the in that database
there is already a a
a
uh an item in the items table that has
name flag but the description is nice
try
so
someone's messing with me right but this
was not sql injection so what is sql
injection is when you're trying to mess
up that query so what defines
the
boundaries
of
tokens in an sql statement
in this case are
double quotes
so if the web the person who programmed
this webpage
didn't account that i can put double
quotes
then he has a problem right so i'm gonna
try putting in double quotes
oh
something up now why did did the
page broke
let's think about it
well
let's replace in our head
flag with a double quote so what we have
is like
double quote percent
double quote
percent double quote this is invalid
syntax so of course the sql lexer when
it arrives in the sql engine
it says
this is not sql man you i blew up
and php was made to fail uh in this case
i'm not ignoring errors i am
uh bubbling up errors
so let's let's try let's start
by
thinking okay but how
can we make it legit okay
so let's put double quote
and then put
or
and then
let's put name
i'm i'm trying to think okay i don't
want to spoil the flag too fast right so
i'm going to put like a b c
and then or name and then i'm going to
finish because the thing is we you need
we need to finish that double quote
correctly for it to pass right
so or name equals and then i'm gonna do
abc and then leave it like that right so
what does this look like
so this works and and let's look at why
it works but we don't get the flag right
so it says like double quote percent abc
double quote or name equal
double quote abc percent double
so it's syntax and syntactically valid
but it doesn't yield the result that
we're looking for
now what would
all right so
the where clause is using boolean logic
okay so if we can do or we can do or
true so it's like
where name like false or true
then if it's true
all rows are gonna be evaluated to true
which means that i will get in my
results set all rows
so we can do then okay let's do a true
statement so we're gonna close that
bracket here
and we're gonna do or and then
the the classic
true statement that you see in every
joke online about s transaction is or
one equals one okay but this could be
simplified to one one is a positive
value it's a true true value when
evaluated so it's always
you guys should come up front it's very
loud you'll not hear anything uh one run
one mirror or one or you can sit
together as you want
um
but so
so we'll do the one equals one because
you know it's the xkcd joke and stuff
but people should do r1 and i'm
explaining why
one equals one is like in every
filter out there right so if you do r1
it's harder to filter one because it
could be a legit value input by a
customer yes
come on
there are many ways to bypass that
challenge many ways
so i'm gonna show you one but now i'm
teaching sql injection so we'll do we'll
do the legit first
but then i there's one you're close
semicolon probably doesn't work but
there's a there's one simpler that works
and
and you have everything
semicolon works okay
no but i i don't want to spoil it man no
we'll get there we'll get there
but so okay let's do or one equal one
but then i'm too in a hurry like i'm too
excited i do r1 equal one and i'll do
i'll do search right away oh error
why is that now since we have the query
it's easy for us to answer that but
imagine when you're doing ctf you don't
have the query output in your face so
oftentimes you need to go
in an actual sql engine and try the
stuff right
and and we could do that if we want i
don't know how i i think i'm slow so i
don't do i won't do this but you have
sql light on your system where you can
do that but so
one of the important tricks
is to know
how to comment in sql
so if you comment the rest of the
sentence you don't you you can avoid to
having it syntactically valid so comment
in mysql and and many sql databases is
two dash followed by a space
so now i'm doing
closing the first part of the where
clause
saying or true value and then the rest
we ignore it's a comment for programmers
you know
let's try that
and boom here we go we look at the like
so it's like everything
or one equal one and the rest is ignored
by the sql database the sql engine and
so now we have like
congratulations
and then flag equals no no and we
realized that we had a little bit of of
a
trolling material in there like if you
put just one equal one you are onto
something but so our flag is here now
let's get
let's get creative
as my friend just suggested
so i i never expected comma semicolon to
work
what's up
so
a person sign in this car in the like
class is
a wild card it's like star in most
things i don't know the old farts who
design sql decided back then that it was
a different character it's not star but
so
here's the behavior and i i'm getting
back at you regarding the semicolon
because i don't understand what's going
on but if if if we do person sign
and we search
it's gonna work right but you see it
here it's here it's showing up so you
you put in person in search when you
look at the query the person that you've
written
is in the query and basically why does
it work it's because this query is
i want
anything anything anything
and it works right now the behavior of
semicolon
troubles me
and i'll show you why because
it's not showing in the query so it's
probably not
as the sql engine that that
gobbles it it's probably something that
php is doing
yeah yeah you can do that but it would
show we would see it because what what
is displayed is what is sent to the sql
engine
so so i don't know i don't know what's
going on but it works you know what
let's let's take a look at the source
maybe
maybe it is showing
no it's not
yes
it could it could be but i i i
i would need to be convinced uh i'm not
100 on this one and i think like right
now i think about it i think there's a
bug in this challenge if i put nothing
is there an error
ah i validated the case where there is
nothing because because then let's say
that i wouldn't have put uh
uh
no this case
the query would be percent
oliver
yeah yeah but why is the semicolon isn't
in the query right where does it
disappear
it's still it's still it still should be
string concatenation in inside the php
variable
okay so okay that let's look at the
inspect okay let's look at this
from the inspect console let's look at
what is sent by the browser when i put a
semicolon
whoops
all right
we are
sending payload we are sending a
semicolon so this is
url encoded as percent b3b which it
should be url decoded by php
then injected in a variable that is
string concatenated
i still i still for me i still can't
explain it i'm still a bit dissatisfied
but uh
i'm sure there's an explanation
but so so let's do uh
let's do let's take the f here right so
if we had the proper f it will work
so let's do the f and then semicolon
see what it does
semicolon really disappears
ah oh my g sucks
that that's my mistake though so i i
tried to use utf-8 characters but there
is a collation in sql where
similar characters will be interpreted
differently anyway we dug deep and you
can see how it can be you know come more
complicated
but let's move on with uh our next one
which is the self xss any questions on
the sql injection
you can see how
uh once you understand what's happening
it's kind of simple but it gets
complicated when you try to exploit it
because most of the challenges will not
be the simplest cases
you really need to think like a
programmer basically
all right oh a lot of people saw the
suffix success that's good
okay so what's the difference between
what we had before
and the self-excess
boom
okay so we have a search very similar
looking to the sql injection so we'll do
right away or one equals one right
and then
this is not the sql injection challenge
but what's different here
is
our output is there in the web page
now
being able to modify a web page
is something that we know and we deal
with the web since ages right we're
really familiar with that
but what's the attack behind that well
the attack is
if i can inject
javascript
i can then have your browser do
something
as a third party so okay i'll do a
diagram
so we'll have like the user
the let's say attacker
then
the victim
and then the web server
so
when we were doing nothing on the
internet it didn't matter xss people i i
was one like in the 90s downplaying the
importance of the of the vulnerability
even in early 2000s i was like no one
gives a about xss it's like
remote code execution or nothing right
but then well the thing is that the
relationship between the web server and
the victim grew in importance and and a
lot of trust is behind it right let's
say the victim is donald trump and the
web server is twitter
if i can impersonate donald trump on
twitter i am pretty powerful not
right now anymore but
at some point in the past i would have
been pretty powerful right but
this is what
i would get people to invest in my
crypto for sure
so this is basically what xss is
you are sending a url so let's i i my
diagrams always start elegant and they
always become a mess but you uh you know
you follow along please so you send an
url no matter how a twitter dm an email
whatever the per the victim clicks on it
it's it it is in that url there is code
injected
javascript
that will be sent to the web server and
interpreted by the your browser and this
is another thing weird it's like and
this is a called a reflected xss
so the victim is carrying the payload to
the browser
the web server reflects the payload in
its page when it comes back to the
victim
there is javascript and the browser is
like
javascript yeah i'm executing this
and so this is the attack and now
we will do a
simple case where which we call
self-exercise so exercises this yourself
exercising yourself it's very for
demonstration or uh
academic almost purposes
but then the real attack is going to be
on the next one
uh where we are attacking someone who
clicks on everything we send his way
okay
so the first one
so in the first scenario we're basically
attacking ourselves
but
what we can see is that
we are modifying a web page with input
so this is always the first place you
start to dig okay
are they doing any filtering
well let's find out
can i do
this right
oh look at that the the html bracket
disappeared but the thing is bold this
is exactly what i asked
and you can see here that there are bold
tags well you might not see i don't know
how small this is but
the bolt tags were carried
this is the beginning of something very
dangerous
so what if we do
put script
tag
and then some javascript
what is going to happen and this is all
valid so script tag
javascript valid javascript
close the script tag then let's let's do
the search
oh my god it's written hello and it's
not written document.write so what
happened
what happened is
we actually had
the javascript executed
you we can see that what we have is
still the script that it's still there
right the the browser the web server
reflected all of what i've written to
the browser the browser when it saw that
line it did its job it said oh this is
script i'm i'm executing javascript now
this is what i do
and then boom hello is printed and then
the rest of the page is rendered
okay let's go back to the challenge
description now because we pretty much
have xss
challenge description says
your payload must absolutely contain
alert one and this is just a cheat hack
so that the web server could send you
the flag
it's not really important
but let's do it
so script
either one
script
we got the alert so as the page was
rendered
it it it stumbled upon
the play so that the thing is not even
available in the inspector and spec
console but we did get the other then
let's do okay
and then search for nothing because it
was just pure javascript nothing was
output it was all hidden by the browser
interpreting code
but you have the flag here right
congratulations you x assessed yourself
and we have the flag
again
super fake
to understand next one is the real one
and it's
you'll see this step up
a bit it's probably the hardest
challenge of ctf 101 is the the next one
and it's because xss are complicated to
perform these are complicated attack to
do
all right
so
xss larry i i should have called him xss
trump now with the example i made
earlier but so
we have the challenge so similar page
i actually i think it's the same page
so
you can submit urls for larry to visit
here so basically larry is a very
enthusiastic
page visitor so whenever you send him
stuff
he will visit
so let's have him
visit
i don't know google.com
so here behind the talking
it was written that larry visited the
page
so we have no output
we don't know larry doesn't reply to us
it's just he's just an enthusiastic
person browsing reddit
so we have no output so how are we going
to steal
larry's secret
well it's tough right
let's continue reading the description
our goal is to steal larry's browser
cookies
for the ctf 101 that insect.io domain
so
a browser will not send unrelated
keys to unrelated web servers so we will
need to find an xss under
that namespace that that
domain
and have him execute javascript
that will send his secret to us a third
party
it's getting pretty complicated
for this task you will need an
accessible web server you can use pivot
bot and this is where it brings back to
the ssh track where we have ssh to a
server that is reachable from that
victim
so
let's so
the
sesame ssh system uh
that
yeah the system and ssh system is shared
okay we're all on it together so we will
all need to use different ports so i'm
going to use a port you're going to have
to use a different one because you will
not be able to start a web server on the
same port it's important to understand
so i'm going to go there and run a
server
uh python3-m
http.server
and i'm gonna pick
one two three four five
okay it started which means that it's
running which is great
now
i want to confirm first before getting
into any xss any complicated payload
what you want to do is confirm that
larry the clicker
can go to that web server i want to see
him
browse i want to see him work
so in the challenge description we were
told
sysadmin.ss
ssh is going to resolve
to the good uh host
but i use a different port so i'm gonna
use that port here i'm gonna send this
to larry the clicker
one two three four five
larry click larry let's go
oh i got a request i have a get
slash http 1.1
didn't have that before
so
larry visited larry delivered he clicked
on that link
now i'm i'm not stealing any of his
secret here i need to figure a way
to steal his secret that's what
i'm after and i need to do this under
the ctf 101 domain
luckily
i have a web page that is vulnerable to
reflected
cross-site scripting
so what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna attack
myself now
but then eventually i'll build the
perfect url in order to be able to
attack larry okay
so the secret arena are gonna going to
be in a cookie one way of having access
to a cookie is the document that cookie
so let's do this on myself
nothing
it could be normal
at the same time i think i forgot to
write it maybe that's the problem
document.write
document.cookie
you can see that i've done this before
right
all right
still nothing well maybe i don't have
cookies do i have cookies
it might not be one that is available uh
for javascript so you can have cookies
that are
http only and that the javascript
context cannot access it so it's not it
might not be the best test
let's do
this
confirm that we still have injection we
still have injection okay
so instead of doing the the the cookie
we're gonna do
uh a query
yeah let's
now that's that's a bit too much
oh no that's not bad actually okay so
we're gonna just decomplexify this a
little bit
uh
uh uh yeah so okay no no no no okay no
i'm sorry i'm gonna start with something
simpler
so
i need to exfiltrate and for
information to a third party
to do so uh there are various mechanism
but one classic is the image tag in html
you can basically request an image from
everywhere there's no notion of
third-party security when it regards to
pulling resources like images
so we're gonna pull an image
from the the
uh
the the ssh service that i used before
so
uh cis and min this is a sage
i should use double quotes and i should
double quotes if they're gonna work
let's try that
whoops double quotes are not working
let's use single quotes
all right
so you can see that my browser is still
working and then i have a broken image
so what happens in here
is i do have
the http
column slash system ssh a dot gif okay
so this works now
uh
i'm not i don't have access to sysadmin
dash ssh this is not a public ip so and
my web server unfortunately is isn't the
ctf 101 docker environment
but will this work on the victim we can
try and this challenge is helpful
because
helpful in the sense to learn
because we we i reflect the query in the
url
so
i can uh
you have only to copy and paste
the the content of the url and send it
to larry so it's kind of making life
easier for you here so let's do that
so larry visited this
we should get a request oh you know what
no i i
i forgot the port
so one two three four five in my case
your case is different right
so let's search and then copy
and then visit
just before so i i put a couple of new
carriage returns so that it's obvious
that it's a new request
oh
so we get we did get the get right so
when i put an image tag
in this via injection the xss i uh la
and when larry clicks on that link he
his browser is trying to pull that image
now i just need to add the cookie to it
and this is where you need to learn
javascript
so
the the
double quote limitation is an important
one you almost always need to put double
quotes especially if you nest javascript
and html
so because of that limitation we're
gonna do everything in pure javascript
it's just simpler
but so i'm jumping a little bit forward
here but i'm gonna explain everything uh
line by line and you'll follow you'll
see no no where is there
so the only complexity that i'm adding
now is that i'm doing this pure
javascript
and i'm adding the fact that it's going
to be dynamically created in order to
avoid double quotes so what we have here
is
i'm using javascript to create an image
tag okay
that image tag i'm assigning it
the
this url
so the url and uh
so this url is
http
admin oh i almost forgot my custom port
column one two three four five
so
my web server that i control
a that gif ada gif no one gives a
what is the name it could already
already be like just the forward slash
then to that i'm appending
document.cookie
semicolon so this is ending so the image
in the javascript uh memory this image
tag has this url but if it doesn't exist
on the dom it will never be queried that
image so that last section
is to add it to the dom the document
object model so that the browser will be
oh there's an image i need to go fetch
it because i want to display it to the
user
so and then image which is the name of
the variable that we assign at the
beginning right
so with this we should have a pretty
good recipe
i see one risk one risk here is that my
cookie is not
url encoded
so it could fail because if there's a
value
that is not legal in uh urls
something either larry when he clicks on
it or something and the chain is going
to fail but we're going to execute it
like that and see
so we know in advance that for us all
we're going to have is a broken image
because sysadmin ssh is not reachable
from my computer
so let's do that i'm going to add a
little like
column a equals so it becomes a
parameter and not appended at the end of
the gif
or gif i don't know which club you're in
so okay so this is a complicated payload
that i'm gonna lose so i'm gonna write
it down here i'm gonna create a web
and then do a readme
and then read me and then put this put
this here all right
okay search
as expected browser waiting it's gonna
get broken image and it it's not visible
now let's send this to larry and c
we're gonna do a couple carriage return
so we see if it's new or not
let's do this
oh no need for url encoding we have the
flag so
let's recap what happened what the
is this complex that is
called an xss
it is
we the attacker sent to donald trump a
url which contained and if you look at
the url
that we we sent right it's it contains a
search
with
characters that are html characters that
should be filtered or escape or whatever
that is not escaped or filtered or
whatever that is reflected by the web
server
so
this victim's browser sending that query
that query is processed by the web
server the web server sends that back as
a web page
which has the angle brackets and stuff
like that that was unescaped and this
goes to the victim and the victim is
like oh it's javascript and it's coming
from a web server i trust let's execute
it and then part of that javascript is
injecting an image in the dom and saying
there is something at
a dot gif on
our
attacker's machine which is not in the
diagram
and then this is the browser that is
going there
and then
we are hiding the secret in the query
we're saying i want an image but this
image has this url which
have the flag in it
spready cool
xss
and this is a simple one like the ones
at nordsec the guys are just completely
crazy like i don't even understand them
anymore there's like oh i found a bug in
this and if you do this
[Music]
so
a twist on
on xss is so we saw the reflected
style but a twist on it is the stored
xss so storage access is basically one
that goes into the database
and then that when you view a web page
it's sent back to you so restoredxss is
very dangerous and can be wormable
for example if myspace you there's a
story that success in it and you write
to a forum post
and you trigger an xss then everyone
visiting that forum post can execute
that javascript and if part of that
javascript payload you are
posting another post on that forum with
the payload then it's just spreading to
everyone it just becomes crazy
all right so
the hardcore shift is behind us
we're back with
encoding
uh which is our forensics uh one on one
so there are many uh
flavors and types of uh of forensics uh
challenges in ctfs a lot of them are
fairly
uh
well i i would say easy it's not true
as as you know everything complexity
gets in and i remember at defcon quals
where we had like pieces of a raid array
and you had to rebuild the raid array
using those pieces and then mount it and
you had to hunt basically the the file
system structure and reconstruct it was
very complicated
but so
a lot of it has to do with having the
eye
for something right having seen stuff
before or having the idea of
uh
oh this sounds like a pointer or
encoded or something so now this stuff
does anyone have any idea what it what
this is
like
what is this encoded with
base64 correct
so
we're gonna learn our favorite tool
for uh those types of stuff
it's from uh the uk secret service
it's called the cyber chef
it's basically a swiss army knife for
encoding and
escaping and and crypto
and so it has a from base64 recipe
so at the top you put in the the crypto
at the bottom you get the result
and so here we can see that the flag is
here
so let's read it out loud
in this field you should recognize basic
encoding techniques just by looking at
them congrats because it looks like you
just did so here is your flag
so basically just basics before decoding
here
and we are correct
all right now we have a document
and in that document uh we'll have
two
two flags
let's look at it this i used to teach
cyber security at uh
ets university nearby
and uh so this is an old
class summary
that i use for that challenge
so okay
what are the things and these these
ctf challenges why is this included in
the 101 it's because i was very salty
about not succeeding doing a challenge
one day
and
these are two techniques that i didn't
succeed at first and i was like it's so
stupid that i need to teach that
to everyone so that they don't fall
victim of my stupidity back then
and so
how can you hide stuff in a document
well
one way
yeah
uh yeah using encryption and stuff legit
yeah but let's let's think
uh secret service like uh hiding in
plain sight type stuff right
and so
a thing should draw our attention but
it's normal that it doesn't but
yeah it's it's kind of stag if you want
but so um what you can do is
you can uh so a word document is super
flexible right it allows you to have
all sorts of of
you can put white on white basically you
can put you know tiny tiny tiny fonts
and like that so one trick is to
copy that paste all that stuff into a
dumbass text editor
and then
search in it and we know you know we're
we're in a ctf what are we gonna search
for we're gonna search for flag right
boom
i got a flag at the end at the
bottom end that you probably don't see
sorry about that oops
somehow dragged zoom
at the bottom bottom and there's
something that matched flag okay now
what we're gonna do is we're gonna go
back to the document select that text
and we see that there is text there
and then we're gonna make it
uh
darker
here we go so
ah
it's nice
since
okay
so the
yeah so basically one trick is white on
white type stuff let's paste it in the
thing and move on to the next one
oops
all right we succeeded the honor you see
the
so the next one so it says
the flag is in french but it still
starts with flag dash all right all
right
okay let's go back to the document kind
of cheat a little here
but this is the one
that i never succeeded in a previous ctf
and i was really salty when i learned
the answer and so
one hint is the the spell check
so why is spell check clear okay here we
have names of people okay spell check
doesn't clear it's not too bad
but why do we have at the top
all sorts of mistakes in words that
looks like they should pass
so let's paste specifically this part
in uh in a console
alright so if we look at it in text
what we can see is
some
weird things right so the first word
that is uh
buggy is informatic
and then e is fine r is is not fine and
so if we look in our console we see f
capital f we see capital l
we see capital a
and then capital j
g capital g
this is basically flag right so it's
hidden there
somewhere
somehow
let's put it in red
uh it's not just red it's like tiny tiny
tiny
so let's put it in uh you know 60.
so f
l
a g
at this point you guys should do it
manually but this is ctf 101 another
lesson i want you guys to realize is
that
the the difference between a regular
challenge and a challenging challenge is
that they will take something simple
like for example solving a captcha
and they will ask you to do it 5 000
times which means that you should not do
it by hand which means that you need to
code something learning to script is a
key
part of solving ctf problems
there's a whole sub category of these
that are usually called programming or
programming related so we're going to do
this but programmatically now have in
mind that this one in this case here you
should do it by hand i'm going to lose
more time programming it but still the
lessons are important and you'll see
also
the the the way i use you i advise
people to operate baby steps not doing
everything all at once
building towards the solution
let's do that
so i'm assigning the string to uh
to a variable
let's let's uh remove
where like here the words are normal
so we're gonna we're gonna substring
this to just that portion and the so
yeah like here okay
all right now imagine that this problem
is way bigger imagine we have thousands
of character and it's like a binary
encoded inside a document and so we need
to do this thousand times so we cannot
scale it but let's do it let's do it
program programmatically so now what i
want to do first is i want
the i wanna i want all words in separate
tokens
and i want the last character of every
word
[Music]
all right so i split into words now last
character last character let's do a test
oh
no so now i realize that this is at the
bottom and i need to put it higher so
i'm gonna have to do something a bit
weird but bear with me
all right if
this is good right you you all can see
at the back yeah okay perfect let's move
on so in c i have one ah that's not a
good choice
so in c i put one word as a test now i
want a last character what's the syntax
oh yeah i got it all right let's go back
to our list
okay so this is a list comprehension a
very powerful python concept i advise
everyone who's programming
semi regularly to really look into these
they are very powerful as i said um now
the we see that we have the last
character but there is some garbage so
we have commas
and and stuff so there's a problem with
the way we're doing things why is that
oh because when we split we kept the
commas so let's just get rid of them
somewhere before we do our last
character
assignment
whoa
okay so not perfect but
pretty close where i think we're gonna
be able to figure out that last buggy
character but so what i just did is
basically this string or yeah i did the
string i replaced comma with nothing
column with nothing
dot with nothing and then i extract the
last character inside the list
comprehension so now let's join that
back together because i'm too lazy i
want to cut and paste
so the string object in python has a
join attribute which takes a list and
you select on what you want to join so i
join with nothing so i have this so i
told before it was written that the flag
was in french so this is flag with a t
it's a mistake
so it's the flag
and the the fl part we can figure out
from the string by looking at it we have
the man and then a
and then
a carriage return and then a zero and
column so i don't know how the document
got like that but i mean we can figure
it out and uh solve it so let's
go back
put that in
fix the little
thingies that are offset
flag and then here it's also
flag
so the flag
observator
and here we go we are correct
all right we're almost close two
challenge left but the crack me at the
end all right network
well pretty much all ctfs have b caps i
don't know why it's a religion for
security people pcaps and i you know
what i love them
i guilt guilty as charge
so pcaps are opened by wireshark
we're gonna we're gonna do things a bit
uh
unefficiently here because you'll learn
some stuff while we do so
so
uh i clicked on something i it up
okay
what we have is a very small pcap with a
sequence of ping and reply and we can
look at them like that and the problem
with pcaps is that it can go in all
sorts of directions right there's so
much data if you start you could you
could look at timestamp if you have tcp
you could look at sequence number you
look at all sorts of stuff you can get
drowned in noise but now ping is pretty
simple
and usually well
people who looked at pcaps before know
the ping pattern for linux and windows
by heart it's like a crescendo and it
used to be to detect error correction uh
not error correction error on the media
so if some bits were corrupted you would
see it in the ping
reply and so ping is is uh comparing
what you what it sends
uh and what you send it and what you you
uh
it sends back
what you send it
so
here our
data packet for someone experienced in
networking
you would see that it's not a regular
someone is is using a different
uh data data package in ping and this is
allowed by the protocol but no one does
that so if we if we scroll down and look
at here
the data section okay
we will figure out what the solution is
pretty easily so f
l
a
g
dash
m
e
so
easy solve would be to write this down
and then uh
submit the flag but we're we want we
want to learn something else we're gonna
do it the complicated way so what is a
good way to scale wireshark analysis is
to use t-sharp so t-sharp is the sister
tool that is on the common line so what
i'm going to do now is i'm going to find
a way to extract the data out of the
peak app just the data section
all right so if we use a dash r for read
and then send the p cap to t shark what
we get is kind of a nice text based
summary of pretty much the information
we have in wireshark's
upper pane
which in itself is not what we're
looking for so the the key component of
t shark if you want to scale it and
automate it is the dash capital t
fields
this puts
t-shark in a mode of field extraction
now the fields that you want to extract
you will add them individually adding
dash e and the name of the field so what
we're gonna do is capital t
fields dash e and then we're gonna add
names of the field how can you know
what's the name of the field you asked
well let me tell you that wireshark is
very helpful because
there is a feature when you
right click that is called prepare
filter so if you do prepare filter and
selected or not selected doesn't matter
what you have is that it will create a
query for you
at the top
so this allows us to learn so what is
let's say icmp checksum what is the name
of that field let's do prepare filter
selected
we know that it's icmp dash checksum
pretty convenient because we didn't have
to look through pages and pages of
fields name
so uh did i i just sweared on the stream
i'm sorry and here sorry
um so we want data so let's select data
and then i'm gonna do all of what i just
mentioned after i drop the mic
okay so we have our data here
interesting everything is separated by
one line it's very neat but now i need
to scale that up another thing i want
you guys to learn
ipython or interactive python console is
powerful
ipython notebook is like
powerful and documentation at the same
time if you guys never use this stuff
you you should learn it and it's called
jupiter notebooks now but we're going to
use a jupiter notebook
to solve
that challenge
so i don't know if you know about this
but uh jupiter notebook's pretty pretty
cool so we can do like you know uh okay
it's markdown i'm gonna write i never do
this but for the demonstration purposes
i will i'm gonna document what i'm doing
so you can embed markdown directly into
it but the other cool thing is so this
is python basically okay but
the ipython kernel allows you to mix
with common line so let's do that
the syntax for it is uh
exclamation mark so exclamation mark
everything that comes after is executed
in a shell okay and uh you can assign it
to python variables
this is sick right because shell script
usually are nightmare to
maintain because no one documents them
properly now you can mix them with code
and just focus on the interesting bit
and have markdown for your documentation
around it's pretty pretty neat so now we
have this and we know that this as a
list in python will be easy to process
so now in the next couple of steps what
i want to do is since it's four six four
six four six uh four c4 c4c and stuff
like that i'm gonna
gonna grab just the last two character
of every line but but not every line
necessarily every line out of two so
we're gonna do this together
so as i was saying i'm going baby steps
right so i figured out that extracting
the last two character is
is to use
dash minus two column with anything and
this is in python to say start from the
the last go back two characters and and
adding the column means but i want to
get the rest of the string up till the
end so this way you get the last two
character now i do i did this for one
item because i wanted to confirm that it
works but if we uh if we do again a list
comprehension you can do that on all
lines so let's do that
oh okay now i have it in the the way i
was interested in having but now i still
have it duplicated is there a shortcut
to get rid of every uh one out of two in
python there is and luckily i googled
this before uh being here so for me it
will look easy but it's not quite easy
but there actually lists take three
parameter beginning and and then kind of
this iterator fancy iterator so we're
gonna do uh just that in order to
extract one out of two
fields in the data list
okay we're getting closer to a solution
so we clean that up so now what we have
is x
for the characters that we are are that
we want to do now let's just run on top
of this uh chr so that we get the the
character value associated with with
this x
and the programmers in the room will
know that this is not gonna work but i'm
still doing it
and the reason i say that is because i
recognize the boston key party people at
the back and i know that they're gonna
laugh about my programming and my stuff
here i'm teaching ctf 101 guys
okay so the reason it fails is because
the character i extracted were out of a
console so it will fail because it's
considered text so now i need to cast
this somehow into an
integer because chr expect integers
so hint in python 3 in the the hint
method
they added a very nice convenience
function where you can
set the base so you basically pass the
string to the end and you say it's base
16 and so it will interpret it as the
proper integer in the proper base and
then you pass chr into it and then we're
gonna do the trick we did last time
we're gonna join that list on an empty
string which will assemble it for us
and then we'll have the flag
so again doing this uh
from the pcap would have been faster but
now you've learned about uh ipython
notebook the fact that it's kind of
documenting itself and the fact that you
have the recipe for later so it's a
pretty neat tool chain that i like to
use a lot in in work and in ctfs
there was a monthly hack yesterday
evening
about
embedding
radar the reverse engineering tool
inside ipython so you could have like
interactive easy to share web-based
reverse engineering toolkit inside of
a jupyter notebook which is pretty sick
when you think about it
okay moving on the crackme so
the goal of that crack me okay
is
so that you're not scared
and we're not gonna understand all of
what we're gonna look at now okay
actually we're gonna understand very
little of what we're gonna look at but
the idea is that
we're gonna open tools that are scary
and that the first time i opened them i
closed them i was like i think i
infected my computer right it's so
weird full of zeros and ones and
and
the the guys doing the reverse
engineering are so better than me that
i'm not gonna ever do that it's too
complicated
uh but that's not true
you can take it bite size
uh pun intended i guess or not but you
can take it you know little by little
and uh sometimes the challenges are
quite easy it's just the way to approach
it not being scared and uh and taking
you know baby steps and this one is a
particularly easy one you can do it in
statsic you can do it in dynamic uh it's
it's quite easy
to
to approach actually
let's do it
so first we're going to look at it
statically so statical static analysis
means without executing anything
and so for that we're going to use
guidra
i used to joke about the nsa having
access of my computer but now uh they're
friends uh i forgot snowden
i i forgot them
bad joke is it too soon i don't know but
snowden in russia
you know
okay
it complains i don't know why
yeah
i know it doesn't exist
give me a break
all right
i
don't want that
okay
so gabriel wants you to set a project
and you you haven't
added the binary to it yet but you open
it it's java it takes a while
uh it's pretty powerful though and uh
ida pro is like a three grand this is
free so
who wants either pro except those that
can afford it
uh uh uh let's go let's load that crack
me okay nice and what i like about
modern tools like that is that for
someone stupid like me
you can go and look at the
the
the decompiler like i'm not even a c
programmer it's not true that i will
understand the assembly right
so why is there an error okay so some
libraries are not found
it's gonna make me running it
complicated
okay so now we we opened it okay we have
access to all that stuff the
important pieces are exported the the
calls
that the operating system makes to run
your code it needs something to be
exported so the first thing you want to
look at when you open a binary like that
is the export table where where what
stuff that is exported to the operating
system everything that starts with an
underscore you should ignore right and
oh in this specific case you saw in the
browser that there were two files so
there's one that is dash hard and
there's one that is regular so the dash
art is
stripped so what this strip means it
means that to save space in the 70s they
decided that we should remove symbols
because the machine doesn't need them
and so it means that there is no human
readable strings in the
in the the file itself
what except if you print stuff and you
know stuff that interacts with the user
but so things like this would not have
nice strings that are readable instead
it would be just f with an address an
address of the in the binary
so
we're doing the easy version here but
oftentimes you'll have stripped binaries
unfortunately for the the real reverse
engineering challenges
um okay so all of this is exported so
it's it's more than anticipated but
there's a name that stands out and it's
called main
so we're gonna click on main
so now we see the the uh the assembly
of the main function but uh let's let's
take a look at the the compiled it's
it's it's better
so now we see okay buffer printf
dramatic oh a function called dramatic
what is dramatic when i look at it oh
it's a for loop with a sleep
and then it's writing a
put char on something
can i cast it as something else here
so in char this is a dot so it's
basically
doing a dot
for how many times
it's not clear it's from perimeter all
right it's coming from the main let's go
back
so it should oh dramatic three so it
will print basically three dots
separated by sleep and then
uh x10 is carriage return so uh x10 is
decimal but uh 10 is carriage return
so you'll see okay after that a courage
return okay
okay
so far it's safe like i could run it if
i want to
so that's good
then
compute okay what does compute do
oh compute is a lot scarier
there is a bunch of stuff in it uh here
you know crypto mumble jumbo then
there's shawn function here
and then some comparison
yeah
anyway it's returning md what's md md oh
it's a malloc so it's a buffer
okay okay
compute is scarier let's move on
and then oops
and then it prints the flag the
beginning of the flag and then raise
what is raise
well when you don't know about a
function in the c library you can always
use man pages to find what it is so
let's do that
okay so the
the
programming api of the c library is in
the section three of the man page so you
because raise has other man pages of
stuff
higher level you need to specify that
you are interested in section 3.
so
send a signal to the caller so basically
this will send the signal to my process
which means that it can destroy it or
it up right which is not what we
want
so we have to keep that in mind for
later
then uh it looks like it's gonna print
so it's printed flag and then it's about
to print but there's this
damn raise at the middle
and then put char another carriage
return okay you know what i've seen
enough i'm ready to run it i'm not
scared i'm no longer scared that i'm
gonna infect myself by the way i don't
recommend this doing this in
in most ctfs here nordsec is friendly
nothing will destroy your computer
unless it's clearly written in the
challenge description description but
there are some ctfs out there that have
been known to have malware or
destructive payloads so always do this
stuff in a vm
usually
so i'm making it executable and then i'm
going to run it
and we're going to look what's going on
performing intense computation the
dramatic function and then flag
segmentation fault core dump
damn it okay there's a raise
so
i could
then
do
several things i could finish to
understand statically what's going on
and solve it
purely in a mathematical fashion so
there is data that is performed in
compute and then this data is printed to
the screen but there's something in
between so i could do this purely
statically
and because it's launch hours soon i
won't do that
otherwise we could patch the binary
so we could remove the raise statement
and then re-execute it without it this
is
uh
involves patching it out so changing
whatever the the call is by not and it's
kind of involved uh so i'll show you
another way dynamically but so signals
are uh caught by
the uh the processes and the process
have an opportunity to do something with
them
by default most signals will have a
process terminate
and a debugger
is a layer on top of your process that
catches your your signal and in the
debugger you can tell it to ignore them
so we're going to do is we're going to
run
that binary inside the debugger
and see
what we can do with that signal
so the classic debugger is a gdb and i i
happen to have a pawn dbg
uh
wrapper around it so it's a lot more
verbose
and a lot more reverse engineering
oriented so uh by default gdb doesn't
have anything about uh the
machine code
you basically usually use gdb along with
source code so
because it's an open source operating
system you have source code but so
i advise people who are getting serious
into reverse engineering and solving
challenges like that they should install
either
phone dbg or jeff
g
e f
or there's another one there's like
three one that are competing severely
right now
uh they all have pros and cons but me
i'm lazy i use pawn dbg since while
okay so
we're gonna run this so r then enter
so it started and we can see we have the
output and then
what did it say what did it say
oh it says program received six seven
segmentation fault so basically the the
raise three is a segmentation fault that
is sent to the os and the os sends it
back to the process
now since i'm in the debugger i this is
basically a trap and it gives me it
plugs the process shows me the state of
the stack so this this is the state of
the registers
then you have the code that is running
right now
and then you have the stack there's a
lot this is a lot right
we're not going to go through this it's
it it would need basically a ctf 101 on
its own it's a lot to understand a lot
of stuff
um but so what we need to understand uh
the easy route if you wanna if you want
me to say is that
there's a the operating system sent a
signal and in the debugger you have the
opportunity to ignore that signal so
this is the dynamic way
lazy way of solving that challenge and
so let's do that
so we're just going to continue
and then boom we're getting the printf
so basically the raise instruction uh
the raise function was ignored and so we
have the the thing but if we remember
correctly we had the flag dash before
and it's the segmentation fault that
added the carriage return
so
we
basically need to append flag dash to
what the output that we got so let's do
that
and this concludes
nicely ctf 101 and i'm right on time i
think
maybe i'm too short i don't know was i
supposed to be three hours or two
hours don't check i want to finish now
at one aha no but okay so
you guys you wanted me do you want me to
do it statically so do you want me to do
the crypto by hand and arrive at the
same result i can do that if you want
but if you want to have lunch you can go
and have lunch
says you choose
i see no one leaving i'll feel compelled
to do it statically
no no no no so i will i will do it like
let's say it's malware
so you don't want to run any of it
because you because they could hide a
lot of stuff in the start and everywhere
right if it's if you don't trust it so
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
focus on the compute function i'm going
to reproduce the crypto that they're
doing there i haven't done this in a
while uh so it might
not work we'll see
uh but uh and then i'm gonna try to do
that and see what uh what's the result
now
this looks like a stack canary
uh
because of the fs access uh cpu uh
thingy
forgot what it's named um
so and it's compared after the function
and if it's it's not valid it does a
stack check fail so i'm going to ignore
that part now the
the beginning of what is sent to sha 1
is
local 48 so it starts here so what i'm
going to do is i'm going to append all
of this together do i need to append 14
14 is the length yeah 40
no that's not it
where is 14 maybe it's happened okay
we'll try with and wait out so i'm gonna
basically just extract all of that hex
and then i'm gonna show on the thing and
we're gonna see if we arrive at the same
result
okay
so what i did is and i
started my ipython notebook
i did a really rough proof of concept
that i can hash bytes so the b here
means that i'm passing bytes now it
looks like a string but soon it's not
going to be a string then i'm doing a
digest on it so hopefully this will
yield to the same
uh
end result then
what i'm
trying to that that what is happening in
the c in the the crack
i'm more and more scared that this is
not gonna work
oh i forgot the column the the quotes
okay now this is
raw strings
this is
this gonna be enough
okay
hey
i don't think this is what
we expected
let's compare
b
five five four eight eight b five four
eight eight okay so i tried and
downwards i'll try upwards
i don't think it's gonna work so there's
something and it could be indian-ness
and it could be
uh the way that geidra is presenting the
information i might need to look better
or the way the assembly is because guy
draw is showing me something but it
might not necessarily be
uh and i forgot do i have i have a
source code somewhere let's let's take a
look at the source code
that is cheating by the way so shouldn't
supposed to have the source code but i
don't want to end like that
okay so it was a it is a string so it is
it's a printable
uh thing that we're doing here that guy
draw can't figure it out so okay let's
try to convert it as such
yeah you see so that this is interesting
and this is actually a good lesson in uh
challenges like that so some somehow
the way the compiler transformed this
and and it might be for a lot of
different reasons that i don't know
compiler and themselves are fascinating
but the compiler decided that this is
way too inefficient and it's gonna just
use
registers to build that string so that
you can pass it to the sha1 function
but by doing so it makes them
look like this in the the disassembly
and then even in assembly they're
basically you know
raw
uh
raw x and i think they are backwards and
i think this is why it's not working
like 73
6 f 75 73 20 6 f75
no it's not it doesn't make sense 20
would be space but oh sk20 maybe not
okay
so
sorry
come on
hex 20.
printable
okay but okay so
do i have either
so we'll look at it and either instead
see if it's any different
compute
all right the stack
strings are here aha here we can
actually
cast it as a string okay
so if we do so
we can see that it's upside down
and again you know
it's probably the way the machine works
it points to a memory region and then uh
because it's a show on expects a buffer
so it's like this buffer starts here and
goes here and it's probably writing to
it in reverse
but then
once we'll have
all of the strings
upside down
so uh
there is no way
you are
ever
going to
figure this
out okay so let's write this in my
python instead
where is it here one second
okay
is there so capital and then no
exclamation nothing okay let's do that
uh whoops it's not the byte string i
need to add the b here let's go
and we got b54 so this looks like we got
it right let's do it and i think since i
already submitted
i
should have still like already submitted
or something
yeah
okay so you have to trust me uh on that
one because it says basically you
already submitted
even if you put the right or the wrong
answer
but uh
it is another way of doing it statically
unfortunately from geidra uh it was it
is a little bit difficult the way they
cast this into a char is not helping
us realize that it's a string but if we
would have realized it was a string
maybe oh
here it is look at it look at it
so
in the c code it's bad
but
in the the
assembly view it's okay
so it's possible without paying three
grand to do that
and this concludes
ctf 101 101 i'll uh i'll hang around a
little bit and feel free to come and see
me if you have any questions i hope you
learn at least a thing or two or two
this is the objective here so
and thank you for your participation
[Music]
is
um