[Music]
so my talk today is how secure is this
thing anyway a guide into bug bounties
and mobile security okay so a little
about me I'm originally from the Bay
Area so I'm from Berkeley California
which is not too far from San Francisco
California and I currently reside in
Charlotte North Carolina I've been there
for the past 10 years I worked as a
penetration tester with the focus on app
set and I've always been interested in
mobile and decided to take the plunge
this year at the beginning of this year
and you can find me on Twitter at the
fluffy double-oh-seven
the goal of this presentation is I want
everyone to become empower to start your
journey into bug bounties if you so
desire so just to give ok so just to
give a little background on this here I
jumped in the beginning of this year and
I participated in a bug bounty weekend
group with hacker one and I had that
expression the whole weekend it was like
what did I get myself into
why but I learned a lot and I found that
when most people they have that same
expression as well okay at this fiber so
the images used in this presentation are
not from actual bug bounties programs
and the reason I'm doing that
for most of them have non-disclosure
agreements and I'm not trying to get in
trouble so this library so what is about
bounties
so a bug bounty is where you can find
vulnerabilities for a specific company
for instance here we have Credit Karma
this is from bugcrowd so essentially
what they do is they provide a short
synopsis of the company also tell you on
the right how many vulnerabilities have
we rewarded validation is after you
submit a report the validating is to
make sure that is actual a true is
actually a true bug and in this case it
takes within four days and 75% of
submissions are accepted or rejected
within the four day period and it gives
you an average payout so in this
instance the average payout was 250
dollars and okay so here it lists the
ranges per for nur ability so two two
hundred to five thousand the five
thousand will be for a more critical bug
like SQL injection in similar bugs so
the types of bug bounties you have
reward and swag so for reward
compensation based based on the
vulnerability and platform and higher
the severity hired the payout so what do
I mean by that so if you look on the
right-hand side of the slide oh crap
sorry too ambitious here on the right
side you will notice that for api's I
an Android a p1 which is signifies a
critical you could you pay 5,000 whereas
if you find it on the website it is 3000
so again so P ones are critical P twos
are high P 3s or medium mp4s are low so
higher the severity higher the payout
you would notice the p4 is 250 whereas
the p1 is 5000 swag so with other
companies and lieu of giving you money
they like to give you prices incidence
clothes hats shirts hoodies gadgets
backpacks and stickers on this picture
here is sample swag I'm sure anyone who
has gone to a conference you've picked
up somewhere before from the different
members ok but bouncy steps here is from
hyper one so this is a guidance for
companies that are thinking about going
into the bug bounty space so level one
is a company that is just entering the
worked out in their program and their
mature you will notice that as for the
criticals the more mature the bug bounty
program the more the payout is ok so to
talk a little bit about mobile devices
because that is part of the talk so I'm
sure
majority of the majority of you have a
little device so you know they're great
you could do a lot of stuff look at bank
information shop if you want to browse
the Internet to you and browse social
media so wow this is great for your
device these are the different attack
their attack vectors from now secure so
it's broken up into the actual device
the network in cloud data center so as
you can see while your device you can do
many lovely things
it is very there's not secure so there's
many things you can do for instance you
can do SMS phishing texted fishing for
apps you know system data storage intent
hijacking GPS spoofing you know this is
the attack surface for mobile devices so
as you can see there's a lot of ways to
hack into your homes
ok so my top would be on Android I have
Android so to give a little bit of
background with Android devices they are
severely fragmented what does that mean
whoa Android is open source and the
fragmentation comes in where mobile
providers can add
some cold on top of the Android
operating system for specific devices so
for instance and if I have a phone and
for this sample Android window sighs I
don't like it I'm like it doesn't work
for my phone is too small I can go and
modify that for my specific device so
well that sounds really really good the
problem with that is it leads to
interoperability issues meaning that you
depending on the device to you can have
two devices that don't have the same
code and that comes into play when you -
but bug bounties because you realize hey
wow you know if the Galaxy s8 you know
is secure the s6 might not be for s7 so
to give a little bit about Android
security it is based on the Linux kernel
it provides the following security
features of a user race permission model
process isolation and the ability to
remove unnecessary and potentially
insecure part of the kernel so
application sandboxing so how this works
is you can ask isolate X from each other
it assigns that unique user ID to each
Android application in words that his
own process uses this UI need to set up
the kernel level application sandbox
forces security between that and system
at the process level to abused our group
IDs that are assigning 2x by default
can't interact with each other and have
limited access to the operating system
application assigning so this allows
developers to identify the author of the
application that provides a more
streamlined process to update the
application every application that runs
on the Android platform must be signed
by the developer an application is that
attempt to install on a device without
the inside rejected by Google Play
that's the repository for Google X or
the package installer application
assignment is the first step to placing
an application in the application
sandbox assigning defines the user ID is
associated with the application and
different applications marking the
different user IDs so let's talk about
the importance of routing the device so
Android only allows a small subset of
applications to run with root
permissions Android does not stop users
or applications or modifying the
operating system kernel organ the other
application so if you had a root you
have full access to the application and
all application data on that device
users that allow applications to run as
root increase their direct exposure to
malicious applications and application
flaws so now I'm going to talk about
components of
application activities services content
providers and broadcast receivers so an
activity represents a single screen with
a user interface this is similar to a
window and a desktop application and the
application can contain one or more
activities a service is a
general-purpose entry point for keeping
the application running in the
background this is not a user interface
performs long write operations are
performed remote processes so for
instance examples internet downloads and
data processing then you have content
providers which supplies data from one
application to others on request
centralized content in one place and
allows different applications to access
it so a common example of this will be
blank database broadcast receivers of
response to system-wide broadcast
announcements these messages are called
events or attempts so an example of this
will be when you've turned off the
screen on your device or if you have a
low battery so I wanted to talk about a
apk tool for a second so it's a tool
that allows you to invert
reverse-engineer third-party apps can
decode resources close to original form
you can reveal the application
after modification so for instance you
can be decompile the application make
changes and then we recompile with your
changes to see if it's there
so after D compelling JPK you'll have
the following folders small e
rest veterans and the bow into our
manifest XML so for smiley you could
think of this as a simply language used
by the Android dalvik virtual machine
and decompose through ad expound is used
for low-level inspection excuse me up a
Natori at content so again I like to
think of it as assembly most people
don't look at the small e Android is
based on Java you build it with Java
code coating with Java so most people
will just looking at the Java source
code but other people who are very
ambitious they might like to look at the
small team to figure out the logic of
the application so right this is the
folder for additional files and static
content such as images
layout definitions user interface
strings and animation strings and the
meta gem folder contains the following
files the SERP de Artes a SERP die
except
mm so the first is assigned contents of
the cert SFL along with the cert
certificate chain of the public key used
to sign the contents the cert SF
contains a list of all files along with
a sha-1 hash and then the manifest
contains information for the application
such as package versions Bureau number
and creator of the package with the
Android manifest this is located at the
root of the project every Android
application has an Android manifest file
and so this file declares components
such as the package of application
it describes the components of the
application activities services
broadcast receivers and content
providers declare permissions the
application must have in order to
interact with protected api's and other
applications and I declared the middle
level of the Android API that the
application requires so we have a sample
Android manifest so here the manifest
describes the package here the minimum
level of Android that needs to run on
that the minimum level of Android for
this
right in this case is number two so it's
like the very first operating system of
Android also the activity is defined
here have intense here along with
actions and categories so to switch back
to counties for a second so you it's
like okay I want ease I think I wanted
to Android found an app I think I found
a loaner ability you want to do Android
so the reason why I specified Android is
because again it's an open source
platform it is a lower entry to pick
Lord intrusive barrier as opposed to the
iOS with the iOS that code is
proprietary and it belongs to Apple so
not saying that you cannot do bug
bounties with iOS is it's just a little
harder so you might be thinking okay why
honey so there are multiple programs
ranging from different sizes from small
to large sample programs you have
defense Apple and Facebook and so when
getting started with bug bounties I tell
people to focus on programs that are
small so because most people are going
[Music]
because with those easier already you
know so I would say reporting is
probably the most important part the
process and the reason I say that is
because there are a lot of people who
found really sexy you know
vulnerabilities but they didn't convey
it and apart in the proper way and the
company was like not loved so when
composing your report you should be
thinking about business impact to the
company meaning okay if a attacker was
able to find this what can they do
can they you know steal all your data
you know what's the impact was you know
it's a awesome reputation you know you
need to think and the terms of the
climate the business and when you think
of that
most times your report will be accepted
awesome
if you find you know you submit your
really good report and you get a
response in this leg hey it's the
duplicate someone you know around us
before you did
don't be discouraged I mean that just
shows that you're on the right track
so you know keep going summer someone
just beat you first when you know doing
bug bounties you know make sure it's the
same notes because you realized with
different platforms different group
different companies you might have
encountered a similar bug and if you
don't have notes you have to rely you
know so similar to this let me see what
I did in my five for that new so
involved with gravities reading products
as possible once again with bug bounties
there is no disclosure and non public
disclosure so what that means is will
public disclosure the company's like oh
yeah you know write a report you know
how you found this bug right and you'll
find other companies there
like well no don't don't release how you
found this you know won't pay you but
don't release and take the plunger to
bug bounties to also there's tutorials
Heffron one has the CTF and after you
accumulate a certain number of points I
think the first is 26 then you start
getting invited to actual bug bounty
programs so I think that's really cool
and then you have but proud University
that teaches you different securities ok
engineering and Android application
using the Olas testing so here are using
an android emulator called android x86
most times we if you're going to do
android reverse engineering where
android apps you will really want to
have the actual physical device but for
this demo i'm using an emulator
machine so here so just to give a quick
disclaimer I did this demo like 30 times
I didn't do that when I first started so
I'm starting from A to Z so that's why
I'm installing it here so after this I
am going and type I have to fear so
essentially I need to get the IP address
because I have another personal machine
that I need I need my emulator in my
virtual machine to talk so I'm getting
that IP address so I can use that inside
not other virtual machine so the 192 168
56 1/2 so this is my other virtual
machine here and I'm using adb Android
debug bridge so and I'm connecting to
the Android emulator so it connected
successfully also I'm using freedom
which is a dynamic and now analysis tool
where you can change the logic and
[Music]
Android applications in real time so we
will be using that shortly
so right now I'm pushing the server to
my emulator and starting as brew and
then I'm already connected but I just
did that for sanity check and again
going going into the shell of my Android
emulator and I'm going to change the
permissions for the Freedom Summer and
then I'm going to start it now I'm
putting the uncrackable app on my
android emulator so next I will go and
install it so I set it to the download
folder inside the emulator
this unknown apps are you sure you want
to install so installing the app now I'm
going to run it in old route has been
detected
this is unacceptable that app is now
going to exit so it stopped us so next
what I'm going to do is show that yes I
am connected the emulator is connected
and then I'm going to use Frida to look
for the part on the different processes
and make sure that the uncrackable
wasn't cooked using Frida which it was
now I am opening
jadx Bui which is a decompiler for
Android apps and for this you can sorry
you can use source code so that's what
you're doing now you're viewing the
source code for that so once again this
is written in Java just a quick note
when you're when you you know D compound
you're not going to get the full Java
code what a lot of companies do is they
use authorization so the reason that
they do that is so because they don't
want it to where when you compile their
application you have the keys to the
kingdom and know how the application
works so what they'll do
though a few states the code and make it
rude hard for you to try to
reverse-engineer you can reverse
engineer after scanning cold I know
with its Android studio they have Pro
Bowler widget which is an option alpha
station tool that should be used to
deoxy scape apps so here we are we use
freedom and now we have bypass that
route has been detected so and I'm going
to show the code and a little bit so
essentially we have bypassed that so now
we need to figure out what is the secret
string so going back to the application
we notice that there is a base64 decode
to the right along with we're using a
site work so next we need to figure out
the string and we're going to use this
code here to get that so next I'm going
to run freida again to get the secret
string
now for this to work I need to go back
to the app and type in anything so at
this point I'm going to type in your
text and it's going to say nope 98
try again going back to the terminal we
have the passcode which is I want to
believe
so now you know success we enter the
correct secret so now I'm going to show
the actual code to make this possible so
with freedom i'm using javascript but
we're freedom to use python and other
languages I just use JavaScript for this
example and so essentially what I did so
essentially what I did was simply
override those methods and have them
return false so essentially for the root
privileges that logic was returning true
that's why that dialog box came up it
was like route detected so I set those
to false to bypass that and then I also
overrode the 880's cold so created an
array and then essentially once typing
in any text basically changing it into
the character equivalent and having the
string be presented to us inside the
terminal
so just showing basically the overriding
overriding those methods
okay so the last little bit is just
basically showing how to use the apk to
the d4d compound so essentially I'm
going to decompile the uncrackable level
one application just showing just how
you know how you would use the apk to
move and then showing some of the
folders that I talked about small e
bread and the Android manifest that XML
then again and really can't see that was
just the XML describing the intense and
everything for that application
so summary the attack vector for our
mobile devices local apps and devices is
wider barrier to entry is loved with
Android you know you can decompile
Android apps and look under the hood bug
bounties are not a one-size-fits-all
freedom you know as a good tool to use
for dynamic analysis as you can change
logic on the fly and there is no silver
bullet
application with mobile security so I
created an intro to Android security VM
so it has two additional apps the
insecure bank in the hacking playground
I will add the debug and secure app and
the next release so to use it
push the apps to the emulator using
Android debug bridge also I'm working
with try Hackney which is a online
hacking company to add the videos to the
site but if you want to download the
video you can go to source board and URL
is right here and just resources and
suggested reading and
you