I've been working on it and until I'm
working I'm the exodus and a hero who I
was with hey I'm DX which is why we let
me talk about today so that the first
out of this August is about what amvx is
how it works and some problems i wiII
happen we try to do next whether the
second happen is all going to be about
what kind of problems are still in there
what does we won't and what what what's
needed to definitive so its impacts on
atiq late a molar movie because of the
desktops
Oh
you reign her output mode setting Mattie
this is the deal Figgis a most improper
library yeah
the night
thank you
so the reckless did the normal rate for
the eggs uber is that Kevin and
friend request in to me ok and
difficulty exit connection bc egg
containing different movements and then
takes after a little bit performs an
essay come here so the right thing that
was trying to the next time you go so
and this is this is a little comparison
that it is over hat and this is what
allows us to work over a network and
remote is made over here in canada the
90 and maybe send a pandemic respect so
with an NGO we open gyoza possibly the
3d and graphics API is available on all
platforms and if you want to use over
here under Deano GX this is
and instead of the extension to specify
how old he'll text yes sir th month and
in this case then connects has two basic
modes of operation SC indirect lower
operational piece which is pretty much
how X formally works and there's a
director so in this case that s the
application wants to be rendering sting
link things to give that kid GL which
this is similar to what amazes when you
render regulate requester links to this
one here like with in internet votes he
found the dx11 works in a very remote
the library razon performed very much
the same time as we takes a level that
is if you want to render this 3d model
you send all the 3d triangles and your
sense of textures and gives has into
detail pls take this hundred request and
network like SNL DX over and again the
extras on the other cells network will
increase connection receives the regular
office and hasn't been
man the way it used to work was that in
this entire case where the xserve
receives the random offense over the
network and the XO would have a correct
implementation of the year yeah so you
want to rather try to enforce a software
so do scale integration of the triangle
and perform the text of the box and
regular to trying it step by step this
won't be done in software and it makes
me live the only limitation recover this
one is the screen and that's also waste
know that if you have a factory so some
40 are indirect granular slow and 10
software and data by noon which is your
case was a fantastic ok so I'm not
rebounding from adam to incur game
because it's done yes I'd we don't talk
to over
alright so so as I mentioned that lesson
has another mode of operation for for
the on GL finding this is the diamond
book and in this case
alright that's a tiny spot so this is
the award BTW we match the answer in
case another nation to UGL just painted
the entire case is where the application
talks to the GH come on wigs for them
and take the regular first panel over
here to the xserver well Felix module
receives the vm their requests in Santa
Costa and since the simply renders
replacing to the gym karate and this
this is a software rasterization house
home about the tanks the triangles do
this kind of information and original
copies if the consciousness cream the
other cases is a dollar case and this is
this is where we reside / tuned to
deviate from how the excellent only
works in this case what we end up with
is a driver eh to moving Nate into the
drive so we have education up here but
they need to live here but then ask
attractions is not rendering then
there's a local author then step in the
yield sahabat alternator and if it asks
the xserve atheism and a terrific
because that's usually the preferred
mode of a break it is the excellences
yes I could do that until not half a key
name of private reload and the address
of the rainbow so so it is part the
client actually no square member the
frame of this we're trying to look in
the system to noted the genomic the
drivers yes is yellow with them d lotus
and in each lattice
so in this part we actually have the
driver for the hardware disco instantly
the client and the car starts somebody
pregnant requests into the driver into
the clinical all the different so we
received a rating of Christmas the iPod
which instead of style soccer well
program Harper to gratify some tracks or
the triangles SS necessarily set up
pointless to the textures swimming naked
video everything in them written
everything on screen directly and the
acer basically doesn't doesn't know what
can happen because it just asked out the
paper project and and the the diagonals
of to do all right so there's a tiger in
case and since this is harper and we
load the driver the times i had from in
the hopper and then the hopper doesn't
mean this is a source of service with
the fat render connection between me and
follow time in your adrenaline was the
XOXO doesn't happen but it is is it is
hardly some someone because you
solutions think the only video she have
a Knicks so if you have a next window
you can run into your ex is in talks
reason and you drank another window the
top of you
with the director has to a state that
window and so you had your surrender
across your external whatever it's your
you having trouble can talk show
yourself whenever whenever the windows
move for the tip Rex chains there's that
civilization going on between the
diagram cloud and Exum so some dexter
assess most you have to be read the
fittest and whenever the diagram time is
ready to do some reading goes and we
doing to campus so that it doesn't all
right does the English okay so
accelerator interest which is what 8 on
your license is the case where we made
1px over to note the Opera and use the
harbor drive to implement any requests i
became committee so we want to do you
want to make the extra work away if you
know the dusk on all is good because
won't use the previous work but then the
reason why we have direct window in the
first place is that and we want the
phones and we'll do the xserver with the
normal version we don't really need that
much performance and the overhead or we
need performance but we avoided for
continued in imagining
in network access is negligible compared
to actual rendering especially if you
have to fall back to software so when
you see you XO being slow if you're
storing the story at pho red rhinestone
is terrific first we have to fall back
to software operating software so
because we have too much time sending it
or a tankful no waste software fell back
but 400 you know we never do something
is always mostly always Harper and since
we're running crate you want the biggest
possible spread wait a second they're
tearing everything matters so we can
avoid the net we access here we might
get one to make some frames per second
wait and then that's one of the reasons
we sung is most compatible so the
question is which we have data better
which is faster than the innervation and
it does to say why we want to fix
everything and there's a few reasons we
both item listen collects it's taking a
role which is which is probably the
timer grab underneath this work so for
companies the combustion render cupcakes
is an OpenGL application that renders
the entire screen the entire desktop
using
deal and the dust so using the
compositing center what the compositing
center allows you to the sample you take
the contents of the window and nobody
went times the applications running to
win any cleaner it's render the right
into the frame of pleased to see the
contents of a large penis as the
applications render what the message
does this is all that rendering and
without the application know themselves
all the regular guy happens to the
office paper so the dedication we going
to remember any requests and the
excellent for these minor arrests or if
you want actually appear on the screen
as you sleep it will go into an
all-school boxes this is why he wants or
needs on this mini river because we
don't need million of these oxygen
bubbles but that's the dissident up we
give this practice very clever quickly
because that allows us then to determine
how we gonna composite however for my
knees off your buffers on screen and
this is where stuff I transparent window
the pedometer also meant because we do
this in a second step where you have
then use an extra channels and injure in
the pic map TT selling the transparency
sticks and then equally scalar windows
SS SS computer and then what are the
cases of these possibilities and
companies actually have another / to go
from your food defense to something how
the negative
for every we need some way to go from
the pic map in external media room or
anything so to end text it to text that
that we can use for NGO to render and
this is this isn't live is it takes from
global attention this context and pizza
not related this was this is a sentence
let's allow a detection so as SNS keep
few questions when we talk about doing a
title next yield to him probably not
feasible because semi education two
different only limitation but conclude
it this way once we have overkill ex
already available inside yourself we can
do this piecewise that's a regulation
accelerate say XD using OTL we can do
that for one driver where we have that
feature able if not something we can do
the compositing for any visual here in a
specific travel we can enable that and
easy so it may be a rose up a lot of
this work in fact the excimer and as
such this is some it is this an ad- and
and of course they able to take you use
exhilarating opium across a network is
you have your free having a server that
s the political arena driving infection
and exhilarating eggs on a desktop and
run the application from it from act and
a foundation server support those of the
GPU accelerated in this case of course
the canyon on this case is that if you
have takes just like you have to say we
take us through the network without
rendering you can't we can download the
protection separated because climate
progress on the same cosmic space but
overall the misery in rate exorcism is
interesting because we we we can then
accelerate these positive manner that
Google uses state so all of it is so
from from an to 20,000 feet perspective
this is easy we have been completely
there's an X or don't do I got in pretty
much same way that the kind would notice
you are similar and another this is the
top that you did such a fine just the
exit will set up to southeast but Emily
we can at the exit you support and
divert me refresh your frame of their so
a king from going on between this line
is the xserver turns out all this is now
just in terms of the excuse so we can
just go into given our next person to
say when you support a direct question
finger so only see plays a subjective
another smoke from going out and hit the
wire and then the Exuma already has a
module infrastructure so we we can use
dildo in the exhibition to go to the
right on making it and any comment and
when it we need to provide some from
functionality to the dr I browser so
that no matter how into the exhibit for
for various pieces of information and
in general it is business tactic just a
better deal opening the driver live
tweeting interfaces to to make sure that
the drunk and get impatient with me for
the external my first yeah gotta skip
this slide this is about how we
initialize official kind of messy but it
was made it before if so what one of the
more interesting case of problems and
we're a nation is what was then the
island so in a case when we have direct
winner we have an avocation way that
notes the driver too much you program
the hopper so this miserable seats to
the Opera 241 friends of triangles the
same time we have the exit over here
soon say who will bit around by from the
matter to copy what happen to us so both
these applications are trying to access
the same hardware and programming 15
things so we need to synchronize this in
some way and and and then way to do this
to list for the people knock around
whole things so that's the way it works
is that the DI driver knows that has to
synchronize X stenography knows that
there might be different di funny you
didn't have to cover some seriously have
quite over here
if you can have several times and at the
same times and you need to respect that
so that your I'd rather then no decline
to do the regular already OSIS details
when they write about you too many uses
it once it's done on the other hand of
the XO doesn't know about the locket you
think that one without me except our
neck surgery just goes off button so
mostly browser written teacher just any
more than you expect whatever they
submit to the card is still valid next
time they come around the Platte River
that's not the case in this because you
might frontpoint one this would be the
river bit in the 80 maybe the exit is
swapped out and the dark Amerikan Gunz
and also in training for t-rex peers and
then make service walking again and now
this day is completely different from
the last time it has to happen so we
need some mechanism around this to make
sure that the XLR get confused so what
we do is s as soon as we receive
requests at request from the other side
we take the island and restore the stage
with XOX ecstasy and then we go off
again rather than a request tisha and
then when we trusted how we render all
the requests that was sitting in alcohol
and tell people we go back to sleep
original sequitur we release enough so
let's listen and people
a server and they declined to start
learning class that result you and then
this is a most efficient way to do
things for the voice and yeah as far so
the question is if this dog is a stir
the freezing when you forget about the
education creases doesn't run continue
the window and a fellow business
students because an essay deprivation to
drag it around the egg so is just
saturated with requests to moving around
and listen a bunion bootie and the
education system the other hand time to
render policies that allow you stayed
all the time especially when you're out
so does this very gratefully locked in a
way which interview so this is this is
not the most efficient way to go so we
get this but it basically words any the
better way to do this would be
I knew about it up and could only take
it for that short on time technique you
to remember which is survived a
connection press them to another or
whatever it is the XO needs to do you do
it probably see this is you go away and
only you have convention doctors
architecture where you submit and the
driver gets rid the software that is but
angry then the interesting part is it
but this lock set up we will begin to
punish wait because we're a primer then
if you are wrong with the tries to wrap
the log before classes figure it and now
we're trying to run it from within the
excess so and what happens is it the
external receives a request of the whole
thing please read the links to the
triangles and then simply goes and
cracks it up because it was that's what
it does for this is russ and then comes
into the driver to render it and then in
the eye barber will think that i need to
back it up before but the extra lonely
has a box so we have a recursive getting
up here because we try to run a crown on
their backs it up for example are so we
had to do some sun hanging on this and
then the similar way to do this is to
just see if you're a guest even the
person comes in and it turns out that
this is a three different then before
the garbage
quick just releasing our correlation
driver and now the dryer is a Democrat
adoptive endless and that will succeed
us he doesn't let go top so the driver
will be able to rent out what every
muscle in his release about and protect
the answers and the extra will then in
easily retailer in case we were about to
do some to be rich so the acyl taking on
animation in da to look back to see so
this is actually works very well means
that I hope taking and repeating with
ours is not cheap because it's not the
same about himself about restoring the
state of the graduates have to be what
makes server or the complete traffic
lights but anything in the end there's
not much of a performance energy
information here for their definitely it
should be efficient ok so the ticker
monroeville this is a big one of the big
article for doing this the big
motivation and and the thing is not a
necessity rather one in from within the
egg server memory and ever space we say
all right but they teach my parents here
because of the data business is an extra
body in this
Taylor address space and now we have you
the street in operating the expedited
space too so we can say to the drive all
right but these Peaks I've out here this
is your texture so that the
implementation is valid or not because
ok we just part to that this map and it
doesn't almost way to do this is the
best way to see if we have that picked
up sitting in Indian River on the car so
intentionally that's what the XO agility
play the video may require a visa in an
ocular on the behavior and Su render
your lips and in the ratings whatever
you do to this window that draw with
accumulated the home screen office
immediately and then when you want to
taste her we want to render and applying
a level to do safety for meditation we
have one two three then two then video
area with the decline and you said
protect me so that's the ideal case but
it doesn't work that way to them is that
initiation works but for now what we're
doing is we will just add the extra
logic to not do things you take that
time to minimize our interpreter in
whole story so whenever you usually do
your improving the overall this render
any of this revelation emotion which
Gregor and when we want to use it as a
cetacean we do text to this
area and the treatise txt downloads /
may have set up the texture so we have
this Bank volcom host memories really
love it all the time not bad for to go
from pokering cover the intervening
refund on every new option so that's
that we're doing now is halogen biggest
component automation nvm compunctions
desktops it was unit today and in 1719
faced
ah
and so they're the property with and
this is it we would like to be able to
use the same on in the media room and
the same people be aware that EXO for
instance you would like to give to you
said protected without counting things
about okay do that right now because the
way the eggs are the main story is kind
of open so we have video ever and what
happens test out of this set we take our
memory for the framework so we do sell
some of this video response rate then
what happens is that we have deriding
which we split the rest of the numerator
to pass and the XR minus one half of the
river another hazard do so so we had to
section of very angry move it around the
exodus extended theorize over the
drivers or sinus TX memory so the
problem is that will be related to two
new pieces just picture related live in
the extra half a gentleman and we want
to use it as a texture we really need to
be in the critical part of the video but
it's over the last so we can't do that
so what we like to do here is just have
one figure of memory on the car and MN
and this is what the work
talking guys to do is worth doing it a
colonel in there were men involved in
the video memory so you can have your
very delicate objects in literally all
right visits of opera and EXO is going
to rain doesn't stop into thinking it's
a big mac and then laid on you as a
device whether it's the texture and the
do I don't use that same problem in the
cultures alert to take so then the work
they do not allowed us to work if we can
head still employs take complete a quiz
you then get rid of the storm you see a
company's composite s and the other
thing is that we have some regression
functionality so the way that is dead
tari Renner works this is said and at
the beginning talk then these outlaws
man asked the xserver for the address of
the paper and then it knows the gravel
and Venice strange their paper but if we
want to get some positive yes it
shouldn't be doing that it should be
very internet peaceful uses iphone
window patterns but then the dark i do
not know about this and just premise it
to power for my sis officer and it
doesn't so no separate it looks like
it's working this is the next is running
it down removal that's what you may not
remove the window run it is obvious that
if that way and then we remove the sun
is down DJ accountable and the thing is
that copies does not any update the
extras idea for the videos until you
give the window set us down we as always
in sporting that this can we tell the
air services oddly shape so it doesn't
even try but the more you let it go its
analysis all right i got an imposition
this is where you should be ready so
it's only when actually has a decision
moves around another thing is that it
doesn't respect it lists here promise i
I think
we have a the wiggle sketching is
different because we have a big
witnessing in front of them desta so now
this love these windows visible anyway
it in the exercise that we're sitting in
front the copies does already over into
this window so we see the movie but the
be again de la drivers from specialists
and ngos presence of a more so soon so
that's something interface what was soon
would need to be here again ties into
the riverbed network because and we
regroup tell me you could only be here
i'm proud to say wait after the famous
racketeer apology with a different
address and say this is where you should
be regularly and then give it given the
address of a nothing if not we do your
quantity relative but that's not what
problems to let it just so with the
technical piece like i did we the way so
till now we actually to have this
contents in hopes terror but if we did
did it 400 it would end up in convenient
and so we couldn't easily use that we
leave a disturbance as a texture so so
that open another thing is that even
though when we look at the day with our
dinner with NBC we see this portrays a
tear or there's a concern or layers of
data Adams and O'Neil frames and like oh
you can do chocolate operate which in
which case we run into the backbone and
then when you say smoking pocket
the back cover is the focus it also has
info us that that that drank some depth
in pixels so that if you renders a new
peeps the name and that case is firm on
that piece of their already in cover but
if the peaceful nuclear energy on
Santorini Island you're just not okay
that people keep the old value in place
it's got other types of offers Stenson
buffers and then there is another
prophecy market commons allocate our
fifth child of the rate that same way
that we allocate from so so if we try to
drain into the spot where they they they
still they didn't want they don't still
keep the rendering accountants the owner
pillows and one litter boxes known as
dedicated for for for sale attempt on a
double and the means that then 3d
remedies to know how to allocate or it
doesn't know if I now just take the
child out a big screens and bottom and
then uses that so so with the memory
when their work the egg with the Dragon
will be able to clone and in the quest
and then he is powerful back offer of
depth buffer and he can then set up and
went
and also you think that's the same way
we do for regular and special needs we
have another apartment losses in Capri
narration and so so if we in da snow say
case this is when their way by so I two
windows here and this is my laptop is a
1024 x 768 screams a lot of space
between two minutes I I had to resize
them and put the next to each other or I
can usually to sync up the feature of
Howdy's this will even throw a loss or
mahogany before please get it down like
that and I get a view of all the words
of a desktop but the xls know that the
way that have been resized and moved
around like this extra the stupid the
three windows of all this full screen
size and all the system talk each other
so he if he might if I could clear his
widow the exhalation Linkletter the
mouse cursor is up here in indy of a
power window even though it looks like
it's almost in email you know what is
the necklace text you i would be picking
up here instead of someone close to them
so the departing it is that the Excel
does know that the windows if you move
round and scale access so it is tries to
english is the witness of collusion very
thin design so in this case conscious is
this clear to know about this because he
doesn't try to get me prank an icon
they're like what would we usually you
could rank pregnant item into this for
that I want to copy polygons but because
this doesn't let me do that because it
doesn't work so what are you still upset
I i can click on the window and select
the thing you should be focused and
that's sort of the limit of what you can
do and what happens is a counting
companies this drawing the window so
comfy clothes that the windows epic
scale town to town and how these can can
highlight the windows move over with the
mouse but i had actually interact with
the winners of this thing so as you
mentioned in your input we'd written
before that a method to take you next
the information instruct the extra-large
of back in with two windows so is this
whether it is shown a way of an opponent
scale down the composite america for mix
on this by sending it as SL triangle
that describes the relation between the
winner is inexcusable screen how
actually this objective so with that in
place we should be able to find again
like how we want how does mean to me so
that you do I just left super them it's
Christmas
yeah so so much space in town as support
for repair windows with on here so with
with them regular eggs when the sweet we
can request a reversal officials and
official is just data structure
describes how the pizza meal and window
is to be interrupted by later when it
was impossible is not possible to say I
want to dress for visual that has an
alpha channel so that not with the right
of being and when I sweet vs. business
transparency of pizza and then you can
use this tool to make clocks or window
like this the shape and then so what you
can out of this half is for you aight
you can't see anything through this but
in this case we have this is slightly
translucent you can see the folder on
the desktop can over here so you can do
this for regular x applications but you
want to use an open here education and
specify that you want a relationship e
opengl application let's we don't lose
all that but i don't think it would be a
proper training with this if we vary
native with the next 15 to american
render and image that has the alpha
values ahead suppose
because we just mostly have Queen
recovering and can provide alpha that is
pleased peacing it is basically just
work I don't some yeah it XP is about
regression that that we introduced with
their for muscle and because it's me
uses it it is a different story but in
the detection simple if you put in HD
and the desktop we shall move your arm
you see that the video is implicit
correct and then this is again that
vehicle e-except amuses in feature of
the outlet at last opportunity in house
based operation and it uses a color
keyed I indicate on the screen where it
should be the video solvation hidden
kitchen from reebok anything with as you
probably know and moved around their
descriptions of each other half of a
group they come to the competition today
and then the summer can only be like so
and as you moved around you don't
actually update that physicians & albert
and you cooked it it was still go to
transform us with us so to get that work
we probably need to use over here and I
know their game from has done some work
in this area and jamie has something in
his HTM swimmers from the Justice but a
alex is still there and that's something
let's go if i buy us anything yet let us
that still slow the net net net falls
down to the way we do the texture of
this crap the implications does and the
external vendors like the window family
to host memory so when you're snorting
on firefox what nobody will find what we
do to disclose right now is it would ask
the excellent to copy the area of 10
pics with our watches going and then
five us will remember that stripper yeah
but what we do now is we really eczema
has been instructed to do this posted so
this wrote to his mother now is it then
copy it also to cover the lives up in
place and then it goes and raises for
this up and in for Paul takes brendan is
upset you want to community meeting
characters into the Gamma Rho bo staffs
are you consider it is compositing into
the this case we fall back to
software to so we have composite they
will inherit and suffer so this is so
then once we've done that gets the cover
that entire from algorithm which in the
texture to bring up then you pray on the
screen so that that's a big public right
now God hopefully if we once the
government in some cases we can be handy
has rendered into one period of objects
we thank you we use an optical mixer in
it food is like you want
excellent so that's the resizing yeah
that that's more involved if it really
comes down to then some educational
resources and have a lot more practice
emoji we definitely need and a ton of
things are interesting that we do the
deposit
actually synchronize the recycler
between the educational interventions
before for those westernization you
resize video and the application would
get another piece activating try combo
and you get these half-breeds out the
window and once it