thank you well it's a huge pleasure to
be here with your today if someone can
suggest it to me three years ago that i
will be speaking for them that I'd be
representing son that I'd be talking
about John being GPL I would probably
laugh almost doesn't matter if you were
so it's it's really quite awesome to be
here talking about this for you today
what I could try and do for you is try
me as interesting as I can by not
talking for too long and getting some
other interesting people up here what
I'd like to do start off by talking to
you about why son is interested in free
software then talk to you a little bit
about the Java platform and free
software and you can use you to some of
the people who are making it happen and
then it'll go Punk thank you okay so I
know if you if you thought about that
the impact that the eight the Internet
has had on society this is if you're
using my presentation I I even enjoy
graphics so everything that I'm learning
so the structure of society for decades
have been a structurally to be
hub-and-spoke it's been government in
the middle with citizens out bespoke
tell you things done to them it's been
consumers that consumer society I always
think is a wonderful phrase it brings to
me above the Belgian idea of geeks
having called full-scale their throats
ready to be turned into foie gras that's
the consumer society hello that's all
part of this hub-and-spoke world with
people doing things controlling lee in
the middle and giving them out to people
out of soaps and when the internet
became a pervasive
necessary part of Western life this
mobile change it was no longer the case
that everyone was distributed out at the
end of spokes instead everyone was going
to everyone else and that began to
change everything now son and the Free
Software Foundation had both been
working with free software for a very
very long time if I told you about a
startup company California that use a
free operating system together commodity
hardware to introduce a computer
technology that completely came to
computer industry you might think I was
talking about something that happened in
the in the mid to late 90s but actually
I'm referring to the work of builder and
vinod khosla Annie and effect all time
and stop really in the early ages they
took bsd unix and combine it with
off-the-shelf motorola arbor to produce
the workstation category completely
disrupting the monopolistic business of
the big computer companies at the time
and that means some for the last 25
years is doing the doing that stuff and
right at the heart of what we've been
doing has been this shift to a networked
society and the Free Software Foundation
has been doing the same thing in popular
culture in developer culture has been
making sure the ability to work is not
dominated in a hub of spoke way but it's
operated in on that way and so with
society shifting to a mesh model it's
time for things to change it's time to
head into this mesh world and to take to
wave goodbye to be fought Rockies now I
don't want to be a consumer anymore I
want to be a participator and that mess
is what produces a participate name the
way that big software companies used to
make software was by hiring all smart
people and locking them in a room and
sliding pizza under the door until later
written whatever it wasn't neatly
writing and then saying tickets to get
into the room and that worked all the
time of statistically you could pass as
smart people BBC one thing still doing
those notice a long time goes you can't
hire all the smart people some of them
inevitably work somewhere else and you
know when you have a meshed society the
people that you could hire are all on a
network forming a statistically
significant unit and the people you
could I statistically around 20 and so
your software business involves having
none of the smart people working on
software in a closed room completely
against all of the smart people out on
the internet producing the same type of
software faster and better and you know
I think I know which business I would
rather be so why is Sun getting into
free software well partly it's because
of our history with free software but
also it's because we believe that the
the way businesses do software is
changing when I got into the computer
industry rather too long ago and the way
it worked was you bought a piece of
hardware and it came with all the
software you could ever possibly need it
was there on a punched tape in the
bottom of the shipping crate if you
could find it in the the huge space of
the computer and so you'd buy a computer
with all the software you could possibly
need and go deploy it and it would all
be up and running and you would have
paid for it at the time that you bought
the computer software was paid for the
work of the laborers producing the
software was compensated at the time
that the hard way was selected in the
80s that all changed and people started
selecting software for business use
separately from the computer that they
were going to deploy it up and they were
then combined that software in that
hardware to produce something that work
forum and the time they pay for the
software was at the time they close it
software companies invented this idea of
a commercial license I've never yet met
anyone apart from a software
manufacturer that likes selling licenses
or buying licenses no software user ever
wanted to buy a software license no none
of us wants to buy software what we
actually want is software that solves a
problem for us and what we would really
rather be paying for is for having the
problem solved and with the the rise of
the mesh society with the availability
of free software being created in open
source communities we've been able to
move to software market 30 in software
market 30 you're able to select the
software and assemble a solution that
works and go deploy it and it's entirely
up to you what you pay for when you no
longer have to pay in advance and so the
business of being a software vendor in
the 21st century is a business that is
about making good software and
unbundling the value proposition of
software for your end users so what
people used to pay for was a license to
get a black box they couldn't look
inside and they would have an implied
right to have all of these great things
down here some code ability to install
it some documentation may be as much as
a page you know maybe it's an education
maybe a warranty maybe a bit of
insurance thing is that most of us
didn't want all those things most of us
only wanted some of those things well in
a world of free software on in a mesh
society you actually only have to worry
about what you need and your it's your
choice what you pay for who you hire to
do things what you buy-in from vendors
to do things and so the software
business of the 21st century that Sun is
moving into is this software business of
being able to demonstrate value to our
customers and providing them with a
service that they can pay for that will
software running doing the things they
need get the new features added get the
bugs fixed and have them paying for just
what they want to pay for we're not
doing this out of a great sense of
philanthropy and love for the love of
the world this is just what's going to
happen because software companies can't
charge at the time of software selection
anymore because we collectively have
broken that business for them forever is
no longer possible to force people to
pay for software licenses because
software is liberated and software is
without charge as a result of being
liberated so what could upset all this I
just want to briefly mention this
there's been two earlier talks for those
of you who got up late and there was a
talk right at the beginning about
software patents and then we've just had
Jim talking about one laptop per child
on the subject of software patents and
son is one of many US companies that
file software patents regularly and the
reason that we file software patents
regularly is the same reason that
Americans buy guns Americans buy guns
because Americans buy guns
and American corporations file software
patents because American software
corporations file software patents if
you don't you are toast so really we've
got no choice but to file software
patents it isn't having software patents
that's the problem it's what you do with
them that's the problem and so one thing
I want to point out to you that you
really need to understand in addition to
the talk you heard earlier is that
software patents are filed in parallel
with development when people in your
community work for American software
corporations those corporations are
incenting them to file patents every
morning they're not getting them to wait
to the end of the process look for the
clever stuff and file patents on it what
they're doing is they're incenting them
every morning when they wake up to file
a patent they're filing in parallel with
development and that means that there is
a very strong chance that if you have
any corporate sponsored developers in
your community that they are filing
software patents on the work that you
are using in that community and you must
be aware of this it is happening in your
community the software patents are there
and the reason that they are a problem
is not because anyone is going to come
after you personally and see you as you
heard earlier the problem that is that
happens there is that whole communities
can be threatened by a threat to key
sponsors in the communities now what
happens with software patents is they
fall into the hands of parties who would
like to do things with them that are not
community friendly so let's say that I
as a company I'm busily getting on
contributing to free software filing
patterns at the same time because that's
what corporations do and it's the same
as you know
the reason you have kitty litter is
because of what cats do software
corporations file software patents I'm
busily filing the patterns I'm unlikely
to be harmful to you if should it perish
the thought some company that has been
filing patents go out of business its
patents are treated as assets in the
open market and the big threat to free
software is what happens when the people
filing in parallel in your community
pass their patents to a hostile party
outside your community and that's the
reason that the art week we heard
earlier that software patents aren't
going to go away in the u.s. anytime
soon and we also heard earlier that
patents as a category in Europe are here
for a while I'm doing my best as I did
two years ago with Mark webbing from Red
Hat to trunk stops the software patent
directive in Europe but it's like it's
like a zombie you know every time you
look around he finds up out of the grave
and running down to the voting booths
down in the European Commission I spend
my time over here trying to kill it off
but it no it's us all keeps on coming
back so what can we do there's three
things that we can do one of them is to
accept patent grants from patent holders
and hold them in common was out in our
community now this is good but really
low value the reason it's really low
value is because if you look at any
software patent software patents don't
contain any useful information to
developers software patents are designed
to help lawyers know how to sue other
companies when they infringe the patent
so a software patent is a list of things
that you can have by which you can know
that someone is worth doing there's no
code samples in there the flow diagrams
are lame the languages are paying the
patents are worthless trust me I've read
lots of them so patent grants are great
and I'm really grateful for the
companies that have protected things
like Samba with patent grants but it's
insufficient what we actually need are
two things we need new software licenses
like the gplv3 that have strong language
that
patents in them and we need to have a
new approach to software standards that
makes sure that if you implement a
software standard like mp3 it's
impossible for any party to prosecute a
patent claim against that international
standard those are the two things that
we need to do and I'd encourage you in
your hatred for software patents which I
share with you to drive it into a
positive treatment of the software
patents try and prevent applicability of
patterns in key areas okay that's my
advertisement for the day now back to a
quiz for you it is a quiz if you were to
look at the source code in the Debian
source code repository which company do
you think you would find had written the
majority of the code in the Debian
source code repository any ideas is it
IBM is it red red heads it's go
well as it turns out scurries number
five on the list it turns out that son
is actually the majority corporate
contributor to the software that's in
the Debian repository and son has
contributed three times as much code as
IBM and five times as much as Red Hat
this is from a recent European
Commission survey and so the question
remains why do you hate us
it doesn't give you some examples of
what that code is this isn't that this
isn't stuff that you don't want is this
is stuff you're using every day this is
the accessibility framework ingham own
this is orca this is the on-screen
keyboard this is the framework that IBM
has then reimplemented as I accessible
to on windows this is the
internationalization code in Mozilla
this is openoffice.org it's a key stuff
so all the people who wrote open office
work for some trust me I went and met me
in Hamburg between so it strikes me that
what's been going on for many years
there's been two ribbons of free
software there's been a ribbon of free
software that has been going on in the
commercial world and there's been a
ribbon of free software that's been
going on in the collective world that is
represented here at fuzzed m and so I'd
encourage you to look beneath
competitive behaviors at the actual
behaviors of developers I've got a bunch
of developers that have come to fuzz
them this time to tell you about what
they're working on like OpenJDK and I
encourage you to go go meet them and
discover that whatever the competitive
postures and the stupid messages
executives give out actually there's
real developers contributing real code
and there are people who have already
changed your life now just to seal the
the two ribbons that are coming up I'm
announcing now now yes I that son has
become a patron of the Free Software
Foundation
and I think it's time for us to begin to
tie off the ribbons of hostility between
the old bsd worlds and the old GPL
worlds and begin to realize that we have
a great deal to gain by being united and
working together and I think that's the
message that lies behind the OpenJDK so
let me show you a video here about Java
I'd love you to hear the words in free
software license the special thing about
this license is that it's a copyleft
license that is to say all versions of
the program must carry the same license
so the freedoms that the gill GPL gives
to the users must reach all the users of
the program and that's the purpose for
which I wrote it it will be very good
that the java trap won't exist anymore
there will be a thing of the past that
kind of problem can still exist in other
areas where won't exist for Java anymore
I think son has well with this
contribution
more than any other company to the free
software community in the form of
software and it shows leadership it's an
example I hope others will follow I
wouldn't I want you to get the idea here
that something big has changed okay I
could imagine going to Richards office
three years ago and asking him to record
a video where he said that the Java trap
no longer existed and that son was a
company that you encouraged other
companies to emulate so if you could
imagine that blew my mind completely to
make that video but something big is
going on here we're seeing a shift in
society that is making it correct for
software businesses to start doing free
software the way that free software
ought to be done that's the change of
tackling so now they're zooming in on
Java for you java as a as a technology
as a community has been around for over
a decade now when global was introduced
it was licensed in a revolutionary way
that meant that businesses all over the
world started to embrace it almost
immediately it wasn't licensed using of
a philosophy that was compatible with
free software but it was made available
on the release day with the full source
code and I at the time work for IBM
rather than for Sun and in her sleep
icked up all of the source code to Java
and we ported it to AIX and os/2 by July
of 1995 because all the source code was
there we didn't ask anyone's permission
we just went and did it and many many
groups all over the world did that and
proved to corporate observers that
keeping the source code secret wasn't
necessary a competitive advantage and
that experience I believe was the sea
that then allowed Mozilla to break
through and become a commercial
commercially visible free software
entity now we did that in 1995 and it
succeeded far beyond son's expectations
some was just completely overwhelmed
with demand and you know when you're
when you're a pioneer you often don't
look over your shoulder to see what's
behind you you can't you just keep on
looking forward and trying to duck the
arrows and if we looked over our
shoulder a few times we might have
realized that there was a free software
constituency that we really ought to
have been working with but we didn't and
it was done and it's taken a really long
time to get to the place where we've
realized we need to fix it but we've
realized that we need to fix it there is
a rich ecosystem already for Java that
includes both commercial activities
includes free software activities
includes community activities and it's
time to bring the ribbons together on
Java as well so I'm last November think
it was we we said that we were going to
GPL Java now to give you an idea of what
GPA lang-java means in software terms
just the java SE the Java platform that
gives you a programming environment
that's the same on every platform just
that code is around about 6 million
lines of code that's before you've
accounted for everything else great big
piece of code and it's taking some time
for mark Reinhold down here in the front
row to get everything done and so what
we did was we started out by just
releasing the Java C compiler and the
hotspot virtual machine I was very
thrilled when that was released to
immediately see people like like mark
villa down here and daddy bought topic
wherever he is and up there and Tom trow
me picking this stuff up and compiling
it trying to break it and trying to use
it to test gcj and doing creative things
with it that immediately started
happening so Java Sea and hotspot are
out already we've also taken the full
java mobile
and embedded platform and release that
under the GPL under the name mobile and
embedded and that's already out that's
already very active that's already been
ported to a number of new places and
there's an interesting free software
community growing around it we're going
to carry on with these code releases
over the next few months in the spring I
think that's about as precise as I dare
be is in the spring they will have
finished moving all the code over into a
public repository and it will be made
available under the GPL with the
classpath exception so that people can
work on that public codebase the reason
we're not just releasing it all at once
is actually we're continuing to do
business with this code we continue to
have business contracts and we're moving
it from a closed repository inside some
that's using something that actually
predates bitkeeper written by the same
guy called teamwear and we're getting it
out of there need to a public repository
called mercurial and we want to make
sure we can carry on fulfilling our
commitments to our customers during that
transition period so it's taking us a
number of months to do it but mark is
definitely going to get done by the
spring on your mark yeah he's looking
very confident down here so so this is
the timeline that we're on we anticipate
having a full buildable java SE jdk jdk
7 down here somewhere in the spring and
i'll leave you to work out where that
line might actually be pointing be
pointing and gets slight off the screen
quickly there's a few bits of the code
that are encumbered in order to when you
write any piece of commercial software
in a world that doesn't have free
software in your mindset you sometimes
go and acquire stuff from third parties
and when you acquire it you don't think
to get the right to give arbitrary
unidentified third parties the right to
create redistributable derivative works
I mean no one even thinks of it because
that's not what you learn
you're about and we didn't get those
rights for in particular java 2d the
font rasterizer the graphics rasterizer
and the color manager and their big
chewy pieces of software and their
encumbered at the moment so when the jdk
comes out in the spring it's going to
have some binary plugs in it but we want
to get rid of those as fast as possible
and that's potentially where you come in
because it may well be that in a like
Sven for example that you've been
working on a color manager and we'd like
to hear from you we'd like you to come
join them in with this community because
I believe that we can have a completely
free Java in the fastest possible time
if we get everyone working together on
the same code base just to complete the
picture we've we've got all of java SE
under the GPL in the spring all of
Galvan mobile is already under the GPL
also all of Java EE is under the GPL we
decided we'd we would add the GPL
license to the existing license on Java
EE so the story was complete now what
this means is that you have available to
you a complete stack of Java software
which is free software under the GPL
that you can do anything you want with
and it stretches all the way from
embeddable code for mobile devices all
the way to enterprise code you can use
to program mainframes and all points in
between the key way that this software
differs from other virtual machine
environments you may have seen before is
is in the area of Java EE what Java EE
does is it virtualizes or generalizes
enterprise interfaces so when you use
Java EE you're not locked into any
particular vendor of databases or
message queuing systems or other
enterprise facilities like you would be
if you use mono net for example you
haven't you have an a generalized
abstracted environment which will work
with any vendor and what
work with any free software okay yeah
JCP yup people asked us whether we
worried about compatibility in all this
stuff the one of the key selling points
of the Java platform the thing that has
made sure that there are over five
million commercial developers working
with it the thing that has made that it
made it be present on two million
devices is the fact sorry two billion
devices is that you can be pretty sure
that the Java environment is the same in
every place you find it inevitably
there's going to be little differences
here and there but broadly speaking the
best way to get a piece of software that
has a binary that runs anywhere is to
use the Java platform and it's through
java compatibility compatibility that
that works compatibility is ensured by
testing and the testing regime is going
to remain in place as we move forward
into the world of free Java that's going
to mean that you can use the code to do
anything you want with if you want a
call it java you'll still have to take a
test we'll make that test available
without charge suitable nonprofits we're
going through a bit of a transition as a
company at the moment and exactly how
that like that testing license works out
is a tricky question for us because
we've actually got a bunch of people
whose livelihoods depend on selling test
kits at the moment and we have to find
new jobs for them so we would really be
pleased if you stick with us while we
find new jobs for those folks but
because in the interim phase there's
going to be a point where we can't quite
do things the way that we'd like to okay
now I've done lots of talking there
let's get some community voices in here
first one that I first thing I'd like to
do is I'd like to introduce you to Tom
marble tom is at son's open lady came
ambassador
nervous about coming up here we go Tom I
i did a dangerous thing I think last
year and took Tom's took Tom to debconf
in Mexico was waterfront and yeah and
and he went native and so so we decided
we ought to move him off his day job
when you were doing something like are
you doing a job a performance
performance testing or something yes oh
yes performance automation and I've been
sort of doing community related things
with with Java for the past year and
going to defcon was a great experience
for me and one of the things that we did
last year as we liberalised our license
a little bit to make Java
redistributable with distros and
opensolaris and the next and so on and
now this year of course we're going the
full way with the GPL yep so the one of
the you know when I just looked at Java
on free software platforms it was in a
pretty sad state to be honest with you
son spend a lot of its time making it
work on windows with a almost unhealthy
focus on competing with a certain
northwestern American company and and
we'd forgotten about the free software
platforms and we were still faithfully
producing rpms of the Java of the JDK
but they really needed to be a genius to
install them and you needed to be a
double genius that then make them run
after you'd install them and there were
no packages that worked with the Debian
packaging system and it was it was
really a really a mess and the the guys
on class path from the all the
affiliated VMs really of doing a bold
job trying to patch up the hole that we
were leaving but really it was necessary
to get a new packaging system together
Tom came to dead conference at writing
it on the floor in in Mexico well I did
a little bit I really
to give most of the credit to Mattias
close I was here who did a lot of the
work with debian thank you my dear so
tell me Tom how are we getting on with
OpenJDK where is it going to be
available sometime soon I think the
springtime Simon yeah for real for real
all of it and what are you gonna do
about community governments well this is
one of the things that I wanted to talk
about on one of the things that's really
exciting about joining the free software
world for Java is that now we're going
to be able to collaborate and a
particular market we heart and I have
talked a lot about ways that we can
collaborate and mark has a couple of
sessions today on a class path and the
runtime Rumble and what's coming for
class path and so we're very excited to
collaborate with the classpath community
and OpenJDK and think of ways that we
can grow together so that's that's today
and then tomorrow we have an open JDK
session where we're going to talk about
governance and we need your input
because we want to have a governance
model for OpenJDK that works for
everyone and it's very participatory so
we're going to have a discussion about
governance tomorrow and a contribution
policy and we also have some engineers
here from Java 2d hotspot the Java
compiler and quality that are going to
talk a little bit about what's cool with
that each part of OpenJDK and we're
really hoping that will become a lively
interactive discussion on the technology
that's cool that you can now access in
the free world with OpenJDK and then
after that we have the Def Jam we have
representatives from Debian RedHat Jen
to hopefully Susie and other other
distributions to talk about packaging
issues for java on all of the
distributions because once we solve the
issues of packaging the jvms the
libraries and the applications now java
can become an inter
a part of a tool chain for distributions
and then we can do some really exciting
kinds of innovation so that's what's
coming great so if you think we're
screwing up at all Tom marble at suncom
ok I really don't every website yeah and
if you can't remember that ombudsman
that suncom will do just as well ok I
rip those seriously if you think they're
screwing up I want to hear about it the
first time that we're screwing up I want
to hear about it at one of those email
addresses and preferably not on the
front page of your website somewhere so
we fixed a number of screw-ups through
those email addresses over the last year
and make his life miserable if we doing
something wrong and buying beer if we're
not he made her mark Villard mark going
to come up and come talk to us
so mark is one of the one of the heroes
of free Java there's a few others around
the room actually who that tom is hiding
up there somewhere i think i got
there'll be sitting there he moved down
the other areas is moved down here and
there's a few other focus there's dolly
ball up there really hiding in the back
trying not to be noticed these guys have
kept the hope of free Java alive through
the years when son's management was
doing its level best to be done and I
didn't say that of course and and I when
we're really grateful to you for doing
that um how do you feel about OpenJDK is
it ruining your life are making you
miserable it takes some let that thing
but luckily you didn't release
everything yet so partly we are now in a
padded spend color let's steal that
cookie before they give it away so we're
actually really working hard to be the
first but and then you released one of
six here what would is behind again to
be honest I think we are going to make
your life a bit harder because half of
our work is compatibility we we saw want
to be the free thing that you can run
any Java and if the Java Java ice cream
then that leaves the compatibility
partners is taken care of and then we
can really compete on on innovating
things and that's when one of the things
you you won't like this of course that
we're certainly going to make all that
brand with not net
oh yes but but we have been doing that
yeah and and it will be fun to see can
donate now now be a better java and java
at least now there's a chance to prove
that or or disprove the same with gcj we
have a native costume party and wow
wasn't always the fastest that at least
was the free one and how we also have to
make it the fastest to be better well we
have good we are going to make sure that
everything that you haven't released the
update that will be available we have an
awt based on gtk+ right to the graphics
based on chi era which i think is
interesting so and we're just going to
talk them see well we have a lot of
things that we can learn from you
already about the way that you
collaborate the way that you automate
testing the way that you you do all
kinds of auto tools related things where
you know we have our own strange and
arcane with a build system story mark
that is going to take some adapting to
you and we can learn a lot from you in
that process i hope so
it's about technology of programming in
the last decade the question of Java's
freedom whether it could be used freely
and made part of free software projects
has been a crucial question sons policy
of GP LOL Java which we are celebrating
now is an extraordinary achievement in
retool program and technology to that
state freely available knowledge son has
now GPL hardware designs son is gpo and
java that's an extraordinary vote of
confidence in this way of sharing
information and we own the free software
world are very pleased and very
flattered to see some taking it's all
very valuable and very important
products and agree with us that they
will be more advantageous to son as well
as to the rest of the community if they
are shared under these laws that really
was everything that I won't say do you
hear today I wanted to tell you that
it's been a wild ride certainly for me
in the last two years with son I believe
that son son is still a corporation and
you should never turn your back on
corporations and I know you won't so I
know you're going to keep us honest but
we honestly want to work with free
software because we believe that our
business is best served by working with
everybody in the open room rather than
by trying to get everyone into a closed
room we believe that that's the future
of the software business and we believe
yes ok I'll admit it we believe will
make more money by doing free software
than all those other companies are going
to do by doing their clothes stuff and
well we go to work with you on that and
well you know I don't know how many of
you are going to work on sons payroll I
don't know how many of you
other people's payroll but we're moving
into a future where we're able to
synchronize the interests that we each
have whether it there be about one
laptop per child and by the way we
didn't just randomly release the open
firmware for one laptop per child I OPC
actually asked me and I released it
under BSD so they could use it and we
didn't put out a press release because
the only people who wanted it with them
just just in case you wondered we intend
to pioneer a 21st century free software
business and we want to do that in a way
that helps you succeed at your goals as
well so at any point that we screw up
Ombudsman at suncom Tom marvel at song
song com simon phipps at song com write
to us and tell us that we're screwing up
and apart from that I look forward to
collaborating and cooperating with you I
over the Java platform / Mozilla over
the Thunderbird and lightning over all
of the other packages genome and so on
that we're working on together thank you
very much for paperless
and we've got time for some questions
that don't go there go away mark we have
got time for some questions and take the
gift what do you fancy getting let go
out there who raised his hand with a
microphone oh he can get to yes go
anyone down the front one to ask a
question while that microphones heading
up there yes raise our hand again please
my question is about dynamically typed
languages I know that the JRuby guys
will hide last year by son what is the
commitment to getting dynamically tight
land which is running on the JVM and I
think you better do it quickly because I
think that northwestern American company
might be doing the same I think I've
noticed I'm hiring a few people as well
yes funny you should ask that because
the guy who's dubba deez is over here in
the front row this is Mark Reinhold I
he's the COO think year ago so so we
develop gods and son had sort of
attitudinally has gone through this
transition where we're definitely seeing
Java as two things which is kind of what
it's always been there's drama the
language which is great for a bunch of
stuff and there's dropped the platform's
the vm and all the infrastructure and
the libraries and java platform is about
more than java the language so not only
we hire their JRuby guys but we're
working closely with them there's going
to be a JSR rd is a JSR for a new byte
code called them folk dynamic which is
useless for john totally pointless as
far as job is concerned but for or
scripting languages or
dynamically typed languages it can bring
like an order or two magnitude
performance improvement and so we're
actively working on that with the JRuby
guys and other folks so so java the java
platform is definitely about a lot more
than just drop the language so one of
the things that i've started 18 months
ago was in our NetBeans tool was support
for four groovy and for Jason so it
isn't just Ruby that we're that we're
supporting there is one of this it's
something I've been I've been banging on
about for ten years five years at IBM
within five years of Sun is that there's
a there's a guy called talks Dorf who's
got a website with all of the languages
that run on the Java VM there's some
like 130 of them and we've finally got
some to admit they exist and so we are
now actively working on on scripting
language or dynamic languages or indeed
other other languages that work on Java
VM I I'm not sure I can think of very
many languages that wouldn't work on the
job of you question of the bag I was
very pleased and encouraged about the
your intentions and your ethical value
systems that you mentioned earlier
specifically in regard to sams patent
portfolio unfortunately I'm not
convinced that your intentions and
values are necessarily shared by the
directors of Sun and even if they are
they are they have to do what their
shareholders tell them and the
shareholders can change overnight and is
there any intention with in San to do
with the GPL equivalent to its its
patents and that is to dedicate them to
the public so that there's not an intent
to do that the reason that we file the
patterns in the first place is because
we're competing against a very big
unconvicted monopolist in the northeast
of the US and a very big convicted
toplist in the northwest of the US and
those two companies and we need our
patent portfolio in such a way that
we're able to use it to defend ourselves
against them and a couple of other
companies what I am keen for us to do
however is to lock ourselves up in traps
so we can't exercise our patents against
the community so that's what the pattern
on cert covenants are avail for example
so we've we've made a covenant around
open document format that says that
whatever patents we've got we promise
you that we won't exercise them against
any implementation of open document
format and that that means that Sun on
its heirs and the signs are unable to
litigate against implementers I guess
implementations of open document format
and going forward you'll see us make
more of those non assert covenants in
areas where we're working with the
community but the the way that the
patent system in the u.s. is set up
there are no easy answers for how to
both defend yourself against aggressive
monopolists and uncommitted monopolist
and how to also behavior ethically and
responsibly in a community and
ultimately I think we need to together
work out what the new new ways of doing
that up I I talk I talked a lot with the
FII folks 18 months ago and goeth
cokeman and on from there and really
we've still not reached an agreement
about ways that that actually work now
there's ways that look good but working
out ways that actually work in
protecting us I mean we got sued by a
patent troll that you'll be very
familiar with company called Kodak they
they state they bought a company that
had bought a company that had bought a
patent that related to object-oriented
technology and they took out an
injunction against this over Java and
were threatening to stop shipment of
Java to anyone anywhere in the world
which we thought was a really bad idea
but we didn't have any patterns we could
fight them with and so we had to pay
them 90 million dollars so that they
would get off
even though we believe that their patent
claim was worthless because in the u.s.
they could get injunctive relief against
this and stop of shipping our code they
didn't have to prove a case they could
simply say we're going to prove a case
later so will you stop them shipping it
while we prove it please and that's the
situation we've got we have to be able
to defend ourselves against I hated that
it's that way and I wanted to change I'm
much more importantly want to make sure
it doesn't happen in this on this
continent because at the moment as you
heard earlier we don't have the laws in
place that make it happen here and I
really want to make sure it doesn't
happen here but in the u.s. I'm sorry we
it would be irresponsible of us to
dedicate our patents to the public
domain but I'm very keen to do
responsible things in connection with
our communities thank you any other
question so we're doing still got five
minutes there's when your assignment the
question somewhere over there tom yeah
ah
mom could you like we got to repeat the
question is there any likelihood of
multiple inheritance being added to Java
the languages that's the question I
think the answer is no a different
answer is hey you already have it with
with interfaces but multiple England
implementation heritance and another
answer is you could always write a
language that ran on the VN the added
but mark you you know the kitchen sink
language that is based on Java Sea butta
pets be accepted in a branch for the
kitchen sink language for that
where's fee that so one of the people we
brought with us is a guy who we've got
this pretty good thank you so so fun
doraha is I guess not here he's the Java
C compiler lead at son he created a
project on dragnet called ksl java.net
this is actually an idea that james
gosling had its the kitchen sink
language so you know we open source java
see the compiler and now people are
taking Java Sea and Remy for apps is
here somewhere he's been prototyping new
syntax for declaring and accessing
properties and stuff and so people are
going wild and it's great exploring
random language ideas as the the baby
case 7 ball gets rolling you know what
language changes might might be
considered for that so that's what ksl
is all about it so let me back up a
little bit the thing about multiple
inheritance II it's not gonna be added
to drop it because I he's actually
technically infeasible that doesn't mean
it's a bad idea of itself it's just
really really tricky to get right and
people who have done it in programming
languages so far at least it might you
haven't gotten a right but that's say
you see me over beer or something i'll
talk more yes my name is patty Knowlton
from the school linux and debian project
and i'm really happy to be one of the
people organizing the dead job in a
later on my question is that when son is
missing some pieces which is encumbered
with the current java and class but
already have on with a compatible
license will you actually take it from
12 top mark
I know the answer to that question but I
let mark tell you we can dip our answers
um we let's see I am NOT a lawyer so
there's a sole contribution we can't
just be we can't just pick out random
code out there and pull it in right it
has to be contributed but we're
hopefully we're going to be working the
lights clasp at folks and and it all
being lb 11 fun good party fit filling
this stuff in so yeah I hope there's
plenty of opportunity for Koecher so I
give my out so well do it come on answer
that was well not is that coke annoying
up and I've been to anything I'm not
church going into up yet ok but this it
certain people will combine and how
precisely we figure out who is working
on what is it's going to be interesting
and of course you yeah but that is why
we are here and besides saw the
licensing and there's the community and
people being proud of their own codes I
i know i am so it will take some
convincing to replace my coat with god
somebody else wrote which can never be
as good as michael and probably they
have the same feeling about some of
their code so we work something out so
in essence there's no reason why I
shouldn't going that there are there is
that there are a few tiny problems in
the way that the AWT in in class path is
architected is radically different to
the way that the AWT in OpenJDK is
architected and so it isn't
matter of picking up and throwing it in
there there is actually some heavy
lifting to do to get make it going I
think I think that's what you told me
wasn't it yeah yeah it is our awts based
on GP k + + d 2 k plus s solution slight
changes in semantics with how things
work and compatibility for some it's a
very big thing so keeping great back
layout working yes it's an interesting
problem actually just a quick update as
assignments encumbrance libelous was a
little bit stale we actually have
resolved the color management library
encumbrance by incorporating I think it
was a little CMS so that that's actually
done Igor who's sitting down here is
from the 2d team and he's actually
working on integrating free type in as a
replacement for the proprietary font
rasterizer so if you're interested in
that topic you can talk to Igor we're
still kind of scratching our heads over
the whole graphics rasterizer thing and
looking at chiro and other stuff and
that's a really hard one so we'd also
welcome think of your your input up
there ok thank you so we're out of time
thanks very much for coming and enjoy
countries
you