hello hello
before i let ruff welcome you to fosdem
i need to say my yearly two words about
the beer last night
i'm guilty for organizing it for the
seventh time now
we broke all records we had a total beer
bill of 5130 euro
despite closing the bar an hour earlier
than usual because some people were
throwing things
and it's probably safer not to let geeks
get harmed
i want to thank everyone who showed up
and who behaved
and i want to see you again next year
for more beer when we tried my beer
distribution algorithm version 3
which will be worked out uh sometime in
the summer during our barbecues
so thank you for being there last night
and
i'll let ruff welcome you to fosdem now
thanks
hi everybody i suppose you wonder what
i'm doing now
well i'm just recording and making of
fosdem this year
and i certainly go around and interview
some people during the weekend so
please don't be shy look
very very carefully what i'll do during
the fosdem dance
so you can repeat it afterwards
you you can see now the the questions
i will ask but i suppose it will be
clear
when when i interview you
so now to to the opening talk
the first thing dance it's coming later
it's coming later
just getting into the mood you know
so this year again about fosdem well
it's a free and open source developers
meeting
you begin to to know it it's the seventh
edition this year uh
two days as usual and this time we have
204 activities organized
so it's really a huge job by
by a big team really well organized this
year
and it's getting better and better
at the organization's side i hope for
you it's getting better also
it's still organized by volunteers
exclusively by volunteers and nobody
gets paid so
when you make a donation to the
organization it doesn't go in the
pockets of
any people in the organization it's
always for
covering costs we have like travel
hotels etc
so you can give us a lot of money it
won't go into my pockets
the tracks this year's this year so
security desktop application development
in languages
kernel web internet services developer
rooms
a lot of developers rooms and a special
mention
of mozilla who have supported us this
year
and who is present for the sixth time
this year
we also have lightning talks a
key signing party and lpi exams
during the weekends the three lpi exams
are
available
someone doesn't listen to my talk
here is an overview of what you what we
can give you back for a donation so as a
as a reminder we don't sell anything uh
we accept donations and we
try to give you something back to thank
you about for your donation
and this time uh we can hand out
uh in addition to the
usual things like t-shirts o'reilly
books we have three
nokia n8 rendered and 800
tablets two sun ultra workstations and
18 magazine subscriptions
they'll those will be uh given in a draw
so for every 25 euros you
you give you donate you get a ticket in
in a draw so everybody participates
in uh every in every draw uh
that was not the case the other years
but we wanted to thank everybody who
donates
those are our sponsors more and more
sponsors
and i think this comes from the freedom
we have in organizing
the events we can concentrate on a
really interesting content
thanks to your donation which keeps us
free from
sponsoring we can always decide to
refuse sponsors
thanks to your donations uh
the info desk is located as usual in the
age building
there you can get every kind of
information like
the folder network who used
wireless network at first them before
yeah that's what i thought maybe five
people and
this year it should be much better there
is
there has been yeah yeah
yeah should i stop here
we have we have received help from
people from greenpeace who have already
set up a wireless network for
big events and it seems everything is
going
fine until now so thank you to
greenpeace of course
and so we are really hopeful this will
work fine they will
this will work out this year you have
the network
information there about food
in addition to sandwiches we'll have hot
food
this year it's in front of the jeans
here
you can get hot food there
like other years we have disabled people
blind people
please help them if they they don't find
their way uh don't be shy we are
all friends here and help those people
you'll find also a feedback form it's
always interesting to know
what you you think about the event
especially about the wireless network
this year
and later on real organized uh design
contest
for the website so if you have ideas
about it you can already start
thinking about
and at last yeah some people were
waiting for that the first them dance
which i'll do with damian
and i hope you enjoy it because i think
it's the last time i do it here
okay so i hope you you serve really
clearly what it is
some of you will do it again i hope
before my camera
so now it's