i'm gonna turn the mic over to our
speaker justin
thank you kat
and thank you everyone for being here
i'm really excited to
deliver this talk
last month i gave this talk at rva sec
and it was really well received and we
had a lot of fun and we're also going to
have a lot of fun today
so my talk is called
honeypot booboo
better breach detection with deception
inception
because it's fun to be wordsmithing
uh
so a little bit about myself
i'm a
authorized partner with things canary i
don't actually work at things canary
but i've worked with them for
several years
and collaborated and i'm very passionate
about
their product and platform because i've
personally seen it
prevent three catastrophic breaches trip
up some of the most elite red teams
in in the world and have pen tests fail
within eight minutes
and
easy cheap effective stuff
and so today i'm gonna
give you an overview of
what we're doing now as far as breach
detection why it's not working
and some ideas for what we may try
to
do better moving forward and also walk
you through various deployment scenarios
for different types of canary tokens
and honey pots and with that
let's kick things off
so
for
starters we need to talk about what's a
honey trap or honey a honey trap can be
a honey pot
or a honey token and
is
a device that's designed to
look like a real service and a real
system that's running attractive
services and you have tokens which are
digital trip wires that can be
manifested as google docs aws keys slack
tokens you name it
both of these mechanisms represent
the larger discipline of deception
technology and this is really fun
because the more creative you are
the more likely you'll be able to thwart
your adversary and
at some point you're going to have
a situation of psychological warfare
where you're going to get them to
question their sanity and we'll get to
that here in a bit
the reason we need something new is
because it takes entirely too long to
detect breaches
it's costing more and more money every
year and exponentially breaches continue
happening
so we also have tons of burnout you know
our the security community is in dire
need of people millions of jobs
depending on what report you read you
have burnout
um you have disaffection and
there's better ways that we need to be
looking at this to help help our
security professionals
and most importantly if you do get
breach because you will it's not a
matter of if it's when the idea is you
want to mitigate the blast radius
because you want to know exactly at that
point that you've been breached and not
212 days later
so
some of you probably know
the pyramid of pain
and laundry room viking
you know for the analysts out there this
might be so
so true it hurts but
you know
the idea is early on you know as an
analyst maybe you work 100 hours a week
and you're not going to go to bed
so you just triage tickets instead and
you might get ahead for the time being
but you'll soon end up dead so
in other words we need to help our
analysts because
it's really hard and i have a lot of
respect for people but
a lot of the time they're spending a lot
of their uh cycles on false positives
and
you know
alerts that don't have any fidelity so i
feel for
them and really like why deception
technology of all things i do believe
this is the year the inflection point
when deception technology really has
started to take off because people
need a new way of thinking about this
and you've just looked back over the
last decade at some of the largest
breaches
you know going back to 2013 with snowden
and he had the most sophisticated spying
agency and
security organization in the world and
snowden just rummaged around for
long periods of time exfiltrated data
and they were none the wiser
you go back to solarwinds we all have
ptsd in the supply chain at this point
everything is about third party risk and
trying to mitigate that
you know the effects are still being
you know felt today
and then you've got a credit score which
is every adult here you know you were
affected by the equifax breach
and
now you
get credit monitoring and
freeze your credit
all of these things you have this
synthetic identity theft problem that's
been popping up
and at this point it's like every other
day there's some kind of breach and the
worst part is things are converging now
into the physical world
um
so we need to do something to
to stop the septa pain
so if any of you remember
jimmy mcmillan from 2012
he ran on a platform about the rent
being too high and he was definitely
right
but the cost of cyber crime is is also
way too high
you know
costs about 6 trillion dollars to the
global economy
the prediction is in
2025 it'd be about 10.5 trillion
roughly every 39 seconds a new business
is breached
fbi last year
had 847 000 cyber complaints
but i'm here
to give you some hope and hopefully a
solution on how we can
fix this
if you look back at some of the largest
breaches as far as the number of records
go
you know it took 212 days on average
based on the ibm report to even know
that a company's been reached that's
entirely too long by then they've run
off with the crown jewels and they've
done everything they need to do
so if you look at cam4 what's
interesting about that service it's a
naughty webcam site but 10.88 billion
accounts there's only 7 billion people
obviously people had multiple accounts
because they probably didn't want to
reveal that they were on this site but
yahoo got breached multiple times you
know yahoo sports yahoo fantasy 3
billion
and in india in think 2017 this was
their government id program
that
was
had you know lofty expectations but was
a epic failure because every single
citizen of india had their data
leaked and the worst part was 401k was
tied to their social security to their
bank account you know everything just in
one
identification system so their life is
effectively ruined at that point
so with that said let's talk about how
canaries
fit into this equation
you know back in the day until 1986
they'd use actual birds
you know when they went mining as an
early warning system
and that's no longer cool cool but we
can use them in our code
and canaries they come in two
forms you've got honey pots which are
known as birds
and you got
honey tokens which are canary tokens
and birds can
birds manifest as real devices you can
have a scada system a smart coffee
machine a dumb terminal
database server and these things are so
real you'd be hard-pressed to tell
anyone that this isn't an actual device
and i'll show you
uh what just how convincing this looks
here soon and then you've got canary
tokens and this is where
the creativity is your only limitation
because you can literally token anything
you can take a piece of data text file
dns record
spreadsheet
even qr codes now and i'll walk through
each of these examples
and the idea is you layer them
in a sort of
deception inception model
which is where everything will kind of
culminate at the end
and you end up essentially creating a
minefield that's hard to avoid at some
point an adversary is going to trip over
something and then they're going to trip
over something else and along the way
we're going to gather a pretty detailed
forensics trail
and when it's all said and done
we may not have all the information to
de-anonymize them but if we provide it
to a third-party company we've given
them like a huge advantage and you'll
see how this works
so let's talk first about
the birds the bird's word
let's talk about from window to the lols
i don't know if any of you remember
microsoft bimbos it was a japanese
computer repair shop
that also had a modified version of
windows xp that was really secure
because all it had was sticky notes
calculator and notepad so the attack
surface was pretty small
and you know a lot of people
organizations that are over 10 years old
probably use active directory and
active directory
runs on domain controllers and the
reason you use this is you want to
manage your users machines passwords
files you name in a central location
this is really attractive to an
adversary if you can compromise ad
normally you can do everything you can
read emails log into any computer listen
to traffic
so of course people are going to want to
come to this so the idea here is we
deploy a bird
that actually is legit not like this and
we
want to see what happens
when this domain controller is
interrogated
and you'll see
so for those that know nmap or don't
it's a classic tool for service
enumeration and port scanning so what i
did here was
i just ran an nmap scan with various
ports targeting a windows domain
controller right and if you look at each
of the service ports you've got
very convincing information about the
services you know you look at port 80
it's running windows internet
information services in fact if you were
to visit that ip on port 80 you'd hit an
is page and it would even let you put
credentials in too
it's you know it's so hard to tell the
difference you can customize
the directory information if you look
here under 88 which is kerberos
which is used for authentication you've
got
realm.kdc and it says ad.thinks.com you
can make it be
b-sides pgh whatever you want for your
company to make it blend in with the
rest of your systems
and even look at
you know like
microsoft sql server it's a dumb idea to
run that on the domain controller but
people do it all the time and even tells
you
what version you have and so on
and then the moment you run this scan a
lot of things happen
you it lights up the christmas tree for
you no need to do it yourself
so on the left side
here's a bunch of aggregated alerts that
you're going to get not only do you get
notified that there's port scanning
happening but you're also going to be
notified that somebody tried to log in
with ftp credentials and it'll even tell
you what username and password and they
can try all day but there's nothing of
value on these birds
you even have microsoft sql
authentication so if somebody's trying
to log in with sasa which is common you
know it's going to fire an alert and
even custom service ports you know if
they run like a telnet command or netcat
it'll capture all this information
on the right side
you can see kind of more information
you gathered the user agent so this is
already helpful right we know now that
whoever visited is coming in on
we're using nmap on a windows machine
essentially
and
we also know we don't have their ip yet
but we will actually we do have the ip
look at the there's a slack alert right
there
it tells you the ip
so you can start to do some reverse geo
location this is actually my ip in
richmond
and
this is our first warning system and
it's only going to get
more robust with our information profile
over time
ted stevens he was
he was not exactly right when he said
the internet is a series of tubes it's
not a big truck i mean it's not a series
of tubes it's not a big truck it is
mostly noise
and specifically it's just grey noise
and if any of you
have
used a service
you know that it's
really a great way to
gather contextual information for birds
that you want to deploy in a traditional
research mode so the bird that
previously was deployed is essentially a
production hunting pot and this differs
from 20 years ago when honey pots really
just sat on the internet and listened
for signals and there wasn't really
anything interesting to you in
particular but what has shifted
is these birds that you deploy
are in your environment normally one hop
away from your public infrastructure and
so they're going to only alert you when
it's relevant but that said canary has a
traditional um
honey pot called the outside bird and i
wrote like a very basic bass script on
github that pulls in the alerts the ips
and it runs it through grey noise and it
gives you
context so essentially what grey noise
does is it says we know showdown has
these scanners we know cloudflare has
cdns we know all these ips we're going
to filter them out we're going to filter
out benign malicious and we're going to
leave you
you know these 4 000 ips will give you
900 so it's a great way to automate for
analysts
the process of you know manually going
through and checking all these ips free
service
community api highly recommend checking
them out
and another native integration
karen aryan rumble goes together like
george foreman grilled tilapia for sure
and what there's there's a native
integration so when you're in canary you
can hover over the hourglass and it
takes you directly to rumble what's neat
here
is rumble
automatically builds an asset inventory
and gives you a lot more enrichment and
context so it tells you
you know services location the
autonomous system number on the internet
um when it was seen and so you can
determine okay did this canary token
fire from one of my assets if if so
i should probably look into that you
know like this was really helpful for a
log for shell you could start gathering
information on public ips and if
machines were communicating you know to
c2 servers and surreptitiously
you'd probably
you know need to investigate that
another free awesome tool hd moore who
wrote metasploit um this is his company
it's awesome highly recommend checking
it out
okay
with birds
taken care of
let's talk about the tokens and the
tokens all the way down
and we're going to start with
chris farley and black sheep and recon
tokens
these are
going to be tokens that people use
before they even have access to your
network and there's ways that you can
gather information on them
to figure out what they may be wanting
to do and why they're targeting you
so one of the first tokens
we can use
is a
domain name system token
and the reason domain name system exists
is because most people aren't weirdos
and like me that memorize ip addresses
you want to type in
you know b-sides pgh behind the scenes
you've got an internet protocol address
that's where
you know you know how to route traffic
on the internet
um
the way that we can use these tokens
really effectively
is we can create dns entries and map
them to unused or dark network segments
so you can create entire
virtual lens that should never be used
and you can have dns pointing there so
if somebody is
enumerating those network segments it's
going to fire this token and you're
going to know snoop dogs in the building
snooping around
and when this token fires
it doesn't tell you
the ip of the host it tells you the ip
of the dns server but even with that it
was able to determine that i was coming
from richmond virginia where i live and
i was using cloudflare their one one one
two
dns server in particular so this is like
a great
initial token just to alert you that
people are mucking around
and trying to do reconnaissance
so this is really helpful
and if we continue along that path
one of my favorite tokens is called a
web redirect
and you can get so much information from
nozi o'donnell just by having them visit
a site so there's a doppelganger domain
that i bought and transferred to canary
called thinks that io
and when you would hit things that i o
it would
quickly redirect you and when you
actually buy the service it doesn't say
canarytokens.com it uses your own domain
so that it looks legitimate but
you know it sends you there then it
redirects you to b sides
and in the process it grabs tons
information it grabs your browser user
agent ip if you have javascript
windows you know after a while
you can start to
you know shrink the pool of potential
people this may be so like
hardware surveys get captured all the
time if you use steam for video games
they always ask you send your hardware
specs microsoft asks you to send your
hardware specs so
there's a good understanding of how many
windows computers might exist here in
pittsburgh and then how many people use
firefox and you can see how you can
start to de-anonymize and
have a
more targeted forensic pool
than if you just try to cast a wide net
so this is where we're starting to build
the trail
until we get to the end
and
that's when things get real
okay
downey dodgeball fans out there
there's a token here called
a clone website token this is actually
incredibly helpful for knowing when
people are trying to impersonate your
your company or they're trying to start
a phishing campaign so i've actually
seen this token
be effective in
allowing for a cease and desist of
domains you know like you get notified
hey somebody's deployed this contact the
registrar and you send them a scary
letter with your legal team nine times
out of ten they're going to tear this
domain down and kind of give up on their
campaign
this is really helpful all you do is you
create the token it gives you five lines
of javascript you don't need to be
technical just embed it in your html
pages
and then if the client redeploy it
anywhere fires an alert get the ip
you get
you know some basic headers
and
yeah
this
this is good information
bert macklin
is on the job
apis
alert protect investigate or application
programming interface but now we're
going to talk about
api specific tokens and how great they
are
starting with
the the cloud the aws
so
probably my favorite token is the aws
amazon web service api key
this looks just like a pair of normal
credentials
but when you use them you can't do
anything
but you also don't know that they're
they're not permission you can though
actually
lead people down a path and you can
provision credentials that have access
fake access to an account
and then you can continue to allow them
to do things
so that you gather more information but
in general these have no permissions
but
when they use these keys
it starts to get even more information
it'll start to tell you
the commands that they run if they hit
any of the buckets it'll tell you the
operation that happens
and what's really cool on the left
is it builds this incident map and this
is on the free
think site canarytokens.org
so one thing to mention is you know you
can spend like five grand a year which
is the best bang for the buck and get a
hosted console or you can do this
yourself for free and you can generate
tokens galore and when you do
it tells you everywhere geographically
that this key is used the idea here is
like
you can automate deployment using
something like jam for intune you can
put it on every single machine
and if marketing all of a sudden fires
an alert
you probably have a good indication well
their machine's been compromised but
what a lot of bad actors will do
is they're not going to run it on that
machine they're going to grab the keys
and use it and in the process continue
to de-anonymize themselves because it's
grabbing the ip
grabbing the particular user agent like
did they use
photo 3 you know python or did they use
some other sdk so you're just continuing
to grab more and more information and
build this forensics trail
you know why you're deceiving them and
leading them along the path
yeah and speaking of bang for the bucket
this is where you can start to really
layer things in
so with amazon web services
you know you've got these simple storage
service buckets and over the years these
things have been prone left and right
you know you've had people accidentally
storing credit card information personal
health info on these buckets
and security was optional with aws you
know for initially you know your bucket
policies weren't
strict by default it would a lot of
times it'd just be world writable and
anonymous and people didn't realize that
they were putting sensitive information
and so given the nature of this zero
trust world we live in
you know companies will get breach
it's just a matter of when and how badly
we know this is a fact this is the only
sensible way to operate in our modern
world
so we just have to make sure
when our preventative controls fail and
they will we have the ability to detect
things
immediately so all you need to do is
create a bucket you can name it
something that blends into your existing
buckets and the mere act of just listing
an account will fire an alert
and you can tie this in with the aws
keys and you can give them permissions
into a bogus account with s3 buckets and
you can have them spin their wheels and
think that they're
doing something
that's valuable but it's really not
and so in the process you go through you
get more information on the user agent
you know we learned here looks like
they're
on linux and they're running boto sdk in
java even tells you here on the right
the actual operation just the head
just to hit the bucket ips same deal
time even the the user right and so
you um you can kind of customize that as
well and
make this look super convincing
and one thing with canary
that's great is you have almost an
unlimited number of endpoints to send
alerts to so you can
email sms slack generic web hooks you
know
splunk you name it
you can send data to it even just
generic syslog and i recommend you do
because
you know you should be sending this to
your sim and building the forensics
trail print area by itself it gathers
this data but their whole pitch is they
don't want you spending time in the
console they they really do just say
take five minutes deploy it and then
don't look at it and most security
companies you have to constantly babysit
the product
but this is one in which it really just
works
um
yeah and we've also got slack tokens
and i like to go meta with these and do
things like dropping them
in your slack space
so you can take your face back to my
space no but the the idea here is you
could put these in public slack channels
so that if people are compromising a
slack account they're going to look
around they might search for xoxp or
xoxb which indicates either a personal
or bot token
and they'll find it and they think they
got something you can drop these in your
code repositories drop them on people's
machines possibilities are endless
and they have no permissions but they're
really appealing you know you ask any
pen tester including
um haroon who you know founded thinks
if um
he would pass over a set of api
credentials no anyone that comes across
credentials is going to try to use them
slack tokens are no exception
and exhibit um
you know exhibit pulls it all together
here for us
[Music]
and then
on the api front we also the latest
token which is super cool it's a
kubernetes or k8 because it's k eight
letters get it and then s and the whole
point of kubernetes
is managing massive amounts of what are
called containerized applications which
is like the next iteration of virtual
machines you know containers like a self
um self-contained environment where you
don't it's platform agnostic you just
spin it up with something like docker or
whatnot
but we can actually create a kubernetes
config file and similar to aws we can
drop these on people's machines
automatically
and
fire alerts when they try to use it and
similar to
aws we also grab information on the user
agent so we'll know what version of the
cube cuddle cli tool they use what
endpoint they hit all the all the really
useful pieces of information and it
looks just like a regular kubernetes
config file behind the scenes though
it's hitting you know a bogus endpoint
that canary kind of like masquerades
it's brilliant
and i've seen this fired
you know probably half a dozen times
all right we're going to talk about some
tokens to protect your telephones and
your devices these are personally useful
for everyone here now and so i'd
recommend
you know creating
the following
so there's a really neat token
canary released last year it's called uh
so wireguard is a new virtual private
network protocol it's faster than
openvpn it uses some different cipher
suites
and it's just more reliable
and
you can create like a bogus
wireguard profile
with the idea that
if your phone is compromised and it's
really hard to know you know last year
you had the pegasus spyware that was
hitting political dissidence phones and
you know it was really hard to detect
unless you did deep forensics i mean
happened to jeff bezos in 2020 allegedly
when the saudi arabian government hacked
his phone
so like how would you even know
that your phone got prone
well one thing you can do is use this
token to create
you know a vpn profile name it something
that sounds appealing like you know
corporate vpn or production whatever
and then if somebody turns it on because
it's not going to be you because it's
useless it's going to fire an alert one
important thing to notice about these
tokens make sure you use a memo that
isn't test make it actionable and and
relevant so i like to automate this
typically by using like variables of
hostname of the machine and then
username so something token on whatever
but otherwise you're going to be like
where's this token and you know because
there are companies that literally have
hundreds of thousands of tokens
and the more the better you get
unlimited with with things so you should
be deploying this everywhere and
anywhere but i love this
and you totally can pull out your phone
right now and scan this code
because
you know bad guys hate it when you do
this one weird trick
qr qr codes are really
versatile and there's a lot of things
that you could do with this
you could put this around your office
and say here's the new wi-fi password
but you know full well that you don't
actually give out the wi-fi password
because you probably push it out
securely so anyone that's trying to get
it is probably just up to no good
but one use case that i've seen that's
really effective is if you have
multi-factor
you can drop an unread email in
everyone's mailbox and make it look like
it came from octa or duo and say hey you
got a new device scan this bad boy and
roll it and then when they do it's going
to send them to some funny site and have
like some lyrics from top gun or i don't
even remember because it's randomized
and where it goes you can rick roll them
you can do whatever you want and at that
point
they're probably going to like
try a little lightly you know it's all
about psychological warfare and as
you're
going along and playing mind games with
them they're going to be more inclined
to want to leave
and on that note
it's trippy but let's talk about mind
games this is where it gets really fun
this is all about the information
warfare where you get to manipulate data
to
convince people that they're losing it
so this data basically database is
just asking me dump because databases
are treasure troves of valuable
bits you know everyone wants the
database
it's usually got credit card numbers
it's got social security numbers we can
make this thing look super convincing
call it nft payments table or call it
you know accounting backup whatever
you know you can create a my sequel
token and
you can drop these things everywhere you
know you can put them in amazon web
services and
use them within your existing databases
or use your imagination right and then
once i go to open this you know database
just running command there's all kinds
of gibberish it looks legit but it's
completely useless but then in the
process you know we get another alert
here
we figure out oh there's the host name
that's helpful
so if they have a specific mysql client
inversion
it'll tell us that and again that starts
to limit our our profile of they're
using this certain version of this and
this so we can start to
you know um like pile it together and
and start building this profile who this
person who people may be
what if conspiracy keanu made the
realization
that conspiracy theories are actually
conspiracy realities so this is a fun
little trick right you create a google
doc or a word doc name it something that
everyone wants to open
if they're up to no good like
organizational structure go to market
strategy ipo whatever and then you hit
them with a truth bomb so you tell them
something that they may not know
maybe that leads them to you know walk
away and question
um you know everything that they're
doing you know mk ultra is a highly
legal cia
program that you know likely created
the unabomber among other things but you
could also drop something in about
operation northwoods or write a whole
story about the jfk assassination is if
you know what happened just confuse them
and below them at this point they're
probably going to go
away
and this is a good point to mention
there's another really neat service
called bittrap that's experimenting with
this whole idea around
giving people bug bounties
but differing amounts depending on how
far along they go in the process so
when you kind of use canary
you know you can have certain
checkpoints and say all right they
popped my web server
if you leave now
they'll give you this you know
five grand but if you keep going you're
going to get less and less money and
also we're going to come for you
and it's a pretty neat service i'm i
don't think they're officially partnered
with canary but
it works works well just like anything
you know it integrates
perfectly so there's a lot of really
neat things you can do
along that line
and
it doesn't just stop with google docs we
can spread some
i just love puns but i'm fascinated with
db cooper
because the fbi closed the case in 2016.
we still don't know what happened to him
and you know maybe the person that reads
this is going to go reopen the case and
do something useful other than try to
you know break into your network and
you know be a scumbag but you know you
can drop stuff in here whatever you want
it to be
i really am curious what happened i mean
he jumped out of the airplane with 200
grand he probably lost it all but uh
you know they're still going to give 100
million dollar rewards so if anybody
knows
there's a there's a funny hbo
documentary about people that claim that
nowhere db cooper is
but they yeah they don't to this day but
that said hey
use your imagination whatever you can
think of that might be interesting
and might educate them this is what you
should do
cool
so now we've worked up to this point to
a seven layer dip or
of deception inception and this is where
it starts to get really fun and this is
where you tie it all together so the
idea here
for example you got an adversary who
pops say your
your actual web server maybe is running
apache struts it's vulnerable it has to
be on the web right now or something you
know there's so many situations you can
think of where you can upgrade this
because of that software dependency so
let's just say you're stuck with this
vulnerable server what you can do
is wrap it in tokens you can do things
like the netstat process which is one of
the first commands in adversarial run to
get situational awareness we can
actually wrap that in a dns token so
when they run netstat it'll fire an
alert
and and then it'll start to build
everything into your knee seam i'm such
a dork security incident event
management system and
then that's part one right so they run
netstat and then oh nmap happens to be
there that's helpful well
once they run nmap
they're going to hit a windows server
conveniently that's a file share let's
just say there's a document on there
that has some credentials
that give you access to a bucket
seven layers you're gathering all this
different disparate pieces of
information you're sending it to liam
neeson
and he will find you
and he will kill you or he will at least
turn the information
over to
the authorities and
you know this is just one example
there's so many things you could do
again this is why i love this is not
only does it
lean on your kind of like analytical
brain but it requires you to be creative
and think of different scenarios as a
bad actor of what you may do you know
what are you interested in if you have a
background in offensive security what's
your approach
and you kind of think of it from the
other side of well how am i going to
trip myself up and you're kind of
playing a cat and mouse game with
yourself and there's bonus points if you
have a team that you can constantly like
run these exercises with
because you're just going to keep
getting better at the end of the day
and
with that i wanted to
thank you all so much and open it up for
questions
and comments
[Applause]
it's all hand
yes
yeah absolutely i'm gonna
share it out on on sketch and um
also yeah you can hit me up on twitter
i'm not very big in the social media
world i'm pretty much a ghost however i
created an account so that i could
interact it's just at justin t varner
send me a message i love this stuff
i love security and i love coming up
with solutions you know i think my
generic title i gave myself a security
philosopher so i just think about
problems and
solutions and i think we all kind of do
that in some way but
yeah i'd love to talk
more about all of this stuff because
it's super fun
what else
bueller
[Music]
okay got a quite honest thank you guys
you're the best