good morning everybody
i'm the one right before lunch so lucky
me and everything i won't feel offended
if 30 minutes in you're like all right
i'm hungry uh type of thing but
today we're talking about pci
now
[Laughter]
um so obviously there's been a big
change with pci
in march they release a new one so we're
going to be talking about a little bit
of what the changes are how could it
impact the environment um things of that
nature
uh before that i'm justin leapline i've
been involved in and out of consulting
i've worked at a number of companies
where i had to deal with pci um i've
worked for an acquirer i work for an
issuer work for you know e-commerce you
name it i've probably done the standard
within pci i ran the pci practice at
trustedsec for about six years um so i'm
going to go through a little bit of that
stuff um working right now i'm actually
uh self-employed
working on a product for uh grc tool for
smaller companies um i'm an alliance
faculty and i actually just this week
launched up a roasting uh coffee
roasting company so like i didn't have
enough time you know to do anything else
i figured i'd do something else here so
let's get started
so first off uh we're not going to talk
about in-depth pci all this stuff
there's plenty of resources out there
we're going to strictly focus on the
delta of what 4.0 is bringing to the
table so if it deals with that and what
they're changing and everything we're
going to be talking about that
if it's the rest of pci how it impacts
scope and everything we're going to
touch a little bit on scope but more how
it's changing with it
the text i'm going to have it's going to
be pretty nerdy kind of bolted out with
this but my intention to this is that
you'll take this as a resource bring it
to your company and then you can use it
as kind of a checklist for when pci
actually comes to fruition you'll be
able to kind of check box it off within
your environment and do this so
keep that in mind also too from photos
perspective i have links at the end so
you can take a picture of that download
the full presentation so you don't have
to take pictures all the way through
just as an fyi
all right so what has changed so
they added 64 new controls into
4.0 so 321 was out there for years
now with 4.0 they're adding a ton of new
controls uh for merchants there's 53 of
them uh with that and then service
provider there's 11 that are strictly
for service providers um and if you
don't know what you know the difference
are merchants is if you're swiping the
card and that money's going directly
into your pocket you're a merchant and a
service provider is you're providing
services for
companies that are doing that so an aws
would be a service provider for
merchants that are being hosted within
aws
now there's a lot of different deadlines
to this
immediate when we say immediate is the
first time you're using pci 4.0 as an
attestation document so whether you're
doing saq or whether you're doing a
full-blown rock
immediate is the first time you're using
the 4.0 standard to submit for your
attestation those controls
become immediately effective when you're
first using that but there's a lot of
four data controls as well
and they are best practices all the way
up to march 31st of 2025 so there's
plenty of time for this um so there's
different varied degrees of that
so first off
one of the big changes is a customized
approach so what is the customized
approach so they have basically what
they call the defined standard uh which
is the typical stuff the stuff that's
already in there they say you should do
it this way
the straight pci one the customized
approach replaces the
compensating controls so if you're
familiar with compensating controls they
are i can't do it exactly the way their
a pci is telling me i have a business
limitation whether it be financially to
put it in technically to put it in and
now i basically have to come up with a
here's how i'm kind of getting around it
so if you can encrypt on your mainframe
you have to make it really hard to even
get into your mainframe to get that data
that would be an example of a you know
compensating control
with that so they got a rid of that
there is no limitation on
for that for you to be able to use that
you can use customize approach whenever
you want to say there's a new technology
that's all
behavioral ai and it eliminates all
viruses from all systems but it doesn't
technically meet any of the like
directly with that you can actually
produce a customized control say this is
why it's better we've done a risk
assessment here's where it goes you know
type of thing so in this if you see kind
of the requirements here you know they
have the defined approach that's a
standard you know control with that but
then they have the customize approach
objective so if you're producing a
customized approach a custom kind of
design to accomplish that objective
this is what you're aiming to accomplish
with this
now i will say reading through some of
these
they're not the best description of
these like sometimes they just re
reiterate what the defined approach is
it's not really the objective of like
keeping bad guys out or not exploiting
malware or something like that they're
just like you know mfa you should have
mfa you know it's like okay well what's
the actual like objective is to keep
unauthorized people out you know type of
thing they're just saying like you need
more than one factor as the
objective so it'd be interesting to see
as qsas we got a while until qsa start
to interpret this to see how they
actually
read into this because right now the
define of the customized approach is
essentially you need more than one
factor so if you're not doing initially
the 841 you need more on the factor you
still need more than one factor with
that
but you can see they do the
applicability reproach this is where
they do like sometimes limitations into
it so you'll see things in the
applicability uh notes that they'll say
you know uh this doesn't apply to point
of sale systems or this is only for this
type of accounts and everything so these
are good things that kind of reference
azure implementing some of the controls
so
what if you want to do a customized
approach customized approach sounds
great you know can't make it directly i
have this new innovative product or i
can't meet you know the the direct
control into this
it's a little bit of work to actually
get to that first off you have to fill
out a control matrix template which is
basically outlining
what you're accomplishing with this
control the testing
requirements and plan that you have with
that with it you have to do a targeted
risk analysis which we're going to be
talking about later they have a lot of
that through now the new requirements
you have to perform your testing now you
can offset some of this to qsa companies
or consulting companies but you're going
to pay for that obviously you know with
it most of the qsa companies i've heard
of
when you're going through especially
with a rock they're going to be charging
extra for any type of customized
approach control that you have into it
so there i've heard people they haven't
fully implemented this you know
but if you have a customized approach
it's going to be a dollar sign per
customized approach added to your cost
with that so just keep that in mind and
then maintaining evidence and then
you're going to have to retain that
evidence and the assessors are going to
have to look over all of that stuff to
be able to approve that customized
approach so some of the templates
with this so this would be the
control matrix
you can see kind of the what
requirements describe it you know
control implemented control performed a
lot of extra work you know to kind of
fill this out you know i'm not going to
go through this in detail but you kind
of get the gist of like it's not just
like hey i'll flip this you know and
it'll be all good there's a lot of work
that actually if you're serious about to
actually implement something along those
lines
and then the targeted risk analysis they
give a template also for this where it
goes through kind of similar to the
compensating control worksheet
identify what you're doing what's the
proposed solution
all that stuff one of the things i'd
love out of this is 1.3 describe the
mischief
that the requirement was designed to
prevent i mean
you know as some english person that
like threw that language in like you
almost think like oh yeah it's some like
evil guy with a mustache you know with
this you could just hear him laughing in
the background but what's even funnier
to this if you actually go to the
definition of mischief like right there
in the middle they give an example of
the mischief is an absence of policy
um and i'm like is that really a
mischief thing like
so yeah it's kind of wonky the way they
kind of describe you know some of these
things here
but you know the the the goal of it is
like if there's a lack of control you
know into it um and looking at that uh
from that perspective there
anyway back to the uh here
so yeah identify the requirement
describe the proposed solution to it
it goes on to analyze the likelihood so
it actually is a targeted risk
assessment you are evaluating on impact
likelihood everything along that lines
you know now
it's not a great calculation i mean
honestly 3.3 you just check the box on
is it more likely is it the same is it
less likely
type of thing um pci kind of allows you
to do whatever into that um
so and the way i know the qsa industry
is they'll probably just allow that as
your risk assessment you know if you
fill out this sheet
with it
and then uh changes uh to it and then
risk approval has to go up to executive
management to approve all this stuff
and keep in mind we'll see in the
controls later
this has to be redone every single year
for all your customized approach so it's
a
it can be good like if you're trying to
do something in the cloud or there's
some product you know that you really
want to utilize not fitting in directly
within pci this can give you flexibility
with it but it's not short of actually
the work that you would also have to do
to actually implement some of this stuff
so just keep that in mind
another thing too that we've kind of
seen this coming um
if you're familiar the cardholder data
environment you know was the typical
definition of systems that store process
or transmit cardholder data that's how
we define cardholder data you know now
they're also dividing cardholder data
that are basically in the same kind of
unfettered network access to around uh
systems that touch cardholder data um
now you'd say justin those systems are
already in scope they're you know around
that you know without any unrestricted
network access the problem is they were
classified as system components and
there are a handful of controls within
pci that actually call out on cd devices
like
administering administering
cde devices with two-factor
authentication internally with that now
this kind of expands the scope other
thing too is that say you have a shared
services environment like and you have
active directory into it or some other
shared services that's
providing service into the cde
if you don't have according to the qsa
or whoever's assessing that
good enough network access controls
between those down to what's business
justified you could basically turn that
system into a cde and then all of a
sudden that system spreads to every
other system in that network as well so
keep in mind like qsas as they're
looking at this it it could expand scope
quite drastically and it really comes
down to how
that definition of like uh network
access and down to business justified
this was something that they introduced
in the guidance documentation
a few years ago and
one of the things we did with our
customers that said well guidance
document had a disclaimer at the bottom
of every single page said this isn't the
standard and it actually contradicted
what the actual 321 standard actually
said
now they're basically pulling it from
the guidance implement it for sure in
this standard here
so just keep that in mind there
so new requirements this is where we're
going to spend most of our time
and i like answering questions so if
there's any confusion or just want to
get a clarification let's do this you
know right in the middle just catch my
eye and everything
so first off they've added
pretty much in every single section
roles and responsibilities performing
activities and requirement whatever are
document assigned and understood so they
kind of had this in requirement one they
actually reworded just to be this
for the network
sections with this that's why that
asterisk is kind of there
but the rest once they added this so you
can accomplish this either through
policy documentation assigning a team to
particular services
racy charts you know in a wiki something
along that lines more documentation you
have to do to you know uh show all these
controls into it
and
the way i kind of have this you know
applies to all entities so that's
merchants and service providers and then
the effective
is immediate so as soon as you use 4.0
as a at the station base you have to
have this uh done
other documentation uh with this um you
have to with your retention with any sad
data
keep in mind this is more to issuers if
they're retaining sad data
you have to have a way to actually clean
that up on whatever your retention
policy is so in card production which i
you know worked a little bit in that
time frame it's typically 30 days you're
allowed to store that information for 30
days and then you have to have a way to
remove it so that's basically just
calling it out into the dss that there
should be a way to actually remove some
of that stuff
there has to be technical controls that
you can't just remove pans through
remote access technology
essentially what this means is dlp you
know there can be other potential
technical means where you might be able
to limit access to dba
individuals and other controls that you
accomplish this but essentially this is
calling out
dlp you know for if people have access
to cardholder data they're not pulling
it over the vpn and putting it on their
local computer
with that
another one from a documentation
standpoint
you have to define your cryptographic
architecture so if you have any soft
hsms certificates anything like that all
has to be documented has to be cleared
to where um your keys are stored where
it's being encrypted
all that stuff and everything and this
is for service providers only but keep
in mind the common rule for service
providers only for this version of
service providers only for the next
version will probably be for merchants
too
for all entities they have to have an
inventory of all your trusted keys and
certificates so there has to be a
documentation pointing to where
everything is you know within your
environment for pci
another thing that's going to be a
little bit bigger you're going to have
to have an inventory of all your
software and all your
third-party stuff so that's custom
applications third-party libraries that
you're doing so you know if you've
followed this the the bill of materials
that they've been saying
all that stuff will have to be
documented and producible to the
assessor as well as any third-party
products that you're installing you know
onto the
onto your environment that has to be
patched into this
and then lastly on the documentation
suites and protocols um in use and
documented and reviewed so you know your
tls certificate you know what's the
cypher suites that you're using what's
the protocols you're allowed with that
obviously you can pull that but now you
have to have a formal document so peers
are approved tls 1.2 you know aes 256
whatever that may be
uh some encryption stuff um
so sad store electronic prior to
completion uh both 3.3.2 and 3.3.3 are
issuers um that apply to so if you're
sore and sad you have to protect it
strong encryption with that they didn't
directly call that out in previous
they're basically just filling in the
blanks you know to some of this stuff
hash is used this is a big one hash is
used to render pans unreadable have to
use salt now you can't just have a
straight hash for your pans
with that it has to be salted to when
it's storing in the back end now
a lot of people will say yeah that's
great you know to be able to do that and
everything which it is but there are uh
potential things that could actually
impact that whereas you know if you're
looking for if you're a grocery store
chain and you're looking for duplicate
card numbers
it's now hard for you to actually just
look in a hash table and say is a
duplicate hash in there because
everything's salted you know into that
perspective so just keep in mind this
could impact some processes
depending on how you're using that hash
another big one they specifically call
out in 3512
that you're not allowed to just rely on
disk or partition level encryption as
your encryption source unless it's a
removable drive so if it's a usb drive
backup tapes or something along that
lines you can rely on you know full disk
encryption ish you know uh with that but
you're not allowed to just store your
documents that contain cardholder data
on an s3 encrypted bucket that's not
allowed it has to be another layer of
encryption onto that that's at the file
level with them
and then certificates over um
just
can't be expired you know with this so
they i guess they had some problems with
this you know at four two one um they're
spa uh specifically just calling out
can't be expired even though it might
still go over tls 1.2 and get a warning
on the consumer they're saying like it
needs to be about cert
so this is one of the things that we
talked about with periodic reviews so
one of the most common terms that
they've added into this is a targeted
risk analysis
so they gave i showed you the example
they kind of gave and broke it down on
what they would do for a customized
approach
now a lot of things if you remember with
321 there was a lot of things that came
out like you have to periodically review
your you know
gas station pumps to make sure that
there's no tampering or substitution you
have to periodically review whatever
there's a number of components into this
now they're basically a lot of stuff
they're either calling out specifically
like you have to do this every seven
days or do a targeted risk analysis to
you know define your own
number or they'll just call out you need
to do a targeted risk analysis so keep
in mind this has to be reviewed
annually and approved by executive
management for each one of these so
targeted risk analysis on any systems
you deem
not applicable to
uh malware protection so linux systems
let's say you don't install any av on
linux systems you have to do a targeted
risk analysis on an annual basis that
say yes they're still out of scope for
uh anti-malware um
the frequency of malware scans they call
out continuous you know in the standard
now
but if you have an alternate like you're
scanning weekly you have to have a
targeted risk analysis
inspections on point uh point and
interaction device uh point of sale
devices
and then the determinant of the
frequency of log reviews and on all
other system components you have to
review it all on the
um the cde but you have flexibility when
it has outside systems with that
and then
[Music]
on how frequently
the targeted risk analysis so this is um
has to be performed to review that and
then uh met with a customized approach
that's three one three two uh what we
talked about with that
and then uh periodic training for
incident response personnel you have
flexibility on you know how often you do
that uh to individuals so there's a lot
of work with this we'll talk about at
the end like the
outside of some of the technical
controls and limitations that they're
implementing in this
a lot of this stuff comes from more
resources internally and potentially
externally on helping you basically just
maintain your security program and
building it up to where it needs to be
for 4.0 luckily we got some time
but yeah there's a lot of work to kind
of do this
going on further outside of the targeted
risk analysis periodic reviews
now they're adding in you have to review
user accounts and
and access privileges appropriately that
wasn't a thing in pci before now it's
sox world all over again you have to
review your access you know on a regular
basis um they're adding in system and
application accounts before pci didn't
really touch on this qsa's were kind of
like hey it shouldn't degrade the
security like you could just don't set
the accounts to password um you know
type of thing now they're specifically
calling out that application system
accounts are in scope and use they
should also be reviewed uh with that
hardware and software technologies are
reviewed so one of the requirements is
putting together a list of all your
hardware and software one of the main
things that kind of called the like call
this out is like when's end of life so
if you're using some windows system 2012
you're supposed to document like when is
end of life for this system and the qsa
assessor whoever it is
takes that and reviews it to make sure
that you're all within supported area or
have a customized approach you know that
you could also do with them
um
12.52
kind of was a requirement so if you were
ever going through and doing a rock up
in the top section the the kind of
requirement zero as we called it um
actually called out you had to review
your scoping and confirm it uh each year
now they're basically putting this as a
specific requirement so you can write
verbage directly to that
and
then the significant organization
changes with that and this is service
provider only you basically have to
review that and communicate to exit
executive management
um
sorry repeat one and then security
awareness program
um
has reviewed every 12 months and update
as needed so you can't use the same
stuff that you use for like five years
now it has to be updated we'll actually
cover a little bit that they've added
phishing as a requirement into this as
well
and then this is for sp only that if
you're logging into multiple customers
there has to be a separation between the
different customers you can't just be
connected to all customers at the same
time
type of thing
all right monitoring so
one of the bigger things that was also
added in is
monitoring your payment page for um uh
for like changes on all the scripts and
everything so this is content security
policy if you're familiar with this
outlining where you're getting your
scripts from if there's any remote
scripts you're doing you're pulling them
uh appropriately you it has to be hashed
so you have to verify the integrity of
it
there's a lot of work into that and keep
in mind we'll talk about this a little
bit later but they even add this into
the saqs as well and even into saqa this
is one of the additional requirements
into saqa which is basically have
outsourced almost everything
this is one of those ones if you're
doing an e-commerce page you'll have to
make sure that you have a content
security policy
no longer
can you have the option to do manual
review of logs or automated review
they're just calling out automated
review of logs which is a good thing
because
my firm opinion nobody really does
manual review logs and when we say
manual review vlogs we're basically
talking about you going into your syslog
server and looking at the logs and
validating that there's nothing wrong
nobody's really doing that you know type
of thing there's some type of automated
triggering system and triaging of those
that's what they're calling out it's
like there has to be some
um you know sim that's raising alarms
that you're triaging in that respect
there
um a lot of things that they got in in
three is
looking at
your security controls and calling out
when they failed um they're adding
things to that that if certain controls
fail you're notified and deal with it
accordingly so uh critical security
control systems are alerted detected and
dressed promptly and responded to
promptly
and then 11 they call out that you have
to detect through ids ips some other
means
you know edr
that there's convert malware
communication channels so um
you know
c2
you know with that um and just looking
at that and detecting and doing that
that's sp only right now but again it's
only a matter of time before it comes
merchants as well
and then change in tampering detection
mechanisms is deployed for payment pages
so specifically on the payment page
and it calls out once a week or you can
define it through a targeted risk
analysis you basically have to look at
your payment page and see if it's
changed and do something if you didn't
expect it to change so some type of
monitoring and kind of hashing of that
page and detecting whether it's changed
without you
without you being aware of the the
change to production
and then failures this is you know um a
couple of additions automated log review
mechanisms you know have to alert on the
failure of those and then code review
tools um have to look at that so if you
have a
devsecops pipeline and it's running to
look at third party packages static code
analysis if that fails you need to be
alerted that it has failed
do we need a break here i mean there's a
lot
and like i said my intention for this is
to give this to whoever wants it and
that way you can have kind of your
checklist to go through and utilize it
on uh the off so yeah the time frames
are you know nice that we got a lot of
time but
i wouldn't wait because there's a lot of
little things that are need to be done
within the next couple of years
for this so
um i think we're almost done here got a
couple more sections so vulnerability
anti-malware um
um
look at electronic media so when you
plug in a usb drive it has to scan it
most you know solutions have that
nowadays so it shouldn't be too big a
deal they're just calling it out um
mexican is a place to detect fishing uh
with that so you know that means email
protection you know on some of the
fishing perspective this wasn't called
out before now you have to have a way to
detect certain phishing stuff you could
probably do it through some edr um
aspects as well
but this is one of the things that
you'll need to measure with it
automated technology so wafts are now
required before it was a kind of you can
do an application assessment once a year
or do a waff now wafts are required you
know with anything that's public facing
it takes cardholder data
manage all other application
vulnerabilities they're specific calling
out application vulnerabilities um that
aren't high or critical risk so you have
to manage them they're not necessarily
calling out that you have to fix them
but you have to have an active program
to manage you can't say medium below
whatever you know type of thing there
has to be a kind of a determination on
are we going to fix it are we not is
what's a risk to the organization
um
another big one that's changing no
longer that vulnerability scans can be
just network based
it's either agent based or credentialed
based
obviously you know my preference is
agent based but you can have the option
to do credentials
around with them
and then 1147 multi-tenant service
providers
support their customers for external
penetration testing this basically came
about there's you know
some bigger players but they've modified
a lot but there's some smaller players
that if you have a you know remote
hosting data center or something like
that um they would like oh you're not
allowed to scan us you're not allowed to
do a penetration even though it was your
site and then was like well are you
doing the penetration test then like no
that wasn't part of our contract so
they're basically calling out like if
you're a multi-tenant service provider
you have to support your customers if
they want to do a penetration test and
just calling it out verbatim into that
identity and access control so this was
a little bit of one where they've um
intermixed um some of the uh nist 800
changes into it uh for good um for most
of it um some of it they didn't really
change as much as i would like but you
know so you have to manage we mentioned
application system accounts you know
into this um
you have to do a minimal of capacity for
passwords when used as an authentic
factor that's now up to 12
with that they do allow an exception for
systems that don't support up to 12 aka
mainframes you know type of thing and it
has to be at the maximum of that
with it they actually specifically
called that out in 836
they still have that passwords are the
only authentication piece it has to be
changed every 90 days you can adjust
that with a targeted risk analysis
but they still have the default 90 days
if it's a single factor to log into that
if it's multi-factor so if you're going
into your cloud environment and it's
always through multi-factor you can up
that to a year you know that you don't
have to change it or maybe not in like
indefinitely you can also
put in other factors where you look at
where the account is coming from so if
they're logging in from nigeria and they
never logged in from nigeria then that
would do some extra flag so you have
some flexibility in actually
implementing uh some of this stuff
um
multi-factor authentication for all
access into the cde um with this
so this is one thing that they added get
out that anytime you're going into the
cde you have to have multi-factor access
the change from the last system that all
they had was administrative access this
is basically anybody logging in so if
it's a accounting person logging into
a
you know a system that have a
spreadsheet of cardholder data probably
a bad idea but example with that
they have to do multi-factor so
mainframe access may have to do
multi-factor if they have a green screen
that you know is going through and
showing full card data and everything
yep
yep so the question was just to repeat
it does that include web applications
with it the answer is if you can see
full card data onto it the answer is yes
with that now keep in mind i believe
it's this requirement here in one of
those applicable notes
they say it's not applicable to ones
that only can see one card number at a
time
type of thing so if i'm a point of sale
you know with that i'm just entering in
one card at a time it's not applicable
to those but if you have a web
application that can look at a
spreadsheet of card data and say you're
dealing with chargebacks or something
like that that would be a applicable
control good question
multi-factor access on systems that are
on systems are implemented appropriately
so just making sure that you can't
escape around it i know the pci council
had a big problem at one point that they
had the multi-step authentication they
said both factors had to be
authenticated at the same time which is
really hard to do when you're doing like
push notifications for it they've
loosened up a little bit um if you
actually read the requirement but they
want to make sure that you can't like
escape around one of the factors you
know um essentially when it comes down
to it
um
manage interactive logins for accounts
used by systems or applications so if
you use a system or an application
account that's used for like back-end
stuff um if that is able to do uh
interactive access like it's going over
ssh or going in the application can
perform other functions
you need to manage those appropriately
same kind of thing you know the with the
addition of applications system accounts
are putting in all this stuff to say
okay you need to protect against misuse
so monitoring what they're doing no
escalate like proper privileges fall
into this um
uh with that
oh application and system accounts so
um and then multi-tenant uh confirms
access to any customer environment
that's logic separated so this is uh sp
only but again the same kind of
component with separating out that
access you know between your different
customers
and then i think lastly no we have a
miscellaneous one right at the end a
little bit on insulin response
that one you have to do
change and tamper detection mechanism so
we mentioned that if your payment page
changed you know
you should actually incorporate into
your instant response plan how to deal
with that so different things like that
if something's tamper detected you need
to have a response in your incident
response plan how to do that so a
playbook would work you know to specific
to that
and then incident response plan
procedures are initiated upon detection
of pan outside of the cde scope you know
so if you detect pan in your
share drives you know and it's not
supposed to be there you know you need
to have a plan to say okay we need to
analyze whole scope look at permissions
who had permissions with that is there
any you know out copying that was done
you know with that education just kind
of writing up something with that
and then have something this is uh
multi-tenant service providers uh for
basically this is a bug bounty thing you
know so if you have if you're a service
provider and your customers find bugs
you need to have a way to deal with them
and then a couple other things we
mentioned phishing and related and
social engineering attacks that's a
specific call out that now qsas will be
looking for that within your training
with it
and then training about acceptable uses
of end user technologies so that was
always kind of called out in the
acceptable use in requirement 12. now
they're calling that for the training
annually as well
and then third-party service providers
um
you know support the customer's request
uh to this um you know whenever they're
asking about their compliance you need
to respond to them
all right take deep breath we're through
the requirements here
got a couple other small things how are
we doing on time oh we're good on time
all right
so saqs so one of the things that's um
they're adding to saqs if you're an sq
fill out not only are they adding like
all the controls that we just mentioned
into this but they're also adding things
that were already existing controls one
of the biggest ones that i've seen so
far is that now
saqas which is basically like
20 30 i think it's 36 controls and a lot
of that is physical because they can
still take faxes you know under this uh
type
now they're adding that you have to do
acv scan so basically almost every type
has to do with asv scan this is going to
blow it up to a lot of different
merchants that have never done asv scans
before and probably have never run a
vulnerability scan as well in their life
so it'll be interesting to see how this
kind of grows you know into the industry
um because one of the biggest things
we'll talk about in just a second is
people missing their asv you know uh
timeline you're supposed to scan that
quarterly at least quarterly um if you
miss that all of a sudden it's a ding
into your pci
and report on compliance rocks so these
are the level one sometimes level two uh
merchants and service providers uh into
this so obviously we talked about they
did away with the compensating control
worksheet uh but that was one of the
sections that they did now they have
they replaced that and now they have in
place with remediation so what happens
if you're doing a customized approach
that's just in place they consider that
if that's all good and your customized
approach that's an in place control so
what is in place with remediation so in
place with remediation is anytime they
the assessor finds a ding against you
um they're going to expect you to
correct it and then they'll put it in
place with the remediation with a
description of why they marked you with
in place with remediation now
what will this happen is an impact
probably nothing you know type of thing
if you're compliant at the end of the
day and you fix whatever problems that's
fine you know that type of thing
but like some of the biggest things that
when we're doing um rocks for customers
missing asv scans you know that was one
of the biggest things we had our kind of
set company policy with this but it was
all over the place from a qsa standpoint
like i've even heard some things like
ridiculous like um we missed you know
last quarter's asv scan because the guy
that was doing them just left and nobody
picked it up so now we're gonna do and i
had a qsa tell me once it's like well i
guess you gotta wait for a year to get
compliant because you're missing one qsa
or one asv scan and you need to have
four quarters you know type of thing
that's not the way pci was designed with
this now they have a specific way they
uh essentially will do they want to make
so you have to be fixed you know with
this so the qsa just say oh you missed
just the last one okay that's fine you
know type of thing you have to run
another scan uh with this you have to
have a remediation to cover why that
failed whatever that may be
and then
the qsa will review that accept it and
put it in place with remediation
noting that there were issues with it
but you fixed it type of thing and so
some of the other stuff that
unintentional storage of like pan
outside the cde missing policies missing
networks basically anything that wasn't
compliant right out of the start they're
supposed to turn it into an in-place
remediation
so and then
here's a little bit of like just the the
heading so one of the things to keep in
mind qsa's are going to have a lot more
documentation work this is one control
and you don't start writing up control
until right at the very end all the top
part
is just filler information so first off
it's the selection of the boxes then it
goes into you know describe why the
assessment finding was selected and
quite honestly it's kind of worthless if
it's in place it's like because i
everything checked out like i got the
evidence everything looked good now it
might change with in place with uh with
remediation or not in place you know you
can describe like some of the stuff but
literally you have to describe why you
selected that which i think it's kind of
a worthless you know type of thing you
could describe it down below
and then you have to basically say
a customized approach or a
control used you know into this for the
defined or customized approach
with this so yeah it's uh it's it's a
little messy the biggest thing to get
out of this um you wouldn't be filling
this out you know this would be a qsa
company
but they're going to charge you for this
so i've heard some estimates it's going
to be like 30 more to what you're paying
right now for 4.0 um plus or minus you
know with this um and then it's even
more if you're doing customized approach
so just keep that in mind that you know
when this actually comes down into being
implemented there's going to be some
price hikes into it
so lastly close up here um you know a
little bit of pros and cons so the
customized approach i like you know that
gives a lot of flexibility to merchants
and service providers to actually do
some of this stuff some of the controls
were actually improved you know to the
way they implemented i think some of the
stuff that you know like uh monitoring
logs nobody really did it good manually
so like just eliminate that you know
type of thing um adding more monitoring
capabilities which you know if you don't
have a good monitoring program in place
you know it's not if it's when
oftentimes so adding more monitoring
stuff into it i think is a good thing
and it eliminates some of the qsa
discretion if you was way back but i did
a presentation on pci 3.0 one of my
slides was actually
slamming how bad it was of them doing
periodically like they just added a
whole bunch of work periodically words
into it now with the targeted risk
analysis they're at least taken out of
the qsa's discretion and putting it back
into the company and saying here's what
we think this means and here's our risk
analysis to support that so that's a
good thing
um
the cons are this going to be way more
work from a documentation standpoint a
number of controls are added
it's going to be higher costs you know
both from an internal resource and from
external costs if you have to pay for
that um
and then you're adding control levels to
the saqs that
i think from a you know smaller company
i've worked with companies that are like
three people you know doing you know
non-profit volunteer work and everything
now you're asking them to go get an asv
scan
they're going to be lost and they're
going to need a lot of help with this
to do some of that stuff and everything
so
that's it
so i made a notion site but that was way
too long they both go to the same place
so if you want to take pictures of that
um yeah that's fine and actually i did
not buy this domain just right now i've
had this for like five years so
but i figured i'd spare you the big hash
at the end so
yeah
so the requirement to when you have to
use 4-0 is march 31st 2024 that's when
you have to well it's actually april 1st
uh type of thing but you have until 2024
to still use 3-2-1
then you'll be required to use 4-0 and
then the you have another year for those
four dated controls to uh to implement
those and everything
if you're using like
if you don't have those controls in
place in that in between time it's not
applicable if you put it there um if you
don't have it in place if you have it in
place you can just mark it uh in place
so yep
immediate is like today you can actually
file with 4.0
you know but a lot of people aren't
choosing that because there's a lot of
immediate controls like as soon as you
file with the 4.0 templates um you have
to do all those immediate controls you
know type of thing um so that's why like
nobody's really filing with 4.0 right
now but there could be some later this
year next year you know type of thing
that you know as they're building up if
they already have those all in place
they'd be like okay yeah let's start the
transition into that type of thing
yeah so there there are a number of ones
i'd actually uh recommend they have a
summary of changes that they kind of
break down
yeah it's awful and honestly i
i dove a lot into this for the
presentation but
every standard it always surprised me
like they're like oh we just modified
for clarity and then you look at the and
you're like well that changes the
definition you know type of thing i
haven't seen too many of those you know
uh as of now you know type of thing that
really substantially change it to like
oh man this is really in scope like one
of the things they eliminated
was the
anti-malware should be on
commonly affected they eliminated that
verbage they basically said it should be
on all systems except for the ones that
like another controls except for the
ones that aren't really you know done
but you have to do a targeted risk
analysis so
kind of like it covers it under the the
terms but they modify the verbiage you
know type of thing um but yeah yeah
yeah
yep
so they did a kind of a cloud guidance
and it calls out some of the
segmentation controls into there but pci
does like they want to basically get
hands off on technology and talking
about that they basically talk about
principles of like okay least privilege
you know limited to only necessary you
know traffic all that stuff and
everything micro segmentation is great
especially if you can automate the the
maintenance of that you know type of
thing but it really just comes down it's
still segmentation at the end of the day
you know into that um so yeah
nothing directly but the guidance
thought they made a cloud guidance
document that comes the closest to that
correct
yep
yeah
so my recommendation on that if you are
shopping around for qsas look for
somebody that's very familiar with cloud
technology you know i've seen some and
nothing slamming you know a lot of that
i've had like
ex-cops come in and try to look at like
my acquiring information on mainframe he
never
saw a mainframe before same thing goes
for cloud like you get some qsas and
sometimes if they're soft you know it's
all right like okay here's our controls
and as long as they're okay with it
sometimes that's all right um but if
they start giving you hard notes like i
don't understand like how is it really
segmented show me your acls it's like oh
no the rules are right here oh i don't i
don't see where it's allowing port
whatever it's like well no you know type
of thing that's where you need to make
sure you have a good partner if they're
assessing in your environment so
okay out of time thank you everyone uh
come and get me if you have any more
questions