thank you all for coming today i
appreciate it
and thank you for attending the 10th
anniversary of b-sides pittsburgh that's
pretty cool
so
there's an awful lot to talk about
stopping ransomware and
threat hunting is part of it and
what i wanted to do today
was
talk a little bit about some of the some
of the threat hunting things that people
kind of miss
when it comes to ransomware
this actually started as a thread on
twitter so actually
twitter can be useful sometimes who knew
but it turned out to be really good with
a lot of really good advice and inputs
from a lot of people that do dfir for a
living so uh really appreciate it um if
you're wondering about the title i am
the ransomware smallier which means that
i do help you pair the right ransomware
with the flaws in your network so
you know if you don't have mfa enabled
i'll give you a nice lock bit um you
know whereas
if you have mfa enabled but maybe you're
not
monitoring your endpoint solutions i'll
get you a copy of alpha v or black cat
so
um
before we get into this let's talk about
the state of ransomware uh so far this
year we've seen
it's actually more like 1700 victims
posted to ransomware extortion sites um
and ransomware extortion sites for
reference are becoming
a less effective measure
of uh the number of ransomware attacks
in the world than they were in than it
was in like 2020 and early 2021 a lot of
ransomware groups
while some are relying even more heavily
on their extortion sites others are
others are
using less
using their assortment sites less
we've also seen 28 law enforcement
actions taken against ransomware groups
in the last year which is more than we
saw in the previous uh
five years combined
um so
and when we're we're talking about
even russia getting involved with uh
uh with arresting um some members of
rival and then of course a few months
later letting them go so that they can
go work for the russian government so
you know that's great
um but we aren't just seeing um
indictments and sanctions we're actually
seeing uh ransomware actors being
extradited to the u.s and you know
standing trial which is again great we'd
love to see that
but of course as you all know right now
it's not slowing down ransomware attacks
uh if anything other than a break in
june because even ransomware actors have
to go on vacation
we've pretty much seen an acceleration
in ransomware attacks this year so we're
still talking about lots of whack-a-mole
but the reason that i'm excited about
all the law enforcement activity that
we're seeing worldwide
is that
um
you know
whack-a-mole's a sport like any other
so if you go out to coney island or
kennywood i guess since we're in
pittsburgh if you got to kennywood twice
a year and play whack-a-mole you're
going to get okay at it but you're never
going to be really good at it if you
want to be a professional whack-a-mole
player you got to go out to kennywood
like you know every week and and
practice your whack-a-mole skills and
that's where i think we're doing we're
early on in that process and so the
sanctions the the you know
intergovernmental cooperation and all
that are having an impact
it's not as fast as we'd like but law
enforcement never moves as fast as we'd
like so i think it's good that we're
seeing that and i know we're all cynical
and infosec but i do think it's good and
i think eventually we'll see good
returns from this activity
one of the other things that's kind of
concerning this year
is in the last six months we've seen 60
new ransomware variants launched so 60
new groups
none of them using new code a lot of
them are using
stolen chaos code stolen county code
stolen rival code
but what we're seeing is a lot of these
new groups don't want to be part of a
larger raz organization
they saw what happened with conti and
the collapse of conti earlier this year
now karakoot mostly um and so what
they're doing is stealing the code and
starting their own
ransomware service uh
generally not offering raz they're
generally just hey it's us five guys and
uh and we're still gonna buy from
initial access brokers and so on um and
we're gonna go out and we're gonna run
our own ransomware operations
so
that may make things harder to track
going forward i mean every day on
twitter i now see or in some of my like
private slack channels and other places
i see people saying hey have you heard
of this variant have you heard of this
variant or have you heard of this
variant because we're just seeing so
many new ones pop up that it's really
difficult to keep track of
so we're also seeing ransomware go
global we're seeing ransomware out of
iran out of china
um uk and brazil with lapses and and you
can argue with me about whether or not
lapses is ransomware but
you know essentially extortion type
groups uh mandiant has a really fancy
word for it because mancy mandian has to
have fancy words for everything i forget
the phrase they use but it's like you
know extortion
groups or whatever and then we just saw
the report about maui operating out of
uh north korea um but of course north
korea has been using other types of
ransomware for years
uh so again extortion is super important
to these ransomware groups now um
more and more companies are doing better
with their backups shockingly it only
took us 10 years of yelling about that
to actually get them to implement
backups so it's great that we're
actually seeing those backups be
implemented and implemented correctly so
not backups oh we saved everything on
the file server that got encrypted we're
actually seeing more offline backups
where we're seeing
uh more backups that are immutable
we're seeing companies going back to
tape which is awesome tape actually
works really well ransomware actors
haven't figured out how to encrypt tape
yet i like that
um
so
that it's you know so that extortion
becomes more important and again as i
said we're seeing groups like lapses
that are extortion only they don't
actually encrypt anything they only
steal files and then demand uh
demand encryption am i moving too much
for you i know you're trying to stream
this i just want to make sure i'm not
like
i'm good okay
um so
if you can extort ransom demand from uh
traditional means uh that blackmail
becomes more important and so we're
seeing this explosion in the uh
extortion ecosystem not just the
sensitive files anymore but uh we've
seen things like uh false media
amplification so we saw this in the nra
ransomware attack last year where
grief paid for false amplification of
mentions of
the nra attack to try and drive
um
to try to try and drive attention to it
and then force the nra to pay
we're seeing some personal attacks i
know some researchers have been
personally
threatened by uh
by uh ransomware groups fortunately for
me i'm not important enough to uh be
threatened and i like that
we're also seeing ransomware actors
reach out to clients so especially in
schools this has become a big problem
they'll encrypt data for schools they'll
steal the data for schools and then
they'll email the parents and say hey
we're going gonna publish your kids
sensitive data to our extortion site
unless you tell the school to pay so um
so we're seeing a lot of these kind of
activities ddos attacks and so on are
really um are really growing in
popularity
and so that's what gets to
the heart of this
um
this the the the extortion
um means that threat actors have to
spend more time in the network and
because they have to spend more time in
the network that means more hands-on
hands on keyboard activity and more
hands-on keyboard activity means there's
actually more opportunity for you as a
defender to catch them
and
i won't sugarcoat this
good threat hunting is hard it takes
planning it takes
knowing and understanding your network
so it's easy for me to come up here and
say oh yeah yeah you got to do threat
hunting blah blah blah
get to it i know it's a lot harder than
that but it is worth it if you can put
together a threat hunting program
um we do need to talk about dwell time
though so dwell time for those of you
who don't know is the time that they
keep the the attackers spend inside the
network you will see over and over again
this quote of 43 days for dwell time
please don't take that as gospel it is
a lot sooner than that
it's not quite as soon as i know i've
seen like dfi report has uh has
published you know from you know initial
intrusion to ransomware in five hours
it's not quite that bad but generally at
least in the cases i've been involved in
it's you know maybe a few days to a week
is what we're seeing that's still plenty
of time
and your mileage may vary that's one of
the other challenges with ransomware is
everybody has a different view into
ransomware attacks and so what i see may
not be what you see may not be what
mandiant sees may not be what palo alto
sees etc but from what i'm seeing you
generally have a few days to a week
from initial access to uh
to when the ransomware is deployed um
so
and part of that is that distinction in
terms of activity from the initial
access broker to the actual ransomware
actor so generally there's two parts to
an attack the initial access broker gets
the access and they'll generally do that
you know we see this through phishing
campaigns uh credential reuse credential
stuffing attacks which are really really
big right now
straight up exploitation for
commonly exposed items and then of
course coming in through third parties
those are really the big things that we
see in terms of
uh in in terms of how that initial
access happens so that initial access is
that first part of that attack
um
and depending on how the initial access
broker works
you then have a few days to maybe a week
or two before the ransomware actor takes
over
so some initial access brokers work
directly for ransomware groups conti
famously
pioneered this activity where they
basically employ
employed contracted their initial access
brokers so that the initial access
brokers only worked for them
but a lot of other especially smaller
ransomware groups don't have their own
initial access brokers so they have to
buy on underground forms etc
we are seeing the number of ads for
for
networks for sale on open forums
slow down um and that's because most of
this activity are moving to private
telegram and talks channels um
just because uh
all of the initial access brokers know
that jackasses like me are watching for
all of these and trying to alert people
to let them know that hey your stuff's
for sale you should probably fix this
so so we are seeing more of this move to
private telegram channels and talks but
there's still an awful lot of initial
access broker activity which is really
interesting um
complete side note and aggression here
but just in case you're not scared
enough after coming to this event
i was talking to crain household who's
head of intelligence at abnormal
security at rsa and he's saying that he
was telling me that they're starting to
see business email compromise actors out
of africa reaching out to those same
initial access brokers to try and buy
that access because then they can send
their business email compromise emails
directly from the email server
which is going to be so much more
difficult to detect and uh find so
something to look out for going forward
that there may not just be ransomware
groups
uh using the initial access brokers we
may start seeing business email
compromise groups also using initial
access brokers um you know again in case
you wanted to didn't want to sleep ever
again
um so let's talk about threat hunting
unless anybody has any questions about
everything i've covered so far or thinks
i'm full of with anything i've said
no
okay
uh so this is basically what a modern
ransomware attack looks like
um as i already talked about initial
access generally phishing credential
stuffing credential reuse third party
third party is really big right now
we see so many ransomware groups uh or
initial access brokers that will get
that initial access
and they will um
they'll get that initial access and
they'll realize oh hey this this company
would be better to get access to their
customers than it would be to uh you
know than it would be to actually ransom
them so they use them to jump to a whole
bunch of other clients
exploitation uh recorded future tracked
52 different vulnerabilities used for
initial access by ransomware groups last
year almost none of which were zero day
they're common you know pretty much
well-known vulnerabilities with
proof-of-concept code so they're not
necessarily using zero days although
you'll hear about that because every
time they do use one it makes the news
most of them are just the everyday stuff
just people don't patch
things that are exposed to the internet
so please do that
insider threat is really interesting
because both lock bit lapses and yeah
both lock bit and lapses are very
interested in insider threat lock bit in
their note includes hey if you're
interested in
having us help us hack your company send
us an email and we'll give you some
money to do that
the good news is right now they suck at
it we haven't seen any
successful confirmed case of insider
threat we've seen some rumors that there
may have been some but nothing that's
been publicly reported in the one
publicly reported case was tesla last
year where you know the russian that
tried to do it got detained at the
airport and the fbi got involved
but the fact that they're very
interested in it means that this will
probably be more of a threat going
forward ransomware actors tend to suck
at things when they first start doing
them and then they get a lot better at
them because they do it a lot
uh so from there you'll see cobalt
strike we see some more sliver now or ps
exec as they move through the network
that's all the tools they use ransomware
actors don't like the command line
some of them do for the most part they
don't so we see a whole lot of remote
control through rdp teamviewer any desk
you know all of those down at the bottom
and then you know they'll get access to
all the servers they need they'll steal
all the files
they love mega dot io mega dot i i o in
any of its sub domains that's where they
love to send all of their data because
then they don't have to build additional
command and control infrastructure they
can just send it all up to there and
they can pay for their mega dot io
accounts
uh with bitcoin
uh then they'll run a couple of tests so
test a couple of boxes make sure that
the encryption works um and then they'll
you know encrypt your whole network as
much as they can um try and delete logs
and clean up
uh and then you'll have the extortion
site which can happen days later or
months later depending on the ransomware
group or it might never happen and just
because
some just because a victim never appears
on an extortion site does not
necessarily mean they paid most of these
guys english isn't their first or second
or third language and so they have a
list of keywords they look for
and i've seen a number of times where
they just pulled out crap data so they
don't even bother to throw it up on the
extortion site you know we had one we
had one client that i was helping that
they pulled up a bunch of old
old log data from systems that hadn't
been used since like uh
2005 and i asked them why they even kept
the logs but it turned out it was a
great honeypot because the ransomware
actor stole all that data and they
didn't care um so they had a good laugh
it's not very often you get to have a
good laugh when you're in the
negotiation chat with the ransomware
actors but they did have a good laugh
about that
um so when we talk about threat hunting
what are we talking about
we're talking about taking intelligence
that you get from some place so whether
it's a talk like this if you follow
florian roth on twitter and if you're on
twitter you should definitely follow
florian roth because his sigma roles are
amazing
but you know if you follow the dfir
report website they have incredible
intelligence that they deliver from
their attacks there are all kinds of
great places where you can get your
threat intelligence you can also buy a
subscription to record a future where
you have to have a booth right outside
the door but i'm not here to plug
recorded future you get your
intelligence from wherever you get it
from
you want to build your threat hunting
packages that look for the expected
badness
and
figure that the intelligence that you're
getting is not necessarily going to work
exactly for your network
so you're probably going to have to
refine your searches because you're
going to get some false positives you're
going to get some
um
you know there are going to be some
mistakes they're going to be some you
know
differences in the way every network's a
little bit different so there'll be some
vagaries in i got this state this
intelligence but my network doesn't
quite respond to this
and so
um we're going to uh
uh you know we're going to make changes
and then always provide feedback that
feedback loop is so important to
wherever you're getting your data from
hey you know you did this i just want
you to know that in our network because
we have this this didn't work and that
allows it to improve so that the next
person that gets that
that pulls that intelligence down will
have a more refined and better solution
this is especially true with like yara
and sigma rules
so again
good thread hunting only works
when you have good network hygiene in
place if you don't know what assets you
have it's really hard to hunt for them
and asset management's one of those
things
i'm old
i've been doing this for a really long
time and i've been talking about the
need for good asset management basically
since i've been in infosec
and we're still talking about it so it
still isn't to solve problem
unfortunately despite all the companies
that will tell you that they've solved
the problem
and so but you need to have good asset
management because if you're only threat
hunting part of the network you're
missing a lot of stuff
and
and it's always hard to tell people this
because asset management and you know
good vulnerability management isn't sexy
nobody's going to invite you to give a
talk at rsa or black hat because you've
managed to uh do good asset management
even though i feel like they should
because that is actually pretty
impressive um but you know you know
whereas like when i get to come up and
talk about threat hunting everybody's
like oh threat hunting is sexy i mean as
sexy as something an infosec can be um
especially when delivered by an old
white guy like me um
but
um
you know um but but without the basics
the the cool fun stuff doesn't work and
it's just going to actually make you
less secure
um and so what you want to understand is
how the how ransomware attacks work the
kind of tools that ransomware actors are
using and especially as those tools
change and then what detections work so
this is an example and and i like to
think of this you know kind of like a a
threat hunting is kind of like a boxing
match right you don't necessarily have
to
get a knockout in the first round it's
you know if you go to the second or
third round all those different stages
that we talked about before
if you go to the second or third round
as long as you get the tko in the end
that's what matters so wherever you
happen to detect them depending on your
capability and depending on what you
have in
uh you know in your network and and
that's the other thing i like to tell
people
one of the things i think we've done as
an industry that's kind of a disservice
is every time we are trying to solve a
problem we solve the problem by selling
you a box or an agent right um you know
so you know and this has been going on
for 30 years right oh hey people are
getting into your network here's the
firewall firewalls don't detect
everything well great here's an ids well
ids's don't detect everything well here
here's some endpoints protection well
that's not detecting everything well
here's a web application firewall here's
a proxy and then you wind up with 30
different things in your security tech
stack none of which talk to each other
so here now you have a sim that you can
send all the logs too oh but they don't
correlate very well things get missed
so
when you're doing your threat hunting i
always recommend people take the tools
that you have already and start
repurposing those for threat hunting
don't go buy new tools if you can't do
everything we're talking about here
today so like if you don't have edr so
you don't have a way to shove your rules
or sigma rules look at some of the other
things that that we're going to talk
about you want to start with the basics
get really good with those and then move
forward to the other things
so that being said
this is a great yara rule from dfir
report
on
detecting quackbot a lot of ransomware
actors have moved especially with
trickbot being all weird
have moved to ice id and moved to
quackbot for that initial delivery
mechanism through their phishing emails
um so you know so being able to detect
that initial entry is really important
you can stop the attack before they get
started
same thing with stock ghoulish so stock
ghoulers also delivered as part of
phishing attacks
generally you're downloading a
javascript compressed file but this is
another yara rule for detecting um for
detecting stock ghoulish
this looks for the specific
javascript hashes that were used
and uh
yeah so this looks for the specific uh
uh java uh uh hashes that were
associated with this and this was wasted
locker delivering
um the uh delivering javascript through
stock ghoulish early on there are other
really good yara rules sigma rules for
detecting stock ghoulish as well
power shell
we're going to be a little interactive
here for a second so hopefully you all
don't mind raising your hands
too many organizations i walk into don't
don't have powershell logging turned on
please do that doesn't cost you anything
i mean i know it costs you because
splunk charges an arm and a leg for
every you know extra line of log that
you collect but
um
remember when splunk was like the cool
vendor that gave out t-shirts at
conferences and now they're like
yo oh wow i can't afford my splunk bill
anymore please no offense to anybody
from splunk that works here you still
make a great product you're just super
expensive
but
ransomware groups rely heavily on
powershell scripts
so
if you can turn on powershell logging
and collect those powershell logging
it's a great threat hunting tool some of
the simple things um if any of you ever
take chris sanders uh
powershell hunting course which i highly
recommend or a threat hunting course
which i highly recommend he does a great
section on powershell but one of the
simple things to do is and again this
involves knowing your network
um
uh you know this this involves knowing
your network know what powershell
scripts are supposed to be running in
your network start with that okay these
are the knowns this is what's supposed
to be there and then look for powershell
scripts that
aren't supposed to be running in your
network that are only running on one or
two machines so that's a simple threat
hunting thing that is only required
your only required knowledge is what is
supposed to happen your network
look for anything that's either
disabling or creating new admin accounts
ransomware actors love to make new admin
accounts
look for um again look for new scripts
look for scripts running at odd times
ransomware actors love to work friday
evening and saturday evening because
they know the socks are are less staffed
and then what else so
for those of you that are doing
powershell logging and threat hunting
what else do you look for as part of
this yes sir
i'm sorry
yep
that's very good anything else
network connections that's another
really good one yes so anybody else
okay at least we got two i'm happy that
we've got some level of participation
here it means i'm not putting you all to
sleep right after lunch um
but you know really think about the ways
that you can use powershell logging and
what you know about your network to find
other things i will say one other thing
that
a lot of people don't catch and this
even isn't with powershell the first
thing that a lot of ransomware actors do
when they get in is they shut down your
security toll so they shut down your
antivirus they shut down your edr or
whatever most organizations don't set
that as a high alert so if another
process is shutting down your security
process so not part of closing the
normal part of you know shutting down
the computer but another process
shutting it off that should be a high
alert because generally the only people
who are doing that are bad guys and
employees that are trying to do bad
things so um
and and you know i know some analysts
will tell me no no no i have to do it
because i have to
um you know because i have to do malware
analysis or whatever you should have a
separate machine for doing that you
shouldn't be doing it on your work
machine connected to the work network um
so be looking for
a
av av system shutting down or security
uh
shell shutting down
again we mentioned the guise earlier if
you're not using these guise in your
network if you're not using screen
connect any desk splashtop or other
remote gui topics get those file hashes
look for those so you can feed those
into your edr and you can be looking for
that because all the ransomware actors
do is they download the executable from
wherever they keep their tools and then
they execute it back to wherever they
are in russia and
and keep working so look for those tools
and that should be a high alert because
again if you have an employee that's
using one of these guise they're
probably not doing anything you want
them to do anyway they may not be doing
something bad but they may not be doing
something that you want
uh cobalt strike cobalt strike cobalt
strike
um
we use we see so much cobalt strike from
the ransomware groups we're starting to
see a little more sliver
than um than we are uh uh than we used
to so sliver is another one and i'm
gonna put together a couple of slides on
that
um
and you know there was just a report
that some ransomware groups are using um
brute retell as well the creator of
brute retell denies that um so but it
still can't hurt because that the worst
that happens is if you find any brute
retell in your network the worst that
happens is you catch a red team doing
red team things and congratulations so
um so look for any of these tools that
are being used by uh
that are being used by these ransomware
groups these red teaming tools that that
the ransomware groups like to use
um so this is an example of
uh
of looking for cobalt strike loader
um but then this is a great one from
kyle kuchi i love this because this you
don't have to have any kind of yara
sigma capability
this looks for
this looks for the name d pipes so by
default and
interestingly most ransomware groups
keep the default settings in their
cobalt strike because they don't
necessarily know how to use it well they
just know how to use it and the tool
itself works really well
but looking for these default pipes that
are formatted as msse dash four digits
dash server
look for event id pipe created and 18
pipe connected for these alerts you do
have to turn on sysmon in order
in order to to catch this level of
logging and again i know making you have
more logs and collect more logs is easy
for me to say but hard on your budget it
is worth it and the type of data that
you can collect with sysmon and using
the system journals tools can be very
beneficial
ad find is another one that ransomware
actors really like we see a lot of ad
find and bloodhound so again going back
to the other slide where we walk through
any of those tools basically you want to
look for them and you want to look for
them in all of the different various
forms uh whether it's leo i mean uh
uh you know some of these you can inject
into memory some of these you just
operate as an executable on the ground
etc some of them have been converted to
scripts
to script formats so whatever those
forms are
you want to look for those but add find
is one that goes unnoticed by a lot but
i do see it in a lot of ransomware
attacks
then data transfer
if you are not using mega dot io for
anything legitimate just block it and
all of its domains
um the ransomware actors love mega dot
io again because they can pay in bitcoin
it's cheap and they can upload unlimited
amounts of data from your network
and so any of the mega dot i o mega dot
nz and there's like 10 other domains
that are associated with them find all
those domains and just block them that's
an easy thing
understand ransomware actors will figure
out a way around that they can set up
their own command control server and
exfil the data that way
but at least you've made it a little
more difficult for them um and most of
the organizations that i talk to and
that i've worked with don't actually use
mega dot io for internal file transfers
even though they do have business
accounts most of them are using um you
know some you know using other services
but along with that look for the tools
that the ransomware actors like to use
to compress and and exfil the data
rclone 7-zip mega sync and other file
transfer tools like that there's quite a
list of them that the ransomware actors
use
um so look for those and again look for
those on your network get the file
hashes because they're using the
legitimate versions of these tools so
the file hashes are publicly available
and they don't change very often which
is nice
and again that only works if you know
the tools aren't being used by your
internal admin staff obviously you don't
want to
um you know falsely flag anything in
your uh that your it staff or your
security staff may be using
shadow copy deletion i almost hate to
include this
because this is kind of like
you know this is kind of like your last
ditch effort but you know i'll throw it
out there just because you have it
um
every ransomware group that i know of
delete shadow copies right before they
start the encryption process
so deleting shadow copies is absolutely
a sign
that you are about to be hit with
ransomware the problem is
that it's a sign you're being hit with
ransomware now so for most organizations
if you have an alert like this set up
it's going to travel through the logs
it's going to go through yours it's
going to go to your sim it's going to
bubble through the sim process 15
minutes later you you know if you're
lucky 15 minutes later you're going to
get an alert that says hey
shadow copies have been deleted on the
server by then it's too late they're
already halfway through encrypting the
machine and probably other machines as
well so i hate to include this as a
threat hunting detection
but
if you can maybe stop you know to limit
the damage especially if you have good
network segmentation which
most networks i walk into don't
unfortunately but if you have good
network segmentation this does help
limit the damage there are some tools
out there again florian roth makes one
that will automatically delete any
process that tries to delete shadow
copies um
and and there are ways to configure your
edr if you're using edr that hey if
something deletes shadow copies kill
that process and send the alert and then
isolate the machine from the rest of the
network so you can automate that and if
you have those automation capabilities i
highly recommend taking advantage of
that and that's all i have i know we're
a little bit early
so i'm happy to take any questions
um if anybody has any but otherwise i
really really appreciate everybody's
time and attention especially right
after lunch so i appreciate everybody
who managed to stay awake with a full
stomach
thank you
no questions
awesome
yeah
yeah no
that's a that's a really good question
um
i like to have a conversation so i'm
part of the the csr team at recorded
future and we we have to do this all the
time where i like to have this
conversation with hey this is a known
bad tool but i know that our developers
also use it so
i mean generally what i do is we we have
these are the developer machines and
these machines are authorized to have
7-zip installed
everything else isn't it's not a perfect
solution but that way i know if our edr
catches anything
outside of the developer solution
then um you know then you know outside
the developer network then that we
should investigate and you know and what
i count on is we implement
a bunch of these protections
uh so that if we miss 7-zip we've
hopefully caught something else
but that's a really good question and
it's definitely a problem
yes
i'm sorry hold on i want everybody to
hear that because i think that was a
really good point
do you mind
thank you
since
earlier this spring zoom actually
extracts with 7-zip now
oh i had no i did not know that
which creates a massive problem for the
monitoring of exfiltration yeah so
something for everyone to think about
how do you
how do you monitor for that now
box zoom
but you know
in a covered
no no i mean that that's a really good
point and thank you again that's
something i didn't know so it's good to
have that additional information and
monitor for that so thank you any other
questions
all right well again thank you all very
much and i hope you enjoy the rest of
the conference