can you switch to my feed does it is it
good
hey all right it works
all right we are going to get started
so those of you that aren't here yet
just let me know when you get here but
we'll just we'll go ahead and continue
from from that point on
um welcome to
securing kubernetes or what i like to
call
the great spaghetti monster the flying
spaghetti monster uh or whatever
friendly little name you have for it i'm
kat fitzgerald um
i have been doing this for a very long
time how many people
go back to defcon 3.
okay i'm gonna leave now because i am
very old
um
wow oh well um yeah i run b-side chicago
i'm also part of the b-sides pittsburgh
team woo-hoo
so yeah i've been doing this stuff since
defcon 3 which is a very very long time
ago
google is a very uh is our premier
sponsor for b-sides pittsburgh if you're
looking
i am hiring i have a very large team at
google so i'm just throwing that out
there
come see me later i'm based out of
seattle
honey pots and refrigerators are
something that i love to play with a lot
especially when it comes to
kubernetes because i use kubernetes for
deploying some of my honey pots
and i love to cook and the reason i put
that up there is just last weekend when
i was
home
i
decided i wanted to put up a new spice
rack in my in my kitchen so what do you
think i don't know is it
pretty cool huh
okay
anyway uh my disclaimer the views and
opinions here are mine and mine alone
have nothing to do with my employer or
current or past
um and anything that i share from the
standpoint of security vulnerabilities
etc please always take them with a grain
of salt do not go and commit crimes only
do things to systems that you have
control over
and you have legal rights to do so
so why are we not here today well i'm
not going to solve all your kubernetes
um security problems that's not going to
happen in 45 minutes
neither will the person and even though
it has crossed out sitting
that's because i never know if i'm going
to give this talk virtually or what it's
going to be but it's so cool to see
people again so welcome all of you back
to besides pittsburgh
and something that i like to say is is
common sense kind of went out the window
a long long time ago uh
part of that is is or that is one of the
problems that we have to deal with we'll
talk about that so why are we really
here well kubernetes for the most part
people are still getting into it it's
still kind of new the reason i say it's
new is because it's always changing and
everybody's still kind of figuring it
out and you never know
but it's fun
and there are very quick and dirty ways
to get up to speed on kubernetes if you
happen to be running ubuntu you can
throw microcase on your system or even
on a mac or pc you can have it up and
running in a matter of five minutes or
so
so think about that containers are not
new
and this is part of the problem
if i were to ask you right now
which is more secure
a virtualized system
or a container based system
what would you say don't answer that but
think about that question
okay
and security is for everyone
i like to say that because i like to get
people interested in doing security and
i lied common sense is required so
please disregard my previous slide
okay
um
something to keep in mind when we talk
about kubernetes most breaches are not
zero day when you look at all the
breaches that we see today
they're not really fancy they're not
caused by these these zero day attacks
and so on most of the breaches don't
come from ooh somebody ran a
vulnerability scanner and figured out
that that there was a problem and then
they broke into me and and so on no most
problems come from configuration issues
and configuration issues when you start
to think about kubernetes
are huge and containers okay a close
second happens to be compromised
credentials
i still
go on github you know once a week or so
and i just search for keywords like
password or root
or aws or token or things like that see
how many occurrences you will find
and then the third trailing um
compromise is over privileged accounts
this is also important if you're going
to be deploying kubernetes in the cloud
i don't care which cloud you do it in
well i do but
no which cloud you do it in it's going
to be a problem because a lot of people
just go
oh wait what are all these i am
permissions what oh gosh you know i
really need to do everything so i'm just
going to give my account everything and
it's like root okay fine
how many people still log in to root on
their linux box and do all their work
all day on route
uh you're all lying
kubernetes really has all three of these
types of events that can cause
incidents so we're going to look at that
as we go
by the way if you haven't figured it out
yet yes i do like cat memes
i don't know why
containers we have to kind of start with
containers before we get into kubernetes
containers are not secure by default
when i do interviews of potential
candidates
i typically will ask the question that i
just
gave you a few minutes ago is a
virtualized system
or a container-based system more secure
and several years ago i asked this
question of a particular candidate and
another company that i was working at
and they swore up and down
that if they took their application that
had vulnerabilities
and they moved it into a container
that the container would fix all the
vulnerabilities of the application
and i kept trying to get them to explain
it to me how it would do this
they went through a very long
explanation which ended up as c the
application is now secure and i was just
like
huh
because containers are not secure by
default and they don't change if you
have an insecure application so please
keep that in mind but
when we work with containers we have
resources think of a container as a
grouping of these resources or a
grouping of stuff stuff equals resources
resources are named spaces
if you do not apply
certain
controls on your namespaces you will
have an insecure container okay
namespaces will contain things like
processes cpus network ports all these
various things
resources can be exploitable
what if you have a container sitting on
a system that has oh i don't know 20
cpus on it and and you know um a hundred
gig of memory something like that but
you don't put any limits on cpu or
memory usage of a container and somebody
either tries to do a denial of service
against that container the the
application in the container
or they actually break into it in some
way well they bring down the whole
bloody container and the system so
always remember that resources are
exploitable so first thing we're going
to start is to look at how we secure the
container we're going to do that with
control groups control groups are limits
so we want to apply limits to these
control groups
come on
there we go
so if we're looking at a container you
know how hard it is to get a cat to do
this
okay that wasn't easy
when you when you think about a
container think about it as a file
system snapshot well where does the file
system come from
oh sure we're just going to do docker
run
and we're going to pull it from wherever
from the internet
how many of you were around
some of you look like you were around
when um docker hub was compromised
and we were pulling compromised images
from docker hub now we have to be
careful there but who's going to decide
where your file system snapshot comes
from
well we probably want to strip it down
and if you've heard of cis benchmarks
which i have the link for it coming up
in a little bit
we want to use the cis benchmarks for
either docker containers container d we
want to strip down
the version of the file system that
we're going to run within our container
that's number one
container isolation okay
we need to do it it's not going to
happen by default so when we look at
this the picture kind of shows us
you know where it all comes from where
we have our name spaces and our
containers and so on
anybody notice if i were going to threat
model this
where's probably
the most dangerous point of attack on
this slide
anybody want to take a stab at it
let's see if this works wait hey there
it is my docker registry right there
because if that registry where i'm
pulling everything gets compromised and
or it is not private and controlled
within my environment no matter what i
do with kubernetes i'm going to be
deploying insecure containers
somebody dropped their watch
okay so keep that in mind
all right container best practices
before we get into before we get into
kubernetes the base image itself i
already said it you need to secure
the repo
so you don't want to be using just some
public repo somewhere sure when you're
playing and learning and so on yeah but
don't be doing it in production also cis
is everybody aware of the cis benchmarks
who isn't who has never heard of cis
and there are some people in here go to
cissecurity.org
cis is the center for internet security
it is an organization pretty much mostly
volunteers and they work on contributing
to the benchmarks for best practices of
security on the cis center you will find
everything from security of basic
operating systems of containers of
kubernetes
you want to start there you want to
start securing your environment by using
cis benchmarks
in some cases it's difficult to do
because you have to do it manually
unless and i don't work for cis or
anything
you have to pay for a subscription and
you get automated tools that help you do
it in an automated fashion honestly i
just suggest people support it and get a
membership because it does make your
life a lot easier
okay
please keep in mind don't run containers
as root
i still see people doing it when i'm
doing security evaluations of kubernetes
environments or just of containerized
applications i go wow look the container
is running as root oh joy
this is going to be fun
coming
visibility
think about this
you're gonna you're gonna deploy a
kubernetes cluster it's a kind of a
complex thing has a lot of moving parts
which we'll see in just a second how are
you gonna monitor all of that
there better be ways to do it we'll talk
more about that in a minute
think of it as kind of a domino effect
because what tends to happen
when you're deploying out into a
kubernetes cluster and you're using it
to get
extra stability in your environment so
on or additional
scalability if one of the containers
falls you can pretty much guarantee that
most the containers are going to start
to fall when you're talking about
insecurity why because well you probably
deployed those containers from the same
place you probably used the same file
system snapshot
to make them secure or insecure
okay
privileges
probably
still one of the biggest problems when
it comes to containers why because
people end up putting out
insecure applications that they get
compromised then an attacker once
they're inside they find a
that it was launched via
a username that they can then elevate
privileges well there are very simple
settings in containers
that say basically do not allow any new
elevated privileges and i'll show you
that in a second
secrets management
uh
several years ago i i had some engineers
come to me and they said well you told
us we couldn't um keep our tokens out in
github
can we go ahead and put user names and
passwords in the configuration yaml
files that are out on github
i said wait wait what
no please don't do that
secrets management use vault use
something
and please
when you're doing a kubernetes cluster
and you create some nodes that you're
going to then deploy kubernetes to
stop
allowing ssh into those worker nodes
because if you think about it
i've got a whole bunch of nodes that i'm
now going to deploy kubernetes on
they're set up to allow ssh
you launch kubernetes
and you have monitoring turned on such
as kubernetes dashboard but if i ssh
into the worker node directly your
monitoring doesn't see me
so i could then compromise your
application
and all this fancy monitoring that you
have with kubernetes won't necessarily
see me because i'm kind of running under
the radar a little bit
so once a system is deployed you do not
want ssh on the worker nodes
okay
namespace limits i talked about it a
minute ago we're going to look at some
of these but we want to have them
here is a great tool it's called docker
slim
docker slim will actually take a
container and the application
you run it through docker slim and let's
say a docker container might be oh i
don't know 300 meg when it's deployed
you run it through docker slim you're
going to end up with maybe a 10 meg
image that gets deployed
saves you a lot of wear and tear in your
environment so take a look at this tool
okay
often
overlooked how many people know what se
linux is
how many people
turn it off when they install a new
linux server
oh come on i know all of you do
why because well you turn on se linux
and you start to run applications and
they start to fail they don't run
anymore they can't open ports and things
because sc linux has not been configured
properly
i've asked other um you know sres and
system administrators and so on why do
you keep turning it off and they'll say
because it's hard
well
um take some time learn a little bit
about it learn a little bit about app
armor one or the other but in kubernetes
and in containers you can turn it on
and it will help prevent things such as
privilege escalation remember the number
three
problem with um
config or incidents and remember the
infrastructure this is ding ding ding
for the win
in other words
your if you're deploying on an
environment that is insecure by default
no matter what you do to your kubernetes
cluster
it's still going to be insecure if i
have telnet running on on all my systems
and then i deploy kubernetes on these
systems
well it's not going to be very secure
so please keep that in mind make sure
the operating systems that you're
deploying your kubernetes cluster to
have been configured securely
okay
so here's that picture again uh well not
again here is the picture that describes
the question that i asked a little bit
ago where
which is more secure a virtualized
system or a kubernetes or container
based system well we see in the first
part you know we see oh we've got
hardware we've got an operating system
and then some applications running on it
we now come to a virtualized system we
have a hypervisor level and then we
build virtual machines on top of that
well there is much more isolation
blocking
within a hyper or within a vm based
system
when you go to a container all you've
got a container run time system if i can
compromise this system then i can most
likely get to all of the containers or
if i can compromise a container i can
very possibly get to other containers if
i compromise a vm
does that mean i'm going to get into the
other vm no it's a completely separate
operating system i could be running
linux on one and
windows on another
people still run no never mind um
so the point here is is yeah a vm system
based system is going to be a little bit
more secure assuming that the hypervisor
is secure that that is an issue yes i do
take that into consideration
uh but
i really have a lot more ways to get
into a container based system especially
with kubernetes
okay
i don't know this this came out years
ago but i still think it describes
kubernetes
in
a great way because if we just inundate
them with quarterly kubernetes releases
hell
it's it's
just going to be
you know security god they keep changing
it um but that's what we're gonna do
there are a lot of releases of
kubernetes so let's see how it's gonna
make things interesting
so kubernetes in a nutshell we have a
master node think of that as the manager
of all the things okay
we have worker nodes and remember worker
nodes are going to be the things that we
want to make sure we we keep those very
very secure we don't want them running
extra services underneath the containers
we only want them running
the the parts of kubernetes that it
needs
we have pods pods are a very interesting
concept and they are often overlooked
when it comes to security think of a pod
as an isolation chamber
so i don't want to have a pod that is
running both the web facing application
and the database
that is being controlled by this web
facing application i want to have a pod
that is dedicated to maybe
hmm
oh maybe the web apps and then a pod
that is is controlled for just the
databases or maybe i'll have a pod that
is specific to dev and a pod specific to
qa and a pod specific to production why
because they're isolation realms so i'll
show you that in a second
services
services are all the pieces that we need
to make kubernetes run and then there's
going to be some very
specific main components we're going to
look at
probably the one that we'll talk about
the most at cd right there
it is indeed something that is
overlooked
and often not well protected and that is
the keys to the kingdom when it comes to
kubernetes
so
here's i like to say you know picture is
worth a thousand words and it is in this
case because it takes that previous
slide makes it a little easier to digest
because when we look at the master node
and what we see on it
that's where we're controlling it with
kube cuddle uh or coug control as some
people like to say
but i'll say coop cuddle anyway
we're going to control the master node
and notice that xcd is actually drawn
like a database and in a way it kind of
is all your credentials all your things
are are there we want to protect that
we want to protect that like like it's
fort knox you know put firewalling
around it and do everything the master
node is where we're going to control
everything that's where the scheduler
runs we have the api that allows us to
talk to it and talk to all the other
things so we want that pretty well
hardened
our worker nodes contain kublets
i i love all the names of in kubernetes
it's just so fun to say kublets
anyway but we have kublets that run
and a common mistake in the beginning is
that people will will do their darndest
to open a couplet to
the the internet they want to open it
internet facing in some way it's hard to
do it can be done but no that's what
coup proxy is for
good proxy is the thing that's going to
allow our traffic into the kubelets okay
but see how the pods
here this is where
we want to isolate things because a pod
is how we want to group our applications
or our environments if a pod falls
it should not take down the entire
environment
okay
um whether it's dev or prod or who knows
what it whatever it's going to be okay
so you see you have multiple worker
nodes um and then docker is running in
there or container d it's all very
similar
so yeah that kind of explains or gives
you a slightly better picture
of what those concepts were on the
previous slide but let's talk about
common sense and how we can now secure
kubernetes okay
first and foremost
tls everywhere
it is possible to configure things so
you're not using tls huge mistake did i
put too many exclamation points there i
don't know
i run into situations where i'm
analyzing a cluster
and i see connections and they have not
enabled tls and my simple question is
why and they say
just
didn't get around to it
i'll get to it later
something like that they never get to it
later
how many times have you said i'll get to
it later and then you don't get to it
i'll raise my own hand
in that case
harden the infrastructure remember i
already said that okay
enable our back
all of kubernetes uses role-based access
controls you enable it with least
privileges disable the asset based
access controls this is
you can do it but
it adds a layer of complexity that just
makes it much harder
i'm not even going to get into it
and you need to monitor everything i
have an example of a great tool i happen
to like it's open source called wazoo
and they have a blog entry that they did
on
monitoring and auditing kubernetes
that's one of the first and foremost
things because most people that are
installing kubernetes are just
forgetting about the monitoring part
because they think oh it's going to run
just fine not a problem
and then
this command here the cube cuddle get
roll binding all name spaces
every time i deploy
a kubernetes cluster i'll run this in
other words this is trust but verify i
want to make sure that all the name
spaces that i have configured remember
the namespaces are part of your your
containers
i want to make sure that all my role
binding and all my accounts and our back
is is set up there are some tools on
another slide coming up i'll show you to
do that
you could use a third-party auth server
for
the api
in other words you could set up
something outside of the kubernetes
cluster don't use the built-in auth
server for doing authentications for
your api calls
hmm
that gives you an extra level
of security that you could put in i
don't have enough time to go into all of
that in a 45 minute session but think
about that if you are in a really really
this has to be as secure as possible i
would definitely do that okay
separate and firewall your xcd cluster
the xcd make sure it is protected from
any and all intruders and you have an
extra level of monitoring on the xcd
cluster
if that is compromised
pretty much keys to the kingdom
rotate your encryption keys use
something like hashicorp vault i like it
it's open source it works great
um
linux security features i mentioned this
before but in the configuration of the
pods there is an option pot for pod
security policies where you can enable
either se linux or app armor it's off by
default enable one
it's not that hard
it will solve so many of your problems
kube cuddle get secrets this is one of
the commands you want to run when you
first install your environment
well
this is a better way to do it it's an
easier way there are some open source
tools that will allow you you run these
it will kind of audit your configuration
and it's going to tell you what yeah
you've got some problems here
um you've got some over privileged over
privileged accounts or oh here's one
without a u without a password or
something you know so run these
and make sure all your accounts are at
the proper privileges they have the
right access controls
there are
some
now i'm not going to say it i i'm going
to skip over that part about github for
right now i'll come back to it
um your image repos remember the repos
they have to be secure those are the um
your docker registries
okay keep those secure
um all of the libraries i mean think
about your supply chain where are the
libraries coming from that that are
getting installed here
application
i watched a team
build an incredibly secure kubernetes
cluster once
and then they installed an application
that they deployed
which they had never done any security
review of it they never ran any
vulnerability checks on it nothing
so the first time i i got into it i
started looking and i went yeah but you
have sql injection
right here on the application and i just
got into the container and i can now do
remote code execution and i've now taken
over your entire kubernetes cluster and
they were like how how'd you do that um
because your application was insecure
minor problem please don't forget the
application
just because you're deploying it with
kubernetes and think about pods think
about using them for isolation
and i can i mean i can't say it enough
also i mean
how many is everybody here know about
showdown
if you anybody not know about showdown
if you've never used showdan
showdan think of it as the web crawler
of all things internet it will go out
and i i use this in my honeypot talks as
well because you can go to showdown and
search for all the
opened webcams of the world and and
things like that but you can also search
for
um you know nsa uh toasters and and what
have you but showdan
you could actually go to showdan and
search for
xcd clusters that are open to the
internet oops
you might find quite a few
because most of the time it's people
that have just oh i'm playing with
kubernetes i'll deploy something
and they just take all the defaults so
it's not very secure and yeah they leave
it up there running and they don't
realize it but sometimes you might even
find some production level kubernetes
clusters that are completely exposed
so i use shodan just for looking and
searching for those types of things i
like to if there's some way of figuring
out who the owner is i'll i'll report it
to them
so don't be afraid to use showdown to
look for your own stuff
come on there we go
configurations
all right um remember most the breaches
come from configuration issues here are
your links and where you want to get the
cis benchmarks for hardening your
environment and i will tell you right
now
besides learning how to harden the
environment
you will learn all the configuration
commands and settings and things like
that by looking through the cis
benchmarks you will learn more about the
configurations
by just going through these than if you
would reading some huge kubernetes book
or something like that so take the time
to look at first docker
and then kubernetes
look at how to secure the container
first
and then how to secure kubernetes
okay so you get the idea
i i don't know if anybody was here in in
the very first talk this morning on the
cissp but one of the things they talked
about was what kind of a learner are you
are you a visual learner you know are
you a thinking learner what how do you
learn things better
or more easily and i i sometimes think
that actually going through these
benchmarks i learn a lot more about
whatever the thing is
because it explains what you're really
trying to harden it against what is what
is the threat that this configuration
change will protect against
okay
what about automation i don't want to
put all these things in by hand
well there are some ways to do it
although my cat is frightened about
automation
what if you use jenkins or some tools
similar to that there are some open
source tools that will plug in to
jenkins and they will take and do things
like analyzing the image that you're
actually deploying it will analyze the
container configuration to see if the
container is secure or insecure
so keep that in mind it's going to help
you to deploy something that's very very
secure
or
more secure than it would be if you
happen to use jenkins or similar tools
like that
okay
some additional tools
let's say you you just installed your
first kubernetes cluster you want to
know is it secure um
love aqua security they have cube bench
this is something that's going to run
and tell you have you applied all the
cis benchmarks correctly
or did you not apply any of them
okay
run it against a master node a master or
a worker node okay there's another tool
called coupe audit
this will be a little more granular
this is going to show you where you've
gone wrong maybe you forgot to to do
some of the configuration changes that
cis benchmarks suggested
okay here's an example
when you start to look at this you can
see that if this works yeah there we go
oops
the read only root file system wasn't
set
see there's a common configuration
setting where
you can set the root file system to be
read only
we don't want them because what's on the
root file system of a container it's
going to have an etsy password file it
is going to be out there we don't want
that readable
i'm sorry we don't want that writable i
guess we do want it readable
we just don't want it writable
but you see how it's it's telling you
and you start to go through
all the little configuration settings
this is part of the problem of figuring
out containers and kubernetes is the
fact that there are so many
configuration settings that's why i say
start with cis
start to go through the ones that you
really need and then run the audit tools
so you start to see oh
mistyped one or forgot to set one or i
set it to yes when i really meant no or
something like that
okay
some other tools that are available
claire this is a static analysis tool
for the actual application containers
very useful clar which actually
integrates claire and your docker
registry so we can look at the whole
package there
falco i'm going to show you falco in a
second falco is perhaps my favorite
thing
falco
looks for weird stuff going on in your
containers
it looks for abnormalities
um we'll see that and then coop hunter
is how you can actually do kind of a pen
test once you're done and you've
configured your environment you can run
coupe hunter against it
here is oh wait
did i
oh i'm missing a slide here i had an
example
of falco sorry
i had an example of falco running um but
i had to take it out because i was
having weird problems with getting it to
to sync up with the video
but yeah go to the falco.org site you'll
see it's an agent that runs within each
of the containers and
basically it looks for anomalies it
looks for suspicious things like if it
sees
somebody is doing cat or or something is
doing cat etsy password
um
yeah that's probably not something that
should be happening inside your
container and yet i have had
vulnerable kubernetes clusters and the
containers where falco actually caught
someone
doing cat etsy password it was a red
team
and we caught them we were the blue team
at the time and we were we kicked them
out and they were like ah
that was how we were going to get into
your systems and make you look bad
but yeah anyway
all right
if i were a a hacker i am hacker i i'm
going to attack
well how do i actually approach
pen testing or attacking a kubernetes
cluster
first thing i'm going to start with is
all the services that run on all the
ports
so there they are
i would start by just looking and making
sure first of all does anybody notice
anything that's missing here
that that might be
important
what might i look for
in an attack methodology within a
kubernetes cluster there's two things
that are missing
what about
before port 443 what about port 80
what if i find an open port 80. oh
somebody forgot to turn on tls
what if i find port 22.
oh crap let's turn that off
okay keep that in mind
so this gives you a kind of an attack
vector obviously
um
6666 for xcd i'd be looking to see if
that is exposed in some way
okay
so it's the same kind of thing you know
if you're if you're an attacker and you
want to go after a kubernetes cluster
these are the things that i look for
can i get to the api server
if i can get to the api server i have an
attack vector that oops
probably shouldn't be there especially
from very depending on what network
check for fcd make sure that cd is
locked down if that is not then you have
a problem
checking on the kublets
the kublet port should always be read
only it should never you should never
find a kubelet that has right access to
it okay
the container vulnerabilities
i mean there's nothing stopping you from
running a quick vulnerability scanner
against any of the applications that are
running within your containers
do you have sensitive files that are not
protected remember falco you actually
will configure file code that say oh i
have these specific files not part of
you know etsy password or something
maybe i have some other files that have
some important things in them that have
to be part of a container application
so i want to tell falco hey keep an eye
on on this file or these sets of files
or whatever
kernel exploits
there are going to be vulnerabilities in
the os's that you're deploying via
kubernetes
so if one comes out
please remember to patch the systems and
then redeploy your worker nodes which is
usually very easy you can roll that
through but i do see people forget that
a lot
they they don't remember
you have to patch those containers you
have to patch the entire cluster
because if we can get privilege
escalation we can take over your cluster
the vulnerable apps yeah that goes
without saying
so some final threat modeling
to think about when it comes to
kubernetes
think of the entire ci cicd pipeline if
you have one
if you're in the cloud you might have a
very automated one might not be an issue
think about your workload security
think about pods i usually say this in a
honeypot talk that i give that
90 of the time you do with honey pots
should be planning
same thing with kubernetes kind of 90
of your time should be spent thinking
about how can we group
applications such that if this cluster
or this pod is compromised
what's going to happen what's my risk at
that level
container security directly
file storage security keep in mind that
in the kubernetes world file storage is
not permanent unless you set it that way
it is transitory so if a container goes
down or the cluster goes down you will
lose whatever storage you might have had
in there unless you make it secure by
default or permanent by default
the network security remember the
infrastructure and then the application
security itself those are the things
that we really want to think about when
we're looking at the entire package
okay so your key takeaways for today
okay common sense is still there
um i like to say in all my talks that we
keep spending billions on fancy software
and hardware and all this stuff and yet
breaches keep going up
why is that because we're forgetting
best practices and everything that we've
learned doing security so stop
overthinking this stuff go back to best
practices secure the infrastructure have
a secure repo
you know don't let people get in and
play around with your repos and things
like that
okay
stick with the basics
stop the fancy for god's sake um just
use cis benchmarks
um that is going to be very important
and then our back
and all of the configurations we want to
make sure that we're applying benchmarks
across the board
okay if you take one thing away from
this talk today if you learned about cis
there's a good one threat model your
environment
okay
the access controls i mentioned this
more than once because it is often what
is overlooked in deploying kubernetes
clusters okay did i mention our back
yes
because it like i said it's overlooked
patch
patch your environment
log for jay just hit back in december
how many people had to patch their
kubernetes clusters because they were
running java based applications
it was a little easier because okay
you're in a kubernetes cluster you can
roll through the containers and get get
all your pods upgraded and so on but you
still had to do it
logging and auditing
if you don't monitor how are you going
to ever know and i throw the wazoo back
up there again take a look at it it's
just it's a great open source tool and
it works very very well with kubernetes
and containers
okay
so
that's it
let's see did i make it oh barely
thank you very much i will make my
slides available
if you watch my twitter account um i'll
post when i post the slides to my github
my github is also rainbowcat same thing
that's it any questions
[Applause]