thanks a lot today for coming from my
presentation uh tomb raiders
the pilfering of critical data from the
graves of decommissioned iot technology
so we're going to take this a little
farther and we're not going to get into
this crazy what's the definition of iot
so i want you to look at this this is
going to apply to embedded technology
for the most part so embedded technology
that are used by consumers used by
medical
industrial
transportation whatever the case may be
we're dealing with embedded technology
technology that typically doesn't have a
monitor on it or a keyboard those type
of things
and the potential risk and threats
around that
so a little more information about me
i'm daryl hyland i work at rapid7 i i
have listed up here as a principal
security researcher for iot i'm actually
the manager
of the research team for ot and iot but
it's a very technical road i do much as
much research
as the guys that actually work with me
or work for me
i've been in information technology for
30 years i've been in the
information security field for 20 years
in the last five years has been
100 focused on research
on iot ot and embedded based technology
so we're going to talk about a lot of
this is going to dive into you know what
do we need to do with this tech
because as the screen says
you're not going to have to eventually
de-acquisition sooner or later it's
going to die
or it's going to be replaced with newer
technology
and historically we've been
kind of trained eventually that when we
deal with desktops laptop servers we
finally got to the point where we don't
sell our hard drives on ebay anymore we
know from all the news stories and stuff
out there that we don't do that the
problem is is embedded technology can
store
quite a bit of data some of these
embedded devices have multi-gig storage
on them that can contain an infinite
number of data and some of the critical
data we're specifically going to talk
about today
so we start thinking about the
acquisition of the things what
technology in your environment or in
your home would fall into this category
i think of a network appliances medical
device technology industrial devices
i also consider printers in this
category smart tvs
smart lighting and this is just a small
list that goes on and on and on in this
new automated world we live in
all of this technology is in our homes
in our hospitals
in our plants in our manufacturing
environments our business environments
and we have to get rid of it sooner or
later
and we need to start thinking about that
now because what i found out there is
we're obviously not thinking about that
and we'll talk about those specifically
so then we get into well we have to
de-acquisition how do we do it there's
so many different ways of doing this
do we resell it
that's a viable option sometimes
companies want to retain some of the
capital expenditures that go into some
of this technology at home consumers do
the same thing
they have devices they're done with it
hey let's sell it on ebay
i may only get 10 cents on the dollar
from what i paid for but that's better
than nothing
disposal services there's a number of
those out there and as more and more
states spin up required laws of
disposing of electronic trash
properly instead of just throwing in a
dump somewhere you get disposal services
that are available and i think those are
important something critical to think
about
recycling recycling takes a number of
different things hey can we feed it
through a grinder which i like that idea
and recycle it for the metal the plastic
the gold the silver whatever is in it
that's pretty good we can donate it as
another option that's kind of like the
whole recycling thing i've seen
companies give their stuff away to
recycle it for other companies to reuse
or other organizations or non-profits to
reuse
we also have to deal with the whole idea
of leased equipment
so you go out there and you lease all
this equipment as example all your
printers or whatever the tech may you
lease this technology it comes into your
environment
after so many impressions on the printer
it goes back out the door
have you ever thought about what's going
back out the door
so the picture in the middle there
that actually shows all the printers i
couldn't find the one i originally took
so a number of years i did a lot of
research on multi-function printer
attacks for pin testers wrote a bunch of
tools did a bunch of presentations and
stuff like that
and i was working on
an exploit that i had developed on a
xerox multi-function printers where you
could actually gain root level access to
these things by sending a print job to
them
and i needed to develop a metasploit
module so it's kind of hard to really do
that when you're trying to hack away at
a printer to set in your office people
don't like that crap so i would up the
buy one and you can go up to these
places that recycle these things and
resell them and you can pick them up
fairly cheap i think i paid 500 for a
printer three years before sold for 12
the warehouse i went into
i could have swore
the freaking printers which so far you
could see them disappear on the over the
horizon this building was that big was
in columbus ohio and i got into the
conversation with them about various
attacks on these devices and harvesting
data off and the guys were kind of
interested so i was testing the devices
to see if they're the right versions and
vulnerable
and i showed this thing to him he's like
wow you just pull data off that thing
that's not supposed to be on that
printer everything that comes back to me
uncon contractual agreement
from the resellers that are disposing of
it that those are supposed to be wiped
so we did a random check
we just picked 12 printers went around
and i checked every one of them over a
half of them i was actually able to pull
active directory creds off the device i
was able to identify where it came from
and the active directory credentials on
that particular device so then i asked
them the question
do you wipe these things he's like no we
pack them and we ship them
i said where do you ship them
we ship them to asia
so really really let that sink in
so if we take this warehouse that had 10
000 printers in it
and let's say only 10 of them
still had creds on it and print jobs and
data and critical information
that's a thousand machines from who
knows how many different companies of
critical data that could be used to
compromise those organizations
being shipped to asia
so then it makes me start wondering why
does asia one of these old printers that
are basically wore out things have like
a million impressions in them half of
them don't even work right
i don't know
but it makes you think about that
so moving on what is the risk well we've
talked about one dealing with the
printers but lots of critical data i
have a couple news stories i thought
this one was oh so freaking fascinating
so this was two years ago i think two
years what was it
uh 20 uh 2020 two years ago news article
came out and it deal with police body
cams
so one of the cities i don't remember
where it was decided they needed upgrade
their police body cams they gathered
them all up bought new ones sold them
all on ebay
every one of them still had police
footage on it they'd never been wiped
this was data of police you know
everything from arresting people to
showing up to
homes where people were fighting and
trying to solve that but it was
probably thousands of hours of footage
private footage in my opinion that
probably shouldn't be out there being
sold on ebay for the highest bidder and
it was pretty cheap
was a good example
another one this was a great article
think about selling an echo dot and this
this goes home to the individual
consumers
and this was done by uh one of the user
universities on
phd team i think it was western i don't
have that information in my head right
now i apologize
but they did a bunch of tests and they
did this on echo ones echo twos various
versions of those the interesting thing
i had done this exact same test but i'd
only done it on
version two of the echo i think it was
they did it on all three of them it was
is data still on these devices
and it was a large percentage of these
devices that they got still had consumer
data on it which is basically amazon
passwords
so you you buy these and you can
actually
pull people's amazon passwords off and
if you know anything about that you can
often make purchases on that data which
is pretty critical the cool thing about
this when you start dealing with the
embedded multimedia controllers that
exist on these devices
they have a thing called level wearing
level wearing is every time something is
changed or altered on that device it
doesn't overwrite the same location with
the same data or modified data it writes
it to another location on the chips uh
silicon
another place and then wipes that out
and that is to maintain the chip to last
for a long period of time keep writing
in the same place you start having
failures in the device
and level wearing solves that problem
so one of the tests they ran
and then i think it was only on device
level three
like when you flush one of these devices
you do a factory reset which you should
do that means you keep it online you go
on the amazon
and you decommission the device
it will wipe the device so when it wipes
the device it's not immediately
it basically tags it and then waits for
a watchdog process to kick in
to wipe that data
version one and two of the device and i
even tested this prior to this paper
coming out successfully wipe that that
means if you do a factory reset through
the amazon application it removes the
data but apparently device number three
the latency between
the what you overriding it and the
watchdog kicking off to actually carry
this out was long enough that if you do
the clear on the amazon and walk over
and unplug it
it will not wipe your data
so and the reason why i tell you that is
you have these devices and you do a
factory reset
leave it online for a little time i
don't know what that time is
but leave it online for 30 more minutes
before you unplug it and then the data
will probably be cleaned up by the
watchdog process when it does its level
wearing on the device
so it's something to think about as
consumers when you get ready to get rid
of any device kind of think about that
you do a factory reset
give it a little bit of time let things
process don't go factory reset and then
pull the plug immediately
give a chance for the internal operating
systems to hopefully clear off the data
and i've tested a lot of devices
as iot research for factory resets to
see does that work and most of them do
it's a rare occasion you'll have one
that will not delete the data it just
tells you it's deleted but for the most
part it's always deleted
this here another example
i do a lot of work with the iot village
of defcon i run hands-on exercises out
there which we're going to be doing
again this year where you get actually
hack on a piece of hardware and pull
critical data out or interact with the
operating system uh to modify things and
get root level access on it so these
were devices i bought these luma which
are mesh wi-fi devices
i think i bought like 20 of these they
come in kits to three ebay i'm just
buying them left and right because i
needed all these for the lab
so when i got them home i started
looking at them
i found out over half of them had never
been factory reset
so for a consumer the threat is fairly
minimal it's there but it's minimal but
it turned out that a number of these
were not used by consumers they were
used by small businesses
so i was able to get the business names
the accounts the wi-fi pre-shared keys
all that critical information
and if you know anything about anyone
who decides they're going to change a
wi-fi access point out in your
organization
you don't always change the passwords
pre-share keys and all that stuff
usually use the same ssids
the same pre-shared keys that way you
know if you have 100 users on your
network you don't have to screw a change
in all the workstations
as a prime example
so again another example of data just
being out there
and it kind of goes on and on so
when you think about pulling the data
off there's a number of ways to get data
off these devices
if i'm just after the data on the
devices i'm not going to worry about
things like jtag and all this fancy
stuff
i'm going to throw the damn thing in a
reflow oven and just rip the chip off
and drop it into a reader pull all the
information i can do that in a fraction
of the time of getting that stuff off
and here's some example of devices
pulling chips
it's easy it's simple this is not
complex you can buy that reader on the
on the right there for 130 bucks
you can buy hot air or reflow system for
another 130 bucks so for basically 270
bucks you could buy stuff off ebay and
strip critical data out of it for less
than three hundred dollars
very low entry point to compromising
critical data
so uh this one was interesting so i did
some stuff with light bulbs i like
bought crap little light bulbs and said
hey you know what kind of data's on it
can i get pre-shared keys off of it is
it easy i only focus on the ones that
were easy
i mean the data's there period simple as
that but how complex did they
did they obfuscated in some way did they
encrypt it in some way obviously they
encrypted the freaking keys are there
too so just a matter of hunt pecking to
find that type of stuff so i focus on
the ones that were easily compromised we
built these into exercises where we
demoed this at rsa we were talking about
from trash to treasure things you throw
in the trash well last year defcon doing
the iot thing i get a lot of people come
up to me afterwards start talking about
iot stuff so i had a gentleman come up
to me and he's like you know
he goes uh i have these smart bobs and
i'm like well what kind of smart bobs
are they enterprise or are they these
type of bulbs he's like these we have a
lot of small offices where there's like
three or four people in an office and we
don't have you know we just have regular
incandescent style
light bulbs or smart bulbs simple ones
you screw in he goes man i struggle with
the problem with these things failing on
me all the time and trying to manage
that
so we kind of addressed the whole
management thing of it you know how do
you how do you manage those and tell
when they're out and when they're on and
all that type of stuff the leds on these
burn out the power supplies on these
things blow out
when these things die
and no longer produce light
if you plug them into a network nine
times out of ten they're still on the
network that means they're still fully
functional that just the led
functionings fail
and even if everything fails on this
thing i assure you the data stored on
the flash memory is not going to fail
and most of these are fairly easy most
of them just have the white block there
happens to just be a wi-fi ship like
an express f or something like that
there's dozens of different
manufacturers out there
so in this particular case we just pull
that chip off we mount it on a test
board over there we hook four wires to
it put the thing into debug mode and use
a simple application to pull the
firmware off of it search through the
firmware there and we're quickly able to
find the ssid
and if i know what the ssid is on the
bulb or what it's broadcasting for
attempting to connect to it's easy to
search with it because
99 out of 100 times it's usually within
about five lines of that it's going to
be the pre-shared key in some form uh
and it's it and they're obviously
defined and this was the case we find
the pre-shared key it happens to be the
whole thing converted into hex
so we just run it through and convert it
back and we can see it right there
that's the pre-shared key on these
particular devices
so i actually showed all this to him
because i had this there so i showed him
how it all worked how easy it was to get
the data
oh the poor guy about crapped his pants
he's like man i've been throwing those
in the trash left and right
uh i don't know i don't really get into
dumpster diving but
hey man if you guys want to start
dumpster diving behind that uh local
business you might be surprised what you
find
smart bulbs contain data
kind of interesting data and this is so
simple to actually interact with these
uh ssid
or these wi-fi chip
devices manufacturers have all the data
out there and they often have a short
programming code that's available where
you can actually interact with it to
pull
various data off the device and interact
with the device in a number of different
ways
some of these are kind of interesting so
if you get these
these wi-fi chips
express f for example and you'll find
these in certain small end devices
that'll actually spin up their own
access points so if you think of
you think of a system that is kind of a
closed system solution
for example like an alarm system on your
house where all the pieces communicate
over wi-fi to each other it often has
its own wi-fi ssid structure that it
connects back to in that in that
environment when you use the default on
the expressives
you can actually connect into the device
and send an at command to it and say hey
what is your wi-fi pre-share key it'll
give it to you in clear text
as an example so you don't even have to
hack at it just ask it the right things
and it'll tell you if it's used as an
access point
another in a simple easy way to get data
off of it
i did this one just recently so air
links it's an industrial wireless lan
access point
and i've bought a couple of these over
the years just out of curiosity but
recently
i've been doing this particular
presentation uh at a couple places in
the last year so i just recently went
and bought one of these things this
airlinks
they're old which is what you do you
know they're industrial access points
people use them for a while and it's
like hey
things getting to be six seven eight
years old time to update it hey let's
make some money sell it on ebay
daryl buys it on ebay
i bring the thing home and i fire it up
look it's still broadcasting its factory
ssid
probably not a good thing i kind of
fuzzed it out there a little bit but you
could probably find it with that much
information so the thing is you can go
to wiggle
you go okay let's see if that
ssid is out there which i've done this
so every time i get a device and i steal
the ssid and pre-share keys
out of curiosity i look it up on wiggle
and go hey
can i identify where this is located at
in this case i was i was able to
identify it and actually find the
machine the one that actually replaced
it because they used the same ssid on
this device
so how many paychecks you want to bet me
that it's the same password
now obviously i can't check that that is
a crime
but
but i can almost bet my life on it that
it's that way and i've done this test on
a lot of technology that is commercial
level not consumer
some that i can't talk about yet because
it's still
issues that have to be dealt with
where i've done this and have been able
to get the
ssid and the pre-shared keys for upwards
of five to eight
major organizations
that's scary
that means we're not decommissioning
technology correctly because we forget
these are no different than a hard drive
they may be smaller
they may not spin around and make noise
but i assure you they contain just as
much
critically dangerous data
on those devices
now i don't encourage you to go out and
do this and then try to use the data
again like i said that is a crime
and it's all about security not
insecurity thus why i'm speaking here
i'm hoping everyone will go home and to
your business your organization and have
that discussion
what does this mean to your organization
what do we do with these devices how do
we handle these things
you know do we have contractual
agreements with
companies that are
we're licensing devices from or are we
just letting them take them away and
sell them as scrap with all your data on
it
something to think
about so what next how do we mitigate
these issues
there's no perfect answer here because
this is fairly new and it's an area
very few organizations have really given
much thought
so
the first steps awareness
here we are
we're all aware now
daryl's buying our off ebay
but i'm the good guy so you don't have
to worry about that
uh so i say go back have those
conversations
develop plans
one of the biggest problem with embedded
technologies in our in our businesses
is there's literally no ownership
they're plug and play you stick them in
the environment
nobody pays any attention to them ever
again they're shadow devices so if they
come in as shadow devices they're going
to go out as shadow devices with your
data
so start thinking about that start
developing ownership within your
organization on iot and embedded based
technology who owns it who's responsible
build a plan on de-acquisition of
technology so you're sure that hey we're
doing what's best for our organization
we know that we've done the factory
reset and we're comfortable that it's
been wiped
or we've contracted somebody else to do
that
or we
feed the thing into a giant metal
shredder and shred it into dust
actually nothing leaves my lab
with a
other than stuff that i give the
co-workers to do hacking on and stuff
like that
nothing will go out in disposable
electronic trash out of my house with an
actual flash memory chip on it
i literally remove them all and usually
smash them
or crush them now
most of us as consumers that's kind of
ridiculous to expect that and i don't
because you end up wasting half a day
probably cut your fingers off trying to
open some of these boxes sometimes
and then you have to figure out which is
the memory chip and how the hell do i
get it off the board
to smash it or what do i do and then if
you ain't wearing safety glasses oh gosh
i can only imagine the damage you could
do to yourself so i don't recommend that
but
that doesn't mean
as a commercial organization a business
you can't come up with a solution
ensures the data is not going out
and they'll build a plan for execution
how are we going to execute that and
make sure that moving forward problem
actually gets solved
so the planning and execution again
reiterate governance
create policies and ownership
of this technology
build that ownership as it enters the
door
don't wait until you have to get rid of
it
because because
on another subject i've been doing
embedded devices for
quite a few years i was a pen tester for
almost a decade
guess what my area of expertise was
attacking all your embedded devices on
your network to harvest data
or use those devices to carry out
attacks as red team operations so your
security operations centers running
around in circles wondering why that
xerox printer just carried out a an
attack against your active directory and
you don't know where it's coming from
you think it's the printer
so
ownership
of that technology as it's coming in the
door will also help with decommissioning
of the technology ensuring that you
don't have any problems so how would
this process look like like i mentioned
before wipe the device can we wipe it
can we clean it are we confident that
it's been cleaned hey if your
organization and you have like 10 000
embedded devices spread all over the
place and you want to know whether the
the factory reset worked or not
contact a company that does iot testing
and say hey
pull this see if the factory reset's
actually working at least confirm it
i can't expect that to cost you much
money it's going to take quite a few
hours worth of work for anyone that
knows what they're doing to be able to
validate whether a factory reset
actually removes the data or not
destruction feed it into a shredder
set it on i don't know get rid of it
make it go away and when it goes away it
goes away in pieces and dust
never assume that if you smash it with a
hammer that you successfully smash the
flash memory chip
if that chip is physically intact in any
way shape or form the data can be pulled
off it fairly easy
change accounts and passwords
so i worked at a fortune 500 company in
security
for a number of years for threat and
vulnerability so i was kind of like
giving them this awareness over a decade
15 years ago
and we often would change out our wi-fi
access
a lot of times when we did that we're
also upgrading the overall security
model that we're using whether as wpa
wpa enterprise whatever the case was
we're always up in the up in that and
every time we did we stood it up
separately
the old systems in place
stood it up separately
sent the appropriate keys and structures
to the workstations and laptops that
needed to access this once they all
switched over to the new system which
was different accounts different
passwords different ssids
then we were able to tear down the old
system
to me that is the smartest way to go
less likely this and then if you do
screw it up
they get accounts that are actually
worthless
and we had done that a couple times in a
fortune 500 company but if you're not
changing the security model often it's
easy to pull it out put a new one in
same ssid same keys so be careful about
that
so electronic waste disposal i think
this is critical we have literally too
much
electronic waste going into trash cans
and garbage
the sad part is there's currently no
federal law guidelines it says this is
how it's going to be disposed of
the eu uk on the other hand
very defined regulations and laws of
disposing technology
various states have different
regulations and guidelines around this
and of course since i'm in pittsburgh
pennsylvania electronic waste disposal
so they do have
government guidelines on how that should
be done
for device recycling or disposing of
those
if you're a large organization and have
the resources to handle some of this
cleanup stuff yourself
pretty good if if you don't then you're
going to contract this out to somebody
and again i recommend if you're
contracting out disposal don't give them
the opportunity to just walk out the
door with your data and sell it
somewhere make sure it's properly
disposed of and
properly disposed of legally
if it's going to go somewhere so it
doesn't end up in some landfill
inappropriately
and of course
pittsburgh has its electronic waste
disposal
this is kind of interesting
i advise taking a look at these things
if you as an organization go
i've never seen these before more than
likely you are now in violation of
pennsylvania state law
and you're doing it incorrectly so
make sure it happens because remember
and i worked at a fortune 500 company
and they were paranoid like crazy that
they were going to get sued
so all electronic stuff never actually
went to an employee if they were getting
rid of it and go out to an employee it
actually went through a disposal service
and was fed into a shredder and then
when disposed of through proper proper
means
but with what but with that said
make sure the per people you're hiring
are doing it right too because if they
take stuff say they're going to shred it
ends up on ebay and then that device
ends up somewhere it shouldn't be
often especially if it's a high brand
name product or something serial numbers
and it was acquired certain ways that is
traceable right back to your company and
that's why my fortune 500 company never
let anyone have anything
because they were scared that if they
gave somebody some laptop after it was
all done or some kind of device that
would end up in some landfill and get
traced back to them
so you need to take that stuff into
consideration and i'm actually running a
little fast today than i normally do on
this
so
i
think everyone should have some
questions for me so we have any
questions here
come on someone's got to have a question
yes sir
uh it's been a while uh i played around
with zigbee and some z-wave stuff
like three years ago uh unfortunately i
don't
i
when you get into certain aspects of
commercial stuff you see that so you
start seeing
variations that like uh um
or back then when i was playing around i
was seeing a lot of that stuff show up
or variations of that protocol in
electronic meters and stuff like that
i see a lot more of that
being tilted over to cellular based
communication for backhaul and stuff
like that
so
it's an interesting field we do uh we do
run assessment work for companies our
pen test teams
do that for iot type stuff and every
once in a while we'll get somebody comes
in has a zigbee or z-wave device
the old stuff was terrible
at least they've improved a lot of the
security uh with the uh the
zigbee the old the old zigbee like the
consumer-grade zigbee
and i'm sure they've fixed it now i
haven't looked at it but back in years
past
when you keyed it up it would actually
use the same encryption key and then
never change it
so all you would have to do is get the
encryption key which i think was
published on the internet
for that encryption so at that point
game over none of your zigbee stuff was
secure but as they get into more outside
the consumer grades zigbee and you get
into different protocols they have
different key rotations capabilities and
stuff like that so it's it's much better
from that standpoint
but no different if your disposal of a
device is still configured somebody
wants to pull that data off there uh it
could be critical now i have not tried
that because wi-fi stuff's so prevalent
and so easy to get data off of it but
like any of that type of stuff whether
it's
bluetooth any type of
wireless communication
if you don't factor your reset remove
your keys remove various things it's
going to go out the door containing that
data and that should be considered also
yes ma'am
medical medical devices i don't want to
go into a whole lot of medical devices
because
yeah there's issues
okay
so i actually have a research report on
that coming out later this year on
medical based technology in
this subject matter
which i think people will find quite
interesting and um
well that's dangerous
yeah i i have a yeah yeah
i have a but this is near field so and
you know you get to find out where my
sugar levels are at the moment so but
yes
okay so uh so i know a friend of mine
jay radcliffe a number of people here
may know him he's done a lot of security
research on medical devices
it was about five years ago he released
a whole uh
uh
research on an actual insulin pump where
he was actually able to decode all the
communications and it had the ability to
actually uh change that data and cause
an insulin pump to
yeah yeah yeah he worked he worked at
rapid seven when he released that paper
but it was work he had done before he
came over he just hadn't got around to
releasing it and literally you could
kill somebody with that so
so
the the the logic for doing it is is to
improve security
so so i so think about it when you deal
with these types
to kill somebody
yeah
yeah if i if i know not maybe not random
i mean i mean think about it if you
remember back um oh gosh the vice
president
uh under bush cheney yeah he had a
pacemaker and if you remember they came
out with a bunch of stuff on the
pacemakers and they went in and modified
his pacemaker specifically so think
about it you have someone in a position
of authority
a government leader in some fashion that
happens to be a diabetic and i assure
you there's probably plenty of them out
there
you could kill them
which is scary which is scary
randomly killing people yeah we already
have enough of that so
but to be able to kill people with this
it's a little more complex you have to
think it around think it through much
more as an attack vector to be able to
do that
to cost somebody their life
it i would expect you know a nation
state as an example
would really want to be able to do that
against another leader of another
country country or one of his political
opponents or something like that there
could be people wanting to do that in
some
some of these countries so i think it's
a real threat so it's a good thing we
have researchers i'm a big fan of
researchers working with
a medical companies to identify and
solve these people these issues i think
that's pretty good
so any other questions
yes sir
you speak up a little bit
um yeah so
there's a number of chip readers out
there um
then they're fairly cheap they're
like i said about 135 dollars for a chip
reader that'll cover like
eight nine thousand ten thousand
different chips out there
the sockets that go in those when you
start getting into ball grid array chips
could be 40 50 bucks out of out of china
and i buy a lot of those
and the ability to heat the board up or
something to desolder it often those
boards are small enough you could throw
them into a hot air reflow oven i think
the one i have i paid 150 bucks for it
out of a chinese product
inexpensive
right there's all you need
maybe some some stuff to clean some of
the solder off of it some alcohol swabs
you know things like that maybe a
soldering iron and some solder wick you
know so i i say less than 300
you could go out there and do that you
could easily look at blogs that i've
posted online
and you'll probably see
various aspects of tools there
from a from an iot research lab
i did a presentation
not last year but the year before a iot
presentation online
specifically on uh building out a lab
so it was it was i did the whole demo in
my lab with cameras set up all around so
we looked at all the different hardware
and stuff about what i could do with it
how it worked what i used it for things
like that so some good data out there
for being able to get started if you're
interested in doing this
well if you're interested in iot
research not if you're interested in
getting other people's creds
i don't encourage that
any other questions
yes sir
yes most most of the time they are
most of the organizations when i see a
real vulnerability uh that's a true
vulnerability the fact that data is
stored on these devices
unencrypted i think if you contact them
like most of the light bulbs that i see
now the data is actually
encrypted or encoded or obfuscated in
some fashion it is in clear text
which is a good thing but some of them
that's not the case uh i haven't looked
at the version three of the amazon
echoes but the ver previous versions you
just you pull it it's kind of crazy so
you have you have chips on them called
embedded multimedia controllers they're
typically
uh i think with those they're called
embedded multi-chip packages so they
contain ram and flash on one ship so you
have to have an oven to remove those
those have on the underside of they have
quarter millimeter pads that balls go on
to put it on that but you can buy these
readers uh you get a cheap one for like
90 but another one for uh
135 bucks and what you do is you clean
the chip up you drop it in you close the
lid you plug it into usb and it mounts
up like an sd drive so literally so this
year this this year this year uh
as a
a pump for iot village at defcon our
hands on exercise this year we're
actually looking at cable modems where
we've actually wired in a sd card
breakout board
to an embedded multi-chip
or a
embedded multimedia controller chip so
you can just plug the actual cable modem
into your sd card slot and actually
mount all of the flash memory up just
like a hard drive
and from there pull data alter it put it
back on to gain root level access that's
what the demo is going to be
so
i don't think to hurt himself i mean i
encourage people to go out and learn how
embedded technology works
it's how we that's how we get better at
securing things is
people to have an interest and learn how
to do it
you know before i was before i was doing
this as my full-time job i was doing
this research and
speaking at conferences and publishing
research
15 almost 20 years ago i started doing
this on my own so it wasn't sanctioned
by any company
and as a professional advance in my
career if you want to go out there and
get this stuff and do it illegally
you're going to do it anything i'm
saying you could find pieces and parts
of this if not incomplete in various
fashions online if you're going to do
bad things
me teaching you
technology isn't going to make you any
more dangerous you're already dangerous
you're a criminal
but
i don't i don't necessarily believe
uh 100 that's the case i see more and
more vendors focusing on
literally full disk encryption
on ships
so we encounter that more and more and
more
you know and you're seeing devices that
use
tpms so
encryption models hardware-based
encryption i mean the cost goes up and
that's what you have to take into
consideration but if it's a high-end
product a commercial level product
and you want to be able to get out there
and claim you have some level of
security which puts you a notch above
everyone else
then obviously you want to spend that
little extra and you're just going to
pass it on to to the consumer so seeing
full full flash of full memory
encryption is kind of cool
uh without a tpm though if the device
doesn't have a tpn or a sam chip on it
for handling hard hardware-based
encryption the keys are on there
somewhere
you know there's ways to hide those keys
pretty safe
but not they're never completely safe
you know there's all kinds of crazy side
channel attacks
to get access to pieces of memory that
you're not supposed to
then but but you work you raise the cost
you raise the amount of effort you raise
the amount of cost so somebody can't
just take a device get all the data off
of it they have to go through and figure
out what the encryption keys are
encryption keys are held in a section of
flash that that is locked down and
prevented access the only way to do that
is some kind of side channel attacks on
the on the chips to be able to pull data
off and things like that
things are getting better you know it
isn't like we have the status quo of
nothing getting better i i see it and
working with vendors on stuff like this
and vulnerabilities and issues
you know 10 years 15 20 years ago you
know i dealt with vendors that didn't
want to talk to me
and and were always kind of problematic
in nature and would take forever to fix
things i would never just up and publish
the data saying screw you and publish
the data because i was running security
for a large organization why would i
want to make my life harder
so i would just be patient and set on
that unfortunately
a lot of people just published that data
back in when a vendor go ah screw you
they would just publish it that's not
the case it's pretty rare the only time
i've ran into that issue is when i'm
dealing with products that are like
white labeled
coming out of other countries
where once they produce a million of
these things they disappear or they
don't care because they're producing
something else those are the only
organizations i've ever contacted and
they're like we don't care
most u.s companies branded devices care
about their security
because failure within security is a
black mark on them and they want to make
sure that they're doing everything and
they'll work with
the work with researchers that actually
care to do it properly
to get their problems fixed which is
nice
i think i'm probably out of time
okay any more questions
these questions are good i like this
no more questions
okay well i hope you enjoyed this i hope
you enjoyed the question section with
some good stuff
thank you for coming i appreciate it
[Applause]