a ver Cheryl London or the former chair
of the a lacks that large Advisory
Committee and she was the election from
october twenty two thousand seven to
december twenty ten so Cheryl you are
one of the most seasoned member in the
icon community could you tell us why a
large was created certainly it was a
product of a process that occurred in in
and around 2000 where I can took a look
at the way the voice of the Internet
end-user an individual domain name
registrant was being brought to the
table and for a number of reasons which
we can go into but there's plenty of
documents on our wiki should people be
interested to look it was decided that
we would form at that stage an interim
at-large Advisory Committee which could
act as a organized kondu to bring the
voice of the wider in fact billions of
people who whose interests we have to
act in the best interest of and bring
that voice to i can and advice to the
board of the support organizations and
be fully engaged in the policy
development processes that go on to help
that work effectively we needed to have
nodes or touch points out in the further
stages of community that we could get
and so the at large structures model
came into being now at large structures
are entities which are demonstrably
acting in the best interests of
consumers and end-users and internet
end-users individual domain name
registrant's within their country and
region and there's a credit ation
process that makes sure we're working
with bona fide organizations and that
what they're saying about the the rich
they have in perhaps their own country
is is is actually testable and then they
become icann accredited at large
structures or shorthand al esas we moved
from a group of founding a lse's who
would have feed directly into the
at-large advisory committee with their
their information of course that large
advisory committee can see
edge information by reaching out to
those aliases there was probably a few
years where we had a trickle of fairly
peak body and well-known organization
some of them were Internet Society
chapters who came on board as at large
structures and as that grew it was
recognized that the geographic diversity
that we needed needed to be sought after
and managed so we created a regional
structure whereby the at-large
structures in geographic regions that I
can users were clustered together and we
put in a sort of a middle layer to
facilitate and enable communication and
information exchange and that's called
our regional at large organization so we
started off with a two-tier approach and
we've come towards a three-tier approach
that's operated effectively certainly
since around two thousand and five six
we found that the importance and
activities of the original at large
organization in each of the geographic
regions is growing and changing and
they're becoming much more critical
points of information exchange than we
had even hoped in the beginning and so
we're all going through a review at this
stage where in the next 12 to 18 months
we'll have had an external look at how
this is all working and we're hoping
that we might even have a smoother more
effective model but right now we have
two hundred and climbing at large
structures we have five geographic
regions and we have the 15-person
at-large Advisory Committee I can just
give you one more piece of important
information about that the fifteen
percent at-large Advisory Committee is a
very unique and balanced thing in I can
because we have three sitting members
from each of the five geographic regions
two of those members are now appointed
by these regional at large organizations
they could appoint someone who's not a
member but they make the appointment the
third person
in each this geographic regions
disappointed by something called the
nominating committee and the nominating
committee which I'd encourage people to
go and learn more about they've got
their own website and they do vital work
for I can put into place a number of
people in a number of parts of I can
including the ICANN board but for us
they put the third person in for each of
those regions and that's bringing a
little bit like an independent director
to a board table that sort of balance
that sort of diversity unique wonderful
and exciting to work with thank you
thank you so much for that insight so we
also know there are many other group
sing I can how does a large differ from
other groups oh well we do and we don't
in a number of ways there are a number
of at large structures and indeed
individuals because the regions will
take members of an individual status as
well who may be involved in other parts
of I can or may be involved in as a
member or an active participant in other
organizations that belong to other parts
of I can so there is often a crossover
but what is specifically the difference
point with us is as we act in the
interests of Internet users both those
that are connected and those that are
yet to connect our view is not
restricted to either the country code
space or the generic top-level space our
involvement our role is to be I can wyd
all of the others you'll find quite
necessarily and quite effectively work
within a particular focus so they may
work within the gns oh as a constituency
within the gns oh but we have our
mandate we're an advisory committee to
the ICANN board but our role is to have
impact and influence and be part of the
process of developing policies across
the board thank you very much Cheryl for
a time and valuable insights thank you
beneficial