we're here at ICANN 56 with members of
the i Ken nominating committee to find
von Gelder Hans butter Hollen and
Wolfgang climb back to welcome gentlemen
all right hello it's too fine can you
provide us with an update on the nam
khan process yeah sure this is actually
the key meeting for us because the
middle meeting in the icon year is our
selection meeting that means that here
we are interviewing finalists
shortlisted candidates that the
nominating committee has decided they
want to hear more they want to find out
more about them they want to hear more
from them and they want to understand a
bit more about who these candidates are
before they make their final selections
now those final selections are also
going to happen during this meeting so
for the nominating committee the middle
meeting of the year is one where we are
shut away in a room for most of the day
either listening to prospective
applicants to prospective people that we
might select or determining amongst
ourselves which are the best people that
we have on our slate this year so a lot
of work for the noncom the noncom is
kept out of the way of the main meeting
for obvious confidentiality reasons and
at the end of the week we are supposed
to come out a bit like a papal conclave
with a new slate of selectees that we
will then be able to announce after a
bit more technical administrative
processes have gone on towards the end
of the year hunts better your chair legs
which means you'll be the chair next
year can you explain how that works yeah
when I was interviewed by the board to
become Chair Elect they asked me to
commit to become chair next year as well
of course the board has a final decision
to to appoint me chair after after this
period and part of this is to make sure
that there is continuity in the
leadership so I
to be part of the leadership team this
year to learn how we've been doing
things and then we also have an
associate chair who is picked by the
chair who's been serving as chair
previously so that we get the historic
perspective and and experience as well
on the leadership team what will your
focus be is the chair after observing an
outcome leadership over the past year
well in many way i would say that to
continue what we've been doing for the
last couple of years before being Chair
Elect i was on the noncom for two years
as well and over the last year we've
been refining the processes and they
seem to be working pretty well no so
it's kind of like developed what we have
and making the improvement that will
learn from what we've been doing this
year working this is a time of
transition for I can but is it business
as usual for the NAM come or are there
specific challenges I think there's very
specific challenges this year and also
the years ahead because if on sep tember
sergey's the younger transition is
completed I can will on its own feet and
is then treated as an independent global
corporation and I think this globalized
few has to be reflected in icons
leadership so that means more than any
before we have to take into
consideration such to your political
geostrategic observations so that make
clear also for the rest of the world in
particular for the 165 members of the
governmental advisory committee that
icon is indeed a global cooperation
another corporation dominated by some
from the north and some male white men
and this brings me to the second point
because I think the issue of gender
balance place also a role so far we have
20 board members and only five a woman
so I think this is a challenge in front
Lee's to find what's so special about
this meeting which the NAM come is
calling its selection meeting let me
just go back to a point Wolfgang just
made on both the gender diversity and
the work
noncom does with respect to the wider
board there is a lot of talk about
diversity within I can be agenda geo
community other types of diversity the
icon community is striving to be as
diverse as it can be but I want to make
it very very clear that the num com can
only select from the amount that the
people that apply we can only select
from the slate of incoming applications
so a lot of the work that we do and
you've heard us say this in past
conversations that we've had for this
type of event a lot of work that we do
is to outreach before our application
period in order to make sure that we can
reach out to people that would probably
not normally apply because they would
either not know about the process or
would not feel that they would fit into
the process and that's a very important
part of the work that we do so that when
we come to this selection meeting where
you know the cards are on the table we
have a slate of applicants we can't
really do anything about that we just
try and choose from the best or try and
choose the best from that slate when the
cards are on the table at this meeting
we have the ability is a non come to
make choices that will promote diversity
so really it does start with the
community and and the people that are
applying into this process if we can get
more women in we can get more people
from different countries that are
underrepresented or different regions
that are underrepresented at the moment
then I think we've done our job and at
this meeting all we have to do select
the best and it becomes easy well thank
you so much for your time gentlemen and
I hope you have a good rest of our
thank you very much