we have the three most recent cheers of
the ale act that a large Advisory
Committee with us it's a Shara London or
Alan Greenberg and Olivia Crippen blonde
Cheryl you are dumb the earliest chair
in this group so how would you describe
the role of a large community and I can
ah right we have had long conversations
about this and during our very first day
like review we agreed as a community
that what we were doing was acting in
the best interests of the internet end
user and the individual domain name
registrar so overarching that is our job
Alan where you think well that's
certainly the right answer as an
overview that doesn't really tell people
what we do what we do within I can in
general we are officially an advisory
committee but the bulk of our time is
not spending is not spent in advising
the board or other groups but actively
participating in the various processes
so we feel that the best way we can
represent the interests of users we can
make sure that the needs of users do
show up in the policies that I can
develops is to be there on the ground
actively working with the rest of the
community and making sure that when the
policies come out they will meet the
needs of the users I guess the important
thing about that is that in order to get
the input from the community you also
need to go out there in search for it
and that's where outreach part comes
from we really have to go out there
search for new people that are
interested in I can that are interested
in the processes and that will then be
able to contribute thank you um so due
to the outreach work I think I large
just reached one of the most recent
milestones are passing 200 a large
structures so what is like to be a chair
for such a diverse community
Alan do you think oh I don't think
there's a single word certainly it's
empowering because when you can use all
of the resources that are out there it's
it's a lot more than any single
individual can do it is exhilarating at
times because sometimes it really all
pulls together and works and it's a
challenge we're dealing with a very
diverse community actually getting them
to come to come to a common end means
compromise it means adjusting people's
views and that's always difficult but
when you do it that's great it's
actually also a huge responsibility and
one that I know is as leadership we've
always taken very very seriously I mean
we we are part of a key voice coming in
to the mainstay of icons policy
development work as well as advice we
may give in a formal sense and it's
being as I was saying earlier engaged
bringing a pinion and voice to the table
taking questions and concerns back to
the edge communities through our at
large structures and things like that so
it's it's a very privileged position to
be in and it's one that I think each of
us have tried to make sure we leave our
personal views and baggage even the
views and opinion of groups we would
normally represent at the meeting room
door and we act with independence and
impartiality to make sure consensus is a
full reflection but it's also an awful
lot of fun I've heard Alan say that it
was exhilarating you know some days
you'll cry some days some days you'll be
delighted about the the effect and
what's going on and you'll think wow it
actually really works but it's extremely
challenging and I would I would just
call it the ride of your life that's
true a very good so speaking of
challenges looking ahead what you think
are the challenges and opportunities for
a large community well I guess I just
alluded to them in the last and last
answer the challenges and the
opportunities go together
we're dealing with a lot of different
people who have very strong needs not
always the same getting them to come
together you know it's it's something I
think akin to raising children that you
put a lot of effort into it and then you
cross your fingers and hope that at the
end they come out right and they come
out good and you never can quite predict
how they're going to come out but if
you're lucky and maybe a bit of skill it
works well so challenges opportunities
they're all merged together I guess the
opportunity is ready to showcase that
the motifs they call the model actually
can work and you know what it does and
that's what I find really amazing about
it look some of the challenges are still
linked to the enormity of the task we
have you know we're presenting the best
interests of us we were acting in the
best interests of the billions of people
on the internet as well as those yet to
join the internet and that's that in
itself is a challenge but of course that
means we need to look at the diversity
of the cultures we have to think about
the diversity of the languages we need
to work in so there's there's logistical
challenges like that but the
opportunities are of course to get that
right and I actually think that this
multi-stakeholder model perhaps under
the guidance of chairs like you're
looking at now and I'm so many years
away i can say that we're an important
part of ICANN getting the
multi-stakeholder voice out of the edge
communities of internet users and
individual res just registrants to the
table thank you very much Cheryl Allen
and Olivia for a time and where
we're delighted