[Applause]
thank you very much so welcome everyone
this is building a diy baseband debugger
from scratch and my name is neko cruz
i am a researcher for exodus
intelligence and my main interest is
vulnerability research and exploit
development
but although we do have a mobile team at
exodus intelligence this is my own
personal research and this is unrelated
to anything that we do at xi
on this presentation we're going to go
really quickly through a very very brief
introduction to baseband we're going to
go through what we actually need to get
started in basement research we're going
to take a look at how we are going to
build a bisburn debugger uh for the
targeting the htc one m9 plus
and uh finally to demonstrate this
hopefully the democrats are smiling to
me we're going to be setting a
breakpoint reading a
message for memory life
um so as i really briefly introduction
to baseband we need to take into account
that a baseband data smartphone is very
different from a computer in a computer
in a general
purpose computer we have a single
processor a cpu running everything and
some peripherals whereas in a in a in a
smartphone we have multiple processors
an application processor digital signal
processors wi-fi chips and the basement
processor that are working together to
achieve a common goal
um
in case of the baseband pressure and the
application processor in a smartphone
they do communicate using sharing
using shared memory interfaces as well
as
in the uh in case of the application
processor and basement processor case
they use 80 commands
so
all in all at the very minimum a
smartphone is going to be running a
linux kernel an android operating system
some user applications and a firmware
for each processor
uh the application processor is going to
be running a linux kernel and an android
operating system and
any application user application that
you can think about
whereas
the baseband processor is going to be an
arm chip in this case in this case of
this particular phone running its own
operating system or firmware
um as you probably know the baseband
processor is the one handling cellular
communications with cell phone towers
why is this interesting to us why is
this interesting to me particularly
because this is a pro code base and it's
actually written in cnc plus which as
you might know
this can bring a lot of bucks
in this case um for the htc one m9 i
found that in the baseband there is no
privilege
separation whatsoever in the basement os
um but however the entry bar is higher
as you do need some hardware
and this
this actually means that there is less
research uh available on the topic on
top of that most interestingly uh
this offers the possibility of
triggering remote qualification over the
air without any user interaction
whatsoever
so as a bare minimum to get started in
baseband research we do need a phone we
need some solar
cellular setup which is comprised of a
hardware setup and a software setup
and we need also some minimum to have
access to the baseband to the baseband
firmware or the always binary it's also
very nice to get some debugging symbols
as always
and it's also very nice to have a
debugger the debugger building the
debugger is the main topic for this talk
um i'm going to be targeting the htc one
m9 plus today uh it is a pretty old
baseband it's from 2015 but it's
actually very great it's a really good
platform to get started this go for
around 100 dollars on ebay and so far
i've destroyed three of them in my test
the pros of using this platform is that
routing is partially supported by the
manufacturer and most importantly the
basement firmware is not signed or
checked whatsoever um for this uh
for this uh research to be extended to
other platforms
uh the basement firmware not to be
checked is a requirement
um
and rooting the um rooting the phone is
usually a requirement also to be able to
override the firm the basement firmware
inside
my target i have placed a sim card
not just any sim card is one
of which the mc is known is these are
manufactured by cismocom
the mca the
international mobile subscriber identity
is going to be known to open bts and
therefore this phone when is when the
sim card is inserted is going to be
allowed in the network although others
should be should should work as well i
so far i haven't found a single sim card
that didn't work
um this cellular setup which i have
right here
looks like this is a tabletop device and
what is the what um
what the box is is actually is actually
an earth enclosure which is going to
prevent radio frequency from escaping
and is going to prevent
interfering
um
with legitimacy or communications inside
it i have the machine the power supply
unit had to be stripped because i could
only drive up to 50 volts
inside the inside the earth enclosure so
i had to
take the the power supply unit of the
dell machine and put it outside driving
just a few cables inside there's also a
usrp b200 which is an sdr device a
software defined radio peripheral and
right next to it there is the target
phone um
under the phone there is a fan because
inside here it gets pretty pretty hot
especially when it runs for a long time
so it is it does need to be cooled down
and this is what it looks like um at a
very
you know in very abstract terms
um
so the digital machine is running ubuntu
and is running open bts open bts is
going to be the base station software
openvts is directly controlling our usrp
and we are also controlling the test
phone through uh through adb
uh the usrp and the test phone are
obviously going to be talking using uh
over gsm
and this all is going to be controlled
by another machine that is sitting
outside of the of the earth enclosure
and it's going to be communicating over
a version over serial connection the
reason to use a zero connection instead
of anything else
is that this earth enclosure is really
good at something this is isolating
radio frequency and therefore i could
not drive an ethernet connection through
it
because their capacitor separating the
inside and the outside so the so the
signal would
would get too attenuated
so
right now we are done with cellular
setup and let's take a look at how we
can actually
find the firmware and the or the os
binary for this for this box
it turns to be stored in the file system
it's really easy to fetch it
and this image
is designed to load at positions here in
the basement processor memory and as
such because there is no encryption or
whatever it can be directly loaded into
airport
um it is
some reason some reverse engineering
showed that it's actually based on
nucleus plus which as you might know is
a real time prevent preemptive operating
system
it is written in c and there's quite a
lot of documentation available online so
it's um
it's really easy to reverse engineer
what mediatek built into this
this source code also turns out to be
partially available online for unknown
reasons so that is that is even better
now that we have the basement firmware
and the os binary
we are going to take a look at how we
can find debugging symbols this can also
be found in the this can also be found
in the file system it's really easy to
find them and they're directly loadable
into anapra
with com with the script that the guys
had consequences
developed and by the way the rest of
this research builds upon path of least
resistance by consequence which is a an
excellent piece of research and a really
good point to get started
so now that we have this really brief
interaction to baseband and how we're
going to start with it we're going to
get to the debugger
we want to build a debugger and we want
to be able to do these things we want to
be able to read memory we want to be
able to read registers write memory at
breakpoints and after adding breakpoints
we also want to be able to remove them
so to do this we need to take the
following steps so we first need to
choose how we're going to
get the
base button processor and the
application processor to communicate
and
for this we have multiple options we can
choose between 80 commands and share
memory interfaces
um 80 commands as you might probably
know make use of the serial interface
between the baseband processor and the
application processor
therefore are synchronous and they're
quite well documented meaning that there
are
lengthy pdfs
documented the documenting the
at command set supported by the
by the
by the basement chip in question
um
there's also share memory which is
pretty undocumented and it's used
primarily by the radio interface layer
demon so we're not going to go for
share memory we're going to go for 80
commands and our strategy is going to be
to find an at command that is not used
and overwrite this command handler with
some sort of debugging stuff the
debugging debugger stuff that we're
going to be building um to send 80
commands on a mediatek phone
um i found out that there's slash dev
slash tti c0 which is the
serial interface between the baseband
processor and the application processor
however the gsm multiplexer daemon is
permanently attached which makes it
useless however the
multiplexer daemon exposes slash dev
slash radio slash atc 1 which stands for
at command interface 1.
we can just echo our 80 commands to it
but of course as you might have guessed
there are better solutions
if we take a look at logcat while we are
issuing our 80 commands it turns out
that
the radio interface layer demon writes
unsolicited input
unsolicited at command output directly
to logcat so we can either grip it or
even better we can install a p-trace
hook
into the radio interface layer demon
to patch a single call to this android
print to intercept whatever was meant to
be written into logcat
um now that we have chosen how
we are going to communicate
between uh where how the communication
between the application processor and
the basement processor are going to take
place
we need to choose a debugging mode uh we
and we need to design between paradigms
we have to decide between holding mode
and monitor mode if we're debugging in
halting mode this cpu the processor in
question is going to be stopped
completely while we're debugging a task
and if we choose to debug it in monitor
mode this cpu is going to maintain
functionality we have different
constraints here
as you as already as i already mentioned
nucleus plus is a real-time operating
system and it has a number of and it has
a number of tasks running these tasks
need to need to continue running as long
as we are as long as the base panel is
working because otherwise we would be
interrupting baseband and we would be
interrupting cellular communication we
really don't want that and on top of
that the communication
between the
between the application processor and
the basement processor as we decide is
going to be done with 80 commands and
therefore we do need the baseband to
cooperate with us therefore
i ended up choosing monitor mode but
this is not going to be very important
until we're dealing with breakpoints
so now that we can get
we have made some key decisions
we are going to um
first try to patch this firmware
to pass the string from the baseband
process to the application processor we
chose the ati command
and i found out that
the handler for this for this h command
is is in the functionary eta handler
which permanently sits as the in this
address as there is no slr whatsoever
the
mm-iit handler function looks like this
there are two interesting function calls
right here are my fast string print
which kind of which is lumiere to printf
and rmi to uart what is happening here
is that some information about the
baseband is being grabbed is being
passed to remember my fastest string
print and finally i remember i write to
you art
and i remember right to ur that's
exactly what you think it does it sends
um it sends some string over the serial
connection uh to the to the application
processor so our strategy right here is
going to be to make some room in this
stack uh you know in the past that we're
going to develop
and we're going to be calling in my
right ur to pass a custom string
whatever we want back to the basement
back to the application processor the
string that i chose is going to be ola
which means hello in spanish by the way
so here we're making some room in this
stack
we're configuring r0r1 and r2 with
arguments and we're just loading the
address of our mmi right here into our
six and we're just calling it
um pretty simple so far and the next
step knowing that we can just send data
we are going to
figure out if we can pass an actual
datum an actual hexadecimal value and an
integer from the baseband processor to
the application processor
in this case
we're going to try to read a single
register for example so this strategy
here is going to be to make some room in
this tag once again
and instead of calling i remember my
right ur directly we're going to first
call sprintf
passing a format specifier um
that consists of percentage x c or z or
zero zero to convert this datum into a
string this is first year c programming
um
and i did observe that if the datum's
first byte is zero zero there's a crash
rather than looking into the into the
root cause for this i decided to work
around it and i did this
by uh checking whether or not the
datum's first most significant byte is
set to zero zero and apply a different
format specifier whether it is or not
finally we call air memory to yard to
return this string to the application
processor and this is what the patch
looks like if this is the mystery
argument that we want to send we're just
going to load it
um we're just going to
call sprintf to create a string in the
stack right here at sp plus 0x4
where it's going this is going to be
where our
our return string is going to be placed
we're going to call sprintf right here
um and with the result string we're
going to call him right you are again
passing the string that we just created
this is really simple and by the way
this is going to be what it would look
like graphically in the in the baseband
uh
in the baseband memory so as you can see
this is what we overwrote
and
this is going to be our this is going to
be our patch and as you can see it is
returning prematurely without executing
the rest of what we did not patch
um now that we can patch the firmware to
pass data from the baseband processor
let's see what if we can do the opposite
let's see if we can pass some data from
the application processor to the
baseband processor
and
fortunately thanks to the previous patch
i observed that it was it is now
possible to read registers and i did
observe that r1 contains a pointer to
the 80 command pass to the 80 command
passes the string that was the string
that represents the 80 command that we
just passed
um so it is very simple once again we
can call atoy
to parse the decimal string
that follows the string ati so
after ati there would be a number and we
can just call atoy on that number
following the string ati um we can call
sprintf once again
and if we call air memory to ur we can
get the baseband to echo
whatever we just sent to it
however
with what we're just one instruction
away from being able to read the whole
baseband memory as with this integer
that we just managed to pass to the
baseband we can index memory
so if we use the parse integer
parsed by atoy to index memory
we can just read whatever there is in
the basement here i'm fetching
the 80 command
the 80 command string which is pointed
which is now going to be pointed to by
r0
i am
calling atoy right here
then
applying a different form a specifier uh
depending on whether the most
significant byte is set to 0 or not
i'm going to call s printf once again
and i
send back whatever came out of sprintf
back to the application processor
we can now read the whole basement
memory
however writing memory is a different
business we will have to disable some
memory protections
and
these
memory protections come in two different
in two different flavors their memory
protection set by the basement processor
firmware on its own memory
and this strategy is going to be to deal
with this
by patching the firmware once again
um there are also memory protection set
by the application perceptron startup
and to undo this we are going to load a
kernel object into the host kernel to
undo basically what the what the kernel
did to us on baseband processor startup
um it turns out that the baseband uh
firmware sets season mpu at the function
mpu underscore in it
and this is done by several calls to mpu
automate region and mpu make region
which if we reverse engineer them it
turns out that they are actually
programming the mpu programming
registers
i reverse engineer this course and it
turns out that there are nine of them
and these are the
these are the memory regions that are
defined
with the respective protection flags
we
have specifically we have issues with
the region number six run region number
seven and region number eight so to undo
them we are going to overwrite
the instructions setting um the
protection flux into the r2 register
which is later going to be used
to program mpu registers we're just
going to override it with an instruction
that
sets a different value in
in r2
uh so to deal with uh regions six and
seven we're just going to relax the
we're going to configure r2 with a
different protection flag that is going
to just disable uh the right protection
and the same applies for region number
eight
now that we have disabled the baseband
processor memory protection
i was trying to
i was trying to write memory after i had
disabled this but it was for some for
some reason impossible and i did notice
on the message during the during the
baseband process of restart
that this was being uh this was this was
being
this was being locked
uh this led me to believe that the
kernel is setting up some um
some memory restrictions
and it turns out that this is uh this
this is the case the partial
source code
for um
responsible for loading up the firmware
and starting the baseband processor is
available in github for unknown reasons
and it turns out that indeed there were
two
there are two regions being flagged as
um
there are two reasons being flagged as
read only or forbidden completely
and to deal with this we can just create
our own kernel object
and we can call eminpu's region
protection to
to undo these protections
here you can see that we are programming
um no protection
for both regions that we are interested
in
um now that we have disabled our memory
fractions for the baseband completely
uh we can pretty much write memory uh we
can write wherever we want in the rom
from we can actually instruct the
baseband processor to write wherever we
want in each room
and
now it becomes now
if we want to if we want to write to
executable memory if we are going to
write instructions instruction barriers
to become important at this point
to our final goal of building a debugger
i did i decided to define two new
special memory areas that are going to
be shared between bleed debuggy task and
the debugger task which are going to be
the the value status block
and the register bank so um both of the
both the debugger status block and the
right register bank are shared between
the debugger and the buggy
and the debugger status block is going
to be a set of flags set up by the
debugger for the debugging to act upon
these are going these flags are going to
be
um downfall registers
or remove the breakpoint or whatever
whereas the right register bank is going
to be basically a snapshot of all the
registers uh created by the debuggy for
the debugger to consume and send back to
the application processor
and um now for the not for the real deal
now the most important most difficult
thing we want to set some breakpoints
um
so
we are going to consider that when we
are debugging a baseband we are going to
have two tasks at any point first the
debuggy task is going the debugger task
is going to be the 80 command handler
that we just overwrought
and it's going to influence the debuggy
task
this is going to be doing it in two ways
first off is going to be setting flux in
the debugger status block for the
debuggy task to act upon
and most importantly is going to replace
any instruction that is going to
hopefully be executed by the debagitas
with a breakpoint
the debugging task is going to be any
other and is going to be stuck in an
active weight loop
when a breakpoint when a breakpoint is
encountered
in this loop it one is going to want to
read the flag set by the debuggie but
set by debugger and act appropriately on
them so for example if the debugger
instructed the debuggy to dump its
registers it's going to do so and if the
debugger instructs it by key to replace
its own trap instruction on breakpoint
removal is also going to do sorry
the breakpoint instruction that we are
using is software interrupt swi also
known as svc
and it's kind of similar to the x86 or
x64 instruction
and when executed
the processor operating mode is going to
become supervisor or svc and is going to
an execution is going to be resumed at
the address
fetched
from the interrupt vector table
corresponding to
corresponding to the svc handler
in memory is going to look like this so
if this is our debuggie task when it
hits a breakpoint it's going to be stuck
in a loop
and it's going to be acquiring the
debugger status block that is going to
be set by the
debugger for actions to take for weather
to for whether for instructions
and is going to fulfill those by writing
back into the
into the
red register bank or is going to fulfill
them by removing it if by removing its
own breakpoint if instructed
after the
after the loop is finished when the
when the breakpoint is finally removed
it's going to want to jump back to the
to the original breakpoint instruction
that will now have to be replaced by the
original instruction
we need to take into account that in arm
we have two instructions set
these are arm and thumb
and the instruction set in use is always
given by the bit by the bit t of the
current processor status register
and to alternate between these two
instruction encodings
the
branches structure
bx and i think most of the branch
instructions are going to copy the bit 0
of the pc of the program counter to the
current processor status register so for
example if we're jumping from an odd
address to an even address the
instruction setting use changes from
thumb to arm and vice versa there are
some challenges with the proposed
architecture namely
that the breakpoints the loop
representing the breakpoint must
contemplate whether
originally the processor was executing
thumb or arm coil
and finally after
the after the after exiting the
the debugging loop
the original processor mode has to be
restored
meaning that if this processor was in
system mode if it was executing a higher
privilege level it must be it must go
back
into into that original mode
apart from obviously restoring registers
so as not to disturb um the execution of
the original program
on top of that if we're running our
tasks indefinitely in an endless loop
this is going to result in uh in
in a starvation scenario which
eventually results in a baseband crash
so we need to avoid this somehow
to prevent starvation i had to reverse
engineer the tasks running in nucleus
plus in this mediatek basement firmware
and i found that there are 60 touchs of
them the way it works
is that lower priority tasks cannot
preempt higher priority so if there is a
if there's a high priority task running
it cannot be kicked out by a lower
priority task
and
the issue right here is that our debuggy
task
might have a higher priority that
that the debugger task therefore if the
debuggy task is stuck in an endless loop
in an active weight loop we might not be
able to keep it kick it out as the
scheduler will keep scheduling it
without possibility to breaking the loop
our options to solve this here are to
set the debuggy task to the lower to the
lowest priority possible but this gives
way to many other challenges
and also on top of that other
the correct workings of nucleus plus
might depend on the priorities being
configured
configured correctly
so
the solution in this case is going to be
to sleep before to force the debugging
task to sleep
in a way to force preemption
and we're going to do this by calling
call sleep task which takes a
millisecond value
and the way this works is when
call sleep task is called then tcc task
sleep is called
which does some error checking if no
errors are encountered then tcc called
task sleep is called
and finally tcc task sleep calls tcc
suspend task veneer which effectively
suspends the calling task
for a given number of milliseconds
the issue once again is that call slip
task cannot be called into into svc mode
and we know that every time that the
the
that the software interrupt instruction
that our interrupting instruction is
executed the processor is going to
switch to svc mode
so the solution in this case is going to
be on each iteration of the debugger
loop we are going to change to the
original execution mode
we're going to call
call sleep task
and we're going to then try to jump back
to the original breakpoint address so if
the breakpoint hasn't
yet been removed
then swi is executed again we go back
into the loop
and we execute everything over and over
and over
however if the breakpoint had been
removed the original instruction gets
executed and we continue normally in
sequence
so our strategy for setting a breakpoint
is going to be this we're going to
override the swi handler address
with um
with uh with the address of a function
that we have patched into the firmware
and our breakpoint entry
after swi
instruction the instruction set in use
is going to be rm so we're going to
continue
executing whatever we want into arm
and we're going to use this opportunity
to check the debugger status block to
see what the debugger requested from
from the debuggy and we're going to
fulfill those so if the debugger wants
us
to remove our own breakpoint we're going
to remove it here if the debugger wants
us to dump the registers we're going to
do it here we're going to attempt to
exit the breakpoint
and we're going to take a look at how we
exit the bracket a bit later
however
if
the debugger had instructed the debuggy
to remove its own breakpoint we are
going to patch again
the breakpoint instruction with the with
whatever was
there originally
and
when we are attempting to access the
breakpoint we are going to restore the
operating mode of the processor as well
as the registers
if this was arm
we are going to we're going to
we're going to um well before before we
jump back to the breakpoint address uh
we're going to call cal sleep task
and if we were executing arm we're going
to uh just jump to uh just jump to the
base to the breakpoint address which
should be given by the link register
if it was thumb we just need to
increment the breakpoint address by one
which we just took from lr from the link
register and we're going to just jump to
the incremental link register which is
which is basically going to bring back
the processor into thumb mode
the patch is going to look like this
so the way it works is that when a
breakpoint is hit
the address of our sv modified svc
handler routine is going to be fetched
from the interrupt vector table
and we're going to jump to it
we are going to do whatever the debugger
instructed us to do
um and um we're going to do whatever the
debugger instructor has to do by
checking the contents of the debugger
status blocked and by updating it if
necessary
once we're done with this
we're going to try to jump back
in a way um
in a way that we are re-attempting the
instruction that triggered the
breakpoint after we have called cal
sleep task
and now for my greatest trick i'm going
to try to set a breakpoint
and you in in a live baseball target i'm
going to
try to read a message from memory live
after sending
after sending a
gsm layer 3 message
um there are two important scripts that
we're that we need to be familiar with
let me debug agent new dot py which is
going to be controlling the debugger
via adb via the android debug bridge
um basically uh
debug the
debugger agent
is going to be issuing the 80 commands
that i'm that corresponds to the actions
that i want the debugger to take instead
of me having to craft it manually
final dot py is another is script that
we're going to be using
to deliver a base64 encoded gsm layer 3
message directly to the basement
because we're using openbts here
openbts allows us to open up a test call
which
results in the opening of a udp socket
in the local machine
to which whatever we send is going to
end up being delivered to the layer 3 of
the of the
of the gsm protocol stack in the
basement
um
and
so this this script actually understands
most of uh the most of the assembly r3
messages thanks to this which is a
spreadsheet
uh that i created by
damping
most of the pdf uh specific gsm
specification messages right here and
then parsing it using scapi
um
the final.pyscript is also going to
manage uh openvds startup if we require
it to do so
it's going to check with the association
of the phone to our
malicious space
to our malicious base station and is
going to do
this optionally by by means of uh
by
emulating taps and taking screenshots
um
and before right before the test case is
sent we're going to paint the baseband
over over an attic command we're going
to issue the command 80 to which we
expect to get an okay response
and finally we are going to send this
user message message over
over the layer 3 channel over the test
call
um we are going to be setting a
breakpoint at this address
and we're going to send this test case
which is in coordinate base64 which
corresponds to a mobility management
location update reject we're going to be
reading the registers on the baseband so
the baseband chip live using the
debugger and we're going to be
reading the memory live using the
debugger as well
the test case is this one as i told you
location update reject
the reason why i chose this message is
because we have this reject cross
field right there
and it is um i i can use it to stick in
there whatever i want i decided to stick
in there as they reject close four a's
which are given by these 441 bytes right
there
and because i am interested in verifying
that this debugger works i'm going to
be taking a look at this incoming ilm
struct which is a variable
passed
to this
l3
um to this l3 module by the lower layer
and i'm going to be interested in the
peer buff ptr member
which should contain a pointer to the to
the message that was just received over
over over the earth
because i'm interested in this spear
buff pdr
um remember i'm going to be interested
in the contents of r7 which is written
to right there
and therefore i'm going to be overriding
that call to mm-com has off
with uh with a software interrupt which
is going to which is going to result
into
the breakpoint getting hit
at the um address of the of the
overwritten handler being fetched from
the from the
interrupt vector table
is going to result into the in the
debugger checking
what indeed checking what it needs to do
from a structure from the debugger and
this um
and as a result of this breakpoint being
hit
execution is going to be stuck
in this swi instruction for a while how
long for as long as we want to given
that
all other tasks are going to continue
normally
so let's get right through it i already
talked about what i have here
so right now there is um there is no gsm
network um
uh started so i'm going to
connect through my cr connection to this
to the dell machine inside the inside
the earth enclosure
and let's see what happens
so i'm using tmax which is terminal
multiplexer and this is necessary
because i only have one terminal this is
not an ssh link this is just a zero link
so i can just get one terminal and you
need a terminal multiplexer i'm going to
go to tab one which should
um
i'm going to instruct open bts to start
now we need to close the lid as right
now there is some
there's a gsm network in here and i
don't want your phones connecting to it
now that
open bts has been started we can go
ahead and install our p trace hook we
can just clear this
start adb
we need to figure out which of uh which
uh process the mediatek
um radio interface layer daemon is going
to be running on so that we can inject
our pre-trace hook on it
so we are attaching to each of the
threads that
this
that this process is comprised of and
now that we have installed our pitch
race hook we can receive
um
we can send and receive 80 commands
directly instead of having an um
and desired output being placed on
logcat now that i have
the
phrase hook running i can just
um
i can just um
go to open bt
i can just
go to um
to my phone dot py task
oh actually
so i'm going to reboot the phone for a
second and when it reboots i'm going to
manually associate it to this gsm
network that i have created now it is
putting up
and after this even if the demo works
i'm going to show you a video of what it
looks uh from the inside because this
shows it much much better than
using it from there
it's almost booted so now that
now i'm just going to
associate it manually to the gsm network
so right now i'm searching for networks
which
should show only one the one that exists
inside
and it did indeed it does show it i'm
going to click on it
and it's regis attempting to register on
it
now i'm registered so now i'm going to
install
the
dp trace full once again
so now we're attached to it
and
we're going to
get our test case
now
uh final lot by is loading the
predefined message types is also going
to make a few checks on whether the
baseband is associated to
is associated to our network
and let's see what those checks look
like
so right now a test call has been
established so we have a udp socket
that
we can use to send messages directly to
the
uh to the uh gsm layer 3 of the target
basement
the test case is now ready to be sent
but right before we send it we're going
to use the debugger to set a breakpoint
and we want to set the breakpoint
we're going to first request reading the
registers
this worked
and we're going to set a thumb
breakpoint
at this address which corresponds to
what i just showed before
so the breakpoint is set
and now we can just go ahead and send
our test case we press enter right here
and if everything worked
the debugger should be able to show us
the registers at the time the breakpoint
was set let's take a look at let's take
a look at them
and indeed it worked we were able to
read the registers at the moment
that the breakpoint was hit
at this point we're quite interested as
i said in r7 which is going to contain
the um the um the message that was
received over there so let's read memory
at that at that
at that place
on indeed as you can see there
effectively
the whole message that we intended to
send including the four a's have been
placed in memory as we could just read
it
hopefully the baseband hasn't crashed
so we are going to remove the
breakpoints and we're going to check
whether or not after execution continues
we are able to ping the baseband again
over there
so the breakpoint has been removed and
we can
instruct find out py to keep
to keep to carry on with the with other
checks let's take a look at
window number five and let's take a look
at what happened
and indeed
we were able to pick the baseband over
there again and we were able to also
check that uh the baseband is indeed
responding over an 80 command and it's
also the phone is still alive it's still
responding over adb
and finally i'm going to go to
i'm going to go back to the debugger
and i'm going to check that the
that the
that the basement chip is still alive
and this is still alive indeed so the
basement processor didn't crash as a
result of uh we debunking it so i would
say that this is successful at this
point now i'm going to show
the demo that i had pre-recorded
which shows the
manual association of the
of the of the phone
i'm starting open bts once again this
you already saw
now there's a json network inside the rf
enclosure and we're going to proceed to
define uh to associate
it manually to our network
we need to search for networks we click
on network operators we search on
networks we search for networks and
right here is searching if you were
really really sharp at this point we
have seen you have seen that at the top
of the phone in the status bar there are
three bars representing that we're
already connected to the network but
we're just going to search for them
anyways
we see that indeed one network is found
so we click on it to associate and we're
registering it
now that we're registering it we can go
back to the terminal and install our
pre-choice hook
and display trace hook as i already
explained
is going to allow us to intercept
unwanted 80 command results directly
from
directly from the mediatek radio
interface layer demon before they go to
look at
this jordan is on so
now we're
going to send the test case we're going
to prepare to send it
and here there's some there are some
checks been done on the phone
to
ensure that
before we try to open a test call the
phone is associated to our cellular
network
and the test call itself is stable
now the test case is ready to be sent
once again
and we send it by pressing enter
we request the registers to be read by
configuring the debugger status block
now we set the breakpoint
now when the message that we're going to
be sending is removed is is received in
the baseband side execution is going to
be stuck
and we can read the registers once again
this is what i showed before already
we're interested in r7
so we can
read read memory at that point
and this you already saw and we did
we were able to retrieve the contents of
memory at that point
also back to the presentation
i think this next slide we don't need
because you already saw the that the
expected results are actually there
and
by overwriting this swi interrupt
handler we were able to indeed set and
remove breakpoints
so our diy basement baseball debugger
wishlist is now complete
and
of course i'm going to be releasing this
code later today which is going to be
comprised of all the firmware patches
the logic to patch the firmware
image itself
the pitrace hoop program and the
debugger agent oh what happened
okay and the debugger agent or all of
them all of this is going to be layered
today in this address so yeah just go
for it
and if you have some questions at this
point and if you're if i can answer them
i would be more than happy to do so
[Applause]
you