um
yeah so i'm gonna be talking about a uh
a project that i did kind of earlier
last year um
wasn't actually supposed to be on
offensive topic um but i started doing
some research and in the course of the
research i ended up finding a bunch of
privilege elevation bugs
in windows so that'll be what this uh
this talk is about
um i'll start give a little bit of a
background kind of about me um so i've
been doing uh computer security mostly
in the offensive uh research area um
since 2005 sir for quite a while um and
then a year ago um i kind of switched
teams joined uh field effect and i've
been doing defensive work uh since then
um which means now i can share some of
the stuff i've been doing i don't have
to keep it secret so
yeah and one of the things i've learned
over that this amount of time in the
industry is that for any kind of
research project to be taken seriously
by you guys and get attention um you
need a catchy name and a cool logo so uh
there i think we've got it
um
right so uh i'm kind of gonna go a
little bit in a bit of a weird order
going through this but essentially
follow the uh the research that i was
originally doing um and then kind of the
bugs i discovered along the way and how
that led on to
to finding other bugs
[Music]
and just kind of a quick aside here
about the kind of techniques used in
things so this was all all this was a
reverse engineering done with uh ghidra
for static analysis
and then using wind bag with vmware
hyper-v for dynamic analysis
which makes it a lot easier to skip over
some of the kind of tedious non
non-interesting parts of the static
analysis
so the first thing i started doing was
oh actually go back up here um
before i get going i wanted to uh just
go over a little bit about uh
some of the windows kernel i o uh this
is going to apply to
several other things that i'm talking
about later
um and specifically uh when user mode is
talking to kernel mode how does kernel
mode access the uh the data um
so there's kind of three main methods
and i'm stealing the uh the names from
uh the ioctal handlers in windows um but
this also applies to how the patterns of
how memories manage from just the
regular syscalls
so there's a the first one is a buffered
io which is where
kernel will take any data from user mode
and make a full copy of it in its own
memory so that when the drivers are
accessing
the memory they don't need to worry
about uh you know it's user mode changed
it or anything it should be a static
copy of what was provided
the second method
being direct i o is when kernel
will lock the user mode pages in memory
and then create a mapping
of a kernel address pointing to the same
physical pages so that
it doesn't require any copying it's a
little faster but user mode both user
mode and kernel mode can
see and change the values in the in
those
memory pages so if you're writing code
that's doing direct i o
you need to make sure you're you know
aware of those kind of issues that can
come up if user mode changes things on
you
and then the last
method is uh just if kernel directly
accesses user mode memory um
oh called neither i o so
yeah that's kind of a little bit more
tricky that uh kernels provided the user
mode addresses uh
and it can as long as it's in the
process context of the user mode
application it can just read and write
directly to memory however um it has to
be within uh tri-accept blocks in the
kernel drivers
because if a page wherever to become
unmapped by user mode it will cause a
blue screen if not
and also kernel drivers are supposed to
enclose any access or before they access
any range of memory they need to probe
it for read or write to ensure that
the address range is in a valid user
mode range and they're not
user modes not providing kernel pointers
um
yeah so that's just kind of some basic
reminders about uh windows kernel i o
and memory access
so the uh
the first bit of uh
what led me down this path was i started
looking at uh into alpc um which is the
advanced local procedure call
and so on on windows this is uh was
introduced with windows vista um and
it's how all kind of a lot of the ipc is
done
in windows and they wanted to
kind of create a more performant version
um compared to older versions of windows
and um so the reason i was looking at
this was that um
just to see if there was any way kind of
our defensive product could could
see any of the messages going by or
getting kind of metadata around what was
happening on the on the system just to
help try and defend the endpoints
against malicious behavior
um
i ended up getting distracted with all
this research and
that that other research is still
pending
um
yeah so the alpc interface is uh
primarily undocumented there's just
little snippets here and there talking
about it
as you can see in the uh
the list of apis here it's not that big
a list of sys calls
and really it behaves a lot like a
traditional
socket programming interface
you know there's a client and a server
you listen for connections and then can
send messages back and forth
um
and some of the uh yeah performance
features that were added a big one was
there's a lot of uses of usage of shared
memory so whether it's between you know
the
client in the kernel or server in the
kernel or actually client and server can
share memory directly so they can
exchange data without even having to
send it through the kernel at all
and then a lot of support for i o
completion ports which just
speeds up
makes it more it makes it easier to
access
to get notifications of reads or writes
or messages that are coming through
another point i wanted to make with this
is that the alpc kind of because it's a
core part of
windows ipc is accessible from all
sandboxes that
all that i looked at anyway
so we'll take a little bit of a look at
alpc messages and kind of what they look
like so this structure definition
is a port message
um
this is a header that goes on all
messages that are coming into and out of
user mode
and kind of the interesting things there
that it's got a couple of length fields
at the beginning anytime there's length
piercings that's interesting i'm not
really sure why there's two here but
there's a
one the first one is uh the length of
the data and then the second one is the
total length of the header and the
actual appended data although it would
make sense if the uh if they did that
for kind of forwards compatibility
reasons if they thought the header might
change size uh old code could be uh
could still handle new additions uh if
messages were changed in the future
um and besides just kind of opaque data
to the kernel messages that are
exchanged can also handle a bunch of
different types of metadata
so client and server can exchange
handles to different things on windows
impersonation information so if the
server wants to impersonate the client
when doing some sort of operation
to ensure the permission checks are good
that information can be
contained within the metadata and then
also shared memory details so if a
client and server have agreed they're
going to be
exchanging
information through some sort of shared
memory region then
the details of that can be shared
through
through the
metadata um
so when you're sending messages there's
kind of
a couple different ways to send and
receive them so
the slow path what i'm calling the slow
path is if you just have a vanilla
client a vanilla server
when a message gets sent down it gets
copied into kernel memory so the kernel
code will allocate a copy of it and then
stick it on the receiving ports uh
message queue and it gets saved there
and then when the recipient says i want
to receive a message
it will get copied off into back into
user mode so that's for to send one
message that's um two copies
sort of drive out
um so the uh one of the performance
to make that a little faster using
completion lists
so completion lists are
they're kind of a region of memory
that's created
by either end of the board or both
they're
optional um and they
it's a shared region of memory between
the kernel and one end of the port
and the what is used for storing any
kind of pending receive messages um
so there's different parts of a
completion list there's a header which
is the structure that you can see here
and then there's a section that can kind
of contains a list of any pending
messages
a bitmap section that's used to
to do allocations out of the data
section which is the last one
and in the header as you can see there's
like offsets and sizes of all the
different sections
um so look at kind of this and a picture
form
um
so this is a
kind of a completion list um and so you
can see at the top there's a header it's
got offsets to the three different
sections
um
and so what happens when a uh when a new
message comes in to be so if the
kernel has a message and wants to
deliver it to a port that has a
completion list
the first things it does is it looks for
free memory in the completion list so
it'll scan the bitmap looking for a
range of zero bits
to cover whatever the size is
so the bitmap's all just zeros and ones
and indicates which parts of the data
are in use um
once it finds a free section it'll do an
interlocked exchange to set them all to
one and then that will claim a chunk of
data in the data section so then i can
copy the the message data in
um and at that point it'll copy the like
four byte offset to the data and stick
that into the
wherever the list
tail is pointing to so the list tail is
just an offset into the list section
and the list section is a group of
offsets into the data section where the
messages are so as messages are received
and kind of waiting they'll get written
in
at the tail of the list
and then when someone calls receive or
when the client wants to receive a
message they don't need to make any
kernel calls
they can just look at where the list
head is get the offset for the data and
then look down into the data section to
read it out and once they've used the
data they would just zero out the bits
in the bitmap to free the memory
and then adjust the list head up by one
to say we've taken the message out
um
yeah so that's how they work
and that's also where
spotted the the first problem that kind
of led me down this uh this research
rabbit hole so this is the code
for
i hope it's big enough to read
for complete dismap dispatch message so
this is the code that handles once a
message has been received into kernel
mode and it's being
added to the completion list of a
client port
um so down the left side kind of the the
interesting parts are marked with
comments so the first comment there
is
the
call to allocate the buffer out of the
data section so from that call um it it
gets an offset of where it has enough
free data for the message and then it
calculates uh the user math message
which is a pointer to this uh where the
message is going to go in this shared
memory region
and then at the bottom
of the screen on the left there
it copies in all the port message
headers so that includes all the length
fields the header length data length and
the flag fields and so then moving on on
to the other side uh it then copies the
actual data in um
through those a couple of calls and then
if so the important part is if there's
any attributes in the message it needs
to calculate where the attribute should
go so it has to um
figure out the location of kind of the
source and that's the source set sorry
has to figure out the location of the
destination attributes
by using the data length of the actual
message
and so the bug here is that
it goes and reads the length instead of
from the original kind of fixed copy it
had it goes and reads it back out of the
shared
user buffer so it's copied the header
already into this buffer that's shared
with user mode
and it goes in and reads the length out
again so if a malicious application is
able to change the length um in between
these two uh
the section and one where it copies the
real value in and then where it actually
uses it um we can end up with the
attribute section or the destination for
the attributes pointing past the end of
this buffer
um
and so that's exactly what's possible
and then you see this um expose
attributes at the end that's essentially
does copying of the attributes into the
pointer so it gives us a memory
corruption past the end of this um
pointer so
i found this and uh i was initially
pretty excited because i
knew you could use alpc from anywhere
i'm like oh memory corruption from
from inside you know kind of any sandbox
sounds pretty exciting
and uh we're thinking about what we
should do with it well to determine that
kind of the severity of the bug we
wanted to look and see well can we prove
whether or not it's exploitable so i
started trying to look at well okay how
do we turn this
memory corruption into an exploit
and so very quickly started running into
a few hiccups
so it turns out that this is not like
standard page pool or non-page pool
memory corruption
which has all been like lots of
information on how to exploit those and
we'll get to that later too
instead with this memory comes from
this call here it's mapped block pages
and so when the
when the kernel says you know i want to
map these pages into user mode or into
kernel memory sorry
the address range it comes from is
actually from the system pte range and
so you can see on the side i've used
windbag to dump the address layout
of the vm at the time
and there's that system pte section
highlighted in red so it comes from that
address range
you can see there's the page pools in
there the couple of non-page pools and
other address ranges um
one thing to note about this is uh so
for all i think all of windows 10
definitely the newer ones
all these addresses are randomized with
kernel aslr on boot
and the order changes and everything um
also something to notice is that the
size is really big a lot bigger than uh
four gigabytes so even if you could
predict what order they were going to be
in and thought well maybe i can corrupt
from one into the other that's
you would need like a very specific kind
of bug you definitely can't with this
one
um
and so i started looking at the system
pdes or what was what else was in that
address range so to looking for some
sort of primitives that could be used to
groom or to you know to turn into an
exploit
and it turns out most of these are used
for parameters and
windows system calls
and so which are typically very
short-lived
colonel will allocate some memory just
during the system call and free it at
the end
and also almost in almost all of those
cases all the data is coming from user
mode are about to go to user mode so
being able to change it doesn't add
doesn't give it give us anything you can
use towards exploitation um
so what really would be looking for was
kind of
memory that or allocations in this
address space that have a longer
lifetime
we can kind of free on demand and would
have something useful in it
i spent about a week
looking looking for ways to solve this
and started
going through all different kind of
areas of the kernel anywhere i thought
something might be using this that could
could be doing something interesting in
this address space
um
and so the
tldr on this is i wasn't successful um
if anybody has good ideas about how to
exploit this i'd be very curious to know
um
but if you're ever stuck and you can't
figure out how to exploit a bug uh the
easiest way is just to go find more
um
so
one of the areas i i was looking into to
try and find uh
things that could be used to exploit
the alpc bug was windows sockets
so i was specifically choosing areas
that i knew
were still accessible from kind of low
privileged processes this one sockets
are not accessible from all sandboxes
like not the browser sandboxes but they
are from from some other ones
uh and i also knew that windows sockets
in particular are very
very complex so i thought oh this might
be a good idea good place to look for uh
things that might have
might help with
the grooming or exploitation of the
previous bug
um
so i don't expect you can read that but
so the the diagram on the right is kind
of a rough diagram of um
windows networking stack layout so
windows provides a standard socket api
it's almost
posix compliant but probably not quite
so you have all the standard socket
calls but whereas in other os operating
systems those are all syscalls directly
to kernel and windows all that is
implemented in winsock which is a user
mode
module and the actual kernel mode
interface for sockets is through the
ancillary function driver or afd.cis
which is
the opposite of simple so this uh the
dispatch table i have in here um
is just kind of a list of all the
functions that are used just for doing
control operations on the sockets and
one of them is even as a secondary table
so there's a whole other list of things
oops
um
yeah so it's pretty complicated um
so i thought it's good to look at so
also in this diagram
so there's afd.cis which is where
user mode would normally interact with
the kernel
but if you're a kernel device driver and
you want to do networking
in the past the legacy interface just
used the transport driver interface or
tdi.cis
and the
new way well
it's been around since vista but the the
new way um is to use the windsock kernel
uh interface uh or wsk
but they keep around for backwards
compatibility uh tdi interface
and then from there uh anybody talking
to afd or or one of the two kernel mode
options would then be able to talk down
the network stack to the different
layers
um so going into a little bit of details
about how sockets were created
so to create a socket you just can open
up the afd device with this
special endpoint path on the end
so you open up device slash afd
endpoint um
and to specify the options about how the
socket can be created you
use extended attributes um and depending
on the specifics of the extended
attribute name and what's in there you
can do
you can create your whole family of
normal networking sockets there's also
sand sockets
for talking to storage area networks
or rio sockets which were news to me so
this is a registered i o extension i was
introduced around windows 8 and it's to
allow faster i o
with sockets um i didn't really play
around with them so i don't know more
than that but if you wanted to do the
standard tcp udp unix sockets you use an
extended attribute name of this afd open
packet
xx and i have in the comments that are
kind of the
the fields
that you would fill out to get a tcp
socket um so you have flags
the flags field you can
just how you specify like you want to
raw socket or connection list or see
root a whole bunch of different options
there's also your standard address
family
address family address type and protocol
fields um and you can also specify a
device name a transport device name at
the end so in this case we're saying we
want to use the tcp driver as the
transport you could also specify
udp or there's a couple different
options
so
the interesting thing when i started
looking at this and how this is handled
is that there's a whole bunch of
different ways to do kind of the same
thing and
changing these
the values slightly in this packet ends
up creating
sockets that are treated slightly
differently by the kernel
so if you send in these parameters here
you'll get a tcp socket
out of it
a handle to a tcp socket and if you
remove the transport name from this and
just put in the address family address
type and protocol you get a tcp socket
as well
or if you just remove set the protocol
field to zero you also get a tcp socket
which seems like you know not not a big
deal but actually internally afd is
going to have set different flags on the
endpoint object that gets created
which is going to result in slightly
different code paths
happening in the kernel so you might not
notice it from user mode at all but in
the kernel
the
the rest of the operations on that
socket are being handled slightly
differently
other thing uh
we spent some time looking into was okay
well how are um
options set on the socket so this is
your standard eye optical socket set
socket option uh calls um all of these
are handled by the uh
this uh afd tli i o control uh dispatch
um
and they come in from user mode and
there's a little bit of validation that
happens and then they get passed on down
to the various uh lower level transport
drivers whether it's tcp or the pacer
driver or the
unix socket driver
and through the validation user mode's
restricted to kind of a subset of
options so on the right this is the the
structure that gets passed in from user
mode so we have a type field which is
tells the uh
indicates whether you're doing you're
setting a socket option getting one
doing the i octal socket
or it can be zero which is uh
not allowed in user mode it's for
internal only you set your
level and then ioptil code and the data
that goes in
um
so in terms of the validation that
happens uh this function here the
on the left gets called and so this is
saying it gets calls that's coming from
user mode so first of all i make sure
that that endpoint field um
is set in the packet
and then it checks the type so the first
block the one or two was set or get
ioctyls set or sorry not iota set or get
socket options um and if you're that it
makes sure that your socket level is not
uh
well these two values you can't do fff c
or d um anything else is okay and then
the else case saying it's also okay if
it's type three which is ioctal socket
and your level is zero
so that restricts any use of the
internal option
and then on the other side
just after this function is called
there's also handling
for a couple of special ioctal codes
so this
the first one is a set qos
and it does some special handling for
that and the second one
function code if you look it up in wk is
in the wdk headers is reserved um but
with the symbols the function that it
calls is associate qos so presumably
that's
uh socket option associate qos
and what both of those
functions do is they just do some
conversion on the buffer so you pass in
some input buffer they do a bit of
special conversion and then send a new
buffer down through the rest of the
kernel stack
yeah so this is going to become
important
later um so next up we have the uh
well i guess i'll back up a second so
one one thing i thought of kind of when
i got to here was um
so initially i was just going through
and looking for
allocations for things that i could
groom the first bug with um
but as i kind of learned more about the
code base i started thinking i was like
well i wonder if there's like a way to
bypass these checks because of all these
different options on the sockets um
it could change how
what different code pads there were so i
started looking
at keeping that kind of in the back of
my mind is something i wanted to keep an
eye out for
so i already mentioned this tdi
interface um so yeah it's the legacy
interface um and so what kernel clients
would do is if they uh
they would create a socket um
through the tdi or an endpoint socket
and if they want to set options they
talk um directly
to uh
originally it was tdi but there's this
driver at
transport driver
interface extension or tdx.sys and
really it's just
provides the old interface and as a
wrapper to the new tcp
afd stack so if you're setting options
in that case the old legacy drivers will
talk to tdx
and can send ioctals directly into the
stack and it
doesn't go through the same validation
that's in afd.cis
whereas a regular application it will
get a socket handle
it talks to afd.cis it goes through the
validation code
and then afd will look up what's the
transport layer endpoint and then send
the ioctyl packet on down
and so i began wondering well is there
any way for us for a user mode
application to talk to tdx directly
and so there is
you can you can open a handle to the
device
but you can't open any endpoints on it
that's all
blocked from user mode there's a couple
of kind of control eye octals that don't
do anything interesting
but
what i did find out was that if you use
some of those different options i was
talking about earlier um
depending on how you create the socket
uh it can have handles as the end the
kernel endpoint for the socket will have
handles associated with the transport
layer driver um
and the endpoint and the transport layer
endpoint can be associated with the
with the socket and there's one of the
afd functions and that big dispatch
table was a function to query those
handles so if you create the socket in
just the right way and then you issue
this query handle call
afd will return you a handle to the tdx
endpoint so which we couldn't open
directly but if colonel's kind enough to
give us a handle then we could start
talking to it so with that handle we're
able to call into the tdx drivers
ioctal interface
and bypass afd entirely in all the
protections that were in there
so
i thought well that's for sure there's
got to be
bugs if we can hit that code path so at
that point i started saying well i'm
going to start auditing some of these uh
transport drivers and look at their eye
octal handlers or set socket option
handlers
and see if there's anything interesting
going on there if i don't have the same
restrictions
um
and so that's where i found the first
bug um
down here uh and so all the bugs that i
mentioned here almost all of them
have been uh
all the ones i'm going to give details
for have been patched already
um
yeah i don't really have much much code
for this i started looking at what you
could hit if you set uh
the type to zero so zero again was the
control only or internal only option
and one of the
things that got called was this query
security endpoint function which simply
returns a pointer to the security
descriptor for the socket there's no
like
it's not even a bug it's just it was
never supposed to be called by user mode
so right away you get a
an address in the page pool
from the kernel so super super easy info
leak um
yeah oh and one thing i wanted to point
out with a slide too is uh if you look
at the i octal structure structure here
um it's a little bit different than the
one that we used through afd so there's
none there's a few less fields
just type level ioctal and then we have
an input buffer and an output buffer but
otherwise it's handled the same once you
get down to this level
um
so i i didn't do a demo of this just
took a screenshot of this so it's
really simple code you just open the
endpoint with the right
flag set
um
but one thing i should mention in order
for this whole bypass to work you have
to bind uh yeah you either have to
connect the socket or bind it to an
address um otherwise the
the handles don't get set for the tdx
endpoint
so that does prevent the bypass from
working inside all the sandboxes i
looked at
so you bind the socket and then you
query the tdx handle and then you just
call this one nioctyl and it sends you
back a page pool pointer
but that's not just an info leaks not
too exciting however
um
there's the corresponding function uh
that's set security so the first one was
a query security there's a set security
it's exactly the same except instead of
reading the pointer out you get to write
the pointer so this lets an attacker
write
set the security descriptor for saka to
any value
so
that's kind of neat well what does it do
with that
there's probably
multiple ways to approach this um but it
turned out the uh
the easiest way was kind of right right
right there as soon as when i was
looking at the code it just takes the
pointer from user mode and then calls
this ob reference security descriptor on
it
and if you look at that function it just
does a little bit of pointer math and
then
does an increment on that address so
this gives you an arbitrary increment of
any address in the kernel
so that's
especially with an info league that
should definitely be enough
to win
um
one thing i found looking for bugs is
what two things i guess one is if you're
in an area of code and you start finding
bugs there's a good chance there's going
to be more because of either has not
been audited well or the person was was
not thinking uh didn't have the right
mindset to program defensively uh and
also i find i'll get to do it like a
role so if i'm able to spot a particular
type of bug
i usually start seeing it
tend to they tend to come in bunches
anyway finding bugs
um just not usually
this many so the second
thing if you recall when i talked back
about the validation
there was also um
besides just the restrictions on types
coming in there was also those two
functions that did some extra massaging
of the input data so there was a this
associate qos or quality of service
function and what that was
did was like i mentioned it was
converting the input buffer into some
other format so
this one was not uh there's no symbols
for what the or use examples of using it
so i don't know entirely what the
structure is
but there was some structure you were
supposed to pass in on the left
that has a file handle and some other
value and then it would get converted to
this structure on the right that has a
file object pointer so it looks up the
object for the file handle
and a couple of other values uh and so
when you come in through
the tdx bypass you're able to pass in
the structure on the right so you can
pass in a pointer to an arbitrary file
object um
which is the file objects are pretty
complicated there's for sure a way to
exploit that
but when i started looking at it
so this is the
the function here at the top
so the second case is if you pass in
that structure with the file object
pointer
it starts doing a whole bunch of stuff
with the file object it very quickly got
complicated uh
all the things hoops you'd have to jump
through to try and keep it from crashing
while getting some useful primitive out
of it
then i noticed that at the beginning of
the this function there was a check and
said if you didn't pass in the proper
structure and you just pass in a pointer
we're just going to bump a reference
count on that so
this is another
arbitrary increment uh primitive here
so that was the uh
the second one
so the uh
the third one and interesting they um
uh when microsoft assigned cves for
these although the info leak and these
three bugs i'm talking about right here
we're all
required the bypass to work
the info leak got a separate cve and
then these three different privilege
elevation ones all got grouped under the
same one
and so the last one was this other
function that i mentioned the set qos
and this one was a little bit different
so this one is in
the the
sdk
so what you're supposed to pass in is
the structure on the right
which is a quality of service structure
it's got a couple of
flow specification fields and then a wsa
buffer structure which contains a
pointer to some other data
so all this special set qos handler did
was say well i'm going to take those two
user mode buffers allocate one in kernel
and stick them in it together
um
right
but so coming in from the uh the
the bypass route um
that didn't happen so we had full kind
of
control over the input buffer and they
never copied the the second buffer in so
this one got a little bit complicated
because it ended up reading out of the
input data in multiple places
in the uh
in the call stack
so it was a bit spread out so i
tried as best i could to get into one
slide
but the buffer length going into this
update flow function here so that was
read out from the user controlled packet
in fact
from user mode memory
earlier in the call stack and then in
this update flow function
it allocates enough memory for it
because it's going to make again another
copy
but then if you look at the the mem copy
down here again
the last line
it reads the length field out of the
user mode buffer again
so it's the same race condition as the
alpc bug if we swap the lengths between
these two um
between the two times then we get a
buffer overflow so this one is just a
regular non-page pool overflow
so just a quick uh summary so at this
point um we'd have this validation
bypass an info leak
two arbitrary increments in the kernel
and a non-page pool overflow
and so i was
very confident that at least some of
these could be exploited into a kind of
reliable code execution um
but i also was starting to get a
bit suspicious about just in general the
quality of this code and so i thought
well why don't i keep spend a little bit
more time auditing
the other option handlers so
in this case i said started looking
through ones that didn't require the
ioctal
validation bypass
uh it turned out there were some more
more bugs so the first one uh
there's this
set multicast filter option
so this is for setting if you're using a
multicast address and you want to filter
either in or out some addresses
you can set filters on the socket
and it takes in a list of addresses so
in this case this particular one is ipv4
only so you have a bunch of four byte
addresses
in a list
of arbitrary size well there's a limit
on the size
and this gets processed down in this
function in
gcp.sys
so here's the the code for this
this was actually in this set session
info function was handled a lot of the
options i was kind of a
big one to reverse but once you get the
case statements broken out it became
not too bad
and you can see there's checks on the
length there are some validation checks
um and then similar pattern to what i've
talked about already um
excuse me
they then read the length again out of
the packet
so
same thing if you alternate this value
between a high high and low value uh if
you happen to
get through the checks with a low value
but hit the the next function with a
high value um
then it triggers a denial of service in
this case it's just an out of bounds
read um it passes in the array and the
size uh
and it just it's just making a copy of
the array and it'll read past the end
so
one interesting thing is i just closed
this one to microsoft
and their response was they don't
consider local denial of services to be
meet their bar for service
so they did end up patching this bug but
i think it's the the way they patched it
was uh
the um the memory buffers they were
passing down here were still pointing to
user controlled uh
memory so they just made a copy of the
any of the user options coming in so
what gets passed down is something that
user mode can no longer
no longer swap um but kind of because of
that during the the rest of the research
i ended up finding a couple more denial
of services but i didn't bother to write
them up um so they're still floating
around out there
so i could play games on
my co-workers boxes um
yeah this uh
so
yeah denial of service not super
interesting um but fortunately like
literally right underneath it in my
decompiler output was this case
statement um and so the previous one was
setting a multicast filter with ipv4
only addresses uh but when they came
around with windows vista they included
support for ipv6
i think that's mostly when it came in uh
and so they added in this ioctal to set
a same multicast filter but with ipv4 or
ipv6 addresses and it has the exact same
bug fortunately
and in this case you can see it's
actually allocating memory to make a
copy of the pool so there's a an
allocate using the length readout at the
beginning um and then it runs through a
for loop and copies all the addresses
into that memory so
the
exact same problem
set it low for the the validation checks
and then flip it high when you get into
the copy loop and you cause a buffer um
overflow so the only um
tricky part with this one is that the
memory is read out again every time
through this for loop so if you're just
flipping the the length value back
between high and low you might get to a
case where you get through the
size validation on the um
on the input but then you break out of
the copy loop before you've completed
overflowing everything you want to which
could cause kind of yeah instability if
you only do partial partial corruption
so the the solution to that was just
instead of
flipping back and forth was to uh you
know in the loop counter that was
writing this value was to write it low
once and then write the high value for
you know 100 times or something uh and
then just repeat that so it was
low for only a short window because it
only has to get through it's only read
once to get through the validation
and then set it high for a lot longer so
you're likely to get through the the
copy loop and it just tweaked the value
so that there was a good balance between
it not taking too long to win the race
um and
not exiting that copy
too soon
um
so just to add on then to the summary so
now we have the original ones i
mentioned plus denial of service
and one more uh non-page pool overflow
so we can move on to
talking about how to exploit them
um this this one's funny because they're
pools that are overflowing
um
right so
uh i hadn't actually looked at windows
exploitation for quite a while before
doing this uh research so
i looked around for kind of what
research is out there to get up to speed
with kind of what the latest tricks are
and there is some really good
research and papers out there one in
particular that i
used a lot was the um scooping the
windows pool paper
i have a reference at the end
and so
yeah looking for
how to turn these uh page spool and
non-page pool overflows into kind of
working exploits
name pipes turn out to be super useful
for this there's two features to name
pipes that make exploitation uh and
grooming a lot easier
so there's name piped attributes uh and
then data entries in the uh
name pipe to write cues um so you can
see the
ins so the reason why these uh
these are both good things is that um
they have variable length allocation so
there you can see the uh
headers on the of the structures on the
side here so they both have a kind of a
small header and then they're followed
by inline data immediately afterwards
and there's really not much limit on
this length you can put in so we have a
big you know variable size allocations
we can choose which size we're going to
allocate
besides the headers we have full control
over the data
and in both cases we can free them kind
of
on demand when we want to
the other useful thing about both of
these is once you set
set one of them on the pipe you can read
it back out without triggering or
triggering a free so attributes are easy
you just set an attribute on the pipe
and then you can go read what the
attribute is you don't cause it to be
freed
and data queue entries what they
actually are is when you write data to a
pipe
they get kind of an entry gets created
to cue it until someone reads it off so
if you go to read it it gets removed and
freed
but pipes also give you the option to
peek into what's on the queue so you can
just say i want to peek into the data on
the queue it'll let you read these data
queue entries and not actually
pop them off
um
and so the other thing when we're
looking at kind of exploiting any kind
of
memory corruption or on the heap
is you need to know kind of details
about what the heap is that you're going
to be exploiting um so the only thing i
looked at was kind of newer windows and
they all use the the segment heap
um
which again has got some good write-ups
there's a good one from
target quite a few years back on a kind
of modern pool kernel pool exploitation
that talks a lot about the uh
the different types of heaps um
and specifically i was looking at the
variable size back end for the the
segment heap which lets you mix
allocations of a bunch of different
sizes
and it turns out that it turned out to
be really
relatively easy to protect the predict
and control the heap layout using that
so i'll talk a little bit about kind of
what the grooming strategy was going to
be and how to turn this
into an exploit
um so the variable size back end
i'm kind of running along eh um
so this is used for allocations that are
bigger than 512 bytes
and not page line
um and it's made up of a whole bunch of
sub segments which kind of get created
when new allocations come in and these
sub segments will hold a bunch of
individual allocations and as bigger
allocations come out of them uh you got
to get these free chunks created
uh and there's a bunch of details with
why there's you know they try and keep
the big chunks page lined uh
and
and that's why you end up with these
multiple sections of small free chunks
um
so for the grooming um
which
if we just uh and i know i'm showing a
picture of just one but really what
we're aiming to do is create a whole
bunch of identical
sub segments in memory
so we start off here by doing one big
allocation uh
in this example we're talking about the
the right data cues so we have a data
queue header on this we do one big
almost 64k allocation
which creates if we do enough of them
we'll create new sub segments um and so
now we have
a couple of free chunks um and what we
want to be able to do is reliably get
our overflow chunk uh in front of that
one so we need to make sure any holes at
the end have been filled up
so now we have this slightly smaller
chunk at the end so we need to do
another big allocation or a round of big
allocations to use up that free chunk
and so now we have kind of two big
allocations um
and then a couple of free chunks at the
end
all right good came back um and this one
uh slightly larger free chunk at the
beginning so now if we filled in
everything correctly we should be able
to
if we cause our overflow allocation to
be around that fc0 byte size we should
be able to land it every time right in
front
um
and it turns out that's uh
entirely possible we just need a little
bit smaller size to make room for the
the chunk headers so at this point we
can reliably overflow
our data cue header
um so skipping along just briefly look
at kind of some of the name pipe
internals and so how we turn that into
uh
you know
interesting primitives that we can use
to exploit the box so the name piped
when you create a name pipe you
initially you get a name piped file
object
and that also the excret the other thing
that gets created at the same time is
the ccb
object
ccb was referenced a bunch i think it
stands for control context block that
was my best guess um
and internally that contains a bunch of
pointers to
lists of attributes and kind of lists of
anything on the pending right queue or
pending read queue
so to get an arbitrary kernel read out
of this
this technique will work for either the
the attributes or the write queue entry
case
they both have kind of the same format
of a list entry at the beginning and
then a length field so even with just a
single byte
of corruption we can just
corrupt the bottom byte of the flink
header
so that instead of
the flink pointing to the start of the
next data queue entry we can get it to
point down into the controlled data
section
so if we corrupt it just right then the
flink actually points into the portion
of the data that we control and we can
have arbitrary values
for the next header in the chain so that
applies to either
the data key or attributes
so the issue with the two overflows i
had in this case is they you couldn't
overwrite just a single byte you had to
overwrite more than that so at least
four bytes at which point you've kind of
clobbered the pointer
and that doesn't work however
you can just overwrite the entire thing
and because of the way windows does kind
of the i o you can just point the flink
pointer right into user mode
and uh create a fake structure there
it also we can modify the length of the
one we've corrupted in kernel mode so
that if we peek into the pipe we can
read past the end of that uh i have too
many zeros in the diagram but you can
read past the end of the
of the data queue entry and get the
headers off the next thing in the heap
so which gives us kind of an aslr bot
aslr bypass because it lets us know
where the chunk is in memory
and then the once we have the fully
controlled one in user mode we can just
change the values uh to get a arbitrary
read of arbitrary length and just change
it as we need to
yeah
to do as much reading as we want so the
next uh
thing i wanted to cover was how to get
an arbitrary write so all the other
stuff i'd seen documented about how to
use name pipes for kind of exploitation
primitives all follow the same path
up to here and at this point they
usually
tried to leverage some
corrupt some pool headers to get an
arbitrary increment and then leverage
that into elevating your token
privileges
so i was thinking was there some other
way to do do this so we can get um
an arbitrary right
so i did find one other primitive
in here with this security context field
in the data queue entry
um it turns out that's uh
yeah it's a pointer to the security
context for the socket
uh or sorry for the pipe forget what i'm
talking about um
and if it gets changed when the pipe's
being read
the code will go and free the existing
value and replace it with this new one
so by setting it twice we set it to some
pointer it gets copied into the the ccb
and then we set it to null in the next
iteration it'll go and free the original
value that we stuck in there so we can
free
arbitrary memory with this kind of
primitive
and so for an arbitrary write we're
using the right queue
to get the reads in kernel
and so a typical pattern used on other
operating systems as well for exploiting
um in fact pipes are used uh
i've seen them used on android as well
if you
if you were able to control the read
queue
that gives you the equivalent of an
arbitrary write because a read cube
here's a pending read for the socket
here's the length i want to read and
here's the address to read it to and if
we can
control what that address is then we can
get essentially a right to any address
and kernel
so with the arbitrary free
we're actually able to so we could have
tried to corrupt one of those entries
but they're small and a fixed size which
makes it problematic so
instead we
free the file
pipe file object and with the read we
can go and read all these objects so we
know what the contents are so
we free the pipe object and replace it
with one that's almost identical except
the pointer to the ccb
points to a fake copy of the ccb and our
fit copy of the ccb is all identical
except for the read queue we stick
values in it um and we point them
to values we control so now
when you write to the pipe you can write
to kind of any value in kernel memory
uh yeah so that's that's uh
that was it for how to exploit these
bugs um kind of the next things i had to
do was figure out how to kind of do some
cleanup and repair clobbered heat
headers
with the overflow have to repair all the
linked lists
and then actually do something
interesting with the kernel rewrite
once you have read write on the kernel
it's pretty much you know game over you
can do what you uh and do what you want
so whether it's elevating or turn off
security features anything like that
so i was going to do a demo
but not only am i short on time but i
also
broke my vm over lunch so
i couldn't actually run it anyway but
fortunately i took a screenshot of what
the demo looked like so pretend this was
running and then a system shell pops
up a very very stress-free demo um
so i'm going to skip through a couple
slides here just super quick um because
i want to get to the
the last bug
so this was just how to exploit a
arbitrary kernel increment so that we
have this info leak in kernel but what
it leaks us is a fixed address in the
page pool
and we need to know what to what to
increment um
solution to this was just
allocate a whole bunch of memory and
then
increment some value in how
up where we've grown the pool so we can
you know kind of guess roughly how big
the pool is and if we allocate a bunch
of big buffers um
with large pipe attributes we can just
sort of increment somewhere in there
and there's a good chance we can land in
one of these newly created buffers so we
just go and read all the attributes
until we find out
where it is
and then to turn that into an exploit
this is just like the example i said at
the beginning where if you can corrupt
one of these flink headers you can point
it down into the data section so we use
the increment to add do a misaligned
increment we can add 100 bytes
hex bytes onto the value of the flink it
points down into the actual attribute
data that we fully control and we have
an arbitrary read
yada yada yada
and with this we can once we have the
arbitrary read we can actually leverage
the arbitrary write in exactly the same
way because we can go there's no free
primitive through the attributes but we
can go back and read out where the data
queue entries are
and
increment one of those and then we're
back in the
using this method and we're back in the
exact same scenario as the um
previous bugs
uh
yes really quick aside uh when i was
looking at this with um disclosing this
to microsoft there were some discussions
back and forth about whether this worked
from the sandboxes that were within
their bug bounty program
that just kind of increased the severity
so it turns out this particular one
works from the
windows defender application guard rbc
broker sandbox and while i was kind of
proving that it did i also noticed that
that sandbox had access to the um http
server api
and i was getting a little bit tired of
doing write-ups so i thought oh i'll
take a look and see why the
what's this what this is doing uh there
and i really don't know why the rpc
sandbox can access uh
the server api but it's in there
so
uh windows provides uh an http.sys
driver that's there on all versions to
do
to kind of provide a web server service
so normally you'd have iis and this
diagram is a picture of how iis uses
http.sys but it also lets you have
arbitrary applications that just do
their own web hosting
by directly accessing the api
um
and this is all well documented on msdn
sorry i'm skipping through this a bit
quick but almost
and uh
yeah there's kind of three main things
you uh you would do with the api to get
set up uh you create a session and a
session is really just a container for a
bunch of properties that are common
across uh your application um and then
you can register different urls um
grouping them again by kind of common
properties
each of these
url groups
gets associated with a request queue
that gets created so you can have
multiple applications reading requests
out of the queues as they come in a good
way for load balancing and kind of
performance reasons
um
so looking at the user mode api uh for
this and i mentioned already these were
some groupings for common properties so
you have this ability to set um
properties on your session
um and one of the interesting properties
here was this uh it's channel binding
tokens which is a security extension to
ssl
yeah and there's a structure there you
can see there's an array of of uh
service names which are the names of the
binding tokens and then a structure that
kind of defines the binding tokens
and so in this one when you're actually
querying them
this is the function to read them out of
the kernel
um
and it turns out there's another kind of
the same time of check time of use bug
um
this uh
the memory that's being used is the
uh
with a direct i o where there's a
pages in memory with a kernel mode
address that maps to the same backing
page
um and you can see down near the bottom
it's uh the length gets written up to
the user mode memory and then right away
afterwards
it's incrementing to the next property
that's going to read out and it uses the
the size that was written
written into user mode memory reads it
back out and increments the loop so if
user mode messes with the size
we get another kind of right past the
end of the buffer
um
yeah sadly however
uh
okay here's the code for it this this
code is i didn't actually try compiling
it but this is actually all the code to
trigger the trigger the bug so on the
left
essentially we just create two session
properties at the bottom
we query them continuously in a loop and
on the right
is a thread that's created that just
keeps overwriting the file size and so
eventually the race will win
and we'll
write way past the end of the buffer and
cause a crash um
unfortunately it turns out this is
exactly the same as the alpc it's in the
system pte range so i didn't have a way
of turning this into an exploit
um
all right so pretty much
done this is the the timeline uh for
when i did this work so
windows vista came out in 2007.
um
i started looking at this stuff in april
found the alpc bug about a week later
found the socket bugs
um and then a week later we submitted
kind of sample exploits and the proof of
concept to microsoft
everything ended up getting patched by
the fall
so maybe four or five months for some of
them which isn't which isn't too bad um
yeah that's it uh have some
acknowledgments so these are papers uh
and presentations i i referenced
um doing the write up uh there's a link
to the paper that i put out
back in november maybe um if anybody
wants more details
and then if there's time i think we're
going into break but if anybody wants to
stay past the break uh feel free to ask
questions or that's me on twitter xnomad
so
you can find me there
you