uh so yes today uh martin and i are
going to be presenting some work we have
been doing
last year
uh investigating the t of the samsung
galaxy s21 of the exynos model and
especially a component of this tea which
is called the loadable firmer
so
why are we here
well
there's a couple of reasons why we're
here
and some more
and a couple more
and a few more
and
some more that are still uh in the
disclosure process
and we're going to talk about a couple
of these things
um so
this is overview of what we're going to
talking we're going to talk about
we'll first have an introduction about
teas and trust zone then we will be
talking about the samsung's te
architecture which is based on their own
tos which is called tigris
then we will be looking at loadable
firmwares which is
most of the analysis will present
how we extracted them how we decrypted
them and then how we found
vulnerabilities inside these firmwares
and how we exploited them
so let's start with the introduction
about about trusted execution
environments this is like a trust zone
centric view of
tes
where basically the
environment is split between two worlds
normal world which is the re rich
execution environment and the secure
world which is a te
and in the normal world you have the
usual applications and android
environment running while in a secure
world you'll have a tos which is runs a
kernel
several trusted applications
which ultimately will protect keys
such as payment keys file system
encryption keys but also biometric data
belonging to the user of the phone
let's look at trustsome a bit more in
detail we have this place between normal
world and secure world that i just
showed
and then you see in the columns of
different privilege levels defined by
the arm architecture so we have el0 in
both normal world and secure world which
is the application level so it's the
least privileged level
then we have el1
which is where the kernel run both the
linux kernel and the tigris kernel in
the secure world we have the hypervisor
in the normal world and finally at el3
which is the most privileged level we
have bl-31 which is also called monitor
code
and this is some dedicated code that
always runs in secure mode and handles
the switching between the two worlds
we see that
the secure world is isolated part of the
system so
it has this ns bit scr fcr and s bit set
to zero and has been known secure which
means if a
secure work performs operations over
secure memory or secure peripherals so
they will be allowed and if instead
these operations come from a normal
world which have the ns bit set to one
this will be blocked
so if we look at how applications will
uh
interact with the te you'll see that
first thing the app needs to do is to
send a request to the kernel that's
because
android apps cannot directly interact
with the
that's
so this communication is done through
some device that the linux kernel will
expose and then the linux kernel will
execute this special instruction which
is called smc secure monitor call
and uh
yeah this
smc will come up multiple times in the
course of this presentation this is a
instruction that will generate an
exception at the bl-31 so the l3 level
mbl31 will then
determine the id that was specified by
the app for this smc call and it will
decide what to do you can either process
it internally or it can forward it to a
trusted application through the tgis
kernel and the trust application will
then process this and
use functionality implemented in the
theories kernel and then start to do the
inverse
path and send the answer back to the
application
so tigris is a tos that has been
developed by samsung it's
been deployed on the s10 for the first
time it's stored encrypted in high-end
models
it's a relatively small kernel but it's
not a full micro kernel so it still
contains a couple of drivers
it conveniently implements projects like
cisco so whenever you want to interact
with the driver you need to open a
device and then you can do the usual i o
ctl read write map etc to interact with
them
and this is some examples of drivers
that are implemented
in the os
now if we go back to the previous
picture there's actually something i
didn't show before which runs next to
the tigris kernel and these are the
loadable firmwares which is what we are
going to look at today
um so
the idea of a split between kernel and
global firmware is that the kernel tries
to be somehow a hardware agnostic and
the loadable firmware implements all the
low level
like register peripheral operations that
are hardware specific
and
so how are these
components loaded
so this is a boot chain of s21 it's a
fairly typical blue chain
so we'll have first the boot rom
that will start the chain of trust it
will then load bl1 in secure mode
bl 1 will run from sram and load the
next stages so epbl which and as you can
see from
this box basically all the next stages
that run in secure world are stored
encrypted both in flash and in firmware
updates so basically this is a bit of a
black box for an attacker and from this
point on you you will have
both secure and non-secure worlds
running in parallel the non-secure one
will have first bl2 and then little
kernel which will then bootstrap the
linux kernel and on the secure side you
instead have epbl which loads bl31 so
bl31 is this monitor code that is always
running at runtime
bl31
will then get images for a lot of
firmware nte from the little kernel it
will authenticate decrypt them
and load them into memory
so uh if we look at the loadable
firmware they are stored in a specific
partition for loadable firmwares ldfw
uh it's actually a single image
that contains many concatenated smaller
images for each loadable firmware so
there are multiple loadable firmwares
each of them start with this magic
loadable
and uh
basically the bl-31 will iterate through
all of them until it finds an image that
is called tail firmer when that is found
it means it's the end
and
yes they are loaded at the base address
100 000 in x
and as i mentioned before they all run
in secure e1 so they are very privileged
as privileged as the kernel and they are
an interesting target for an attacker
so uh as i mentioned there are multiple
firmwares um
we're going to list them uh here uh
from the biggest to the smallest this is
the crypto manager it has a lot of code
because it has to implement all the
cryptographic functionality that is done
by the hardware it does stuff such as
encryption decryption using the hardware
key random number generation
otp fuses and so on
then we have a drm loadable firmware
which is used for trusted ui for
payments so when you enter your pin
a secure camera
for a face unlock and secure video path
for drm
we have the flash memory protector which
is done for a transparent flash used for
transparent flash encryption
hdcp which is the like the cryptographic
component of hdmi
and rpmb which is some form of secure
storage that is implemented on the
flash
so
if we now extract
one of these loadable firmwares from a
firmware update
we can take a look at what's in there
we see the magic as we mentioned earlier
this is the size all of the values are
in a little endian so the size would be
21 10 0 0.
then there's smc base and this is
interesting so basically um each
loadable firmware has a smc range
assigned so every smc as an id
in this case the smc base for this
loadable firmware is 82.001000
and then the last byte is ignored so
the basically there will be a better
match on the first three bytes if they
if the caller specifies those three
bytes
as
smc value they will be forwarded to this
loadable firmware
then next one is just a version number
it's actually a date so in this case it
was the 29th of december 2020
and then uh there is a name so this is
the cryptomanager it's the largest
loadable firmware we mentioned earlier
and finally at the end there is this
huge block of encrypted code and data of
course the real device is much larger
and it's just yeah basically encrypted
you can't do much with it at the moment
so let's take a look at the how
loadable firmness look like when they
are loaded in memory
so
they have a very simple memory view
uh
basically this is the lowest 32 bits of
uh the memory ranges and then at address
hundred thousand there will be the image
of the loadable firmware as stored in
flash but of course decrypted and then
stored into memory
and then at this address there will be
all the registers that are supported by
the soc
and then at the address 80 and then all
zeros that's where the drm starts so
this will be the two gigabytes of dram
mapped of this address
which includes the dram configured as
secure so this is a
drm which is reserved only to the te
and it contains
also another copy sort of alias of the
loadable firmware as view in the
physical memory
so um
now if we go even more into detail
we see there is this
on the left there is a header of the
loadable firmware
and at address at offset c there is a
pointer to the function that is used to
handle smcs so it will point here
so whenever bl31 will receive an smc
that matches the id which is stored here
of this loadable firmware
bl-31 will read the address at offset c
and then it will then call this function
to process
the
smc
and
inside uh
these loadable firmwares will have smc
handlers which is normally just a big
switch
which takes five arguments the first
four of them are simply
the four registers from x0 to x3 that
were passed by the caller were invoked
the smc
the first one is always the smc id
and the remaining three are specific and
their meaning depends on the smc
and then you'll have all the handlers in
this case the hender for smc 3806
then there is the fifth argument which
we called is nsec and this specifies
whether the caller was running secure or
non-secure mode
so
what this means is that all these
loadable firmwares have a way to
identify who called the global firmware
smc and they can decide whether a
certain smc is only allowed to be called
by the te
like it is in this case
or
if it is allowed to everybody so even
the re would be allowed to invoke
certain smc's
for now let's take a closer look at the
secure only smc's
so the idea of secure only smc's is that
they will be called by the tigers kernel
and the tigger's kernel runs the dl1 so
it's the same privilege level of
loadable firmwares
however
tigris implements
some more functionality
and this is a
overview of the ta permissions
and we can see one of the permissions
that the a can have is the permission to
issue smcs
so
of course um
smc is
just by architectural the definitions
a privileged instruction so tas cannot
directly use smc instructions
but
the kernel has an interface exposed to
smc that's what we were seeing at the
very beginning like some drivers
that are accessible using the posix
ciscos
and tas that have these permissions and
there are a couple of them can call this
um
this driver and then
pass smcs to the loadable firmwares or
to bl-31 and this is actually the
compiled view of this smc handler
as exposed by tigris to tas so assuming
a ta has the correct right
for
talking to the
to issue smc's the first thing the
kernel does is validate and parse the
smc arguments
this is not very interesting because the
ta can always specify a combination of
arguments that says do not validate and
do not check any of them just pass them
directly to the smc handler and if that
function succeeds then the kernel will
forward the arguments and issue the smc
so
we started thinking um
let's assume we exploited the ta we have
runtime control over ta
what can we do with this smc
interface exposed by the kernel and uh
getting runtime controller ta is not the
something we will be talking about today
tas are just applications they have a
usual set of mitigations and
i mean vulnerabilities happen they can
be exploited
so if we have such a vulnerability what
can we do with it and
two years ago martin and i also looked
at the s10
and back then we identified the
vulnerability that gave us full control
of the te which means thanks to this
vulnerability
we were able to extract the loadable
firmwares uh from memory as they were
running on the s10
and our idea was can we identify some
functionality that has not been changed
in the stand uh compress in the s21
compared to s10 and try to exploit this
on the s21
so this is what we identified this is an
smc implemented in the crypto manager
and this is only reserved to the secure
callers
and the first thing it does it takes an
argument passed by the caller
this is a structure of c0 bytes and it
checks that this structure needs to be
fully within the tv memory
and with team memory i mean anywhere in
tv memory can be ta memory uh crypto
memo crypto a local firmware memory
kernel serious kernel memory anywhere
once that is verified
it will then
extract two
physical memory buffers as specified
within the structure so basically the
structure will have a physical memory
start address and a length
of the first buffer and of the second
buffer
and again it will check that these two
buffers are fully within the te memory
after all these checks are done
it will call some hardware functionality
that will do an encrypted dma
from
first buffer encrypting data into the
second buffer
so is there a problem here well
it's good that the smc verifies that all
the buffers are in the secure world
but
there is no as i mentioned there is no
check that these two buffers are within
a ta memory or within te memory it's
just simply somewhere in there
and
it sort of expects that this these
parameters are set correctly by the
caller because it expects the kernel to
set these parameters correctly
but what if instead the ta specify
different value for these parameters and
passes them through the ta interface
and this is actually our plan so the
idea was use this smc interface to the
kernel
to issue an ioctl the kernel will simply
take our data forward it's to bl 31
which will see okay there's an smc
coming from the kernel
and it's the for the crypto manager so
it will simply again pass it to the
crypto manager the crypto manager sees
okay this is the smc used for um
encrypted memory to memory dma
and then it will configure the crypto
engine
uh set up
the mode which is encounter mode and
this is the actually the only thing that
is enforced
by
the crypto manager because all the rest
he
iv
source address destination address and
length will be controlled by the ta
the crypto engine is configured what we
can do from a ta is for instance point
the source address
from crypto manager memory and
destination address
in some memory belonging to the ta
itself
and because we know the key
we can simply encrypt memory
put it in the ta memory space from
within the ta decrypt it and then we
extracted memory belonging to the crypto
manager
and we're not limited to the crypto
manager we can extract bl31 memory we
can extract the kernel memory everything
just copy it within the ta and then read
it out
we have only a small problem left and it
is that the smc handler and the dma
engine expect physical addresses and the
ta has no idea about physical addresses
ta runs in its own virtual address space
and we need to find a couple of physical
addresses one is the physical address of
the structure that contains the
definition of the buffers
and the rest is the physical addresses
of the buffers themselves for doing the
dma
uh fortunately this is not too
complicated
because there are a few things that we
know
first thing we know is where the t
memory starts and ends this is just
something you can read out from android
and then we know that heap locations are
relatively predictable so we know ta can
allocate at max about 50 megabytes and
this whole space is 120 megabytes for
the te
we know that if we have a bigger
location uh contiguous
pages in the va space will be also
continuous in the physical address space
so that's nice you get a nice contiguous
view
and the start address of this allocation
and i mean the physical start address
is more or less constant so there are a
few pages that differ between different
executions and i think these
mostly depend on just the state of the
te memory at that time
so
what we thought was let's spray the heap
let's put thousands of copies of this
structure
and execute this smc from a rope payload
that runs in a compromised ta that has
the smc permission
so once we do a big allocation this is
what's going to happen we will allocate
something on the heap and these are the
start and end address plus minus a few
kilobytes of
located heap
structure on the heap
and then we'll start filling this
structure this
space on the heap with a lot of copies
of the structure
and all these copies in the structure
will set a destination address at
somewhere close to
bbd000 because we know the destination
address
that destination address belongs to the
ta and the source address to other
memory areas that are outside the ta
memory space
then we issue the smc
and then this whole
buffer that we allocated will be
overwritten with encrypted extracted ce
data that we can decrypt offline
and we try this approach it works and
the nice thing about this approach is
now i presented how we managed to read
out
protected memory from the te kernel
but we can also overwrite it and because
this happens through a dma engine you're
not restricted by the mmu settings that
normally would prevent you from
overwriting code and so on
with this you can simply tell the dma
engine write this on top of the code
section of the kernel and it will help
you replace the kernel
so
this was the first vulnerability we
found
which is nice but
can we find more
and
so at this point we were at a stage
where we had the loadable firmwares
fully extracted
we decrypted them we got their plaintext
value load them in ida
and the smc we currently exploited is
only accessible to secure memory which
means you would first need to exploit
the ta
which has the smc permission then run
your code from there and then run the
exploit which
i mean there are it's quite complex
and we thought
is there something that we can do
directly from the android side because
as we showed earlier there are some smcs
that are accessible to android um this
is not so simple though
because
it's not easy to issue arbitrary smcs
as i mentioned smc is a kernel-only
instruction
and in the running system in s21 there
is no driver that exposes this
functionality even if you are rooted
there is no driver that just takes your
smc id and passes it happily to the te
so for the purpose of this research we
decided okay let's just make a custom
kernel
where
we can flash on the device and we added
two drivers to it
one is an smc driver
which does exactly what i just mentioned
takes
smc id and some arguments and then just
passes them to the
to the te
and the second driver is a sort of
helper driver that we use to access
physical memory from the android side it
basically maps physical memory and then
allows
user mode application on android to read
and write the contents of this physical
memory
so
now that we have the setup ready we
started
looking for vulnerabilities
and
i would not like to ask more time to
come over to tell us a bit more about
this
so
what can we find because
these are encrypted binary site and it
sort of means that this also
means that not that many people are
looking at these type of binaries
so could that maybe reveal interesting
vulnerabilities
so let's start to have a look so we
start with looking at the rpmb loadable
firmware
and what it does is um one of the first
things you need to do is you need to
register some memory that you are going
to share between the secure and the
non-secure world and somewhere during
the boot process you will um
the linux kernel will issue an smc to
say like this is where i want to have
this shared memory
and
what this smc then will do it will check
like if this memory is fully in
non-secure memory because well you don't
want
the linux kernel to maybe provide a
pointer somewhere in your secure memory
so it will do arrange the act like hey
is this really non-secure memory and if
so it will register it and it will set
up the context for
the rpmb loadable firmware
so this works as expected
but then we started looking and we
noticed that there was some new code
added that was not there at the s10 yet
and this code was remarkably small
it was basically four lines when you
decompiled it and that's a bit odd
um especially it means that we are for
sure not checking where this call is
coming from so everybody can call it
secure or non-secure site that was even
weirder
are we really directly writing to some
pointers that are provided by the caller
without any pointer check
and the answer is yes
so
we have now a primitive and directly
reachable primitive from the non-secure
side that we can write a 64 or a 1024 to
any address we want so how can we use
that can we maybe cover up a length from
a buffer or from a range jack to maybe
create a buffer overflow can we maybe do
some
magic
with maybe the pay sales well we decided
to take a slightly different approach
we decided to actually let
the hardware and use it basically
against itself so how is it actually
working that we have a separation
between a non-secure and a secure world
how is the memory from the secure world
actually guaranteed not accessible by
the non-secure world well your cpu core
is running either in secure motor
non-secure mode and this is controlled
by the ns bit that is part of the sdi
register
and then the cpu wants to access some
memory it will put an
memory transaction on the bus
and this transaction will then get
routed to the memory controller and as
part of this
bus information we send the address but
we also reflect our execution state on
the bus
and then this will reach the memory
controller and the memory controller
will then access that address for us
except there is a reality one step uh
happening in between
that is uh going to check like is this
actually a secure on a non-secure memory
access and the hardware that is doing
this is called the t-set asc the
trustron address space controller
and your and the threshold address space
controller triggered to the hardware
registers something called secure ranges
these are
a group of start and end addresses with
permissions with what the hardware will
consider us
to as memory that has a special yeah
that has special permissions and this
could for example be it is accessible by
the non-secure world or it is accessible
by the secure world and not by the
non-secure world
and then what the tsa asc will do it
will
basically compare the memory transaction
against the secure
ranges that are configured it will check
the
execution state and it will decide
whether or not it will allow it in this
case we are doing a transaction to
something that is part of the secure
memory while they are running in the
non-secure state so in this case the
t-set asc will just say this is not
going to happen and it will generate an
interrupt
for a security violation
however if we are actually running in
the secure mode the t-set asc is going
to allow the memory transaction to
happen
but how is this actually
really working on from an hardware level
so how are
these secure ranges configured well
there are standard designs for that ase
and some vendors use these standard
designs they license from arm directly
however samsung has decided to create
their own controller that is
functionally the same but the register
interface is completely different
and what you see is that
when you start checking the registers
this is not documented so we had to
figure out where these registers are and
then start looking like what is the
meaning of all these bits but you then
at a certain moment see is that we have
two blocks of 30 bytes
in the register space that looks an
awful lot like hey this could be a start
and an end address and we see some other
bits which are probably permissions
so what do we have here well in this
case we have a start address from
b8a0000 to
e0 which is actually one page less than
what it is really protecting
and actually
this is even
a simplification in reality we don't
have one memory controller and one t-set
asc but we have four memory controllers
f40s at ascs because samsung decided
that it is sort of interleaving the
memory so every
256 bytes of memory is routed to a
different memory controller
so depending on the address you want to
access
it will go to a different controller and
a different tset asc and also each dsc
has its own set of hardware registers
that configures what the secure ranges
are
well let's start messing with these
registers what happens for example if we
set an end address before
a start address well
you would assume that this will
completely break the system right it's
for sure this is not a valid
configuration
well
you start trying this and maybe you see
some interesting behavior
so for our smc driver in the linux
kernel we have created a very small
command line utility that allows us to
interact with the driver and we can just
from a shell an adb shell
issue arbitrary smc's with arbitrary
arguments which is very convenient
from a research perspective
so
we provide smc id that we want to call
and we provide the
the hardware register address
of the end address of the secure range
for the te memory and we do this
once for every t-set asc because we have
four of them we do it four times and you
actually can see that the end address
the third byte is basically incrementing
that is the shift of where these
registers are mapped
and then our tool
will do simply an ioctl with the
arguments provided to our driver put it
in the right
registers and issue the smc instruction
because well from user mode we cannot
issue that instruction directly
and when you then check back like what
has happened well the last one was
writing 1024 to the end address
we still have the correct start address
for
our secure range except this time the
end address has been changed to 1024
and well we no longer have a valid uh
configuration anymore but what is now
going to happen when we access secure
memory
while we are running a non-secure mode
so with the ns bit set to one well from
the tz.asc perspective we have a secure
range with the secure range with an end
address before the start address and the
tjsc is just like okay i'm going to
allow this fine go ahead
and this is exactly
what we are going to do
so
i have here an s21 with the firmware
from may last year
that is the one that is still vulnerable
and first i'm going to show you
a part of
first i'm going to show you a part of
secure memory and
we have nothing done yet which basically
means we read back
zeros
at the moment our request is being
ignored and what we then can do
we issue our
we issue our four smcs so you can see
that
it is actually for for convenience
printing all the register states before
and after for debugging purposes
but we have now four times issued the
vulnerable smc and let's check the
secure memory again
well we have actually unprotected the
bl31
memory rail the entire secure memory but
this is the place where it stores its
version number
basically showing we have now from the
non-secure site completely unrestricted
access to the secure memory
so what else can we find well
let's take a look at the completely
different low level firmware let's
so we had a bit more looking at uh the
rpm b1 um well we decided that after a
while we wanted something else so we
started looking at the htc people and
the htc p1
is a bit interesting so
for some reason
it allows you to configure an internet
id which is somehow associated with how
they handle the
secure communication with the end device
but
the non-secure world is
assigning which interrupt is being used
for this or at least saying to this
loadable firmware this is the hardware
interrupt you have to use for this
so we have an
smc that allows us to specify this
interrupt but then we have another smc
that um
is going to configure this smc in the
hardware so what we will do is we will
change in the gic the
the generic interrupt controller that is
basically a configurable
yeah
mechanism for how you want to route your
interrupts and if you want to route them
to the normal world or the secure world
and
we are going to change this based on the
interrupt index we have specified
by the normal world
except we don't do any form of
validation on it and we directly access
the relevant hardware registers
so what allows us to do that well
because we are adding this internet
index and we calculate which hardware
register corresponds with a certain
index by
masking and shifting
the index we actually get a right
primitive in a part of the register
space well actually it's sort of the
entire register space except
a small part at the very beginning
what we can do with this is from four
bytes we can selectively set one bit to
a one we can decide which bit we want to
set but it's only one bit
um
so what can we do
the a bit of a challenge with this is is
that we don't really
have a very deep understanding how all
the hardware registers work right it's
not like that for
socs like this that the registered
documentation is freely available so
what you want to do would mean full
reverse engineering and of course things
like linux kernel drivers can be very
convenient for it but we want to have
something that has an impact from like
the secure side and basically meaning
things that the linux kernel can access
are probably not
interesting from this perspective
so what are we going to overwrite well
we decided to just go for the teas at
asc again it it is within
it's within range
but this time we actually set the high
bit of the start address of
the secure range
effectively setting the start address
after the end address
again unprotecting
the secure memory
so
how are these loadable firmwares
actually loaded
because well they are stored in a
separate partition we have seen during
the boot flow that um
they will get loaded by blt31
actually in collaboration with little
kernel
so how is this actually working and we
started working on trying to reverse
engineer this mechanism and try to get
an understanding how this encrypted blob
of data is loaded and authenticated
maybe something interesting is going on
there
well
what happens is little kernel is doing
the load from the ufs puts it somewhere
in non-secure memory provide the pointer
through an smc to the secure world
to the monitor bl31 because
that's the one running at that moment
and then that smc will trigger the
signature verification the unpacking
the decryption put at the right location
in the secure memory
configure
or triggering an initialization
mechanism
however this smc
is this
only accessible during boot or is there
maybe something interesting also during
runtime
well
this is the smc
and this smc in bl31
it does the pointer check yeah so you
provide non-secure memory it will copy
in that memory
from the non-secure side to the secure
side because well while it is unpacking
it
you don't want that the non-secure site
can mess with it and maybe cause some
issues like some doctor issues
and then it will do a signature
verification either directly in the
in bl31 itself or if you have already
loaded your loadable firmware before you
can actually load it again and then you
will verify
the signature using the crypto manager
and if something fails you will erase
the secure memory
so
this is of course in
separate buffer right
so
you you
maybe don't dynamically allocate it but
during development you have said okay
this is the buffer that i'm going to
load my loadable firmware because well
if you can load it again
that's probably not the best idea
well
is it actually a separate buffer
so what happens if we try to send the
smc
even with just a blob of null bytes
well
we have the phone let's try
so
the phone is still the secure memory is
unprotected
sure we can directly poken it it's not
relevant
so
let's
fill
some
random location in non-secure memory
with null by
phone is happily
let's then actually trigger
the
smc
well
the phone instantly became unresponsive
and we can actually see the smc
in the previous smcs you saw it
returning and printing
like the register state after returning
in this case we cannot even get to that
point anymore so
what has happened here
and you will hear a beep in a moment
because um well the crash is silent and
the hardware
watchdog needs to kick in in a moment
and we'll restart the phone
so what happened well this was for sure
not a separate buffer
we were directly stamping over the
memory where the loadable firmware is
currently running from
of course
this is like an encrypted blob of data
an assigned blob of data and we are
going to verify the signature and this
signature unless we of course reload the
original loadable firmware this
signature is not going to match we
cannot force signatures
and when we fail
the
signature verification we're also going
to zero out that part of the memory we
have already filled it with zeros now it
doesn't really matter but
you have seen what happens with the
phone so
either we because we directly fill it
with servers or you try to put there
some real code it will zero it out the
phone will crash within a fraction of a
second because those loadable firmware
are in use
so
how can we prevent this zeroing out of
the after the signature verification
fail can we somehow bypass the signature
verification
we can maybe race it so
the segment of verification
it's quite a
significant amount of
code and data that needs to be verified
it will need to hash it it will use the
crypto engine for it it's relatively
fast but we can probably race it
um or is there maybe an easier way
because
remember
we had two ways of verifying this
signature
so if you load the loadable firmware for
the first time
we were loading verifying it using bl31
but if we had the loadable firmware
already loaded we were verifying it
using the crypto manager
and the crypto manager is a loadable
firmware
so
if we overwrite the loadable firmware by
what are
what code is doing the verification
well
actually we have replaced that complete
underlying code by overwriting the blob
and trigger the authentication we
actually automatically also trigger
jumping to the data that we have written
there
so
basically the only thing we have to do
is
the authentication smc
make it return yeah this signature is
perfectly valid
and you can completely replace the
loadable firmware at runtime it will not
be erased and now it's our code running
uploadable firmware
um what else do we have well
every system needs
debug information
if there is something that develop
developers love its debug information
and well i love debug information as
well
so
if you check after you boot up and you
grab the dms of your f21 or basically
any exynos based
phone you will see messages of something
called the seclock and this is really
doing what its name implies it is
getting the messages from the secure
world and putting them in the non-secure
dms of your linux kernel
so we have for example seen
about the rpmb the initialization the
registers from world shared memory the
non-secure site provide
the address where we want to have the
shared memory well
the loadable firmware is nicely saying a
message i have registered your shared
memory and here you can find it
well how is this actually working
because
how is it possible that something from
the secure world can write to the kernel
lock on the non-secure side well
this mechanism the secure lock is
basically a set of ring buffers that are
shared between the secure and non-secure
site
and we have then a kernel driver
running
in the handle on the linux side that
basically takes the data from this ring
buffer and will then
k-print them to
the kernel lock
and that way this is how they show up in
dms
for i guess convenience we have per cpu
core
a separate ring buffer probably also to
not have to
too many issues with
concurrency locking and similar kinds of
problems which can get a bit hairy if
you have to do it across a security
boundary
so
we have here our smc handler we register
our message and we call well we have
called it printf we have no idea how
this function is originally called
what is
shared in our ring buffer is defined by
this structure and what we have is
basically a right counter a read counter
a base address and a two flex so one of
them is like the buffer is full so the
linux kernel was not fast enough in
picking up new messages and something
about that this system got blocked for
whatever reason
now of course we properly validated
information right because we share it
across the security boundary from the
normal world to the secure world both
the normal world and the secure world
are dealing with this information
changing the lead counter changing the
right counter this is perfectly
validated right
so let's take a look at how printf is
actually implemented
we start with based on on this score we
are running getting the address of our
ring buffer and in log info we are now
pointing directly into memory that is
non-secure
and what do we get from that well we get
the right counter because well we are
going to add messages to the ring buffer
and we have our base address
and then we calculate based on the right
counter and the base address where we
are going to write
and we write the message there
but what is missing
that is the check that we don't specify
an overly big right counter that is the
check
for the base address well it's not there
so
the ring buffers are
at c3000
one of for each score they get in
incremented addresses by roughly 10 000
hex
we use our driver to directly poke in
that
in that memory
and what we basically do
is
we set both the read counter and the
right counter to zero so
effectively the ring buffer is empty
and we change the base address
where the lock message is being written
to well
i don't know if you recognize this
address
but
this is the tz isc
one thing
we need to be quickly restore it
strictly speaking it's not needed you
can also unload the kernel module
but if you don't want to mess too much
with the system if you quickly restore
the original information you have a
pretty high chance that you are not
crashing the system at least as long as
you are not doing it too early after
boot because then the system is still
quite actively writing messages to the
sec lock
one thing
the ring buffers are core specific so we
need to pin our process
to a specific core or we need to change
all ring buffers
well the phone rebooted from the
previous
demo which is exactly why that was a
crash demo and not something else
because otherwise i would forget to
reboot it
well i forgot to show you
that we cannot access the secure memory
yet but you have to trust me on that
because what you can see is we have only
protected one t-set asc this time not
all four of them we can simply repeat
this four times and
unprotect all of them what we could also
do is we have access to a quarter of
the secure memory code and data so we
can also
simply change the code of a few smc's
that are exactly within this quarter of
the memory that we have unprotected
and that way
further compromise the system
well
that brings us to the end
um
the loadable firmware is really critical
in samsung's security model it is so
privileged and also
and it's this attack service is not only
on the secure side it's
actually both to the secure side and the
non-secure side of course you need
kernel level privileges
to reach this smc instruction because
well by default
there is no driver going to give you
that i'm not sure that for this audience
that's an overcomable obstacle
we found some critical vulnerabilities
we have a few more in the disclosure
process
and what is particularly interesting is
actually the simplicity of these bugs
the obstacle is that this is encrypted
not because this is some
super
crazy exploit that
you need to study for i don't know how
long it are relatively simple attacks
however the barrier for actually getting
to this is
high and that um you notice that
when you are looking at this type of
code
and for the people that have samsung
devices i would say update and also keep
your update
in the coming months
anyway
that's the presentation i hope you liked
it if you have questions please ask them
otherwise feel free to come to us we
will be around for well the rest of the
these two days