thank you everyone
sorry by advance for the people that was
looking for the ios
ios like talk i mean i will be your
replacement but i hope you will learn a
lot of stuff basically the really good
part is that my i think my talk will
just follow what basically mark told you
uh during the keynote like about the
step of being like a researcher and
testing stuff and so on because that's
basically what i've done on the last
past two years with this project was
basically i was
kind of a bit new about like the
blockchain node and especially at rom
and what was
supposedly like the evolution that will
happen
and um you will see that it's basically
a told focus on the fuzzing journey and
the different step i made to reach a
certain goal that was finding
vulnerability and so on i will not talk
too much about the vulnerabilities
themselves
because i mean
i suppose not a lot of you are on the
blockchain security
ecosystem so it will not make sense but
at least you you will be able to reuse
like i hope
a bunch of
like tips and tricks regarding dealing
with huge projects and especially with
projects
and
that are not really common and
dealing with
a bunch of characteristics that are
really special
so um just to tell you a bit more about
me i'm patrick i'm running the fuzzing
labs company where basically i'm doing
training about fuzzing and on a bunch of
stuff mainly lacrosse go web assembly
browser and so on and a lot of
blockchain stuff of course
i'm french you can hear that of course
and i'm also running the fuzzing labs
channel so where basically i'm doing
like fuzzing every week and there is one
video per week
so first of all i will need to tell you
a bit more about what is a term 2.0
and
also what is a term for the
ones that are not aware of course so
basically at army i consider it's like
one of the first blockchains that i was
i think it was even the first one to run
smart contracts so of course really
famous blockchain with the crypto
pump and and so on it's basically in
terms of
if if i need to synthesize uh is like
what is under the hood it just appeared
to be a network where basically you have
multiple nodes that will discuss to
each other the way they will discuss so
it's using p2p
stuff and um they will basically send
block and transaction and it's basically
they are sharing the database together
and yeah that that's basically pretty
much all so that's uh that's
mostly one
so that's the that's the idea so
the first thing we can say is of course
there is a lot of stuff to do with the
networking stack especially if you are
thinking that all those nodes will
basically communicate to each other so
the main
kind of attack we can have in such case
is basically another miner that will
attack you to maybe do the denial of
service or this kind of
vulnerability
so it will be basically using the enr
and all this other networking stack
and then we have the
beacon chain itself so the different
basic blocks that are sent to each other
and this one are basically serialized in
and encode into what we call ssd so it's
specific format and it's more easy to
just give them and share this kind of
stuff and basically this one this object
will contain
the block the transit the transition and
all this kind of
blockchain specific stuff
so in terms of bugs that are really
interesting we have all the stuff that
will crush or panic
because as i mentioned that means a
complete denial of service of the
node so that's really bad of course we
are looking for memory option and
if we can get rce that's even better but
you will see that because of the
language they actually choose
it's not something that we will see
really often to be honest
and one kind of bug that is
really specific to blockchain are
consensus bug so that's mean it's a
logic bug but since we are dealing with
blockchain um if we have a logic bug
that means you will get part of the
network that will do some one thing the
other part will do another thing and
that's what we call a fork so if we have
something like that it's really
again
one of the most critical vulnerability
you maybe heard of some of them recently
um
on other blockchain and that's the kind
of bug that
leads to the development of this further
that we're gonna
that i'm gonna discuss
so the target of today will be this one
so the first one is lighthouse developed
by sigma prime and in rust the other one
prism in go nimbus in niem so maybe some
of you don't know what is it and that's
perfectly normal
you have tekku
in java and you have
so i put this one as a client it's
a client and not really a client i mean
it's written in javascript and tab
scripts so you you can think that
it's gonna be maybe complicated to have
like some proper node and proper
software at the end that will just run
everything in in this language so the
main idea is lostar is also providing a
lot of library for
web application and so on related to
sram so that's still a really good
target for us
and especially because if you remember
they should all follow the same
specification so that's
already a really good point
so at this point the main difficulty as
you can see is we have
let's say five different software
written by five different team in five
different language and they should
basically follow the same specification
so what can go wrong
so let's talk about beacon first so
that's the further we uh i basically
wrote and i wrote it with sigma prime
another company that
specialized in blockchain security
and also one of the developer of one of
this
client
so basically to give you a bit of
history the project starts not with me
but with guido that is really well known
with the um i think it's crypto first
project
and basically he's doing a lot of
different shelf fuzzing and so on so
basically create a proof of concept um
using
a leap further written in simple spruce
and he was already starting to do the
job in 2019
so after that sigma prime gets the lead
on that and they get they receive a
grant by the hrm foundation to basically
continue the project and and find some
new bugs and after some time i discuss
with the sigma prime game and we find
out that it could be a good fit to to
work together so that's the the start of
the beacon first project
so as i mentioned i'm going to discuss
about like basically the complete
process that we have been through
so the first
thing we i take a look was basically the
existing code and it's in simplest press
and i really don't don't like simple
spreads so that was the
main issue for me at first
because i mean if i need to spend like
one years and and more on a project and
i don't like the language and i'm
really not happy to write any separate
place line of code
it's going to be complicated and even if
you take a look at all the other
projects there is none in separate place
there is in rust and especially sigma
prime
is wrecking everything in rest so i can
also leverage the fact that the people
where with who i'm working are actually
developing one of the clients in russ so
if i need any advice any help i can just
basically ask them
so the first road map that we come
was this one the first thing
it was needed for me to understand the
context of it i mean i was familiar with
atram but not with the current future
evolution of it
um
after that i was planning to do
what we call um
eth2 first so basically coverage guided
fuzzing
that will allow us to generate a fuzzing
corporate that will be reusable
across all the different clients
then we find out that it could be really
interesting to have like a really basic
differential further that means we will
just provide an input and compare the
result against all the other
implementation but
actually in that case without writing
any line of code because it was just
basically you leveraging on all the
testing tools available
by all the different clients so that was
really easy to implement and you're
going to see that and the final one the
most painful one
in in that case was the differential
further beacon first two
and basically this one is doing
structural fuzzing
and
especially it's doing differential
fuzzing against directly the
older client and the painful point on
that is basically that um it was needed
to create ffi bindings to basically
communicate directly with all those
clients in turn in all those different
languages so that was kind of easy
as as a project but the return on
investment to bns was
really really nice and we we're gonna
see that
so yeah i'm on shown some design choice
already so
rewriting everything in rest
better lean and so on and so on i will
not
give you
too much love but trust
and after that
why should we create multiple fuzzing
tools and the main reason is
we will not target the same piece of
code each time
and also
something that is really important to
keep in mind is
all those different teams are following
the same specification
over the time
the specification is changing they are
not always following the same one and
they
don't always follow the same
architecture and reproduce exactly what
the specification is all about
so
the main idea with creating multiple
phrasing tools is basically to be really
fast if there is any broken
changes and if
one client is only at the same
specification version numbers and
another one and so on having something
modulable that will still allow us to
find bugs even if
we got some stuff that are broken
after that the second question we can
ask is why not directly use the most
efficient technique as i mentioned i
mean the
big differential frozen that
i mean
typically you can just find every bugs
that we we're gonna find previously
and the main idea is always to find all
the longing fruit the faster because if
you have for example a bug that will
you succeed to trigger it and it's on
the ssd decoding part that's mean
whatever stuff you're gonna send that
actually trigger this bug
you will get a crash maybe
probably thousands of crashes and you
will just be stuck and you will not be
able to go deeper in the code base and
find the bugs that are basically after
so it's really important to to be fast
on that and
try to find all those longing foot the
the faster
so let's talk about the first one eth2
first so as i mentioned it will be
coverage guided fuzzing so right now the
question is oh are you doing coverage
guided fuzzing on all the language i
mentioned so i will just give you some
detail and also show you the result of
it
so that will be this specific part and
just keep in mind that everything we are
doing we are not just standing bugs we
are also generating a fuzzing corpora
and that's really interesting and really
important because this corpora will be
like a key point into the complete
fuzzing ecosystem that we are building
right now
so the first one um i actually first was
lighthouse directly because it was
written in rust and i was already really
familiar with fuzzing with rose code
and in term of
further available you have really a
bunch of them
typically these are just bindings on the
the surprise plus furthers that already
exist so on first cargo first and afl
so really easy to to use really easy to
maintain in terms of complexity for the
fuzzing harnesses itself
the first step was to basically using
those further generate ssd object so i
will just generate some ssd binary
and after that i took this ssd binary i
tried to convert that so do a decoding
into a proper object
then i try to load randomly one beacon
state because in that case we have um so
there is
when we are doing like processing of
this kind of stuff we have
an existing state and basically the
block we're going to process will update
this state to another one so it's always
like an association between state and
some object to process
so in that case i i've made something
really simple i just took the all the
unit testes given by the adram
foundation
and i extract all the beacon state and i
basically just pick randomly one each
time the further is restarting or after
some time
and finally the processing of the state
transition so you can see that the
i mean in terms of piece of code it's
really simple not really fancy
but
that's also the good part of having all
the clients following the same
specification they
got a bit to use like the the same
naming and the same um
function prototype so it's even simpler
to go through the like switching from
codebase to codebase
so the result of that was basically
three bug phones so the first one was a
memory allocation failure so it could be
weird since we are talking about trust
and
a lot of you might know that rust is
well known to be pretty good in memory
safety
but the fact is this one was basically
trying to allocate too much memory and
it was just like growing too fast and at
some point just shut down
the two other one was some panics so
panics in russ are really really common
there is multiple ways to trigger panics
and
if you are
developing a
like a cli
tool
you don't really care of panics but as a
reminder panics
mean denial of service
when we are talking about blockchain
software
so that's the idea so the good part of
this is that in terms of limitation i
was not really limited when developing
the stuff it was just like taking some
more time to just target another part of
the code and that was pretty much all so
that's nice to to not be limited
either by the fuzzer or other by the
client itself
in terms of improvement there is a lot
of them
basically the first one will be
structural fuzzing using what we call
the arbitrary trait and you're going to
see that that's basically what we're
going to use later
for another tool and yeah of course
adding more fuzzing harnesses mean
increasing the code coverage and
potentially finding more bugs
so that was lighthouse and
if you remember
the scheme
this stuff allow me to generate a
fuzzing coupler so once i have this
fuzzing copper that will basically be
assess the object
i can just do them fuzzing so
basically i'm just taking an existing
client so for this one it was prism and
i just use like one of the utility tools
they give me and i just provide
everything and hope for crashes
sadly i failed to that for this one
and i mean
it was not
so important to file at this point
because
i mean basically
it's pretty simple and that means
we we have still a lot
lots of stuff to to do so this one from
no bugs
okay whatever let's go and do coverage
guided fuzzing again but this time in go
so you have multiple gophers there again
so
personally i prefer to use go first but
with the specific leap further flag that
will basically just
create an archive and you can just
compile it with clang and that's okay
you are basically running lip feather
and not something else
so that's good in terms of complexity i
call it medium because the main issue
that i got was all the self regarding
like seagull and especially they are
using some bls implementation that is
like something in c that is used in
their project and so on and on top of
that there was using basel so i don't
know if you're familiar with basil
it's supposed to help people to
maintain and compile more easily their
stuff
i mean it's the case only if you know
basel otherwise it's a complete mess so
hopefully uh they um
at some point rewrite a bunch of the the
codes they they was using and they uh
called what they said the biggest
feature of the year that is basically
having prism that is go gettable so that
means really easily installable and
usable and so on so it helped me a lot
so that's basically under the snee path
of code if you
want to first in that case it was like a
blockader so as you can see it's taking
some bite and after that we are creating
some beacon block so i mean it was
extracted and loaded from somewhere else
we are doing the un-martial ssc so we
are doing the
decoding of the ssd object once we have
the object we are initially
doing some initialization sorry and
after that we are doing block process
block header and that's that's okay you
can see that we are using like process
blockade or no verify that's because
and that's again some really useful
feature if you are doing fuzzing
in that case i we ask the all the teams
to basically
provide us
like the equivalent of the real function
but without all the mathematical
verification and all the cryptographic
verification that can be in place so in
that case there is some dls
refrigeration and so on and the main
goal with that is
since i will do fuzzing i don't i mean
if there is any ashes comparison and so
on of course it will fail
every time and i will be stuck at this
point
into the fuzzing process so basically
i'm just telling them okay let's
consider that all the verifications that
you are doing in terms of cryptography
are okay and for the rest we can just
continue
so the result of that was three bucks so
that's uh that was nice um in that case
we got some slice bond outer front one
of the most common vulnerability in go
software and also some nil pointer de
reference also something really common
especially if you are not checking the
error that is returned by the function
so that was the the case uh right there
and yeah it was it was nice it was fine
it was generating some new um corpora
some new input that was completely
actually different
for some of them
than the the rest one and so on so we
can just move on on that
so after that
again i took the shot to
go to another one in that case nimbus
written in nim
so i will talk a bit more after about
nim and basically they are also
providing a bunch of testing tools so
dumb fuzzing again and this time i was a
bit more lucky
basically because
the implementation and the way they
developed the ssc coding was buggy at
this time so
i succeeded to find like five bugs
and typically there's the kind of
longing truck that you are looking at
because
those kind of bugs will have
the completely blocking my other
coverage guided further in the future so
that was really nice to just be able to
find them so as you can see we have some
segmentation fault um some assertion
error and index error
so let's discuss quickly about the
what is nim and why we are getting some
segmentation fault basically nim is a
programming language that look like
python that you have like some snippet
of code right there
and it's a compile language with some
strong type static typing
but the way it works is basically the
nim compiler will compile
your name code into c
and after that they are basically it's
the classical compilation of c program
so you
you start to see what could go wrong uh
with like name to c c to binary
and of course we can get some bugs like
segmentation fault and so on but the
good part of it is we can easily
integrate some and
add some existing further on top of that
and also the good part in that case
really good part is that actually the
nimbus team that is developing this
stuff
is actually like contain a lot of the
developer of the nin programming
language so i can it was possible just
for me to ask them if they can just
implement a new photo
and basically provide me some something
really easy to do and just continue my
work and and find some new bugs
so in terms of complexity in that case a
completely new language to learn and to
deal with
and
yeah as i mentioned the further
abstraction was not available so just
need to wait a bit and it was not like
pretty straightforward like the other
one
i will try to be quick on the other one
but you you get the you get the idea so
this one find two bugs um not a lot of
limitation because once i i got my lip
further running on meme code that was
pretty nice
and so on so
pretty pretty nice
tequi was in java
again some dumb fuzzing really simple
just using the docker getting some cli
clients testing the stuff five month
five
sorry so one that was really interesting
was the daniel of serbia the nail of
service infinite processing of
one
basically ssd block and after that a
bunch of exceptions that was not handled
directly by the by the program or by the
cli
in term of coverage guided fuzzing it
was a bit more messy
maybe some of you heard about jaser
that is
really famous right now but at the time
it was not available so basically the
only stuff available for me at this time
was gqf plus afl
so i don't know if you ever try it
but it's really really really slow i
mean
not really useful so that's why um
i only find one bug with that
it's not because there is no bugs it's
basically because it's taking so much
time to further that
i mean i was
just not finding anything else and and
getting i don't know a thousand
execution per per hour or something like
that even less so
as i'm as you might know fuzzing speed
is kind of important and especially when
you're dealing with this kind of stuff
in that case
so definitely some improvement possible
at this time
of the of the
of the project and it was basically find
another way to first java code
last one lot star i'm gonna be quick
there is gs first really useful really
simple to use that's the rns i mean it's
difficult to to be more simple than that
basically you are just launching the
stuff i have not done any dumb fuzzing
because just implementing coverage grade
diffusing in that case was already
way way much simpler
so in that case seven bang
oh sorry seven bugs
found mainly type error ranger
but either the ssd decoding or other
some networking stuff you can see some
enr
string right there and for example this
one are basically like the
the proof of concept to just reproduce
the bug so as you can see it was not
really complicated
so that was nice so basically all of
that of the all this coverage guided
fuzzing leads to this result so at the
end 26 bug funds so far 10 of them using
just dumb fuzzing just replaying
existing physical power and 16 of them
using coverage guided fuzzing i mean
generated by the coverage guided further
so the pros are pretty simple i mean
it's
it was really efficient in terms of
ratio like the
bugs compared to the time i spend on
that
for most most of them
and
the really good part is that coverage
guided fuzzing basically
produce reusable and interesting corpora
that you can just reuse over time and
it's not just specific for blockchain to
be honest i mean you should whatever the
library you are facing i'm pretty sure
there is multiple implementation of it
and i don't know you are using
let's say lip png so okay you are using
lip edging you will generate some png
picture but there is not only one parser
of png you have some other one written
in other language and so on so if you
are facing a project it can make sense
for you to just give it a try and just
provide your corpora
to other library and see if it's if it's
finding any bugs i mean the corporate is
the key in in that case
the good part also was basically what i
mentioned they all follow the same
specification so really easy to for me
to just switch from one code base to to
the other and in term of unique bugs and
so on as you can see it was mainly like
lotstar nimbus and tequi that was
containing bugs at this time and
you will see that but it was mainly on
ssd decoding
stuff so decoding is hard
so the cons
i mean
in that case i was mainly dependent of
the
different coverage guided further
available for me
so as i mentioned for teq it was a bit
hard because basically java and gqf afl
and so on so it was kind of messy
also the cryptographic bls nature stuff
could have been
an issue it had been at the beginning
but after that as i mentioned they
developed a new verify stuff like they
allow me to just
bypass this part of the stuff and it was
increasing the coverage a lot at this
point um difficult to detect logic bugs
of course because i'm i'm leveraging on
the fact that the coverage guided
further will basically tell me there is
a crash but i mean logic bugs
most of the time will not lead to a
crash
so that's the the issue and finally time
consuming because i need to write all
the fading harness myself and
test do the testing running and so on so
not also the most
appealing stuff
of the day
so let's right now take a look of
basically the other tool i create based
on that so i was working on this stuff
implementing my my stuff and so on and
so on and after some time i decided that
it could be really interesting to
basically as you saw the
dumb fuzzing was basically reusing the
the different toolings and command line
tools available so i just create like a
really basic
program in rust and you can even do that
in in bash that will basically take an
input provide that to the to the
different cli tool and just take a look
at the output if it's like crashing not
crashing if it's like passing properly
getting some error or not and just
comparing the output of all those tools
it was really easy to implement i mean i
just need to
basically compile all the stuff into
some dockers and after that extract all
the command line tool run them in
parallel and just compare the wizard
so that stuff was as i mentioned really
easy but i only found one bug with it so
the main question could be is it really
useful is it really worth it to spend
some time for that and the answer is yes
of course because what i've done is
basically having a way for me to
get for one input all the output of all
the clients so for debugging later you
will see that it was basically one of
the most useful tool for me because when
you are dealing with logic bugs
it's in that case really important to
know if
your
the main target you are focusing is it
the one that is buggy or and is it like
all the the other ones that are doing
the stuff right or is it the opposite
so that's the kind of tooling that in
that case makes the the more sense
the cons of course i mean it's not a
further that's basically just like a
replayer or a common basic command line
tool or script um so i mean except i
mean you need to provide some input and
the input are not coming from
i mean are coming from somewhere so at
some point you you need to have input as
well
so that leads me to the biggest part of
the project that was basically the
differential further um so we call it
beacon first v2 and the main idea was to
find logic bugs that's the only goals
for us with this
this piece of software we are not
expecting expecting to get crashes and
so on because
if you remember we already have eth2
first for that and i mean when i was
developing the stuff eth2 first was
still running on some server and
eth2diff was using only use for like
debugging and so on so if there is any
bugs hopefully i mean crushing bugs it
was already catch by eth2 first or it
will be in the future so
it's not really the most important
what was really important in that case
was to leverage the fact that we can use
structural fuzzing and
the really important part with that is
as i mentioned before that we was
basically generating ssd object
that was then decode and then process
the main idea with structural fuzzing
will be to simplify the stuff and only
generate valid structure
directly at the beginning so we don't
have the ssd decoding process anymore
and we are only valid creating some
valid structure i mean valid in the in
the format maybe not on the content
inside but at least we are generating
and
simplifying a lot the the process
so in term of complexity this one was i
would say medium hard
because it's depending which client you
need to deal with and which language
especially
because
we have the structural fuzzing so for
that i've used rust i will discuss
that right after and after that you have
the old ffi bindings and the main
question is what is happening if the
language is not really
like easy to use to create like share
libraries that can be used later with
ffi bindings and that's that was
basically what happened and of course a
lot of manual writing and compilation
process i mean compilation is the worst
in this kind of
project
so let's take a look uh at the
architecture of beacon first so that's
basically what i mentioned
my main goal in that case is to generate
uh
at sorry at the station uh so using
structural fuzzing so in that case i've
used um as a
main project
lighthouse because the further is
written in rust and lighthouse in rest
as well and we can leverage on what we
call the arbitrary trait that is a
really simple way to basically generate
some object using a rust so really
useful really efficient so once we get
this attestation i will basically do
some ssd encoding and
the main idea
is because when i will communicate with
this one
they are written in another language
than rest and that also means that maybe
the memory mapping inside will not be
the same so it's not possible for me to
just
create an attestation put that in some
chunk of memory and just tell to the
other guy okay access to this one and it
will be your structure and yeah don't
worry it's gonna be okay
it's not possible so what i've done is
basically
convert that into a ssd object that is
cross-compatible against all the
implementation and after that i provide
that to the different other clients they
have done the decoding so of course we
are wasting a bit of time but that's
okay and then at this point in time
everyone got the same object following
the same specification and containing
the exact same data on it so what i can
then do is
do all the
the processing
of those object and do the complete
state processing and after that at the
end i will just output the result and
the output result could be either the um
the new state of the blockchain or
either it will be just
like
they got an error
it's not possible it's like an invalid
state or invalid object and so on so i
can detect in that case logic bugs at
multiple levels i can detect at this
level if they are not able to decode an
object that is actually a valid object
i can detect at this point
that they are trying to do the
processing and they are failing to the
processing of this valid object against
something else or i mean very
succeed or fail in that case
and the last one is i can
check what is the output result and
verify that the output result is always
the same against all implementation
so we have a really good granular
granularity on that and
of course the main question is
is it possible to find bugs with that
and the result is yes so in that case we
succeeded to find six bugs
mainly in prison
and it was
[Music]
really like logic bugs it was incorrect
validation um no verification of some
index or subpart of the structure um
mainly like one client on that prism was
maybe validating the state or creating
an output state when all the other one
was basically rejecting the stuff and so
on and so on
so that was really interesting and
i mean in terms of results as i
mentioned all those bugs basically are
consensus bugs that mean
the kind of one of the most critical for
blockchain software
so good result
i mean the only downside could be maybe
the speed
because i mean there is a lot of essays
encoding making all the stuff working
together and of course the
most
issue is basically that it's taking a
long long time to write all the bindings
all the stuff and especially the
compilation you need to compile some
share library for all the projects and
just run them together and hope it will
work and if
one guy one team is basically using
updating too fast or not using the same
specification version it will always
fail because you will always get some
different result than the other one so
you also need to be sure they are all
following the same specification at the
same time
so let me conclude and give you like a
big overview of the complete project
that was basically all those tools
so at the end 33 bugs almost all
critical as i mentioned
so that's the like the
the total number as you can see most of
them was like prism nimbus tiku um
lotstar as you can see it's only seven
uh and i've not mentioned anything about
lovestar or regarding the differential
fuzzing and so on
the main reason of that is at the time i
was
lost the los satum was a bit late in
terms of developing and and following
the same
versioning of the specification than the
other so it was not useful to to add
them to the differential thing but it's
not the case anymore
also something we have done
we have done the community fuzzing so
basically
i put everything into a docker
and i basically we basically just ask
people to run the docker and try to find
bugs for us
and if they succeed they just report the
stuff to the github and after that we
communicate to all the teams and that's
okay
so
that was really efficient
and it was really nice to just make my
father run on everyone's laptop
it's only possible if you are dealing
with something that is not production
ready in that case it was under
development um if you are familiar with
the current evolution know there is
already like a kind of a main net for
that that is running
it will not be something that we will do
again right now if it was possible i
mean it's too impactful if there is any
bugs that are just
found and not reported directly by us
the main difficulty of this project was
basically keeping everything up to date
as i mentioned specification team
language
and so on
kind of eevee stuff
and i'm doing fuzzing so basically i'm
trying to find bugs on all the parts of
the code
and it was
painful for the compilation part
i will say
in term of impacts that's also really
interesting because at the end we found
like 23 crush and panics and as you can
see we found like seven logic bugs so
if at some point i was only focused on
doing coverage guided fuzzing um like
eth2 first
i will basically have missed a bunch of
bugs that are right there and
and most of them especially the logic
one are definitely critical in that case
so it's really interesting to see that
even if it's take the more time
it will lead you to increasing the
coverage and find
some stuff that will not have been found
except in production
and
that's the worst cases for us
lastly
i want to
give you a bit of take away and
statistic basically about that
for me
blockchain software are really
interesting
i mean you have a bunch of concepts that
are really interesting
and
you have as you saw the networking stack
the
everything regarding logic that
maybe in other kinds of software are not
as critical and so on so really
interesting definitely
you don't need to have complex further
to find bugs i mean if you remember i
found a bunch of bugs by doing like
replaying the fuzzing corporate so
dumb fuzzing definitely
and if we take a look at
where this bug was as you can see
ssc decoding that was the main
source of bugs and
again decoding is always hard
and in that case
all many all those bugs was basically
just one with them further so it was
already some good state after that some
networking stuff and some state
processing bug as well
differential e fuzzing is really an
extremely powerful to find logic box for
me it's the best way you can do it and i
really invite you to take a look at the
crypto first project of guido
and you will see that it's running on
oss first and it just found i think more
than 100
logic bugs in crypto implementation and
so on so
it's not a subject that is discussed a
lot uh and i think it's a bit bad we
start to see some differential fuzzing
also like in in browser especially with
like
jit compilation and jit output
but definitely i think it will be the
one of the next few things if you can
try to implement that and it could be
really
valuable
for the future of the project
by the time we remove all the gql afl
for offering java java code and we was
using jazer
it's already in production it's spanning
bugs so that's nice we continue to
improve the target and so on continue to
find some bugs i think we have like 10
or 12 more bugs right now on may on also
the different other phase of a term 2.0
basically
and um yeah we just update also all the
fuzzing analyses and we actually also uh
just
follow the specification so at some
point the specification right now it is
choosing a snappy that is another
encoding
format and
so we are again doing some fuzzing on
this other part of the code and finding
bugs
in that as well
the last
one is
the pi is basically
regarding phasing techniques
what was the most efficient
as you can see coverage guided is
a pretty good move but dumb fuzzing
actually perform really well so
don't just think okay
i'm new to fuzzing
i don't know how to compile and use
coverage guided further and so on
just give it a try and even some dumb
replayer
and i don't know i mean like using dev
slash dev
random can work sometime
not for that but it can
and
you can already have some good result
with that
thank you
[Applause]
you