very much and thank you for being up
this early in the morning the title of
my talk is play CTF because I believe
it's a really great way to learn more
about hacking and just improve your
skills and what you know about it yeah
so okay so my name is Fabian I'm still a
student at the Technical University of
Berlin still haven't finished my
master's degree and I also work as a
freelancer doing penetration testing
most of the time things like code audit
and I'm doing a lot of application
security web app security and it's kind
of important to keep in mind because
this is my bias on to the topic this is
where I'm from in the industry because
as you know there are a wide variety of
different kind of jobs and skill sets
required I also have a youtube channel
called Life overflow where I create
hacking tutorials and you know also CTF
write-ups and so this talk is kind of a
little bit related to what I do with the
YouTube channel it's not a big channel
but it's possible that you have maybe
come across one of these videos these
were kind of like my viral videos they
were linked in some of the new sites
that were reporting about the Nintendo
switch vulnerability and the dirty
calico root exploit just in case you've
seen those then you can connect the dots
so before we start I just quickly want
to recap what CTFs are because I assume
that most of you know what it is but I
just don't want to lose anybody already
so what is capture the Flex capture the
Flex are security competitions where you
can solve challenges hacking challenges
to you know get a good ranking and
here's an example challenge the
challenge crater would create a piece of
software and it makes it intentionally
insecure puts it back in there so that
it can be exploited in this case the
Creator are named this challenge follow
the rabbit it's a web challenge and
assigned to it 200 points based on the
difficulty the challenge crater also
places a secret file on the same
/ and then you as a player you have to
access this website and you try to find
this vulnerability this bug and when you
are able to exploit this vulnerability
and for example get a remote code
execution this allows you then to read
out this secret file and this file has
been a secret code inside that's what we
call the flag that's why it's captured a
flag and that serves as proof that you
hack the that you hack the server and
then you can hand this in to the
challenge platform and you are awarded
points accordingly ok so to the
structure of this talk because we only
have 30 minutes it will probably more
look like this that we talked mostly
about a bit blah blah blah a little bit
try make an argument why CTFs are great
for you and then in the end I hope we
can look at an example vulnerability
that you can find in CTF possibly maybe
more depending on how fast I'm talking
so let's take a step back and think
about how different jobs in our industry
are there are so many different kind of
jobs a hacker could go into so for
example there's classic Red Team pen
testing where you maybe target
corporations with thousands of employees
you send out fishing campaigns and you
go on site try to get access to their
networks and you scan services with
Metasploit and necess and whatnot you
kind of have also this opposite where
you're going to back bounties where you
target very single applications and you
test them thoroughly you could also do
code audits that's kind of what I'm
doing a lot so just reading a lot of
code there's also a possibility for just
doing consultant in general where you
help companies designs a cure software
before they even get implemented and you
can also be mathematical in the crypto
reviews and build those complex
protocols that are running on our secure
messenger applications you could also be
somebody who just sits in front of EXO
and us risk analysis and pushing around
some numbers to see how much damage
could be done or
what the probabilities are or you are
just a developer who has to write secure
code and that's good if you identify as
a hacker and you are developer hopefully
you write you know not as insecure code
and I believe even though these jobs in
our industry are so different you would
be better in all of them the more
technical knowledge you have the more
detailed knowledge you have and for for
example a Red Team pen tester who uses
Metasploit might not have to ever write
the buffer overflow themselves or
understand it there are just too many
exploits in Metasploit to understand
each one of them but I believe that if
you would know at least a few of them or
if you at least have an intuition for
how binary exploitation works and if you
have seen basic heap exploit then you
are better at it you develop a better
intuition for it you are maybe you
probably make better decisions when to
use certain exploits and when not to
when the same goes for somebody who just
sits in front of excellent does risk
analysis if you understand how
complicated certain attacks are and how
easy other attacks are you will be able
to look at the news about security and
you will be able to identify the snake
or the snake well stuff and you
identify the stuff that is actually a
real risk so how do we even get there
how do we get even this technical
knowledge to get one of these jobs
generally I mean this is not meant to be
these are all just examples doesn't mean
to be complete but maybe you have just
been part of a community you find very
early in your life some online community
so you've been part of hacker spaces and
just you know learned it well while
being part of it
maybe he also nowadays you just study it
universities often our classes on
security and some universities even
offer degrees in this field or maybe you
have for example transition from an
entirely different job into the security
field by doing by investing into
trainings and going to conferences and
maybe also doing certifications or maybe
you have also just been a developer who
realizes
wait I built these systems I know how to
break them to this kind of where I'm
coming from I was a web developer and I
created websites and then at some point
I realized I always wanted to be a
hacker and then I realized oh wait with
all the knowledge I acquired being a
developer I can also you know abuse this
knowledge and I believe that generally
the traditional way of learning and how
we get into it you know you will do a
good job you will know enough to raise
the bar for the attacker in a meaningful
way and generally you are a good
investment to have but you all know that
we all of all of us don't know
everything we know that there are people
that are way better than us they have
just a lot more skill and if you would
let them do the job they may be better
at it than you are
so we understand that there's a margin
upwards and depends on you personally
but I do want to you know always take a
step forward or was try to improve and
not be stuck at you know a basic level
and even and with all this there are
still educational challenges in in this
field for example to not even fall back
you need to constantly evolve with the
field when I started out professionally
as doing web pentesting three or four
years ago we our clients had a lot of
PHP applications and nowadays they all
just come with no GS JavaScript web apps
to us so if you have you know been
really really good at auditing PHP
applications four years ago then you are
kind of just a newb again and a trainee
at this point even though maybe your
role is a senior penetration tester
because you did so well four years ago
also maybe you need to learn entirely
new fields what if a client comes to you
and has a website that is interfacing
with some kind of binary maybe some
audio processing or something like this
are you able to audit this will you
ignore that part or what will you do so
that's generally you know a broad field
of knowledge is very beneficial
a lot of interesting vulnerabilities
happen exactly where those different
fields are intersecting with each other
and if you have knowledge on many
different fields you have a lot more
interesting attack ideas and ways to
hopefully exploit the stuff and then we
shouldn't also forget that hacking in
its essence is something very creative
hacking has always been something to
play with technology bent the system's
you know to the rules that were
unintentionally implemented and we
shouldn't forget that because especially
in the business environment everything
has to be measurable everything has to
be able to assign a number to it but
then we lose this creativity and with a
lot of audits for example you kind of
work through checklists you know this is
what happens in PHP applications so you
check exactly these things but then
there are these weird loner abilities
that are unique to a certain application
that you won't be able to check if you
just follow those checklists and I'm not
saying that checklist are bad everybody
has those checklist in their mind but
you should not be forced to just follow
those checklists and you should be
allowed to be creative and explore
entirely different areas of these
applications and I believe if you are
aware of these things and if you you
know think about these and invest in
these areas then it's then you are
taking steps forwards and become better
and you hopefully get to this point
where people are looking up to you and
think oh my gosh you will do a really
good job and I believe that CTFs are a
way to solve all these challenges at
least for me and it might not be for you
but I want to introduce it to you why I
think it's a good thing and and
hopefully it's for you as well so the
great thing about CTF is that a lot of
the vulnerabilities are just basic
vulnerabilities and those can then be
used to just you know see how well you
are actually with those challenges if
you do web pen testing and and try to
solve a basic web challenge then you can
try to speed on it and see how fast you
are just to see you know I know my
field but you can also use those to get
into entirely new areas with my first
CTF I used it to as an opportunity to go
into binary exploitation I was coming
from web programming and I did my first
buffer overflow was something very basic
just jump into the stack to some shell
code and that took me eight probably
days I think but I googled the hell out
of it and in the end I was able to solve
it and so I used this as an opportunity
to as an entry point in an entirely new
field that seemed so far away and mystic
Ultimo then the other thing is that a
lot of CTF vulnerability or challenges
are kind of about esoteric stuff and
this is what is criticised often about
CTS that they don't reflect the real
life and what's realistic but if I kind
of understand where this is coming from
but I also think those people that held
this belief have never actually audited
clients code because I have seen the
weirdest kind of vulnerabilities in
client code if you are looking for them
and that means being creative and I
agree with you that this particular CTF
vulnerability will probably never be in
an application that you were awed it
ever but that's not the point the point
is these vulnerabilities could
theoretically exist and the question is
not whether it's common or happens a lot
the question is rather would you be able
to identify them if they were in this
kind of code and if you can't do this
then you know you maybe don't do the the
best job you could do and then the third
point that is also very important to me
is that with CTFs you will get a reality
check you will get a punch in the face
and you will fail because these
challenges are really hard especially
the creative esoteric ones is where you
really have to understand a certain
framework a system or language to its
smallest corner that is so uncommon and
this really shows how much knowledge you
don't have or what skill you don't have
and this is good for two reasons first
of all we are often very arrogant we and
I include myself here definitely I'm
laughing at
developers that write shitty code and
the code I ordered that's just how it is
but it kind of shouldn't be it's it's
kind of a shitty thing to do it's very
arrogant the other thing is that when
especially in my line of work where I
write a report an audit code I usually
never get negative feedback of how good
my job was I sent out those tickets they
paid me because I didn't find it
themselves or generally they want to
know how they are doing
so they trust me that I do a good job
and find them and there's no way to
verify if I actually did a good job and
found a good amount of vulnerabilities
and the good thing with CTFs is it's
kind of like an exam where the solution
is known when you know that these
challenges are intentionally insecure
and there there is something in there
and it's kind of also not a huge
application it's a small challenge that
focuses on the small thing and you will
still fail to find this bug and this is
a good reflection yourself okay you know
I may be not that good yet but you know
I'm I'm learning so how do you get into
CTF there's a website called CTF 10 the
orc you can look on the upcoming events
and generally look for the waited events
generally the CTS are running for a few
days like the one here at the conference
just like two or three days maybe over a
weekend and I say you look for the
waited events because this means they
have a score attached because they have
proven themselves in the past obviously
there are a lot of CTF and a lot of also
not that great ones but if you look for
those then you know that you have a high
quality CTF they also might already be a
bit too complicated they are still they
are quite difficult so maybe you have to
look for some other CTS but generally
it's a good advice if you check out for
the first time and want to get your feet
wet look for those then I would suggest
you just take out for example three
hours of your Saturday afternoon and
just pick out one challenge and dedicate
the time to it
don't play this challenge with an
intention to solve it just you know take
a lot of notes Google the hell out of it
and write down everything you can think
of every idea you have even though you
might not be able to implement it you
know if it's a binary you say ah this
could be a buffer overflow but I have no
clue what to do write this down and then
accept that you would didn't solve it
and afterwards and if you solve it great
but you know most likely is be realistic
that they are really hard and you might
not solve them and then you go
afterwards on IRC where the players are
discussing their solutions and this is a
great learning opportunity to just read
the chat what people are sharing their
scripts and write-ups and you can also
look on CTF time and github and Twitter
for those write-ups and then what you
can do is you sit down and compare those
write-ups with your notes that you have
taken and this is then where you can
learn because you can analyze where did
I fail what did what did I miss what did
I not know about was it just a
carelessness that you ignored that you
shouldn't have ignored or was it an
entirely thing that you have never heard
about before that that's even a thing
and this is really where the learning
that happens so that's good that I
talked a bit faster because now we have
a bit more time to look into more
technical stuff it's a technical trick
today after all so I will it's kind of
like now some life over flow many
episodes just we go over some examples
really quickly and it's not meant to be
that you understand them right away I
hope they are not all stuff you already
know and in generally it's just more
like that you know that these kind of
things exist and that you are aware of
those and that when you test
applications or when you play CTF that
you have that in the back of your mind
and when you think that could it be that
that's what it could be then you can
google and learn and read up on it again
so the first example is about how Python
compares objects or data so here's an
example it's a website where there are
you messages you are allowed to read
only the last three messages the message
1 & 2 are hidden already you are not
allowed to read them I don't know what
kind of application it is but that's
that's why how its implemented so you
can read the last three messages and
there's also a JSON API where you can
send in the ID of the message that you
want to read so for example here we see
how this works you send in the ID 5 in
the in the JSON format and then you get
back the message and if you would try to
access the idea 1 it's forbidden
obviously so here's the piece of code
that is implementing this and there's a
back in there and I won't let you take
time to look at this because I don't
want to waste time I'm telling you the
title is already Python compares object
so it has something to do with
comparison in line 8 the post idea that
you send in with the JSON request is
coming in and then there after that is a
comparison that checks if you are
allowed to read the message or if it's
forbidden and the checks if you're super
user but you are not so bad luck but
then it checks if the post ID you
entered is larger than the amount of
messages available minus 3 so you are
only allowed to read the last 3 messages
so we entered 5 and there were 5
messages
5 minus 3 is 2 so 5 is larger than 2 you
are allowed to read it one is not larger
than 2 so you are not allowed to read
now let's have a look how comparison
works in Python 5 is larger than 1
that's true and one is larger than 5
that's false now let's have a look at
this what happens if you compare a
string with an integer
I mean it's nonsensical that that you do
this but python has an answer for it so
the string 5 is larger than 1 that kind
of still makes sense but the string 1 is
larger than 5 it's also true what is
happening has to do with Python how
Python works but what this means is if
you enter obviously the number then the
number 1 is not larger than 2 but the
string 1 is larger than 2 and in this
case the database layer where you
request this ID doesn't care about the
type of it so you are able to request
the one but the Python code that
implements this check is just happy to
bypass that comparison and just for
completeness sake in Python 3 Landry
would throw an exception that you can't
compare string with an integer that I
guess how it should be but anyway if you
didn't get it it's just a general
example of validate your inputs if you
expect a number make sure that it is a
number and especially highlight this
because of the JSON format because in
the basic web post requests that we are
used to with URL encoding we kind of
expect everything to be a string and we
kind of do this automatically but with
Jason you suddenly have different types
you can have numbers you can have
strings you can have lists for example
and so our developer might have the
expectation that a certain number value
that is coming in is from a certain type
and might not do this conversion
automatically how maybe they used to be
and so the story is just here you know
make sure to check everything before you
process it and also I want to be honest
do I have I ever seen this in real life
in a application and I have to be honest
and say no in every Python website or
code that I get to audit I specifically
look for these type confusion kind of
things and I've never seen it but the
point is not if this is is this a likely
vulnerability
the point is would you have noticed this
vulnerability what you have tested for
it would you have tried to enter
different types in this JSON format
which we have tried or would you have
known that these comparisons could be
screwed up like this in Python and
that's kind of the story here and it's
great that we have more time so we can
get more so format string
vulnerabilities if you would do binary
then it's a basic thing and you know
about it if not it's
maybe hopefully interesting so when you
program see for example printf the first
part of printf where you specify how you
want to want the data to be displayed as
a format string and here's another
example with two variables present so
you want this one to be replaced with a
decimal representation of the number and
this one to replace with the hex this
play off of this number here and the
former string vulnerability happens when
you can control this format string and
so here's kind of how this looks like
with a simplified stick in memory
because printf has a variable amount of
parameters and it basically just trusts
that everything is on the stick so if
printf encounters a percentage D it will
take the first number from the stick and
display it and then it encounters the
percent as X takes it from the stack and
displays it and you can imagine that
when you can now control this part of
the string and you enter as an attacker
just a lot of X that you start consuming
a lot of values from the stick and you
will leak a lot of data from it so this
can be used to bypass a SLR for example
because we know that on the stick is for
gamma be return pointer so you have at
least a valid address into valid code
and from based on that you can most
likely get around the a s all a SLR
issue but there are even modifiers that
allows you to write into memory and it
can be even used to completely take over
the control flow of a program but this
is not only the idea the abstract the
idea of controlling the format stuff is
not only an issue for see here's a
Python example and I mean it's a
completely ridiculous example who would
write this kind of code but the question
is would you realize that this is
happening if you would audit it and in
this case we don't look so much into it
there's a global conflict variable and
there with dot so you have a string and
dot format and this is then the format
string part of it and this is prepare
response it's coming from here long
short user can enter format parameters
like curly braces temp or place into
that part and because of format it gets
interpreted and here's the idea that you
do the prepare response because you want
to pre-paint the name of the application
but you also pass in what an attacker
could potentially control and so you can
access other conflict parts I mean it's
a ridiculous example but the point is
that if you have something like this in
Python it's also kind of a format string
vulnerability and you are able to then
just read and print out the secret key
this if you look at this in your web
into web security you might think this
looks very similar to a template
injection and in fact if you think about
it template injection also just kind of
a form of formal string the template
specifies how the site is formatted okay
so if you didn't get it
format strings can be abused make sure
that they are usually not controlled by
an attacker often they are just about
leaking data but sometimes it can be
even worse depending on what kind of
template engine or whatever you have how
to fix this yeah keep those strings of a
static and have you ever seen this kind
of double format string from Python I
have also not seen it again the point is
would you be able to see it if you audit
this kind of application okay another
example has a tightly a cone ski
hierarchy so rising stack is apparently
a company that offers nodejs
trainings and consultant and development
and they have this nodejs module called
protect that apparently protects against
or detects XSS and SQL injections and
they are referencing and based this work
on an article from 2004 by Symantec and
you can imagine if that if it's at an
old an article is probably pretty bad
and that site suggested to use some
regular expressions so this is the
regular expression that is supposed to
detect XSS attacks there's a cool
website called debug X where you can
build the finest state automaton based
on this regular expression so
very easy to see what kind of strings
are matched by this and what strings are
not and so it's pretty clear that for
example script another one the script
parts are matched its opening an
optional slash then some characters and
then closing the tag again and it's also
clear how that can be easily bypassed
you just enter space because this one
doesn't match a space and so it's
useless and the moral of the story here
and where the title is coming from is
the consu key hierarchy because in
formal if you have studied computer
science you are aware that these the
study of formal languages and that
certain grammars languages are more
powerful than others and require more
complicated parsing than others and so
for example regular expression are kind
of a really good example of what a
regular language is because it
implements this finite state automaton
that you just saw from somebody buggies
and the hierarchy also tells you that if
you have a more powerful language then
you can power so implement the lower
less powerful language but never the
reverse a regular language can never
fully implement for example context-free
language and HTML and SQL are so
complicated that they are at least
context-free and not to mention that
browsers are screwing with HTML anyway
you don't even have to write valid HTML
and and still work so you know it's knit
it's a mathematically impossible task
yeah so if you didn't get it well don't
use reg X especially if you want to try
to match very complicated languages and
languages where you have for example
opening and closing records or tags like
XML these are always much more powerful
than what a regular expression could
implement because you would need an
additional stick to remember what is
open and what has to be closed again and
in general how do you fix this well just
don't try to detect XSL or SQL at all
just you know try to fix it that's more
like a defense and death kind of thing
you actually want to focus more on just
making sure that this doesn't have met
on and I can really
recommend debuggers okay so you can
maybe get an one other example here's
like some kind of language sandbox
escape what do i mean by that
so sometimes applications implement some
kind of security sandbox so sometimes
you want an application where people can
run arbitrary code but you want it to be
safe code a good example is the browser
where you run code on your kind of your
machine but you want it to be secure and
especially Java applets for example and
Java is a very powerful language with a
lot of low-level access to the system
and you want this to run securely and
then you have but this comes up in many
different places so for example
angularjs expressions you can define
javascript in these expressions but you
want this not to be fully JavaScript
otherwise people can use it to do XSS so
you want to kind of sandbox that so that
they can only do what you know for the
application and not something very
intrusive and then you can also play
with that there are CTF challenges where
people implement a Python sandbox where
you can submit Python code but you can't
for example import OS and then execute
system so here's the example of
angularjs the expression would be you
would write this and it would be
evaluate like this and in order to
support this complex expression
angularjs kind of just interprets this
as JavaScript it's not just a full eval
because they at least in some versions
try to make sure that it can't be abused
but this is the first version where they
didn't take care of this and so the
bypass for this is to break out and get
access to very interesting functions or
objects on the in the dom is for example
you want to get access to like window or
document or something like this and in
this way we can go from constructor to
constructor and then call alert and if
you look at this how this works
you start by a variable and constructor
of this variable is the number
constructor and
of the number constructor is the
function constructor and you can pass in
a string that is code that you want this
function to be so this now creates a new
function where the code is alert and
then you can just call it here's a
Python sandbox example where you can't
just easily import OS to call system
because that is built-in is disallowed
and it's removed but you can from an
empty Dick you go over the class the
base you list the subclasses you find an
interesting subclass you take its
modules you take its built-ins and then
from that one you can get to the import
and OS and the one that was used here is
the warnings catch warnings object it
mean it looks crazy but the moral of the
story is that you can you know from you
can kind of escape out of this not
allowed object by trying a different
path through the objects to get where
you want to be and this is a kind of the
same thing with Java applets that were
used in drive-by downloads on your
machine they were I mean sometimes they
were a memory corruption but sometimes
they were just bypassing the security
manager kind of thing and in this case
for example this kind this proof of
concept code is loading a class that you
are usually shouldn't be allowed to load
and it's basically doing the same thing
by traversing through all the objects
available and somehow getting to this
fine class method that you shouldn't be
able allow to get access to and
basically the idea behind all of these
sandbox escapes and this can be again be
generalized it doesn't matter if it's
JavaScript or Python or Java itself it's
basically you have these complicated to
object-oriented languages that have
references to all these objects and all
you do is you try to get to this magic
object you are not allowed to access and
you try to find a way through a lot of
different objects to kind of try to
traverse the jungle of objects to get to
these juicy classes and that's basic
what is happening with any sandbox
escape so you can generalize this and
this thinking to any other example okay
so I didn't get it
implementing sandbox is hard generally
don't try to run arbitrary code if you
do it expect a huge overhead that you
have to fix stuff like this
I'm already over my time I'm sorry if
you want to stay in contact you can find
me on Twitter like overflow you can also
subscribe to my youtube channel we have
a lot of technical examples and I'm also
happy to hear by email so if you have
feedback of the stork or generally
questions and stuff I try to answer to
everybody thank you very much for having
me and I guess that's it thank you
[Applause]