hi so this is a measured response to a
grain of rice I'm Joe Fitzpatrick you
can find me on Twitter at securely Fitz
this is my first time the black hat
Europe which is pretty cool I'm glad to
be here I've been to the black hat
United States a few times but that's
very close to home for me so I was glad
to make it out here I have about 15
years of experience playing with
hardware that includes starting out
doing silicon debug I was doing a speed
debug of desktop and server CPUs from
that I moved more into hardware pen
testing pre and post silicon of chips
and while I was doing that I moved into
the training side I there were a lot of
people who had a lot of background in
hardware and functional validation
making things making sure things work
the way they were supposed to and I kind
of tried to help people understand how
to pick out the hardware security bugs
that they should be you know flagging as
well instead of just looking at things
from a purely functional perspective I
do own a pair of shoes that have LEDs
inside of them and a shirt that is sound
sensitive and has LEDs inside too and
yes that's at a conference I was at work
when I took that picture I now for the
past six years have been doing training
I teach classes I've taught at blackhat
us several times applied physical tax
training on embedded systems x86 systems
these are all about using your hands to
hook wires up and undermine the security
of systems by using physical access so
before we go any further I do want to
put some disclaimers in here I think
this image summarizes it pretty well I
don't know about about Hardware implants
but I got a buddy named Joe who does so
let's give him a call I don't know if
you know the mean but this is a from a
TV show that I've never actually seen
about pawnshops and this guy you know at
a pawn shop often has people he calls so
it seems like I'm the guy who people are
calling about Hardware implants since
for some reason in the past two months
people are a little more interest to
them in them than they were before I've
played a lot with Hardware implants over
the past several years but I'm Joe I do
this for fun essentially I do this solo
by myself I don't work for a government
agency
I know that there are a lot of people
out there who do do this professionally
whose jobs are to build these hardware
implants that might go in servers or
telecom systems or anything else but I
don't think you're gonna get any of them
to come and talk to you at blackhat so
unfortunately I'm just Joe I'm what you
get so you know know that what I'm
talking about is from my own experience
building things and creating things and
not necessary from the perspective of
someone who is funded with several
millions of dollars and has signed their
life away on all sorts of government
forms and whatnot so what is a hardware
implant I'm using this word perhaps some
people aren't sure what I mean by that
the first time we we see this word this
term of implant used a lot is around
2013 it was used a lot in all the leaked
documents from Snowden covert implants
software implants Network implants these
are essentially malicious bits of stuff
payloads code whatever that is used to
generally do surveillance type
operations right so these are
intelligence agencies who want to get an
implant into a server so they can
monitor what's on that so they can have
a way of collecting intelligence off of
this device hardware implant came into
more common use around 2013 at the end
of the year when Der Spiegel published
an article about the ant catalog this
was a purported leaked document that had
several pages that described little
malicious hardware devices that could be
implanted into servers into mobile
devices into cables that would give
Hardware access to those systems so
historically when we think of Hardware
implants we think of Hardware attack
devices the basic classical example is a
keystroke logger this is a USB keystroke
logger you plug it into your USB port
you plug the car you plug into someone
else's USB port I would never do that
but apparently that's what people do
plug it in someone else's keyboard and
their USB port and it logs all the
keystrokes that go through you retrieve
it and then you can retrieve all the
keystrokes that were stored on it they
even made these so old that they came in
like ps2 connectors and and 5-pin din
connectors
before we even had USB but that's been
around for four decades at this point
the other thing that's been around is
mod chips who's ever played on a game
console before who's ever played like a
game on a game console before okay so
apparently you know once you once you
modify and solder things onto your game
console you can still play games with it
too
I don't know that's the fun part is the
soldering these mod chips on they
basically change the way the device
works so that you can do things the
manufacturer of the hardware didn't
intent this is a hardware modification
you know the model is a little different
because the attacker is now the owner of
the system as opposed to the attacker
being not the owner and the the the
malicious agent on the system but we get
the same types of devices the same
examples of what we're looking at we
also have counterfeit bypass devices
this is a photo that someone posted on
reddit a few years ago saying hey I
bought a bunch of switches on eBay or
some other strange source of equipment
and I found one that I took apart and it
had this weird chip stuck on the bottom
anybody know what this might be and you
look at it and of course the reaction to
post 2013 is like oh my gosh it's
implanted you know you have spyware on
your system but no this is just a by a
counterfeit bypass device you buy a
switch you pay for the number of ports
you have on it and or the speed or
configuration of it if you want to be
malicious and make money what do you do
it you take a bunch of the cheap
switches you put a bypass device on it
so that suddenly they work as the
expensive switches you change the
sticker on the front you sell them to
people who are willing to buy stuff on
eBay and you profit right again we still
don't have Hardware implants that are
being manufactured and used by
intelligence agencies so this is a
project that I work on with a friend of
mine killa okay Mike and we made the do
B key so on the left which way is left
on the right you have an actual Yubikey
and I got a free Yubikey at a conference
and I thought oh this is great I wonder
if it's real how do I go verify that
it's real I go to UB Keys website you
because website they say Oh does it have
a serial number like does it say powered
by UB come on the back then it's real
I can fake that so we invade our fake
dooby keys we're the ones on the left
and you can see that the case on the
dooby key is not as good as the case on
the Yubikey yet but we're still working
on that it also has a programming part
of the board which hasn't been snapped
off yet but we made these devices to
show like yeah we we get these hardware
security devices and we don't really
have a good understanding of what
hardware security means because again
there are a lot of people who receive
those those free UV keys at a conference
off about of a bowl at a table and don't
have any reason to believe they should
be suspicious of the supply chain that
got them to them another example from
last year or two years ago is this the
RSA token so you know you have an RSA
token if you flip it over you'd see a
little display with a six digit pin that
you type in when your login I flipped it
over took the back off and I soldered on
that little extra board which has a
bluetooth module right so you take an
off-the-shelf hardware device you open
it up you add some extra parts to it and
suddenly it's Bluetooth enabled which is
like what everybody wants right so it
broadcasts a six-digit to every 60
seconds it broadcasts your 6-digit pin
so everybody can listen to it or you can
pair it with your computer and it types
it in for you
which you know whatever and then even
further along we've got these lots of
examples of skimmers so these are a
series of skimmers that were found in
gas pumps in Colorado Sparkfun is a
supplier of like hobby electronics type
stuff and they were asked to go and take
a look at some of these and these are
basically really cheap off-the-shelf
devices you can buy them for roughly $5
you can actually buy them assembled as
skimmers for $5 pre-programmed and what
would happen is someone would get one of
these or they would be given one of
these and say hey go go plug it in that
gas pump you know open this service
panel and plug it in the socket and then
all you have to do is go back every
couple days pull out your phone pair
with it over bluetooth and it downloads
all the credit cards that have been
scanned at that gas pump right these are
all methods of manipulating hardware
devices using up their hardware right
that really and for most part doesn't
leave a software a trace right we think
about everything we do everything we
have systems of logging and detection
for we're always counting on software to
leave a trace or network access to leave
a trace so these
ways to avoid that so let's talk
specifically about USB hardware tax so
USB is kind of the easy one everybody's
heard about how oh don't plug in a
random USB Drive you don't know what it
is
well how did we get to this point and
why do we still do it anyway I mentioned
before we've got these keystroke loggers
you know you plug it in the USB port you
get all your keystrokes that come
through you retrieve it and you get the
can get those keys later
so there's also specifically programmed
devices they are designed to be
malicious USB devices we've got in the
middle the USB rubber ducky which
focuses on a lot of keyboard type
attacks you plug it in it plays back a
series of keystrokes that will open up
terminals and type commands on the left
you got the bash Bunny which is similar
except it shows up as a USB network
device and it does a few network based
attacks again these are hardware devices
you can buy for pretty reasonable prices
you can carry them to computer you plug
them in and have a surprisingly high
level of success at exploiting systems
with these but again these are these are
purpose-built devices they're designed
specifically to be attack devices if
you're around tomorrow tomorrow morning
Luka is going to showing off the the W
hit injector this is essentially a USB
what's it called rubber ducky it does
hid and other attacks but it's connected
to Wi-Fi I believe it's also a GSM
version so you can remotely do these
these Bluetooth these USB attacks once
you've plugged this device into your
system right we're talking about ways
that we're expanding the hardware
ability to access and proxy physical
access to systems bad USB was pretty
interesting basically there's this
chipset the fission chipset you find it
on USB drives and it's a chipset it's a
SOC a system-on-chip
it's got a core that's programmable it
stores flash and it gives you access to
the the NAND flash the big volume of
flash on the other side that implements
the USB Drive you can reprogram this
sometimes these are sold off the shelf
without the the the reprogramming
ability being taken away so sure enough
you can take an existing device off the
shelf modify it with just software and
now you have a malicious hardware device
that isn't even
a fabricated device it's a tamper -
modified existing device USB is even
more exciting from the attackers
perspective right you've got this port
that instead of just being USB it also
carries your display it also carries
Thunderbolt 3 it can carry all sorts of
different alternate data streams over it
as well this is two examples of USB see
to display adapters the one on the left
is the Apple one which costs about 80 US
dollars you plug it in to your USB C
port on the other side you have an HDMI
port a power port and a USB output right
but if you look at it you've got a lot
of chips on there and I believe on the
opposite side from that diet that
picture you've got a JTAG header for the
chipset that is on there JTAG being a
debug port you can go and reprogram the
firmware
luckily the latest firmware is lockout
JTAG access so you may not have to worry
about that unless someone goes and
resolder x' the replacement chip on
there without JTAG just enabled I'm
sorry disabled details on the right you
have an inexpensive $20.00 USB USB C to
VGA adapter and you see three chips on
that little board and I don't know if I
can highlight them well enough but
you've got the biggest chip is basically
what turns the DisplayPort signals off
of the USB into VGA signals so it's kind
of a passive analog chip then over here
you've got a very tiny chip that's a USB
power delivery chip that's telling the
system to give it power says oh I'd like
5 volts at 3 at 500 milliamps or I could
say I'd like 20 volts at 3 amps all
software and then lastly as this chip
right here that the middle middle sized
chip in the corner and that's a USB
micro controller I open this device up
thinking I would have to find a pin to
short out to reprogram this micro
controller sure enough it turns out it
was by default reprogrammable all I had
to do is plug this into a USB port and I
could go ahead and rewrite the firmware
on the USB side of my display adapter so
I chose to program it to also show up as
a USB HID device so I plug it in the
screen shows up and suddenly random
keystrokes got to start getting entered
while I'm presenting and slides flip
around pretty annoying but it's one of
those things you can't do you can't tell
just by looking this device what's
inside so even further along you know we
have these devices that we previously
thought were passive like output only
devices we've got the point where we
have lightning cables that have enough
extra space in the housings that you can
put a malicious USB device inside of
them a friend of mine mg has a series of
videos on his on his Twitter account
where he basically in the little housing
of this cable is able to put just enough
logic to playback a USB series a series
of USB interactions so you don't even
realize you're just using a cable and
this cable can be malicious and this is
all like kind of the high point of this
that I've encountered is this Cape this
is a seven dollar cable that I bought
from China and you look at it and
there's a media tech arm CPU right here
and the reason is because this USB cable
inside that housing which is no bigger
than a normal USB cable has a cellphone
module it has a slot for a SIM card
right and it has a microphone right so
all the previous USB attacks were
focused on interacting with the system
this one doesn't even bother this is
completely decoupled it just gets power
from the system so you hand someone a
USB cable and say oh here use this to
charge your phone and they plug it in
and they're charging their phone or they
leave it in their car and use it to
charge their phone or listen to music on
their phone and the whole time it's
powered on it's on the cellphone Network
it's reporting its location and when you
call the device you can open up a hot
mic and listen to what's going on write
a theory that I have not yet you know
proven is the fact that when you plug
this thing into your laptop it's close
enough to your laptop that you would
hear the tap of keystrokes right timing
analysis would be able to let you use
this cable to figure out what keys are
being pressed without even electrically
sorry logically being coupled to your PC
so it's pretty amazing to me what is
possible with just USB right and we're
only scratching the surface here so how
else could we connect a hardware implant
so let's say we want to make a malicious
device we can hook up to USB or external
ports that's the easiest way but they're
kind of obvious because you see a little
little thing sticking out of a port on a
PC so you you don't want to do that if
you're trying to be covert in any way
inside the system we've got PCI Express
how many of you have extra slots that
you're not
using a desktop system probably most of
you you've also got on laptops most
Wi-Fi modules are removable lots of SSDs
are now removable those are PCI Express
attached devices so even in a laptop
you've got spots where you can plug in
extra hardware what's also really neat
is you can tap internship communication
on a regular system you've got tons of
devices that are all communicating to
each other and every single one of them
has a protocol they speak if you're able
to access the wires that connect to
chips you have no reason there's no
reason why you couldn't sniff that
protocol there's no reason why was a
little more modification to the system
you couldn't intercept and man in the
middle of a protocol and lastly you've
got debug headers right when boards are
manufactured they're manufactured and
tested they go through a qualification
process and then finally someone says
this this board is done let's
manufacture it for production and no
one's gonna go and do another revision
of the board and remove all those debug
headers because that's extra risk you
don't have the ability to go back and
debug stuff that went wrong so you often
have debug headers on the board if you
could just tap on to those debug headers
and pins with a malicious device you
could go back and play a series of debug
commands to modify that system in in
operation so when we could talk about
hardware we've got we've got entry
points we need these entry points to get
into the system but how many do we have
so this is a what we might see inside of
a server
this photo is diagram is from AST this
there are manufacturers of BMC board
management controllers and on the left
side we see the board managed controller
on the right side we see that the
classic CPU Northbridge Southbridge
setup and these days it's kind of
all-in-one Northbridge Southbridge but
don't worry about that we see we've got
network connectivity our Mir GM III
right those are connectivity is between
the chip and the physical layer of the
network we've got USB 2 2.0 1.1 we've
got PCI Express connectivity LPC which
is a low speed version a low pin count
version of an ISA bus we've got UART
we've got sd card slots we've got
additional NIC connections as well as
display and serial ports so we've got
tons of opportunities to hook up wires
to this system to base
Stickley maliciously modify its
operation so when do these hardware
tacks make sense oh I gotta speed up
quite a bit so what if you have airtight
security practices you have employees
who are involuntary attacks you have
perfect network security then hardware
makes sense if you're dealing with air
gap system systems that are not on a
network that are not couple in any way
then it makes sense to have a piece of
device that is what is your link between
this and the outside world sometimes you
actually do a decent job you have a
heavily monitored network for any
various reasons sometimes you have
industrial control type scenarios where
you have these data diodes that are very
careful about letting data only flow in
certain directions sometimes you just
have a very rigid policy that doesn't
let outside access happen so again
physical access is a way to get into
these systems that wouldn't be otherwise
remotely accessible and of course supply
chain if you have access to the supply
chain if you have access to how the
hardware gets into the the target system
then you have access to that to the
firmware that's on that Hardware the
extra components where those components
come from and supply chain isn't just a
one-stop thing this is the supply chain
of your boards the supply chain of your
chips the supply chain of your passive
components the supply chain includes how
these devices are shipped around and how
they're assembled where they're
assembled once you've manufactured a
board with all its components on it and
you ship it to the end end user where
does it go is it sit in a warehouse
until it's it deployed when we go to the
situation with voting machines right
there's a lot of talk about how voting
machines are so secure because they're
only used on a certain day of the year
and the rest of the year they're stored
in a closet in the school where the
voting happens at least in the United
States sure it's very different here but
again perhaps it's different here but
again you know the no one thinks about
the security of the physical security of
these devices because it's a box it's a
heart it's a piece of hardware that they
kind of think of as immutable when it
comes to a Hardware attack if you are
able to implant a hardware device right
there's no network logs there's no
traffic there's no backwards
observation that can happen perhaps
you've got surveillance cameras that's
kind of a different story but there is
this deniability that comes with a
hardware device expect especially if
it's an off-the-shelf type hardware
device and last exfiltration if you're
on a network where you're very careful
about what data gets out are you also
careful about what hardware leaves and
how it leaves I heard a story it is just
a story and as a multi hand story so I
don't know how factual it is but you've
got memory modules and memory modules
have a very tiny piece of Flash on them
that let you program the parameters of
that memory module and there was a
report where system had memory modules
that kept failing tests and so the
memory module was packaged up and sent
out to RMA and in that process
someone was caught trying to steal these
memory modules from the mail room
turns out apparently legend story there
was data on these on these little SPD
flash modules on the memory modules that
was exfiltrating data so hardware access
gives you an interesting way to get data
off of a system lastly if we've got
vulnerable Hardware if we have a bug in
a space of silicon it's pretty tough to
fix that it definitely doesn't get fixed
in a quick way and you generally don't
want to destroy your hardware just
because it has one bug what that means
though is we might have a situation
where our hardware vulnerabilities are
baked in and known to be good for
several years whether it's five years or
thirty years if we've got vulnerable
hardware that's always gonna stay
vulnerable we don't have to worry about
a patch or a software update that fixes
it then we've got an easy way and like I
said unpatch noblemen or abilities
format as well what's also interesting
when we go to the lower layers of
hardware the the deeper we bury
ourselves into the hardware the harder
it is to detect right it's just like in
software realm if we have a malicious
process the operating system can observe
that if we start tampering at the
operating itself operating system itself
we can't trust the operating system to
report on itself when we have a higher
privilege levels or lower privilege
levels depending on which perspective
you're looking at you may have the
ability to hide from the operating
system and even an even lower level when
we get down to hardware it's the same
way we have lower levels of hardware
that are pretty much invisible to the
upper layers because
the way the abstraction works and of
course social engineering with hardware
is so much more effective than just
talking on the phone because I mean free
you be keys who doesn't want a free
Yubikey right so again like let's put it
back in context why is any of this
relevant why am i if you're talking
about these things so what does a
hardware advanced persistent threat look
like right examples we gave were kind of
a you know more homebrew a little D more
decoupled from the system but what if
what if someone had millions of dollars
to go invest in creating the ideal
Hardware implant what would that be so
there's a story the big hack and as you
can see there's a tiny little chip on
the tip of a finger and this story a
news article reported how allegedly
there was this tiny little chip the size
of a grain of rice that did some really
bad things and it was implanted in the
entire supply chain and 30 vendor T
companies had found or may have
allegedly been on the list to get this
malicious implant right and again its
device size of the point of a pencil
supposedly did all this stuff and if we
look through the article we see the
technical details which are very limited
something happened at a crucial moment
small bits of the operating system were
being stored in the board temporary
memory and route to the server central
process of the CPU the implant was
placed on the board in a way that
allowed it to effectively edit this
information q injecting its own code or
altering the order of the instructions
the CPU was meant to follow from a
technical perspective this doesn't make
a lot of sense but if you put it through
the journalism filter and like realize
it's written for laypeople we basically
have a description of malicious code
right or manipulating existing code or
maybe you could call return on to
programming kind of the same way because
you're messing with the information q I
don't know the point is we've got a
piece of hardware that allegedly causes
some issues in the way the software runs
everything and this is a bat this is a
big deal if we look at the example that
was shown in the article we see that
they're talking a lot about super micro
motherboards there's a photo of a super
micro motherboard and targeting
specifically the board management
controller
you have a server you've got your your
x86 CPU that's doing the big tasks and
all the big work connected to lots of
memory and network cards but you've also
got this backside this baseboard
management controllers extra chip
usually an ARM processor that helps you
power up and power down the system and
gives you a virtual terminal so that you
can remotely administer this thing
without having to walk down the aisles
of servers to get to the ones who ever
you actually want to talk to so number
one is that chip the a speed a CPU
system on chip it's got an arm core as
well as all that connectivity we saw on
a block diagram a couple slides back on
the far left we have a flash chip number
two this is a I believe this flash chip
is connected to a speed controller it
has all the firmware this controller is
actually gonna run and execute right
down below and the bottom left is number
three there's an additional flash chip
that's that's the BIOS for the CPU so
when the processor boots up it needs its
own its own UEFI bios whatever it uses
that's executing off of that chip over
there so we have two chips sitting right
here in this like two square inches of
board space that hold code that hold
firmware we look up between the the
cipta the flash chip and this and the
board magical controller we see number
four a little bit hard to see and that
is a spot where there's like eight
little pads love of metal but there's no
chip there it's little white outline as
well as marked um eight that's a spot
where you can actually put another flash
chip and some of these board management
controllers support failover so if one
flash chip seems corrupted it'll go away
from the other sometimes you see this
when you have a board that just
depending on what she was cheaper that
day they'll either use the eight of the
16 pin version of that chip so we've got
an extra spot there and in the bloomberg
article they had an illustration where
that's where they put this grain of rice
sized device and then number five I
circled just above the the board
management controller we see a whole
bunch of those little little golden dots
those are test points and whenever I'm
dealing with a CPU like if I were
developing a system with a CPU I would
want access ability to its debug
features so my assumption when I see
golden dots right next to a CPU I
probably have a debug port of some sort
right so a little sleuthing you might be
able to figure out what those pins are
what they do a little bit of datasheet
research you'll find details like that
again we are just talking about two
square inches of this board happens to
be a very capable 2 square inches but
this is what we can see and what we can
try and do within that little area so
based on this article there was a lot of
reaction of people who are panicking
because we have these little devices
that are the size of a grain of rice
somewhere in everyone's systems or no
one systems we're not really sure how do
we test for them what are we what do we
have what's our indicator of compromise
how do we know that we've been affected
by this issue so open up your case and
look inside do you have grain of rice
sized components on your motherboard yes
you do
ok here's the dilemma though that's how
they're made right actually that we have
little flash chips in the background on
this slide but your board is covered
with resistors and capacitors that are
all the size of a grain of rice this is
how we assemble these boards this is how
we get so much complexity into such a
small space so will you see these
components yes are they necessarily
malicious components probably not now do
your boards exactly match the best
schematic you can get of them so this is
assuming you can actually even get
schematics of your boards oftentimes the
data and information you'll get from
manufacturers kind of just a block
diagram or maybe a little bit more
detail about what chips are what and how
they're connected to actually get a
complete schematic right with all the
electrical connections and all the parts
numbered is pretty rare and when you go
and double-check things it's very likely
that they're not going to match why is
this right we have engineering change
orders updates and revisions that pretty
much guarantee that by the time your
board gets shipped to you something has
changed from that original schematic
right oftentimes the original schematics
never get updated but what you need to
look at is the schematic plus the stack
of 13 engineering change orders to
figure out what chips are what where
they are what values they are and
whether or not they're pops it or not
very often you'll have a bank of
resistors small little components that
are used as switches to tell you whether
things are configured on or off and
depending on how you want to configure
this specific board because this board
is is one we charged an extra five
dollars for feature for
we just pop a little resistor in the
right spot and we enable that feature so
you're really can't count on just a
slight difference between your your
billow materials and your board to be an
indication that that something is
malicious from the hardware implant
perspective here's another great one
there's a follow-up article about
Ethernet issues and how there was some
backdoor to ethernet jacks do your duty
do you have metal housings on your
ethernet jacks yes you do
this article implied that that meant you
had a hardware implant because they were
used for heat diffusion that's not at
all true
nearly every Ethernet jack today has a
metal housing so why they are listing
this as an indicator of compromise is
kind of baffling right
the reason why they have that metal
housing is to shield the noise that
might come from the transformation that
transformer inside of there so what's
the point
what are these implants do so there is
very little description in the article
about like what the actual indications
of something happening was so we still
don't know we don't know what network
activity might have happened that led to
their discovery we don't know where they
were contacting what they were doing so
we have a lot of assumptions we have a
lot of like doom and gloom but we don't
have any information so what's the point
right why would someone go to all this
effort to put these little devices on a
board I mean is this component graffiti
graffiti is someone just showing off and
claiming their turf by throwing a
strange component on a board it's not
necessarily a surprise that this would
be possible without something else going
on
so the problem right now we have no
useful information to help with
detection since two months ago right
nothing has come up no details so we
also need to be very careful should we
really trust anyone who says they do
because if they do they probably have
some more information and it'd be great
to have that information but otherwise I
think it's kind of a a good indication
of someone just trying to take off take
advantage of the opportunity an
ambulance chaser or snake oil salesman
whatever you would like to call them so
is this real or is it a hoax
I don't know right I will say that
you blatantly I don't know I don't have
enough information I am no expert beyond
my own research however the question
that I can answer is this possible
right yes I absolutely think that the
things that were described are
technically possible I'm a technical
person when I see challenges I see an
opportunity to go and implement
something since this was published less
than a month after it was published
cholesky security did a blog post where
they had this little device that went
and reprogrammed over the the I squared
C interface a network adapter and showed
that you could basically send undetected
network traffic over I squared C I
squared C is a low speed serial
interface right in this example they
have a USB connected device this is the
Hydra bus there's no reason this
couldn't be implemented in the
microcontroller and there's no reasons
my controllers can't be implemented in
the size not of the size of a grain of
rice but not much larger and in a
package that would be really obvious to
find on my motherboard NCC group did a
great article discussing Hardware
implants and supply chain issues in
addition if you're headed to CCC later
this month Tremmel Hudson's gonna great
have a great presentation where he has
his proof of concept he's gonna examine
the design of a spy bus hardware implant
with similar capabilities of those
described in the Bloomberg super mikro
article these are you know these mod
chips of the state so again we're going
back to these mod chips from game
consoles it's kind of where where the
the old art has come from and really
it's what we're doing anymore where
we're modifying an existing system with
some some new useful features so again
is this possible yes but that's not the
question we need to ask right that tells
us what's gonna happen in the near
future but Swift on security who is
clearly a very great authority talks to
US government hackers on their
experience and ask the question how did
Bloomberg find the only Chinese supply
chain hacking story that wasn't true so
I'm up here telling you that it seems
improbable to me I'm not saying that
it's improbable that there are supply
chain hacking going on I would have to
guarantee there's that supply chain had
no no
but I'm questioning the details of a
story and how we should probably be
properly reacting to this so why would
they use a coupler the device that was
described as his little white chip that
has no place on a motherboard it belongs
on a network a Wi-Fi adapter or a
Bluetooth module or cell phone it
doesn't belong on a motherboard why are
there no first-hand accounts and if
there were even second or third-hand
accounts of it existing how come there
was no reports of what it actually did
what was the actual end cause did it did
it exfiltrate data did it steal data
didn't manipulate did it blow things up
and catch servers on fire we don't know
so the a in many apts
is often missing the advanced part right
is it realistic for us to assume that
the first half to the first Hardware apt
would be an advanced one so finely
polished and tuned that it's a custom
chip that was designed in a custom
package that was you know sneaked snuck
into a specific set of boards for a
specific vendor that's a bit of a
stretch for me
so joecraine had the greatest quote in
the article which specifically said
having a weld on nation-state level
hardware implant surface would be like
witnessing a rainbow rainbow jumping
over a unicorn jumping over a rainbow
right this is the type of stuff where if
they're actually doing it to this degree
you're not gonna find it and if you are
gonna find it it's not gonna be done to
this level of perfection so I want to
believe right from a technical
perspective this is so exciting to me
and I'm looking forward to the next few
months where people start proving that
all the technical details are possible
but I can't put any faith behind a story
and afterwards if you come talk to me I
have a bunch of stickers of this so ask
me for one of those so you may say I'm a
trainer I'm not the only one because you
will need to expect I know of at least
four groups of people who are working on
proofs of concept you will see them at
CCC blackhat def comm upcoming issues of
P or C or gtfo so keep your ears out
keep your eyes out for more details on
the technical side of this how is this
possible
how can we make it work but how did we
get here right this is still a little
bit hazy right earlier this year we had
Spectre and melt down they really
changed the landscape in my perception
of how we treat Hardware right this is
a hardware vulnerability but it was
software exploitable right that was the
big difference and this is the first
time we had a really like solid response
to a hardware vulnerability there's been
hardware vulnerabilities in the past and
they're sometimes BIOS updates and other
other mechanisms but spectrum meltdown
had this coordinated response from
nearly every operating system vendor at
the same time across multiple CPU
vendors at the same time all in response
to a hardware architectural
vulnerability this is different from how
we've treated Hardware vulnerability in
the past side channels between caches
and you know multi multi-threaded
processors have been known for over a
decade but only now is a big deal so why
do people trust their hardware because
they don't know that they shouldn't
they've never had the experience to
think that this piece of hardware is
actually mutable it's modifiable it's
manipulatable to the same way that our
layers of software are so the question
is would anybody listen if we didn't
have this choreographed disclosure this
song-and-dance website logo theme and
all that stuff would anybody pay
attention to these hardware issues I
don't think so but now that I have your
attention because other people have done
this let's talk about the right things
to do so a measured response means not
like reacting not doing a knee-jerk
reaction like actually having a logical
and well thought-out approach in
response to something that's happened
right so let's say you go to the doctor
you just read in the news that someone
died from cancer some person of I don't
know who woody and you go and you say
the doctor hey let's let's start
chemotherapy wait wait what's going on
it's like well I want to start
chemotherapy so-and-so died of cancer
and I hear that this is how to fix it
well why don't we you know do a physical
checkup see if there's anything wrong
with you as I go no no no I just I know
this is gonna fix something so let's
just do it well you know chemotheraphy
Swee don't even know if you have
anything that might be cancer we don't
know whether it's malignant or or
treatable or untreatable like you know
well then what can I do what can I do to
protect myself and the doctor would
probably say something like well you
know eat lots of vegetables exercise
regularly and stay healthy but no one no
one puts a lot of effort into that right
they want solution I don't think anybody
actually wants chemotherapy this is a
obviously a exaggerated example but this
is the response that people are having
to this kind of news right you can't
find something that's not real we don't
know whether this implant exists or not
you can look for it you can spend a lot
of times looking for it and lots of
money but that's only going to distract
you from the actual risks you need to
worry about right think of a hardware
implant as a complement at the opening
note Jeff Moss mentioned that at the
executive summit he heard like c-level
executives bragging to each other about
who got which apps like attacking them
which which nations were attacking their
companies which is a sign of how
important you are if you've got a
hardware implant in your system that is
a compliment right however if you're not
already defending against apts on a
regular basis and doing a good job of it
then you're not ready to worry about
hardware a PT's entirely different
league okay and so an effective attack
actually does something right can you
detect malicious software or news
network activity what I took away from
the the ant catalog which came out which
was leaked in 2013 is we had all these
examples of Hardware implants I'm a
hardware person and I think about how
everything can be done in hardware but
the hardware implants in the ant catalog
basically were hardware devices that
gave software access as soon as the
software took control it was a software
solution from that point on so if you've
got the infrastructure to monitor your
network monitor your software then
you're gonna detect something when a
hardware device goes and levels up to
that level of privilege they that's how
the hardware is going to do it so what
should we worry about right so you know
what are the big threats we've got today
we've got botnets with Dioses and mining
on people's computers we've got data
breaches we've got ransomware and and
crypto and somewhere and all different
variations thereof right all this
happens from money and disruption right
and the few other scenarios too but
hardware it has a couple specific things
that are unique hardware lets you bridge
air gaps so is there a way to make money
or cause disruption by bridging an air
gap that's when hardware might pop up
right hard
let's you persist wipes you can erase
the entire system and somewhere in the
hardware whether it's firmware or actual
like silicon or other additional
modification you can persist that wipe
that happen on a persist the wipe that
happened to that system reinstallation
of the operating system even reflashing
of the bios right this is a scenario
where hardware might be a rock an actual
threat right hardware lets you show off
your capabilities right this is that's
that corner case that's scenario like
hey if we wanted to just show off that
we can make this chip that is very tiny
and does things then yeah it's not
Trinity to show off but it still doesn't
make sense to go to that level of detail
and a custom-designed chip and a custom
package to just show off that you can do
it so a typical server will have about
ten or so components that have their own
firmware right this is an edition this
is not including the drives or anything
else this is the the the BIOS flash chip
you know the hard drive controller the
network control all these devices have a
little bit of firmware on them right in
addition it's going about have hundreds
of active components these are
components and whether they're doing
excuse me power regulation or logic or
anything else they are going to be
active they're gonna actually do do
things just switch switch current switch
signals or switch data right on top of
that you're gonna have thousands if not
thousands of passive components these
are these tiny little grain of rice
sized resistors that are just buffering
power that are that are regulating power
throughout the system so you've got a
huge surface to look at if you think you
really need to look down to the level of
finding grains of rice that are actually
secret active components this is an
image from a presentation again I gave
at blackhat USA two years ago the the
Dow of Hardware the Tay of implants and
this is a stack of Hardware implants
that I built and aside from the one on
the far right they all cost a few
dollars the one on the far right was
like a hundred US dollars the point is
like these are pretty hodgepodge wired
together things these are hobbyist level
but these are just as much a threat as
these grains of rice that we have not
been able to see so is it makes more
sense to look for something that we
can't see or look for something that we
can
so what can we do about it right ripping
up the servers is probably much a waste
of time
right do you have hardware acceptance
criteria when you order a thousand
servers or ten thousand or million
servers from a supplier do you actually
do any review of it do you actually have
any requirements about what that
supplier does and where they acquire
them even as minor as saying oh please
don't buy gray market parts that's a big
step that many companies don't even
bother or know to take did you look
inside these systems before accepting
them you know it doesn't it takes a lot
of work to find some of the size of a
grain of rice but if you open up a box
and find there's extra cards in slots in
your boxes that's a huge sign that most
people aren't taking the time to even
look right where did your hardware come
from right are you sure it actually came
from there right how do you audit this
right do you audit that the hardware you
accept is actually the hardware or you
ordered and did you order do you audit
that the hardware you order from a
certain source actually came from that
source these are important questions
that are going to go a lot farther and
actually being a rational response to
realization that supply chain
vulnerability is is a threat to you
right have you ever had this discussion
about supply chain security with your
vendors if you haven't yet don't waste
your time tearing servers apart spend
your time building understanding with
your vendors understanding of what your
requirements for hardware security are
and collaborating to make sure that your
future systems at least have a realm of
verifiability to them whereas the
existing ones perhaps do not so do you
consider a five dollar hardware
attacking your threat model the previous
example was that where there's gas
station skimmers right
five dollars of hardware stuck into an
exposed port on a gas station pump gets
some one value right does your threat
model consider 100 euro attacks right if
you have not yet done both of these
please do not waste your time with fret
modeling for 1 million dollar attacks
because you have to realize that what's
going to be the problem is is the thing
that's more likely right would you
notice a Raspberry Pi or an Arduino
stuck inside one of your systems these
are big you know development boards
these are off-the-shelf parts if you
don't have a mechanism for identifying
something like this then again you're
not making the right uses of your
priorities when you're looking for and
reacting to reports of other supply
chain issues so why even start looking
so what's the impact of an attack right
a lot of the reporting that happened in
the past two months pointed out that
basically if you have a hardware implant
it's game over
right and the issue is how common is
that attack right because our actual
risk is a combination of the impact of
the attack and the frequency of the
attack and so when we deal with more
common software issues the impact is a
lot lower but the frequency is so much
higher so we need to actually consider
the risk when we rate what's important
and what's not so what in summary right
hardware attacks are a real threat I've
talked about this many times for the
past several years so if you want after
the fact please let me know I can refer
you to other sources that will give you
details about what is possible from a
hardware perspective but you really
means remember you need to respond to
the threat and not respond to the hype
and that is what I've got for you today
thank you
we have time for question or any
questions oh it's fun so got a mic
coming I'm not a hardware expert not
even on my hardware implants anything
but to meet a grain of salt that or rice
that you're showing that you know
Bloomberg is showing really looks like a
register or something like that right
has anyone actually been able to like
take high-resolution pictures of those
images and take a look and compare it to
like existing pictures of registers or
diodes or same thing similar you know
shaped packages and say oh I've seen
this before
so there there's a very well understood
procedure for doing something like that
I don't know if that has been done or
not that's part of a fact that like even
people who've said that they've seen
these things haven't ever followed up on
like how they observe them analyze them
or anything so if I had one of those
devices you know I would go through a
process of you know basically a metric
acid2 to find the silicon inside or
x-raying it to find out the structures
inside to see whether or not it's just a
resistor or it actually as an active
device but again this specific device I
don't know I don't know anything well
we'll see I think very soon some
examples of people putting together
chips in a larger package that is
indiscernible from the naked eye but
would very easily be identified from an
x-ray or something else yeah look if you
think that it's possible for someone to
build this kind of device would it be
easier to directly inject in one of the
big chips some years that is already
malicious it's the same persons that are
building them so I'm sure you're asking
if it's easy to put like logic VHDL into
an existing chip yes versus modifying
another one
you know so the story described like a
multi-prong supply chain issue where
they they modified the motherboard they
modified the build materials they
modified the components right the thing
is any one of those things should have
been sufficient to get the job done like
the only reason they would do all of
them is if they were really like intent
on blowing money which is apparently not
odd for government agencies to do but
you know when you ask that the question
you're asking is it would it be easier
just to go and implant it at the silicon
level and you know an example the a
speed BMC right they're all sourced from
China they're all pretty much designed
in the same place so yeah it might
actually be easier to go and infiltrate
the design of a CPU like that just
because it's harder to detect and it's
all in one place so I'm not saying it is
it's totally possible though yeah all
right what's your take on the hallway
discussions that are going on with New
Zealand banning the use and the u.s.
banning in the UK allowing minute and a
while with Islam is a bit larger than a
grain of rice but nevertheless is it a
real threat or so my my sort of
tongue-in-cheek cynical reaction to that
so a couple years ago the US government
like asked said hi couldn't why wait
could not be used in any like government
and was not recommended elsewhere in the
US you know basically they're pointing
out that like they can't guarantee that
it's free from Chinese government
interference right it's interesting
because we see evidence that like every
government is doing the same thing right
different countries maybe have like
different legal systems and different
rules for that and maybe are more likely
just to disappear people than others to
make stuff like that happen but I don't
I don't see how that was any more a
statement about those companies than it
was about you know US companies or
European companies or you know Japanese
companies or Chinese companies so yeah
is my cynical response but that's time
I've got stickers and I'll be around
here or in the hall if you want asked
any more questions so thank you very
much
[Applause]