hello ooh a lot of people and thank you
very much for having me and I just want
to share my research something I
discovered and for me I find it really
interesting I will try very hard not to
bore some of you to tears and I but I am
going to be moving very very quickly
I've got way too much content just my
favorite little video it was rather
appropriate considering the the topic
right and I'm the global head of
hardware security and capability
development for IBM's x-force read I
didn't come up with that title it's a
really really big mouthful I spend most
my time creating capability hardware
capability offensive tools for IBM when
the consultants need some capability or
they need a piece of hardware that that
we can't get or is only available in the
dark web then I'll go ahead and actually
build it and my alias is the toy maker
simply because that's why I spend most
of my time doing and that's a lot easier
than simply you're spouting that long
title and some of the boring bits and
because some of the content I'm going to
be going through here is I believe it
would be irresponsible to tell you the
company's affected by it and any other
particular details simply because they
can't fix it with software they have to
re-engineer their product and as a
result the target component as you can
see is just going to be referred to as
component throughout the entire
presentation there are some company
names in here but they're not related to
the disclosure so to get on to the topic
I'll give you a very quick summary there
are some I think I'm popping a bit there
are some IOT manufacturers that are
taking a very serious action to make
sure that in the event of a software
compromise that the users privacy is not
affected and I think that's really
admirable so they're actually building
in hardware to make sure that on the
assumption that software can be hacked
when it is hacked the user still has
control over their privacy and
there's a particular component or series
of components that's been used to to
make this happen
I'm targeting one particular one in this
paper that or this presentation but the
same research they've done here I've I
have been able to apply another context
and you'll see what I'm talking about
but this product or this particular
target component just once again from a
disclosure point of view makes no
security claims it doesn't pretend to be
a security product this is all about a
circuit board util implemented so how
these products are being used at the
circuit layer and how you can manipulate
some of the physical properties by
finding a certain characteristics and
but before I get into the the fun bits
that's what I should do a little bit of
a recap security as a design problem we
we all heard here about sdlc and secure
software development but if you're not
familiar in 1970 the DoD commissioned a
report which was nicknamed or being
named the ware report and actually state
that you require as you can see a
combination of hardware software
communications physical personal and
administrative procedural safeguards is
required for comprehensive security in
particular software safeguards alone are
not sufficient I think the really key
part of this is this was in 1970 we're
still seeing in the industry a lot of
people purely relying on software
safeguards and if you've if your systems
are stuck behind firewalls in a data
center that's that's probably fine but
in IOT space embedded automotive people
have effectively unlimited access to the
target product in which case you need to
look at the holistic picture I'm a firm
believer that I'm not saying that you
should but anyone who uses product
should be able to publish all of the
information all the schematics source
code design documents about their
product and their product should still
be secure because it's been engineered
properly in the first place just a nice
simple case study this is actually nota
motive one the first thing we do in
Hardware Security's you get given a
product you pull it apart you find out
all the components anything that has
data stored on it you try and get the
data off we did this for a telematics
unit you know in a vehicle and you can
see the little flash chip over on the
side here and the manufacturer said all
that's fine yes you've got access to the
file system but what did you do how did
you do that so well we use a data man
reader and a flash chip socket and they
said well you know that's that's a
couple of thousand pounds that's a
little bit of a barrier I said it's not
a barrier we simply do it that way
because it's quicker so to prove a point
and now there's somebody in the audience
who's going to heckle me for this one
I'm gonna say I did it but that's
actually my wife because she's better
with a soldering iron than I am and
soldered seven wires on to the bottom of
the BGA chip and most people don't
realize that flash chips will actually
emulate an SD card if they're wired up
correctly so seven wires straight into
an SD card adapter stuck it into an SD
slot mounted the filesystem got past all
the software controls so this system was
well locked down had good software
controls but all you had to do is pull
the flash chip off to recover the entire
file system and a couple of hours and
Mego come on solar faster I want to get
on with this but that's just a classic
example once we had access to the file
system the rest of it fell we're out to
decompile you know java we're able to
get access to the storage any
cryptographic material and that was just
to prove a point
another very simple one this one's a
typical of security through obscurity
approach once again it's really
difficult because the the engineers the
electronics engineers mechanical
engineers always do such a good job
they're just not thinking like the
devious people we all are so we actually
explain to them some of the processes we
go about to recover and get access to
these systems it makes a lot more sense
so this one was a an atom based phone it
had quite good security controls in
place from a software point of view
again but I'm being a very impatient
person well spent about 15 minutes
trying to get past the software and
decided this just wasn't worth the
hassle so I simply pulled it apart a
little USB microscope and started
looking over the circuit board and I
found that there was a small cluster of
unloaded components so to cover a long
story short those components are
typically option resistors which is how
the developers choose whether or not the
bootloader is to go into development
mode or production mode so one by one
put one of these resistors on reset the
device and went round and round in
circles
I also found one I was pretty sure was a
serial port but that on logic analyzer
nothing happened the first few times all
a sudden I put on one of these
components reset the device and a load
of data spat out and it was I put it
into real term as you can see there it
was the BIOS boot screen so is the
entire terminal straight into the into
the back end there's no user name no
password on the control some once I had
that it's a little bit blurry but I went
in there and disabled you feel secure
boot then I once again I was able to get
access to the entire file system the
this was so easy because the parts are
so small that literally with a
screwdriver you could scrape the solder
paste that's leftover from the
production process to actually bridge
the part so once again with a
screwdriver is all that was actually
required to get access to this
development mode so as I said before I'm
a firm believer that security comes from
process yeah you don't choose security
technology you choose what your
requirements are first once you know how
you want to what you're what you want
your product to do how you want it to
function part of that should also be how
you want it secured then you can go
ahead and choose technology anyone from
an engineering background we all love
gadgets we all love toys something new
comes out let's use this to build a new
product that's not actually the right
way around so if you implement a proper
process and make sure before any designs
are done product requirements functional
safety security and bold obviously
commercial life cycle part of the
security requirements obviously doing
cover life cycle as well end-of-life
that sort of thing
so as I said earlier a lot of these
companies are assuming their products
will be compromised
so if you assume it can be compromised
design it with that assumption in mind
so for a traditional data system risks
will compromise are typically to date or
availability let's say for semi
autonomous systems or vehicles you end
up with a security risk that can
actually have an impact to life safety
risk
so if we look at the I Triple E guidance
on EMC and functional safety that's a
massive book but this particular part I
think is really really important warning
of a hazard is not considered a
substitute for guarding against it where
guarding against it is possible guarding
is considered no substitute
for designing the hazard out in the
first place where it is possible to
design the hazard out so you're talking
about anything embedded it's really
important where you can design these
hazards out don't simply tell people
about it so if we put this into context
with an autonomous vehicle telling a
driver they may not have control of the
car if someone was to hack it really is
not a substitute for guarding against
that in the first place
conversely you know adding edge security
devices is not considered a substitute
for designing the system properly so
that in the event of a hack that the
driver still has sufficient control to
control the vehicle safely and that's a
hardware design problem that's not
software design problem you've assumed
the software can be compromised
so I've done things with some automotive
manufacturers where we've redesigned
their steering controllers so that in
the event of a software hack the
steering the the controller actually
validates the human input over the top
of the software input so it's actually
relatively straightforward process so
now getting onto the topic this is the
bit which I get really excited about so
I had to get through the first bit so as
I said earlier some IOT designers are
taking really serious action actually
building in hardware so you imagine you
know their IOT devices where you've got
a mute button you've actually got a
button to mute and unmute the system
you've got laptops with LEDs at the top
to tell you when the camera is on these
are all things designed to make sure
that we are aware when our devices are
listening to us or watching us so some
of these hardware designs require as I
said a user to physically press a button
so I've implemented that not through
software they've implemented that
through digital logic and that's what my
little board down here is all about the
question that I asked them was you know
just use your logics floorless does that
mean your implementations flawless and
no it doesn't because of some of the
physical characteristics so if we look
at the failsafe logic itself now once
again setting a little bit of scene
there's a lot of technical content here
so I'm going to try and move fairly
quickly there's a this particular
component and is a very small mixed
signal component so it's like if you're
familiar with a tiny little field
programmable gate array so FPGA tiny
little thing it's you know small cluster
of look-up tables and some comparators
and a few other things but it's really
ideal for building these small state
machines in
so this is the development board and
just to put it into context you can see
the USB plug on the left hand side and
you can see how small the actual
component is it's tiny it's I think it's
2 millimeters by one and a half or you
know 2 by 3 something like that it's a
really tiny little component so this
development board and that that carrier
board I actually have that carrier board
plugged in to my target IOT device and
I'll show you that later on but that
little tiny component is actually the
the target of my research on this
particular instance so so what it does
this these mixed signal logic they have
a series of gates so you imagine the
whole thing is just a matrix you connect
columns and rows and actually form a
small circuit inside that and depending
on what you want to do you connect those
those circuit paths to as you can see a
lookup table that lookup table is
functionally a NAND gate so anyone
familiar with electronics is where what
I'm talking about and then you then
route the output so once these things
are program they can't be changed so you
actually defining this logic inside so
this is that's a screenshot from the
actual designer software so you can see
we've got some and gates so that the
blue the blue parts around the outer
edge are inputs and outputs you can see
by the direction of the arrows we've
then got the all the gray parts which
are the configurable logic so depending
on how the signals are actually made you
you simply draw and line you know draw
these lines throught this nice little
schematic and then you can test your
logic so the logic of this one is that
the user has to press the button to
disable privacy mode so the software can
put the system in to privacy mode which
is fine as in it can turn off the
cameras and microphones but the user has
to press a button to re-enable it and
that's done through the the bottom path
which is the the there's a button
debounce there's a latch in there and
some other bits and pieces and you can
also see that the privacy LED on the
right-hand side you've got camera
microphone gate enabled and then below
at privacy LED so they're actually
running separately which is really
important so that you know the the logic
itself because they might both run at
different voltages or different
characteristics and you might want them
want to be inverted one not to be but
those two are both actually run so in
the event that the camera
turns on the privacy LED because
actually two different functions so this
software can also turn it on and off if
it needs to if it doesn't have enough
reason to it but the minute you press
the mute button and the software enables
privacy mode there should be no way for
the system to listen to what you're
doing or see what you're doing without
you pressing a button so said this is
the this is the bit that gets a little
bit dry so I do apologize this is a
typical data sheet this is a data sheet
from one of these particular products
anyone involved in hardware security the
first thing you do is you go to the data
sheets you have a look see what the
manufacturers say the actual tolerances
are see what the voltages are anyway
when I was doing this research this was
many years ago the first thing I did was
look at look at this and I saw a ball
there was there was a couple of gates so
there's a couple of gates in the chain
one particular gate if you see here in
the middle at 3.3 volts the center
column there to change from a 1 to 0 or
a 0 to a 1 takes this these little gates
15 nanoseconds that's pretty quick but
one when you add them up to change from
1 to 0 to back to il-1 again that's 30
nanoseconds all of a sudden that little
gate can only handle 33 megahertz so
you've got total bandwidth of 33
megahertz and I started thinking what
happens we've got two of them together
what happens if I go above that
frequency then these things are not
designed to go quickly but they're
connected to a very powerful processor
that can make these changes very quickly
once again a little bit more context so
I do apologize about this with any any
electronic component this manufacturer
didn't take any manufacturing there's a
manufacturing bell curve in the data
sheets they say typical so typical is
that redline that's where most things
should actually work then you've
obviously got the low end of the
spectrum you got the high end of the
spectrum with these sorts of resonance
attacks you will find that you made it
depending on what sort of voltages you
can get out you may find that your
attacks work on typical and below but
won't work on the higher end because of
thresholds are slightly different
there's a lot to actually consider but
because this is all about manipulating
physical properties you have to
understand exactly what you're looking
at so once again you can get these
manufacturing bell curves and these
tolerance curves from the manufacturers
so if you're trying to do one of these
sorts of attacks it's you characterize
you
target you then go through and find all
the data shoots from all the parts and
actually put together a chain to work
out best and worst case so without
boring your too much the that's this the
the picture I've reproduced it again and
then underneath it this is a very very
simple logical version of what I've got
my little board here so you've got the
microcontroller you've got that logic
and you can see a little physical button
there and then there's a load switch now
the load switch is simply to turn the
USB power on and off because I've seen
these some of these systems where they
actually have a USB camera and
microphone so they simply turn the power
off because they think they're doing the
right thing turn the power off you can't
hack if it's powers off which is which
is really good so they also turn off the
the data but that's controlled the same
way so my objective is or was can I turn
that load switch back on through
software even though the hardware the
hardware's there to make sure that no
matter what happens to the software
unless the user presses that button the
camera and microphone should stay off so
obviously I wanted to understand what
happened so as I said earlier my
question is what happens if I exceed the
bandwidth so what happens if I start
sending a signal out that's faster than
what this little chip can actually
handle so some sciency stuff really
technical and an inductor is a small
passive electrical component that stores
energy in a magnetic field more from not
it's just some copper wire around a some
sort of ferrite core or something like
that and I put all the equations at the
bottom because I thought they look cool
and they made a slide look really cool
and there's a lot of maths behind it and
it's that's really dry and but we'll get
onto some of some more sciency stuff
exam really creative in my lessons my
slide titles and don't a voltage Delta
time so anyone who deals with
electronics is aware of the fact that a
1 and a 0 isn't actually a 1 and a 0
when you change from a 1 to a 0
there's the infinite ranges of voltages
in between as the signal actually
changes the rate at which this change
happens is called Delta voltage over
Delta times how fast the voltage changes
over the period of time so the the top
on there shows you obviously time and
voltage so if you look at a simple clock
signal it looks like a 1 and a 0 and in
software it is a 1 in a 0 but the
electronics has to change from a 1/2
zero if you zoom in on an oscilloscope
and actually have a look at any clock
signal you'll see something more like
the one at the bottom where they're
actually on an angle so in when you're
designing products for EMC compliance or
whatever else you need to slow those
curves down because every time that
changes you get a small amount of
emissions and to get those emissions
down most EMC electronics designers will
actually slow those curves down mostly
thio t products they're not designing
for that purpose so they have really
really sharp edges and it's actually
those sharp edges that cause the problem
that's what I've actually well that's my
theory anyway so we'll get on to a
little bit more context an analogue
switch is like a relay except there's no
no parts so it's an electrical component
that allows electricity to flow either
way when it's turned on and when you
turn it off it stops so when I was
mentioning earlier about those and that
matrix all those little points where the
columns and rows join is actually done
by an analog switch now analog switch is
really important it's not a digital
switch it's an analog switch that means
it allows ya analog voltages to come
through now more electrical stuff once
again really created with my slide
titles and a charge pump a charge pump
in electrical terms is where you have a
signal that's changing rapidly and
you're actually able to use that signal
to charge capacitors via diodes etc and
reach a higher voltage and that's
actually really important there's a
parasitic charge pump in some of these
systems that if you keep the these these
systems moving fast enough you can
actually reach a high voltage internally
then they're expecting so back to the
essentially a scope trace just to show
you and the blue and the yellow are
actually in millivolts and what are they
I think they're 20 millivolts per
division so they're tiny little voltages
and normally if you're looking at system
you wouldn't see these it's only because
are specifically looking for it the
green is actually on five hundred
millivolts per division so that's that's
a clock signal now on an oscilloscope I
noticed that when the clock signal
changed and this was under normal
conditions if I captured it correctly I
could see a very small output following
so through this logic system I noticed
that there was a small very small output
that followed on the edge so as you can
see green goes up the yellow and blue go
up that's
to the outputs from this particular
target device when the green goes down
blue and the yellow go down but they
going below ground it's not that's not
that's not a digital signal that's an
analog signal and well that's really
interesting so once again you have to
have an oscilloscope to find this so I
used a signal generator and then I
started to increase so I set the signal
generator up to be the same
characteristic same impedance as the
processor and I started winding up the
frequency when you start to approach the
resonant frequency of this of the
particular target the amplitude goes up
so you can see the first one I think is
a bit hard to see from here it's it's 20
odd you know 22:03 megahertz
22:52 megahertz and you can see we're
starting to form a sine wave and you can
see the amplitude is going up this one
is twenty three point three six
megahertz and it's near as matters a
perfect sine wave so we found the
resonant frequency of that particular
target so at that particular that at
twenty three point two three six
megahertz that target was actually
resonating so those tiny little signals
that were earlier on we're just in
millivolts and if you're doing a normal
logic design you'd never notice them
because your scopes not even haven't
configured it to capture that you hit
the right frequency constructive
interference and you start in this
resonance then we go above it we're at
two twenty three point nine megahertz
and the amplitude is dropping off 2300 a
twenty five point nine and it's really
starting to fall off so once you've
modeled the the characteristics you can
start to find the resonant frequency and
then of course what we need to do is
reproduce that so we have a quick look
at the the target that target is here on
the board or sorry on the table so
standard sort of IOT device but rather
than having any Wi-Fi or anything else
this is literally just like a test the
AC characteristics of it so I simply
include a USB to serial interface
normally that would be a Wi-Fi module or
something how you talk to it is
completely irrelevant and we've got the
switchable USB so the actual block in
the middle the purple block is this is
the actual target component and we've
got the microcontroller in the middle
this just happens to be one of the
microchip MIPS cores and then the
component interface because this
components so small and I can't solder
it not without using pick-and-place
machinery so it's a lot easier when you
you can program them once you program at
the
bring the carrier board across so the
fact that I'm using a carrier board as
opposed to the chip directly on there
changes the AC characteristics and it
does make a small change but the same
thing happens if the chips directly on
the board is just a slightly different
frequency so it's a matter of finding
that frequency so that's that's the
picture that's the little board which I
designed and loads of test points so I
can see what's going on and you can see
the little carrier board sticking up
from the right there I put in those
those switches those dip switches so I
can turn on and off the signals from the
microcontroller I can also include some
slow rate limiting resistors in the path
to show that simply by putting a
resistor in line actually solves the
entire problem so it's that it's
connected to the PC that's the same
docking station and I've got here so we
go through that and you know that's the
little board we've got the FTDI chip for
providing a us a USB to UART interface
we've got the mips core we've got the
component adapter and we've got the
switchable USB so that I can reproduce
the reason I did this is so like we can
reproduce this attack without mentioning
any of the products that are actually
vulnerable to it because like I said
that would actually be responsible
because the only way they can fix it is
to redesign it so anyone else can
reproduce what I've done I just simply
did all using harmony literally pick the
chip pick the framework you know went
through and configured all the bits I
wanted to do so there's nothing there's
there's nothing particularly clever
about this and use their configuration
tools to configure the the processor
turn on the framework turn on the serial
drivers turn on the console so basically
using existing framework to build it all
the other reason I did this is that this
is a very common approach you see a lot
of people building IOT devices much like
this because the frameworks like
fantastic they make it easy why write
all this code yourself when you can take
a few boxes and it generates it all for
you it's another reason I did it this
way so you can't really see that but
that's that's my console handler so I
had to write the write that bit itself
but there's a buffalo cated on actually
made say on stack I didn't proofread
that properly and and then there's a in
the middle boxes the you are afraid so
that's a that's a function provided by
the framework to read the serial buffer
if you look at this
code itself it's an unbounded right so
it's an unbounded right to the calling
functions stack so you've also send in
the wrong payload or whatever else like
actually overflow the calling convention
oh they're calling function stack get my
remote code execution which is how you
can actually make this this sort of
attack happen once again this is just an
example this happens all the time and
when you're doing code reviews you see
this sort of stuff yes you can fix that
but the assumption is is that the
software can be hacked so I'm just
literally put that in there for that
purpose and that's the the dummy IOT
interface that's just a little a little
terminal and I'll show you that and in a
little bit and that just allows me to if
you can see that enable to turn the
power on or off so enable or disable the
minute privacy mode is enabled that
stops me from turning the power on and
off because until the user presses the
button so basically the software can
enable privacy mode which means the
software no longer has control over the
power the user has to press a button
from the earlier logic which then allows
the software to actually yet turn the
power back on and I think that's that's
quite straightforward you can't disable
privacy from there so what about you got
is a little video here simply because
this room's very wide but if I've got
time afterwards I'll do the same thing
on my I'm like computer right here but
this is Jo so everyone can see it yeah
is that gonna start yes okay so I'll
just talk through this that's that's
just a hand tech USB oscilloscope I've
got the two traces and this including
the autofocus thing it's a little bit of
fun so I'm trying to set this up
properly now on the device itself you've
got the power LED as you can see down
the bottom there there's also another
LED that says when privacy mode is
disabled so that means that the system
can potentially be listening to oh I'm
actually talking through here as well
I'll just mute that so if I press the
button itself as you can see from there
you can see that second layer actually
turns on so that's a fairly typical sort
of you know workflow you press the
button to unmute the system then says
I'm potentially watching you or
listening to you and to simulate that
I've got a USB light
here as well just to show you once again
all I'm looking at his peril not looking
at the data and and you can see on the
oscilloscope that the yellow and the
blue voltage both went up so the blue
voltage is at 5 volts there and the
yellow voltage was that I think three
point three which is the target voltage
so then with the software I can enable
and disable it at will so I skip to yeah
okay so if I actually run the the
exploit you can see that now all of
sudden well that's just because the
earth probe fell off you can now
actually see that it's not a one or a
zero and if you look on the left hand
side you can see where ground is it's
actually above and below so there's
actually the resonant output by find by
sending in the clock signal at 70
megahertz the yellow line is actually
oscillating that oscillating has a
charge pump effect which actually turns
a system back on once again you should
be able to see that that shouldn't work
and if the frequency is wrong you barely
see a glitch you get exactly the right
frequency and the entire thing starts
oscillating so I've got a few theories
I've said I'm not a hundred percent sure
as to what's what's causing it there's
probably gonna need to be some much lot
of people than me looking at the problem
to identify exactly what's causing it
but it's really easy to solve so it
doesn't really matter so if we look at
the edges you know the green clock
signal goes up the output goes up the
agreeance clock signal goes down the
output goes down so this means that
there's a distinct coupling between the
input and output signals on the edges
and only on the edges when the privacy
hardware is operational the faster
that's the faster that slew rate or
faster their change in voltage in volts
time the larger the output is so this
tends to indicate a number of different
things
now I've had lots of discussions with
lots of people including some RF
engineers who came up with some other
potential theories for why this is
happening
so I'll included all the theories that
I've heard so far and I think honestly
it's probably a combination of them all
so I talked earlier about an inductor
just being not much more on a copper
wire that stores energy in a magnetic
field so this one if you look at my very
early diagram
the analog switches join effectively to
two or three or four lines together that
is by pinching an inductor depending on
you know the path if it's actually
looping round back on itself that's an
inductor then you have something called
parasitic capacitance which is the
natural capacitance that any component
has at a certain frequency
you put those two together and you get
what's called an LC circuit an LC
circuit has a natural resonant frequency
so that was that was my initial thought
but the actual resonant frequency of a
circuit that small is going to be up
into the gigahertz and I'm nowhere near
that so that could be part of it I said
I don't I don't entirely know this is a
my theories but the it's possible that
the parasitic capacitance of other parts
of the board how it's how it sold it on
etc I've reduced that frequency quite a
bit and an RF engineer said to me and
that he thinks this might actually be
partially an RF strip line he said you
might beginning reflections so at the
right frequency effectively ending up
with either end of this this small
inductive loop at you know at different
voltages and you do it fast enough you
end up getting RF reflect reflections I
thought okay that that might make sense
once again if you get them at the right
frequency
coupled with everything else and I think
the main thing is is that there's
there's parasitic capacitance on the
inputs and there's also a ground bounce
if we hit it exactly the right frequency
I think the parasitic capacitance and
the ground bounces we're driving this
chip so fast that it's actually bouncing
above and below ground therefore the
outputs are simply following it and as
it's all analog switch basis we end up
with this AC signal coming out and the
observation that I noticed is that the
capacitance does change the resonant
frequency so if you touch part of it the
resonant frequency does change so it
does very much indicate that there is a
capacitance there if you change the
decoupling capacitors on the thing it
changes the resonant frequency that
doesn't stop it but it simply changes
the frequency so I think there's a lot
of going on so just going back to the
slide again as you we approach the
resonant frequency the amplitude goes up
we end up with a near perfect sine wave
certainly for this purpose you can see
it's not a perfect sine wave for anyone
whose particular detail focus it's
pretty close
so the next part I needed to understand
is why is this turning on the USB switch
when the USB switch says it requires a
minimum voltage to actually enable the
the output so I started looking through
all the data sheets and of course the
manufacturers aren't going to tell you
exactly how their chips work internally
but with my best judgment talking to a
cup of engineers as well we came up with
a number of different simulation models
that we thought were pretty close they
had the same basic characteristics as
what the data sheets were describing
when we actually modeled and this is
just one particular one you can see the
the green trace along the bottom when it
starts resonating we actually end up
with the the parasitic capacitance of
the gate of the FET at the top actually
playing into effect of this we're
actually charged pumping that capacitor
so the switch the logical switch the FET
at the top has a its gate has a
capacitance in it we're actually using
that storing energy and slowly pulling
it down which is where you can see the
the purple signal yeah they're purple
signal so as we reach also and we reach
the on threshold so we're charging it
frantically if we keep charging it comes
down then when it reaches the on
threshold you can see the red line all
the sun starts to go up now if you turn
this on normally that red line would be
near as mad as vertical and that blue
line would come all the purple line
would come all the way down but because
of the characteristics we're using that
the charge pump effect we can turn it on
slowly while relatively slowly from the
time you actually start the attack to
the time this turns on it's still only
five microseconds so it's still still
pretty quick so that was all research I
did without using the software that was
a signal generators and everything else
although this is an interesting
characteristic it's not really very
useful unless it can be done by a
software so then of course how do you
actually get these exact frequencies out
of microcontrollers etc so this was a
software exploit fir for one of the
versions of this board most of the
microcontrollers if you familiar with
them they have had this processor core
they then have peripheral hardware they
have you know output comparators all
sorts of analog lovelies and they've got
pulse width modulation Hardware all that
stuff turned on or enabled the exploit
what it needs to do is to turn on
this hardware so he turns on this
capability adjusts the relevant divisors
and then you get exactly the right
frequency so as long as your clock
signals 50% duty cycle and you can get
the right frequency purely using the
hardware so the CPU core is not actually
involved in this all it has to do is run
this code configure the peripheral
hardware and then your away so I've come
across some of the CPUs where their
actual GPIO s can only go to 25
megahertz and I like what our CPU simply
can't go to that but what you can do is
you can drive two signals out of phase
to each other and you can double the
effective frequency so there's all sorts
of funny things you can actually do to
actually you don't have to have a
perfect sine wave you can find the
writes of a combination of input signals
to these devices you can create the the
AC signal with a high enough RMS above
ground to actually turn these systems on
so once again once again this is all
based around the assumption that the
software has an RCA of some sort which
is the assumption that these products
are being built around hence they put
the hardware in so turning that into
assembly language and thirty-two
instructions 128 bytes of code if you
can inject that into a buffer overflow
like I showed you earlier on you can
configure the hardware the system can
continue running as normal you've simply
reconfigured some of the peripheral
hardware to enable this exploit the
output stays on but the LED itself never
comes on so the user is completely
unaware that the system has actually
enabled the camera microphone or
whatever else so this particular device
here I captured it on a scope and set
that the triggers up properly and you
can see that once again the the yellow
signal the voltage at the bottom that
says 1.3 volts that's not correct that's
just because I had to design the time
base out so far it's about 750 million
volts something like that but once again
you can see the the output actually
drops slightly because of the charge
pump effects are actually pulling the
whole system down slightly below ground
then we charge up the output sorry we
charge up the gate capacitor on there on
the high side FET and also then it turns
on because it's quite a slow turn on
anyone who's familiar with electronics
that's quite slow but it's still turning
on within 12 microseconds and that's
quite a that's quite a slow slow edge
it's not all as bad as it as it seems so
we we just summarize it quickly
you've got the change in voltage so the
rate of change of voltage has a big
impact on this so that main means it's
actually really really simple to stop if
you reduce the speed at which the
voltage can change this attack goes away
altogether
and that's part of the problem that's
why it's unpatch well you can't do that
through software because if you can
change it through software it can be
changed back through software all you
need to do is actually put it in just a
simple resistor in line with all of your
logic signals going to and from any of
these devices just like you would with
software your software controls I was
validate your inputs hardware needs to
validate the controls from other parts
of the hardware system make sure that
the maximum input frequency of your
devices is it here too so if you've got
a really fast CPU like the one I'm using
here that can generate these signals
make sure that anything it's talking to
you validated those inputs you've slowed
the signal down so that no matter what
the software does it simply cannot exert
that level of control so going back to
it the purpose of this hardware state
machine in these designs is to make sure
that when the software on the main
processor assuming it can be hacked to
make sure that the user still has
control the risk is that these these
designs because their logic is flaws but
the implementation is not that the
hardware actually serves very little
purpose it's good it looks good it's
nice really fantastic these companies
are building it in and they should be
commended for that the problem is that
software can manipulate then they view
spend the time and actually understand
the target every model of device would
have a different resonant frequency
every manufacturer would have a
different resonant frequency depending
on how they've designed it but once
again once somebody did the research and
actually targeted these particular
systems it's just a matter of doing a
simple software exploit to actually turn
this back on so there is some stuff we
can do through software
I said software alone can't mitigate it
which is true but there is some things
you can actually do now depending on the
the the processor etc so there's nothing
we can do about the silicon level stuff
because that's outside of our control
anyone doing hardware design you have no
control over what the companies are
providing to the faster the slew rate
the faster the change in voltage over
changing
the greater the output amplitude we can
do something about this simply put a
resistor in line now in production these
you know you're going to talk fractions
of a cent cost differences it's
completely immaterial if you do it when
you're doing the design if you wait till
after the design you have to do a
reengineer it gets very expensive it
probably ends up tens of thousands of
times more expensive if you could simply
adding these parts is at the design time
that there's no cost to it to speak of
now see oh I just dropped out then right
as the signals that are under software
control and you can do some hardening
depending on the processor that you've
actually got so I'll talk about there
this particular MIPS one so if you do
some hardening and make sure that some
of the hardware security capabilities
are turned on now the really obvious one
is on this particular chip you can make
sure that those pins can only be changed
purpose once so if they're being set to
GPIO you can say do not allow these to
be turned to an output compare all
pulse width modulated pin later that's
fine for the RC e running in this
instance but if it's the persistent RC
and you can actually restart the device
then that doesn't serve any purpose but
it's it's a countermeasure it can help
it's all about defense and depth try to
make the thing more more difficult the
other way to do it once again is a
redesign issue on the microchip parts
they call them are Pepin's as in
remappable pins you can change the
function but there's a lot of pins that
are not remappable so if there's
something particularly
security-conscious that you want to make
sure can only go at certain speeds and
no matter what the issue don't use a
remappable pin if it's remappable then
it means it's got this put this
additional hardware connected to it that
you can change through software so you
can see here I've just picked a couple
of pins
you know the RPM means that this is port
e so remappable and it's and it's bit v
you don't you don't want to use that if
it's particularly critical the pins in
green they're not remappable well
technically they are you can see there's
analog there's a parallel port and
there's GPIO stuff on there as well so
you could potentially remap that just
those pins into the parallel port and do
something similar with DMA but once
again it makes the thing more
challenging but there's always ways
around it the simplest one is to simply
add resistors inline and to show that
was again a really really simple
simulation so if we
Shoom a parasitic capacitance on the
defect gate of say five Pico farad's
which is fairly typical for some of
these peach and fats you can see the the
the blue signal you can see we're
getting a nice nice large amplitude the
minute you put a resistor that are 1 in
line the amplitude drops that little
green trace that's all it is it's as
simple as putting a resistor in line to
change that slew rate so that we don't
end up with same amount of current going
through to effect this charge pump so a
summary of all of this some of these
some do say some some of these
implementations are vulnerable to
resonance attacks there's a lot of
characteristics but than any sort of
side channel it's all about
characterizing the target if somebody is
used a particular component with a very
high logic - abling it that may not be
vulnerable I haven't researched all
these options but I'm not going to say
they all are because that would be
completely irresponsible and a lot of
the modern systems on a chip or
microcontrollers can generate signals
fast enough to exploit this behavior I
said even if the front side will only go
at just a 25 megahertz by running two of
the pins out of phase to each other you
can actually generate their right sort
of signals that you're looking for you
can also do some funky things with DMA
and actually changing the tri-states as
well so you can float pins and pull them
back down to end up with some of the
doubling effects the other thing is to
use the one time configuration fuses if
they're supported so if your chip has
the ability to set some of this stuff up
in you know permanently then use that
capability because if you don't use that
capability somebody can actually exploit
this through through you know through
software now I'm gonna try I'll put them
onto that one but I'm going to do this
first it's gonna pong and bing and if
anyone wants to come have a look you're
welcome to get my mouse working oh and
of course it's suspended well that's
going to slow things down a little bit
but what's that's resuming does anyone
have any have any questions whilst I try
and set this up wow that's quiet
either everyone's asleep so bored you
all or no one once asked a question is
this like wait waiting for a kettle to
boil it's not even that big a virtual
machine
hello sorry have you looked at the power
output of the circuit while it's
resonating in terms of emissions so does
it as at resonance also have higher
emissions yes I could tell you about
something about the system yeah actually
that's a really good point and I did
notice whether I used a waveguide
antenna as with an SDR and a spectrum
analyzer and when you actually hit this
resonance you do definitely see a spike
at that particular frequency and
obviously I don't have the equipment to
see exactly what's going on inside the
chip and exactly it's sort of the area
around that particular component is
definitely resonating at that frequency
yeah on the spectrum analyzer it's quite
loud there's a wouldn't be a good way to
explore this a bit further alright let's
see if it just will work and see my
little scope on stress no I don't want
you're going to feel scream can somebody
please tell Microsoft to stop doing that
all right
and I thought it would be a good idea to
show this live what I Muppet and
and connect that one alright alright so
we got that there oh is that connected
yes okay so if I press the privacy
enable button you can see that this
light here turns on so that's simulating
the USB power side turn around so you
can see that's on try not to blind
anyone if I tell the system to disable
the lighted turn off so I saw a
reflection online oh it's not turning
off but it's a light over there so I can
enable and disable it from here and you
can see the scope traces behind me are
going up and down as well so if I enable
privacy they go down and obviously the
the software itself says privacy modes
and they will be you can't do that but
the actual logic in this little device
here guarantees that so now yeah where's
my little program connected jolly good
ok so if anyone wants to see the privacy
LED is off saying that the system cannot
watch so I can try power on power off
nothing's happening if I then do the
resonance exploit the lights turn back
on and you can see the resonant signal
you can see the signal at the bottom
though that is enough to create this
charge pump effect to actually turn the
system back on so you can see the lights
actually on I can then clear the X point
and if I turn on measure one source one
just look at peak to peak so I'll go
back through it again
press the button
okay and Paran it's really hard to see
that that's actually on from here it's a
power on and power off and you can see
that that's all working there so I'll
enable privacy mode again and turn it
back on and you can see we've got peak
to peak of 785 millivolts and you can
actually see it's actually slightly
below ground but that's enough to create
the charge pumping effect actually turn
the system back on and that's purely
through software okay and most people
still awake Wow thank you very much for
having me and I said it's just some
research which I find fascinating so
hopefully of interest to you all as well