hi everyone thank you for coming and
Netanya our talk we're going to talk
about container security and how we can
reduce the attack surface of containers
and go beyond the standard namespace
isolation so this is a joint work
between Accenture lab and Stony Brook
University and these are the people that
contributed to this work there's myself
there's Jay who's present here they
we're all part of Accenture Accenture is
a consulting company but they also do
research so we're part of the tech lab
of Accenture in a past life I used to
work on mobile security I worked on car
security assessment and also cloud and
binary security under DARPA and I our
patented projects and lay used to work
on document classification machine
learning and Nicolas is a is an
assistant professor at Stony Brook
University in the computer science
department working on system security
and in the past life we used to work
together in this you know research
funded programs and I'll let Jay
introduce himself hi everyone my name is
Jay currently I'm working in the
container service reduction project with
Saladin and previously I've worked on
the blockchain security and industrial
control system security so I assume if
you're in the audience you probably want
to know about container and you know
already about it if you don't I have a
container 101 which we'll go over
quickly if you already know I apologize
and if you don't know anything about
vm's I don't have a one-on-one for VMs
but basically the main difference here
between virtual machines and containers
is virtual machines can be thought of as
a completely different system where the
instruction gets translated by a
hypervisor and they have their own
kernel the downside is that they're very
heavyweight they require a lot of
resources on the other end of the
spectrum you have containers they're
more lightweight and docker is the most
famous one but under the hood there's
LXE there's a bunch of other
containerization technology that could
be used the biggest difference here is
that you can have a host that shares the
kernel with multiple containers of
course there's some insulation
properties that are handled by the
kernel and it's done through namespaces
relation memory space resolution and all
these things
why containers right what does it
actually mean and what are the
advantages of using containers so this
is a this is a great picture that I have
not done I took it from the Microsoft
website that's where you can see the
Visual Studio development lifecycle but
I thought it it was very abstract enough
that it got the point across on how
people use containers in CIC the
environment without giving too much
details about it so the way people build
containers and it can vary right they
can be different instantiation of this
workflow but people build their
application they you know whether it's
Java Python however you want to build
your application and then they add
docker to it once they have added docker
support for their application and will
go back on that one after they're on
their application they run their test
Suites and that's where the CI CD you
know loop happens if the application
behave as expected and passes all the
tests in your Jenkins pipeline then it
gets pushed into production or it goes
back to the developer and the developer
has to make changes to this to the code
or the container support but really the
key problem when people are building
containers is in the second step so the
way you add containers you know
container support your application is by
using a base image the base image think
about it as your operating system for
your container once you have this
operating system you can actually build
and deploy your application in it
it's a copy-on-write file system so
every changes that are committed on the
file system will make a layer and then
that becomes your image and then your
image could get pushed to your
enterprise repository and that becomes
your image the problem in this loop is
that sometimes people they build a
container and it has all the
dependencies for specific application
but they overload the container image
they build a lot of other dependencies
so they can just use these images of
drop-in replacement for other
applications and sometimes they rely
straight on public images which we'll
see after have a lot of vulnerabilities
as well so this is really where the key
of the you know the source of the
problem is so now if you think about a
couple right let's let's be even more
abstract you're a couple you live in a
Great Neck mention I don't but if you do
that that's great
but let's say you have all these windows
and you have all these doors that that's
a lot of entry point for a burglar
right somebody can you need an alarm
system you need sensors you need all
these things unfortunately that's the
state of containers and application
today there is a lot of unnecessary
pieces and we want to D block this house
I guess and in that case the containers
and we want to put you in a tiny house
that will suit your need and if you're
probably I need something bigger than
that but let's assume you're happy with
this size house and you have only the
things you need hopefully by reducing
the size of these containers or this
house you'll have less entry point which
means less vulnerabilities and if
there's less code it's just a numbers
game right less code less bugs less
vulnerability ideally that's the
expected outcome so we had a hunch when
we started this research right so we
were using containers for other purposes
right not necessarily doing container
security research and we pulled images
that were six hundred Meg's one gig and
there's no way you need like one gig
from my sequel or any other type of
application right so we decided to look
into how people are actually building
containers and if you remember before
this is the step to when people are
docker to it so when you build a
container image you start from a docker
file on the left-hand side of this
picture you can see the first line from
with which is basically you declare your
base image what is going to be the
foundation on what this container image
is going to rely on and hear you say
that basically you want to bun to 16 to
be your base foundation okay there's no
way you need all bun 2 to run a specific
application right you should be able to
tailor it and trim it down to actually
the pieces that are required for this
application to run and then you declare
a bunch of environment variables
commands that you run into containers
you can see the run up get so all of
this operation until we reach a command
will basically be written on the
committed to the file system and that
will be part of the layer and on the the
upper right corner of this picture these
are basically all the layers that
composes this container image and this
is this is really the problem that's
where the problem starts so
we had a hunch and we decided to to look
into actually you know like everything
when you do research you need to ask
yourself is it a valid question is there
work already done in that space and is
there something we can do right can we
improve on the situation so we have a we
have actually looked and analyzed some
darker epazote so that's not the focus
of this work but we we literally pulled
all the container image across version
since the inception of docker hub and we
decided to pull some statistics out of
it
so on the right hands on the left hand
side you can see all of these packages
so these are the top ten vulnerable
packages some of them have literally
thousands of vulnerability for what it
means is if you have a lazy developer or
not so careful developer that would just
pull some images and run them into
production
you're gonna inherit the cost of
managing fixing or patching or
containing these vulnerabilities on the
right hand side these are the most
vulnerable package that are used
currently it's not as bad a left-hand
side right left hand side or probably
older versions but if you look on the
right-hand side so these are more recent
versions and you can see that they still
have double digits vulnerabilities so we
looked into that you know after that we
this is addressed some some other number
and I'm gonna just display this picture
for for a little bit and let it sink in
for you so these are the top at the time
where we conducted our experiment these
are the top 20 docker images in use by
the on docker hub so this means that
these are actually probably running
somewhere in production and we did
really something very simple right we
automated the pool of these containers
we deploy them into an environment and
then we assess the vulnerabilities using
clear which is an open source scanner
and you can see that some of them have
literally triple digit vulnerabilities
and you know and we'll see after that
the size is pretty big for what it is
but this really means that for us that
there was a need and something we knew
that we could do something in that space
and and really there's a need nobody
should be managing maintaining and
paying for you know these
vulnerabilities when you can just get
rid of them or at least the hope is we
can get rid of Master
them and focus on actually the pieces
that we care about and now I'll hand
over to Jay and he's gonna tell you a
little bit more in details about how we
can address this issue thanks Ali with
all the issue that with all the voting
issue that oscidyne has mentioned as a
security researcher we went to diverse
solution to mitigate the problem so we
tried so we want to deploy this protein
image the concept of container is that
each container should be designed with
single purpose and similar to the for
that philosophy in Unix each container
should only be designed to execute one
task and only do one test that we do
that for example a container with
webserver shouldn't be a database in the
container which they shouldn't be a file
file server however most of the or a lot
of the containers we see today are built
more like a virtual machine maybe
because of the legacy issue how they
convert a virtual machine to a container
now a lot of containers actually contain
a lot of unnecessary package or or
components and when you add these
unnecessary components and packaged into
your container image while they are not
doing doing anything for application
they introduce a lot of vulnerabilities
and thus the texts of the enlarged
attack surface of the container image
with all this problem we we are
proposing a methodology a two-stage
methodology to create a more secure and
lightweight container image in the first
stage we want to profile the normal
workload of a container once we
understand the normal behavior of a
container then we can use the profile to
build another
smaller container image that contains
only to function that this application
really need so I so at the end we will
have a smaller container image with and
hopefully with less molar
vulnerabilities to profile a container
is not too different than profiling UNIX
or Linux application we can do it from
either users base or kernel space
however we prefer to do it in user space
because it is not always possible to
make change to the kernel space one way
we can do it in user space is using the
system code code fan notify to get a
callback for any file system activity
including the file open file close or
file read or file write very simple in
user space and another way we can
profile a container is using the library
interposition so light library
interposition is a very cool technique
that allows us to instrument any
function in any library however before
you can instrument any function you need
the the prerequisites that you need to
know the simple name of the function and
another concern is if you tap in if you
instrument a function a very busy
function or if you instrument too many
functions at the same time it can cause
a lot of overhead and impact the normal
performance the normal behavior of the
original application and in terms of the
networking activities they are also made
multiple options that we can tap into we
can monitor the the the networking
activity of a specific container on the
left on the top left side top left hand
side we can
again use library interposition we can
tap into the function that you like
chili beef library in the container
itself and for networking activity we
can tap into the connect asset or pine
network networking related functions to
see the networking activities we can
also tap into the networking interface
eth0 or eth1
directly inside the container or inside
the container and networking network
name space and we can use act we can
actually round like TC to attack TCP
dump directly in the specific narrow
space and another option is to actually
tap from the host itself in terms of
attacker they usually create a bridge
between the container network namespace
and the host network namespace and we
can tap into that bridge on the host
directory and see all the traffic
between the container and and the hosts
to recap our methodology we want to find
a way to profile a container in user
space we can use either library
interposition or leverage the existing
system called API to get event
notification and there is a limitation
so in our first face that we have
completed today is that we can profile
an application using these techniques
and based on the profile we can build
another people that reduce the image
that can support only the functions
observed during the profiling process
however there is a limitation or a
container is as good as the profiling if
there is anything that we did not
observe during the profiling process the
deposit that reduced container will not
be able to support those function that's
why we we are aiming for them in the
second phase we want to do a
genius monitoring in production and
provide a continuous refinement for the
deposit image as well now I'm going to
do a quick demo to show how our
container D protein technique can help
reduce attack surface of container and
this is a live demo I hope you can work
this looks better so the specific
epicness a specific container
application I'm using today is worpress
so i'm start i'm starting the war press
up a patient normally in trying to load
this load the web web page then there
were is there will be slow here and okay
this is a homepage and i'm going to look
at adam insight and one thing i want to
point out here is the plugin in the
wordpress container now there are
currently three proteins and none of
this protein are actually activated
however we know there are no funner
abilities in this protein and i'm going
to show you that even without this
plug-in activated we can still exploit
this vulnerability so in this terminal
I'm going to run a simple command to
leverage a vulnerability and upload a
script file that allow us to explore the
container file system so now I have
successfully upload a file
next I will try to access this file from
here so this is a script that I just
uploaded and with this script running
basically the attacker can do anything
in the container download edit or delete
any file and any command can also be
wrong here so we see the
the issue here and next I'm going to
show you how our deporting methodology
can help mitigate the issue so I'm going
to run I'm going to start a container
again but with our profiler running in
the background so I start the container
again refresh let me go back to the home
page and why I'm doing now is to
simulate a system that mean and suppose
there are only few few features few
functions that is sittin at the mean
actually need in the admin site so
trying to log in it's a very simple
password and let's assume that all that
mean care is to see if there is any
update in this website and if there is
any post from the guest and let's assume
that all the admin care about this
website and now let's look at what
output not terminate the profiler and
look at exactly what profiler has
created so this is one of the output
file of the profiler in this file it
shows all the files that the container
has touched so it started from the
Packer entry point where the container
start to the point where the WordPress
application actually wrong without the
PHP for PHP file being assessed and
with this profile we can now build
another reduce or deported image that
hopefully contains less vulnerabilities
and with less component in it so I'm
building the image now here we go the
the image build less than a second ago I
actually want to show the size okay here
we go
the size is eighty nine point one
megabyte it's called WordPress our edu
reduced version comparing to the
original WordPress container which is
four hundred and seven megabyte we have
approximately 80% of a size reduction
and now let me try to run this reduced
version to see if the intended function
still work go back to the home page
it'll be slow but loaded successfully
login so the admin page is still there
and let me see if I can still check the
update yes and let me check if I can
still read the post yes but now let me
try to do some abnormal behavior if I
want to activate one of the protein it
is not working because we have remove
the function needed by this by this link
or if we check the users no longer
available and I'm going to show let's
write the same exploit again the result
is 4/4 not found this is because during
our D protein process the vulnerable PHP
file has been removed finally I'm going
to show a cup of a comparison
the vulnerability before and after our
deporting process so there are 180 a non
vulnerabilities in the WordPress
container and after the deporting
process we have zero number of
vulnerability don't be too excited this
is too good to be true and there's no
way we can remove hundred percent of the
vulnerability the reason is that during
our deporting process we also remove
some of the components required by the
vulnerability scanner to identify the
installed package and the
vulnerabilities so that's what happened
not I mean we are not saying that we can
remove 100% of the owner abilities and
with that having impact as a teen to
talk more about the detail okay so a cat
must have died somewhere because our
demo worked so somebody made a sacrifice
that's good thank you
now if you if you guys remember what we
said before about our top 20 docker
images we actually we actually applied
the same method the graph is not as ugly
as it is here as it is on my screen but
you'll have to trust me on that so
basically here we we took the top 20
docker images that we've had before and
we've run them through our the blotting
process and and here are the results so
I'm just going to give you a couple of
highlights so the light blue bar I
notated at the top it's the original
size of the container if you look at the
green bars this is the reduced size this
is after we've processed them and you
can see there's a significant size
difference and then the dark blue bars
are the original vulnerabilities and
then the the red bar which you cannot
see because there's zero or the reduced
vulnerabilities right so I'm I'm not
selling you snake holes right it is it
is not possible to achieve zero
vulnerabilities and now we're going to
expand on to why this is happening but
across the board we've observed an
average size reduction anywhere between
60 and 90 percent depending on the
application and we've observed
by our own tests right about same thing
60 to 80% of vulnerability reduction not
100% but it's still a decent amount now
let me let me explain you why we have
zero vulnerabilities and why if you run
that at home you probably are going to
end up having zero vulnerabilities as
well so you guys are not familiar with
overall definition so it's just a way
some UNIX or Linux distributions are
sharing information about the CVE the
severity the package name and which
version of package or packages are
affected by a certain CD and this is
what you know and this is how vulnerable
T scanners are working most of them they
rely on some information about the Linux
distribution or the package manager that
handles it so if you use Ubuntu or
Debian it's apt if you send to s its yum
and then it tries to cross check and and
you see by cross check it's very it's
very shallow what they're doing they try
to identify what you have installed on
your system with what is actually
presenting this over all definitions and
sometimes it is as shaky as a regular
expression right so they they tokenize
the the entry into the the package
manager list of files that are installed
they extract the package version the
name and then based on that they match
it with a novel definition okay doesn't
take a genius to understand that these
kind of tests are not very accurate
because if you've installed something
outside of your package manager it's not
going to be listed there if you change
the file or if you don't have the same
file that is described in the overall
definition again it's gonna fail so
again this is a I think this is a
research so we can its own but we did
our best effort and we actually tried a
lot of leading security container of
vulnerability solutions not gonna
mention any names but I'm sure you've
used them if you use containers but
really what these tools are creating
today is a false sense of security right
you try you test you assume that your
image is clean or clean enough to be run
in production but the reality is you
cannot really trust these tools
and these are just some of the examples
right if you you know for some reason
they don't work with fedora or Sue's
package manager they just can't detect
some vulnerabilities and I say when I
say must it's really must not all of
them but close enough and if you have
malware into your image right you'd
think they would pull some hash from
virustotal or something to assess them
no they don't they really just rely on
package manager and oval definitions and
now let me tell you how you can be a
talented hacker in the world of
containers just change the file name all
of them do not detect it seriously I'm
not kidding it is that sad but basically
this is the problem right the the way
these container testing tools are
working is very simple and naive and
there's a lot of ways to bypass them I'm
sure the bad guys figure that out too so
we presented you a solution right where
we actually look at the application
running within a container identify the
components that are required for this
application to perform and strip down
the rest right and if you're in a you
know higher functions I guess and you're
close to the corporate overlord you can
see how it is a problem right so our
corporate Overlord we're like there's no
way we cannot change the containers you
cannot change the structure and
everything that is hash based is going
to be an issue so you need to find
something that actually works for us so
what we did is okay instead of removing
everything if you know that all the
things that are required you can just
generate a whitelisting policy and
that's a way it's a cheap way to contain
the vulnerabilities because they cannot
be exploited because you have a policy
that denies access to these functions
and I'm sure you're aware of mandatory
access controls right so the only
problem right is when you do if you guys
have tried to write SELinux policy or
up-armored you can you can see that
there's a lot of issues with the special
files right proc if you want to read
some kernel exposed information in user
space that is an issue how to write
policies you need to be it's a little
bit tricky there's a runtime overhead
the more rules you have and if you write
them naively
I mean if you have a rule that applies
to each files instead of having a rule
that applied to the directory and the
sub components that also generates a lot
of overhead so there's a there's some
tweaks and optimization that you can do
but the bright side is you really have
fine-grained control on the operations
that run within your container you can
you know whitelist file and and we'll
show an example you can grant
capabilities and also your corporate
overlords are happy because the
containers hasn't been touched the
hashes are the same and you've
maintained the integrity of whatever
container image you were working on and
this is just a recap of the the type of
permissions that you could enforce with
Mac and and the interesting one is the
capabilities right you can limit also
the capabilities that you offer to an
application and today we feel really
lucky because we're gonna try again
another live demo and hopefully it
doesn't fail
so I'm going to drown around the very
similar demo again but with the only
difference is that this time we were
used mandatory access control policy to
secure a container instead of actually
remove the component inside the
container we will be around the same
container but instead using the same
power file we will generate a set of
policy to limit the file access
permission inside the container
so I'm against starting the container
with the profiler running in the
background and I'm going to simulate the
normal the normal user activities again
we first look and log in again and I'm
going to perform the same to two
functions that the system that means
suppose only need check the update check
if there's any security update and check
the latest post from the guest and local
that's it suppose these are the only two
function that the system that emitted
mean neat I'm going to terminate the
application and the profiler and show
you exactly how the profile look this
time so again this is one of the profile
that generated based on the file system
activity this time we collect a little
bit more information we also collect the
file permission and also the the type of
access previously we can when we do
protein and a container a file is either
available or not but this time when of
all the files are available but we can
actually provide more granular control
to each specific file we can specify
specify if this file has read access
right as as executable access memory
location or linkable access so which
policy we can create more granular
control to each file and with this
profile we can generate a set of policy
that I will show you next so this is
basically the policy that why list the
files in the WordPress container and
this policy basically will only allow
the
the function that we observed during the
profiling process now let's run the same
container application again with this
policy deployed in the kernel know the
home page and login and let's see if the
intended functions to your work check
the update check the post and let's see
if we can do any user check any user
know the page is not available and this
time we get a slightly different error
message instead of saying for for not
available this time we get a permission
denied because the file is still there
but we simply enforce the policy to deny
the access to this specific file and
similarly if I try to pour the same
attack the same exploit again I'm
successful and we get a different error
message failed to open stream permission
denied again the files are there but our
policies this file simply is not in our
pie list
okay let me get back to you as a team
okay so we've just shown you a demo
right two demos the first one is think
about it you're running an application
and you have dependencies in that case
that was plugins but that could be you
know libraries sitting on your system
shared objects that are completely
unnecessary for your business purpose or
your application purpose yet you're
still exposed to a lot of
vulnerabilities and potential compromise
for something you actually didn't need
and we showed that removing all the
things that are not you know whether its
components whether it's files we removed
all the things that were not used for by
the application you actually reduce the
attack surface we reduce the number of
vulnerabilities and as a you know right
side down side you reduce the size of
your containers but this is really
coarse grain operations right we're
removing binaries by binaries I mean elf
files or Exe if you're using Windows but
what happens when we actually you know
when you actually need to run this
application but the vulnerabilities are
still within the application itself and
let's assume you you know you also don't
get to the source code now so this is
the application layer and you know I put
this little surgeon picture because this
is really like surgery and it's more
fine-grained than working with the
containers themselves and you know if
you think about container I mean if you
think about containers and application
today there's a lot of bloats and I like
to think as them as being a very fat you
know containers applications there's
really a lot of things you don't need
right this application today like I
don't know I think Facebook is 400 mega
on iOS or something that's ridiculous
right you don't need that much for
web-based application that's another
story anyway there's a there's always
gonna be bugs right in application and
and if you look today the leading you
know the leading cause of system
compromises bugs bugs gets exploited
through buffer overflows and Rob gadgets
and all of these good things and of
course there's a lot of initiative in
that space you know patch Tuesdays and
you know updating your system and
and package manager to make sure that
you have the latest and greatest
versions but really it's not enough
because you know the attackers might
find before you patch the application
and of course if you look through
history right through smashing the
stacks return to leave see and Rob
gadgets you know the technology evolved
and there's a lot of mitigation
strategies that are applied and that are
working very well and put you know the
script kiddies at base but there's still
talented people that can exploit the
application and in terms of attacks
right there's a there's application that
simply overwrite a return address and
you can return to leap C and execute you
know we prep the stack and you return to
certain functions that you care about
there slightly and of course in that
case you can you can target functions
that are not used by the application or
even better if you guys are not familiar
with return oriented programming it's
basically a way to leverage the code
that resides within the application
binary so you disassemble your
application you have a bunch of basic
blocks basic blocks are basically
something that finished with a return
instruction that allows you to set the
stack and call up you know call
arbitrary functions and set the stack in
a proper way so that you can pass the
arguments you care about and of course
same thing as before there's a there's
techniques right address space
randomization there's a control flow
integrity the shadow stacks there
there's a lot of techniques right in the
defensive sides there's also a lot of
talented people that can bypass these
techniques so what we think about what
we did before why don't we apply the
same concepts to an application
you know it's sounds intuitive right you
take the application you look at the
functions that are used and you simply
strip them out
I said simply because binary is a little
bit tricky right there's a lot of
offsets and things that you need to care
about if you do it statically but if you
do it at run time think about it you
load a lot of library in the address
space of the process you can null some
you know memory pages that contains the
function you don't care about and you
know if the exploits are actually
leveraging functions that the
application doesn't use then the
application you know the exploit will
break but this is this is all you know
all type of attacks
these days it's more you know all the
hype is wrong return-oriented
programming and gadgets right so this
type of attacks will still succeed even
if you remove the functions that that
are not used by the application and
there was some work that was done
previously to remove these functions so
that's the if you think about their
level of granularity that's you know
lower than what we presented before but
that was cut stripping and cut stripping
says the same thing it basically removed
this function these symbols from the
other space of the process here what
we're doing is we're looking at gadgets
and the way they're built they only
leverage a couple of critical functions
so these functions are still required by
the application to perform so cut
stripping is not going to work so what
we're doing is we enforce something at
the API level API I mean you know
windows 32 API and so this is the case
that this is something that we call API
specialization and the threat model is
we assume that they have full function
reuse they can do everything and our
main goal here it's to really restrict
how the API will interact with the
operating system and you know if you
think about virtual lock or and protect
or malloc if you're using Linux we
really want to enforce how these api's
are used and make sure that an attacker
because the attacker side is using the
same functions but with different
argument right you may you may allocate
a memory page and mark it as readable
but the attacker will use the same
memory page but market has writable and
executable so these are the same
functions so cut stripping doesn't work
you will need to enforce how these
functions are called and the type of
arguments that are passed to these
functions and this is you know very high
level functions if you have a Windows
binary so this work was based on Windows
oh and by the way I'm channeling my
inner mikelis because that was a most of
his contribution in that space so you
have an application Windows application
most of them will map kernel32.dll into
the address space of the process and if
you look at the button on the right side
of this picture we're using only four
functions right but because you're
mapping kernel32 in the address space of
the process you get access of you know
you and an attacker get potentially
access to thousands of functions but you
really need all of that so this is
really the case for API specialization
that we're making here and this is a
simple study right we look at these
windows for it to api's or DLS however
you want to call it and we looked at the
number of functions they have kernel32
of course being the biggest offender
Etta's provides a lot of features and
support for the you know windows
application has 1900 functions and then
we looked at the application and how
many functions were they actually using
within these libraries and you can see
that VLC only needed 38 functions out of
1900 and if you look at a TV API for VLC
they needed only two functions yet
there's 900 functions loaded into the
address space of the process again it
makes no sense right
if intuitively you don't need to
overload yourself with all these
functions when you can strip them down
so what we did is we want to create a
you know specialized version of this API
and then for some policy on it and what
we did is we looked into all these api's
and how they're used across you know rap
chains and exploits and we've identified
52 what we call you know security
critical API functions right such as
virtual so that's the equivalent of an
protect malloc and connectors connect
everywhere and the goal here is we
analyze how the application is going to
do in third you know the arguments for
these functions and ideally and most of
the time actually the malicious
application right the exploits are using
the same functions but in a different
way with different types of argument and
of course you know that's that's the
main intuition behind this work and you
know hopefully that works but spoiler
alert it does that's why I'm here but
the idea is that this approach should be
we want to work on binary we don't want
to do live profiling as we did before we
want to do something completely
statically because if you if you're able
to observe the argument then that's it's
not cheating but it's easier so to speak
it's a best-effort approach so if we
cannot infer the arguments that
for a function we're not going to try to
enforce a policy on it we only enforce
the policies of the arguments were able
to identify statically and then of
course you know like any technique right
now it looks great but maybe tomorrow
someone will find a way to bypass it but
that's you know that's the game and
that's why there's a conference every
year in security and the idea is that
it's it's lightweight enough but it also
can be alongside other applications so
it's a two-phase approach basically we
take the application binary we
disassemble it we extract a control flow
graph which you know enables us to see
all the basic blocks and we identify the
call sites for the 60 to critical
functions that we've identified once we
have that we do backward slicing and
we're able to infer the argument on the
stack that are pushed to this
application and then we generate a
process wide per function policy which
means that we enforce a certain behavior
for specific API calls and then at
runtime it's your you know your
classical library interposition and we
leverage something from microsoft
research so what does it look like in
practice so this is basically the same
as before but in picture in case you
don't know how to read or you didn't
like my explanations but basically we
look at the intersection of the critical
functions and imported functions by the
application we identify the call sides
and this is the argument right this is
ideal scenario you have all the values
that are pushed on the stack prior to
invoking D you know the API calls of
course many times it is not possible and
we can't infer a policy for specific
functions but every time we can infer
this arguments we're gonna enforce it
and some of them will be determined at
runtime and that's fine as long as we
enforce part of these arguments that are
called for this API call so the
prototype we have is Windows based no
secrets we're using Ida and and the
enforcement is done with detour so if
you guys never used it or never heard of
it it's a I'm not sure it's I don't
think it's open source but it's free to
use for academic licenses and basically
what it does is that every time you
enter one of the functions you care
about it inserts a trampoline
instruction and then it drops to your
own implementation so that's a very nice
way of doing library interposition on
binaries for Windows because there's no
LD preload on Windows and for
so these are the results so we we took
251 shellcodes and 30 rock payloads that
applied to you know common application
the we took 10 what we call popular
end-user programs and that you're going
to see the names right it's zip VLC
crawl man and things like that so that
is it's real work right we can it can
actually work and the main results as I
told you so it improves slightly for
shellcodes
but shellcodes will use functions that
are not used by the application right so
the improvement is is minimal here
however if you look at ropes ropes chain
will use only one or two critical
functions but it will use it very
differently and it has a very negligible
overhead and this is just a graph of
these results so we used chrome edge
Firefox and a bunch of other application
so this this is actually working on a on
a real application that you may download
today so we call this API specialization
shredder so that's a that's a best
effort software reduction attack surface
reduction tool it goes beyond the simple
code deep loading to API specialization
we really believe that it's fine you
could load you could have multiple
instances of kernel32.dll memories cheap
you know we can we can store many
version of that DLL and load them into
the address space of the process it
relies on static analysis and then the
policies run force at runtime so
whatever we can infer at you know
statically we do it and we enforce it
and of course the major improvement is
unwrap chains as opposed to you know
shellcodes so now it's time for me to
conclude so we show we showed multiple
approaches to reduce the attack surface
right we looked first into the coarse
grain approach for containers and
container image and really removing all
the binaries and then we targeted
something a little bit more fine-grained
where we look at the application and
what's left of it
and the main takeaway here is that you
know whatever vendors tell you whatever
solution that you read you know software
solution or security is really a defense
in that solution there's nothing that
fixes everything you know I know some
people believe appliances will fix
at the network layer some people that
sells API solution will tell you just
protect your ideas and you're all good
but really security is a defense in that
solution and really all of you guys
whatever you're running today your
attack surface is too big and your
security team is too small right so and
if you look at all the techniques right
incident response and all that the
biggest problem is reducing the noise
with this you can literally reduce the
noise because all the alerts or
everything you you get is going to be
targeted to your particular need and the
functions you're actually using so
containers are still good right not
saying containers are bad and that talk
containers are great for DevOps they're
great for agility and deployment but
again the problem is the really the sad
state of the testing tools today that
really gives you that false sense of
security and there's a lot of things you
could do right and and I know and I'm
sure in the room people say oh you can
just use Alpine you know from dockerfile
yeah great Alpine still has a lot of
dependencies that you don't need for
your container and for those of you who
don't know Alpine is just a lighter
operating system that contains less
blood than others that really container
should be built as a single purpose tool
and they should only have the things you
need for your application that's it you
guys have any questions I think we have
time no no sorry no we don't have time
[Applause]