hello everyone thanks for coming I'm
twanda ting front ensign security SRAM
lab and they are my colleagues wei wei
and ji pung-ho
so the colorful paper asked us to submit
a cutting-edge research which is exactly
what we did so it's that easy so this is
our first time here at blackhat we are
here to talk about internals and when
abilities of Microsoft web browser so we
all work at Tencent as security
researchers jensen is the largest social
media and entertainment company in China
and to better understand the threat
landscape and protect our user data and
infrastructure tenzin security lab focus
on applied security research in both
software and hardware in 2017 we
participated in the pendulum contest and
is the winner of Microsoft edge category
where we also have prepared for Pantone
2018 to place in March this year however
for regulatory reasons we could not
participate instead we reported the
vulnerabilities we discovered to nsrc so
this talk will be based on the versions
of Windows 10 when the vulnerabilities
were first discovered in the next 50
minutes we will first take a dive deeply
into Microsoft edge architecture
internals we will discuss the browser
startup sequences and how add device and
sawing privileges after that an overview
of address IPC mechanisms and finally a
detailed walkthrough of our bugs were
prepared for pound two on Microsoft edge
is the default web browser on Windows 10
Microsoft says it is the faster safer
way to get things down on the web it is
a universal Windows platform app and
more on that later it became one of the
targets of the county-owned contest
since 2016 Universal Windows platform
apps or uwp apps are built with Windows
runtime a vis or
we are TLP ice which was introduced in
Windows 8 we are T is layered on top of
with 2 AP ideals from the security
perspective you WP apps bouncing a new
type of sandbox called app container app
container introduces many isolation
technologies such as securable object
restrictions object namespace isolation
global accountable restrictions and has
the you IP i and network network
isolation all these isolation techniques
used the app containers load box token
for access checking the Lodox token was
also introduced in Windows 8 it has
three important logical members
integrity level at container set and
capability sets or uwp apps runs at low
integrity level and has a unique set and
a list of capabilities windows use these
members to determine if a new WPF has
access to resources such as internet
microphone or clipboard for most uwp
apps one app container is enough this is
true for other pre-installed apps such
as calculator naps or OneNote however if
a new WPF wants to further lock down the
security it can also create another type
of F container called child app
container there are many operations that
requires permissions not available in AB
container such as reading or writing
user files or accessing the clipboard so
Microsoft edge needs brokers for its
privileged operations
this diagram illustrates the
architecture of Microsoft edge
the manager process with process name
Microsoft edge exe is responsible for
managing the renderer processes and
implements basic functionalities of the
browser the manager process runs in a
tab container in fact it is probably the
only browser with with its main process
running in your app containers and docks
there are several different types of
renders in Microsoft edge they are also
called the content process with process
name Microsoft edge CP exe and running
as a chart app containers of the manager
process browser broker runtime broker
and shell infrastructure host all runs
with normal user privilege
therefore they can perform privileged
operations for Microsoft edge now we are
going to talk about startup we are not
going to cover every detail when we
really care about is what privileges are
send to each edge process especially the
internet a see the manager process is
the first to start a the process it's
responsible for creating child processes
let's see how it starts like traditional
win32 applications double clicking or
desktop shortcut starts direct but
instead of directly creating new process
explorer.exe since the activation
request - as I host the exe as a host
gets the request at the door to launch
Microsoft edge and the activation
request will be sent to our PC SS
service there are pcs s will use
Activision information to create a
container process family or manager
process it started by the RPC SS where
those are pcs as guest activation
information from the information isn't
starting in registry
it's dynamically loaded only if needed
Activision information is stored in your
packages directory under program data
each apps activity activation
information is stored in your staff
directory named by packages full name
your file named activation stored at the
file would be loaded into registries
through NT loader kex the data structure
a similar would calm for example to
active makers of that I'm sorry sorry
Oh
okay no tickets data structure similar
with home for example to activity
Microsoft edge we can look up the makers
of the edge key under activity bill
class ID here the activation height is 1
which means out of process activation
the server Vario because the server name
we can get the executable path of the
store they look up the server name under
the server key which is Microsoft edge
the exe after getting the activation
information our pcs will start process
creation the most important scene of
creating up continual process is to
create a low box token first a package
each seed could be calculated from the
package family name second care
Templeton seeds for the process then
create a low box token
finally create process with these low
box token
where does the competitors come from
we know each UWF has a appx manifest.xml
which defends the needed competitors and
there are two special cases the first
one is a capability to access the
package itself generated by package ec2
package can be detected the techno one
is cellular beta it's all computer to
access
cellular network our phone which was or
Windows Phone feature now it's counting
the processing time contain the process
is or child ever continue process there
are many types of content the process
for different jobs but their startup
sequence are almost the same Microsoft
edge would create content the process
with restricted name from 0 0 1 to 1 to
1 because it is also an ad continual
process in all the center the creation
requires to remember when hamburger
we use the package seed and the campaign
a seed to create a low box token which
is also called oh I see token here the
it will transfer the talking and the
creation request to as I host as I host
will register the token with our key CSS
and request it to activate finally our
content the process is studied by our
pcs the talking of child of continual
process is created England hamburger and
hamburger get activation information
from Microsoft edge
for example talking of manager process
under the restrictive name then
generates or new at continuous seed
through a very long name foundation the
driver restricted F continuously from AB
continously than restricted name next
random broker care to the competitive
seeds from Microsoft edges through comb
Quebec and creates tokens of account in
the process
up-up contingencies is calculated from
Texas A&M used shuttle in this example
the manager process seed is at the top
the seed in the middle is from the
Chateau of zero zero while the child
said is a combination of parent seed and
the structure of rejected name which
became the seed of internet AC the
candidates listed on the air are child
processes competitors they are not
stored in register instead they had
coded in each binary in this example the
child has computed access location
printer clipboard and more child
processes with restrictive name larger
than zero seven one will have two more
candidates the private network
client-server and enterprise
authentication okay whatever we try to
find a box for in a complex system the
first thing we need to do is looking for
attack surfaces this divides directions
and the scale of our research everyone
knows IPC components most available to
privilege escalation box so let's look
at the IPC mechanisms used by Microsoft
edge there are three types of IPC
mechanisms used by Microsoft the
action-rpg come and LCA IPC we will go
over usual our PC is an inter process
communication mechanism it will ask land
and a server to communicate over several
protocol sequences such as a RPC named
path socket and the more and many more a
server interface will be bound and
opened with the suppressor file protocol
a calendar can access the interface with
its identity RPC server can use
security descriptor to control access
permission of independent it can also
use interface the security callback
function to check the permissions of
Auckland
there's many RPC service in Windows some
of them are accessible in a container
sandbox my use case of RPC is a
Microsoft artist jet engine the internet
evangelist and JavaScript code to jet
engine who are RPC for completion the
jet engine will reply with the generated
machine code the second a widely-used
the IPC mechanic mechanic technology is
calm windows news is come to implement
active X control Microsoft Office also
users come to implement a compound
document come has become the foundation
of Windows it is widely used to in
Windows share components and the service
components because it provides a secure
reusability secure ability and a
solution there are two types of consoles
income imposes come which are
implemented in your deal and auto
process come which are implemented in an
executable file for the security
prospective we are more interested in
Auto possess calm because the rainy
different security context and may have
more permissions than AB container they
open the app or a larger attacker
surface for sandbox process to lunch now
actuate an auto process comes over the
class comes Branton will send a request
the two system actuator that addressing
our pcs s our pcs s we are forced to
check a clearance permission the natural
actuators associated a server
reverse all stars
we are registered as class and the
interface information with our pcs is
next
obviously access will return the
information by the token and the client
can cover more information about the
server such as our PC and appoint family
the client could directly communicate
with the server where our PC come has
defined the multiple security settings
in the registry system rather security
settings controls the default lunch and
access permission and the code level
capable security capabilities for
consoles process process why the
security settings are supplied by
console at random every common local
server can has its own app ID key in the
registry there are two way of seeing the
key to define the launch and access
permission console can Coco initializes
security explicitly to override the
default permissions
otherwise the kamerun term will
implicitly coedes
with registry settings during
initialization as a remission earlier
RPC SS is a responsible for launching of
activity in consoles our pcs as check if
Clint has lunch or activation
permissions
buying lunch or actuation allow the
function lunch means to create a new
instance of Aucklanders over activation
means create a new object existing store
access permission is checked by chrome
runtime at the server side the
interfaces security callback function
registered by console is used to for
checking calanis permission Microsoft
edge uses an auto process comes over
called
Mme broker to create a dictionary and
the words
the third type of a PC used by Microsoft
edge is al CIA PC loosely covered the ie
was introduced in Internet Explorer 8
it isolates ran dollars from manager to
improve reliability performance
performance and scalability because LCA
IPC uses shadow memory to simulate to
Windows messaging it is also known as
shared memory a busy during the manager
initialization LC ie map a PC creates
name destructions through creative Val
mapping the renderer and a broker rather
to our read from the shadow memory
through US Open File mappings after
sending a message an event is asserted
to notify the target of processes there
are three types of shared memories
messages intrastate scope trusted there
are others are untrusted renderer
process has no permission to write
messages into the trusted scope in
manager and the broker sensitive
functions check the message attack if a
message is untrusted it will not be
handled this prevents untrusted precise
from Cohen sensitive functions the
trivial use case would be Randall adding
URL and the Pharaoh account to managers
history after use navigation
rhiannon ran Delaware Piper website a
URL as an LC a valid message and Sunday
to the manager manager gets the website
URL from untrusted scope zone Daniels is
far away Farrakhan and Adam to history
I became the target of Ponta Wong in
most bugs used in the contest memory
Corrections by the way prefer logic bugs
we think they are most nimble more
generic and most importantly lack of
attention encounter on 2017 we used a
logic bug to escape the sandbox we are
the only team that used logic bug to
force sandbox escape here is the
voluntary taser we use it in a contest
browser broker browser broker is an
important part of Microsoft edge and it
is a lot of process comes our new entry
in medium integrity level to perform
operations that are not permitted in our
container since like launch Internet
Explorer instance open a folder and sing
on the manager process belong to the
browser broker with calm activision
using clsid browser broker the manager
process long change to the server and
get an interface for access the broker a
calm interface could be matured into an
object rich and pass it to another
context of the manager gets the
interface in order mature each turn of
the wave and send it to other processes
you with CIA IPC
objective reef is the name of structures
of matured interfacing calm this is an
example of a much older browser broker
interface it's a block of memory that
starts with signature meal it's all
standard a brief is in the facilities
are eyebrows or broker factory and it
has o ex ID or idea and the IP ID with
all the information the can be emotional
back to our interface pointer in
another context well content process
starts in order Michelle and get a
browser burglar interface this is how
calm interfaces are transferred between
different Microsoft edge processes here
Islam browser broken structure manager
process long chains and install a
browser broker and cinder the browser
broker to each count in the process in
the long chase contain the process can
access the browser broker and call
interface methods but not so fast most
of the methods has accessed checks to
limit operations or child process can
perform before we talk about the exceed
check here is the description of any
process integrity level we know Windows
has integrity level such as low medium
and high and all app containers are low
integrative but in order to limit
privilege privilege a demon father age
also has its own integrity levels this
is related with restricted name for
example the internet AC process is
integral in a greater level each one
which means an are easy now let's go
back to the access check there are three
different type of access check first is
trusted is only which means only trusted
every container could call is for
privileges measures such as long Hawaii
second is everyone it's basically means
no access check so is all of container
accepted zero zero two measures like
endocrine disorders from attackers
perspective almost every useful method
would check for trusted AC but what
instructed AC trust the AC is not
hard-coded it's registered through
request
broker method manager process long chase
the browser broker and the course
request broker to initialize it which
means trusted AC is always always the
manager process request broker is used
the tool register app identity
information such as AB container seed
application name and location it can
only be called once by the manager
process so the content of process could
in the cause is measured
let's look at the browser broker design
again do you see something strange why
should the way follow the way that is
supposed to be using the design assumes
that content the process couldn't launch
a browser broker but is this really the
case by looking at the launcher
commission you can see application
packages is allowed to launch and
activities in Microsoft's official
document implementing an app container
it says to allow all up containers to
access all results and the application
packages seats to the ACL of a data
resource now the vulnerability is very
obvious also an Internet renderer
couldn't access sensitive Master has a
unique system browser broke her amazing
amazingly it is allowed to launch a new
browser broker if the render then kills
request broker with the Internet ACC the
internet AC would become attracted AC to
the new broker and the renderer could
call almost all broker measures now we
only needed to find a measure to escape
the sandbox for example we could call
the launch a method to launch Internet
Explorer with control document but there
is an easy way this method is called
right class of category it codes notice
a single possible SP friend deal for
this process from the name you couldn't
know it allows a deal in to occur in the
process it opens or hard-coded the name
through our application directory to
build the do pass and guess what the
application directory global variable is
also set to request a broker during the
initialization so now we can load our
custom deal into browser broker
these are the steps first drop a
customer model the deal to our edible
directory next activate a new browser
broker and the request broker with the
Internet is a succeed and the ratable
directory picks finally to the red cart
of category method and we are out of the
friend box
how did Microsoft fix this the launch
permission of the browser broker has
changed now only the manager process is
allowed to launch the browser broker in
fact starting from Windows 10 RS to
restricted app containers are no longer
allowed access objects labeled with all
application packages Microsoft did this
by adding a token attribute got no all
application packages and we introducing
a new group called all restricted
application packages is this the end
and guess who comes to rescue here
Adobe Flash Adobe Flash used to lift
away on well for rich content gaming
animations and media of all kinds
it is pre-installed on Windows starting
from windows 8 well this is a brilliant
design decision because it significantly
reduced the time between user installs
the windows offering system and see a
flash based ad last year
Adobe announced that flash will no
longer be supported after 2020 and will
be replaced by html5 adobe flash player
was also interested in integrated into
Microsoft edge and enabled by default to
face out flash Microsoft edge start
limiting Auto wrong it implemented a
click to wrong mechanism Iran's Flash
Player
in a special renderer called BC host as
mentioned before it is also a charm app
container the internet render cannot
access flash so attackers cannot exploit
flash vulnerabilities within web pages
with web pages same as michaelsavage
flash player also needs its own broker
to perform privileged operations flash
broker delegates privileged operations
from flash player running window
processes as a result flash broker
becomes another attack surface of
Microsoft edge sandbox in fact Microsoft
has considered isolating flash broker
when designing Microsoft edge that is
why Iran's Flash Player in a special
render and access to flash broker is
also strictly restricted no render have
launched or activate permission to flash
broker and all in PC host and local zoom
renders have access permission to flash
brokers interface so how can a render
use the flash broker this diagram this
diagram shows the activation process of
flash broker co-create instance is
shipped in the render process and calls
are related to the browser broker the
browser broker launches the flash broker
and past the interface back to the
renderer then the render can access the
flash broker with that interface pointer
flash brokers supplies a lot of
functions such as pop-up file operations
GDI device access as structs etc the
most important thing is that iran's at
median integrity level in the last few
years near helping multiple
vulnerabilities found in flash broker
but is it still insecure we've
discovered an interesting behavior Adobe
Connect is a software used for
presentations web conferencing and
shirring when user enters the meeting
room created by Adobe Connect on a
webpage Flash Player prompts user to
install an add-in if the user then
clicks the yes button flash broker will
download and launch the adding with
median integrity level in flash broker
functions with name stars list broker LM
are used for downloading and installing
add-ins they are caught in this order
and for each adding a pair of files will
be downloaded first it downloads a dot
zip file the compressed data block must
start with the metric string Choi looks
like the deer outro is making a
reference to certain historical events
when writing this piece of code before
the metric string is a digital signature
block will be verified with the
hard-coded certificate chain following
the metrics screen is the uncompressed
file size then it also downloads a dot s
file it is also signed and host a char
two digits of the uncompressed add-in it
is used for verifying adding at a later
stage all digital signatures of
downloaded files are verified with the
hard-coded certificate chain this is the
entire process of downloading and
launching and adding it the flash
protocol only downloads files from a
hard-coded domain markula Mediacom the
adding can only be wrong when a
signature of downloaded files are
verified and the char two of the adding
matches the digest once it's downloaded
and verified it can run the adding with
controllable arguments this makes the
attack surface significantly larger
these settings may contain
vulnerabilities or become all maintained
so as we sew all we need to do is to
find as many headings as possible then
review them if we can find bugs in these
settings we may break out of the sandbox
we found several Eddings and digest
files on the marker media web server
many of them are still have valid
signatures some of these headings are
built with the ancient Flash Player and
can open an SWF file via command line
arguments we can use known
vulnerabilities to get code execution
here one of the ADIZ is marco media
please it is used for live communication
and he has a built-in flash player
released in the year of 2003 a there are
DEP and even stack cookies only exist in
academic papers at a time so all we need
to do is to find a 5000 exploit to get
code execution in adding process do you
miss that error for most the browser
attack scenarios the first step is
always to get code execution in the
internet around Allah generates
privilege escalation bugs to escape
sandbox so how can we escape from the
internet regular let's look at what we
what we already have we can get our code
execution in internet irregular we can
also escape sandbox from pc host the
Rinella our local zone renderer what we
still need to build a company to
exfoliate the chair we have two options
first find a way to run JavaScript in
busy host eronel second find a way to
get into the local zone however as we
mentioned earlier Kathy is a PC host
analyst erroneous user confirmation we
come now to control the confirmation
button within renderer funding a
universal secure cross set status quick
impact is also not easy so let's think
about what we can do with code exclusion
in the International zone when we try to
navigate from internet zone to local
zone the council size the access
was denied this mixes same origin policy
for based this can of a behavior to
prevent cross status cross status
information leakage so we are as the
operator performs a song check within R
and Allah
let's take into navigation internals the
navigation will happen when we visited a
website through address bar or click a
hyperlink on the web page follow
hyperlink tool we are be called & randle
aware checkers a target a URL Microsoft
edge Dodgers don't check within Randall
if it determines the target the URL
needs to be opened in you a new Randall
ER the navigation we are the navigation
request we are personal to the manager
otherwise it adjust the redirects in the
current renderer manager will also
checkers a targeted URL with the
redirection policy and the determine the
type of renderer to use the new type of
page render will be used for plant page
the local zone regular for local fare
and a privilege to the renderer for
settings page when navigating to look
who's own manager will get the PRC from
zone ID for Chakotay URL so ID is
calculated from target URL by calling a
ecozone a URL function manager will
create a new local zone randall of
process with PRC 121 if target a URL is
in local machine zone intranet zone
Ultra state serisone
there are two security issues in the
navigation
first the zone check is completely done
in the render process we can navigate to
a local page when Karen the URLs
protocol is fell this can be bypassed
with craft editor or request manager
directory second manager retrieves
Piazzi from zoo ID which in turn is
calculated from target a URL
however there is no additional check
unfair URL and as a local zone ran
dollars PSA is returned when target AOL
is a local HTML fell by abusing this mr.
Randol local HTML fell dropped by
internet Arundel in your local zone
granola to exfoliator is a sop purpose
first rattle a local HTML fell into a
temporary folder that can be accessed by
local xunran dollar then create anchor
element with data file as a source we
can locate as a host to URL where the
anchor element and modified it began
with fell multi core protocol is only
trivial and navigation where on click
event this purpose resume check and an
eric is to look whose own nest protocol
together this diagram shows the
in-charge sandbox escape first cat code
as children internet is own the uses
Allanson use SOP bypass to navigate to
local zone next another code execution
in local zone finally we use a flash
Booker to xscape the sandbox here is a
demo video for the exfoliator Chan
first stage called fq teens in tonight
or another
second stage is a sop bypass to local
zone and we gather the coded children
okay
next is the flash poker back and we are
out of sandbox
so however this box first for the
flagship poker back o da be removed as
those burnable Eddings
from macro marriott calm for the SOP
bypassed Microsoft added of our
integrity level check in IE carosone a
UI or if it's a target affair has a low
integrity level label it can only be
opened in integrity in internet alone so
to recap we walked you through the
security architecture of Microsoft edge
by minimizing attack surfaces Microsoft
edge is much more secure than its
predecessor Internet Explorer by react
attacking the entire browser new
inter-process communication mechanisms
are needed we typed into these IPC
mechanisms and interactions between
processes and components by abusing
design flaws in these components and
features we were able to find to change
bugs for exact escaping the sandbox so
we just detailed to complete compromise
above Microsoft edge sandbox logically
but why logical bugs are usually not
come from trivial programming errors
they are bad design decisions from the
very beginning to find this you must
have a deeper understanding of the
target software than those programmers
that are actually working on it it is a
combination of programming logic
hardcore operating system internals
reverse engineering and creative
thinking the result is a bug change that
is stable across versions 100% success
rate and simply found to talk about so
we would like to thank Alex ionesco and
James for shell for their excellent
talks papers and code we will also like
to thank our lab director Jung Yu for
their for supporting our research and
thank you all for listening
it's question time
[Applause]
ouch
so we will be releasing a white paper on
blackhat website later today so if you
have any further questions you can also
follow us on Twitter thank you
[Applause]