right let's kick this off I'm Jeff Moss
and I'm here with a panel and so this is
what we call the LOC note session it is
a unique blackhat innovation thanks to
Steve Wiley and Steve Oldenburg who
cooked up this idea it's part of a trick
to get you all to stay longer and it's
working and so the idea of a lock note
is to have more of a conversation
between some of the review board members
and some audience members we definitely
go into a question and answer session
later on so it's not just us talking
amongst each other at some point
you get to talk and ask us questions get
our opinions and the idea is sort of I
always notice that when there's a bunch
of us sitting around we're having beers
who are at the bar afterward people
would always come together on these they
want to hear what sort of the experts
are talking about and just listen in
like well what do we talk about in our
spare time and it turned out that a lot
of people at the con were interested too
so we structured this sort of as a
conversation you might not agree with
one part of it but I've got a list of
you know several topics and we're gonna
go through them all and we don't
necessarily all agree with each other
and then hopefully you'll learn
something and we'll learn from each
other and then we'll go to Q&A so today
we've got all the way on stage right
Veronica Valero's got Daniel Cuthbert
and Antonio's atlases before we get
started I'd like to introduce one of our
sponsors that are making the whole
conference possible Phil Marshall with
security scorecard is going to say a
couple of notes and then we're gonna
jump right into the conversation so come
on up so thank you I'm so impressed with
the crowd here I can't believe it
this Israel it really impressive and I'm
just standing between you and a very
interesting session but I wanted to
first of all just thank everyone in the
room here for your wonderful questions
down in the exhibit floor I can speak
for security scorecard but also for
several other vendors that I spoke to I
think at
this event especially above any other
events if we're paying attention we're
creating better products because of your
questions and the depth of those
questions but I also wanted to sort of
give my observation or a couple
observations from this show and as you
might notice I have a few gray hairs so
I've been to a few of these and what's
changed and my key observation is the
audience this used to be an event that
was largely very technical folks and
what we're seeing now is a combination
of suits and technical and both
audiences are valuable to us to talk to
but I also think what's changed and has
changed for our company and other
companies that is that we're paying more
attention to things like user interface
user experience because we know that
part of your job has changed because
it's no longer security as a function
but it's security as a practice that
informs not only your company's profile
but also your company's valuation it's
changed to that level and I think that
is a key observation that many of us on
the floor are making now that part of
your job is not only talking about
security but talking about security to
your board and to your c-level and
that's that's not an easy challenge and
we realize that so we just want to again
thank you for your contribution to
hopefully a better user experience for
all of the titles and different user
users within your organization we hope
to do a better job and continue to do so
so thanks again appreciate it and look
forward to a great session thank you all
right everybody let's get this started
so I think I figure there's a pretty
thinks open-ended question though how
what are we what do you think as a
community as security experts what are
we winning that what do we do really
well
and also what do we do well I mean we've
been in some of us have been in this
game for decades and we seem to be
facing the same problems over and over
and over like what's going on and so I'm
gonna I want to throw it off to Daniel
first we're really good at breaking
stuff yeah we're really good at breaking
stuff you really crap at fixing stuff
yeah I think we're struggling the moment
I turn to earlier breach fatigue the
isn't a day that goes by where you don't
hear of another breach and you start to
wonder especially you've been doing it
this would be my third decade nearly
like if we've got all the tools and the
products and the people why is it still
so easy to hack and it's almost
embarrassing for me because you know we
are trying to fix it we have built
standards as great people out there but
we just really bad at communicating how
to make this stuff secure or is it
securing stuff is just not sexy it's
easy to get a roof shell which is quite
sexy so but is it is it more like we're
sucking less yeah like we could suck
more yeah we're sucking less yeah and
also it's reducing the sukkah tude yeah
we are definitely suck or lesser yeah
and that's probably a skillset and
LinkedIn soon I suck a letter maybe not
but yeah I I don't think it's as bad as
it was in the 90s because that was just
awful and then the early 2000s with web
apps that was also really bad um but
we're just we're not where we should be
so but imagine you're in I don't know
automotive safety and you've got airbags
and you've got anti-collision systems
and you've had safety belts and you've
got all this stuff and you still have
automotive fatalities right is that
where we're gonna get to there's just a
sort of acceptable amount of damage and
we have to be okay with that or does our
mentality tell us no zero zero breakin
zero breach fatigue that post but maybe
that's done to the nature of who we are
we want everything to be that Unicorn
yeah maybe we were just really better
admitting you're never gonna get the
Unicorn you know it will always be said
about what do you think well I know that
most of us are quite optimistic and I
want everything to be reduced down to
zero but huemul it is not possible
I agree that the level of Defense has
increased over the years on the other
hand who can still see same attacks over
and over again for instance in this so
had at least three Kenda related attacks
yeah
the topic is quite old what's the
difference then have we failed I believe
not it's a fact that wound reduce better
defenses but we have more sophisticated
attacks from the other hand so the whole
game goes when it goes on over and over
and over again now salute it at some
point that will face this kind of
attacks I don't know what you see but
certainly things are getting better and
better
so ok so that's what we're good at or is
that what we're bad at well depends the
perspective yeah you can say both I mean
I said I'd say damn we're really good at
breaking stuff I mean a new technology
comes out and we're all over it really
quickly but then it seems like we move
on to the new shining and is it because
it's not really our job to fix it like
we didn't produce the thing we didn't
build the operating system that can bus
whatever we're just sort of like these
tourists speculating on all the problems
but it unless the manufacturer fixes
their thing all we can do is and so is
that maybe why we we point out problems
and move on because we're not in a
position to fix it I think I think
previously the industry was very slanted
to making rock stars of breakers and I
think unfairly like I've now moved into
another defensive role I still break
stuff but defense is damn hard like
anybody working in blue team or building
and defending like respect because that
is not an easy time I think you turned
it it's easy to sit in your bedroom and
poem stuff but if you're trying to fix
that with risk and compliance and
politics and do we have that Network on
crack yeah we've still got that Network
yeah that's that's hot maybe we're going
to talk about the defense fatigue right
like you're breaking you're alone you're
you're breaking stuff and it's so cool
and then it's like ok let's fix this and
it's not explaining things and they
don't understand or maybe they do but
they don't have budget so maybe you get
one year of waiting to get the budget
and then no one wants to fix that it's
kind of really exhausting and at some
point is like why what is the reward
right I'll just drop it on full disclose
your mailing list and move on with my
life and yeah and it doesn't make a
difference like at some point if like
from the defense perspective it's like
if no one cares what should I oh we
don't care right why that's why we are
breaking stuff right we want to make it
better but sometimes it's like it's so
exhausting that it's just not worth it
so I've seen a lot of defenders like
burnout because it's like this is just
too much so one of the ways we try to
mitigate burnout I think as we try to
automate a lot of things right so if
you're doing something that's burning
you out to automate it and do the cool
thing are we reaching the limits of that
you know you know I don't think we're
doing in love it seems not not enough I
think there's a lot of manual yeah a lot
of manual stuff yeah so Antonio I had a
we were talking a little bit beforehand
so what normally happens is we get
together we float some ideas and then if
we find ourselves actually talking about
it for a while it's like stop right we
have to save this for the room otherwise
we're gonna have the conversation and
you won't get to hear it and Antonio's
brought up a really good point where he
thinks we're maybe not doing so well on
mentoring him yeah and actually to be
honest this topic was brought by
Veronica I guess today during dinner
ahead oh okay
yeah and she raised the point that okay
I'm being approached by several young
guys and asking what should do what
should move on and I thought that this
was a really good point and the really
good question so I was wondering how can
we mentor young people for instance this
afternoon had a very interesting opinion
talk by two Israeli guys about training
teenagers this is one part training of
course but the mentoring serve something
else and in my opinion this is something
that probably will fail as a community
and you need to you need to see how can
probies yeah so so I think that we
should go back to the basics at some
point and get stuck again like start
asking some hard questions and ourselves
like for example like we love what we do
but what about the next generation of
security professionals they are going to
be solving problems that we maybe have
no idea how they will look like we don't
know what the internet in 50 years would
look like so how are we going what are
we doing right now to make sure that the
people that is joining the field it's
ready for that so there is a lot of lack
of communication like and lack of
mentoring guidance and lack of direction
in the sense of what are the challenges
we are facing right the questions we are
we are doing right now like what are we
gonna do that
what are we bad at like yeah sure would
be when you listening to you - it
reminds me like back back back in the
old school days right before YouTube and
Google like you had to find a mentor if
you are a hacker you didn't get anywhere
unless you found a mentor hacker who
would help steer you and I remember
spending half my time just trying to
find a mentor and once I found the
mentor oh my gosh my life was so much
easier I didn't have to speculate about
everything I actually could ask
questions and we seem to have lost that
yeah yeah and I think it's so crucial
because it's like you can learn about I
don't know pocket analysis but if you
have someone that it can show you the
way it's not a shortcut right you still
have to do the work but if if you have
someone around that will say start here
it's much more easier right so we need
more people kind of willing to pass and
I remember I think some people think of
it as like well if I help that person
have a leg up they're gonna take my job
and it's like no there's there's plenty
of jobs for everybody people is
desperate for like hiring everyone is
like in two years we will need some many
millions of InfoSec positions so we need
to create that it's like the idea that
you don't lose the job you have people
there to help you do your job better
yeah
I'd love to know how many of you in here
have been in this industry for less than
three years show of hands
less than three years that's quite a few
yeah we'll turn it around more than ten
years and so how many of you have
mentored someone else once that sounds
wrong there's a bit that sounds really
weird okay
so I think we should need more more of
that like sometimes it's not like oh I'm
mentoring you for five years and
spending my life with you listen it's
not about that it's like getting
reaching out and just going to a local
hackerspace and helping out a local a
couple people who have interests right
it's it can be a lot of different things
but you're you're giving back and you're
helping people find their path so I want
to tie it back a little bit to some of
my remarks to opening which was it seems
like some of our problems were facing
now are sort of tech adjacent they're
more social tied to tech and I alluded
to that with I think we've built these
giants a social media platforms and only
now we're starting to realize like hey
there might be some downside to
centralizing all that not from an
attackers perspective we've got all the
eggs in one basket from a regulation
perspective you've got all the
regulator's that only have to look at
say five platforms instead of 500 it's
sort of an attractive nuisance that was
a byproduct and so I'm curious from the
panel and maybe the audience it does it
feel like the next set of problems were
facing have much more of a social
component whether it's deep fakes or
disinformation or synthetic
personalities I saw the talk on that you
know we're gonna be dealing with these
issues that seem to have much more of a
social component does that does that
sound right to you or am I just kind of
it my own biases it does and I think for
me that's where I think we as an
industry gonna struggle I mean
traditionally hackers are the least
social people in the world they don't
like humans we don't wanna talk to you
please don't look at me okay and that
was fine if you would worrying some code
or doing something with hardware but now
you've got to talk to people and that's
awkward but you can automate that
probably that'd be weird chatbot type
thing do you have like 50 pull downs no
mom I'm working right now I don't want
dinner but yeah I think we've now got to
get new skills of how do you deal with
people in all the social stuff that you
mentioned and like genuinely we're bad
at that
really bad it's like or profession kind
of a ball Ryan's like before we were
just technical I was enough and then we
got to learn to manage others because he
was needed and now we need to learn even
more like more like politics and socials
and stuff funny it's like I don't think
we can avoid it like we grow up yeah oh
my god damn it well and I think so if we
don't do that why don't we just keep
talking to our computers right what's
the downside fake I think we keep I
think we need to keep a leg on the
social part because otherwise like we
get to really like serious issues like
we get regulated we get regulated and we
don't like it so if you don't like it
you should you have to be involved yeah
yeah yeah at least from my perspective
yeah any thoughts well certainly the
topics it's of interest nowadays and we
must deal with this now this brings my
mind that talked about diversity
before coming here and this is one
aspect of diversity be age and social
media for instance are mainly used if
not mistaken by youngest they are more
familiar with this when we are not
familiar with something from outside for
instance then you may not be able to see
the risks behind it and you may not be
able of course to face or fix them or
help someone to fix them so this is
maybe an come back to work or previous
topic that one more reason to suit right
in order to train young people in order
to face these things sense of trying to
face this thing somehow
oh I'm from a different generation and
or maybe the flip side like I have no
idea what a youtuber is like I'd never
thought you can make a career especially
gazillions like they do becoming a
youtuber and that's a social thing and
genuinely we'd be terrible youtubers
does it be a black screen with us maybe
mom have you seen have you seen some of
our friends who have twitch channels hey
if you'd like to watch me reverse i'll
be on twitch like oh yeah I'll jump
right on that why don't you fight Ida
for three hours yeah oh look he's loaded
a debug module but you know yeah we'd be
bad at that that's nature but that this
next generation is really good at that
like fair play time my kids watch this
one guy called blippi and blippi does
these amazing things he jumps around
with orange glasses and get me teza he's
an ex u.s. fighter pilot who's making
four and a half million a year John and
around with the edge being an ass on
YouTube alike respects like to die I
never do that but they seem to be better
at becoming more social which so so that
kind of I want to use that as an awkward
transition so have you noticed like I
think within the last year Google switch
preference ranking preference from
desktop to mobile so all of a sudden I
get all these emails is the website
administrator for Def Con saying hey
just so you know we're now
preferentially ranking mobile scores
over desktop scores like okay that makes
sense there's more more mobile use and I
look at like who's viewing our site with
what platforms everybody in China is on
mobile so basically our future is mobile
everything's gonna have to have a mobile
component if you want to be relevant and
so I was wondering okay does that mean
we get to be more secure these mobile
though you're in the walled garden of
Apple or Android and is a byproduct we
might just our nice overlords might make
these more secure platforms for us right
as a by-product like we've moved just by
avoiding the problem long enough we've
ended in this garden of - yep well one
cuz let's be honest androids never gonna
get secure really we've tried that
battle
for buy some product manager on on
Twitter saying he spent three months on
the problem and it was fixed now no
Apple yeah I mean like Fairplay to Apple
I think what they've done is nothing
short of phenomenal like a modern iPhone
and iOS is an incredibly secure device
and you know I tear it apart and I look
at the hard and I go wow like that's
what happens when you've got a budget of
X and they've hired some of the best
people I've ever known and I'm sure you
can all agree like an iPhone is solid
Android different path I guess they want
coverage and that makes really hard you
know if you want to get on every single
hardware device it's not gonna work
maybe at a point like we bypass that
ugly period of desktop which was just
bad yeah yeah I'm just kind of wondering
what does that entail for our industry
and so you've pushed the attackers up
the stack you have to be really good and
so what are the attacks now against
mobile we were we were talking earlier
like is it down to somebody has to set
up a fake base station somebody has to
have a zero-day on a base band I mean
it's getting down to a pretty small
number of things I have to worry about
well what I wonder is is it's more
secure because it is really secure
because people is not looking at it like
Windows is still kind of or wasa still
kind of on the focus and spotlight right
so there was like thousands of people
looking at the security and trying to
report vulnerabilities and in mobile
phones I get the sense that yes kind of
we are reporting stuff but it's not as
fast and we are not for example you know
us you don't have antivirus you cannot
capture your own traffic you basically
you have no idea what is going on so I
is more secure so far but in the end I
disagreed like with the review board we
can see the waves that happen a year and
a half ago like we saw a massive drop in
anything to do with mobile mostly
because of political pressure and China
saying you shall not released your
research now traditionally you see a
good amount of Android oday coming in to
submissions you know
and what's really bad we'd rarely get
IOS like genuinely this year's been a
little bit different there's been some
good RS but if you look at say a exploit
for latest iOS or iPhone no NSO are
dropping 50 million to our friends in
the Middle East like you know a good
Aussie and iOS is still a million plus
there are people looking it's just yeah
that really raised that cost so why
release it at a show when you're gonna
get one to two million dollars for it
exactly you know so the market pressures
driven it up to such it but for Android
you can still get them yeah because the
price isn't so high yeah it's it's the
Walmart of the phone you know yeah yeah
so I'm wondering then does that that
creates sort of like two tiers two
classes of users like I don't
necessarily like iOS but I absolutely
have to use it like I have no choice
right I can't have an insecure or less
secure phone so I have to give up all
these cool features that I'm I liked on
my Android but I don't have a choice and
so when you look at your friends it's
like they're all using iPhones because
they prioritize security over blinky and
it really sort of creates two classes of
the population which is weird it's not
supposed to be like that so I spent a
lot of time in Brazil and Brazil still
uses a lot of Android for Android for
4.4 yeah which was great you know if you
need to do lots of nasty stuff but
genuine ease because they can't afford
to upgrade and that's an awful problem
because most the handsets that there are
riddled with malware like it's it's the
desktop from the early 2000 yeah they
can't afford to upgrade and I think
that's quite a bad position because by
nature they're now punished for not
having good security because they can't
afford it
yeah okay so I've got I've kind of got a
funny side thing which was topics you
alluded to earlier we the review board
sees hundreds and hundreds of hundreds
submissions dorothea over probably over
a thousand are more considering all the
conferences so you get to see trends and
so I was asking them earlier like
remember we used to hear a lot about
Canaries and virtualization and honey
pots and deception services and I was
going through looking at the talks and
the least the
talks I listen to where their attackers
I never heard one speaker say and then I
check for the canary then I evade the
deception system it's like it's not even
was that a speed bump was that something
that had a lot of promise but it's not
just didn't come to who here uses
deception services on your network
Canaries two three four I'd love to know
why like what's going on there it sounds
so cool but it's not so you had a Dan
you had a speculation of your sprinkled
landmines all throughout your yeah I
mean like as an ex attacker like if you
breach a network you go for the juicy
stuff right but as a defender like we
suck at basics we have no idea what we
have and you look at any of the breaches
it was always that struts bucks or prim
face or something else the moment you
throw deception tech on there we've now
got four networks so then you have IT
trying to patch the deception Network
because I think it's outdated that I
already know and the Sox having no idea
like yes it's an overhead nightmare I'd
love to know why it's like three people
using it like that that is I didn't
expect that
and we also because of law issues of
regulation issues because for some
organizations for instance having this
kind of deceiving services may not be
allowed it oh I hadn't thought of that
or their regulatory are their regulatory
requirement but why are you not using
this kind of technology I'm wondering
anybody throw something else yeah so
what are some of the other things though
that we've come across that you
mentioned the fall in Android zero day
what are some of the other things you
finally surprising when you well
surprise me I wouldn't say but clearly
on this so that is okay not it's not you
know but there was a clear trend on
using machine learning core most of for
everything learning everywhere
yes exactly please stop the machine yeah
about there were five talks presented in
the show dealing with network defense
was aa seed with simulating attackers
was a lot of stuff and I remember many
many more submitted in order to present
it so there's clearly NF
to use machine learning for everything
conservative is it the new blockchain
yes and AI because AI blockchain helps
machine learning along with the cuantos
remember the quantum yeah but the point
is machine learning itself not only is
not new but I have seen this story
repeated now because I recall from my
early days when I was dealing mainly
with networks there was then an effort
to build machine learning for network
elated problems in ideas it was all
about contouring and yeah but I did
still here what is machine learning in
the networks yeah so I'm wondering
eventually all this strength that we
face nowadays regarding machine learning
will have any real effect will have any
products that they will stay there even
in the same level as ideas I mean that
to use to be you somehow or they will
vanish I am here I think we we even went
farther because most of the talks were
like deep learning
so that's deeper right but I'm another
effect that I notice is that these
generated like division like people
poaching for machine learning thumbs up
and then people hate anything this
doesn't work don't sell may smoke right
people like Daniel saying I want
superficial learning not that i don't
just don't learn anything just do the
basic side but i think like we are
making a mistake and i think that i
think there is a topic that just keeps
coming that is coming back to the basics
right machine learning is great because
right now we have a lot of data and it's
good at looking at a lot of data but you
still need humans that as a machine how
to work how to learn what to learn so we
are needing analyst to keep the input
and we should not SPECT deep learning to
do anything extraordinary because you
know we are still not there and again
like we are still fail falling in like
phishing scams and macros attacks and
iot opened the net ports so
we need to kind of I think slow down I
wonder if I'm wondering if we're over
not over specializing but I think we're
over specializing to a certain degree
in the sense that do you have enough
time to understand all the various
permutations of ml and AI and is it an
expert system and is it a and then all
the other tech I mean there's so much
going on in our space not no one can
keep it all in your head so that means
you have to be part of a team and then
you have to have divisible skills
amongst the team and then and it goes
back to sort of the fatigue question
where I try to protect the DEF CON
Network I spend a lot of time on that
and I can tell you over the last five
years it has gotten monumentally more
complicated like to run a web server
five years ago was pretty straight
forward now I've got to deal with DNS
second OCSP revocation and key pinning
and it goes on and on and on that's and
then the DNS server used to be one file
now I have to deal with everything has
gotten more complicated and so it's like
I'm doing the basics turning a webmail
and thing but I'm spending like three
times as much effort doing it because we
just keep layering on more and more
technology and we're kind of standing so
it's like the other sciences for
instance in medicine
you must have expertise on something you
can not have a or doctors do not be a
doctor and you can cure everything yeah
you have specialities right so probably
were leading we're as well in the cyber
science that we need you need to be
expert in a very very specific topic
which becomes narrower and narrower all
the time right and the whole team
eventually will defend the castle so I'm
wondering in the old days you could
defend with four or five people now I
need 20 people the joke is just to
understand the JavaScript executing on
my webpage I know that's that's a team
of 50 just to do JavaScript yeah that's
not beanie bushes that's the mess yeah
and so we do that because it helps our
careers you're the guy that's the expert
in this one little problem
but that means we have less generalists
so raise your hands if you consider
yourself a generalist okay raise your
hands if you have gotten by being a
specialist
well less specialist than I thought why
do you sell right what's the rest of you
then you break is so I'm wondering is
that do you see that there's a lack of
generalists that see bigger pitchers
that might be needed for this new social
requirement or we need both yeah but we
need both but what we have I don't think
we have enough generalists out there
like from my perspective I see a lot of
people really specializing really fast
like most of the young people they just
go straight out of school to like
reversing some malware a really specific
model right and you talk about other
stuff in general info second they kind
of not know it right so why is that and
how that will make your work better like
like it's something missing that we are
not seeing it's like the the malware
thing the Stephanie middles trend and
lost five years like if you want to get
into our IT circuits its Mel with Mel
reverse engineering but there's an extra
attacker like the malware is just that
small part it's it's something I'm gonna
drop to get somebody to do something and
then I'm raping pillaging the rest of
the network but I need networking skills
app skills all that kind of stuff but I
worry that the concentration of malware
and learning Ida or anything else it's
like you're forgetting about the fact
that it's a bigger picture yeah and
there is a lot of other jobs out there
that people yeah I'm looking for right
of the field and and I think that people
do not understand that being a
journalist means that you can look and
solve the problem in a different way
with more knowledge and more specific
and you can also get better at the
basics right like I'm seeing a lot of
Marvel oh cool I have more to reverse
but does bands like something in my
network that is not working um you know
we need more of mainframe how many
people here work with mainframes it's
one time keeping a real read there
guarantee jobs for life because contain
you know we can never get rid of a bit
like telnet telnet
it is the cockroach of the IT industry
yeah
survived everything in which it's still
hit well and if you look at the history
of where FTP came from right it predates
TCP yeah right it's like you can never
get rid of it I'm at yesterday tweeted
somebody mom I was using FTP tohc and
they're like can't kill that Arthur
so yeah going back to review board stuff
also talked a little bit about I've
noticed diversity of people submitting
right there seems to be more
international more Asian and some of the
Japanese submissions have just been
killing it lately it's it's so
traditionally you had a lot of you don't
have the circuit people submitting the
same color thing and especially for the
USA and here last two years like there
are people you've never heard of but
they're talks they like amazing so this
traditionally Japan has always been very
quiet in the global research world like
it's maybe one every couple years this
year like wow what has happened and
there have been some phenomenal talks I
mean I went and had a full man gasm with
the pastor talk cuz I'm like great
research amazing problem solved
well-built I'm like that's solid
researching and engineering there's that
there's a lot of other countries you've
never really expected anything for now
pushing stuff through so I think the
balance is definitely tipped it's it's
now very much a global research
community than just UK us Germany yes
Island yeah and I think that diversity
is great and I think it also relates
with this new generation of
professionals right we are seeing like
researchers presenting top-notch
research like really young like oh
that's great
like some people some years I will
complain like oh we got the conference
is all the same people
anymore not only moron we were wondering
what is the young people right where are
the submissions and now we can see them
well Steve and I were having a chat and
gentlemen if he's in the room came up it
was his first submission to blackhat
it was on Windows kernel protection like
a solid topic this was the first time
he's ever submitted to a conference him
his family so proud his gym teacher was
proud his grandparents are proud from
Russia I'm like respect like this is
your first consummation and this is a
solid solid subject like you are
protecting the Windows kernel like
that's that's amazing that's your first
submission like Jesus Wow okay so I have
a final a final kind of common question
and then we gonna move to the audience
participation and then we were talking
about log generation and and threat
feeds and how much some of these threat
feeds cost and how actionable is the
intelligence is actually useful and I
was joking it's like well I get attacked
all the time how do i monetize my logs
can I make some money it's like we
should all pull together I think we'll
start a new business I'll call it new co
you send me all of your logs I'll find
somebody to buy them all and we'll share
all the money and it'll be like the
blackhat my beer pool right because like
our logs have got to be just as valuable
as those other peoples lugs I mean how
is it any different I look I think if
you look at people who are targeted a
lot like that stuff golden it's not just
some random box and Romania's you know
who wouldn't want to pop you yeah like
the star gonna be worth at least 10
beers
exactly yeah but I think that um
the discussion on that intelligence log
is like I think there are these pipes
right all thread intelligence all feeds
or machine learning or blockchain uh
it's not talk about that but and we we
really need to be more critical we
really need to ask the hard question is
this useful it's like where's the
scientific analysis that shows that your
beads actually there was this great talk
during these two days doing a really
nice comparison
so it was like May is more useful to run
my honeypotted pain a lot of money for
is you feed that it after today is not
worth any more right so I think that we
should start like questioning why why
I'm buying this like make them hard to
make them convinced here like show me
the numbers right but that was always
one of the things like the early hacking
days was question or we verify
everything and I think we've lost a lot
that we trust a lot of oh yeah I guess I
must do that you know blockchain will
fix everything
how many Bitcoin millionaires are in the
moon and that is awkward and I think
that we all know this is hype but let's
buy it just in case it works right so no
we should kind of ask the questions
before before that okay let's go to some
questions raise your hand we've got a
microphone on either side of the room
okay it looks like this side is winning
the site is snoozing so you all said we
need to improve our social political
procedural skills and that's something I
mean learning those soft skills takes a
lot of time and mentoring people to know
those soft skills takes a lot of time
and we all know that the mentors and the
people that are being mentored are too
short in time which means it'll come at
the cost of learning technical skills at
least to a certain extent so at the same
time you've said that I've heard a lot
of we need to improve our technical
skills so where's the balance I mean we
can't do everything I'll take a crack at
that first which is I think you can't
you can't be all things to everybody
right and people do have natural
affinity some people are better at
certain skills and others and so I would
say if you
if you are somewhat technical but you
lean more toward the soft skills maybe
that's your maybe that's your rollin
InfoSec right don't try to be a howl of
our reverse-engineering
if you know you can't be at that level
of game you know put your energy into
where you'll be most effective right
you'll get the best wins you'll be the
most helpful to your organization and so
the might of it might just be you
reflecting on like where are what are
your strengths and playing To Your
Strengths I don't think we're saying
everybody has to have all these skills
but I think if the industry if we
acknowledge that there is a role for
those skills and those skills are
valuable and they will help us then we
should put some energy thinking about
them I think talk to your question like
when you're starting out in this
industry you you have like such a wide
array of things you can do and naturally
you you levitate to what you're good at
well you could be a halvah who has a
god-given gift that just terry stuff you
can be mr. Fitz over there when it comes
to hardware it just falls apart in front
of it but you're not going to do
everything and I think naturally as your
career goes on you go well I'm really
good at I enjoy hardware I understand
how electronics works but put me in
front of Ida and there's just lots of
blue lines and with red I don't know I
did it and then you'd expand upon the
hardware top stuff you shouldn't try and
do everything so I think you will burn
out really really quickly yeah I want to
add that like 10 years ago we were
joining the industry in a different time
like we were not so pressure with time
and we were like more relaxed I could
have take a day to learn something right
now it's like companies want you to be
productive in three months right and you
are just out of school so I think in
that case like you if you don't take the
time right now to learn it you will
never have the time so you need to okay
I need one day a week to learn this and
negotiate right it is your career you
will be more effective in three years
like a shalini wait under the next
question so get some couple in there
hello
touching back on the beginning of the
conversation where
and we have attackers and defenders and
knotting out so and we trip all for the
same problems all over and over again so
it seems to me like that like attackers
work is I agree is much sexier and like
at most attackers and defenders I kind
of get the same compensation on the
market so it seemed don't you think
there is a disproportion of that there
are more attackers which
find problems but there are not enough
defenders to fix them and if you agree
like do you think there is a way to fix
it somehow to make a defender position
more sexier yes I'm with definite order
and review board like we want good
defensive talks because a they're harder
like I think the day of popping calc on
an internet-connected dildo or well and
truly behind us like move on seriously
other stunts hacking and yeah stun
hacking like it has this place sometimes
but you popped something that shouldn't
be on the internet and like okay so what
I think defensive talks and we do look
at that in the review board like this is
a cool thing you can do and somebody can
action that on Monday morning and this
is gonna save a lot of stuff like
respect but I think the balance is still
very much in favor of the attackers and
defense is hard look at hacking team
like they were very good at breaking
stuff and they got popped really badly
up second defense is hard one other
reason for this disproportion could be
that an attacker needs to find one
witness one bug in order to break
something the defender has to defend
more or less everything he will design a
protocol the higher level protocol he
has to examine all the filthy stellitita
it's much more difficult as a broader
scope if he forget something
the attacker can fight it and DM over
for the defender so I believe this is
one of the main reasons in addition to
what you say that it is sexier to be an
adequate this is one more reason that
why have all this attacking style talks
but when I see an attacking style talk
I'd ICS a defender to be honest because
this help us to make products better to
improve the cadence of disguise before
it saturated right if you didn't have
all this ever freedom tackle
we wouldn't have all this well that's
movement the defensive when I've talked
to some universities I was talking to
one that said we want to be world class
we want to have the best information
security program I'm like that's great I
like your enthusiasm you've got budget
fantastic are you gonna be okay teaching
offense to your students cricket hmm
maybe we'll be the second best it's like
there were some hard questions it's like
they didn't fully realize like to be the
best you're gonna have to teach offense
and they couldn't get that past the Dean
of the school okay we're gonna take a
question over here and it'll be the
where the end that's more like
consideration if I step out of the this
kind of community and I think about
designing a product the perception of a
company today is that it isn't something
the market wants it I want to put it on
the market and then we have a cage with
three different level of badges with a
bunch of dogs which are these technology
people they come out they say I did
everything wrong so they start doing
thing they correct a patch then
everything they delay my my stuff and
then they go back in the cage so my
feeling is that this we're talking about
social and everything they're not social
we need in my opinion to socialize to
make this technology people more social
to be part of the process but they
haven't started well sure we should put
them in cages that's a bit hard core
pages might be a bit weird well and I'd
say we should socialize the people
pushing these products out so fast
because they're doing social harm but
somehow we're the ones to be blamed for
it doesn't seem right yeah I sort of get
where you're coming but I think that
there's a balance here I think you know
it's easy to smack internet of things at
the moment but at the same time
consumers demand stuff really cheap
instantly like there's got to be some
give-and-take well we still have airbags
you still don't get run over yeah yeah
you don't get to buy a car without an
airbag no that's true okay so we're
winding down on time I want to try one
last question and then that'll be it so
sorry about that
so if you notice always spin the last 10
20 years it hasn't really changed
vendors keep on producing products that
have security vulnerabilities I think
that what we're we're still in the job
here I guess so I guess developers do
not learn they will have been spending
more than 20 years with the same problem
seeing the same problems over and over
again but it's not the same developer
certain right you're cranking out new
developers time and time again yeah
which is a bit strange and I was always
time I was thinking that there will be
some new regulation that would force
vendors to actually create more secure
software but at the moment it seems that
even from a regulation side the problem
is being passed down to banks or other
institutions zero here and everything
else
what do you see do you think that we
will ever hold vendors accountable for
producing crappy software or I mean
that's a long conversation but I'll have
one one observation if you search for
source code examples almost all of them
are insecure right so if all you do is
go to your favorite code repository and
make a comment when you see insecure
code then the next person to come along
and use that code right might get might
copy and paste the secure version and
I've talked to the people who produce
books for universities on there's a
couple standards in the United States
and it's like if I got $300,000 or
whatever and code reviewed every example
in your text books would you include
them so that we get examples and it
turns out it's not a 1020 hundred
million dollar problem we're talking a
couple hundred thousand dollars to
review code in text books all right so
some of the problems we think are huge
they're really small we just need to get
people together to do it I'm waiting for
a backdoor by a stack overflow and a
comic read example yeah how many people
copy and paste my stack overflow like
yeah I've been the laravel what a pain
in the arse I remember talking to
somebody at a major search engine and
they said we you submit us the proper
code and we're happy to make it the
number one search result we're just too
busy to do it so I mean you'll
that's people in industry are accepting
you know we'll accept some of our
examples it's just we don't we have not
organized as a community to do that and
sometimes there are developers that they
want to cook sick do secure coding but
they don't have time because you know
deadlines so I think it's like um it's
like a balance like but try keep pushing
and keep trying to educate your bosses
to kind of accept that as well all right
well thank you very much for sticking
around for the lock note and thank you
for making just a really good black hat
hope to see you next year
Thanks see you guys around
[Applause]