we're going to be talking about titled
network defender archaeology walking
through some offensive stuff with decom
as well as our research which is
primarily defensive on top of that now
before we get going my name is Justin
Warner I'm on Twitter I go by a handle
six dub I'm a principal security
engineer at a company named gigamon I'm
primarily on our applied threat research
team so I spend my days looking at lots
of network data trying to find bad guys
doing bad things
my background is pretty varied I spent a
couple years in the US military doing
defensive work and counterintelligence
work and then I got bored with that and
decided I wanted to go break into places
for a living
did that for three or four years of the
small consulting company in the u.s.
worked on some public tools PowerShell
empire veil some of the other tools and
then after breaking into places using
the same technique for three and a half
years I decided I wanted to try to stop
it for once
and so pivoted back to the blue side
here I'm speaking with Alex here hi my
name is Alex sir I'm a security engineer
at gigamon with the a PR team background
not quite as exciting as Justin's yet I
was an intern with iceberg and later a
security engineer and I recently
graduated from the University of
Washington so with a lot of these
conference talks here it's really good
to start out most research nowadays is
always built on top of the research of
other people so I like to start out
every conference talk and say thinks
this research was really inspired and
driven by all the people who came out on
the offensive side and pioneered these
techniques and found them so a couple of
folks are down below Casey Matt Phil and
Joe big shout out to these guys our work
builds on top of it highly recommend
following them or checking them out if
you get the chance so we're gonna start
with a little bit of a fun story so why
are we here today so it's the 90s let's
take a step back some people might not
even be born then Alex we have cool
movies like hackers that start to come
out making this scene popular people
start to realize this is a thing we have
really sexy computers these things are
workhorses they never fail never break
really sexy operating systems you got
Windows three one here that's really the
powerhouse and then this operating
system starts to grow and it's built on
top of old technologies but there's old
technology stick along they have to be
there because people built things on
Windows three one and they want them to
work forever one of those technologies
happens to be a system called decom
we're gonna be talking about but then
when you pivot into the modern day with
all these youngsters you got Matt Nelson
running around they're focused on
breaking all these old sub systems so no
longer are they worried about using them
for good things they're looking at them
as a way to get in cyber reason has a
great blog detailing some of this guy
named Bo hops does an awesome research
into this these this technology is now
part of threat models and ways and
document and methods that bad guys such
as many of the Iranian threat groups are
using to get into networks so it all
started with old technology and sexy
operating systems and now we land in
despair in threats so let's what are we
here to talk about we're here to talk
about this so quick video really quick
demo purely using a protocol called
decom in a language called powershell
we're able to pop a calque on our remote
system yay calc it's the best thing to
show and you'll see this is all the
defensive telemetry we get with Zeke and
Suri you'll see it's a whole lot of
mumbo-jumbo nothing even says the word
decom nothing's logged and Suri using
popular open source free rulesets
you don't see any massive alerts blowing
up that a well-known and documented
technique was launched and so that's
what we're here to talk about today how
to how to improve and you'll see this is
another zoomin of that bro or Zeke log
this is just a hot mess so you can
clearly see that it's very hard to
discern what actually happened here so
we're here to talk about the fact that
adversaries are using this technique red
teams are using this technique it's been
around for a couple years
yet nothing rarely addresses it so our
challenge is to rise through the
occasion of understanding this technique
understand the protocol which is a big
enough challenge on its own understand
what makes it malicious and then author
and adapt our tools to allow us to
detect it and we're going to focus
primarily on the network so let's go
ahead and get started this is one of
Justin's favorite slides actually early
on we grabbed a sampling of books on
decon and justin pointed out how a lot
of these books were older than I am so
again just a little bit more perspective
on how long this thing has been around
for but before we can dive into decom we
want to talk a little bit more about
calm or the component object model and
this is a language independent model
allows applications to expose objects
with functionality to a system so what
exactly does that mean it means that
objects can be written in any language
of a programmers choosing and then other
programmers can use that object also in
any language of their choosing to gain
functionality from it this is kind of a
big deal as it allowed things such as
getting away from shared libraries being
imported into projects and it also made
all these objects very first time and
portable which was great these objects
are identified using something called a
class identifier these are globally
unique and so they'll be the same for
the same object across all systems and
what this means is that you can use them
to look up and correlate exactly what
object is being used so for example when
something like Microsoft Word is being
installed it'll install a couple objects
and if any of those objects CLS IDs show
up in logs or over the network you can
immediately go take that ID look it up
and immediately correlate what object
was being used and you can start to get
an idea of what's happening in an
environment and so we say on these
slides that components are typically
registered there are a couple ways to
kind of get around this and use comm
objects' when they're not explicitly
registered but for the purpose of this
we're not going to get too far into that
we also say that components implement
multiple interfaces and these interfaces
are purely for interoperability so these
help to define and expose common
functionality to any component that
decides to implement them and one of
these interfaces of note is the I
dispatch interface and this helps to
provide automation so that means that a
client can interact with an object at
runtime the eye system activator
interface is also pretty cool as that
helps to work with the instantiation of
an object and it can either do this
directly or through an AI class factory
kind of pass through and so in our
bottom image here we show an example
object you can see that it implements
multiple interfaces and that can be any
interface that the programmer chooses
however the one interface that it must
implement which is defined by comm is
the ion milling interface so every
common object must have the I unknown
interface on the side here we have a
breakdown of our MMC
- oh application class this is kind of
used for command-line snap-ins and it's
default on windows in the bottom pane
there you can see that it influenced a
couple interfaces and among them is I
unknown and I dispatch so with comm out
of the way we can talk about decom and
become simply is an extension of comm
that allows objects be exposed and
callable over a network in a distributed
manner hence its name distributed calm
be calm uses RPC as its primary
transport protocol where RPC is the
protocol that allows services or client
access services across the network on a
remote machine and since RPC uses a
client-server model this means that code
is executed on the remote server and so
this is why comm works as a lateral
movement technique without this code
execution on a remote server you're not
going to get very far so this is why
again this is a workable protocol for
lateral movement so within RPC there are
a couple different calls one of these is
bind and this allows a comm interface to
be attached and then you can use the
alter context call to kind of navigate
between these bound interfaces and
interact with the different methods that
that was exposed so those two calls will
come up a little bit later as well
and then after binding messages can then
be passed using very specific structures
so this is how it's going to be seen on
the wire so in the decom request we
start out with a simple RPC header
followed by something called an RPC that
this structure and in this structure
there are a few things such as the comm
version being used any flags or
extensions and something known as a CID
or a causality identifier this allows
calls to kind of be related to each
other and this is finished off by any
method arguments that there may be decon
response looks pretty similar we have
another RPC header but instead this time
we have in our QC that structure this is
pretty simplified and only contains the
flags and extensions and this also ends
with any method return arguments and
we're gonna be getting into a lot more
detail about these method arguments
later on
so now that you got a brief overview we
wanted to give you another overview and
focus more on the offensive side so
starting with calm broadly calm is an
extremely useful functionality that
allows adversaries to accomplish
different techniques or different
tactics across their life cycle it's
beneficial for a number of reasons in
general there's been the whole living
off the land craze everyone's probably
heard about this kind of falls within
that living off the land in the sense
that it is native in the windows
functionality you don't have to bring
anything along to use it therefore
minimizing what you introduce to the
environment which is always a good thing
as a bad guy but even more so this has
beneficial because it's so legacy and so
poorly documented that it's very hard
for people who might stumble on the
during an investigation to understand it
so it increases that cost of how people
having to dive in and do your research
to do defense which is never a good
thing you don't want to be in the middle
of a VES investigation reading MSDN
articles it's a painful process so they
can be used a couple different places as
I mentioned a lot of the endpoint focus
talks and blogs out there such as the
one by Casey and Matt at the bottom of
the slide they focus a lot on the code
execution and persistence components of
comm and so we're gonna let you go read
dot has anyone read that hints yeah cool
all right so a couple people it's a very
great talk I highly recommend it we're
gonna focus on this middle category
which is lateral movement now most of
you might know but you're enterprises
have calm objects that enable lateral
movement all over them so all of these
allow lateral movement pretty much the
entire Microsoft Office package enables
calm objects in the local Windows System
that exposed abilities to run command
lines or load dll's
same thing with the MMC object which is
built into systems so this this is a
problem and it's just about everywhere
so we'll start with the demos and the
demo is to walk through how to find an
abusable object so how our researchers
finding these first I want to show that
on this system in my demo my default
implicit privilege or permission is set
to administrators to allow comm
launching so with that assumption that
administrators implicitly cannot launch
comm we can go in here we can search for
all comm objects using a tool called
Ollie view net for anywhere
launch permission is not set on the
common object what that means is
administrators are allowed to run these
objects implicitly you can see the MMC
application is in fact allowed allows
administrators to run it through the
implicit permission so remotely if I'm
an administrator I can use it that's not
always the case now exploring this
object can be quite simple you can just
load up the object using something like
PowerShell and simply use the help
documentation the best way to understand
a lot of these objects is just reading
the help so I'm using git member here's
a command to essentially lift the help
and I'm exploring the object and listing
the different functions involved in
listing what's in play so with that in
mind let's take the next step let's use
that object that we just explored which
we know can be launched by an
administrator maliciously so in this
demo we essentially are going to do the
first command which is get type from
program ID essentially activating and
loading that object I'm sorry it's it's
Stan shading an object to the object and
we're gonna create instance which
actually activates it that's when the
network protocols begin and then we're
gonna use a function that was exposed by
that object simple function named
execute shell command pre blinding in
the face and we're gonna run a
calculator on the remote host again
calculator could be anything from
PowerShell to any other executable you
want to run any of the law bins and
other things so three lines of code
native windows functionality code
execution requires an administrator like
most of lateral movement techniques a
little bit more of a fun one is Excel so
Excel actually allows you through decom
to load up Excel L plugins which are
essentially a Microsoft Office plugin in
Excel so in this case you're not
spawning any command-line arguments
necessarily like you would be in the
previous case in this case you're gonna
plant the DLL on the remote system using
I don't SMB and then you're gonna have
Excel forcibly load that DLL and the DLL
is just a standard like standard export
standard DLL it can have any
functionality you want doesn't have to
be formatted specifically and when you
load it you can have it do whatever you
want so in this case we pop calcs and
again
the loading the DLL kind of gets around
that command line stuff of having to use
like execute shell command anytime you
can force your defenders this crazy to
post-it notes and printouts to do
protocol re you succeeded as an attacker
so this is after a a month of diving in
on the protocol and trying to write
parsers for it Alex had literally gone
mad and wearing tinfoil hats and post-it
notes on paper it was the best way he
could find to figure a lot of this out
so that we can get into a bit of the
behavioral analysis of decom
so justin kind of walked through a
little bit an example of how to find
abusable objects we're going to talk a
little bit more about what exactly we're
looking for in those he mentioned the
launch permission detail that's nice as
it can kind of allow an attacker to have
a bit more of a broader scope on the
user's they target so instead of
targeting a very specific user who's
allowed to access an object they can
target general administrators with the
lack of launch permission but by far the
most important detail is that the
objects must have functionality to load
or execute code without it again you're
not going to get very far so looking for
those specific functions that allow
either you know DOL execution or you
know straight command line execution
that's what attackers are going to be
looking for and in general there are a
couple different ways for people who are
just curious to be looking for these
there are a few different ways to do it
obviously justin showed off all you view
net that was a great tool for us it's
what a lot of the initial researchers on
decom used to explore this kind of thing
but for an adversary they're not going
to want to go ahead and you know start
dropping that so they can use a couple
different methods one of them is remote
registration so they can remotely query
the registry on a remote system to kind
of start a numerating and understanding
what objects they have on that system
what objects they may want to target
also there's an awesome class in WMI
called win32 decom application this can
be used to help enumerate all of the D
column arguments or objects on a system
so when it comes to D comms network
behavior there are three main phases
there's the activation phase and this is
where an object is instantiated on the
remote host there's a series of optional
type operations this is basically where
the client resolves any function
information understand a little bit more
about how to call these functions and
then there's the execution phase where
they're selected execution or they're
selected function is then executed so
we're gonna go into depth on each of
these phases a bit more we're gonna use
our MMC - oh application object within
powershell as our primary example so
what justin demoed earlier and so when
it comes to the activation phase these
were the network functions that occurred
so first there are these i oxidant
operations and this is where the client
binds to the remote RPC server then
there is a series of authentication and
authorization requests making sure the
client is good to go once that gets the
thumbs up PowerShell in this case since
that's what we're using issues and I
system activator remote get class object
requests and this basically will provide
a handle to a class factory that will
create that will eventually be creating
the object that they requested and so
this occurs within the AI class factory
operations so that's where the at the
object itself is actually fully
instantiated and ready to use and then
another handle is passed back so that
the client can begin to operate with it
and so each step here actually creates a
whole bunch of network chatter back and
forth so these are kind of generic
overview phases but within each of these
you could have anywhere from two to
eight packets back and forth for the RPC
requests and responses so quite a bit of
network chatter involved during this
phase yeah so a lot of this is pretty
loud a lot of this is pretty easy to
take a look at and detect so here's a
screenshot of Wireshark specifically a
remote gate class object the request so
this is what the client is sending to
the server saying hey I want this object
to be instantiated
within the stub data as you can see
specifically at offset hex 0 1 EI we
have a CLS ID so this is the object that
the client is asking the server to
create for them
and so once we kind of ungentle it
there's some interesting formatting for
the clsid so once you piece that back
together
we get down at the bottom there so again
since this is a well-known clsid we can
take it to the web and try and figure
out what was created again for this
example we're using the application
object so of course that's what shows up
and you can see the CLS ID matches
exactly that within the packet so this
is a great option for when you want to
understand kind of what's going on in
your environment you can take these you
can collect these and then start to get
a baseline of what of what objects are
being used and furthermore what objects
may have execution capabilities so now
there's this series of I type info
operations and the I type info is an
interface that allows a client to start
to query and understand how functions
need to be called so since this is
happening at runtime they need to get
things such as they need to understand
how a function needs to be called on the
server and this is provided
automatically through I dispatch so
there's gonna be three functions that
we're going to go through we're gonna go
through get func desk which is for
function resolution purposes we're going
to get names which is for property and
function name resolution as well as get
documentation which of course handles
any help documentation retrieval so
here's a screen shot of what the I type
info operations look like in Wireshark
as you can see it's kind of a mess it's
pretty hard to understand exactly what's
going on here it actually took us a
while to understand what these
operations were we had to kind of tie it
all the way back to at the I type info
interface and it's really only giving
you a high-level so I can see okay
something's happening with I type info I
don't know what and I also it's gonna be
a real pain for me to understand at a
lower level what's going on here so this
is something that we're gonna return to
later when we talk about how we went on
to wire to modify Wireshark to help
improve the parsing capability
specifically for this interface so again
first function that we're going to talk
about is get func test and this is used
to allow a client to query for
information about how to call a specific
function so if some of the returns to
this are
such as how many parameters of function
has what are their types so there are
primitive types as well as any return
types and stuff like that so gives the
client a good understanding of how to
call this function so within the request
we provide what's known as a function
index and this is kind of in the in the
peek apps you'll kind of see this
counter rolling up as the clients like
I'm curious about this function curious
about this function hears about this
function and so on so in this one we're
seeing a function index of hex 21 and
this blue section right here these are
the method arguments that I was talking
about before so pretty much you can
think about anything above that is the
previous decom like the RPC headers as
well as the RPC this structure but that
blue part is the method arguments and
then when we get to the response from
the server for this specific function
again the blue is going to be the method
return arguments for the decom response
we get a couple things we get the full
function description which contains all
the stuff that I described before and a
little bit more and we also get what's
known as a member ID and this member ID
in this case is hex 36 and this is what
we're going to be using in future calls
to identify what function the client is
curious about and what's the query
information for so the next function get
names and people generally prefer to
call functions by name rather than some
kind of you know weird hex number we're
you know whatnot names are always great
for people so that's what this function
helps to do so it'll resolve any
function names and parameter names for a
client so in the request we're gonna
pass in that member ID that we got from
that last function this case hex 36 and
then the response is going to give us
just that so you may be able to make out
in the hex dump on the side some ASCII
strings in there specifically we see
execute shell command which is the
command that we're interested in and we
also see the parameters that that
command takes which are command
directory parameters and window state so
again this can be consumed by a client
and then presented to a user
and then finally we have to get
documentation and this of course is
sometimes users need a little bit of
help understanding what exactly a
function does they want to check and
make sure that this is the right
function that they want to execute this
is you know get all that information so
that's what this function helps to
provide specifically again in the
request we're passing in our hex 36
member ID because that's the function
that we're interested in and we're also
passing in a series of flags and this
will tell the server what kind of help
documentation we're interested in in
this case we're passing in saying that
we want the help file and any docstrings
and again we get a full response from
the server containing full ascii strings
that can then be consumed by a client
presented to a user and this is
typically going to be seen in scripting
languages so things like powershell are
gonna use this and consume it and
present it to a user and now the final
phase is execution and so for execution
we use the I dispatch invoke function
and this will invoke a given function on
the remote server so again in the
request we're passing in our hex 36
member ID as that's the function we want
to execute and we're also passing in any
relevant parameters that this function
takes now remember from get func desk we
now know what parameters the function is
expecting there types and whatnot so we
have a good idea of how to call this you
can see down in the hex dump of the
request you can make out an ASCII string
that's a path to calc PXE so again you
can start to see within the package
exactly where you might be able to pick
out where potential adversaries might be
dropping their commands again calculate
XC probably not that useful for an
adversary so they can use whatever
whatever they want there in terms of the
response it'll provide us any output
that that function has in this case this
function does not provide any output so
that's where that null string is coming
from but we do get provided a standard
constant which will tell us whether or
not function execution was even
successful in this case we get the Sok
constant meaning that we would have
achieved lateral movement had we or I
guess we popped calc exe in this case
so drawing that all together here's kind
of a lot of you know going through
Wireshark screenshots so pulling it all
back together
we know that the member ID relates to a
specific function that the client is
interested in whether or not they're
executing it such as in this case or if
they're querying for specific
information such as in the previous eye
type info operations but that memory ID
came from the get func desk of the eye
type info operation so you can kind of
trace it all the way back and you can
even go further so we know that all of
these operations are relating to a
single function exposed by the object
clsid that we requested in the very
first place so by chaining that all
together we now have a full
understanding of exactly what was
occurring because we can pass back we
can even kind of replicate we can look
at the get names we can understand what
function is being run what parameters
are being passed and relate that all the
way back to an object which is pretty
cool so with this behavioral analysis
complete we can start to define some
criteria for detection and we're gonna
do that with three different criteria
sets we're going to talk about strict
criteria and these are components of an
attack chain that are required to be
present for the attack chain to even
exist in the first place we also have
loose criteria and these are criteria
that are in the adversaries control so
for example we probably don't want to be
looking for the string calc dot exe
right because an adversary could change
that up they can change what they want
to run they can decide they have full
control over these criteria and then
there's also exclusion criteria and
these are things that appear to be part
of a check chain at first but are
actually benign so we want to exclude
exclude these so think kind of about
detection tuning so you want to tune out
kind of the noise to get to the real the
real bad and all of these kind of work
together in boolean operations so you
can see in our diagram how we want to
add together any strict criteria we have
because we want to make sure that those
exist every single time before detection
fires then we want to order together any
loose criteria because these are things
that could change but we want to make
sure that they're still included and
then finally we want to not out any
exclusion criteria because we want to
disregard any of that criteria before we
decide to alert that detection
so we're turning back to decom these are
our criteria analysis so in terms of
strict criteria we know that activation
must be done with a relevant Hewitt or
clsid so that must be present for the
attack chain to exist and that that CL
clsid
must relate to an object with code
execution functionality because again if
it doesn't you're not looking at much
lateral movement in terms of loose
criteria we know that the clsid can vary
so Justin pointed out a couple different
methods of how to obtain lateral
movement and that was through various
different objects so that clsid will
change and there may be I type info
operations depending on how the common
object is explored so in our powershell
example it would actually explore every
single function that an object had to
offer we also tried weaponizing this in
something like python and that only
explored the function that we decide to
execute so it can vary depending on what
language the attacker decides to use
there may also be a series of I dispatch
invoke depending on you know how many
functions they want to run specifically
like their commands and their parameters
are going to change and the objects
instantiation can vary so in our example
I class factory create instance was used
to kind of use a class Factory which the
client then had to build the object off
of but I system activate here also
offers remote create instance which will
actually instantiate the object directly
and so actually in PowerShell as I
mentioned it was using the AI class
factory operation in Python it did it
directly so is going straight to AI
system activator remote create instance
so that's a case where you want to make
sure that you have multiple signatures
that will pick up on both techniques and
this really hammers home the importance
of doing a good behavioral analysis and
testing a wide variety of tools and
techniques because those little details
and artifacts are really what can break
detection logic and detection scenarios
in the real world exactly and then for
exclusions we want to get rid of any
systems that may use D comm for normal
operations obviously we don't want to go
up flagging benign systems that are
known to use decom in their standard
day-to-day use and this is greatly aided
by
data set so being able to look across an
environment and say okay these are the
systems that are using decon now these
are what objects are being used we can
start to funnel those into exclusion
criteria and say when we want to start
detecting bad we're gonna push those off
to the side because we don't want to get
many false positives off those systems
so lots of bits and bytes everyone's
hanging in there so now we're going to
jump into the fun part actually catching
the bad so I mentioned that I was a red
team or like the like to do a lot about
this is this is what gets me excited now
so before we go too deep into specifics
on decon detection or NSM one of the
level sets some more detection concepts
so if ever anyone's ever heard of Dave
Bianco's like pyramid of pain or you
ever read any other recent stuff coming
out with rich Balak or Rob early there's
various definitions over what defines an
indicator or what like how how detection
logic should be authored think in
general the the general acceptance is is
there a wide array of indicators so what
what a lot of people who might not have
deep threat intelligence experience
would call an indicator would be like an
IP address or a domain like purely
atomic indicators and that is an
indicator it's one form of an indicator
but when you start talking like reliable
detection you have to expand that
mindset to understand there's a wide
spectrum of indicators so that the
atomic indicators is one if you have
what I generically call simple
behavioral indicators so these would be
like single singular events and rich
data on top of singular events you're
really looking at a snapshot or point in
time it's behavioral because it means
that something has happened it's event
based not entity based but it's not
quite difficult and this can be done
with things like Zika bro any Simms or
event automation systems can do very
simple matching with queries and that's
where this falls then you have complex
behavioral indicators it's all the rage
nowadays you want fancy machine learning
models it's really just statistics and
you want to strap that on and know and
anomalies are occurring or when
novelties have been introduced to the
network and that starts getting into
multi event scenarios and when you start
looking at multiple events having to
chain those or understand behavior or
cross events that's that's a different
form of indicator altogether and if
for implementation these qualities or
these indicators will have various
qualities as well so in general there's
a very generalized statement which is
dangerous on a stage on camera but I
think in general the average case
complex behavioral indicators are robust
because they're very abstracted so they
look at behaviors across events the
adversary would have to be a lot more
careful across a longer lifecycle to be
able to evade whereas atomic indicators
they can simply just buy a new server
and change their IP or they can buy a
new domain name for twenty nine cents on
Black Friday and Namecheap and just keep
rolling these two to change up now that
does increase the cost of their
operations but they're a little bit
weaker on the other hand fidelity
complex behavioral indicators are so
broad that it captures a wide array of
activity including a lot of potentially
system administrator activity and it's
also not generally not specific to an
adversary a lot of times it's it's
specific to some behavior that an
adversary is using that might be similar
whereas atomic indicators at least for
that small time period it's specific to
that bad guy
generally obviously their shared hosting
environments and many complications here
so one more concept to understand to do
reliable detection specifically with
decom so imagine this dotted line
burning of science II imagine this
dotted line represents an adversaries
technique the attack surface so this is
a two dimensional space which represents
all the possible ways with many infinite
numbers of dots of all the possible ways
that a bad guy could in percent
implement a technique so we have dots
and those dots represent variations of
that technique to be very applied in
this case imagine weaponizing decom
attack and powershell and leveraging
decon lateral movement python to
variations
they're both decon lateral movement
might air attack causing the same thing
but they're different they have
different artifacts and they fill this
attack space our goal as detection
analysts is to form detections of many
types with many different specificities
and broadness levels to fill this space
we want to be able to capture every
technique one detection might cover
multiple techniques very rarely does one
detection cover all techniques so
there's a chance we might need multiple
detection logic here
and then even more fun if your detection
is too broad you start to get false
positives you fall outside the box or
too narrow you get white space and white
spaces false negatives those are bad
things for detection analysts so this is
kind of the science of where we want to
go and we want to use our entire
technology stack to accomplish this for
NSM purposes which is where we live and
breathe every day we're gonna focus on
these ones there are three generic
categories we like to talk about so rule
based IDs let's think of full packet
content snorts or cata classic IDs
that's been around since the 90s these
things look at network traffic injects
and ingest that traffic and then they
based on some boolean logic or signature
they output an alert so input is network
traffic output is an alert not contacts
not packets just the fact that something
happened and generally it's full text in
etc then you have metadata extraction
based IDS's this is bro or Zeke I keep
saying bro Zeke for everyone don't know
bros a metadata IDs that was recently
renamed due to fun conflict in the name
and so this IDs it looks at all the
network data just like the rule based
IDs but instead of just alerting when it
sees something it takes the time to
actually parse out any elements or
fields from within that network data
essentially parsing metadata so elements
or fields it will not give you full
packet content so the idea here is that
you just feed all the events that are
occurring with they're important or
critical data points the this starts to
get a little bit better than rule based
IDs because it allows you to start doing
time-based analysis and full context
eventing so you can see everything
happening versus only bad thing
happening obviously with more data comes
more overhead so you start hitting
storage concerns and how do you stream
this and how do you detect on and all
this other stuff and then it gets even
more complicated when you start
introducing things like full content
fantastic capability every Network
forensics person in the world will will
swear by give me P cap or give me
nothing like it's the only thing that's
worth it this is great it can be
extremely tough to scale ask your
fortune five sort ends of the world how
much throughput they have in their
network on how long they can store that
if
have a lot of money cuz they're a
fortune five or ten maybe they're
willing to shell for it but many time
cases they're not willing to and quite
frankly the way that most people utilize
this in a soccer and a defensive
scenario is they just run a metadata
parser over all the pcap anyway and so
the primary thing they're working with
is metadata similar to Bro or Zeke and
they really only go back to that full
pcap in a limited fashion sometimes it's
even hard to go recall that full pcap
depending on the system so let's start
with Brewers Noir let's look at a
detection scenario for that MMC
application object so here's an example
signature in the white paper were
releasing with this talk we actually
provide a number of these they're fairly
plug-and-play this is meant to be whack
Amole kind of you're basically looking
for the known bad or known common CL IDs
that attackers use and so in this case
we're looking for optimum number three
now Optum number three depends on what
can be used across our PC so autom
number three specifically for the MMC
object represents remote key class
object the eye system activator in this
packet we're also looking for the
characteristic meow I kind of just put
it in there because I like saying it on
stage a lot of fun I don't know why this
thing is in there I'm sure it represents
something but it's always in the
activations so it makes a really good
thing to include to help weed out any
potential matches and then the last one
the content is essentially the the hex
string looking for that clsid we know
for so take this take all the list of
all the objects that people are abusing
and plug and play class IDs and you
start to get a little bit context when
these are used we've had this deployed
these rules deployed in enterprises now
so we work in a SAS platforms we got
lots of data to play with and it
actually is a very confident signature
very simple not rocket science but with
the understanding the protocol it gives
you that context we actually had a true
positive detection on this recently with
this exact signature so it's reliable
it's it's proven it's worth so diving in
the next one a little bit more about
Zeke or bro who's used it see your car
bro all right a little bit more in the
audience and a sim people great so
metadata parser it has three key
components that allow it to do what it
does first it ingest data on the network
those full packets then go to the
eventing engine
the eventing engine in bro essentially
leverages a binary protocol
specification called bin pack these are
files that define structures of what
network traffic looks like so it's a
very high-level way to define a decom
request packet looks like this a decom
response packet looks like this
so the eventing engine uses these bin
packs to take these protocols and then
parse them into fields when it parses
those fields it then generates an
internal bro event that's internal to
the engines and then it has a scripting
subsystem that allows you to attach to
events so I can say if the decom request
happened run my script on all of that
data it's called a bro script or a Zeke
script and these are handled by these
event handlers basically consume all
these events and then do things by
default what you see the normal
functionality of bro is a whole bunch of
built in scripts that just emit logs so
you're just getting raw log data of all
the fields that happen so quite honestly
looking at this when we first ran into
this attack scenario we are seeing this
attack in the wild and we're like well
we obviously need to detect this let's
see if anything detects it and we ran it
through a bro we were kind of
dumbfounded that like nothing stuck out
same thing with Wireshark same thing
with snort it blew our minds that this
was a thing and it wasn't correctly
parsing it so we dived in we tried to
identify why why weren't we getting the
data that we expected from these open
source tools and why are many people
running these open source tools and
probably not doing this individual unit
testing being robbed of this experience
and frankly bro and Zeke's an open
source project and so anyone can
contribute to and they rely on that they
like community contribution so when we
the first object that we saw or the
first problem we saw was that our PC
which is the supported protocol by
default and the current bro version is a
very high level protocol it's a Swiss
Army knife there's many things that
happen over RPC everything from the
service controller language to the
remote registry like all of everything
you do on the Windows command line
remotely is all mostly over RPC
including decom and so there are many
different forms or subsystems
within this generic protocol and so what
is currently implemented in the version
of Zeke is a
the high-level generic piece it's the
RPC component so it's the headers and
the in point and operation that's called
but nothing specific to that operation
so a little bit more of an abstracted
not related example let's say I want to
do a service controller action across
the network I do a create service the
only thing that's logged in Zeke is the
fact that the create service happened
not the service name not the return
value not this other stuff it's its RPC
it's not the service controller language
the other piece that was really
important to understand and was was
important to Pete pick out was the fact
that there's entire functionality in
Zeke that's commented out in the RPC
parser like it was attempted to be
implemented but it didn't get all the
way there I'm sure the developer likes
this is a difficult language I'm sure he
struggled and wanted to get this out
but at the time alter context completely
commented out which means that if decom
which it does often jumps between
interface context every time you makes a
jump using alter context every log after
that's actually not just emitted it's
wrong it's completely wrong it's logging
the wrong end points to the wrong
operations because state tracking is
performed only on the binds not alter
context so important to know that if
you're using this right now you might
not be seeing the accurate logs you want
to check your version of Z so what we
try to do for the purpose of proof of
concept here to show how we could be
done as we took the easiest road we
could not necessarily the most
performant or reliable and we took every
RPC request and said for every request
we're gonna pass the stub so we're gonna
pass the stub along to the requests and
so now I'm this is not performance I
this is alpha 3 alpha extra state on
Sage I'm a researcher not an engineer
locally and so this basically allows me
to take scripts and do whatever I want
with that stub so I can say if this is
an SVC control operation parse this bury
this area and the stub and this is the
new field I want to emit and so we get
to the point where I can write scripts
like this which basically say if this is
a remote gate class object call parse
these parts of the stub and call that
the remote class ID so I can start to
parse out individual field within our PC
what this allows us to do let's rerun
this attack real quick we're gonna run
the MMC application attack what this
allows us to do is very quickly get in
and start to see when things have gone
bad so you can see here I just ran that
attack and my magic zoom in I got the
class ID of what went across the network
this is slightly improved from what I
had beginning and I also get my sir cata
alert that it recognized the same class
ID so it's a little bit better it's not
perfect but better we can start to get
telemetry over which decom objects are
being used in networks so we can get at
least a basic IDs indication of known
bad or suspicious and really the goal
here is to empower detection that's
specific with sir cotta and Zeke is
empower detection and power forensics
and so in this case I can do one of a
couple things I can just look for all
the new and bad that's the easy one you
just cross that off your list I can sit
down in 20 minutes
knock that out but then you can start to
do more fun things like I can start to
introduce statistical modeling on all of
the decom data in the network and look
for abnormalities I can start to do
anomaly detection I can start to do
first observes like the first time I
ever see a decom network up here in the
network why is it there and then I
always thought a fun project this is
sort of a sidebar but I always thought a
really fun project would be to leverage
all of this decom eventing data to try
to statistically represent human
interaction with be calm versus
programmatic or machine interaction we
be calm so like if I'm a PowerShell guy
and I'm like in PowerShell querying all
the help Docs and going back and forth
between functions that's gonna look a
lot different with the I type info
operations then if I'm a script that
simply runs one function so being able
to pick out like hey human is using V
converse as a program is might be a
really interesting problem set to use
that data for so when it comes to pcap
analysis Wireshark is to go to tool for
most people I pretty much use it daily
it's one of my favourite tools and of
course it's used extensively in
forensics and response situations for
its protocol parsing it has two main
components that help it along one our
dissectors and these are built directly
into the Wireshark binary and kind of it
early iteratively take data parse it and
hand it off to other dissectors so that
they can add more information that
eventually makes it to the end user
they're also plugins and these are
external components to Wireshark written
in Lua so these can be added in at any
time and they just generally extend wire
sharks functionality and these can
include protocol dissection as well so
again we're going to return to our
screenshot of the I type info operations
again quite a mess very high-level we
struggled for a couple hours to kind of
work through and understand what was
going on here when we first started
looking at these peak apps so Wireshark
handle law they're classic decom
operations
properly I type info completely
unemployment 'add and then a couple
other endpoints and operations lacked
full dissections so if you recall back
to the gate class object it parsed out
its name and stuff but it left the stub
there so we had to kind of dig through
and find that class ID within the byte
stream so to fix this we decided to go
ahead and add on to be Conner two wire
sharks existing decom dissector so it
exists as a dye sector not a plug-in so
we added a couple things to that and
then also added our type info that
sector along with it and so this took a
lot of protocol reverse engineering and
of course learning how to actually write
Wireshark dissectors and this was my
first time doing this as you saw from
Justin's slide I started to go a little
bit crazy in terms of how I was taking
apart this protocol so here are a couple
tips for anyone who's interested in
maybe getting started in protocol
reverse engineering or want to try and
contribute back to Wireshark the first
thing is that the existing tech sectors
and plugins were incredible for helping
me understand exactly what should be
occurring within them so they helped to
provide a structure as well as show off
any functions that already existed for
certain operations so it saved me a
bunch of time also using official
documentation specifically for the
protocols so things like RFC's and in
this case MSDN articles were incredibly
helpful as they outline exactly what a
structure should look like so things
like properties and their associated
types so you can begin to pick out where
things need to be within or what things
should exist within a series of bytes
and then by using multiple variations of
an attack so changing up parameters or I
even implemented a custom comma or decom
object so
that I could change like the number of
parameters I had the types of the
parameters you can start to pick out
known properties so you can say okay
these are probably the parameters this
is probably an array showing all the
parameters here this is the length of
the array at such-and-such and this is
the result so now you can see that the I
type info operations are fully parsed
and dissected not only can you tell
exactly what operation is occurring but
also you get a full breakdown of what's
occurring within them and this is
something I'm going to be trying to
contribute and make a pull request to
Wireshark when we get back so we're
network people we obviously sit up on
the stage a bunch talk to all about the
network but we'd be silly to not mention
end point simple fact of the matter is
is bad guys evade just like they know
that people are watching they try to
evade so let's say they're focusing
purely on evading the network anyone
who's doing detection on the enterprise
scale really needs to rely on both your
network data and your endpoint data and
your application logs and the whole mix
of that and so we'd be negligent to not
talk at least I slide about endpoint do
you know that there are ways for
adversaries to evade alter context is an
obvious one given the current
implementation packet privacy you can
actually force the packet contents of
RPC to be encrypted so we miss all the
underlying decom stuff well note here
though that in most networks I'd say
almost all the ones we monitor like this
isn't a thing yet it's coming but it's
not a thing so if you start implementing
packet privacy as an adversary it's
actually an indicator like you turning
on encryption stands out to me because
it's not normally there it's not the
default domain setting so command line
is king for endpoint on this stuff I'll
note that when any time you launch a
decom process so let's say we're using
an outlet comm object it spawns over SVC
it spawns under the decom Launch SVC
host
it is very easy to say which decom mob
or which processes are spawning under
this host and which ones should be and
should not be so like Outlook probably
shouldn't be spawning random become
services all the time and then another
one is a lot of the office applications
have command line parameters - embedding
or / automation for their decom objects
when they start up so it could be a good
thing to go look for and this is this is
implemented by the actual underlying
services themselves so we'll run in
short on time big takeaways we want you
to walk away with the detection the
repeatable and resection process to
evaluate your tools emulate that
adversary
look at those components that are
involved conducting analysis to identify
strict and loose components build
detection criteria around that test it
out deploy and gain advantage if your
tools don't allow you to do it better
the tools that's what they're there for
in many of the open source cases in the
non decomp specific take away is kind of
that raw mission like we're there to
detect bad guys on the defensive side
and if you're a red team or a pen tester
you're there to help us detect bad guys
so it's it's all a big happy community
work together understand the threats and
figure out how to stop them
understanding is a key component that
you have to start with you have to
understand the protocols you have to
understand the threats so I think we
have one minute so we might be able to
get a question and luckily only one
question yes or you guys are holding
back appreciate that
Oh
[Music]
that's a great question the question was
how do you implement this in a cloud
environment TLDR like you know you have
to worry about other people's
environments too so two answers to that
or one explanation there are network
monitoring capabilities that are in
cloud native capabilities but they're
mostly their flow so you don't get not
only do you not get RPC level data
you're not getting Beacom data you're
not getting any of the bottom neath you
could look at port numbers you could
look at flow behaviors most of these
cloud environments our server lands and
so like should your servers be even
exposing this do you see connections to
them etc that's a very Wild West
approach in practice I would say that'd
be very difficult flow data is actually
very hard to do not reliable detecting
around there's another approach which is
many vendors I will not do too much
vendor pitching many vendors sell
technology that would get you full pcap
data on in the cloud environments there
are pluses and minuses to that in
throughput and bandwidth and processing
power and stuff but there is ways there
are ways to gain full pcap contents
inside the cloud environments you might
be something you select on your crown
jewel servers my honor on a small subset
but we've seen success with that
technique and gaining some visibility
and that is it for me I am up on time
thank you guys for attending
[Applause]