hey everyone good afternoon I'm impact
at home its Naga I'm really lucky to be
here because my two days ago my fright
Narita to here was the shelter then I
got reassigned flight to yesterday but
it was delayed so I'm not sure I think
I'm here but finally I'm here so I'm
glad to see you all thank you our title
is a real-time detection of attack
Rivers degree domain administrator
pre-baked knew our talk focuses on
Active Directory and the machine
learning we are from University of Tokyo
and back home it's Naga and Vitaly
Matsuda and America Yugi moto
we will search in the talk so University
we're doing a research on cyber security
or a security FinTech security and we
are also providing cyber security
training not only for students but also
industrial people or government the
people we sometimes published book or
research papers and our new books will
be published next to you so this is
agenda of our talk first
we explain purpose and background as an
introduction and then we talk about
previous research and proposed method
which is combining sugar based detection
and the machine running then we'll show
you the demonstration our method and the
tourists then concludes so other
introduction in the targeted attack
Active Directory tend to be a target but
occurs because if they get the mini
administrator account Xing can control
everything inside Eddy environment
and the after they obtained
administrator account
sometimes they create backdoor called
wouldn't get it is not so easy to detect
the golden ticket obvious because they
use golden ticket they can disguise
themselves as a resonate domain
administrator so in this talk we will
explain the tools and the detection
method which is combining a signature
base and massive running detection using
analyzing the event of route to detect
attacker activities including golden
ticket so once Active Directory active
directory is a centralized management
system or Windows computers and accounts
if you use any environment it is so easy
and effective to control machine and
accounts so many companies use the
domain environment but on the other hand
if attacker get a dooming account in
domain they can control everything
so ad tend to be a target for attackers
so this is example flow of attacking
Eddy after attacker interviewed inside
network there they try to get try to
obtain the ad environment this is number
three under after they can get any
account idea Demi account they try to
move different servers rack file server
this is number four because after they
get at me account they can move to
everywhere inside ad domain
in our presentation we focuses on the
phase 3 and phase 4 which is attacking
ad domain controllers so Gordon's get is
the backdoor against the ad which is
introduced Blackwater USA 2014 if they
create this guerrilla to get back door
they can use golden ticket for wrong
time like 10 years and they can pretend
as rhythmic admin account so it isn't so
easy to find what is it to detect the
attackers activity this is the image of
how to explain the difficulty of a
dedicated orange get the roofed one the
green a low means their usual operation
by limited me account they use the
account to domain controller and the
account name is DC Adam II and the left
one is attack activities after you they
interviewed the network they can get the
compromised account to write to user 101
and then they use if they use govern
hCAP they can pretend this girl's
account with a privilege like a DC Adam
E and then they use their this guy's
account with domain controller so in
terms of domain controller monitoring it
is not easy to tell the difference
between usual operation and the Ithaca
activities
that means the windows commands in
addition to attack tours for instance in
this case an attacker impersonates
himself as a domain administrator DC at
me and then removed access to the domain
controller and execute some windows
commands such as IP config and these
activities are recorded in a domain
controllers event logs but if the
teammate domain administrator also use
the same command so it is difficult to
differentiate attackers acquit
activities from normal operations from
event logs so this is our proposal
mossad so we implemented a real-time
detection tool for attack activities by
virtue domain administrator privilege
including golden ticket and our tools
yun use full signature based detection
and machine learning but because and
they have advantages and disadvantages
and the signature breadth detection can
eard
high recall rate by using several
signatures but on the other hand a first
positive can occur depending on the
developer ations then so our to
reanalyze the rocks by using machine
running in order to reduce a false
positive rate by comparing rocks with
daily operations so this is a problems
of the signature base infections so we
have a bra creased over some windows
command but for instance IP config is a
one-off command into progressed
so if rich tomato domain administrator
use IP config in their operations
signature based detection as detects it
is attacks because IP config is included
in the forest
on the other hand a machine-learning can
detect it is normal because
ipconfig is used in daily operations so
this is a structure of our proposal
method so when someone access to the
domain controller the activities are
recorded in the event log on the domain
controller and blogs are sent to the
absorber in real-time
and at first a looks is analyzed by the
signature based detection and then next
Android's by the machine running and if
any attack activities are detected our
system center of words to system
administrator so we used only domain
controllers event logs for input data so
activities occurred in Windows systems
are recorded in event works on each
computers but it is not realistic to
investigate event rocks of all computers
so the reason why we focused on the
domain controllers event log is a to
pretend to access the domain controller
in order to create golden ticket and
there are a lot of event IDs but we only
used a specific events so which
attackers activities which golden ticket
are recorded so we extract and this
following the data items and used for
input at first we explain about
signature based detection and severe
existing approaches have been proposed
but we found that a several approaches
are needed in order to detect a
sophisticated attack such as golden
ticket so we pick up a severe use for
existing message
and organize a specific detection
signatures like this at first a
signature is monitors are expected
administrative privileges it is useful
food and detecting a privilege
escalation by an activities so there is
a very famous vulnerabilities or
privilege escalation so Amazon 14 + 6 8
so it is used in many targeted attacks
and this signature is relatively easy to
detect so it is useful for detect attack
activities in every stage and a civil
service monitors execution of the see
arrow I tools which attack or tend to
use so at occurs sometime use a Windows
command such as net or 80 etc so in
order to expand infections or steal
informations so we register this command
and in the practice because this command
are tend to be used by attackers but
these are a burrito in Windows command
so legitimate administrator also use
these commands so in these situations of
course forces can occur so that's why we
utilize machine running so signature see
use the monitors the use of
administrative shell resource
administrative share resource is a
special hidden and network services and
attacker often use administrative shell
in order to touch at actors or steal
information and to nature these monitors
suspicious caravels
authentication of which is suspected to
accordion to get attacks then attacker
use a golden ticket
TCT requests events are not to record it
before the service request
so from here water we've explained about
machine running oh I'll see mentioned
the using using breast lead to false
positive so we compare robust with the
daily operations to reduce false
positive but it's difficult to create or
men maintained of white restore
characteristic manually so app reporter
method it learning a daily operations
using unsupervised machine learning our
system not only daily operation works
we don't need attack rogues if our
system detect unusual behavior it can be
attack you behavior this red shows over
V of detection after all supported me so
to learn only domain controller event
rocks related to the process because at
akkad activity is recorded as the event
related to the process so we've we focus
on process almond so to use unsupervised
learning to to detect on user command
execution on this assist should be the
inventor was only of the normal state
she do not containers of an attack this
is premise and we use eventuaiiy domain
controllers even drops ID four six eight
eight and four six seven four four six
eight eight has or executed cannot
information on the other hand four seven
four husband specific command
information but it has detail
information so we use both event ID for
both data set we need pre process we
discovered some data commonly included
in if every raagas
vigorous of environment because they are
user s they had no future for detection
of example addresses and services dot X
they are discarded and we combat from
character to numbers using one hot
encoding but we know with one cross s um
it is an unsupervised algorithm
it optimizes decision function for
mobility detection with only one level
and we we've already adjusted hyper
parameter to get best to result in real
and gamma are hyper parameters and we
evaluate using this metric precision and
recall so this is a result of detection
rate but you can see machine learning
reduce false positive
so only signature-based the number of
cores per chip is 17 but combination of
signature and machine learning so for
specific only six as a result we
achieved the prison rate its husband
improved we achieved the modern 90% to
the core and prison rate we implement
our proposal method using elastic stock
for real-time detection arrow stick
stock is open-source product for
correcting on writing and visualizing
the event orders the elastics elastics
taqueria right this item is a windowed
event office under detected in almost
all their time on send or a train attack
detected a special curry now we
implement a like this the first the
window quit this it's logged transfer
agent is installed in domain controller
window go be the central event rules to
elastic stark window beetle receive
event rose and launch the detection
problem of programs the first of a
system called signature based detection
process and if much signature our
systems and our odd and vidyard with
Shobana but in case of matt single
signature this is suspicious commando
execution
our system call sis machine learning
process and if machine learning process
judge suspicious suspicious activity of
process of a system also sent a lot
email for notification and this red
sauce demonstration scenario on TC if
the premise that this is precondition of
scenario so the de tomato domain
administrator its TC adami DC Adame
access domain controller using domain
users PC under DC a domain often use IP
config and ping command in daily
operations but DC Adam II does not use
80 per month in daily operations and
destroy Isis attack outside attack hub
already compromised the target Network
and the domain administrator account DC
Odom under his computer it his computer
and coordinator is created to by
attacker annexed and we will show that
the most recent movie but our
demonstration for us this scenario first
attacker access domain controller in
within PS exact PS exactly remote access
tool using golden ticket
an attacker executive eighty comment on
the domain controller the signature
based detection can detect on 84 mod
successfully because it's on the brach
forest machine gun also detect 80
command because it's not it's not the
user in daily operations finally of a
system send email to security operators
okay now you will see at this moment
first no I'll show the a socket activity
attack outside so now you are watching
the current OPC and I can to them it
becomes a tea this is the row car user
account to name this PC is already
compromised by attackers
okay Attica execute mimic odds mini
heart is very famous hacking tool for
Windows computer Attica with golden
ticket attacker in tech - Gordon
staccato into the memory no so if this
is a golden ticket information here the
trying to name it to DC Auto me using
this domain using this golden ticket
attacker can impersonate as DC attorney
and here the expiration year date is
very wrong almost 10 years is the
characteristic of the cordon ticket and
the attacker access the domain
controller using PSD common TSM
decreased demote access to attack access
to domain controller successfully if the
desert of who Amari attacker in count
this impersonator at DC Adam
successfully in this situation attack
attack attack attack attack tivity is
recorded as DC Ottomans activity an
attacker can execute any commando one
attacker want to do but in this
demonstration attack I use 80 command 80
command is used for used for tasks
schedule management attacker executive
cannot for investigation okay next let's
take a look at defend outside Security
administrative display here this given
key panel shows Windows Event office and
you can insult attack crooks easily
using filtering function now we filter
and the keyboard attack here you can
easily find out what was going on on the
domain controller 80 commando is
executed but it's very difficult to keep
watching keep on a display so our system
send email
for notification you receive the email
uncivil Judas with several emails Adil
cancel you can see several signatures a
lot and this is the last email this
e-mail tell you the executed executed
process name and compromised IP address
and account this information very is
very important very beautiful to respond
against computer security incident
quickly our demonstration is all thank
you so this our consideration of force
detections at first a first- can occur
if the offering and conditions are
satisfied at the same time at first
attacker use the same command with
legitimate administrator and second
attacker compromised resume to me
administrator accounts and their
computers because in these situations
there is no difference between autocracy
activities and resubmit administrators
activities in event rocks and avert or
cannot detect the Windows command which
are not included in the perk rest but in
these difficult situations there is a
possibility that our Mossad can detect
attack because etapa uses a similar
command not only single command and we
prepare several signatures and next the
first footstep can occur if commands
that are not frequently used in daily
operations are used by attackers so
avert sir need a certain period for
running normal operations so this is a
conclusions the abuse of a domain
administrator private means a pocket of
Directory environment is a flow control
of attackers so we need immediate
actions but a detection is very
difficult if a legitimate account and
windows command are abused like a
coordinated attacks and our message can
detect attacks even if the difficult
situation in timely manner so our tour
here
our immediate in incident response and
for future works we are planning to
analyze the appendix of a client
computers for further investigation and
we published our detection tools on on
our github it's free to use for
reference and if you have any questions
please contact this email and we are
going to introduce our detection tools
in an Arsenal section tomorrow so if you
have interested in our missile so please
visit our pers so thank you for about
tensions
[Applause]