everybody thanks for coming to my talk
it's super exciting to see people
responding to some hard work and and I
think it's interesting as well right
soon and I want to thank as well a black
it for having me
despite the cute name that I gave the
talk and that's good that it unto it so
my name is van min sure I'm a software
search from Israel for my day job I like
to I like to take on challenges that
involve a lot of reverse engineering be
it OS kernels firmwares your name it and
I grew a special conclusion with
vulnerability has been doing up in
abilities a long time now and I grew an
appreciation for exotic bugs and have
the special privilege today to tell you
about such an exotic bug that have found
recently in the windows fragmentation
mechanism and the reason I think it's
interesting well one reason is it's
quite a simple bug really it's quite
even a stupid mistake and nonetheless it
has a really significant impact on the
security of the system and quite you'll
see it's quite the opposite the
intention of the designers had been and
another reason is well it really is a
simple bug
it has been on the surface of a driver
like tcp/ip sis a lot disappear pieces
and which is something that I'd
considered well picked clean before and
not the best target for reverse
engineering and vulnerability hunting
but well and this bug which really
should have been found using automated
tools in the security design lifecycle
that they have well has existed for the
past five and a half years and this
makes me think that there are such bugs
lurking simple bugs and I encourage you
really to explore such well pillars of
Windows is TCP accusation and you will
find out such bugs and therefore it's
worthwhile to I think we
maybe the fragmentation and such thing
that were the choir erlik's of the path
maybe in attacks and some of them have
been brought back to life now but let's
quickly recap fragmentation and
fragmentation is really when I'm I'm
standing a packet that's too large for
the underlying link layer and in this
situation what happens is any router in
the middle and also myself as they at
the sender we are allowed to split this
packet into small fragments and in this
case so that we can reconstruct it
the other secret we constructed we
assign all the fragments that have the
say that they belong to the same packet
we assign them the same identification
identification is a field on the
fragment we assign the same to the same
IP or we also call it IP ID
we assign the same IP ID to all the
fragments that belong to the same packet
there's also a notion of offsets within
the packet and a flag that tells us
whether or more there are more fragments
coming up or this is the end of the
packet another thing is that the
fragments that are not yet completed to
a full packet are stored in a cache of
the of the reassembling part and the
last fact about fragmentation is that
it's an oddly cursed and we've known
that for a long time actually from at
least 87 and what these guys mean is
that that there's an implicit trust
between the reassembling part and the
sender and that that it that the sender
wouldn't bombard them with fragments
blowing up the resources the caches and
creating a denial of service and this is
not the final denial of service the left
and a lip service to be found in
fragmentation letter there has been for
example we blacked out on the name of
the vulnerability but there have been
vulnerable ities in the implementations
wide widely affecting but widely
affecting vulnerabilities but in the
modern times they're less and less but
I'm gonna burn a reference another
another service vulnerability in
fragmentation itself but I think there's
more there are more interesting things
to to be found with with the
fragmentation one of them is has it has
been found is a as a great way to evade
IDs and the way you do it is you'd send
multiple fragments overlapping fragments
this is one way to do it and the
fragments the IDS wouldn't know which of
the fragments to discard in case unless
it has really adequately implemented the
same exact checks as the the receiver
would and integrate an idea servation
and it's even been implemented as a
router that you send your packets
through to the sender to do it and one
this is one example another example has
been suggested by Kaminsky you know five
where you have where you play with catch
times that are different between the
between the IDs and the actual receiver
or the router again creating an IDs
evasion but I think I'm more interesting
or maybe the more interesting attacks
have been revolving around the fact that
the operating systems at a time have
implemented the algorithm to generate
the IP IDs very naively as in the form
of a global counter actually right up
until modern times 2012 2011 in
different operating systems and hackers
found creative ways created things to do
with it for example to kind to count
hosts behind a nut the other example is
to scan the network really stealthily
without exposing the IP address of the
compromised host throughout the network
but the more interesting even attack has
been suggested by Lipsky in oh three and
he was researching ways to inject
packets into TCP sessions we have to
guess predict the TCP sequence or the
and the destination port that you have
which are hard to guess and you realize
well if there's such a mechanism that
well already has this the first fragment
of the fact of the packet would have
these data valid we don't have to guess
if you only have to guess the IP ID of
the packet and the and definitely when
it's implemented there's a global
counter that it's a cool thing because
you can you can inject data into the
session the downside of this attack is
that you'd create invalid checksum but
we do know that some network gear would
either pass it ignore it pass it as if
it's okay or even fix it for you in some
other cases but a cooler attack even I
think is has been suggested later and
based on this work by Illidan Hertzberg
in 2011 and they found it in a case of a
nut and this also applies to the case of
we have tunneled network then the
network would it would do is it would
choose where to send your packet based
on the data that's in the header that's
the destination port and so they figured
if you inject decide to inject to the
first fragment and not the following
fragments and maybe the following
fragments have data that you're really
interested in then you can effectively
create you can intercept those fragments
that data if you have a house behind the
nut because you'd get the nut to route
the packets to you and they've also
found that this is a really effective
denial of service attack they claim to
have dropped 40% of fragmented network
from the traffic in their network and
yeah so obviously the vendors have
rushed in to close this issue obviously
not only in 2012 and with Windows 8
Windows have moved implementation Linux
around that time as well where they now
create a you'd get an IP ID differently
depending on the IP path and this is
their jargon and we're gonna use it and
buy a cue path I mean and they mean it's
the pair of the source and destination
IP addresses and so effectively what you
have an attacker couldn't get any IP ID
series other than his own conversation
and so everyone was happy and safe as
long as you don't touch the code but
obviously 48.1 a year later and actually
someone from prank stuff told me
informally that oh this is such a
classic bag you don't understand the
details yet but this is a cheap OC bag
we had a refactor and we change you just
change an array to a pointer and then
the size of being fine so I was curious
what's this refactor and I opened up the
disassembly and but seriously I hadn't
found anything different other than the
bug being introduced and another thing
that could be just a compiler change so
anyway let's dive into how the PID is
generated in order to understand the
attacks and the implications in the new
form so it's all about IP path and I
prepare that reminder is the source and
destination IP addresses and you build
the identification field with connecting
the sender gold base and an increment
and the base is simply just random 4
bytes random D word
innocence is books or the hash of the IP
path and you add to that a random number
out of a table of random numbers you
pick a cell by again the hash of the IP
path and so this the second part should
give you that sweet separation between
conversations that you have an IP path
or and W between conversations so this
actually can be looked really good and
until you look at the way it's
initialized so what happens is what
happens is they have to initialize the
random table the way they do it is they
allocate you don't understand really the
graph I'm explaining it they allocate a
the dynamic memory for this table it's
8,000 hex byte
and the second thing they do is now they
need to initialize it and apparently
they have been initializing it wrong
initializing only eight bytes
effectively out of the table and the
rest of it it gets worse for them is is
previously use kernel memory that the
user shouldn't be able to see because it
will help him bypass a SLR ok SLR and
definitely not a random host in the
network unauthenticated or nothing and
it gets better for us so statistically
what happens is because you get multiple
pages a lot of the pages are practically
zero you get many many zeroes and you
have the increment that you get in the
end as a zero and this is great for us
because given enough samples it's true
this for a significant number of samples
you get this true that the
identification exactly equals the base
and let's talk a little bit about this
base now that we know that the
identification is just that for many
samples the base is four random bytes or
a hash of the IP path and let's explore
the hash
well the hash is something that you I
don't expect most of you to know if
you're coming from security because it's
something that well didn't know either
it's a it's something that comes from
performance and it's called a topless
hash and quick history lesson
well they Microsoft has been the reason
it's there is Microsoft has been
implementing similar SS that's a
received site scaling and what they're
doing is what RSS does is they're
distributing the load that it takes to
process packets evenly between
processors and the way they do it is
they hatch some part of the packet with
this hash and then they use that the
hash just sang uniformly a processor but
that doesn't account for why we're doing
it in a in a on the sending side as if
it's received site scaling and be more
importantly is that doesn't
for why they're using it in a security
critical things such as the IPA
degeneration you gotta you gotta ask
Microsoft for that but what I do know is
how it works I'm gonna explain it to you
so you start off with a key and the key
is 40 bytes long initialize again booth
40 bytes long of key and they take now
Windows Windows out of that key windows
of four bytes and with those four bytes
and explaining exactly later but what
you gotta know is using the four byte
windows they create mattresses four by
four matrix that that is something out
of the key I'll explain that something
later and from each window one metrics
when and we use those mattresses against
against the input to create the hash
what we do is we take the input nibble
by nibble and each nibble is a an index
to simply an index if it's skewed then
then we take cell number two if it's F
we take some number after 15th cell and
the final result of the hash is the XOR
of all the values of all the mattresses
as indexed by the input and this gives
us some cool characteristics which I'll
give the bottom line of in a second I'm
explaining the I'm explaining the the
way that the mattresses are built and it
matrix is built with a different number
of different roles a roll of different
amount to the key should have a roll of
0 on the 8th cell that's mark there you
have two elements joined together by X
or for example the cell to its right a
roll to the RO 3 in a roll of 0 sort
together and actually have you seen if
you've seen that the cell number 8 which
is exactly the key part because it's a
roll of 0 to the key part then actually
this phenomena is true for all 2 pairs
all
two cells that have that their indices
are acts or eight of each other so well
and this is this is an example cell a
roll of to slower roll of tubes or zero
gives again the key part exactly it's
true for all the pairs of cells that
have sort of eight of their indices so
together with the fact that this has
been all along just soar arithmetics on
the base side we can see that given two
inputs of the Tash and we're talking
about the hatch and again the inputs for
the Tash is just two IP addresses that's
for example I'm standing from 1000 1 to
1000 to well four identical inputs that
only differ by one nibble and that
nibble is a sort of a to each other
you'd get identical elements up until
one element which is the curve which
would give you that key part again and
if we remind ourselves that the the ID
is that hash source um something and
it's the same something for all IP IDs
then if you if you sort two samples of
the IP side I P IDs where you have the
increment as 0 then you actually get
just out the key part so imagine that
you take two samples X or them there
would be mostly the key parts
statistically and this is great this is
exactly the opposite of what I think
they meant the separation between the
conversation you have now a strong
connection between IDs and and the key
and this gives us attack number 1 which
is key recovery and the way you do it
practically is you generate as many
samples as you can of pairs of IP paths
of IP IDs that belong to IP pets
organized with that sort of 8-1 able
difference with them you're then you
store those pairs the values of the
equities and you'd get key candidates
you can rank those kinky
and get the exact key out and you repeat
it for the rest of the key key parts but
didn't tell you what good is it for to
get that key out but if you look closely
at this real connection that we have
then we know a notification where the
increment of zero exists because it
helped us find the key it was one of
those that were correct with the key we
know the key part and we can now start
predicting IP IDs for different IP paths
so this leads us to attack number two
it's quite complicated I'll explain to
read kernel memory and the recent works
is because you can predict the IP a
comes out and if you can actually get a
sample of the IP ID that comes out now
what happens is the difference has to be
the content of that table not being 0
the content of the table is the
uninitialized kernel memory and you can
now read up to 8,000 hex of of that and
it says memory and let's see a let's see
a demo of it all right and this is sped
up what happens in the demo is we get
many many samples of these are three
candidates and we're ranking them
because we've generated many pairs of IP
paths giving us different okay these we
have found a key that's outstanding in
the ranks and we've just started to get
out some data kernel data and we're
looking them up on the tcp/ip sis memory
we found them but not spot-on with an
offset of two with an offset of 1 there
are some reasons why it happens I'm
pretty sure that it's enough to bypass
SLR and but I think there's statistic
ways to eliminate it just to get it
spot-on but I didn't go as far so going
back to the presentation
so this was attack number two getting
I'm mrs. Colonel memory and but I didn't
this doesn't connect it to the attacks
that I've mentioned previously and the
way does is where you have we've
implicitly just now predicted IP IDs for
IP pets that are not our own and this is
actually practical for for any IP pet
that doesn't have an increment of zero
to it that does have an increment of
zero to it and there are many of them
actually it's a zero-sum game the more
zero increment that you have the more IP
IDs that you can guess and the less zero
increments you have you can predict more
IP IDs accurately but for all those that
have an increment of zero it's a huge
number
if the problem is reduced to assessing
the number of packets on the IP path you
can either guess because there's some
cache time to the reassembling equipment
or with a with a side channel attack
that you might have and so this is the
end this brings up well some of the
attacks that have mentioned previously
definitely the Zalesky attack where you
can inject data and the interception
attack that was suggested by Galaga
Hertzberg and to sum up I have a few
takeaways that I want to share the first
is actually to reiterate every article
that mentioned here mentioned this
research there stating both we do
anything you can to not fragment in your
network and the second one is my own
thoughts that you should never never
refactor working code it's not worth it
and the third piece would be my advice
to you go out on your search such
pillars of Windows things that are
considered picked clean such as tcp/ip
sis and you will find it will find it
before automated tools if this is an
example and thank you yeah that's all I
have if you have a question if you have
questions this is a time where also
easily found in on mail Twitter
that's it Thanks thank you guys all
right this is the same question a really
quick one because we have two minutes if
someone I can't see but if someone's
raising his hand I don't see but maybe
you can see if something's raising his
hand oh there's a guy Thanks
has this been attached and what's the
timeline on that all right it has been
patched on not this not the November
past Tuesday but October 1 so it's quite
recent and I therefore I think it's
worthwhile to experiment with it with
those attacks
I definitely gonna see it in the next
few months on production and networks
and a timeline has been four months
until they have disclosed it and until
they have patched it after my disclosure
and that answer is yeah thanks
all right so I think we have time for
just a quick one if anyone all right you
can catch me in the hallway thank you
[Applause]