uh
this is by yardan shafir
hello yarden hello how are you
i'm very well thank you how are you and
and uh where are you calling in from
i'm good i'm calling in from greece
right now
ah lovely excellent and is is that your
artwork on the walls behind you or is
that
no no this is not mine this is
good anyway uh we are well we're
in order to try and stay on track we're
going to crack straight on
you are going to talk to us about
uh and since i'm definitely not going to
know what this is about
uh call back objects everything you
didn't know
you wanted to hook in the kernel
um so yarden please take it away
and i'll be monitoring for questions and
get back to you
at the end yes let me
share my slides
okay let me know if that worked
i think that's worked i will
leave you to get on with your
presentation thank you very much
thank you uh okay so yeah
like i said uh amiodan and we're gonna
talk about
callback objects is um
an internal communication mechanism in
the windows kernel
that you're probably gonna want to
use or look at for your next rootkit or
adr software so first of all about me
um my name is joden i'm a software
engineer at crowdstrike previously it's
center one
uh doing windows security research and
development
form of defense purposes i'm also
an instructor in onesider teaching
windows internals classes together with
nesco and i'm also a circus artist
instructor and performer mostly
working in israel teaching aerial
teaching performing aerial arts
i do a lot of things i'm a pastry chef
and during quarantine i
mostly taught my mom how to unmute zoom
almost by herself so that's probably my
greatest achievement so far
and what about callback objects
we might sound familiar to a lot of you
because the windows kernel
has a lot of things that have the name
callback
in them there's a lot of user mode
combat
kernel mode callbacks some of you might
know
the process and thread and load image
notifications
which are also called callbacks
those are all different things for
example process and thread
on notifications are legacy callbacks
which are a different thing in which the
kernel
notifies different drivers about certain
events happening in the system
now callback objects are a slightly
different thing
they're an actual object like a file
like
process like a symbolic link they're one
of about 70 different
object types in the system
and they're named when you create a
callback
you can choose a name for it or not you
don't have to
and that's how other drivers in the
system are going to recognize it
and the thing that makes callback
objects different
from a few other communication
mechanisms in the kernel
is that anyone can create a callback
anyone can register for one and anyone
can
notify one unlike other mechanisms in
which the
colonel exports some functionality some
options some call back like
here you can register to receive
notifications about processes
with callback objects anyone can use
them
in the kernel any way they want
there are certain callbacks that the
kernel
makes available like power state
um you know if the system is going to
shut down
or restart or go to sleep and a few
other things
but you can also create your own
callback object for example if your
product has
two or three or four different drivers
that want a way to pass information to
each other
you can create internal callback objects
have all your drivers or some of them
register for those and any of them can
notify the others
to pass any kind of information you want
callbacks
when notified receive
three arguments two of them controlled
by whoever is notifying it
so that's as long as all sides
as long as all sides of the
communication agree on
which arguments these are which types
they're in
you can have your own internal
communication mechanism
inside the kernel but it's not private
anyone can register to
any callback almost
um we'll see how that's not true and how
it's still
kinda true anyway
so this is roughly
what that mechanism looks like you have
a few drivers
one of them creates a callback with
excrete callback
creates a new callback object that they
said can have
or not have a name and other drivers can
register for that callback to register
for they first need to find it
they do it again with excreate callback
which create which gives them
pointer a handle to the object and then
they can register functions they can
register
functions that will be notified when
someone wants to notify the callback
and then after there are registered
drivers
anyone any of the registered drivers can
notify the callback and anyone who
registered a function will be called
thing is you can technically you can
notify a callback without being
registered to it
you just need to have the handle to the
callback now
you're not supposed to have the handle
without registering because you're
supposed to receive it
when you register callback function or
create the callback
but you're in the kernel you have access
to
basically everything so you can kind of
get the handle
anyway by yourself
here is some simple code um
a simple poc code to show how to create
and register
a notification function for callback in
this case
it's the kernel's image verification
uh info callback that's that's one
that's provided by the windows kernel
starting in windows 8.1
and that's a that's a fun callback that
gives you for every newly loaded driver
information about its hash its signature
its certification
um so for an edr tool that's a fun one
to use
as you can see like with almost any
object
we need to initialize the object
attributes part of which are the name
of the callback we want then we call
excreate
callback to get object and then we use
that object
to register our own function in this
case they called it image verification
callback function
and then every time a new driver is
going to be loaded
kernel is going to notify our callback
and any other callback
and any other function that was
registered for this call
fortunately the internal structures
that are used for uh call backstation
are not public they're not documented
and they're not in the symbols which
makes
callback objects a bit harder
and more annoying to work with um
especially if you want to debug them
because you can't use
public symbols for that um but the
structures are pretty well known anyway
we have two main structures that we need
to know there is the one
on the right that's the callback object
itself that's what you're
creating and receiving when you call ex
create callback
it has a signature which is not very
interesting and a lock
and then it has two linked lists
first thing i like linked lists because
that's
the easiest way to get access
to information that you might
not normally have access to
and you want to find something windows
kernel if it's not
exported or
some official documented thing you might
have a hard time finding it that's why
we have
makes like binary scanning trying to
match specific
bytes signatures but if something is
linked in the list
it's enough to have one part of the list
to have all of it you can just walk the
list so i like lists in this case we
have two
the last field here is the callback list
which links all the callback objects in
the system
in a single list which means once you
have one callback object
you can find all of them and the second
is the list of registered callbacks
because when you
register a function to be notified by a
callback
you don't just register a function you
register you create a
callback registration structure that's
what
that's what gets internally created
and we'll look at that in a second and
those are all
connected by a linked list which makes
sense girl needs to
have a way to get all the
registered functions and notify them one
by one so alex there's an easy way to do
that
and the last field in the callback
object that's interesting is allow
multiple callbacks
like the name suggests that's
um boolean value that says
allow do you want to allow
more than one callback function to be
registered here or not that's
that field is being specified when the
callback is first created
and if it's set to false when you
register
callback function the kernel will check
if there's already someone registered
for this callback and if there is
it won't let you register
no that's not a very major limit because
the callback is in the kernel
your driver is in the kernel you can go
and catch the list yourself and just
add your function there anyway but
you're not supposed to
so now when you create when you register
a function for a callback
behind the scenes there's a callback
registration structure that's created
again that has the linked list
connecting all
the callback registration structures it
has the pointer to the callback
function and it has a pointer
to something called a callback context
now that callback context
is see if i have that in my example i
didn't use it
um that callback context is
a pointer that you supply when you
register
for a callback and whenever your
callback whenever the
callback is notified every
function that's listed in the list is
going to be called
and receive as one of the arguments
the callback context that it registered
it's not something like the caller it's
not something that whoever notifies the
callback determines it's not something
that the kernel determines
whoever registered the callback will
receive
its own callback context when the
callback is notified
on first look that might not make much
sense because
why would you register an argument that
you're gonna receive
later actually that's um
the logic behind is that this is a
pretty
um rough way to implement
classes but kernel is
is not built with classes it's basically
c there's no
there's no complicated development
concepts there there's no classes in the
kernel
but that's a rough way to implement a
class where the whenever the callback
object it would
is notified would receive the class
instance
basically it's a way for drivers to have
some
internal global data structure that they
want to have available
in a lot of cases including in their
callback
in their callback function but
without saving it as a global that
anyone can easily find
so that's that and why is that
interesting
because that means that those callback
contexts when used
can will probably be pointers to pretty
large
internal data structures where we might
have information that
we're interested in but we'll have a
pretty hard time finding otherwise
because it's usually
full memory it can be anywhere it
doesn't usually have
something that makes it easy to identify
to find if you need to go and dig inside
the driver for pointers
but the callback context is an easy way
to find a pointer into it
a lot of drivers don't use that callback
context later we'll
dump some callbacks and see and mostly
it's
null but when it's not you can sometimes
find some interesting things there
here we basically have the same thing in
diagram
form we have the two lists we have a
list that connects
all the callback objects together and
in each one of them we have the internal
list
connecting all the callback registration
entries inside the callback each
callback registration is
one driver that registered a function
to be notified when the callback is
notified
as we can see here if we get
one of them any of them a callback
object or a callback registration
we have all of them we can find every
registered
function in every callback object in the
system
means even if there's callback objects
that we can't easily find
for example unnamed ones that we can't
index by name
we still have a way to find them
now who actually uses those callbacks
first the windows kernel itself exports
but not exports exposes some callbacks
like
a very popular one pretty well known one
is the
power state callback i mentioned earlier
um there is a processor add callback
there's license there's a license
licensing
data callback and like we saw the image
verification one that's pretty useful
for edr software
to to know what drivers are loaded
one thing i have to add is that callback
objects are unlike some other
parts of the system callback object
objects are just notifications
for example being notified that a driver
is being loaded doesn't give you the
option of
blocking it or changing it in any way it
just
sends you message saying hey this thing
is get is being loaded here's its
information
good luck uh so there's a few of those
there's some interesting callbacks in
the kernel
that some of them are used pretty often
for example win32k has some callbacks
that uses mostly anonymous callbacks for
internal 132k communication and
for whoever is interested in win32k 132k
exploitation and bugs and
finding more ways in there that might be
an interesting direction to look at
other than that there are security
products that use them for internal
communication
security products that have more than
one driver and want an easy way to
synchronize between them and pass
information
might use that for example windows
defender has a few
different drivers and uses callback
objects
for communication between them and it's
actually a fun example to look at that
we'll
look at in a bit more detail later and
another example that's
that's pretty interesting is patch card
patch card has a callback object that is
used to
initialize a pointer to
a function that does patch or periodic
checks
and we'll look at that a bit more later
too
now i'm mentioning all these callbacks
but how can we actually find them
these callbacks because they're not just
the when just the kernels callbacks
because anyone can use
them each of you will have different
callbacks on your system based on what
products run
run there like is windows defender
running
or do you have some other security
product or
some other things that use callbacks so
a few ways to see
what callbacks you have one of them is
using winobgx that's a pretty easy one
just
looking for callbacks with window gx the
only limitation is that it's only going
to show
named callbacks it won't show you the
unnamed one so you'll only see ones that
have a name
another option is to use wind bag
and run bang object uh slash callbacks
i'll show this later when i show the
demos uh but that
again that will only show the named
callbacks you can also use winback to
write a script a dx script or
javascript to a javascript script
to manually parse the callback objects
and then you will
have all of them not just the named ones
the
part that makes it difficult is again
the internal structures
are not documented and not in the
symbols
so you'll have a bit of a hard time
doing that it is possible
but it will be slightly difficult to
it's that difficult to work with
undocumented structures in one bag third
option which i'll show later
is using just using c writing either
debugger api which is what i did or
write
a driver that will parse the callback
list
both are valid options i i wrote a tool
to do that
um a debugger api tool that i'll share
later
and then if we look at the list this
this way ex screenshot is from
my machine and we can see stuff like
that first one the one with the
with all the weird named number
that's the patch card callback actually
then we have all sorts of callbacks
from my audio and video cards
there's a few of them here
we see the power state callback we see
the image verification callback
and at the end we see three wd callbacks
those are the windows defender ones
the one that windows defender uses for
its internal
communication
now we've seen this mechanism we see
what it does we see how we can
legitimately use it
how can we abuse this mechanism
there's all sorts of fun ways like i
said
this mechanism is can used for internal
communication
but it is not private
as long as a callback is not defined
with
don't allow multiple callbacks anyone
can register to it
you cannot specify who is allowed and
who is not allowed
even if technically a callback is not
allowed to have multiple callbacks you
can go and patch them
and patch the memory yourself you can
find pointers and hook
um communication by replacing the
pointer with your own function
or just adding another one to the list
and listening
into callbacks that might have
interesting information that we want to
follow for example
the windows defender callbacks you can
also
remove remove functions from those lists
which will
probably break something depending on
what you remove
and from which callbacks
you can use the callback context to find
pointers to interesting
structures interesting internal
structures used by
drivers that you that you care about
and you can also notify those callbacks
yourself
with possibly false information
which good with security products which
could lead some
to some interesting results there
a couple of the examples that
i mentioned that we'll look at are
windows defender and patch card
so windows defender a very rough um
very rough design it has is windows
defender on windows 10 has
three drivers first one is
the filter driver which does love the
work it registers for the processing
thread notifications it
monitors file system does all sorts of
things
that one has one callback
the second one is the network driver
which communicates with the management
system and that one has a second
callback
and the last one is the boot or elam
driver
um for anyone who's not familiar elam is
a microsoft program in which it allows
certain
av vendors to load their driver
very early earlier than most drivers are
allowed to load
and what those drivers are allowed to do
is
pretty much one thing register for
windows callback another callback object
which will give them which will notify
them every time
a boot driver is loaded
with with information
about the hash with some basic
information about the driver
this one allows those allows the boot
drive allows the
av driver to use
um an allow list or block list
to decide if it wants to block those
drivers that's meant to
allow some av drivers to block
early loaded malicious drivers like root
kits that will be loaded in the system
so windows defender has a boot drive has
a
has an elam driver that is loaded very
early in the system
for this callback and has an internal
callback object of its own that it uses
to communicate with the other
with the filter driver so what does this
callback do
um one thing to know about elon drivers
is that they have to
unload early too they're allowed to load
very early
see all the boot drivers load uh block
or not block them
and then they need to unload they can't
keep running so what the windows
defender driver does
is that it receives those driver
notifications
and it saves the information about the
drivers in
an internal data structure then when the
filter driver
loads right before the boot driver needs
to unload
the filter driver registers for
the windows defender boot callback and
notifies it
telling the boot driver hey
send me all the driver information that
you kept
so it can use it for whichever detection
logics or notifications
or whatever it wants to do with them and
the boot driver sends back
the all the info that internal data
structure with all the information
about the early loaded drivers
so that's one callback which is if you
manage to
load early enough before the boot driver
is unloaded
you can notify that callback and receive
all that information to us and when you
know how to parse it
second callback is the filter driver
callback that's the
call we had it here that's the last one
on the list
w the the boot driver callback is the
wdeb notification callback
and the filter driver has the it creates
the wd
process notification callback
so like the like it sounds from the name
the wd process notification callback
is a way for windows defender to notify
other drivers about processes
um starting in the system because what
happens is the filter driver registers
for the
legacy process notification callbacks
the one where
the kernel notifies drivers about every
loaded process
so when your defender receives that
notification
that a new process has been loaded it
does some analysis gets some information
about the driver
and then it wants to pass that
information to the network driver so it
can pass it on
to the management server to the
centralized server so when a windows
defender is notified about a new process
it gets whatever information needs it
saves it in its own internal structure
and then it uses the windows defender
callback object
to notify the network driver hey
there is a new process in the system
here is the information about it
now what's fun about this callback is
that something that you haven't
mentioned before callback objects are
not very well known
and as far as i know they're not really
monitored by
anyone i don't know any security
products that monitor them
uh tools like when check don't
dump callback objects as far as i'm
aware
so they're not really looked at
but for example the call legacy called
accept
legacy process notification callback is
a much more well-known one and
a lot of products are looking at it
seeing who is registered
there where does it point does it point
to driver memory does it point to
non-driver memory if you register there
you're a lot more exposed but you can do
something interesting
if you have windows defender running and
you want your rootkit to get cross
notifications
but not be super
out there about it you can let the
windows defender register for
pros notifications let it receive the
data process the data
and then register your own driver
to the windows defender callback so
whenever a new proxy is loaded windows
defender will notify its own callback
and as a result will notify
your driver too and not only do you get
to
sort of hide and not
and not be super visible because you're
not registered to the
system's pros notification callback you
also get slightly more processed
information
and kind of letting windows defender do
some of the work for you
the only downside here is that windows
defender uses an
internal data structure for its
information so you'll need to
figure out how this data structure is
built
and how to parse it properly once you
have that you've got everything and
that's actually the most interesting
callback that windows defender has the
third one
is the network drivers callback which is
only actually called once
it's called when the network driver
starts because it starts a lot later
than the filter drivers then the filter
driver
when the network driver starts it
registers for this
callback object that the filter driver
creates to notify the filter driver hey
i'm up you can start sending me
information
and then immediately the
filter driver sends it the information
about all the processes
that were loaded before the fill before
the network driver started
so it's only actually notified once you
don't really get
different information than you do with
the process
with the process callback um you just
get a
more you get information about more
processes but you don't get actually
different information that's just an
internal
synchronization mechanism for them
so the second callback object that
seems pretty exciting is the patch card
callback it has this
very unclear name because it's not going
to be called
patchguard notification callback
and that one is also only called
once it's not called to trigger patch
card checks
it is called to initialize a pointer
to the function that performs patch card
checks
um the kernel notifies this callback
once when
initialization of the system ends when
um phase zero ends up
the system wants to make
patch cards start running to enable
patch card because everything is where
it's supposed to be everything is
initialized
now it wants patch guard to start
monitoring
so enables patch card and as part of
that it notifies that callback
which has one registered function to it
the function is in ms-sec-flt
and it notifies it with a pointer
to the function that will perform
random random patch card checks
to tell i'm a second faulty this is the
function that you need to call
to do patch card checks now the
interesting thing about this is
registering for this callback is not
very useful because
you're going to register too late um if
you somehow manage to
have your driver running before phase 0
of uh system initialization ends there
are more interesting things you can do
than registering for the patch card
callback so registering for it is not
going to be
very useful because it won't be called
by the time
your driver is up but
looking at the look at the way it's
implemented
the function in msc flt is implemented
in such a way that it
initializes its own global with the
pointer that it received
but never checks if the pointer is if
the global
is already initialized which means
if you notify this callback again you
can replace
the pointer you would expect it to bug
check
because hey the pointer is already
initialized who's trying to change it
and why
but it doesn't um
so you can notify the callback again and
see what happens
now my guess is that on newer systems
with hyperguard
this pointer uh will probably be
protected and you will probably
not be able to change it but it might be
worth checking might be worth
seeing what's there and also
if if ms flt is still registered for the
function by the time your driver is up
probably won't be you can walk
the registered callback registration
structures
to see who's registered receive
the pointer to the callback function
do some simple binary parsing
there it's not a very large function and
find the global which has the pointer
to the patch card to the patch card
function
the patch card um monitoring function
which is fun for some path for some
patch card research
uh if you want to do some patch card
research
um obviously this is this is a very
rough
description of callback objects we only
kind of scrape the surface here
there's a lot more interesting callbacks
to look at
i would look at security products i
would
maybe look at some other third-party
products that might be using them
there is a base for some very
interesting research here that can go in
a lot of different directions
but what doesn't really exist is an easy
way to
investigate callbacks like public tools
or whatever
so let me unshare and
share uh all that i wrote for this
okay so i wrote this
simple tool that analyzes a crash dump
or takes a crash damper of its own or
connects to a kernel debugger
and dumps all the callbacks
and registered functions that are in it
so we'll let it run and while it runs we
can look at things
so the first ones on the list are as
you'd expect the kernel ones
there's enlightenment state set system
time
now here's the power state one we see
it's popular there is
stuff registered here that you'd expect
to see in a power state callback there's
acpi there's hal
there's a lot of other drivers here
registered for that one
now here we start seeing different
callbacks
we see
different here's for example one of the
win32k callbacks we can see that it's
unnamed when 32k uses anonymous
callbacks
for its port signaling
um here's our few who chose the name
null for the callbacks those are i think
my graphic
um my graphics drivers
[Music]
here's the dam driver which always has
some interesting stuff
in this on this machine i don't have
windows defender running
so we won't see so we won't see that
and just because we have a couple more
minutes i'll show
how we can also dump callbacks with
windbag but only named ones
[Music]
so simple we run bank object
and give it a minute because always a
bit slow
uh internally it just looks for
all objects that have that part of the
that have slash callback as part of the
name
now while it's running right
never remember if it's one or two so
while we're letting it run
uh anyone has any questions
so we don't have any questions yet uh
i'm afraid
jardin i think uh i think you've blown
them away with your
technical expertise and um you need some
time to process
exactly exactly and i can tell you as an
ex-ciso
one of the great advantages of being a
cso is you get this
very high level view of everything
that's going on security wise in the
organization
the downside of being an ex of being a
cso is this with this
very high level view of the organization
i didn't understand a word of what you
just said
but but i do know
i do know that there are many many
people in the audience who
will have found this incredibly useful
um
and folks if um if you're still
processing not quite ready to
ask yarden a question just yet you can
still use the slack channels
um yard and you'll be on slack available
to ask any
answer any questions that sent your way
please
continue the conversation uh afterwards
um uh having someone like yardan with
such
a deep level of technical expertise here
is
invaluable to you please take full
advantage
and um really really
uh um you know make the most of it
uh let me just check time we do have uh
a couple of questions now typically
they've literally just appeared
um so let me just check to see do we
have time
we've got four minutes to answer
questions
so let me yes thank you for getting the
photo
do you have any interesting structures
in the object context that you've seen
yeah i'm assuming you mean the callback
context there um
so yes if i'll
sec i'll reshare the output of the tool
i wrote
i'm going to it's on github i'm going to
publish it later
um and i'll send the link okay so
yeah we have your text out here
yeah we have the callback context output
here you can use it to see
which functions have initialized a
callback context and which one's
not um like here we see that dom doesn't
and one specific one
that i know if you're interested in
graphics
drivers almost all the graphics and
audio drivers do use a callback context
so there are probably some interesting
stuff there they're all pointing to very
large structures
and the windows defender driver
uses a callback context for all of its
callbacks and that points to the
internal windows defender
global data structure that always has
interesting information of
all sorts of kinds depends on exactly
what you're interested in but you're
probably going to find it there
okay excellent and i think we do have
time for this
second question what should you look for
when window defender is
stuff and admin cannot start it anymore
i'm not really sure what the question
here is
uh when windows defender is stopped
maybe
uh an admin i'm not sure
windows defender technical support i
don't really do
okay and in which case
let's go on to this final question
uh what is the difference in the image
loader callback object and the regular
load image notify routine
uh there's actually no image loader
callback object
the image load the load image notify
routine
is the legacy callback that notifies
about newly loaded image as far as i
know there is no image loader callback
object
if you mean the image verification
information the difference is that the
image verification callback
is only for kernel mode images
it only notifies about drivers and it
supplies
information that's actually a public one
all the structures are public because
it's meant to be used by edr
software and that gives you information
for example about
the who signed the image
uh it gives you it gives you some
information that you don't
get from the load image notification but
they're used for separate
purposes because one is only for kernel
mode images and image load
and the legacy image load notify routine
is for both kernel and user mode
i hope that answers your question uh
yarden
thank you very much one of the huge
downsides of a virtual event is that you
don't get a round of applause at the end
so please take mine
or your presentation um the
um please hang around on the slack
channels afterwards folks please
um ask questions there yard and you'll
be posting links to the github that you
mentioned yes i'll be
i'll be posting it there um and on
twitter and even after a slack channel
is not
relevant it's easy to find me feel free
to ask
questions if you think of any later
fantastic do you have a twitter handle
or anything that people should know
about
i do it's you then sofia the same name
that's on the slide so very easy to find
okay excellent yarden thank you very
much