[Music]
yes very well thank you very well and
uh where are you calling in from i'm
from india here lastly
kerala okay excellent excellent so
you're talking about is it
quines or queens coins yeah it's okay
and it's
sql injection right i know much
there we go well i mean sql injection
has been around for about 15 years right
so
yeah yeah it's in the os top 10 forever
um okay so um
please uh get your presentation uh up
and ready in the meantime can i just
remind everybody
the left uh sorry the left of their
screen now that way
the left of their screen i'm gonna
rephrase that again
the right of your screen is where the
comments are and where you can place
your questions
if you have any questions you'd like to
discuss later on
uh please jump on to the slack channel
where i hope you'll be able to
um jump into the chat yeah sure yeah
fantastic
so is my screen being shared now yes it
has
uh yeah you are ready to go take it away
uh don't forget
okay so hello ron i hope everyone is
sick and safe and secure
uh i'm gonna and today i'll be doing a
presentation on coins and quiet sql
injections
so i think the topic finds a
self-producing syndrome itself is making
it
pretty self-explanatory but again let's
see
a little bit about myself i'm bachelor
and technology student at
amrita university amrita puri and i'm an
avid ctf player of team bios which is
the number one ctf team of india and
also the member of team shakti which is
one of the
three women only ctf team in the world
i focus on web exploitation and web
security
we are also the hosts of shakti city
which is an upcoming ctf for women and
various other cool ctfs
okay so as i mentioned our
team is ranked number one ctf team in
india which started in 2008 by our
mentor
vipin pavitran sir we take upon
security researches vulnerabilities and
its mitigations and so
we are the host of in ctf international
which
is pretty popular in ctf national which
is like the national level ctf
for college students then it's like the
first
one in india and institute of junior
which is
the national level city for school
students
okay a little bit about team shakti team
shakti is a
only ctf team we started our team in
we conduct work workshops and see other
programs to bring more women into this
field of security
yeah as i said we have an upcoming ctf
exclusively for women
cool set of challenges okay
so let's look into the agenda of today's
talk so
starting off personally i feel like i
prefer more examples and demonstrations
than theories or definitions
to understand the concept and i'm gonna
make this beginner friendly as much as
possible
so i'll start from the basics and
increase the level
okay so i'll begin with a briefing on
sql queries for those who are new to it
i mean yeah
i'll brush up on the syntax and how the
queries are used
to manipulate the database add delete
change and so on
um then i'll give a quick explanation on
sql injection
since without the basic concept it's
going to be really difficult for me to
explain what i intend to it just for my
satisfaction
i'll explain a bit on what sql injection
is like
how it happens why it happens when and
so on
and then what are the types of sql
injections we
will check a few examples for clarity
then we look at a few prevention methods
and also uh yeah the cool thing
we can see like check a bit on the
bypass of web application firewalls with
sql injections
okay so for those who already know this
hold on patiently because i'll be taking
a short sqli
101 before getting into coins i want to
make sure
things are presented clearly to each and
every audience
okay so next we'll get into coins
practically what how when why
and that sort of stuff what is the whole
purpose of coin like
uh how it is interesting so it's like
something about coin
it's what friedman said it's like coins
are practically something that popped
out of biology
the whole concept so unless and until
you look at it
in a curious perspective it's actually
really really interesting and exciting
but it can feel very useless if not
understood properly
okay i'm being brutally frank here in
the beginning
yeah in the beginning i was like what's
going on here like what even is the
point of it but
yeah it's pretty fun okay so we will
look into the uses and a few examples on
how it works
and then talk about injections like in
coin
called an endurance this is not a
squinosphere injection but a method
of injecting in coins finally we will
talk about coin sql injections
it's pretty neat and fun again what
where how and all
then a demonstration payload i'll break
it down into small small pieces where
they it's easier to digest
okay we will yeah we'll also discuss on
the impact severity of this attack how
it can be mitigated because
that's an important thing and check a
demonstration of coin sql injection in
a weak authentication check so the whole
prevention part can be understood from
the vulnerable check the vulnerable
authentication check we're
seeing in the demonstration itself
okay so starting off sql is
a domain specific language it's like
used in programming
and it's basically designed for managing
data held in any sort of relational
database management systems
so let's just say we have a login system
you type in your name and password and
at the back end it fetches the details
with respect to the data you
like with the data sent and it sends
back the response
so the mechanism which selects the
content where username equal to s
and password is equal to y that's where
sql comes into play
right so we have the accessibility to
manipulate data
unlike our files which can be
disorganized
and you know less secure when compared
to like when considering data handling
right
so some common relational database
management systems that use
sql are oracle microsoft sql servers
access ingress etc although
most databases like systems use sql
most of them also have uh would say
their own additional proprietor
extensions
that are not only used on their system
like it's like
exclusive to them it's not it's not
common for everything
however there are standard sql commands
just select insert
drop delete update create and all that
can accomplish
almost everything one needs to do in a
database it's like
you know manipulation complete it's all
the manipulation needed
okay so the basics basic
you know the basic function of sql is to
query data
contained in a relational database as
you see start
and yeah on the contrary every
functionality comes with the flow right
so no method in this world would be 100
efficient
so there comes the attack to destroy sql
functionality
and to all the people who say sql is old
school and not fun anymore it's hard how
they miss the wide variety of the attack
okay next slide okay so injections
sql injection is a code injection
technique yeah
which is used to you know attack
data-driven
applications which is like very much
malicious sql statements are inserted
into
entry field or where the input is taken
for execution
like yeah like the input fields so
yeah like injection has made a like yeah
like our host said injection has made a
constant appearance in
top 10 web application security
vulnerabilities for over
10 years sql injections like it
allows an attacker to spoof identity or
tamper with existing data cause
repudiation issues
that could be like voiding transactions
or maybe
changing balances allow disclosure of
data
in even many cases destroy data like
make it completely unavailable
and there are also cases where they can
get a privilege escalation they could
become like administrators of the whole
database server
okay so as i said sql injection must
exploit a security vulnerability in an
application software
so for example when a user
is either incorrectly filtered for
string literal escapes
characters which is embedded in sql
or use input in you know which is not
strongly typed
or unexpectedly executed or like
you know accidentally run or so it's
most
known as attack worked around websites
but yeah it can be used in
you know any any type of sql database
too
next slide yeah okay this is an example
sql injections vary yeah definitely but
mostly it
it's like using the input and closing
the query running in the back
adding a few queries and removing off
every bit of the rest of the query with
commenters so here
we have our inject in red this is like
very basic injection where we inject
malicious code in the input comment of
the rest whatever comes in
yeah for those of you are new to this
i hope that's clear
yeah let's go for a short demo
so what's happening here is it's
selecting
uh the output where username and
password provided
with what is provided provided with what
is there in the database
okay so it's like normal authentication
checks
it if it finds the correct one it prints
welcome
else it prints valid so here i'm giving
them valid ones and
it's it prints welcome if i give an
invalid password or username it gives
invalid
as easy as that
okay so let's say we wanna login as
admin
to you know get his or her privileges
and we don't know what the password for
admin is
what we do is inject a query which
comments the rest
of your rest of what is there on the
back end
rest of the select statements so finally
it becomes select
it just selects your username is equal
to admin without asking the password
simple as that that's like very basic
form of sql injection
yeah next getting into the types of sql
injection
they can be classified into three main
categories uh
in banned sql injections in feral sql
injection or blind skill injections
and out of band sql injections okay
inbound sql injections is usually the
most common and
easy to exploit kind of sql injection
attacks
like in inband uh skills usually it
occurs when
an attacker you know is able to or say
you see you know the same communication
channel use the same communication
channel to both
launch the attack and also to gather
results
right so the two most common types of
inband sql injection attacks are
error-based
sql injections and union-based skill
injections
error-based sql injections usually
relies on the error messages thrown by
the database servers
so if you use mysql or something if
there is an error it it pops
like okay there is a syntax error so the
errors are
thrown back union base depends on
the union sql operator which is like the
combinational operator like it's pretty
self-explanatory
so it combines the results of two or
more
select statements right okay in
blind sql injection it's practically a
pretty long down right for an attacker
to exploit
the attacker would not be able to see
the result of an attack in an inband
which perhaps explains
blind as in the attacker closely
examines
like indirect loss in behavior like when
we
try to get an error fix it try again
sort of say you know try an error
if trial and error stuff the injection
doesn't
you know reveal data from the database
directly
so clues can be like http responses
blank web pages for certain user inputs
and how long
it takes you know for the database to
respond to
certain user inputs are those other
things that can be you know close
depending on the goals that occur
and yeah the two types of blind sql
injections are
blue blind boolean based and blind time
base
yeah boolean based sql injections depend
on whether the query
returns true or false statements as the
name suggests boolean
yeah in time based the query you know to
the database which forces the database
to kindly
wait for a specified amount of time and
the response time
explains true or false like let's say
wait for five minutes
five seconds if it waits for five
seconds it's true
something like that okay next yeah out
of band
out of band sql injection occurs when an
attacker you know is
unable to use the same channel as the
law to launch the attack and gather
results like it's the
opposite of in-band this is pretty you
know common one of the fan
okay this is the fun part of sql
injection
yeah it's like when we get to break the
exclusive rules like
it's particularly given that don't do it
and the first thing is like
do it so of office of a web application
firewall helps to protect the web
application
by filtering and monitoring http traffic
between
the publication and the internet it
typically protects web applications from
like
crosstalk scripting cross site foreign
file inclusion
secure injections and other kind of cool
attacks
so as i was saying a wolf operates
through a set of rules
called policies these policies aims you
know to protect against vulnerabilities
in the application by filtering out
just the malicious traffic right
so in applications prone to sql
injections they tend to create a web
application firewall
that sanitizer blacklist the common sql
keywords
in the input okay so uh
sql injection worf is generally like
yeah same as
the policies it has it follows a bunch
of rules
to prevent speed injections so
most common filters supplied by warps
are by possibly
it's easy to bypass let's discuss a bit
in the common ones
okay so union blacklist can be trashed
by blind sequels so
it actually uses the method of
requesting a true or false statements
as i said before uh as the responses
from the database
using and operator or or operators to
brute force the data
okay this can be used when the database
does not give out any output
right next is buffer overflow by fasting
so
while writing into the buffer with a
huge value
with huge values surpass the buffers
boundary
like overwriting the memory of an
application because most of the valves
right are mostly written and combined in
c
crlf is carriage return line feed okay
these
control characters can be used to
subtract substitute
for spaces for comments which are
blacklisted
hpp is http parameter pollution
okay the parameters in the http request
like
is like maliciously you know malibu
dated with maliciously
you know unlimited different unintended
malicious statements methods to
or methods to achieve sensitive
information uh
it's like you know multiple parameters
of the same name are interpreted
differently in different languages of
frameworks i said
so to give an example php or apache
it's like controls the last occurrence
occurrence of the parameter
so if we give user name equal to kim
jong-un and username equal to pass
admin it would consider the second one
so we get the access of the admin
and if the you know framework the
server is jsp servlet or apache tomcat
it contrasts the first occurrence so we
swap it
right to what our requirement is
okay so character substitutes it's like
we
using characters like uh parallel
question marks double quotes single
quotes uh
percentage like yeah ampersand and dot
usually the wolf
would consider these kind of special
characters as spaces
and completely ignore them okay so which
is like which is like a
help for us to bypass various keywords
which are blacklisted links
so be it space a lot hex in coding yeah
when particular keywords are you know
blacklisted we could substitute with the
hex encoder value because after the url
is passed it obviously decodes
and turns the hex value to plain text
right okay so unicode encoding
yeah in this encoding standards like
some of the characters can be you know
used as the substitute for
ascii character values if at all it's
blocked
and thus by we can bypass it and dump
the database
okay lexis base conversions
by base conversion i think they are
that's self-explanatory it's like by
representing values that are blacklisted
in different basis it's like yeah zero x
base is bait base 16 and base
8 values are differently printed but
it's the same value
right so yeah what we can do is
represent values that are blacklisted in
different basis would help
bypass that filter
yeah when we provide a url encoded null
byte which is like
percentage 0 0 before the string to be
bypassed
it will remove everything after the null
byte so that
can be used as you know maybe comments
substitute and so next is ascii
substitute
it's similar to unicode substitute it's
like these ascii characters can have
you know multiple alternatives which has
a different value but
their functions would be similar and can
be used to bypass
any blacklist that's created right
changing is okay this is this is not
that common but
yeah it's quite i mean i don't think
servers are that's
that them to you know keep let you know
keep a walk that can bypass okay
changing cases
we can bypass with the changing case so
the sql keywords are
obviously case insensitive and hence
when a waff blocks a particular case of
string
you can bypass it by giving varied cases
right okay url encoding it's also
similar to hex encoding
by substituting hex values to all the
blacklisted words and
bypass it once the url gets decoded
replace by bus i don't think this is
very common but yeah the works
that replace you know all occurrences of
particular keywords
with empty strings can be bypassed by
giving a keyword in the middle of the
same
key keyword and hence getting the same
keyword after the work replaces the
keyword in between
so practically these are just a few
methods like
the letter is just a huge wide ocean of
exploits and methods
next slide okay now the pretty mystical
one
in injections coin sql injections
but before that what is coins okay let's
get a
good idea of coins before we move on to
coin injections
a coin is a computer program which
prints its own listing
okay the concept is actually as i told
from buyers it's actually from
cell multiplication concept in living
beings as in
in molecular biology dna replication is
the biological process
of you know producing identical replicas
of dna from one original dna molecule
we got that right okay as in how
dna and other protein stuff is
replicated
as well as in the new cell okay so
that's self
uh replicating programs it's similar
like that's what
coin does that's the characteristics of
coin this may sound either impossible
trivial
or trivial and stuff like that like
what's printing its own listing
okay what is the point of it like this
means that
when a program is run right it must
print out
precisely those instructions which
programmer wrote as
you know as a part of the program alone
so okay let's just say we have a program
print hello so the output is obviously
gonna be hello right
so for coins it's like if the program is
print hello
the output output will also be print
hello rather than just hello
okay the easiest way to do that of
course is like
go seek the source file on the disk open
it print its content
okay what's the use of it that may be
that may be done but that's definitely
not a program which is printing itself
besides the program might not know where
the source file is
it may have access to the you know only
the
compiled data of programming languages
may simply forbid that sort of
operations
right so coins are actually you know
it's something
that's possible in any during complete
programming languages
it's like a direct consequence of claims
recursion theorem
okay claims recursion theorem uh it's
like a pair of fundamental results about
application of computable functions it's
like to their own
descriptions so uh
to their own descriptions and sense it's
related to what
say a fixed points determined by
enumeration operators
so which are like computable kind of you
know a computable correlate
okay and the comfort part of coin
is that in all general purpose
programming languages
coins can be developed like mixing the
programming
programs and data and all for example
escaping
quotes inside strings of characters okay
so
there there is some difficulty like the
difficulty of programming these
languages
and you know lengths can be reduced this
these you know
reducing the difficulty of programming
these quant languages to get the
particular fixed point and you know
you're reducing the length because
there's gonna be a
you know multiple recursive copying of
data and code
in this so that can be reduced if the
program
so you know the program language that we
use
has features supporting structural
reflection
right that is like uh the ability of the
language to provide
complete refrigeration you know it's
like complete verification when
the program is run or executed okay so
refrigeration
means that you know the program is you
know during the execution
it can be encoded as data right
in our cases what we're gonna use for
now we're
you know with our programming languages
javascript skill
or whichever we check with reflection
features and not using them
okay yeah next thing about coins
coins take no inputs right and it prints
its source code as output generally
coins don't take any kind of input
they are allowed to you know they are
not allowed themselves they are not
allowed to step out of itself which is
like
it can print its source code alone but
there can't be
anything any stuff like buffer overflow
or getting out of the bond and print
anything
more than the source code
very restricted okay
yeah the interesting thing the advantage
is obviously the interesting thing is
that writing coin does not depend on
any kind of stuff like being able to
read the source file or
able to represent you know codes in
several different ways
and that sort of stuff and it's like
um let's just say we have a code it
to printed store source okay we might be
just
having the binary to run and not the
program right
so we might not know where the store and
all so for coins they don't depend on
any of this it's like you run the
program and you get the source printed
no strings attached
okay yeah
so here we see different examples of and
types of points so first is constructive
coins
in general the method you know
is used to create a coin in any program
from a language you know is to have
within the program
two pieces it's like code and data i
think i've mentioned before
code and data so code is used to do the
actual printing
okay it's like in print hello print
print is the code part hello is the data
part
right so there are data that represents
the textual form of the code it's
usually inside
codes okay okay
so the code functions you know by using
the data
to print the code which makes use of the
data
in sense it's like it represents the
textual form of the code
but it also uses the data processed in a
very simple way
to print you know the textual
representation of the data itself
right so it's like
you know summarizing it's like code
prints the data and the data has the
code
which prints itself eventually again
the same reference to cells where when
it replicates the dna
is in it also replicates as the data in
the code too
right
okay next is oroboros in auroburs the
coin concept can be extended you know to
multiple levels of recursion
originating aurora's programs or you can
also call it
coin relays these coin relays or roboros
programs
which produce a chain of you know
continuous files in different
programming languages
eventually coming back to the original
source code
okay it does you know it does its
recursion and pops back to getting the
source
getting to the source so the next is
multi coins
multi coins and auroboros coins is not
the same thing
there might be a confusion at some
points but it's not the same thing
like multi coins one run normally it's a
coin
but if you know if it is called with a
particular command line
argument it will print a different
program completely different program
let's say it's a relative program it's a
relative program that's which is also a
coin
but then again in a different
programming language okay so
the second one prints its own listings
when run normally
right but when it's run with a different
command line argument
or let's say a fixed particular command
line
argument it prints listing of the
original program that's the parent
program the first relative okay
so summarizing multi coin is a set of
two pro two programs or
maybe two made to be two or more which
is able to print either
of the two like it's it's a set of n
different programs like not just two
in n different languages each of which
is able to print
any of the n programs it can also be
including itself the parent
parent coin according to the command
line argument which is passed
okay so summarizing it's like
multiple recursive probability of coins
of
number of languages right okay so
another misunderstanding
is polygon coins is a coin that can be
read
right and is up is also a coin in
several different languages right
so this might sound same as multi
coins but no it's not multi coin it's
it's you know
if you think about it it's it pretty
much
fits in the definition of multi coins it
can be a subset but it's
completely not a multi coin okay so
polygon coin
could be thought of generalization of a
multi coil
it does the same thing but it doesn't
need you know command line arguments
and all you know of the programs that
are identical or the
child coin or something like that right
so the next one is a radiation hardened
i have no idea who's keeping these names
radius and hard hardened or worse okay a
radiation haran coin
is like a coin that can be you know have
a single character removed
and it still produces the original
program the original
data that we inputted with no like
literally no missing characters
this seems like magic like how you just
lost a part of your body and
again you come up with this complete
part of your body how does that happen
but yeah it's that particular fixed
point as i discussed in clean's
recursion theorem
it's that what makes you know still
makes it a coin difficult to get there
but yeah
fun okay so
eval points something you know some
programming languages might have the
ability to
evaluate a string as a program not many
but there are yeah a few that has that
functionality running
okay coins can take advantage of this
feature val is
actually one of the easiest way to you
know write the coin since it reduces the
need to continuously copy the code and
paste it the copy the data part
put it in the code copy the code bar and
put in the data
stuff like that so like before we had a
loop of you know code running data
and data having code and all as in the
majority of the coins require two copies
of code as i said
one to be executed one as data right
so this can end up in doubling the
length of the source code
making it harder to maintain obviously
so
trying to treat your code as data is
often not possible right
treating data score can be done in many
languages using
eval
your coin basically consists of storing
the main body of your coin
in a variable then evaluating that
variable that's pretty
you know basic kind of coin basic
instance easy quite a coin
okay that's something that's more easier
and i don't know why it's in you know in
the classification it's cheat coins
they seem self-explanatory as i
mentioned on how
you know coins don't need location or
file or have the physical file
files accessibility and auto reproduce
the source
so what is the point of not coding and
directly you know getting the print of
the source code but
again you know those cheat points fit
perfectly under the definition of coins
it it's a program that's run and you
know it prints the output so i'll just
give it that acknowledgement to them
okay so yeah two types
so source code inspect it's like coins
per definition cannot receive
any form of input including reading file
which means that a coin is considered to
be cheating right it
if it looks at its own source code
in many functional you know functional
languages
like numbers are self-evaluating it's
like
when you print one it's like a one byte
coin if you know the last line of the
program is returning
the returned value is displaced
displayed on the screen therefore
and it's like in such language
programming is right containing a single
digit result
in a one byte coin since such score does
not construct itself it's like
it's like a proper tapes it doesn't
construct itself
this is often considered cheating so
that's not a proper coin
i'll try to give a few examples or demos
if time permits is the end of the dock
yeah okay so we will take an example of
this python coin
which prints itself okay so as i
mentioned it has a code part
and a data part here the data part is
inside
the codes okay
so and the rest is the code part which
runs the whole thing and gets the code
replicated as it is all right
let's just take a look at how this work
i start with the skeleton
and then add on explaining it to explain
the
oh okay
okay so we give the variable
no value printed nothing happens there
right
we give the variable the data part in
string
here we've given a variable with you
know the first program we wrote to print
that
you know and we call it recursively the
percent is r is to call it recursively
again usually usually it prints the data
now we have to you know print the print
function
that should come out as output right so
we add that data
next is like we have to print this as
string
i add yeah we've added percentage s
along now that we have added a
percentage s we have to have a
you know something that to print
percentages so that's where we use
percentage percentages
to print percentages and there we go we
have a super easy coin program
separate which prints itself right
next slide okay so let's just say we
have
this is a fun thing it's not again what
i said it's not
sql queen sql injection but it's a type
of
attack it's a type of injection in coins
okay so let's just say we have we would
like to add
viral payloads to the coin but we
we do not want to harm its self uh you
know reproductive ability
right so to achieve this we can use
introns
which are like uh you know pieces of
coin data
that are not used to output the coin
code
but there are also you know copied when
the data is
returned the output it's like
non-essential coin
data but you know the portions of data
that are not used in
the dna to produce proteins it's like
you get 88 percentage
of your parents yeah dna but the rest is
like
i don't know what rest is i don't know
biology yeah it's like it's useless but
it gets copy copied
right you know it's not useless it could
go it's get it gets copied
so that's introns like it's copied but
it doesn't affect the
product productive ability of coins
okay so yeah as i said uh coins uh coins
in drones are reproduced along with the
coin but they're not necessary
to be you know to the self-reproducing
ability of the coin
yeah so therefore an intron can be you
know modified
without a reproductive penalty making
entrance the perfect place
to put sql injection attacks right and
yeah that it doesn't contribute directly
to the functionality of a coin as it and
it placed no part in replication but it
just gets copied
next slide
yeah let's see uh
okay so basic intron injecting somehow
it responds like
yeah now this is an input method which
takes input from users and injects it in
coins
right so like it prints the coin and
also prints the input user gives
okay so it's waiting so we have an intro
and it's waiting for an input
right because for us it's waiting for us
input something
because because of the input function it
was waiting for us
so when we don't keep anything it just
prints the whole coin as it is
no inject part it just does the
self-replication and inputs it
i mean uh produces the replication
replicated code
this is practically the main source code
so now that we give hello or something
right
what happens is it's printed along as i
told the data
is also printed along it's like just
that we've
what the same it is yeah it's printed
along with the coin here the function of
the coin is still doing fine
just that we've injected a few bits
which are practically useless in the
replication process the hello part is
practically useless in the replication
process without which it can replicate
also with
with if even if it's there it can
replicate also
but can be of great use in lots of grey
areas
okay so now coming to coin sql
injections
so basically we've checked on sql
injections and coins
right okay and you put them in a box
together and we get coin sql ejections
like if it's a select name from table
the output
is also select name from table so the
first thing will be like
where does this work or like how does
this
how is this going to be useful so i
missed out one cool thing about coins
coin school injection you know can all
be like
yes it's it has a very certain purpose
which is concerning
but what about what you know something
about coins is that
we have competitions as to who can build
the perfect kind of coin
or let's just say radius inherent coins
it's like
what to say who can construct a coin
without cheat coins by omitting two
characters three characters or n number
of characters that print the
parent coin and stuff but a sql
injection coins is more than
just you know fun programming and like
you know other kinds of physical
injections doesn't need any kind you
know any control on data
where it is or how it is put up on the
table the arrangement
or that sort of stuff so even if it's a
ghost table or like
even if the whole table is empty or
returns
null values for queries these coins
right
you know it can still work it's like
it's amazing it can still work so one
thing is like it's not very common
like you cannot see this injection
everywhere it's not a severe bug or so
and why does it work this way this can
you know without any dependence of that
actually can be understood from where it
works
okay so here we can see that the
resultant array of the query
is you know in the variable r and they
are checking if the resultant password
and the
password is same as the input we've
given right so which is like yeah the
right password to crack it
so basically what we have to give is
that sir
it should be something same as a
resultant of the output of the input we
give
right so simple as that input a coin
and check you know the check will be
satisfied since coin will produce itself
and the authentication is done but how
does this work in an empty table
of you know something which responds
null statements
practically oh am i running out of time
okay
practically this whole check only
depends on
if the input and results are you know
same and
the authentication is done okay no
matter what's in the table database or
date tables
where it is organized you know we don't
have to go to all that
get the you know get the database name
from schema table names column names row
names and thoughts are said no it's like
a direct win win
okay so coins are not you know only the
option here right obviously there's a
lot of possibilities
sql injection attacks that can be done
here like you can
actually find the password through blind
sql ejection it's like it's
as i told it's pretty difficult it's a
darn long ride for an attacker
you know let's just say it's attack of
the row does not actually exist in the
database or the password is a whole
hash or something right so with
two or four statements how long can we
sit it's like
uh you know tiring right
yeah next thing next possible attack
this could be like a union
injection right so this is yeah this
is not that tiring this is let's just
say you
see you have considering the info column
of the information
schema process it can't con you know it
contains
the currently executing queries right
so we can make use of that so mysql
process actually indicates
operations that are performed you know
performed currently
it's like by the set of threads
executing within the cell
so the info part of the process list
like that contains the statements
the you know the thread is executing
okay or null if no statement is executed
the statement might be the one sent to
the server or the innermost statement
okay so here we've used union select one
admin database from information schema
dot process list
so this invokes the process list and
obviously it would print
the same query executed as in the query
wave
given input right so here
we'll see how the process list works so
i'm running
the statement to show how the full
process list and
info you see in the process is printed
so i've
written show process list and it's given
okay
yeah here in the info it actually prints
show process list
so it's like the process that's executed
is
run i mean uh process that ex has been
run is
executed as the output okay
so we hop on to this demo and last
demonstration part
that's quite an sql injection that's one
of the easy thing on our
hands now so this might this look
disturbingly confusing right but
i'll break it down and make it look
easier so here we are just recursively
you know replacing
to put back to the same initial query
right
and the data part according to if we
need a single quote or double quote
so if we need a single quote we replace
you know replace double quotes to make
uh
turn back to single quotes just like
that so i'll show you the breakdown
so yeah here when we in this breakdown
when we pass
the innermost data part the replace
statement will do its work
and we see that double quotes are
converted to single quotes
in like the in the second inner replace
we replace character of 36
our of our last output but the new
statement and end up bouncing back to
our
input program that's like the source
program right
so i'll show up this query and the
this is basically our query run so we've
given the same input and gives the same
output
right so that's a coin we have the coin
with us so let's try this demo
so here in this check let's just try a
basic attack and see how the
server you know responds to it so we
close the codes and do a union select or
something
right okay i'll show the demonstration
directly
okay
yeah here we can see that we close the
codes
and do a union select one or something
it's it's like you know when we give it
us password so basically the initial
check on
what kind of sql can be spent injection
can be used
if we if at all you know we don't have
the source code or authentication
you don't know what the authentication
or it's a blackboard box testing
something like that but what's going on
is not known so basically
start off with something basic queries
to put out
you know errors or hints which can help
us you know fi
find what kind of injection can be done
error based or flying base
so yeah here we have the response as
password equals one
the one we gave in the query right so
basically we're gonna make
one equals to the inject query that we
provide obviously our new
favorite option coins here in the point
query
we add the in you know the input code
and put a code
combine the union and comment down the
comment of the rest
right so it's like we clear the
authentication check easily with this
coin
okay we can we have to encode it
yeah when we give it us the password
input
yeah it's it's the same what we gave as
input is output and we've cleared that
the authentication check is clear and
clear right so finally
yeah finally it's prevention it's like
our host said expedition has been there
it's it's still going on and
it's not gonna stop anytime soon so i'm
gonna be
talking about prevention and mitigation
for you know the disaster management
system
disaster management right so oneness
input validation the validation process
you know is aimed at verifying whether
or not the type of input
you know submitted is you know by the
user is allowed
right so input validation is like
sanitizing the inputs it makes sure
you know is it's the of the right type
right length format
etc escaping you user input right in
that
you know always use character escaping
functions for user supplier input
providing like you know each database
management system this can be done
you know to make sure dbms never
confuses it with sql statements provided
by the developer
okay so yeah next is like never
connect your application to the database
using an account with
root access this should be done only if
it's absolutely necessary
you know it you know if the attacker
gains
that you know against that accessibility
it's like the whole system
the whole integrity of the system is
ruined
right uh yeah and that that's
administrative privileges
okay next is parameterized queries which
are like means of pre-combining and sql
statement
so that you can you know then supply the
parameters in order to
for the statement to be executed okay
the user
input is automatically quoted and the
supplied input will not
cost you know that's what the same the
change of the intent
right so that's another prevention
method
that can be used and it's like stored
procedures
you know that requires the developer to
group
you know one or more sql statements into
a logical unit to create
an execution plan it's like so
whenever you know you need to execute a
query instead of writing it on over and
over again you just you can just call
the store produce
process right okay
so that's that we've ended this
discussion is
there any questions wow that's