good evening everyone I introduce you I am fabio
that after 3 f bz we will see tonight a
technique used by radio amateurs to
be able to communicate at great
distances using
the plane as a passive reflector
what is meant by the passive
sector we mean the fact that  the plane that is
the wave that bounces on the were is
amplified it only comes is only
changed the path of the is
reflected and is dropped on
the other side this thing actually happened
very often there is often a past of being
able to communicate with  some some
radiomators maybe in germany for a few
minutes seconds then it disappeared completely
and the causes were given the propagation
reality can be discovered this thing
here that is actually at that moment there was
a plane in the middle two years ago we
saw how you can marry the  moon to
act as a reflector, however, to use
a moon it requires both as power and
as a system, let's say a decent
station for  do this thing here instead
the normal powers
we use are enough that are used by
radio amateurs what this system is often
used and during the
races that are commonly called
contests
because because in the contests the score is
given by how much the km fi that is a point per
km  15 fi 10 km 10 points you do the 900 km
and 900 points so the farther you go the
better
how it works
I say it quickly because you don't go and
see the probable idea when there is
a race a report is passed
that yes  calls rst that we say is how well the
signal arrives is a
progressive number that is needed for the controls and
he hulk and thor hulk and thor is nothing more
than a further subdivision of
the latitude longitude squares
so practically from the
typical position here we are in jn 65  charlie lima I
identify a square around here of
about 4 km, passing these data and a
certain precision, it is possible to calculate
the kilometers of distance between the d  and
stations basically
[Music]
what happens what he wants later can
come to
us at this moment we are receiving
thanks to I drive the every plane transmits
telemetry information
inside to outside via radio on the
frequency of 1.090 mega giga 090 that it
transmits
of the data
about the position then what is it that
transmits position and that's it because then
the speed is given by the distance
then the city I thought it was given its
identifier however it transmits
a whole series of information including a
fundamental one that we need the
position and the  height because from these
two information we know where
the plane is and we know at what height and from there
we know where we are and
we know later I'll explain how our
correspondent so we know the
software does the calculation to say that
you were around and when  there will be the
time window useful for making the
connection, it is logical that if the two
stations are at sea level the
connection  o the distance of the
link is given by the height of the
plane so the higher the plane the
more the kilometers of the
link increase this is mono-directional it
means that if they see 550 450
kilometers they are 400 plus 400 then 900
km
in reality if a  a little more because it
may be that the two stations
are in the mountains like 2000 meters and
therefore the distance also varies and therefore
technically we are around 1,000
kilometers away on a frequency
of vhf up where these are
frequencies that tend to be
optical therefore
they do not bounce like the hf of the
in the sky and go back but go
straight away so they tend
to cover distances around and 3 400 km 5
100 if no one to do more uncertain
conditions with the plane it is the safety
to always do it as you can see  as
the height of the
correspondent increases, so does the range
of these so I have this as you can see in
a station with two stations that
are both at 100  0 meters
so I am in the mountains at a
kilometer high
[Music]
another thing that must not be in the
way are we will give you the example
in our case the alps the alps can
create a problem if the altitude
of the plane is too low because
the incidence nevano ends up behind it
does not pass over the others but ends up
on the mountain so the software
also takes this into account so that if
I have the alps and I am too far below the
alps and the plane is behind the alps  for
example he will tell me that the connection is
impossible so another
fundamental thing that suffers from calculating is
the let's say our optical profile
regarding the mountains
this is I am giving a little fast
because
if we have drilled I would like to fall within the
terms of themes stop me  if there is
something you do not understand this here is
how you can see then software
basically there is the map with all
the position of the planes that moment
you see our profile and that of
our correspondent
and qu  i tells us all that all the
planes that are inside this
purple part are planes that are right
for making the connection because
there may be cases where you have more than one
plane inside this case there is
only one  that this is here that you see in
purple so this station that here in
venice is communicating with this that
in germany
through this plane the software
tells you the position and now you can't see it
but it also tells how many minutes it has entered
and how many minutes it is still  seconds and
what is still good for the
connection attention that there are here
there is none but there may be other
rich ones can enter become active
and therefore continue to generate
connection is interesting because
depending on the incidence of
the how they say of the  entry of the
plane because in this case the plane
enters
as the line is said transversely
if instead it is parallel to the line the
connection lasts longer so an
airplane that is parallel  lo to this line
which therefore was a direction that is towards
the destination operator or the one he
is calling tends to have a longer duration
when it passes through through the duration
is shorter then also depends on the
speed of the plane but usually at
that height there  are always fast
software must be configured substantially
by inserting our call is also
the frequency because the frequency
because depending on the frequency the
wavelength varies from 144 meters and 194 mega two
meters to 430 and about 70 centimeters to 1200
a gig and two  indeed agi ge3 23 cm to 10
giga and three centimeters then bounce
then changes according to the
frequency you go enter the window
opens and closes according to the
possibilities
this is what I said before to the
landlord that instead of having up to
four  it is further more precise
this is what we are going to
connect the z7 that
that low area italy tells you those b
then 596 km this is based  from these
two calculations these these here is how to
give longitude latitude for the radio
motors corresponds to the point and inserted
these data automatically the
software calculates the area between the two points
for which you see the plane of the mountains
this here is our friend  this
on the other hand so our
correspondent we want to connect
redemption that does not refer to
the first sense that in reality the
person you saw before is here in the
Veneto there are no mountains anyway who
makes the profile and tells me that at this
moment  there are two good planes to make
the connection on those in purple there
are two it
is probably one of these sooner or
later it could go inside to
make it good so right
now this is a link that we
radio operators that but this is  feasible
when we go to see the planes he practically gives the
name of the plane the
geographical position the altitude the
direction also gives the model
let's say that  from one point of view it is not
logical that if we have a boeing
what is a 78 and giant if we have a
tiny piper and therefore the bounce is
much less
distance to the intersection and the time of
intersection so at some point
this  now it is zero because already inside
if it wouldn't be I don't know there are three minutes left
for the connection in this case it is for
fourteen minutes it is possible to make the
connection the colors and the planes are
interesting because the gray one is a
plane that has nothing to do with that
route  that we have decided it does not
interest us that is it has nothing to do with it
is not interesting for us so it is
completely out of the way the
yellow one is an under-share euro so it is
too low to act as a repeater
the red one and useful height but it is not
yet inside the window  useful for doing
so still distant the purple one is about to arrive
instead useful for doing
these or those of that moment you can
connect as I said before the intersection
can be of this  type and this
tends to last longer because
the plane stays longer inside
the interesting part i.e. in the
window in this case it lasts less
keep in mind that in any case to make a
connection it takes about 30 seconds
so it is not necessary to big  minutes
that is the connection on the races very
fast because they are exchanged between data
the connection is finished so 3 15 to 20
seconds is more than enough to make
the connection to exchange data
well this is not interesting this here
is just a curiosity information title
this  here are practically all the
air traffic that there was
practically throughout the contest that
is when a race in Europe is due
as you can see the black part on the tracks
of the past planes as you can see the
coverage is total so finding a
plane is much easier than that  which
usually seems to be only a matter of minutes
not hours to find a useful plane it is not
that difficult to find one and this does not
seem to be  lando of 2013 every year since yesterday there
are more not less so if you want there is a
video but here there is no internet
so you cannot see there was a video
in which you could hear the voice of a person
who did not  you hear nothing during the
call then at a certain point you hear
the voice go up you make the connection and then
you hear the voice go down because
interested anyway there are all the
connections on youtube where you hear
this
the two meters are connections in 144
these 10  giga these two giga and 3 1 gb
2 so you have the opportunity to see
different useful frequencies how it
works during the race during the race
you have to find the
interesting correspondent is interested between the
connection tendentially
a chat is used where all the connections
that is  all connections sorry
all people who are interested in making
that type of connection sign up for
this chat and say i want to make a
connection and i am ready
who is interested gl  i said i am here
this is my landlord you know
that information is essential to know
the position the position is put
in the soft software it says ok or
no but at 5 minutes but also ten minutes
but also at two minutes and dani  you decide
the connection must always be done
via radio
this is only a support to say
let's start and let's say let's synchronize c
otherwise the connection would be impossible
then the chat that via
internet is made only to
start
let's say
to see the possibility of the
connection then the connection and all
the data is always passed it is not
possible that is you are disqualified
you pass the data through the chat
the data must pass through the
radio
I am not here to explain it because I do not
see before that with the talk that this is
what practically is used
who  is interested in seeing the software
may come from there we can do some
tests
to get an idea of how the
slides son works  o been made by alessandro
example you avoid h who normally operates an
aspect of this type of connections
which unfortunately is not there because he is going
blog doing a race that starts tomorrow
at 4 is going near
guido's house they are on those mountains there in  high
and that's it if you have some questions
someone had already asked before about the
antennas for the antennas there are no
big problems in the sense that it is
better to have a directive eight elements
of the five elements forward you don't
even need great power
and logic which
then depends on the  type dario type of
distance
keep in mind that an 8 10 elements and in
any case an opening of 20 30 degrees
or rather up to around 20 30 degrees so
the plane is always inside
all you do not need to go behind the plane but
just point towards  the
correspondent automatically if
the vertical opening is the
front opening of the antenna more than
sufficient to make the
connection therefore it is not necessary to have
pointing in a  zimuth and zenith
to follow the plane because it is
absolutely useless it's like pointing
a farther pile you go through the pile
opens then the plane you always catch it
naturally the plane in sin
really a small part of that
part goes back and a  small
part ends up on its correspondent ai
is not all the signal there are questions
but we need this
good proof from where we get
all the information about the planes that
are passing to the information and
what software did that one of
the German engine
initially  he took from between ilarda
24 then
I assume this is a company I know it was
okay he
wanted money at some point to
get the data then this he said
is an open source product so I
do not see anything is basically they
are rowers between  which alessandro who
have receivers that the same thing that
for those interested can come and
see us receives and sends the data
automatically to a cent server  rale that
practically everyone's position
keep in mind that this is used here
in europe in america that is where there are
airplanes in africa for example
it is hardly used both because there is
a very few of amateurs and because
there is no large and therefore  it is feasible
only in certain cases, however, the reception
that is the positioning pose that
you see since yesterday is done by other
radio amateurs who receive and send
free of charge to him because he
is interested in giving other questions
well thank you
[Applause]