then 20 25 minutes in short we talk about
non-technical things because clearly here
we are talking about the h factor
I speak on behalf of isaac after visp I
give you a face a flash on who on the
association for undertow I made
a couple of publications in 2013 on the
rules  of engagement for a penetration
test and the following year on let's say on the
violation of industrial systems
the topic conceals today's talk
presents the latest research that in
fact works the patronage also of
discomfort as well as some associations
even if a  work in progress precisely on the
problem of wellness and jacket
I know that it is a non-profit association
that groups people who deal with
t governance and cyber security but
more at an organizational
level at the business level does it offers courses and
is clearly  all things vender
neutral the after maybe we also
do them a flash I tell you but
basically it makes disclosure
so for example the photo that there
in b  ace you see we
sponsored the cyber challenge
that has been talked about a bit about but lately
after macaroni then the contest at
an Italian level
then the constitution of a team
that does ethics activities the king and the
try to go and challenge the rest
of the world
at the level of count
isaac in three chapters there is milan rome and
venice venice is the most
recent chapter we are about 250 members we do
indeed disclose some
events the next events we make one
on 27001 at villa manin where we
also bring a couple of  testimonials who have
embarked on the certification path
and maybe someone knows the event that
never the sixth edition on
application security that I think we do
in October at ca foscari and therefore it is a
very talked day
so let's say there are also
international testimonials so basically
we do  we make disclosure and in
cyber security issues well because
this is the starting point in short  l
as regards the part of the
awareness because it is the problem
of human error it is an
absolutely important aspect so here I
took an article of some let's say
some time ago there are
conflicting voices but substantially a
sum director that the postal police
some  some time ago he had made an estimate
that 90 percent of accidents are
due to the human factor
and he is certainly the person a little more
competent who also wrote a book.
the
burglary tools for which those who have
read it
in short find things that find
content that despite being an
absolutely old old book in short,
is still valid today because in any case
we are talking about vulnerability on a
psychological level but basically it is
recently I had to face
the topic  there is no documentation
no there is anything I found for
example a little book he wrote there
Franchina for those in the sector maybe they
know who they are
let's say about social genres but there is little
in short there are there is little
station and I got an idea that
the problem is linked to the fact that
psychological skills are needed, that is in the
sense that  however, whoever deals with
security is always a technologist here
you have to reason with a psychologist
currently, in short, psychologists who
will also be computer science surely
there are there are few
this is the structure of the white paper
more or less in short I told you  I have
done more than someone
so it is quite run-in
I normally do a survey I try
if I can also bring a business
that is therefore a real case of a
campaign maybe it is awareness raising
to explain how how to do it and this is
the working group then  I am the
coordinator then we also have
a sociologist inside who was a former manager
of information systems and in any case
people or all the people operating in the
company for  Because in my opinion the component
here that really makes the difference is
the experience only the user who
manages we tell their users
so whoever is in the training systems that
manages the users knows what are perhaps
the most common errors and errors
then I am  figured this the title is
born a little from this idea but that in
any case
the brain can be assimilated to a
firewall and therefore hypothesized and that
a firewall arrives that
you have just bought it you have to do the
configuration then define the
rules for
the accesses rather  what to do the arden
ying and then you put it into
production so I searched on let's say
this concept on google
this beautiful kit came out
on amazon that we say at the end clearly
school to assemble and brain
then the optics is that you receive
this thing here had to assemble it by
putting a minimum of hardening on it
so the effort here is certainly
not talking about  technology but let
's talk about some psychological bases let
's say about the functioning of the mind
so let's say the brain is anyway
some me I'm not a doctor so
discouragement and coppo I can say
[ __ ] and let's say I'm not going to deal with
the topic in depth but
who has it  done who does it for a living
let's say he defined the
rules well so there are
real vulnerabilities a bit as we say
there can be vulnerabilities on
a system even the brain nor any and
therefore fear the concept the prize
the curiosity are aspects let's say  that
are the vulnerabilities of this thing that
is part of my security system
these things here are clearly
usually well known for example to those who
sell those who sell I know if you have ever
heard of pnl pianelle are strategies
of
interaction between the user also  in the
language in the way of posing for
the sale
then those who make the sale know very well
these vu  lnerability
what is the concept that if it goes into the field
of security
the impact maybe it can be it can be
different anyway here is let's say
the brain is part of the people who
are my users it is part of the
security system and therefore the myth is
let's say that  maybe you have seen
dave's cartoon so the point is
that I do packing I do hardening
I behave etcetera etcetera
and then on the other side or of the
dave users who continually create
flaws in me and so this thing here
I have to take into consideration and do with it
some reasoning absorbs the
work in progress so this here is not
the work is not finished the publication is
not finished yet his party let's say
two three months in short we are working
now we have about 35 answers and
these are the questions you see that
anyway the topic  it is precisely linked to
the human factor are typically companies and
we say
companies that are now not in
public administration services  one a little less the
cut of the companies is quite large
and this in some way especially
on the question linked to that we say them
with the orange slice
if you can then see the answers
then it is linked a little to the type
of sample after we stop on this
so what goes first one of the
questions of which this here the result is
there are computer accidents
due to human error so you see
that compared to the initial screen they
are therefore we are talking about a 72
percent but what is the problem with the faith
of the slice  red no, that is,
while on other things
when this question is asked about
penetration tests or security problems
if I talk to those who follow security
maybe they deliberately say no that is,
however, not for a disclosure speech that
problem is that probably share part
of  those freights and also because they do not know
because the user is difficult to
admit that he has been cheated in quotation marks and
therefore in here  that no that is already
a bit reduced compared to the standard
in my opinion is reduced dramatically
because probably the head
of logical security does not even know that
his users have done some [ __ ]
in quotation marks maybe he is then the
problem but he cannot understand who did
it  the trigger another question is
in the event of a cyber incident
people do not know what they have to do and
therefore here you see that at least most of them,
at least linked to the sample,
can be traced back to the training systems
if I had probably gone down with it
if the sample was of companies  a
little smaller the slice in quotes
of the nos which is quite small
would probably be a bit
bigger here there is also a certain concept
of maturity so the orange slice
that demonstrates that for individual
accidents users know what to
do
means  that somehow here or
of the users at least according to those who answer
that they are a little more mature then instead
for or  Instead of calling
training systems or those who deal with
safety for managing
incidents, users may know in quotation marks to
debunk the basic problems so
here somehow demonstrates a certain
level of maturity on his program
another thing is  tests are made
on to measure
the level of security
so the most classic things
are clearly the vulnerabilities to penetration
tests if you are interested that there is the
understood it is the notebook that I
told you that I have taken care of the rules of
engagement is freely  downloadable fate
search notebooks isaac in venice and
the notebook is the number one notebook we do not
talk about this and we do not talk about magic or
office-like concepts because
now even the difficult tests,
let's say in a certainly
corporate environment, are also starting to be
fairly standardized what is the
problem is the aspect of
social engineering because engineers and social is
the real test  in the h factor then in
this speech of the firewall of the
human firewall and you see that the answers are
very low on 35 1 he said that he does them
because talking about social in general
because it is an absolutely
important component so these this text
here taken from a slide of let's say  by
raoul church of 2009 so we are talking about
almost ten years ago this is that
however the bad guys have understood they have
learned to use the narrow let's say
social engineering and this wait
will be more and more advanced because
clearly milic stuff today of
the security apparatuses or in any case the
technological and self-supporting part then
artificial intelligence etc.
etc. so it will be more and more
sophisticated so the importance
of the h factor of the human capacity
wait will grow if you want to
see a good movie but you have
already done it that of el is the title and
in short, there is this image of this woman
who tells is that she presents
herself as ingenuity  social re and explains on
the other hand a person who deals with
security how he manages to convince his
wife to give him all the data and he
says absolutely no my wife is
trained and knows it is instead let's say
also exploiting concepts for
example of affinity  in short, there is a moment
during the film that
on the other side the wife a little
reluctant is made to start the noise
of a child crying this thing here
decays we say the inhibitory brake
so the person on the other side
assumes that we  is a mother who has
problems as a mother and so let's say
the harmony is there so
somehow then the rules
certainly fall in any case social in general it
is something that we all use no, that is
in the sense that if I had to understand
with  someone I look at his social profile
so surely it is an
important aspect and it will grow let's say in my
opinion that he will leave more and more this
is a let's say a nice intervention done by
those in fashion from seas  or a few years ago
on the illustration of an expert and shawn
test and this nickname makes you understand a little
no so here there was just
the illustration of a case of a priest
on the text the aim of demonstrating
vulnerabilities and all the initial phase
of  goethe ring had practically given
negative feedback then and password
strong so doing the bag
could give nothing
the hardening was quite advanced and
then in the end one is forced in
this case to fall back on social
engineering they found a bus
the illustration of a  real case they
found the receptionist who had
passion then the year targeted
passion for apps
well her child so let's say up to
give to her child then they made a
few words they sent me an app
then compromised the cellphone
4g connection and with the wifi  internal
ghetto then gateway towards to
enter with the perspective of beams a back
door then hypothesize in short this
mobile phone incan  descente that let's say I have to
work to get a more solid back do
because if this turns off my
mobile phone, however, the whole phase of
summer escalation started from a
social engineering activity has
however it is ineffective
so what is the characteristic of one
of social engineering  one thinks of the
one with the sweatshirt there is not that there is
a photo for example of one who was then
arrested and who had skills and
let's say in some way of hacking of
social genres and wanted to break into the
world of fashion then they have it  taken
this is not the stereotype of who
makes who makes who is so what are the
characteristics of social engineering
with skilled interpersonal skills and a person
who hides in any case but in the end that is,
if you see for a moment those lyrical things
fundamentally does not necessarily have
skills  of a technological type
therefore those who do ethics activities the king
santa madonna must
also have technological competence those who do social
engineering no and therefore  of in the end
let's say simplifying the vision is that
a salesman who uses
neuromarketing tactics for criminal purposes
so that is what is
possibly on the
other side how it works
surely is also based on
targeting the person so it is a bit of
a difference  between the fiji and the spy I mean
I still have to aim it and then
let's say the aspect of pretending to be authoritative
give support hypothesize to give
support then exploit ignorance
on the other side let's say who is
mine my my prey are
fundamental aspects  and therefore in some way
you have to pay attention to
people looking for information but
in my opinion this also lies in let's say in
what for example I do, that is
surely if someone asks me for
information at my house he makes me the
marketing calls
I tell him look not me  interests
etc. etc. the same thing must
also be reported within the company
but here is this but this stuff
here called c  The brain is still made
therefore by those who study it from the
elements so there are 33 brains
so we call this three parts of the brain
so the part is the most extended part
then the most outward part is the
rational part and we say the part where
there is the intermediate brain 15 with an
intense rational veil and the intermediate brain
listens but whoever decides is the part
that is more low-level
so when the neanderthal man
let's say he began his
let's say his growth in terms of
knowledge  had let's say his brain
was first it was primitive and yet what is the
catch that is what they
decide so if I can
somehow compromise the
primitive brain it is the reaction
happens instinctively and then maybe
rationally I realize the
of the problem even more so if I
realize I also find it difficult to
disclose it so even what is
said the first the problem of saying that I
had an accident
d  we are of a social nature is because then I
realize that I made a let's say
made a chapel and therefore
somehow it shows a weakness
no but actually it happened to me
even recently it is a customer who
later fired the person that yes you do
it  you fired the doctors there may
be but it is clear that these here are
professionals so to people who work
at an advanced level if you have not
explained anything other user did not
inspire him what a
partner-type attack is yes maybe that  is the final outcome
but maybe you have to give it a moment
also of elements so in let's say the
primitive brain is still the let
's say the point the critical point
the thing to work on ten
commandments in the sense that we then say
to make an awareness campaign
substantially these  are the points to
touch because because for the brain to
learn I can only work here too
let's say at a
medical physiological level that is the
concept is that  and it is the repetition to the
emotion these are the only elements
for which one learns so when you went to
school to ask the question
continue reading the thing was created
the synapse and those oscillated to speak
to answer the questions to make the theme
or the  emotion the emotion one puts
his hand on the fire it is not that he has to
repeat it no that is to say one remembers for the
whole life that the hand that the hand
burns that the fire
clearly you tv so you must
somehow be able to pass it
let's say this what I will do there  'human you have to
go from an unconscious incompetence
to more advanced states so
the incompetence and unconscious
I would say that it is here very often it is the stunt
of my users that I have around so
they do not know and are also unaware
therefore already an advanced state and at least
of  to be not to know but to be
aware that is this is 1 st is already an
advanced
stage the stage let's say maybe the one let's say
more advanced is the includes a little more
evolved is the comp  conscious mind you have
finished a course on
cyber security the user before clicking
on the name of the buildings reads
carefully but the stage
the best is that of the
unconscious competence which is that for
example at the moment I am
walking breathing that is or a pocket
open on walking on breathing therefore it
is however not impacting on the fact that I am
talking so let's say they travel of
their own life
so that is the state the state the
point the point of arrival
primitive brain is still visual so if
you can get through let's say
visual concepts then  cartoons rather
than films the one with a greater grip
because let's say the brain remembers
precisely because the primitive part
remembers the part the images you can
do more and it is then the strategy maybe
in the banks that you do lately
always banks do a lot these cartoons
animated simplified in the business space
that will be later in the white paper
this was adopted  to this strategy you have to
give some indications on what to do
because this is also up to werner
so if you leave the user a free hand and
let's say him you risk that he improvises
maybe you have the good one who does it
correctly but the not good one if you do not give
him at least  an
IT regulation and he can't understand so
somehow you wrote
what the basic rules are he must
have them
and he signed it when he was
hired so somehow a minimum
of responsibility in what he
read as he had to
sign us  well I told him work in progress
but there are certainly some first
ideas that I can give you that is you have to
think about the primitive brain this
is the fundamental element to be able to
maximize the return
on investment on this type in
some way maybe awareness if it is
do towards us students
the concept is the fact of no we say to
do a continuous activity because
precisely if you do not reach alone  the state of the
conscious user but you have to
somehow create the synapse so
the user must act in an
unconscious way and on s ii it is a problem
however also of the brain I tell you for
example something related to passwords for example
that is eight-character passwords
we are all aware that they are
insufficient
so there are people who begin to bring
to 12 characters such as the rip-off that the
brain does not have the
physiological possibility of measuring to
memorize more than seven eight characters
so you bring it to 12 and then
automatically if the user writes it
a let's say on a piece of paper
so it is not a forcing with respect to the
physiological nature of the brain and
you have to take this into account you must also
think about let's say on the level of
maturity of my users so when
done in an IT regulation
sometimes I happen to find
very outdated IT regulations but it
is something that is
probably there in the making  and vulnerabilities
we are talking about now in two years they
will not even exist anymore no so we are
all aware that cyber security
evolves very very quickly
we must certainly start from who and most
critical icon spoke before let's say that
typically the paron is in the
starting stage 0  no, that is, he is but
whoever you want him to come from less that is in
the
unconscious sense and let's say he does not know, however,
it will not be the problem but alas and the
target defined by the attacker who
also makes a reasoning on the costs I go on
what he does the movements and with the
movements  financial in the
administrative managers has commercial information
commercial manager
the CEO i.e. they are the
targets for those who do social engineering
certainly the favorite one the signal
is to verify in different ways
then to the concept of females use
so you know that the news
if you want to repeat them  you are able to
distort reality and therefore also here
the fact that one introduces himself and
perhaps asks for information explain the
concept of making a check and
live on who is the interlocutor so
do not react instinctively but take the
time to answer me use
short and non-technical contents this is a  a
fundamental aspect precisely because we said that
the brain is visual to focus on the
personal sphere because in any case in my opinion it has
more grip
so let's say that if you explain that s1
you double click and it strikes you all the
photos of the holidays on your pc instead it does
the same thing on an example  company
maybe it makes more sense in short to do it
in the personal sphere and also form
your account parts so alas the
firewall h I do not have it only in the
company but it is also
with the counterparties and therefore we say
sir triggers  the whole speech two words
about let's say about isaca then do
neutral certifications in the world of
security are the most recognized
in Italy but it requires a little less but if  go
abroad and work cybersecurity if
you do not have the isaca
difficile certifications maybe that is, it is even worth more than
a degree in computer security in
short, it is clear
outside Italy they
are also those, let's say they are
definitely tough but then they are the ones
who also give you a  return this is
a statistic from a few years ago on
computer certifications therefore not
of security but computer certifications
the first is the I can and the one
on the implementation of the risk the earthquake which is
what they are mac and for those who make the
sisal min and the optimal  so, however, you give yourself
a vision also from the business point of
view
and then there is the cisa i am i cisa that
at this point it is a little more we call
it even more at a high level
well if you have not answered the
questionnaire do it I think that  the
publication as always will be
free then I hope it will be finished by the
end of the year
let's say we have just
started anyway if you have any
do  send if not I finished so that here
is the wing he put me and you are interested in
the topic if you like it you are
also interested in being part of the
working group
no problem in short ago 13 the only
thing is that how do you have to  dedicate
weekend evenings to these things someone but
in principle we divide the
capitoline that is here area anyway
reading is a bit like making a thesis in the
end no my goal is to be able to
give some rules in some
simple way not the ideas that you  I gave
this is the problem that
I found myself in this situation
normally I do the publications
because when I do not know I could start making
me understand but
in short, in short, it has always been ours to
do it for me I do it for the purpose of
dissemination  there is not in the sense that I
then share the
let's say the experience and I also share
let's say what I learned perhaps by
studying his on the individual topics
so it is a question of reading the
documentation what  there is therefore nic
surely I have read it but for
example where I am reading a book on
the brain where I understood these
aspects related to the state the speech is
that this is precisely how the tweet seems above
all not clear for who it is for who it
is let's say  psychologist absolutely these
are unmarked concepts on sales
if you are interested,
write to me and then we will evaluate in short, the
volunteers are always welcome well
thank you
[Applause]