hello everyone thank you for coming
sorry for the delay but there was an emergency
and planning kittens basically
so a very very serious thing
excuse me if in the meantime I go
back and forth with my eyes but the sight is
killing me this this beautiful
thing reflector  let's talk today indeed
let's do it a little step
back
hi my name is michael i do the given
scientist i mainly deal with
machine learning i work in a company in the
province of padua
we do some of these cute little things
we don't have many cats but we are
gearing up in short then since  where
we start with this discourse
we have machines that do practically
anything we are thinking of
using machines that drive
themselves we organize drones in a lot of
ways
we use a lot of technology a lot
of this technology but the lacking from
a fundamental point of view is not
able  to see how we see
and there is a fundamental problem with that
we see in such an
intuitive way that we think it is a simple task
it is not a foreshortening task at
all at all at all
that's why we find it a bit difficult to give
this ability to the machines precisely
because we ourselves have a little difficulty
in understanding what it is to see exactly
what are the focal points to solve
what are the problems to solve in the
vision what is this this is called
unstable figure I don't know if ok this
thing doesn't work well on this the
reflector is an image with
an unstable configuration
you have seen all those images  who
have more than one interpretation able
to see it as something that comes
out or something that goes in at the
same time
this type of illusions and are
fundamental to make us understand what are
the mechanisms underlying the vision
basically the fact that it is not
taken for granted that we  we can
interpret a three-dimensional world
we have an apparatus that gives us an
i  Two-dimensional image
from which we insert the
three-dimensional shape into the objects but on
our retina that
two-dimensional image to insert this shape
we use eu ristic, that is,
simplified rules of computation methods that are
not exactly exact
but very very fast and light that
can go there  the 3d image respects
what we are looking at the problem
is that being heuristics are not always
perfect the optical illusions
are basically the blitzes
within the system all we see them
if this is able to see it but maybe
you are color books simply the other
was  due to the three-dimensional inference
of two-dimensional images
this is the context effect we have
the same color even if
you know it you can still see the different color
this is essential to be able to
navigate in a space to obtain
additional information on the quality
of objects in the environment
of things not  we had this ability that
there s here  it seems a vision defect
we did not have this ability we will not
be able to solve a lot of
tasks our complex vision
even just the apparatus how to say
the camera sensor
already only those very very complex
we think we think that the
deer image on the retina a  place if you see is
that thing in the shape of hicks with the now
the optic nerve
at the point where it crosses it is
called cassation a part
of the information the right eye is
conveyed with a part of the information
the left eye and goes to  left and one
part of the left information does the
same to the other part because it's okay you
can be the
exact answer because having eyes that
are basically spheres
we need to integrate the
information coming from this part
of the visual field with  the information that
comes from that part of the visual field
that is collected and from the two eyes
simultaneously at that point
once the info  rmation is sent to
the optic nerve and is actually decorated
then a journey begins a part
of the information b a neural network
that passes over the brain another that
passes under the brain and the 32
literally is an extremely
intricate system that joins everything  the rest
of the systems that are internal to the
brain to allow us to see but
this thing is very complicated
when we make the analogy
with the camera for vision
the camera is roughly the retina
not much because there is much more
that is c  'is already processing the first layers
of the
retina realize that we should have for
example
a hole in our visual field for each
eye the point where the optic nerve
fits into the socket of the
eye there is there there is a  empty there
are receptors but we do not see this
thing of or
integrated our eye among other things is
taken for example by creationists as an
example of perfection that cannot  ò not
result if not from a creator but in
reality it is absolutely bagato our
receptors look back that is
blood vessels and innervation are
in front of the receptors with respect to the
image and it is a designer type thing
I do not think he would have done it
this way  and we to be able to see
how we see we have to integrate that
information example this work is
done in the early stages immediately
but then we have a lot of other things
we have to do to make sense of
things
an image can be easily
represented in rgb with three
two-dimensional matrices with a bit of values is not
a difficult thing but from there to understand
what is in the image the past so
much that really passes here we have
a small representation of
what is the structure of the neocortex and
of the pause court but let's say  yes of
a cortex
there is a primary visual recall air is
the only area affected by the vision
no it does only that n  or however it is called the
primary visual area you see that there
are overlapping layers
this is a hint handwriting
basically they took a
piece of the brain cut it
and colored it to make it evident
if you see there is a hierarchy
remember it will come  will come back after
this the pixel does not mean by
itself we said it
I hope it is a clear concept I
do not know how to make it understood the fact that it
gives an image pass a
representation of the world
passes a few identifications of
objects and one  of the many tasks we
do every day when we see
without even noticing
what it is this is a beautiful kitten and it is
easy to recognize it is not immediate a
two-year-old child recognizes it as a
kitten in the early stages of history
and artificial vision was attempted to
approach  interesting to solve the
problem of identifying
objects that is modeling
what is a cat then do us  or more or less an
index of the distance of the image that I am
seeing with respect to the model I get
an idea the cat is also easy that is that they
pin the longtail field the fia
quite soft etc. etc.
so it is easy to identify and now
what we do our model  where
exactly it had to we can have
different points of view
the cat can have different positions
remember that the cat is not a
solid and less liquid and what happens with
this difficult little one is difficult if you
use a model so at
a certain point in our history
this story is very long that is if
we start from the beginning of the history of the
study of vision two centuries ago
roughly when we began to
understand something a century ago the kittens
intervened even then to give us a
hand
not so voluntarily electrodes in the
skull and something like that
a nobel was won for this the
nobel on the identification of
perceptual fields was fundamentally
found that some neurons respond
specifically to shapes with
specific and specific inclinations and some others
with different inclinations
this thing is very important because it
has given us insight and norms on how
vision works how
neural computation works in our brain
we have been taught
something  a teacher who
explained to us how to do these tasks how to
infer three-dimensional geometry
how to distinguish objects how to
exploit the context to get more
information comes to us
absolutely naturally
but then wanting to solve the problem
of artificial vision
wanting to give machines the ability
to interpret  the world is a good way
to use a model to explain
specifically what it has to see what it
has to do
maybe not so much at some point
an interesting thing
happens that machine learning then
that set of statistical techniques
that are used to solve problems
problems without having to explain the
machines what the solution is but
making sure that the machine derives from the data
the solution autonomously ok
they encountered the internet and at a certain
point even the computational power
reached a sufficient level to
allow you to take advantage of certain  algorithms
certain algorithms that were carried
out for many years to solve
this problem but that just couldn't
do it in reality we are talking about here
more or less 2009
in 2009 it was founded for example by
some scientists many
psychologists imagine that it is a database
of images with balls
this is a cat this is a dog
this is a flower more or less 15 thousand
classes took a lot of effort a
lot of effort a lot of human work
but basically they took advantage of
the internet so kittens
intervened once again to  give us a
hand because without them without the
preponderant presence of the skies
inside the internet  we would not have
had some of our classes and here
comes a technique to deep neural
networks basically what we
call deep learning what is this
thing indeed for we start from this
nice old man a professor an
english professor what is called
the cause of neural networks  for
years to solve the problem of
artificial vision for years it went
on no this best method the
best method let's use it true lost
all competitions
until the internet arrived
the computational power from lillo and
defined the standard to solve the
problem then  the combo lution to the neo
to the networks a specific type of
neural network before people use models
used decision 3 used other
machine learning techniques now that's the
standard musi something different or
better then he knows something different because he
just released another model
of neural network that perhaps will supplant
the previous one
that  what is a neural network, however, now
I am doing the most pulpy part of the
presentation do not be afraid for the
letters in greek it is one thing it is a
summation basically what a
neuron does a number it takes the inputs
that are weighted in short it has its own
internal function  with a threshold and says it is
quite
ok it is quite no when he says ok he shoots
too the neurons do this they are very
simple units in a very
very complex network
basically learning happens because those weights
are modified in a sensible way
to achieve the purpose you are
looking for  to reach iteration
interaction after interaction to
the vip neuro networks federation we put
a lot of these things together in
the next layer and then we do
instead of one thing my little one we limit
many one after the other the result
of the previous computation and it becomes the
input of the next computation
and  so on
from here to give computers the ability to see
let's talk about it then take a nice
image image made per pixel
then let's say that the input value of
each single input neuron is the
value of the pixel
this value is multiplied by the
weight of that connection with the
next neuron
at this point there is the  'integration
means that some of these neurons
some of these married pixels
will pass through the
mathematical filters ok of the kernels of the
mathematical filters and with a
topological localization so the neighboring ones
will interact with neurons that are close
and so on and so on
and at this point they will slowly begin
to  extract future features
gradually more and more complex
we start from what he had said in the
kitten lines lines with certain
inclinations line assembled in
with the other curves backgrounds fields more or
less dark color differences
gradually as there is computation
we arrive  to increasingly complex features
a structure that resembles an eye one
structure that resembles the nose is a
structure that resembles the cat's tail
more and more complex until the end
what basically does a
neural network that has to do image recognition
extracts these features and stay
these features and then uses
the last part of the network to  make a
classification says the object that I
know as a cat what characteristics
these ok has them
all yes no what is the cool of neural networks
that are very robust a
model just changes the object you are
seeing in the most suitable to represent it
the network  neural instead ekstrand by itself
the characteristics and very robust
noise you have given that it is so and so to
a paw above anything
you can identify it because you put
within the data set the variance
to which you want to be able to respond and
therefore basically building a
dataset you are already giving the
neural network the ability to respond to
those tasks ok maybe
ok you remember what  we said
before
you see this hierarchical structure do not
jump kittens this our my
cortex we have
inside our head a
neural network that already does this task
what you see there on the left
basically neuro indifferent
arranged in layers predisposed for
specific computations
we still do  struggles to determine
which exactly with
organized votes to succeed the arcella
ability to interpret the world
around us starting from a
two-dimensional image projected on the retina
this is a way in which we see for
what we know now from here we
have managed to  extract the concept and
apply it to machine learning to
transform it into a technology that are
neural networks facebook when it tells you you
want to pay foo in the photo he has
just uploaded what he is doing knows
that it is foo because he uses your
images to pull models of
neural networks  for facial recognition
when we want
I don't know there are a lot, he said to himself
steini google
we are full of this technology sometimes
we do not even realize
exactly how for us to see is
perfectly normal we are also getting used
to the fact that the machines begin a
little timidly to acquire the
ability to see therefore  it no
longer amazes us to see these things the
fact that now
systems can automatically tell you ok in this
photograph there is a person
taking a plane it is not taken for granted there is a
lot of technology and there is a lot of
understanding
times questions I know  that is a lot of stuff
girls I know perfectly I can go
on talking now so I pray
one thing is from around 800 that
three-dimensional photos were taken with two
with photographic manga there is some
development also in this aspect
in what sense some development I think that is
having information from a
single photo you get certain information
but if I have two they are three-dimensional
images it is easier to est  obtaining
information is a little easier
we can evaluate the distances within
a certain range but not beyond
and we are not too close in reality
so within a certain range we are very
good we have stereoscopic vision
basically because in our
period of evolution as a species when
we were  on trees it was very
convenient to have the exact distance of the
branch we wanted to cling to during
another it was a matter of life or death
and for this reason we have eyes on the
front of the face other evils year on the sides
to have a wider field of view to
identify  predators we needed to
have stereoscopic vision when
the object we want to estimate is too
distant we can no longer use this
system we use others many
others it is not a single system for example it is
the relative movement of objects more
or less distant systems  of occlusion
of one object with respect to the other if
we are moving more distant objects
they move less than
us
and this is an index of what comes first
compared to what and therefore we make a
more distant estimate of things we do it
in a totally unconscious way
unaware yes like
most things
someone else
there is a lot  of stuff from neural networks
to the history of psychology and ecology
as needed a beautiful field
remember that a lot of this
technology comes from people who have
studied those materials unfortunately in
Italy we have preconceptions
about technique and psychology put together but
obviously they work
now he explained to us  substantially that
the understanding of a cat passes, however,
initial 7th step among the more or
less complex mechanisms you do not enter into this matter
because I am not able to understand
that it is a cat if the dataset we say is
poisoned by dirty data
substantially
the concept of the cat  of the machine
will become a monster sixth time that can
happen a human accustomed to
see knows that what a cat is
wrong a window for him will be a
cat ruin condemnation of
dirty dated a neural network is
something irreversible or something that
once you have ruined the mind of the
machine then you never go back I
don't know if  then I explained myself
as usual ctc tout if the
bagato dataset turned out to be that you
paid for a capacity and it may happen that
you do a training again by adjusting the
dataset basically ok so
let's say you have not lost knowledge because
maybe something that lasts over the years the
knowledge that learns
is learning
no actually basically what
is done is an interactive process
that is computationally extremely
heavy because you have to what happens
to train a neural network and
to present it to him he starts
with algorithms to make an algorithm more
used in this case is the back
propagation basically makes
the signal propagation
the right one  or a little bit and weights to see
if the result he has obtained with respect
to the input he has been given coincides
and you do it once twice three times
billion times every time exposed it
tweaks the weights a little with some
minimization algorithms  'error
and then the result arrives however it is
very heavy however despite being both
very heavy they sell
computational power to do it in reality from
what you should do is re between in
now is very heavy as as as what
in fact data set
indeed the most used neural networks
also  open source to do all these
tasks are basically driven by
large companies
together with scientists who start
doing these tasks etc.
and then distributed because you can do
something called transference learning you
take the network that is the description I say
of the structure and of the
mathematical processes and understandings that are true
knowledge knowledge in this case
is in and distributed between the values of  the
weights of the net
you take those weights to the complete net
and what you do
take the last part the top one
and cut it the last part was that
of the classification you can cut
the part of the classification and make it
a new training on yours  dataset of
some kind why do you want a
neural network that can distinguish the
different batmans in the different movies the
different actors who made batman
what you do
you are taking advantage of the learning of the
network that has taken a lot of
precedent to learn how to extract the
characteristics
what is an eye what is a nose what is a
mouth
etc.  features that have already
been taken from the network are already the
inside of this thing is very convenient
because it really means that you and I
on our pc can arouse a
network  neural learning
something quite famous was for
example a company that produced
cucumbers that made a neural network
to distinguish
different types of cucumbers in their machines so as
not to have to separate the harvest to do the
harvest all together then there  it's a
machine that sorted them you can
really do anything with them at that point and
the training is
really simple once the network is
pre-trained because otherwise disaster
disaster if you don't need a nice
cluster so many graphics cards a lot of
time
let's talk about graphics cards in between  the other
because the neural network
problem of the graphics problem is similar to
matrix algebra nothing else
we take matrices with numbers
and turn them one way or another
some other
moms my question was about the
inputs when we did these  types
of jobs at the university
we usually always start from the fact that we had to
precisely have a fixed number of nodes
in in  gresso we had to take all the
images and rescaling an equal size
but it seems to me in some cases
impractical for example in this photo
maybe before doing the recognition
of the sawn ato it was even more to the
right I would like to cut it first image
that we do so also facebook and stuff
of the  genre for the faces so there is
still the constraint anyway to have
all the dimensions impute the same
dimension in it depends on the models
but basically you need to re-
scale there are you can apply some
algorithms that become invariant but
you are in fact doing a
internal restyling of the network so
somehow if we have not yet
overcome that problem
these rhythms work in serial in
parallel it is not so easy
this question I remember in the 90s
with silicon graphics and you could
schedule the jobs on the n nodes of the network
a in that  sense no
absolutely in parallel the facts
the problem can become  are np complete if
for many points of the network
if I a matrix with 40 thousand cells and or
a graphics card with 40 thousand inputs
I can do it in time 1 that is, it is totally
paralyzed of the two that point of
view the various frameworks that are
available today so it is  in software
nx net teano there are many
are fighting at the moment
more than anything else
at least for the two big ones then google and
amazon then tensor flow mx net on the
ability to paralyze then on the
internal parallelization of a single
machine on graphics cards  or the
parallelization on multiple machines with
graphics card is doing the
battle so much on some other because
for the rest that is the young yellow
is not that they are so complex once
you have created functions to create
the most common mathematical functions that
are used  for each layer a
framework of this type made so much
more that and coordinate the paralyzing
of the calculations that yes a
full place someone else
[Applause]