hello everyone my name is igor
falcomatà i'm someone who in Italian
sounds a bit bad a penetration test air
so i'm someone who does
attack simulations obviously in a
controlled environment in a controlled environment and
that is the important thing to check
the safety level of  network
applications systems infrastructures
etcetera etcetera
according to a very old motto that exists
like many places born in
cyber security which is try to break
into your system for next 2
try to break into your
systems before the attackers and
they really do I deal with
security  computer for some years
and among other things I am the founder of
security punto org which is one are
some mailing lists in particular
one called ml that deal with
computer security
when it was born in 98 it made sense
now perhaps with the forum with  internet
with all these things here a little less
sense but still some messages each
month every year passes I am active in the
various bz lug
r lug fluke it depends on where from cat
hat from where he resides at that
moment but at the end of the fair we will talk
today about aid and security aid
especially first of all very
fast since we have little time
what  I already know it to you I am not going to
explain it to you are all those things that
we increasingly put at home
from our refrigerator to our
television to our smartphone at the
end of the fair that is also an
object for good or bad that to do with
the iotti according to all the statistics to
an exponential growth it is estimated that
there will be c that there are already 20
billion devices more or less
connected in some way directly
or indirectly to the internet and that these
will reach 50 billion
2020 or so when  we
talk about garlic tisi
basically talks about anything
that uses ip technology and talks
to a command center directly with
others  objects and things of this kind
ok so much so that the most used term is
internet things the internet of things but
we also talk about the internet of every
thing or the internet of machines or
even a machine to machine that
when we talk about objects that  between
them in mesh networks or similar they
exchange information and make
decisions about things to do based on
a pseudo-artificial intelligence or
so on the internet or fas you have heard it
internet of server security skynet
internet of [ __ ] is a beautiful account
on twitter  where all
the failures of all these objects
connected directly to the internet are collected,
especially if we go and see if
we go and see when I made these
slides it was the period in which I
do not know if you remember alexa which is
the objective that did  amazon to
have at home something you can say to
order mini fries or
order spare panties and so
on here there was a period some
six me  yes it seems to me in which device alex
have begun to make some
satanic laughter seriously i'm kidding
ok so even the terminology is
very confusing ok what the hell does it mean
all this stuff the two ems etcetera
etcetera at the end of the fair
we are talking about objects objects that
they talk to other objects via the net
usually ip network ok that can be of
any type
this definition these slides you
see stolen here or stolen from
a talk I did with marco calamari
in a cassandra computer point
so that he knew him at an event that is
very interesting that it is called and
privacy which is held once or twice a
year where we talk about the law of
new technologies or privacy or
things of this kind,
big brother awards are also assigned to those
companies that have distinguished themselves in
quotation marks for  being particularly
little interested in our privacy or
vice versa too interested does not know
privacy more than it will be  had
legitimate use and users
of aids this interesting here now
we have done the introductory part
this part here instead start to
put a bit of brain
if you search internet of things on google
you will find few results
40 million results but what
interests me is that  what interests me
is the user more than the use i.e.
what can I do with the hot i everything what
i am interested in doing what is mine what
is your relationship my relationship with
the help try to think about it do not
use aids c  'is someone who does not
use me here this is already a
good good thing
we are talking about consumers private users
that all those who have the feed bit
the mobile phone we are talking about business users also
begins to talk about industrial
ouch ouch ouch ouch then the internet
about things in the industrial sector things of
this kind
we talk about resellers we talk about things
of this kind I am interested
especially if there is some developer
of aid because the security part
must begin to implement it
mainly they therefore ascertained
that your use of aid
is none because no one by now in
2018 can think of not having to do
with lyautey at most if he thinks he
has not made records  of not having to do
with lyautey is a passive user of
aid but lyautey is now there because in
your car it probably will
be if it is not already in your TV it is
in your telephone and very soon it will
also be in your boiler and already in the
your light meters
etcetera etcetera and in your traffic lights
under the house the cities begin to make a
lot of use of
aids as regards the
parking sensors sensors of the viron while things
of this kind victim of aid an
interesting thing the miniaturization
of these objects allows  also to do
some very unpleasant things that are legal
in quotes so it was interception
etcetera but also illegal  there if I want to
make a gps locator to put
under the car I drive now I
do it with a big deal so of an
attack under the car from a
battery and if he does not go to look
for it expressly he will never find it or
I can take a router in a  raspberry
one of these mini appliances with
wright here with battery put it in
your office on a network port
have an access to your
company network without you leaving with
you realizing it up to
what I think is perfect even
if  in reality there will be a lot of time
for if tomorrow I were to design a
backdoor to an object a trojan that
is on someone's network I would put it
in the firmware of a printer
you know how printers work
in a business environment now you usually
go to a supplier  buy a
contract make a contract it's called
cost copy where he brings you the
printers sails he attacks you don't know
anything about those printers  and for three years they
are there the easystel installation to them
the possible maintenance to them
etc.
have you ever seen if you have never seen it
search it on google there are people
running doom on the hp
laserjet color display ok then signing of the
printers is a particularly
malleable object interesting for those who want to
make these objects is a business that
is in your network over which you
have no control and that can
do funny things but it is not
what interests us today so
I gave it to you  just as a starting point alioti and
security this I could not put it
this is a twitter ad so tweeted and
refused to whom it is not known that he can no
longer give the shaun tribe the s in aid
stands for safety
where the essen aid is not there  it is
another article not from yesterday not the day before yesterday
but if I remember correctly 2013
is not films mor light internet of five
actors the internet of things but more than
anything else the internet of attack vectors
see  Let's a little bit about the technology that makes up
this whole bubble called aid
then lyautey is made up of
some new interesting stuff made
especially for the iotti but in reality at the
end of the fair there is a lot of
technology already super known so
web  Mobile 2.0 that you love already has
rpc servers and things like that there is a little
bit of technology in bad the
legacy in the sense that some of the movies
some of the operating systems that are used
in the field of hot in reality were already used
simply not you  they were calling help
we think of vx workshop we think of
operating systems of this kind up
to the point of reaching even pieces
of things that are very much in the
scada field p you know what scada are the
control systems and
data collection systems in the industrial sector ok
those  that in the factories they
make the machines, the refrigerators, the
iron poles and so on
there are many differences between I
escada but there are also some analogies
ok we will try  even here to mention a
few to tell to outline some
differences and similarities in particular
now slowly
this stuff which is called io
ti industrial internet of things begins to spread, i.e.
the use of technology helps in the industrial field
the first big difference between  lyautey
and objects in cs scada areas is that
usually the aids are engineered
time to market therefore quickly and
forgive latinism often ad
kazum while in theory in the industrial sector it
is one of the few things that they care a
lot about is the quantity and we say
it  ability of the object to withstand
wear and tear to withstand a whole
situation then security is horrifying
even in the cs field but at least
the engineering field the
quality field is usually much more taken care of
the extra one in
all it is hoped that  both because they want to
apply the production processes of the
cs scope to the objects aids to
be put in the factory network because
this  stuff here has problems the first
reason is simply a matter of
line of code
I don't know if you know if the
security jobs anyway of
software engineering probably have told you
but there is a direct relationship to the number of
lines of code  totti errors in the code
mathematics is not true statistics it
cannot be done and it cannot be ignored
let's say that every thousand lines of code
there is an error of these errors every
thousand lines of code that one out of ten
of these errors has an impact  direct
indirect on cyber security
ok so doing one plus one plus one the
more there are lines of code and the more
likely there is an error in these
lines of the code and the more
likely one of these errors is to impact
cyber security
here  there are a couple of examples
we went to the moon with less than
10 thousand lines of code a pacemaker at
about 100 thousand lines of code as well as
photoshop 1.0 when it came out  to
now photoshop the linux kernel is over 3 and a
half million lines of code
and it is interesting to
oh well 65 million lines of code
including applications let's say in
the basic package of a
distribution eni so debian a bit old ok
windows xp  and windows xp compared to
windows 31 we are talking about 43 million
lines of code compared to 2 million
lines of code and then oh well also the one
on the f35 f 22 and boeing 787 etc.
other example non-industrial
machine machine of the modern era that 50
million  of lines of code
what is the problem that thousands or
millions of lines of code together with
inexpensive objects why the typical
help object must be little expensive
think about the feedback
how much can a bracelet cost
that reveals the beats ok and that has a loop
of life a time to market that must
be very fast because if I have
teeth
we make a bracelet that detects the
beats nice idea but how many
will have had it in the world and that  moment
so once I have the idea I have to
realize it in the shortest time
possible plus a lot of this stuff uses the c
which in itself is not a problem if it is
done well but has notoriously for those who do
computer engineering will know I love it
notoriously
memory management problems that are much
more delicate than those of other
languages that are called scripting,
however, more of a higher level
so put this thing together
millions of lines of code objects
developed as quickly as possible
that must be cheap with a  time to
market very low script up what
can ever go wrong so
the problem is that there is too much
software for sure it is a problem but it
must be managed with software hungary with
a good quality of the software
the problem is not that there is  it's just too much
software the problem is that there is too much
software written forgive again
latinism to ad [ __ ] that is a lot of software
written quickly or without the ops
some software security guidelines
things like
this this is a bit for what we
said before a bit also because often
rightly in this
business model who writes an application is the
firmware of an object of this business
here often is a  new graduate or
even with a start-up of people
who have put themselves there and do this thing here
not that the new graduate cannot
write the beautiful code but one by
one let's say the experience having lived
a series of situations usually helps
to have a more defensive approach a
more defensive mentality in fact it is very
important it must go very well what
is happening now that is that
in the university there is more and more talk
about the quality of software engineering security
of things of this kind
I remember  when I didn't go
to university
so we're talking about 97 98
I didn't see one of the various
reasons the other that there is no desire to
study one but one of the m  reasons why
I did not go to university and that I
was already interested in cyber security
and on a five-year degree course
the cybersecurity program
was like three days now
luckily things
have changed a lot I think of polimi I think of
cream I also think of  venezia padova the
whole series of maybe someone from here there is
also various in groups of the various
diversities that are asserting
themselves around the world
we talk about the micro hardware that is the
long hardware of the business ni ok
then the hardware  of these in farini the
first problem that knows that these in
farini have a hardware
that is often not designed to run
a multi-user multi-use operating system
and with protections so they have a
flat memory management
ok if I can write  the memory
is not
a difference that ernst and user especially
there is a single software that runs if I
abuse some of the inputs of that
software to go for an over fl  ow
to overwrite they are directly in
memory very often they do not have those
security measures that the
server and client devices have we now use
so the impossibility of executing
code in the detachment things of this
kind
ok they do not even have the ring in the cpu
so they do not have a differentiation
between kernel and user space not all some
yes some no and even here often
especially in the smaller micro business
are everything is always written
in c so with all the problems
that this entails for the part of
memory mag ing etc. etc.
this is  the objective then the
bracelet and so on the
next step is often the controller and
so an embedded operating system
we think of the router the camera
we think of a sensor that collects here
that collects all the data of our
bracelets because maybe there is a
system of  tracking or things like that
ok very often the us operating systems
are 10 12 of these objects  15
years behind what are
the protection technologies of a
windows or linux machine or what is
current so they do not have what
are called anti
exploiting techniques are very very trivial but
I already did a talk in 2010
talking about  android security in
10 android was at the level of this
business here there was no kind
of anti exploitation technique and
things like that very often then the
techniques to attack the
communication interfaces
of the management maintenance interfaces of
these deals are very trivial
common techniques telnet compass by default or in
any case tel net http with
common vulnerabilities step by default
network communications based on traffic i
declare things of this kind and
api web based interfaces what
can ever go wrong
this we do it very quickly
this  is a comparison table
on the site of a project
called hartnett di as  i know if
anyone knows it is basically
a version of freebsd that some guys
are patching
kernel level anti exploiting and
stuff like that
this comparison table takes
arden airgest of freebsd open vs net
bsd and shows  all the various techniques
now we do not go into detail
and says who has them by default and who does
not have them
if you take linos you will probably find
only these three
I looked up to here because I am talking about linux
if this slide does not talk about linus
you know it  what is the
most used operating system in the field hot i am bad
etc.
good he is that this is an
article even a bit controversial for charity
published in the washington post so not
in the grandmother's gazette and not in a
specialized magazine in 2015 that
spoke  about the security problems
of the linux kernel
you will say but linux has been operating
very safe everyone knows it is better than
windows
no at the kernel design level
of antic sporting measures in the
linux kernel unfortunately linux is
lagging far behind all
the other commonly used operating systems
so windows mac way six
the only one on which we probably still
say better features than
and freebsd all the others that in the
general purpose operating systems
have much better functionality and mechanisms of
antec top team than
those of the linux kernel
so much so that now there is a project
called curling the kernel garden inn
project that wants to back
port  a whole series of security patches
made by the gr security project to apax
inside the kernel john harbor post with
a whole cinema behind him
we are not interested in entering but keep in
mind that the linux kernel in the
state of affairs especially as we say
compiled by default in
embedded objects and in objects say ai in
servers in workstations is
probably not kerned  and now with the
best state of the art
another very important thing to
evaluate when it comes to the internet of
things is this the internet of things to
face that is to one account and update 10
servers 20 servers one thousand servers 100 thousand
servers
one account  and update a billion
parking sensors around the
world
if each of these deals has a
small signature that has a vulnerability and
I put one in each
parking sensor of an entire parking lot for
a city for a continent for the  world
ok
the idea of having to go and do the
reasoning of those affairs is
complicated not to mention that maybe they
are not updateable there are objects
that are not updateable or are
only updateable own site
then we will have new slaves that
go around take the same restart  the
sensor attaches it usb press a
key they hang it up a good job
ok so an important thing when
evaluating an aid speech is a
good level in the meantime  security by default but
also the possibility of having a
management of
firmware updates etc. that is
substantially interesting
up to the case and this too
is not really help in the classic sense but
think about
those of you who have a cellphone anyone who
of you has one  smartphone
anyone who of you with the latest version
of the firmware
released by google on android or by
apple on his who instead has a version
that is no longer supported not if it is not
that you raise your hand obviously it was a
rhetorical question but they are raised your
hand  been that the concept is that that is
there are a lot of objects that it is no
longer convenient to update because I
am going to pull some trouble
I am vodafone I mean I have
sold a million phones that
work because I have to go and
engineer the update patch
distribute it  on a million phones
that then maybe it doesn't work and on a
million customers who get pissed
instead leave it like that  as it is until it is
the end user who is a consumer or
business who asks the manufacturer to the
supplier to give him an updated device i
will have this problem
this in the same yautja there are a
lot of objects that are abandoned
we do an interesting key study not
everyone knows
that league rabbit and the beast there in the
upper right the with the upper right you
know it is a hideous plastic rabbit
that moves its ears makes
sounds of voices is called
nabaztag ok is produced in any case in
over 100,000 copies and in the  2005 was
a considerable number for an object extra
help is precisely the paradigm of the aio
team you don't need a [ __ ] the joke is by
marco calamari this always of the slides
that my rabbit made me together
is the only thing in computer science
that in  30 years of living together
made me make a good impression with his
wife
ok because precisely morea the ears
said sweet things are programmed and
things of this gen
This was to show how much we are
esteemed and recognized in the world to a
button on the head two ears with
multicolored LED motors a ray
feed reader but above all to a firmware is a
wifi card and was controlled by a
remote server that was used to make
the  to send him commands then the
batak nose connects to a server
I connect to the server send commands
arrive at the
nasdaq this is also interesting from the point of view of
me because it is the iotti paradigm it
is almost always like this
that is it is difficult for you to have an
object  help that has commanded
directly from you often the object
help well you stay a meter from you go to the
cloud in the cloud here he gets things said he
sends things what can never
go wrong here is the protocol of the
nasdaq and interesting to do a talk
to the  flight that is dedicated tribute half an hour
we did a minimum of reversing of
white shark and looked at what it does
uses the protocol of an already mpp sedan
then choice intelli  people also for
the time that was basically encrypted
in that case behind encrypted with tls ok
but then in reality when they get
mp3 blobs to play
etc. these instead are
transferred with normal
http requests from the rabbit that  it was a gap
on the server and so on
ok so the two interesting things are
that you use the tls so it uses an
encrypted protocol for the
communication channel of the commands but it does not
verify certificates so you can do
man in the middle you can
play the  two certain films of the three
certificates he is connecting to
the xmpp server a jabra server to which he wants to
connect I intercept the
direct traffic and give
him any certificate he takes it for granted and I
do it myself baby doll simply
using the xmpp protocol or better
still  when he downloads mp3 to say
hi love i love you i
replace mp3 on the fly and
saying your rabbit has been caught pays
a bitcoin if  you want to get it back ok so it goes
well here there is the attack we are not doing it
but it is done with hard spuches with burt and with
these things here what I just
told you then encrypted command traffic
but does not verify the certificates
traffic of the contents in  clear therefore
directly interceptible use of
resources in the club so there is a whole
channel miss fund the central nas kotak server
against the
world tag jumpsuit ok
in addition it is also an orphan in the sense that the
company in the meantime has gone bankrupt has been
sold re bankrupt not  nobody cares anymore
so the nose but pays is a
discontinuous object no longer exists there
are amateur servers but it is a
classic even here in the yacht
if the business model does not work
I still fail I close the project
I find myself with 100 thousand dead rabbits
you will say oh well design of 2005 that
the studies you show us are in 2018
tell us something more interesting is
fine in 2018 better actually in 2006
that is the article of 2  018 but a
search was done in 2016 which is called
aid and security on three places and one of
these various cybersecurity news sites
this and that I think is
sponsored by kaspersky but every
friday antivirus siena 1 ok aid to
pin nerds  points in the problems
guess what they found
in 2016 these researchers looking at
many help objects have seen that ok 6
out of 10 devices have
a management interface that is vulnerable to
classic vulnerability i s injection
koman injection etc.
ok eighty per  one hundred devices
do not require the use of a password
of a certain strength complexity
so if I put foo foo as a
password in a b says the name of a
more robust password 70 percent of the
devices allow numbering
of valid users 70 for  one hundred
devices are using honey crypt network
services in 2016 70 percent so
that case of 2005 wasn't all that
isolated and po  oh well this is another
important thing especially for privacy
90 percent of devices collect dat
least one piece of personal information
via the device and sand to the cloud I
don't know if you have ever looked at the traffic that
an average android application makes or  the
average operating system sends a lot
of information about you who you are what your name is
penis length all
these things here to google servers
ok same stuff objects do help
there are also here an avalanche of cases the
most striking is that of this up  of
these dolls of these let's say
games toys for children that
had a mechanism to recognize the
voice speak take photographs everything
on a cloud server of the company
moreover it breaks through the bill and this object is not beautiful
here I do not know if you recognize
the shape I tell you the  name is called where
there was vibra tissimo that vibrates tissimo an
object to yachtique there is its
bluetooth interface its
companion cloud server eh  year found two
three vulnerabilities clubti wirth storage
password exposé from an institution
interface which is customer database
credential disclosure an authentic and
bluetooth el connection also this is
a classic
if you have devices that use bluetooth
and she who is a bluetooth version
made especially for lyautey that  uses little
energy even a little effort in
breaking it usually which is a whole
series of other things
you will say if I buy myself it vibrates very much I
would like my privacy to be a
minimum maintenance managed with the
correct measures in this case not here
but it is only to do  an example another
example if someone then wants to see
it a little faster it goes it happens more
complete go to the report site and look for
it is called I want to cry the episode
we took an epic but any
bought at the supermarket
ok brought home and we looked at that
what could be done with this epic but
above all what could be done with
this epic but without the knowledge of  a person
who installs val ip cam in his apartment in his
apartment you know what an ip camera is
a webcam that has the
tcp ip stack directly and talks to the internet
ok this is the very difficult and very
complex exploits necessary to
enter once you know the  'public ip address
that you find with sodano so
on in
the ip cam administration interface instead of doing get flash
login fi get login and he tells you the
password and the user the password set
at that moment this is a
2004 vulnerability published by
luigi  ariemma and that to date has not
been resolved that is this signature is not
from 2004 and 2015
from 16 2017 doing a further research
a French man is called pierre
something now I do not remember the name
pierre kim he too had taken a bit
let's say  various webcams and found that
basically there must be more or
less a single film producer of
this webcam that was sold to 800
million different producers
ta  nt is that according to him there were even
1250 camera models so 1250
different models that have the same firmware at the end of the fair
which must
also be a firmware made burnell
forget in the sense that it is released
there are no updates etc. that is
every time they stop
maybe make some changes throw
something in but then bye thanks goodbye
and in this film there was an avalanche and a
half of vulnerability ok for example
another that had seen others in the third
minute to the second minute the web sharka is
that this application beyond  to
do as webcams very often do, i.e.
use the universal plug
and play protocol to ask your router
to be visible on the internet which is one
of the worst bestialities in history,
i.e. you put an object on
that universal plug and play on your
internal network  protected by your nat and
this object tells your router and
hello hide enabled then
disable the a  iverse plug'n'play
tomorrow if you have it enabled
I would like to be visible from the internet the
router says but of course which port you need
trakl 81 go calmly then from that
moment on on the public ip of
your router on port 81 and
yours is accessible  webcam then
that vulnerability above for
those who do not want to use
the public address of the cam directly there is also
a beautiful application in claudio
I had never seen such a crap
with ten minutes of white shark this
application in the cloud practically in
capsule i  naked p then send the
beaver packet to a server on
amazon on the vs
ok of the http traffic then it makes some
pc packets it makes http requests
and throws her and the answers so
obviously all clear not only in
this traffic it also puts us  the
serial of the camera which is easily
predictable so it is not that zk
underscore 914 his is different no if
real the camera is 000 1000 2000 3 if it
joins this  I am passing by default to man of the
application in the cloud a request by
saying only the owner of the camera
serial 1 with the default password
you show me my room if you take the
default step you
see the room of any other
then dozens of projects  of
different products all derived from the same
signature universal plug and play
default credentials so much so that the
famous botnet mirai also used the
credentials of this of this room
here an out by pass on the
login interface known since 2004 traffic in the cloud is
absolutely no chance to
have the slightest update of
the camera signature there is the only
possibility is to buy a
later model hoping that they have fixed
the vulnerabilities you have this is
one of the 500,000 articles per week
that come out on webcams open on the
internet c  'is a lot of broletto mouth sites
so this genre that show me
webcams at home these are
the most shocking because there is  d'ippo
control room of a nuclear power plant
children and things like this
let's close that we are already
behind the times
then this is the ohio ti acta
surface arias so it definitely has the
resource we say that if you want to develop
help and if you are developers  of help
you have to go to know how your
pockets are to know what are all the
attack vectors the whole
attack surface that when you develop a
signature in an application etc. you
have to go to advice
then to properly manage this
wireless stuff in stand for internet
then  when you make an object you help
this object remember that it will end up on the
internet and the internet is an
extremely violent eco system extremely
attack where you have 4 billion people
who do not even know who they are who
may have
zero day vulnerabilities or simply be able to fly
may want to enter yours
more or less targeted object is not that
they have it with you eldo cojo co  jo that is they
sweep the whole door 81 ok
and if he finds a webcam as the
vulnerability there he entered it then I go to see what
security by design is privacy by design
this fortunately you have it requires it
in theory also the gp was therefore  at least
this at least as a term should
be quite known and then secur
software developer lifecycle that is to
think from the perspective of
software development with adding security
at the beginning I never at the end
as often as we do then I recommend using
platforms framework protocols and
standards  known and
safe usually especially in the
cryptographic field but more generally in
computer security
whoever invents hot water often
makes it cold ok
that is if you decide that you make
your own notification system
that no one knows how it works you are most
likely doing
ok more [ __ ] then go once you have
the product more or less working to
do a security review both from
the  to design is really technical
so a penetration test what is it
from someone who breaks that stuff
there at breakfast which is
certainly what makes sense I
still put in the slides that
I imagine will be downloadable from the eastern site
two or three links it has  it makes sense to read
because even there if I go to look
for security help on google I find 100 thousand
links
let's say that these are the most
interesting at least those in my opinion if
you have never looked at it go and
see shodan shodan
an internet search engine  of
things and you can search by banner per
door for things like this and
you will find a billion webcams a
billion industrial equipment
etc.
another object another site that I
really like elphinston collector what is
fim with collector is an engine of
research that searches only in the titles in the
extras of the cybersecurity conferences
keep in mind that for how
cybersecurity works now the  research
if I discover an
interesting vulnerability on gb on pippo tronic on
what it is most likely or I
do it because I do it for someone who
pays me very well I keep it a secret
public role because I want to
advertise I want to let myself be known
etc. so if you have tomorrow  to do with
a protocol with an object that you do not
know go there and look for the name of
that object siemens simatic what you
have probably found all the
public knowledge about what it is I did it
a security then the and the techniques
of attack towards  that kind of deal
we only overshot by six minutes
so at this point I would ask
you if you have any questions or if you have any
answers otherwise thank you and he went back
to putting on some music
[Applause]