thanks for coming today what we will
talk about and the [ __ ] i will explain
shortly what it is and why there
are actually so many myths about this thing here who
are actually right speakers is not
important I do security stuff I am
interested yes I do penetration test
to eat
this is about the same as what I
will show you today today I will talk to you about what
is meant by fuzzing what is a phase
and I will show you some theories and one
thing I really care about which is siri
versus practice so that  what you
think it is is what in reality if you
try to do it you will discover I will
show you a couple of fasslers that are
interesting to us and because in my
view but not only
the right file is the one you sign
up for yourself then I will show you  like how to
get a lot of software that you can
grow out of the box what good is
fuzzing well if you say you fuzz
you are already in the hacker elite cause
oh god you are group phase
you can between  nquillamente go on twitter to
be cool and very briefly you will
receive an avalanche of likes what
is meant by phase for fuzzing sorry
then these are the definition you
find on wikipedia and on another site
that is enough for you to search for
description fuzzing I found it nodal
first results is very nice because it
tries to explain the second the second
nice explanation because it says it is a
spray thing technique related to
sending random characters as input
the request for an application no then
what is meant by actually doing
we can summarize the  fuzzing how to
send create something that puts
our target in an unexpected situation
ok it is not necessarily
something random and it did not
even say that it
is a simple input to create this
condition
you can let's say we can divide those in phase
into two large categories  software
you see on the left from left and
those hardware you see on the right
today we will talk about s  Only the software part
because on the hardware side it is a whole
world unto itself for those of you on twitter I
advise you to follow this person here
who actually deals
exclusively with hardware security
also does courses and is a person who
really has the  hair on the stomach is not
mine what's the name of my field so
we stay on the software part in reality
unfortunately I will show you a
screenshot in reality the animation was
quite simple those of you who
remember the crash or rather the ex plate on
but  this in version 10 12
something was enough to press a few times enter
on a mask that asked you for the
root password and you actually
boasted the root
if you have not accepted a password on the
system jokingly a person on
twitter had prepared this woodpecker
that went back and forth  on the
keyboard and says this is my phaser
for marco is actually so he
could get broken when talking about
phase actually fa d  the software actually
many are ready you do not need to
invent hot water
Fri I have brought here four examples
what you see on the left is
sulley is one of the most famous if you are
also looking for books on fuzzing
you will certainly see it mentioned is a  bazaar in
python that some very
nice peculiarities unfortunately is no longer maintained a
person so decided to carry
on making a forte of this project is to
create buffaz those of you who do not watch
cartoons both salle yc ebook are
two characters of monsters co ev this
little girl is the only one who actually manages to
scare this monster
the third is pete faser pitch faser is a
commercial faser while buffon and salt
are open source it is commercial and
I can't tell you more in the sense that
before contacting the company  I tried
to look around a little bit how much it
cost and we tell you for the
fragmentary information that I found we speak from
30k up to the year of license for which
I stopped  I said but you know that there is
sti [ __ ] the last one I mention is in fact that it
is a very well known phase has found
I think about fifty vulnerabilities
in different soft sorry vulnerabilities in
about fifty different software and it is
definitely a tool from which
take a cue to look at but also
how to learn how to use when it
comes to phase the software we can
go and divide the fire into various
components
leaving aside the part of the core that
if you want the one that makes
everything work regardless of how it is written
the fire the part that actually
interests us is how I prepare what they
want to submit to my target and
how this something is then
used by the phaser to create
something unexpected ok so
a rule that describes me for example a
protocol and how  within this
description various fields will be
initialized with values that decide the
phase is very nice to grow the software
is absolutely  It is useless to grow it if we
do not know how we did it break
ifad normally try to do as
soon as possible to give me a result for
which they find thousands of interactions
per second so if you let it run
maybe a couple of days then went to
double check the phaser you find that it is
approved  175,000 different interactions
your crusader software but you don't know
which of the 175,000 was actually
due to the crash you can try it hand
you can relaunch it externally to look
at the penultimate one you lose a
day and a half of life watching it
so normally the fans also allow you
to monitor what is
happening to understand who created what
you also have an interface someone
allows you to have a web interface
someone else a little more crude and
allows you to use an in-phase
command line interface it depends
is not is not  that it is nothing particular
the important thing is that it gives you the
information you have b  isogno
let's say that the most important part
in my opinion of a phase that
you really need to try to understand
beyond how it works is how I can
describe the interaction with my
target and how within this
description of this scheme if you want
the phaser  it will initialize the various
fields and approve the various interactions
what I bring you is an example of a
description of a protocol with
buffon I apologize for the fact that I
had to blur some parts but
this is a project that I am carrying
out on  a software of which in via
tion I have some details that at the moment
I cannot to which I cannot
disclose the idea anyway you have is
enough
that you can understand enough holy
cession of the fields that are defined
as static so the phase will take
them as they are  if they are
limiter fields there are fields for example
being string the first iteration the
phaser will send to what you put
in from the second in
teration onwards buffaz will start generating input
see how it behaves it will teach
numbers it will insert letters it will
insert as they say very very
long inputs inputs with very
particular characters and in all this continues to
monitor what happens on
the other side  that is, if I receive a response in
this case 22 requests have been defined here
through a direct protocol
this is an application protocol
described based on http and I do
nothing but go to define various fields
of the payload races and go
submit them what buffaz does is
take note  this scheme is going
to generate some input the part let's say
that 111 bites is missing from the transmission to
the authorization part you see below
is the part of the payload generated by buffon
and sent muffat as forbidden it
also goes to monitor what the
reply he sends  an input expects
an answer formed by a
way seamstress says the answer is correct
perf  so the target is still on I go with
the next iteration if the target does not
respond you can decide how to
operate
stop the phaser restart to you the target
try to continually submit
because maybe it is just a matter of
time out and you have network problems there
there are various reactions that you can
choose as I told you this is more or
less how a phaser works in the theory
I anticipated you create the input
below you put it in the theory in practice
if you go to see 95 percent
of the agents who are on the net  of how to
use how to do it sorry fuzzing the
answer you find is this then
this is an example if you want a little
pulled by the hair of what can
be fuzzing in this case here is
clearly an example but it makes you
understand what we are  talking so many
times we talk about income butorova [ __ ] and
I hope that some thing grows you have
luck every now and then it
actually works it works well for example
like you  I anticipated cup before it has
problems if it is not written
correctly it
may be that you try to lose
thousands of inputs first after you go to
have memory management problems
the application grows and you if you
actually send [ __ ] [ __ ] you are
lucky and you get  actually a
crash in the theory to be a hacker
a ok I take python I make it generate
a hair of the long I send it and it is that
something that will leave this done I
write to myself the former light I become famous to us it
does not work so
first thing when it comes to  paddling
if you take a phase how can it be
buffaz american phases love what you
want
normally you have some
default options example how to generate some input
this is wanted because we wanted to have
a default option that works
because so started using
those default options  and understand if
everything stands and then in theory
you should start doing all
your customization n  In reality
this is done very little so you
take the puzzle you throw it as
it is is that left alone a hacker did not
leave the software is not vulnerable
the other the other problem is the
standard behavior of
the dl phase the  phaser as we will see also
afterwards it has a predictable behavior
because because if you want to launch
the phaser twice you put that in the summer the father
finds a crash you re-launch it you want to
have exactly the same iterations
to have the crash again check it you
can do all your tuning and
yours your analysis what
does this mean that if I launch the phaser
I get one with the default options
I get interactions if he loops
the phaser with the same options will get
exactly the same interactions
then there are preconditions for
reaching parts  of example code we
imagine that you we want to
interact with a web service this
web service is authenticated if I send
random stuff is mo  It is very likely that I am
only trying the first iteration,
that is probably the authentication but
I am not trying what is after
the authentication so it may be that
to reach some parts of code and
therefore have a broad and cod cover I have
to  respect the conditions and
must respect what is
called the end state machine therefore
the set of various states in which the
software must be found to reach
that particular point of code
this thing here also works with
protocols you can make a software
but in reality  you can also make a
protocol
if you find a problem in a
software you report it the software is
probably and hopefully broken and
everything goes back as before
if you find a problem in the
finished state description of a
protocol are dicks because all the
implementations of that  protocol them
will have to be readjusted that
protocol will have to be is spent and
corrected this thing here has an impa  tto
huge because there will be several
implementations of this protocol
if you want to have something that has
a very long persistence because
maybe you sell them zero day go to
work on the protocols and much more
time consuming but it
can't give much more duration than
you  went to produce and therefore
probably the price that will be
paid will be much higher the other thing
is that typically unfortunately those who care
about computer security the first thing
they do is take the piss and the
developers can stay there a few times
from the other times  other times the
developers know a lot more than
we do because because we simply
have interactions with 250 million
different technologies
the developer usually uses a
little less and becomes much more
vertical so maybe the framework
knows me much better than us that
language  he knows him
much better than us so he is much
better than us  calm down a moment
let's try to stay relaxed indeed
many times you can take advantage of the
developers and let you teach something
that maybe penetration test after which
the other thing that
normally developers are very
good at using tools
create for example bill system that can also be useful  we
dream they know how to configure the
development machines in a fairly
correct way i phase ii are also used
if they can take them too from ge
tabs they can be configured they can
dance if we go to
use the fas on products in products
meant both  known open source commercials it
is likely that we do not find
anything because because maybe they have already
been used against that target
the other thing is that each phase of the
advantages and disadvantages for which for
example there are some American phases,
for example, the op is super cool  for local programs
that is able to generate vi of the
input simulate the user simulate the
files that come  or read while for example
buffaz is used for fuzzing
on network protocols you can
probably never have done it probably
you can use it to attack
something local then generate
files and see the interaction of the target
but it is specialized on the part  network
because for example buffaz allows you to
describe the protocols has not
a super cool way a bit rigid but
super cool so even there choosing the
right phaser for what you
want to get can be an idea to
take a as they say in one phase
relaunch it  against some
target in some target it works
well unfortunately it is not always said that
you can manage the crash I
mean take a router ok it
started throwing in 9 you see that
at a certain point that input
actually makes the perfect web server grow
oil crash ready to write them xplor no
to touch an exploit they want a lot
of other ancillary things that maybe later
we will see
and  for example maybe in a home router
you have to have access in some
way to be able to understand
what is happening before writing
the ex plate it is not said that this is
always something that can be done in half an hour it
may be that maybe  that device
ii is particularly badass or
particularly poorly documented for which
you must also pour all the pd to
understand what is inside you
do not find ports maybe the
az port that the serial port on a
disable so you have to find a
way to interact anyway not  you can
disassemble the flash because it soldered in
smd so I challenge you to chip off
and do it heated somewhere else
and interact there are all
preconditions it
may be that you are making
systems perhaps to do bug hunting
on platforms that  they pay you but it is not
said that you have access to those systems
to see what is happening
so maybe this service grows
maybe from  The other part is pissed off
as well and you have no way of understanding
why it is
growing.The other thing is that maybe you
also have the device
maybe it even managed to make it
grow
but from there to understand what
happened and understand how  exploit it at the end
because because the
operating systems are no longer what
they used to be
we say that if you want if you start with
the windows precondition it makes [ __ ] if
I write the ex plate immediately
if you want to write it for windows
10 because it is really something that
once it worked well now much
less
that is, it is much more difficult here is
what I mean will be a beautiful report
that I left you here let's say
only the initial cover I invite you
to read it is a research that has been
done on the zero day market how much
they cost and how much it costs to develop them
who does it
how long they last etc. etc. the
interesting part for us is that currently
it takes usually 637 days
to develop  an exploit appears we are talking about
people who do this thing here for
work, that is, it is not that they pick up and
wake up in the morning and disney whoever
writes to me explore it takes 37 man days
to develop an export means that
it takes more or less two months  and a half
of continuous time because
obviously you also have other things in between
it is not a foregone conclusion indeed some
have requested as you see much
much more
as I told you the basic problem is
that if we always submit
the same interactions that if input that
is  series of interactions that is to
visit in a certain sequence of the
states of the protocol of the target that
we go to and with which we are going to
interact
if you explain to me where the next input ex is
or in any case the anec specter condition
is not there is not there  because why all
predictable stuff and how hackers
crackers do it how bug hunters
do it developers
do it what I recommend you do from my point
of view what I recommend is
parts  you with a target of you what do I know I give you
an example about me I like the
stuff I say absolutely so as a
target
I chose something that was on the
network better if something that has a
great impact therefore tends
to be exposed  on the internet the stuff
that showed hatching and super cool go on
chance
for example a bit of protocols see
which one has some million of
devices exposed on that protocol and
decide that those are your target
after which I advise you to
start analyzing how it is managed  the input
from these software that implement for
example that specific protocol weight
once you have done it keep
doing it get rfc get some
demos that are around maybe of
clients that interact with the service
and set was etcetera and try to understand
once  that you understand this it is
very likely that you already have
a feeling of what can be done
then develop your bone phaser  to
subscribe something that allows you
to try what you think
might work in my opinion the
most interesting thing to do
try a moment to tighten so we
recover some time and select
the target I will show you now a 4
place where you can actually find
tens of thousands of
vulnerable software used by tens of
millions of devices on sports the
gitav clubs old google code that has
been discontinued we like the
tale of open
source so much it is possible to do the queue
review it is possible  do the code
review surely someone will have done it
if surely someone has done it the
open source code is safer I
am not convinced because if I
have to attack
what I want to do is to have the
return on investment exactly like
a company  normal
on the one hand I have to take some
closed code and go to a repository on
the other hand I have to make a clone kit of a
repository
in addition having all the source code
the symbolization of crashes
debugging what is growing is
much more convenient but much more
if you go and have a little patience
go and see yourselves maybe not the best
known maybe you don't start from open
ssl which could be a little
complex but from the software that are
integrated into commercial solutions
you will see that you will find a lot of
repositories corday disclaimer type
a penetration test has never been done on
this software so it is advisable
not to use it in production what
i'm doing it i'm doing it on a
software that is integrated into something
like 10 million devices to this
exact disclaimer
in reality i found it on a serp a
subset of these devices on a
version not the latest which is exactly
the same disclaimer the last one
still has the disclaimer
in reality because because no one has
time it is not paid that is and requires
a sac  co of effort to do a code review
of a software that is complex
maybe there is someone who puts himself there and
that good will but to take this for
granted is very dangerous unfortunately
those who develop commercial solutions many
times need to have so many
brands must  going out must put
something out for the customers
so open source software is
fine because free that is, it is
associated with free open source they
take shape and throw it into
devices the more or less it will be safe
and I put it on the market this is not true it
is a  wrong precondition and
actually implies that there are tens of
thousands of software worse than worse
yesterday's free when you compile
evidence must install these libraries
goes towards we put those in
there too I invite you to spend some time
trying to run more without
not even of hazzard you start to
believe more
if it does not crash then try to start
making them but they already begin to do  rla rushing
view you will see that you have found a lot of
interesting things
this is how much I hope I have not
bored you too much if you have this
question maybe I will wait for you outside
so there is the next person that we are
united 5 delay from the two minutes of questions
then there are hi  In the meantime, I would like to
clean up the terminology a bit, that is, there
is no commercial software
open source software there is proprietary software
and free software and it is not true that
open source software is free and
many large projects are
paid and made by people attributed
like the others  absolutely
absolutely I apologize for being
a bit crude in the last part what
I said what I said is really
open source is associated with
free and he was wrong he is absolutely
right
among other things the time to market that go
is the software  open source that
proprietary software with the difference that
open source and the claim earlall aic
in the others no but i des  k lamer there can
also be all those others and
we will never know it
is in fact absolutely absolutely
this in practice impacts what
I am talking about
in reality unfortunately no it is something that I
am sorry that never regrets a lot
because in reality there are a lot  of
superb projects that companies
companies that invoice millions
could support with very little and
they do not and they make millions on
what is the commitment of people who
may have put themselves there have written
super cool software but what I mean
is there  even the hour has no finite resources
has no way of seeming in common parts that
in your thor I did the glorification
of security baio fioriti
no absolutely
absolutely no indeed my sorry
that this concept has passed
what I meant is something else that is  if
the security
does not work it is a fact
that it is open source does not guarantee me that
this thing is guaranteed because unfortunately it
is here  it is but it has been said many times
before starting to get into it and
it has always or almost always been
passed on to me the concept is open source I can
read the code so someone
has surely read it and verified it
therefore it is safer this is according to
me a very wrong precondition is
in fact they say it is not true and it is a
pity because in my opinion it is something that
passes and I will say more that is I find
resistance many times from open
source projects that maybe 61 almost attacked by
this thing in attack is just an
observation
all here also because then we know
better that is, it knows better than me that
open source software on a problem it
has and fragmentation if there are 50
projects that do the same thing so that
the resources for each project
are obviously less and it is not possible  to do
even with review you are never beautiful when
there are more ways to do things
absolutely absolutely I just say
that the downside is
fragmentation then  few resources to
test different software trying
to achieve the same goal
[Applause]