this is a remake of a lecture
i had always done here in 2016 bland
of a project i have been working
on for some time
is something i started at
university as a master's thesis
abstract of an
encryption security transport protocol.  authentication
is a work in progress still the work
that needs to be done behind it if still a
lot but before judo since
this is an impromptu conference
let's see if I still remember what
this whole presentation includes
then what it is
like I told you before  it is a
transport protocol
we are trying to take
everything you feel cp
or even more and authentications such as
kerberos for example and put them in a
single package see what comes out
is what the result of all this is
a very compact tool thought
to focus on safety it is
extremely efficient
the problem is a bit that we are going to
break what is the classic pilla
of pr  otocolli iso osi you are
used to then classic
transport protocol layer of sessions etc.
maybe we will see better later in these
are the topics that we will
mainly deal with the focus of this
project is to completely detach
the authentication of the application
from the management of its security
as you can see all in all after
all the authentication done in
a completely federated way the first
question is we seriously
need a transport protocol in we have
several batteries we have less
so let
's try to reconnect density
I was hoping to have more battery but here it is
old  it doesn't last long
since you can
continue the topic the
transport protocol commonly used you all
know a little bit there is the tc pilot of
p
how many of you know a little
more advanced protocols such as sctp or ccp ever
heard are are pro toga we are
speaking of transport protocol,
think about those born in 2001 for themselves
ctp 2006 for  of ccp have not taken
much hold because being protocols
that are above ip they have the problem of
[Music]
a problem of going through
firewalls do it generally they make you
pass just what ethics most dp
notice what they can the rest they
throw it away and  enough but
sctp a very
interesting protocol because introduced the
concept introduced two things the concept
of multi streaming that is being able to
have multiple data streams within
the same connection is power and the
power to decide whether that
rai hubble transmission stream then tcp style
or completely  areas liable therefore
dp style and not to the mechanisms of 10 k behind
to recover packets valeee if you have
followed
I imagine the evolutions of other
protocols plus 9 minimum week type the
team are protocols that try
to bring minimal fan a focus more
on security here than instead  others
focus on more performance on
trying to put tcp and tls together in
one  only package they don't make a
completely new protocol we are
on ud ip to be able to pass
through firewalls much easier and and
it is used a lot now about the
last figure 60 percent of
traffic to youtube
is now all about which however  a
constantly evolving protocol also
this quite new managed
completely by google
as encryption we have classic tls here
which actually takes up minimal tls it is
made by dj b if you know very famous
cryptographer a focus purely on
key encryption the ittic much
more static not  it is flexible so with
we can change it is not like pls where you
can change ciphers etc. but it is
very interesting if you want to
take a look
and then as authentication we have the
classic kerberos which has
clock synchronization problems
as you know in kerberos if one self two
computers  users try cassin
kerberos hand schedules that are more than
five minutes fuo  re one of
the other the authentication does not work or out
unfortunately for him I like very little and
speed that by now as Italians you will know
quite well has followed a bit of
the evolution from the beginning so of
various the various alternatives and we have
however  already done that we have to choose
between the many alternatives it is a problem
for developers there is
not a single protocol that brings us
all together and put us on tlc limits
to having for example connections all
all liable therefore all style
advances  we can not use anything
ubp style and if we want to have something a
little flexible we have a stack of 56
different protocols plus all the
problems that it carries with it or out
where you never try to make
your own implementation because you
will be wrong wrong google
wrong facebook  wrong it seems that
twitter
the implementation brought with them
several security bugs not
indifferent at the beginning ok then
we talked before the canvas  some
protocols yes by josie here you have more or
less the classic stack of protocols that
caused in web applications and with the
temptation o out tls for encryption
that
you actually see that it has no
direct consideration on the stack and you don't know
where it should be  secure
could be at level between 45 a little
earlier even on the level of similar bisex picks
but problem is that following
this
according to this classic stack you see that
there are several protocols that
implement for example the
session level we have a tct session
an obsession  tls a session for the
cookies of our web applications a
session but out in the middle we have http
that does not usually manage
everything in your application a nice
mess
gets worse as we said before if you want to
start using multi stack to
manage
I don't know audio video stream  stuff
like that for multicast you have to do them
all love security including there is
absolutely nothing  you who saved you
we were talking about biotech speed
here is what it does here then ok
[Music]
the problem is always in the layer here that
mini minds try to put together
tcp and tls
or auto is always above
all the applications you find today
anyway  they do not use the
authentication that you can find
in tls because problematic to manage
you have to pass it to me from prs august
web browser to big excuse web server that afterwards
has to pass to the application there are a
few steps in the means they are not in the
middle nobody uses it
the  main problem of these
indications is that they are not
even federated or out that when you see the
facebook login button then
google always all out is a
semi-federated system in the sense that as
long as my site trusts
google
I have to explicitly put  dl
google login button, however, since
the car works with web pages
the authentication on a certain web page
each implementer a page
different web which among other things
slightly different parameters and therefore either you have
the implementation for google for
facebook for twitter or you don't
have an authentication so a
semi-federated system because we have
different federations google facebook
etc. but they don't talk to each other  of them
as we described before the layering
c
leads us to manage security at
the application level so
we took a problem that we had to
manage at the tls level we
postponed it each time a higher layer and
so it's all stuff that has to manage  the
programmer programmer in reality if he
had a tool that could
manage authentication and security for
his own he would use as they try to do now
with libraries for however high end is
again everything I have out speed etc.
is managed via http that a
efficiency level is crap
we have seven eight hour direct series
in the middle we go through two divers web browsers
i as we see for use shaun below
this is taken directly from the
speed specifications
i am not explaining it was a lot but you can
imagine how problematic it is also
having to manage the radars and why this
means that your applications
actually every time you use or car they
need  of an internal web server then
other things that can go wrong
the other added complexity is moved
to the application level so to
solve everything and what
we take the federation at the kerberos level we
perform the 44 roles that
can be had
we have the application the manager who
the let's say the
client-side kerberos server that you use for example active
directory that simply
an application that will manage you after
your your authentications
forced then security
the authentication server that the
counterpart from the server side the service
that can be web pages or
anything else
this leads to a sharp separation
of goals  therefore we can
make sure that applications and
services do not have access to each
other have no excuse we
do not have access to
the user authentication database to tokens
that instead with out you have to manage all of
you who have to save the token of
that user if  a replay itself
there are libraries that give you
a hand a little but up to a certain point
by dryly separating these two things
we will practically have a kind of
blackbird kerberos tls that will manage the claim
manager the authentic shaun server and
your application apart from loading
that library will not have to see
absolutely anything because even that
library itself will not have access to
authentication information with respect
to kerberos the novelties are that it
uses tokens as like kerberos so
after a first use of your
passwords to verify that it is
really you you pass  finger use that
generated instantly that can
be tracked and erased
instantly that can track you
are built in such a way that they track you
not only not only
the application but also the device on which
it was indicating so I don't know for
example lose to the mobile phone
unlock everything for the mobile phone
until you have found it again or
definitively  delete the token you have
seen upset and fine because there is a
management of the dl also touches on the
server side that allows you to do this the
services are in turn identified
by tokens
and this allows us to
completely detach from the identification
of the service  as simply dupla of
protocol ports tiple web server gp80
tcp 443 if I want to use sl it is a
very nice thing that allows us to do is
that it allows us to put any
service on any set of ports or or
other that allows us to get out
of the dl problem  manage the two
problems, one of virtual hosting and
two that of the fact that ports
less than 1024 are
therefore privileged ports  theoretically only
broken pay it so we are
even moving all the management of the
applications completely in the user
themselves in short, it is one more thing always
for security as before it is one we are
talking about federated authentication and
therefore you could have your
authentication server for the domain you
prefer  you, however, the federation is
built within
the protocol so I my
authentication server, ideally google
would have them able to speak
automatically whatever mine
is, we don't need to agree with
additional trusts for
I don't know with  how it happens, however, that
the button for google for facebook must have,
however, you as a client
will have to rely on your
authentication server so again you can
study your normal domain up
to a certain point in reality because for
how it is built all that unfortunately
we do not have  time to go into very
good details but  if your
authentication server is also punctured
the attacker will not be able to impersonate them
within the services you live on
authenticate which instead on auto
still happens yes obu with
application server or out
I have control of all of all
users  that the workflow is a bit
classic as we said before we have the
separation 3 4 roles the application
that connects to the train manager simply tells him
I want to authenticate here
it also tells him with which user the club
manager will then ask the user with which
account  wants to authenticate in that
service will manage all the
authentication part and then it will
simply be said service that there is a
new user connected and this generates the
encryption keys that will be
sent back all the application
of new realities there is security in the
means by which the authentication server,
despite making a for
words of the authentication key,
cannot encrypt it, cannot use  le to
decrypt the data in transit etc.
which also leads us to have
connections after authenticated
that are without additional round trips
for data etc.
we talked about the efficiency of
the packet management
here you can see the structure in
byte of what there  it is used for a
tcp connection with tls and we are still
ignoring the whole part in http because
now everything must run in http and they
are with you see several huts in reality
going into details there are again
several repeated parts that
would not serve to infer the only one instead
what in clear is the
connection of a header for encryption
because you need a minimum to be able to
decrypt the single packet in
its own right and then everything else encrypted you can
see absolutely nothing
while even with tls you see what
as version
also type that identifies the
date type and other data type and other
small things may be in the clear but
the worst part is that the whole  apart from
tcp and clear so I could
reset the connections of those who want
this on vacation in reality it is not
possible again as we have seen the
part in green
sure the repeatable part of paddling
so I can have more streams of
connections in even a  single
packet that can decide in each
streams do it three lai a bollore liable
whether to enable
retransmission mechanisms for packet loss
ordered or not if I want to give you
ordered or not in reception
of the application if they want it to data
stream data g
that is if I want it with  a stream of
data in a structured tcp style and after
you manage there it starts at the end of
the messages or if su
directly manages the protocol at the beginning and
at the end the nice thing about having the
dry connection lines so generated
for not having  the classic the classic on
sport destination port we have
free things like the multi homing roaming
station
so simply I cell phone put
with wifi networks after a while I move to
another wifi network the connection auction
on regardless of
who manages the two wifi networks to
new things that we can also manage the
multicast we need a bit again to
go back to the public key encryption
private we cannot purely stay on
the symmetrical one because we need
to identify who is sending the packet
otherwise there are some
possible ailments in the middle but this would be
the first protocol that manages to give
multicast reliable because it uses another
error decoration library where
substantially  I send but of my data
I send an additional data stream to
allow me to recover any
number of lost packets I just have to
decide how much more stuff to send I
add another stream
juni cast for why single clients
can ask from traditional
this way I have something that is a lot
similar to a multicast quite relae
ball going on like like yes  love
careful the other speaker has arrived
ok then I will try to detail very
very short
we talked about authentication and the
main problem of authentication
is always where the trust comes from ssl
certificate certificates need
a certificate authority we have seen
the mess that is  possible with in the
past years with all the
certificate authorities all certificates have also
been generated also for
fraudulently even for entities such as
google.com
so I decided to throw away all the
management of certificates and to move
the authentication directly to dns  sec
that the secure version of bns where
we simply put
our public churches in a structured way
directly there we have control
of the business and this allows
us to manage the renewal of the keys
of anything else
directly from us we have no other
intermediaries in the middle  not to mention
all the complexity in parsing 5  09
I just tell you that in minutes and reads I think there
are 35,000 lines of code just for
parsing the certificates let's skip pollein
sheikh just say that there
are several different types of reeds available
that depending on how efficient
we want to have it for obviously more
efficient there  we have it there is at least
entangled we have and the more we risk
something in security even if we
generally speak only of god it is
if possible also this we can
substantially skip there are
seven additional secrets between client and
authentication server and
final services for which like  I said before even
if the authentic shaun server pierces
me and I am forced to regenerate
these certificates
the attacker cannot use the hotel the
data of the authentic shaun server
mathematically precisely to impersonate
my users from the various services where there
are  a house where there are many
cati and in fact once I regenerate
these certificates I am automatically
declaring  r by all users this not
these certificates these secrets
shared automatically declaring
all users that my server
has been pierced and that they check
before re-authentication
subsequent will ensure final novelty
we have an authentication graph where
we can define in a structured way
a hierarchy of  possible of the
possible permissions that a con
klein can have these permissions
are forcing the
authentication server side on the
frank manager side so I can say for
example my mobile phone will only have
read-only authorization for this service and then
maybe from a mobile phone
further limit if there was something under
read-only for that service is
again this is completely separate
from the application management so
the application is with one type of
authorization and you keep that
then unless you have bugs or something else inside
the  service e  the application is
limited by the protocol to that level
of authorization this final data
the user must never use his
username and
password apart from the very first time onwards false
tap of the clan manager because then everything
else is managed tokens and that's it  give
the service an authentication confirmation
so my web application
for example does not see authentication
data authentication does not even see the
client side counterpart and a new one
we have limits from the protocol
managed by separate applications so
it is not the single application that is
strive to stay jean ping on
reading as he says no we said before
simply it was the project
we have error correction libraries
now unstable
ferrer instead as a protocol
still quite in development
I think I have gone a little further in
time so if you have some
quick questions if  no, let's immediately leave
the floor to the next speaker for
blender
if you want silo as axis to talk out
as much as you want
to agree then we will get back
to agreement and we will see if it can be put back
or maybe even in the lineup so
they also see other
thanks for your attention but their
people
[Applause]