now i'm very very excited to introduce
our next
speaker this particular talk is one i am
specifically super hyped about because
it's a topic that i love
and a fantastic speaker and adi is such
a nice speaker as well she's a very very
nice person i just met her backstage
and we're really really happy to have
adi here because uh adi
has never presented at b sites tel aviv
before so we're super excited
to have a d on the stage let me tell you
a little bit about the talk
and about a d okay so this talk is now
you tcp
me now you don't and that is such a
clever statement adi i'm gonna get a
t-shirt made
that says that because it's so so on
point
so now you tcp me now you don't this is
going to be about the
internet scanning tools like showdown
and other tools
i have known to feature showdown in many
of my talks
i use it for my security testing many
security pros
use tools like showdown and other
internet scanning services so this is
what we're gonna
hear all about right now and adi ben
israel our next speaker
she is a really really fantastic nice
human being
and she loves the internet and she says
that she has loved the internet
even before she found ways to connect
into people's routers
so that's pretty cool adi and actually
she also likes to dance
and play the trombone but not at the
same time
although that is an incredible talent a
deep probably if you would play the
trombone and dance at the same time you
would have
uh you will be able to join the circus
uh but
thankfully for us adi is here with us as
a security professional
as an internet internet
astronaut if you were looking for
interesting things to find in the
internet world
and she's really passionate about
sharing her knowledge so please help me
in giving a
super warm welcome to adi ben israel
welcome adi thank you so much so happy
to have you with us
there you go adi hi i'm adi
and this is now you tcp me now you don't
the strengths and weaknesses of various
internet scanning services so
a little about me i am a former
a recovering internet security
researcher i did this for
five years and about half a year ago i
decided that i want to learn how to
program a bit
so i am now work at a storage company
called weka where i program in the very
common language
called d but i still keep up with
uh with the internet and networking by
uh
by being the one who installs all the
routers at every place i live
before we start two things the first
thing that's very important is that
everything i
talk is a free offering from all the
services i will talk about
i will not talk about any enterprise
options or anything that costs more than
giving up some personal details and
second there will be a quiz
on this so please join the v sites
workspace and
the 20 talk or 20 lobby channel to see
the to see to be part of the quiz
so first of all why scan the internet
well if you're asking this you're
probably looking at the wrong conference
we scan because we can the internet is a
safari
and scanning is just one of the many
ways to understand it
through scanning the internet we can
find new services
new resources and possibly even new
vulnerabilities
and you would think that the internet
was scanned from its inauguration
but that's not the case the the first
open scanning project was the lander
project in 2004
and they scanned the internet by running
a pin ping scan
on all on all ipv4 addresses
the map here this is the most famous
census map of the ipv4 addresses and
this was done in 2012.
so why not why don't why haven't
people scanned the internet well that's
because scanning is hard
if you scan on your home computer using
the regular bandwidth
it's very slow comparatively there are
for about 4 billion ip addresses and
about 65 000 ports
and combining them all together it would
take a very long time to scan the entire
internet
also isps don't really like you spamming
syn packets
trust me don't try this at home it's
very hard to get an isp to unblock you
so either you slow down your scanning
face considerably
or you start using a server or multiple
servers if you use servers you have to
get the data back somehow
and then you have to to save the data in
some sort of db
and if you scan only once instead and
and if you don't want to scan only once
and want to
scan the internet continuously you have
to have a lot of space
and you have to version the db because
you don't want previous data to override
the current data you have
and all of this is it would just take
too long for a security researcher as a
side job
if it's not some it's too much it takes
too much time and resources for security
researcher
on their own to do this but luckily it's
hard but it's not that hard
there are a lot of bots humans and
crawlers that scan the internet
because all the stuff i mentioned are
pretty
if you take this as a full-time job
they're not very difficult
but most of the most of the scanners on
the internet save data to themselves
this interesting thing is scanning an
internet scanning service does
is that it doesn't only scan the
internet but it also displays the data
in a way that is easy for users to
query and because of this
and the fact that regular security
researchers
on their day-to-day jobs would not be
able to do this
in their free time this democracizes
access to internet scale data sets
so the first scanning service and the
most popular one that i'm talking i'm
going to talk about
is the one that i also show here which
is choden
sheldon was founded in 2009 and
as far as i know it was the first public
internet scanning service
anything else that came beforehand has
been lost to the internet
there have been so many talks about
showdown and what it can show in 2015
they even tweeted
the control page of a particle
accelerator which is pretty cool
and one of the reasons that children is
popular is that
it has it was alone in the landscape for
about five years but and then
came along came census census was
started
as the zed map project in 2012
by a group of researchers in the
university of michigan
they wanted to see if the internet was
getting safer
by um want to see if the internet was
getting safer by trying to scan the
entire internet
and the way to do this and their
their new idea was to instead of
creating a full connection
just send tcp packets uh syn packets tcp
syn packets
and then if you get a result then the
port is open and then they have another
tool called that grab where that you can
get the full
hdp response or any other port data
you're looking for
they spun out into a company in 2017.
so how do we compare these two services
showdown has a more focused search for
example if you give it a
a string it will not look in the tls
certificate
for this data which census will but
this is because census indexes every
piece of data it receives
especially tls data which this is really
helpful if you
find a certificate a unique certificate
length i want to see
if there are any other ips that
have this length of certificate for
example
also census uses known tools since
census
is based on zmapp and zedgrav it's very
easy to um to check
what census missed or if there's
anything that could bypass
it this is a very interesting
and this helps as opposed to showdown
who's uh whose tools are proprietary a
point to showdown is that
it scans more ports children scanned
about a thousand two hundred thirty
fourth as opposed to
since this is a thousand forty it's not
a lot but you're
if you're looking for an esoteric port
this could make the difference
so we see see that we saw that scanning
is hard
we saw that scanning is not hard enough
so that nobody will do it and we found
two scanning services that exist
there must be more how can you find more
we need the opposite of a scanning
service and this is where gray noise
comes in
grey noise is a sensor network um
it is the opposite of showdown and
senses in a way that it is completely
passive
um greatness has served multiple servers
across the world in different autonomous
zones
and when a scanner
a showdown census or something
proprietary
tries to scan grey noise gray noise logs
ip
the four and the data received
now let's see what greenhouse has to say
about choden
this is the gray noise visualizer and if
i enter
showdown
i can see
i can see that it's loading but if we
if we let it load
okay if the demo isn't working let me
go and redo the the slides
okay let's look at them through here
here if we look at what showdown shows
with greatness here about showdown it
shows a lot of different
um the different ips that choden uses
and let's pick a specific one i can see
the ip that it scans from reverse dns
if it exists possible
scanning types and the number of ports
now remember that i told you that choden
scans about 1
240 ports they don't
actually document that anywhere what i
did is because grain was recognized as
both showdown and census
i took the reports that grain noise
recognized that diabetes that grain was
recognized as showdown
and the eyephase that is recognized as
synthesis
made a unique list of ports and compared
the two
so granois classifies all its ips
into three categories
every ip that it finds malicious unknown
and benign malicious ivs are those that
show indications of trying to brute
force passwords or scan for recognizable
exploits
unknown services just scan the internet
not for any specific re
um but grey noise doesn't recognize them
it doesn't know that it's showdown
for example or any other known scan or
google bot
and the benign are scans that choden
recognizes
such as jordan or census they might also
show indications
of sending a vulnerable packet but it's
possible
that but since greno is only a sensor
network and
doesn't um doesn't run a full
interaction it's possible that they
check only if
this um only send a vulnerable packet to
see if
they get the the expected
vulnerable response or if it's an iv
that close the vulnerability
so we talked about great uh showdown and
census
and we talked about grain noise and how
grainoids can recognize sodium census
so let's see what other scanning
services greenways recognizes
i'm going to talk about two of them onif
and rapid7
onif is a front scanning server that was
started in 2018
it's not it doesn't scan very many ports
only about 100
but it takes data from a bunch of
different places such as
it tries to resolve the ip to see what
where it's from
or it takes data from pastebin to see if
um if the ip um
was ever seen in different um in
different pasties and
rapid seven rapid 7 is interesting
because it displays the data much
differently
unlike all the other scanning services
which show the data
you give a single ip and they give you
the response in rapid 7
you find you get uh once a da
once a month you get a dump of for
example
all the http get responses that rapid
seven received
in the in the last month from 480
or port 5555 they have a list of ports
there
and this is really useful because
showdown
to get this data from showdown it would
take a lot of credits
and that's a lot of money and a lot of
other possible searches that
could happen but are all the data
are all the actors that green noise
defines
as benign really benign there's
pdr labs which called itself an internet
mapping experiment and an
industry research group i didn't find
much data about it
and it looks from gray noise it looks
like its scans are benign
they don't try they don't try to check
for any vulnerabilities
on the other hand there is stretchoid
this is stretchy's front page and the
only page you can find
on its website it pretty much says give
me your ip and i promise i won't scan
you
i don't really trust it and
it scans mostly from digitalocean which
is um which is a small cloud player
and unlike pdr labs it does send
vulnerable packets that contain
vulnerabilities
it's been seen to try uh to try to send
requests that exploit an elastic search
called the injection vulnerability
i'm not really sure what's going on
there
but it's very fishy
and now i want to talk about a service
that gray noise
recognizes but barely
um fofa uh grey noise has
only eight results for fosa
it's possible that this is because fofa
is
a chinese internet scanning service
as you can see from the text and what i
like about fofa is that it has
some things that stand apart from
showden and census
for example it displays data not only
for an ip it doesn't only show the last
ip
but it also shows data
from from before so if you want to look
at the lifespan of an
ip address fofa is a good place to look
also it um
it saves a lot of a lot more of the html
page
now i'll show this using anglerfish
anglerfish
is a honeypot whose uh
page is about forty thousand more than
forty thousand characters all of these
characters are vulnerable substrings
um that of substrings of router names
titles server names pretty much
what they're saying is come at me bro
just try to exploit anything you can on
me
and while showdown shows about 12 000
characters of this page fofa shows about
28 000.
and that really shows the difference
when you're looking for
um for some sort of service who's only
recognizable substring
is further down very far down on its
page
or does have a page with a lot of
characters
so i wasn't kidding about the quiz
so please uh please go on to the slack
channel
and um and let's start
scenario one a security researcher
believe they have found the new
misfortune cookie
and is interested in seeing all the
pages from all the ips that have port
open in the last month which scanning
service would you use
please uh please fill out the survey
the the quiz and um
let's see
that's right i would use 7. because
rapid 7
gives a dump of all the data in the last
month it's a much better service to use
than all the others where you have to
query a specific
ip or have to use a lot of credits to
get further pay
more pages on to the next scenario
scenario two d-link dsl 2750b
has a command injection vulnerability
according to exploit db
but the device name at the is at the
very bottom of its login home
page what scanning service would you use
that's right i always use fosa because
sofa has
indexes more of the html data then it's
a much better service to use
and as you can see um while
showdown has only 63 results for this uh
this router census has 393
and fofa has 519 unique ips
and note that i took a span of about two
weeks so it's not the fact that
fofa has saved scans from the past
doesn't make sense and for our last
scenario
i want to find data about a specific ip
address because it came up as possibly
interesting from my company's ids
what scanning service would you use
well it really depends what what you're
comfortable with or what you like
i would use showdown if i'm more most
comfortable with that or if i want the
most
what i want to look at the most ports
i would use onif if i want to see this
if this ip for some reason
is has been found you in pastebin
i would use sofa because it's chinese
and might not
have the exclusion lists that other
scanning services have
or i would use census because i'm most
comfortable with that and i want to see
if there's any
interesting data that was indexed
i wouldn't use rapid 7 for this because
it's not a specific ip
but in conclusion
no scanning service is an entire toolbox
and i very much hope
that next time you find an interesting
ivy
you won't use a screwdriver to try to
take a nail out from a board thank you
very much