I am looking forward and excited to
share with you that our next speakers
one of the speakers I'm personally
excited about she is an amazing security
professional she's actually a not just a
security professional she is a team
leader she leads security research for
Windows Defender advanced threat
protection at Microsoft now I have to
share with you a secret about our next
speaker her name is Donna Burrell
Donna was here in Israel during the
pandemic but she got called by Microsoft
to Seattle so she is joining us from the
west coast so this next talk may not be
as live as we would all like it to be
she's not right here on this stage but
we're extremely thankful for her for
joining us at this early hour of 0 4:00
in the morning I think or something
around that time all the way in the west
coast so Donna's going to be talking to
us about eliminating alert fatigue a
fantastic topic for an after-lunch
coffee break session grab a coffee
because this is going to be a fast fun
talk about eliminating alert fatigue and
how to do better as a security
professional so Donna started her career
in the famous 8200 unit I know you know
what I'm talking about
wink wink say no more and she's also
worked for Google in their security team
in Zurich Switzerland Donna is very
passionate about operating systems and
windows internals and in her spare time
she also volunteers with high school
students mentoring the next generation
of cyber security experts I first met
Donna through the black hoodie
initiative which is a reverse
engineering seminar for women first
started in Vienna but now it's become a
global phenomenon and Donna was working
super hard to actually bring black
hoodie to Israel this summer it didn't
work out because of the pandemic but
sign me up for next year so I hope
you're ready for this amazing talk about
eliminating alert fatigue please welcome
give her a round of applause even though
she's not here in the room Donna Burrell
thank you Donna
hi everyone thanks for joining my talk
about reducing other's fatigue through
better engineering I am super excited to
share with you some of the work we've
done over the past two years before we
start let me introduce myself my name is
Donna I am the security research lead
for Windows Defender ATP I am originally
from Israel and currently based in
Seattle Washington in the Microsoft
headquarters I work on fascinating
research projects and how do you / to
knit to present some of my research in
conferences like black hat and blue hat
and I love dogs so let's talk about dogs
for a second I don't know about you but
my dog is a Barker when I got her I
would be alerted every time she barked
but now I learned to ignore the barking
as I realize most of it is false alerts
when I expect what I experience is
alerts fatigue I am tired of wasting my
time investigating my dogs alerts this
is exactly what happens to stock teams
hunting for threats if they get too many
false alerts they experience the same
alert fatigue that we would like to
avoid as security vendors you are
probably thinking so why do we produce
FP in the first place there is a number
of reasons for that first we need to
remember that most software and
environments that we use are dynamic we
install new software and we
update existing software in many cases
these contain API miss usage the benign
software uses api's in ways that may
seem suspicious
another reason for producing FP alerts
is data gaps sometimes the security
provider doesn't have the required data
to determine if an activity is malicious
or not when that happens some will
generate an alert out of conservatism
one more reason for FP is false
detection logic this could be related to
a lack of testing flawed assumptions or
other human mistakes I'll talk more
about how we can minimize this but I had
mentioned that the the first two reasons
are the core sources of a piece and
fortunately the human factor is normally
insignificant the last reason has to do
with a lab alerts misinterpretation
when TP alert is identified as an FP
Lert as part of the work I'm presenting
today we made some product improvements
to address this however this is beyond
the scope of this engineering discussion
all right so we understand the root
cause for FPS let's tackle is the
traditional approach to producing
security alerts is to cover as many TPS
as possible with the minimal amount of F
beat as the diagram shows we set the
threshold based on the context balancing
fans and fps highly sensitive
environments
in conservative to ensure they don't
skip any TP
generally you want to cover most cases
introduce the list number of offense
while avoiding FPS this should be the
approach when introducing a new
detection algorithm however this
approach introduces a trade-off between
offense and FPS we were looking to shift
the card
eliminating fans without compromising
FPS through better engineering in order
to do this we need to leverage data to
drive engineering improvements data that
helps us understand FB generation
focusing on alert conclusion data we
will average data from three different
sources first wheels customer feedback
four inch alert we produce we ask
customers to provide us feedback while
we don't always receive feedback it
helps draw our attention to pain points
next we leverage expert graders that's
our in-house experts that verify alert
accuracy initially the gradient alerts
randomly however in order to optimize
their productivity we developed
contextual clustering so instead of
working through alerts randomly degrade
related alerts in bulk to save plenty of
overhead this to manual sources are
great but not enough in order to
understand our detection precision rate
we need to scale our testing
for that reason we introduced a machine
learning model to predict to predict
alert conclusions leveraging our manual
inputs and scaling their impact this
tool predicts individual alert
conclusions conclusion using multiple
machine learning models to achieve high
confidence alert grades so let's take a
moment to understand where we are we
understand why we have a piece and the
trade off that involves reducing them we
can leverage alert conclusion data to
transform this trade off so let's
examine how we we started by analyzing
the other generation process breaking it
down into its components to identify SP
root cause I like to refer to this
process as a loop producing new alerts
that are being assessed then being
monitored to identify pinpoints to fix
breaking the loop into steps helped us
to focus our attention on the most
vulnerable components to ensure our
efforts move the needle as part of this
we analyze the process step by step step
by step to identify which kind of a
speii can be avoided in each component
this included better engineering
guardrails and reiterating engineering
guidelines in addition we started to
measure SP fixing time in order to
minimize it we then tackled the alert
fixing process
introducing new tools and I will cover
in the next slide these tools enabled us
to discover SP cases faster and solve
them quickly so even if we produce
unwanted FP the fixing cycle will be
closed first without customer reporting
and before customers even notice it in
most cases
for example we introduced a note a new
component into the alert generation
process that's the FP filter this filter
combines rule-based logic and machine
learning models to address FP in real
time before they become customer facing
the rule based filtering enables us to
apply broad filtering for common FPS
patterns across different type of alerts
the machine learning model predicts FP
based on prior conclusions and other
contextual features if the FP filter
makes a definitive judgment on a
specific pattern we will circle this
insight back into our detection logic
however this component is intended to
pick up on unpredictable behaviors that
cannot be programmed but cannot be
programmed into the detection logic and
last I previously mentioned Auto grading
tool which is another addition to the
alert generation process that enhances
our detection capabilities the auto
graders the auto grades are fed into
this flow supporting the precision
assessment
and the detection fixing and of course
the SP filtering the next step to reduce
SP through better engineering is to
introduce new tools the first tool we
developed is a proactive and normally
detection tool the monitors alerts
monitor alerts production in real-time
and flag the suspect FP based on
observed anomalies such as volume spikes
this tool notifies us when it detects
cross customers and normal ease these
are phenomena that impact multiple
customers making a bridge less likely
this notification will trigger an
internal flow of urgent fixing to
address this case we also introduced an
alert clustering system which clusters
alerts based on features similarity and
then delivers a conclusion for each
cluster this way we get an overview of
alert patterns and we can tackle them at
scale providing a conclusion such as TP
or FP for each pattern this allows us to
review the alert patterns and their
conclusion automatically and reduce time
to fix to summarize as part of our
engineering efforts to minimize FP cases
we first analyzed the overall allure
generation process
for improvement in addition we
introduced a new SP filtering component
to filter FPS in real-time
next we developed the automatic grading
mechanism to create alerts at scale for
better conclusions then created the
alert and normally monitoring to detect
FP cases in real time so we can tackle
them quickly last is our alert
clustering approach which was introduced
multiple times as part of alert grading
and as post alert FP analysis our main
takeaways from this process
our first clustering increases our
productivity so that instead of
reviewing FP case by case we can cluster
similarities review alerts in bulk and
tackle them at scale second by breaking
down processes we can better engineer a
solution it allows us to analyze steps
along the chain determine which ones can
be automated and of course scale human
impact empowering researchers next like
the old-fashioned engineering approach
we should always start small with a few
C proved its value and then scale
everything I presented today started
from a POC last in order to produce
meaningful results that move the needle
I must identify which key levers we need
to optimize for we optimize for time to
discover time to fix and detection
precision precision to keep our eyes on
the ball