veto no no it just I don't know if it's
the
or whatever okay this is a minute this
is a five gip meeting site meeting IETF
95 in buena side and this is the agenda
out there since we are not officially
chartered arranging we don't have to do
any agenda bashing but if you have any
question on the agenda the times are of
course we try to impose not the one we
are going to do we cannot really like
much mystic maybe you can exceed little
bit okay everything is ok I guess there
was a request about the slide set after
the meeting we have all the slides and
hopefully we can post it on the mailings
I think that is the best way for us
because we have no other place okay so
don't worry about this lives just a you
know listen and watch and then you're
going to have this lights after the
meeting okay and the sign-up sheets are
circulating around please write down
your name just for us it's not anything
of you or the other thing is meaningless
that i'm sure you guys
meaningless make sure if you are not to
subscribe or let us know that you're
going to begin subscribe you to the main
okay okay so we start with GM is the
first we have we have a couple of remote
participants on the vehicle here and see
so you can have some questions from them
too okay your speedy right PDF I happy
okay here with the name 5g this move I
let's go no no no but we hit it
I'm truly apps I she saw from can't just
no help us no no not this one no
let's see something that's hey today I'm
finally home ownership rate so until you
use a little witch which made I'm here
because I said I'm sorry for breaking
capsule Japs you know we refer to save
this fight
oh my my Shaitan navigon salute
presenter personal rights I lose focus
no nation okay we will go to the next
presenter dark sorry about that I thing
I have you find the other one in the
meantime this all right okay okay yeah
thanks for for coming so this is
essentially a summary of a little
article i wrote the end of last year and
then some sudden and discussion we had
on a couple of mailing lists and it's
essentially a a call that when we think
about what we could possibly do in 5g
really take a close look what's actually
wrong in today's networks and what can
actually learn from the problems that we
experiencing today next slide please i
can at the moment yeah yeah okay
ok so anyway when you look into the
textbook how mobile network looks like
today so you see things like access
network core network application service
user equipment and so on and then there
are a couple of protocol somebody
management and so on to make this work
but so in practice we have a whole lot
of machinery but it's actually needed to
provide useful service today and next
slide please for example and you move on
for example in a typical network
deployment you would see at least one TT
proxy if not more which is they deem
necessary operators like to to have
better control of aggression control
loops next slide there's quite some
elaborate machinery for traffic
management so extracting real-time
information from base stations radio
data and then using that for policing
for example or other forms of traffic
control next slide they are definitely a
bunch of application optimizers so video
optimizes mainly that do things like
transcoding next night keep going and so
so in the ITF people also have thought
about say how to directly inform
application servers better of what's
going on in the network so there's a
proposal called mobile throughput
guidance so you get a bit of the idea so
there's lots of stuff that is needed and
practice to provide a good performance
ok so addition of that cadet and as you
know as soon you cannot really roll out
a major service today without CDN so
that's another say essential component
that also needs to be considered when
you talk about the big picture so
CDN today is mostly done by like having
big caches at colocation points and so
on but in the future there there are
definitely trends to move this deeper
down into the network so edge caching
these kind of things and this is
essentially needed if you think about
like the upcoming epic tation so
blending video on demand and India TV
having a multicast like distribution
tree with that that's another thing that
we are adding on top and if you think
about other applications so there s not
only like the netflix casters there's
Akamai their social networks there's a
danger also that we have really arriving
at a slightly complicated and also
siloed system in the end so couple of
activation so we today already we need a
significant amount of stuff to really
make things just work and so it has not
only to disappear in performance but
that's one of the topics I wanted to
loot here then tweeted in today so
caching is really important and it's
likely going to increase question is so
if you want to enable new use cases so
new so called OTT applications what will
that actually mean for a say useful and
manageable and network in the future and
so what does it mean for so if you look
into the say published ng MN use cases
for 5g like a couple of things that are
interesting and if you try to distill
the technical requirements for that so I
only picked like to hear so if you want
to cover IOT send the network's tactile
internet so super low latency internet
you have to really think about what you
can do for performance so optimized
forwarding for all these different kinds
of access technologies in one system if
you like move more and more critical
service to the network you have to
really think about security and user
privacy and that's the topic we are
thinking
about her today and for security so I
mean we are I think it's safe to say
that may she be too is it's a here
Tuesday and it's good because we want to
have more encryption in the network and
on the other hand it'll creates quite
some headaches or for operators that
have been used to use all this machine
II like traffic management application
layer optimizations and so on to provide
better performance this all becomes more
difficult now at least or more expensive
and so we will have to think about other
mechanisms do that so we are partly
doing this so there's an a record of em
this week that it's taking some of these
things but its arch over nothing
regarding security is so when we say TLS
it's often like sold as providing better
user privacy because your connections
are encrypted in fact what it means that
not normally that your connection to the
next CDN cash is encrypted and what
happens after that is actually beyond
your control so of course you can assume
so Akamai probably will encrypt the next
stop as well but what happens to attend
the cloud so this is of course by no
means protected and so our TLS or
channel based encryption service today
yeah protects the connection but not
really the end user data so that we have
no control no ways to authorize that
copying was goofing and so on I'm i need
six minutes magnets so and the other
topic is so if you want to address all
these say demanding use cases it would
be probably difficult to implement this
was like TCP as is today so these
different control loop Conservation's
it's not really an effective solution to
extend the use of TV proxies so I think
that that's a road nobody wants to go
down
the network of proxies doesn't really
sound convincing so what I want to do
and propose an a kind of explain it a
bit more detail in my my article is to
think about more say additional
forwarding layer functions that could
help in covering all these heterogeneous
network links so for example enabling
local regions version in some cases
enabling a simple form of cash in
without requiring the full C n
complexity so that's like one IBM didn't
and ok ok that's all right i got i think
say we're interesting feedback on this
that is also on this slide but so if we
have time later like that we can go back
to this ok ok any questions under
quickly when Aaron like Kevin Smith
Vodafone as so my take on this is that
really the major problem is the lack of
harmony between the radio layers and TCP
flow and congestion controls if we can
get that right together we probably
won't need the tcp proxies until yeah
hopefully I mean okay so I am so one of
the things that it's probably true
estates I mean there's lots of say aqm
technology that is not really deployed
right now so that could be helpful to
improve end-to-end performance for tcp
you know what sort of one of the
comments I I got funding from people
yeah thank you hi my name is Padma care
snow um I have a question specifically
about the hop by hop forwarding that you
mentioned right um the reason why is
because i really think that pork us and
eventually optimize routing how do you
expect this to work with help i hope i
think there should be other mechanisms
on top of that right right i mean this
is
certainly a like like future-oriented
say proposal so but there is this work
for example in the ICN community on like
full balance and so i hope i hope
congestion control so the idea is
basically that you enable the forwarding
layer or you provide better visibility
for the for the for nigga hoped so for
what's going on in the network regarding
latency to your next stop for example so
this can be done if you have a bit more
visibility of say so in ICN did kind of
request names for example and match that
to your different outgoing faces and so
that you can achieve better performance
of course it's not something that you
can do directly today without modifying
the network on the other hand i mean so
we talked a lot about slicing in 5g and
and and and software-defined networks
and so on so it's not that these things
are totally impossible or say really
expensive to implement so you can
experiment with things today and so
people are building and software alters
45 and 5c right now yes uh wanting in
its color that i have in line is about
section continuity I don't see how we
can do that with hop-by-hop especially
with the latency of sub-millisecond so
I'm just working this out um I would
like to understand how yeah I wouldn't
take me at least another five minutes to
but I mean it's you actually can make
things like multi management much easier
because if you are thinking about like a
request-response type of interaction you
don't need to signal location you
basically can resume your session
seamlessly but just continuing to
regress on your new point of attachment
of course you also need to take care of
the other directly interaction but um
it's the pets doable
yeah moving on next no next Marcus
presents Merkel what does your new
representations PDF either the next is a
very short presentation about challenges
in next generation core development so
one of the major challenges is for next
generation core to tackle a huge amount
of devices and you diversity of devices
so devices have different communication
patterns mobility patterns I'm a power
constraints some are not so um this
brief presentation is about how can we
be smart and providing connectivity and
maintaining connectivity for these
devices joint effort means there is a
European project it's an industry
collaboration project running I have one
slide on that which is a group of
partners from industry first light no no
I will come to that later it's just
intro I keep the five minutes that were
um to tackle these these challenges so
various cases are being discussed for 5g
including io te machine chap devices
sensor devices mobile internet with a
high speed internet access smart devices
mobile content sources and the mission
critical it's not the latest one right
which is in any way it's fun that is
proceed with this one um and then
mission-critical devices which have even
more constrained on bandwidth and
reliable communication so for machine
type 2
vices there s more there are a massive
number of these devices some are
stationary some are mobile even if you
have a stationary device you may need
something what is called today paging
not to locate the device but to wake it
up right in case it needs to be
reachable some Sanders they wake up
periodically and send a measure and
sample to the network so you don't need
to reach ability so the question is how
to tackle all these different challenges
and devices about her to heterogeneity
not only heterogeneity in devices but
also heterogeneity in different access
networks how to manage these resources
and how to because sufficient on some of
the enabling technology is being
discussed is network slicing which is
mainly a group of network functions
being isolated from other one so that
eases network management separation of
control data plane separation of
locators from identifiers there is a lot
of work also going on the ITF which may
be relevant here so how can we be smart
and Taylor service being provided to a
particular device next one so here um so
how can we be smart we identify there
are various device with diverse
communication patterns mobility patterns
energy constraints and also capabilities
so there is a lot of context information
being available what we have today is
subscription context we can find out
more about the device capability it's
about profile information maybe even
only mount references being sent from
the device or the subscriber to the
network can be taking into account
statistics can be taken here so we have
a lot of information available of a
particular device about the service
level agreement and the expected service
behind so how can we be smart so we have
two categories identified the one is
selection so mainly a choice from
available resources we have
different isolated control plane slices
and data plane slices we can select from
this set maybe a large set of small set
and then how to peer control and data
plane slices so we may have a one-to-one
relationship between one control and one
data plane slide or I want to end so one
control brain slice can drive if
multiple data plane slightly after
selection of the slides we need to pick
the particular network functions which
we need that can be a control plane
anchor on the data plane can be dead
obtained anchors which basically
determine the path of the data traffic
so after that selection we can perform
configuration the configuration means
the setup and use of only the required
resources not a default set of states
and resources but tailor it to the
devices needs so what all the devices
need is connectivity so that's a base in
fundamental requirement for other
devices otherwise they would attach
everything else which is today default
which is location tracking reach ability
handover optimization IP address
continuity can be made as a service so
we add this on top of the connectivity
and in that sense create States under
control plane and data plane only if
required next one so as I said there is
a currently industry collaboration
project running in Europe which is
called conflict control of 5g networks
so the main objective here is
convergence and being excess agnostic so
I have a common control plane in the
core that drives multiple access
networks um functional modularity so
intention here is to not stick to 4G but
to be a little bit more disruptive in
addressing new or defining a new work
functional architecture and have this in
the modular way which allows you to pre
design control plane slices as there is
neat so we identified different
functional elements for connectivity
management mobility management flow
management
30 in excess transition context
awareness is a very fundamental part to
an able smart selection and smart
configuration of control and data so
this activity runs actually as a regular
European project we have work packages
about use cases requirements functional
architecture and then about the
solutions one of the key aspects is to
specify solutions for smart connectivity
plan is to evaluate and prototype this
dissemination and standards impact is
very fundamental and 3gpp also onf are
also mainly IETF we see as these
standardization tracks where relevant
work is being done Thanks all right
that's it thanks a medical hey any
questions quickly one question you can
take any questions for Marco anyway you
can ask you with us correct
representation so don't judge here I
have your sweat finally I'm sorry I my I
had lost my network connectivity that
was the reason you will give me problems
ok ok everyone listen Jade oh and i'm
going to give a high level analysis of
the gaps in ipe transport for the 5g
requirements ok right ok we know that 5g
brings a lot of new requirements from on
the transport network basically the most
important ones are list here like a low
latency large bandwidth networks lycée
and the programmability so we need to
identify whether the IP transport
network today has some gaps in this
areas ok so for the low latency we know
in 5g services some of them will require
ultra-low latency liked for the front
hall CPI transportation that will
require 100 microseconds delay in the
transport and for the mission-critical
IOT services it's typically the delay
can be afforded is 1 to 10 milliseconds
and which means if we want to use IP
transport to support this services et
need to provide pound 8 latency and
currently in ITF that networking group
is working on this area and which may it
may also need to coordinate with other
organizations and add a mechanism like
the working I triple you a toe to toe
one and the sixties ok for the large
bandwidth we know that a front-hall
super I may need the several hundred K
base for each side and for the another
popular servicing 5g the virtual reality
it may require a large bandwidth for
each user so this will all have a
requirement on the transport about the
huge bandwidth and for IP network and to
put mrs. bandwidth requirement there may
be something to consider the first thing
is how to pour compounding the ports to
provide the larger bandwidth stone which
can be supported for one single part and
another things provide guaranteed
bandwidth for this kind of services as
for the front hall of a real virtual
reality they may require a very
stringent bandwidth and you cannot mix
them with low priority services but not
the final previous a nothing is a
benefit of using IP transport ISM
statistical multiplexing so we still
want to use a state statistic
multiplexing where it is possible in
these scenarios so this is a kind of
challenging for the IP transport this
one the network slicing is a very
popular and hot topic recently which
means the 5g will provide
diversified services seeing the same
single infrastructure so for the
transport it means each slice need to
provide a different trend transportation
service which including the different a
topology requirement and then maybe
different slides will require different
forwarding paradigms and the different
queue as parameters like lost delay
jitter and bandwidth also for different
services they have different requirement
on the reliability so we have a question
on this part is kenzie existing vision
technologies meet the network's
licensing requirements in the transport
and the analysis my email phone ringing
I think this part we need to have more
analysis and Modi investigation is that
especially for the any topology
connectivity and for the service
resource management maybe there's still
some gap in the existing Vivian
technologies okay for the
programmability is mentioned a lot in
the white papers that if I will require
the stn for the other program ability of
the network and to do we have the
distributed network today and it is not
quite likely that a tidy transport
network will be become totally
centralized control so what we need is
to find the balance between the
centralized control and distributed
functions to meet the to learn to
provide the required natural
programmability and the meet the
requirement in the flexibility and
scalability which means we need to
consider both the North Mountain
interface source phone interface and as
well as the signaling and control plane
between the East and the West
so for the next step I think we need to
work further on identifying the missing
gaps in this area and also a not analyze
and discuss potential mechanism to fill
these gaps one question Eric not mark
just a clarifying question you said
different forwarding paradigms on the
slicing so I would not actually mean
yeah what I mean is some nitrous last
may require later three IP forwarding
some may require later to forwarding or
some name because even none IP
forwarding hard times like what is
called i c'n or something what is ours
yeah yeah yeahs information-centric
networker so there's a lot of
flexibility you need to meet all these
requirements in the same network we
prepared the dark a couple of slides as
we want to show it as a as an overview
so basically what happened in the on the
mailing list we have been discussing
many things and one issue that wisdom
raised was we need to simplify layering
someone I think the President on the
mailing list so how can we simplify the
earring because inherently special
invite us that works we have a lot of
friends layer that are being used and
they close I could long packets like mac
and IP header rows and so on
so are here what is being used today and
I what is being used today for example
the esky side of all day then in the 53
areum what we can have so basically the
FI if I in future internet architecture
and so a simplify this to only three
layers on the side the bank and then
about that the transport layer so on the
user side and then the servers then the
network can only be three years three
three layers in the Playstations and
wrapped and so and ready access
specifically are only limited to the
lower too late now this is another
proposal more sophisticated again am
based on this narrow waist idea narrow
waist IP but you can fish in the wood is
it going to be the end result is going
to be so narrow waist but so all these
things then we need we need to add in
order to satisfy the five key
requirements to the IP layer and then
linked a rather later than that change
so I'm going to talk about leaving
shortly either from the so-called
mobility first project that was
conducted in in some universities in
llame in America and they completely at
the end of last year so they came up
with several interesting ideas and some
of them they try to work out some detail
but it could be that for us to look at
look into these things and then maybe we
can get ideas for some feature work
in this group if if people are
interested in because basically our
attention I think should be since next
generation ID is this I p AF and so what
what is going to look like IP layer in
the future in the 5g networks so then
these types of things we see in there
and the IP layer in the data plane and
then control plane these are things with
you so now next I and then again this IL
MP identified locator network protocol
has been discussed very shortly and also
this was discussed on the list and then
Cameron binds I don't know any of you
know him is from telenovela t-mobile and
an ITF crime he contacts us offline and
he suggested this I LMP is a good
direction to go so we made up few slides
about lmp2 into just interview and then
I noticed that he had a draft is there I
think he is presenting interior
afternoon about the LNP so I asked him
to come to this session just because we
have we are talking about Olympia so
I'll MP is I think this I identified
locator for a pony this project was
finished in 2012 four years ago in the
routing area idra ire research I I group
I our idea what what you call our ritm
something yeah so but it was all
published in a series of RFC's like
eight nine 10 fc's
there's a little more work going on in
research dark contacted them maybe you
can talk about it later very shortly now
basically the idea is very simple we
have an identifier and allocate a
separate and then this similar police
idea then I think they started this
first and then discontinued in some
other way so the approach here is
different from list in the sense that
the I LMP does not modify the routing
system and it's completely compatible
with IP with ipv4 and ipv6 mp4 version
was defined ipv6 version was defined and
some modifications here and that Alex
Alex plane what is modified post is
modified of course then I see MPL I have
are modified and Venus flavor so it's
very limited modification to the current
IP life so so we can see that IP layer
modification required here normal
discussion to IP multicast and no
modifications routing system so
basically the transport layer keeps
identifier look local identifier and
remote identifier in the state so this
way when your address or locator changes
so the session doesn't break because
it's based on your look at your
identifier and identified is very simple
is the EU i-64 formatted some node name
okay it's called more likely an ID or
they didn't fight and then located in IP
subnet work that they noticed though the
interface is in so like the network
prefix network routing prefix associated
with that sub network so on okay now I
don't want to talk very long about these
things button it's a yeah someone
comment so we're working tomm Herbert
yeah thank you okay I
so we're working on something very
similar to il NP identifier locator
addressing the differences so it's
basically a 64-bit locator 64-bit
identifier like I LNP unlike I LNP it
does not require yep the same doesn't
require changes to TCP which we like and
we actually have implemented this for
data center ability have not thought too
much about the more general context I
can certainly look at it but it's kind
of like I LMP best way to think of it I
LNP but a real manifestation of it so we
actually have implementation and
starting an appointment of it thank you
i think it your experience is very
valuable and we need to have contributed
more maybe if you continue on this in
distraction just least you're a teeny
will be so and one thing will be
presenting ila Friday crowding working
group are twg ok now ens changes and of
course you need to define all these
things and then put they define these
are hours and then they need to be
supported by the by the dns server that
you are contacting basically you give
them the identifier you get the locator
so that type of normally say fqdn but
then with this they change the
identifier nie then get a locator for
for the north you are looking the others
of afternoon then so the host sending
packets to the correspondent not CN is
corresponding not so what does it how
does it work I think it's pretty simple
now how so basically what they're most
main interest was the host mobility
multi-homing support and so on so I
didn't include multiple mean discussion
here the horse movie stream is and
basically two things every time the
earth moves we need to do a locator
update
the message icmp v4 or v6 located update
message the horse sense that as you
messages to all the corresponding so
then the year and then is a dynamic dns
update muscles so I think this is what
something that they wanted to avoid in
at least so they decided to change the
routers routing system and that makes it
more difficult to deploy so why are we
interested in this because then the
first of all the other is only mobility
of issue of 5g LMP compared to with Lisp
is easier to deploy and Cameron been
suggested to work on 3gpp specific
issues 45 cm ability using I LMP so
that's the reason we got into this and
then I prepared this light so it looks
like if you if you want to apply this to
3gpp maybe you need some changes in the
current ILM people so that is something
we can look into if developers
interested and dark concession II he was
not really yeah yeah but I did not talk
in detail to himself I hope that he will
contribute to the list further one and
we can then discuss there so it's not
much more than I that I know this one
thing they say I think there is no
socket interface doesn't change with
this so I think that's a that's an
important result that they got through
okay next is the mobility first slides
having a flashy I if we can cut any time
if you like so this is explaining what
what I showed before what those things
are like a like generous global name is
a global name resolution service and
then name was it NCS
so similar idea but that they're
defining more globally unique flat
identifiers EU ID and then below the
resolution service which should be very
quick to resolve these some nice idea
then you will post this thing and there
in the internet actually I didn't make
this life so they're all public domain
document so so basically the idea is to
keep these extensions in some name this
header in the pdu but the first part is
always the current ipv4 or ipv6 doesn't
change they try to not the chain similar
things in di di LMP they put into the
optional optional earth and tv6
extension headers and so that's the idea
to not disturb the current routing and
forwarding here okay now so we have this
year there is slides the other one is
the storage area I think on this one
this passion for word processing in the
router there is this segmented segment
talking I think it's being done in the
inner eco-friendly segment working group
is working on that these two doctors
have storage and then you can you can do
hope I off from transfer of things Ohio
transport example the whole movie can be
transported this way in the routing
system and this is currently going on
unity of segments working group so some
of these things are being implemented
and then context-aware delivery this is
also very interesting idea basically you
want to address things them with the
context like all taxis in Buenos Aires
or all taxis in and around Hilton things
like that so so with these context could
be like geographic coordinates and first
Hispanic so then convert these tools on
your global name resolution service to
some EU ID and then some multicast
convert into some transport mechanism
and then this can be processing Network
i think is a great idea they need to be
worked out for different IP layer type
of changes ok so this move is the first
and then what we can do many this is
many issues in 5g not just movie theme
and many new directions like TNS and she
has named certification services and
sorry radar thing as i said is already
being i guess in deep in a etf somewhere
then on text content and context
delivery but these are the things we can
we can look into more in on the list
discuss and then hopefully in the coming
months and maybe next year sometime we
can find them a good subject and go for
a bar far this is one of our aim so when
do couch arm so i'm not sure how to
articulate this best but i don't think
it's a very good use of our time when we
kind of jump into very specific
potential solutions from a bunch of
research projects without really having
discussed like design goals architecture
let alone having some common
understanding about that so i'm not sure
how helpful this release at this point
and so I want to be impolite but and I'm
not sure Michael if shot
have a clarifying question so at the
very beginning of your presentation you
showed to architecture proposals and
both of them you have something like one
you said it's a next-generation IP and
the other one that was something like I
p plus mentioned in the architecture so
can you just clarify what's that is it
still IP or is it something that will
replace IP here here is that something
like next-generation IP and on the
previous one there is I p plus mentioned
and I'm just wondering what's that yeah
yes clear a few plus yes this means that
candies in the IP layer was is for that
feature internet architecture FIA this
is the time they use in in the
literature reviewers project yeah we
still have IP across all the changes
that we had that I mentioned for example
DNS changes icmp extensions those are
the sidekick plus like you know I killer
the blonde criteria actually play your
favorite video but the other project
introduces more changes a bigger see
kind of analysis dream kind of another's
uc3m so I have a clarifying question of
the day goal of the meeting itself my
understanding was that the goal of this
effort was to identify some issues that
Phi Z may may bring and related to ATF
and try to identify those issues and
then to identifying which working groups
those issues maybe taco not thinking of
both but first in defined the gaps
whether there is room already in in IDF
and and then start working on those so
that was my understanding and if that's
correct so how we can progress to get
there because I and that's I thing is
not an easy SSID but I think that that
will be the useful yeah I think okay I
agree so the issue is to scope better so
like we we have an you know many
proposed I think who dirt talked about
congestion control which is more like
transport layer so
here we wanted to do more ideal air
stuff so by significant consequences in
control of people are are interested so
that's the I mean these guys have that
aim that we can go around the IP layer
and still find the good things to do
Eric nygren I one of the things that
jumped out at me a lot of oh eric nygren
on Eric nygren um one thing that jumped
out as a lot of these slides seem to be
on the let's just throw away the
architecture of the internet and come up
with something whole new of new from
scratch it seems like there's a lot of
that which it where I wonder why there's
not more of a focus on on okay let's
forget about ipv4 we move on from that
let's not try to deal with any
compatibility for that other than as a
service over ipv6 but for everything
going forwards just look figure out what
are really the problems we need to solve
to be able to terminate server IP
connections to user equipment deeper in
the network rather than having to go
through centralized p gateways like it
seems like if we could do that that and
just figure out what are some of the
changes to the existing protocols that
we would need to do that the there's
less of a throw everything away and more
of um and then it becomes a okay how
what are some of the things we need to
do to focus on the mobility stuff or
which are the bits of the congestion
control that we need to go change in
that within the existing framework
rather than starting from scratch with a
whole new framework so you sorry
anything that the you're suggesting that
we should more look be revolutionary and
i think more i think more i'm making a
little sketch i think more i think it
seems like being more evolutionary maze
is no like these look most of the stuff
here looks completely and totally
revolutionary in a a throw everything
away start from scratch like if rather
than the evolutionary which is is ok we
have we today we have effectively on
ipv4 and ipv6 a lot of the mobile
networks are now really deploying ipv6
to the point where we're on a path to
being able to not really worried about
the ipv4 other than for legacy stuff
but even that ipv6 continent
connectivity is um is terminated on to
the Internet something that in a place
it's far away from where the handset is
it actually gets tunneled over some
other some other protocols before it
gets there how do we move that like if
we focus more on how do we move that
closer to the edge which i think is what
some of what Cameron was trying to
propose what you're talking I think you
might have been talking about with is
like trying to keep TCP the same trying
to actually just keep IP the same but
focus more on what changes you we need
for congestion control what changes we
need on the routing side what things can
we do to make multihoming work better
what are ways we can hook better into
into cdns or DNS for being able to
handle some of the load balancing
mapping situations better than then it's
something that becomes a more tractable
problem to solve with you with kind of
with existing real world situations I'm
relieving a problem understanding your
your proposal because I thought that
this is what we are doing here all these
changes especially I NLP is basically
very evolutionary approach so small
changes and I think some of it is it's a
bit but still even an island pier look
when you start getting into the do well
let's just replace TCP with something
slightly different to require kernel
level changes everywhere you start
getting into the realm of things that
take a really that that are very hard to
actually practically roll out like this
is from the the side of a a kind of from
the content delivery operator side just
seeing how hard it's been to get to the
from type just to get from to where we
are with ipv6 today that that trying to
change too much of that stuff in the
narrow hourglass less you change the
easier it is to roll out ok thanks a lot
yeah I have to do this hi I'm Natasha
Rooney and so I was looking at this
slide and part of the things that we
were trying to do with the output of the
Marne eboff and lamar new workshop in
the awkward buff that happens later this
week is to promote more people in telco
space to create drafts based on some of
these problems
so the presentations fantastic but if
you write this up as some sort of
informational document in an ITF format
that would be beneficial to a lot of
people and my personal viewpoint on the
congestion yeah that's a good point we
need to write yeah I and I want to do a
lot more of that myself actually so it's
a reminder to myself to and the other
thing is is that with the regards the
congestion controls stuff I still feel
that that exists perhaps in existing
groups or new groups that might come out
or new work that might come out of a
court rather than in here and this is
more 5gn IP so I i think it probably
needs to be more focused towards the IP
stuff and in the presentations I only
saw one real clear reference to a piece
of work which was the aisle MP piece of
work the rest seems to be suggested sort
of ideas of things that we could look at
which seems too cool for something more
than you know jumping straight into
doing work but gathering more people
around in a bar before something like
that I'm not sold myself my hopes are
this meeting that it would be more of
their kind of requirements of stuff
that's come through on the internet the
week of perhaps bring to the 5g space um
but that hasn't really coalesced I guess
um but yeah that's my commander thank
you I think I suggest said you put these
things into a mailing list and maybe try
to get answers a better more better
discussion later they all appreciate
that actually for everybody who asked
questions that if you can start some
discussion threads on the list nothing
let's go to help us a lot yeah so so I
Eric Nam marquee on so I think that at
least I feel that so there's some
high-level problems that have been
described that people want to solve in
the 5g space but I feel like it would be
useful to sort of drill down into those
a bit more and understand those problems
a bit better and there might be some of
them may I understand better than others
but but what what motivates these things
that people are proposing because then
we can see do we have IETF technology
that already applies her work that's
underway etc because right now if you
like I don't have enough information to
I what kill me what's already there all
right what is it just an educational
problem that all we have this piece over
here you can just go use it thank you
Tom Tom Herbert again so I agree mostly
with evolutions better than revolution
but there is one thing that I think
needs to be addressed and was kind of
alluded to and the since we're
encrypting packets we're losing
information and this is specifically for
forwarding and I think that's kind of a
I don't know if it's an architectural
flaw or why but speaking from the end
house we never really think of
forwarding as using definitely TCP
payload or TCP header is even and it
would be nice if and somehow this work
became more protocol Gnostic so if we
actually needed something in the
forwarding paths that is related to say
the transport layer put that into l3
information somehow so in the end of the
day if forwarding would just be layer 3
and we use a light information that
would be good and I actually think ipv6
has some nice hooks to be able to do
something like this anyway sis patnem so
there is a couple of things that people
have been saying and I i came to agree
with eric is that i think there is a
number of requirements and some of those
proposals of those architectures need to
be assessed and refined i don't think
there is a one solution that fits all
the requirements of 5g in any of them so
I really encourage that we actually look
at the requirement and like you just
said for me borrow pieces that we know
work maybe but I don't think that we
have a ready solution we can just say
jump on that one and it's working right
now thank you thank you had a little fun
participants on the meat ago but not
mushy yeah okay folks thanks a lot for
for this coup de tendance and let's
continue in the next day
in berlin and then again we will mess
will make a call for presentations
people want to design make sure to
prepare a good presentation yeah a
little spider little yeah hi like ninety
percent of
you