oh right what would suck some doesn't
touch is the point this is TS VW g if
you're hoping for something else then
stay anyway
it's going to be chaired by me and
Martin David isn't able to make the
meeting will hopefully have David back
for the next meeting is the audio
working well go and get some more people
this is the ITF not well and if you
haven't read this please read it all
contributions to the working group today
will be covered by the IETF not well if
you don't intend to do that just leave
the room join those people outside but
please read it agenda for today and the
agenda has been bashed slightly and so
we'll just go through the agenda we've
got the ecn encapsulation guidelines by
Bob is Bob you well ok diffserv and I
trip really 802 11 and another
presentation requested by Bob on l4s and
its use of cold points we're not having
a presentation on tunnel ecn the authors
aren't present at this meeting and they
didn't think it was worth doing a remote
presentation so we'll have not yet from
that later and then finally we're going
to look at TTP alternative back off with
ecn is this draft was previously
discussed in TC p.m. and IC c RG and
it's here because this might be the
correct home for actually progressing
the draft so this is the current agenda
does anybody have comments on the agenda
whoo Tim's doing the noise reduction
that should help we don't have Bob Fred
do you like to do the first top yeah you
can sit well is for this slide
admit I was different ism yeah okay next
slide please okay so at the last IETF
meeting um we went through the services
that are discussed in RFC 45 94 and in
this draft which basically duplicates
those services and had a fair discussion
and walked away basically understanding
that the working group was saying that
they were fine with the services that we
offered and then the chair of rich
working group does she chair it the
chair of the right working group
whatever was came up and said oh by the
way you didn't reference my RFC or our
RSC and by the way our deserve good
points and services were all different
so could you please do something about
that so Tim and I went in and did a fair
bit of analysis looked at looked at the
bad RFC pretty hard and she's right
these services are all different it's an
overlapping set of good points
normalizing the thing in this
specification is just plain hard so what
we wound up doing was we inserted a
paragraph but you can read here if you
have microscope that says in a nutshell
yes there is this other RFC we don't
know how to know
moyes and so we think that a user of
this RFC and of RFC 45 94 and the entire
diffserv set of services that it's based
on ah that needs to talk to a GSM a
system is going to have to do dscp
translation at that boundary which is
described in the diff serve architecture
it's how you handle different disks or
domains and sorry they're different
deserve domains and you translate at
that point and did I say anything more
there um no that's literally what I said
and that's the end of my presentation so
so my question for I have two questions
for the working group one of them is is
that okay are you guys okay with that
outcome with respect to RFC 7561 yes no
indifferent we can take comments in
anybody's got comments we can also of
course and we can probably hear for the
people that are here we could probably
hum um what are my questions on what are
you okay with that or on this well yeah
okay if we need people to comment if
they've looked at this yeah has anybody
looked at this and have opinions on this
particular paragraph the drafts been
around for a while and we just added an
extra paragraph so I guess we need
eyeballs on it and yeah so obviously a
welcoming comment will take comments on
the on the list of people don't okay
it's not fine that works for me now do
you want to go through the working group
draft question or wait for the comments
no I want to go whether we wish to adopt
this okay so second question is we want
to adopt this does anybody want to talk
about the adoption question anyone comes
to the mic they can say things if not
we're going to take a hug you're allowed
bring eggs to my throat admit okay okay
right and we're going to take a hung em
please and we're going to ask for two
hums and the first home will be pleased
hum when I say if you think we should
adopt this as a tsv WG working item and
the draft is not on the list so if you
want the 802 11 nothing's for diffserv
adopters are working on your part and
please some now okay I hear hums please
hum when I asked if you think this
should not be adopted the working I by
this working group at this time for any
reason if you have any reason not to
adopt it please hum now I hear no hums
against adopting this therefore I shall
take this to the working group list with
the recommendation that we consider
adoption the document will yeah and the
document will then require reviewers so
because the this documents being a
simple mapping which we've talked about
before so well we're going to call for
adoption we're also going to ask for
people who might be willing to review
this okay did anyone see Baba in the
Carter okay so Bob mrs. is to meeting
slots at the moment and next up will be
Abe this draft has been presented in
before and it's brought here because it
was discussion with our IDs about where
the best place might be to form a
discussion on this draft and since it's
an update to RSC 3168 which is a
RFC maintained by this working group
they invited the authors to come here
I'm an author but I'm just sharing at
the moment my Michael's going to the
talk over to you Michael thank you okay
yeah so the context of that is the
following sentence from 3168 it gives
context it says the dance system should
react to congestion at most once per
window of data most most once per round
trip time so it's not something we're
criticizing or changing or anything the
point is that this is a specific
contents that context that rrc 3168 sets
there are other proposals in the space
of using easy n and this is not about
them it's about this context next there
is the problematic text there is a well
the two separate paragraphs in two
different places second one is easy to
miss we missed it in the previous
version of the draft also in our
conversation so but I've seen it before
and the text the first text says that
the indication of congestion should be
treated just as a congestion loss in a
non easy incapable tcp and this means
having the congestion window that's
using a lowercase should but it's it's
seems to be a clear recommendation but
there is also another text that says
upon the receipt of an easy incapable
transport of a single seed packet the
buyer such a transport the concessions
were algorithm follow that the ancestors
must be essentially the same as the
congestion which corresponds to a single
drop packets essentially the same I
think from the other context is clear
that this means having for example for
easy and capable tcp the sources source
TTP's required to have its congestion
windows those explained here for any
window of data containing either packet
drop or an easy on indication next so
the issue here is that this rule creates
poor link utilization whenever we use
smoke use when you ecn mark at a point
in the queue or you know even if it's
the same point as loss when you do that
at the point that is way below the
pencil a product you could use
small utilization with this in
particular with modern hmm algorithms I
think this is not what we want and this
rule prevents us from utilizing the
knowledge that ecn gives us which is
that we actually have an indicator here
that the queue is not necessarily a
panel today product so therefore we
think this rule is harmful next so there
was a Dadaist is this draft that Corey
has already briefly introduced it was
the reason most recent version is called
graph cadamia alternate back off easy on
03 this draft was presented in TC p.m.
in ITF program Yokohama it was done
later discussed in icc edgy it changes
to send a reaction to easy n and it
proposes new language for this RFC 3168
this combination turned out not to be
good so we plan as a next step step to
split the draft into a PS update to our
C 3168 that just fixes these statements
that I showed you and the short draft to
recommend an appropriate congestion
response now the first thing is
underlined this means this come with
this talk here is just about this first
draft next so the question I'm asking is
whether this working group will be in
will whether there is energy and
interest in this working group in on in
adopting an up kind up coming post
standard draft that will just update the
text of RFC 3168 and to no longer
recommend that you would have liked you
would react just like you would
recollect to loss when you get an easy n
mark questions commands questions hi
oprah's cohen apologies for being late
cuz i think i've missed the slot i was
going to be talking in but answering
your question would you be opposed to
adding a bit more stuff in here to
update our esli 3168 as well i know i've
been talking with praveen
about some of the control packets that
have to not be easy and capable and
things like that and and now there's
some work needs to be done before that
they were allowed to be easy and capable
but it may be better to pile more things
into one update and have lots of little
updates I don't know but then it would
hold hand back your one I guess my
answer depends on how much it is and
what it is and we were kids per case not
not in principle of all we control
everything yeah and I'll put my chair
hats on rather than my author Hut for
that one and just say that if the
working group or adopts this then of
course the Wiccan group will have
consensus about what goes in but we
don't really want to add feature after
feature to this eventually that
documents going to have to be updated
and probably abyss issued and so we want
to try and keep it well focused but if
there's something pressing that the
wicket really feel should be changed
because it's wrong then we should do all
the corrections yeah 3168 if you went 61
9847 um don't want hi uh Brian Trammell
um yeah um just a clarifying question I
want to make sure I understand exactly
what you're trying to do with that PS
update you're basically just removing
those restrictions so is it so that
other things can be done in the envy
informational or experimental the other
document yes what's your your plan for
the other document is informational at
this point or experimental not
informational experimental probably go
um yes then do it I think it's pretty
easy to get done I would be um skeptical
of trying to say oh well we only get to
update 3168 every and moons and we have
to throw all of the stuff in there this
is not an ietf process document I think
it's a pretty easy slam dunk to just get
the thing done um so I'm definitely in
support of okay thanks alright thank you
Eric not mark this sounds useful but I
didn't quite understand why
need to split them in two separate
documents as opposed to having the PS
update update the PS as well as having
non-normative test text saying well
here's a possible algorithm that
satisfies to both constraints we will
aspire advice from the 80s arca so
there's one standing behind you he
connects ok you can probably say
whatever you think is it good or bad
idea why because there's an implementer
it's easier if it's one document that
says oh yeah you know go find it one
things you won't blow right and I
wrecked you just to be just to be clear
on on the document contents before our
Allah yo decomposes what he's going to
say and the the practice a parameter not
an algorithm so the update it proposes
to allow a range of parameters and then
the specific one is to choose a
parameter which they think is safe a
number a single so managed managed
emitting you're ready for the next two
hours and then I'm going anywhere now
what the process wise is better if you
have had two documents because one is
proposing to change too easy and the
other one is meant to be experimentally
the first place to figure out if it
really works on the white squares
attended and now I'm Dave Ted as a
designer proxy for him because he's in
Jabbar and he was writing in Java that
he would like lost class ii CN markets
in one RCT to be discussed in this
document morrison marks in one or two
teas that was sorry what was it more i
c'n maximum velocity okay okay but
that's not the just above is suggesting
to change that's different yeah mario i
wonder if there is you know
experimentation to make it proposed
standard immediately I don't understand
that the store could you speak up I
wonder if there is enough
experimentation to make it proposed
standard immediately if there is enough
experimentation to make a pee hole with
other values than 0.5 is that where you
are I mean there are several things that
may go wrong first of all the when you
are now using fly size as we are you
asleep or lost base
it works correctly when you an
inconsistent avoidance but when you are
in fast recovery there after the first
round review suit still reduce the
consistent window if you get the easy
and a call right yeah but during the
first recorded flight size is a random
number it doesn't reflect correct idea
recurrent bite size that's one thing oh
the 30 3168 was very careful making this
correct because when you are using
consciousness wind enduring the perfect
cover everything works fine okay and
second the second in east europe where
you have small window to so sub 6 MSS
window you are practically not
necessarily reducing every round window
when you get a sec an echo because minus
fifty fifty percent doesn't mean
necessarily full MSS you practice it
won't be produced in your window each
round trip as you should can I get
clarification what you d are you saying
there should be a reduction of at least
one MSS uh is that lot of something like
that i believe so there are things like
that which deserve some experimentation
before going TS in my own and you think
you can get experimental evidence for
the so you think we have to use our
engineering judgment but is that is the
reduction by one ms s something that we
can do experimentally or something for
which really need engineering judgment
so i can see the logic of discussing
this i believe you can do it okay so so
there are two ways we pick a algorithm
one because we judge it to be safe and
the other because we can measure it and
we can know that it is safe it seems
that there might be at least a case for
discussing a one MSS reduction and as an
engineering this
because we consider as a working group
that that's a safe thing to do without
necessarily doing an experimentation to
confirm it because we understand how the
congestion behavior works so I'm asking
did you feel that to verify that choice
you would actually need experimental
results or whether we perhaps could make
engineering decisions what was your
feeling more I'm not quite sure but yeah
possibly engineering is your son is
enough hmm because at least that I
believe I I can figure out what what
happens if you do it in a correct way
but there are certain cases that that
should be very carefully design so the
context is not enough that's the point
yeah okay you can even I have a question
is this what your proposed is a specific
to the reduction to enter the reaction
too easy n or what this also apply to a
lost signal partly yes so so this is
what we reaction with small windows it's
the same thing with the loss paste but
you're the first recover it's different
of course based recovery handles this
correctly there is no problem so okay
this is one of the good things about
bringing things to the ITF you can get
discussion on the topics and it's good
to receive comments and this is a chair
speaking still what we need to do is
decide whether this is a correct hope
for doing this activity and whether
whether we should do it so is there
anyone who wants to speak on again on
whether we should do this as an activity
or whether we should avoid doing this
but busca just just going back to the
history of when I actually 3168 was
written and why it was written like it
was at the time it was there was great
concern that if different TCP responded
to eating differently from the loss but
it it would create a safety problem if
you like you know that there would be
people stretching the numbers further
and further if you like and so I mean
I'm fairly well known for not worrying
too much about rape fairness but the
difficulty of getting together some text
that allows us to allow a bit of leeway
but not too much he's going to be
difficult was all I'm saying you know if
it's it and the idea of just having one
number I'm not sure it's the right idea
cuz that that's a bit too specific you
know he's trying to summarize that
that's what the bottom line this slide
says then which is find some text to set
some bones the appropriate relaxation
but don't set the number in this PS all
right yeah is that what you're saying is
okay um as a process i'm not saying
anything's okay or not okay i'm just
saying in the thought how you would
write this text in such a way that it
would be clear enough and you can find
enough but also flexible enough you know
you know that's why we have working
groups to do this work it would take
more comments while we're taking comment
I'll make a procedural note we can't
adopt a draft that isn't actually on the
table so we want you to be doing an
adoption call today so we're just doing
a discussion prior to in the future and
you draft appearing and then adoption
column but we have a working group
meeting here where a massive opinion so
please come to the back you have
opinions so we get to be picky in the
worker meeting okay um so I do have one
question and that is that I believe that
IETF 94
you had what amounted to a barb off and
we're discussing an alternative back off
proposal and um I walked away from that
I I wasn't actually able to attend I had
a conflicting thing but I walked away
from it with the idea that you had some
intellectual property do you well
somebody has some intellectual property
somebody has that is there and what what
is the status of that especially spin
tonight yep i'm not sure why it's
relevant to this but the status is it's
not being declared yet it's not
undeclared yet and that's actually okay
i assume a declaration is coming at some
point but is that going to be an issue
where are we going to be tripping over
ourselves for that no not an issue for
what Michaels trying to do here at all
actually Michael can you go to the next
slide next cuz we have the actual
practice out the previous slide Oh is
there then we have that yeah they
dropped on top is an extra slide yeah so
Michael um now just just showed up real
quick so there's ooh text and make it go
away because I actually yeah cuz so I've
actually had a look at it and um then
what but yeah I don't know no I really
really really don't if he wants it I
really don't I really don't want to have
the debate about this text yet I want to
say that we're gonna adopt it first I
want to say now that I've actually seen
the text this is a good start I think we
can quibble about the numbers a little
bit um I'd want to talk to you offline
about like where you know where the
numbers came from I think there's number
equivalent to be done here but that
should happen within the working group
and unless the new area directors are
going to make a reorganizational change
to where the ecn stuff lives then this
would be the working report right so
this is the ecn maintenance and minor
extent
working group is traditionally the ecn
we can Grissom ok trying to answer both
questions so no that's fine Brian and
I'm keen on people quibbling with stuff
and making comments here because it
indicates some energy to actually do the
work that needs to be done to get that
text just right so that's good you're me
to start growing on my mirror make you
live in turn also i'm i'm not super sure
how the text should look like this this
is not cool i know i don't want it go
into details but MC I'm just saying it's
not not that easy to get it right not
sure alright we can get it yes I agree
to jump up here and the other question
is do we need to update the draft and I
agree that what's written in the draft
is extremely confusing and should not
have been written that way but I'm still
don't know if you need to update the
draft because it's still written in a
way where it actually kind of could be
okay to do what we wanna do it update
which dropped the sorry not drive the RC
ah ok well because like any overseas 13
yo's now you have to be difficult to get
around the wrong side take the other one
oh yeah and which one do you want this
yeah sure nick sonyae so I didn't want
to be picky but this is essentially
right and just you know changing your
number from 0 point 5 to point season 7
might still essentially be the same
reaction or whatever I don't know it's
like yeah well okay and I think I didn't
say this as Nikki I'm just saying I'm
just saying I'm I understand that it
would be nice to clean it up but i'm not
sure how correct we can get it and so
i'm not sure if the update is needed but
I'm just I'm just I'm sure that's mirror
I'm sure ok so right ok so now I have to
think as a working group sure what I'm
recommending what I'm recommending is at
least people have opinions on this which
is good news and I'm I
would personally encourage that we try
and find a a document that clarifies
this point because we're going to be
working on ecn in various forms as
things go forward we keep advocating the
use of ecn I've always had a lurking
concern that if we do this then we have
to be clear about what 3168 says so I
would encourage you to resubmit the
draft and then go to the working group
and ask if they can adopt it here as a
work item to work upon and if you're
doing that please do split at the second
document because we should be discussing
the number while we're trying to get
that we could make two documents bring
it to the working group and then let's
talk about it so that's actually a good
thing i think if we can come up with the
text that actually everybody can agree
to and that totally makes sense at the
end then why not updating a right but
like even even and I I think we should
work on this so that's something I'm
sure and the point is even if we adopt
the working the document and then we
cannot come to a text that actually
makes sense we don't have to update it
it's like only if we actually can find
something that makes sense we have no
because an ad problem then at some point
we have to decide what do with the work
item but for the moment that's the
planet like that let this place make two
drafts and bring it to the working group
receives as energy yeah in this case I
would like to have more discussion
before we add a milestone you would like
one more discussion on the extra text
before we atomized stone is that mirror
as mirror or is that Marisa support your
daughter it's my personal opinion here
I'm not sure what that means it was
totally confused so I would say just
just read the draft submitted for the
group and figure out what's going and
then we can see how it ends up it was
just because of Corey was saying the
word and wise don't it was welcome
what's kind of like just just do it all
right okay so you have an action when
King do it for Michael when can you do
it for when you're going to revise the
draft I always ask this ah I mean as is
it in the next month yes something like
that
is that good enough this is a famous
link give me another one too cool once
Jeff time thank you 1.5 right fine okay
and so we've reached the end of our
agenda but we didn't we didn't get Bob
schedule so we need to go back and
showed your Bob Bob would you like to
talk about the EC entendre no easy and
over there too which is this that's fine
we all right but this is a sub turnin
around um hello oh is it ok Gary here
that's the only thing right and next one
so the purpose is to give guidelines to
protocol designers at layer 2 and tunnel
protocol designers on how to ensure he
CN is correctly put into their design
and Floyd cross-layer and we've also
been doing some liaisons with other
groups that designing layer two
protocols and systems with layering in
them to catch any systematic layering
problems with ecn with on one with the I
Triple E that's completed and very easy
and 3gb p is ongoing that's what I'm
going to talk about other reason well so
the the activity on a 3gpp one we have a
response to a liaison to them in
December they identify he asked them to
identify working groups and specs that
that reference dca they identified six
working groups and i'll put the
abbreviations there yuvika three to
compete speak and twenty spares that
reference ECA I
31-6 De Los Lagos around 66 79 which is
ACN in RTP and so next we break them all
all 20 really big space ok strictly I
search for LSU and prepare to admit to
the chairs yet and others me and John
kapiti compiling reveal who works in the
freaky BP so I've got another slide on
the other recent activity but lighter
from this graph is rated to another
legend critical trill presentation
earlier this week on that oh and that's
actually redesigning easy and supporting
drill because that changed trill and
finally there's been some discussion on
how to apply a large number for both
static on space I'm going to talk about
what a couple of slides on the first one
one on each on the vast the 3gpp liaison
context don't forget to read that
essentially it says we believe there
could be problems here it looks like
you've not may be fully understood iris
lee 3168 and that's about obviously 3168
again if we've already said is quite
unclear and just got bigger and bigger
so the context that way of talking about
is mostly go but you know the other way
station which is a lie to device and GTP
tunneled information comes in and it
goes out pptp which you pack it take to
something convergys protocols and run so
anyway next slide these are all the
specs I read
most of them are about yeah and the
poles ones are normative or they
mentioned easier normatively only mine
3gpp normative rules are different from
ITF and the italic ones the bold italic
ones sorry the normative ones were the
ones that we were told mentioned ecn
normatively and the italic ones ones I
found some normative easy and texting
but we were told ya ok so I it made a
difference in my definition of normative
to yours but they might offense insureds
other than whether there's normative
public it anyway top of a summary all
nearly all of those are about ecn in RTP
UDP and all of that stuff seemed fine it
was people it just made me realize just
how complicated mobile network is how
many boxes have to say yes we understand
ECM before he ain't going to do anything
but the ones that seem to be more
problematic for the radio access network
ones which the last two and second
column okay I've got another slide on
and also to a certain extent the third
one at the top there 23 401 on GPRS but
otherwise everything else they've fallen
apart see if you find next so the
texting the random ones you try and Andy
evolve Utah is there I've shown this
text last time but we didn't want to do
anything about it we didn't want to talk
to the 3d people about it and this until
we found maybe there are some other
texts that qualified it was something
like that but now I've seen them all I
think this is a bit efficient two
problems with it first is talking about
reading and writing the ECT
no point on a node that isn't I peer to
be idea where it's a if you went back to
that layering diagram I showed earlier
it's a layer to these the under IP node
so I think it needs to be clear or what
it means when when a NOP is reading and
writing the IP header and secondly the
mark on behavior not just the protocol
mechanisms but the behavior is very
unclear and I think that highlights a
difficulty enough having 31-6 gauges
matches where as much to blame it like
so next yeah so maybe this is the reason
why we're trying to write this document
in fact yeah yeah yeah so it's not
really quick system show the layers me
across from the leave the user equipment
and I've highlighted here some of the
protocols going on so firstly there
doesn't seem to be any spare anywhere
that refers to I've see 60 40 which says
how ACN gets propagated in tunnel and I
it must be tamil hard to have all this
GDP stuff going on that that ought to
I'm given even the level of detail at
which RTP has been specified for all the
middle policies to get it right I would
imagine also that the tunnel endpoints
have to refer to obviously 6044 there a
i hope this largely 6014 isn't clear
that it covers GTP and that's going to
be on the last slide secondly it talks
about a PDC p header which implies that
it's only thinking in the downstream
direction and downward those oubli also
introverted
investing in the app's rating when it
would be writing into the GTP italy NOP
and then when it's as easy and co point
in the PDC p as to use which are i think
it must be the easy and header inside
there but don't think edct has gotten
easier ever you want care took sam i'm
wrong but i don't think it has and so
you know there's these questions how's
it know they're particularly because
there may be a robust robust header
compression especially in this is a
voice service so the IP header inside I
not have an immediately obvious to bcn
built it may be compressed no yeah it's
I'm not sure how anyone could implement
this right so at least in theory some of
the rock mods will transport those bit
but not be visible because will be rock
compressed yeah yeah okay so we will put
this into a formal yeah because Lecter
that seems to be that seems to be
problem fair than a violent no one can
implement this or that they'll be into
non interoperable and logistics
presentations of it or whatever doesn't
see enough okay the thing I speak on
that before I move on to a trailer and
stuff Your Majesty meaning speaking as
individuals I'm not not a few GBP radio
expert so but I su bloody Rock
compressions just happening on the radio
pod from the unit B to the terminal and
that did that you know be can let's say
he's doing the compression and
decompression so he sees the bit yeah
and I think you're right and interpret
any saying that the PDC BSU is the
userland IP header interests in action
which is strangely described but I think
that's the reading I'm gear up Maya I'm
the liaison responsible from sweetie PP
towards ITF I'm also not a radio guy so
I can't help you with that but I want to
say thank you
very much for the great work at it and
for even opening dead specs like 23 or
whatever that was so that's really
impressive and thanks a lot and I hope
you get this rolling and we can maybe
talk offline them how to best push this
into the right working groups thanks a
lot excellent yeah Kevin Smith eye
definer thanks Bob think our greatest
great work and we talked about hcn could
this also scale two things up connects
for example yeah so could the work we
make a bit more generic so to speak to
say well it's not just the ecn co point
that others we should be getting access
to for this drop around so long not
extended scopus I think we're about to
publish it so I'm one of them right
through there yeah sure okay we could
take some of the thinking maybe with in
3gpp yeah thanks right there is one more
sites are about three PP which about the
Mafia well away but it's that he talks
about marking and congestion is if it's
a sort of on our state and it gives the
implications that it will then start
setting the sea bit all the time and
then when the injection finished it was
people turning off it's not absolutely
clear but if the codecs are expecting
that and that's what they respond to if
you get some congestion in a normal TV
network outside it's going to not doing
that and and so the credits could really
feel with other or we have to
standardize one which i think you it'd
be best to spend those and more
randomized behavior that is normally
make um but I don't exactly know what
intended or what anyone's implemented so
that that's a bit more difficult issue
because I know the 3gpp probably doesn't
want to spend those too much about
behavior
I think we've seen these issues talked
about before so important things to call
this house and also to reply to them and
see what the feedback is it's more about
constraints on behavior that doesn't
seem to be specified it might be
somewhere and i'm founder yeah right
next trip right trail the only reason
I'm bringing this out is this could be
quite independent but before we put the
driver I think that the draw a new mural
work improve our school but we had an
idea on how to do easy and supporting
trail that if we both really need to the
drawers as a more general case because
there's a there's a list of ideas
perhaps or ecn in there and the way
we're doing trailer is hopefully this
way when we presented this morning which
I said this is really cool if it's a
it's a really easy neat way of doing
surveys and if the reason it's cool is
because Trillo has been properly
designed for forward compatibility for
things that come along later and it's
made it really easy to do all right and
it's not yet in that draft but it will
be writing into that draft within the
next 1.5 months i believe is the current
fashion so when it's on 01 see the idea
where we can get the slides for the
session early right next is updating
some specs and this is a more processed
question we ask this on the list and lay
flat homie reply and so i'm going to
keep asking until i get require one the
the problem is that when RFC 6040 was
written and i wrote it but obviously we
all wrote it in the end the it says
but if you it was it scopus Becky
tunnels and he didn't cater for the case
where you've got an idea nike tunnel
with the shimmy in between H which can't
exist independently so it has to be put
on by the same node here as the IP
header because it's a it's definitely a
shame it's not a header and all we
really needed to do was just extend
scope just a little bit to cover all
those places and we did it so I'd like
to update as a proposed standard that
what we're talking about here is vcp and
I don't think well they'd be like I said
that any advice is that a bcp cannot
later proposed ended with a maybe the
brute is that correct probably but look
less less not less not and we're not
having that discussion here so you just
tell us what you think and then we're
going to discuss you don't work to look
a wall chair this is another another say
only proposed standard as a piece for 64
I think would be a lot better by the
cleaner so wanting to implement 6040
they don't know how to read this massive
long easy any capsulation justify this
one sec I think we need to be very clear
about tunnels in general because there's
a growing number of them and we got to
offer good advice to people making them
and I personally look to stop creating
new tunnels to keep doing things but
well I can't predict the future and then
I suspect people will steal still find
new uses for new tunnels and all the one
who's taught about tunnels is nothing
like a little mr. tunnels Eric I'm Mike
I just heard about the new one its IP /
UDP came up this week but we're getting
better at creating them faster as far as
I can tell but whether that's a good
thing or a bad thing yeah after you um I
think being able to capture sort of a
paragraph saying this is the behavior we
would want right and having that be
fairly condensed and then we can figure
out how to distribute it because some
other
when I saw the X line on this back right
so that's not a product of the idea and
it so that particular RFC is a bit
tricky right in terms of you know we can
have some other document that refers to
it saying if you doing the X client you
please do this and we'll make sure it
goes into the current set of envy or
three drafts the expand GPE etc Jodi you
right GUI but but in the current one and
in between would achieve that thought
process because the machine is putting a
PTP in a row IV editor but I think the
way around here us to say when they
don't hit or a lot of it or even if it's
assuming between this is how you
propagate emotion between and then three
GBP or the egg zactly refer to that firm
yes and that well I don't know my bcp
versus PRS but to me that sounds like
this is protocol behavior that we could
standardize right and and and where you
apply it is a separate matter but yes so
Bob without prejudicing my options would
you be willing to write an internet
draft which just catches this particular
bit of tunnel design thing as a separate
document and then we can figure out who
should read this and how we should
capture it maybe some of it you're going
to the design team activity in the
routing area maybe it should be copied
maybe to be reference maybe should be a
separate document I don't know but
having it as a separate piece of text to
start with would be a really good thing
yeah and then we could we could add
references to it from other places and
make people aware of it and if it's you
know a page to read or whatever it
should be easy yeah
most people think we're assuming that
our FC 64g applies to them and it just
clarifies if it does apply okay next
steps so yeah I will give you a response
to the for the liaison and that will go
through the approval process presume
mission I think I we the co-authors will
help you the bash there's a couple of
eating and calves habits to do and you
just asked me to do that and you draw
first so pull it there the second one
I'll just have to drill for technique
and then I'd like that if we can get
that shot up for a working group last
call or something is think it's been
around enough isn't it we've got a few
reviews down a bit yeah yeah and I'm
thinking about whether and how we know
we got to working group lost coal status
when we're trying to inform people in
other places about what's going on I
mean if if we knew that the advice was
being taken well and they were
understanding it then that would really
feel immediately jump to let's go for a
working group last call and I'll go this
is a bit of a unidirectional pipe
sometimes so and we can offer the advice
and we don't actually require a response
so let's it by bearing that in mind ask
again when you've done the edits and you
probably got any questions about the
draft apart from what we've taken
interactively the intention was always
to get this thing published so that
other people would start designing
things in the way we thought they should
be designed as in TS VW g this is advice
to the community on how to use ecn in
places where people might get it perhaps
wrong if they didn't actually think
about it carefully and my guess is
you've captured most of that so please
read this draft we'd love to see
comments on the list would look to see
notes that you've read it and that will
help us figure out whether we're after
working group last coal position how
but for the various things you've no
promised I'll make notes you'd have to
be able ambitious just tell me in real
numbers 1.5 months for everything it's a
new standard okay good 1.5 months second
right and went to the session end in
four minutes so you have four minutes
and you have a presentation this is
bringing monetary ecca semantics for
this much larger agent with Horace Lola
t a loss scalpel to those next you may
have seen just so you know which thing
remember to report for the emerging
demonstrating prize very loyal didn't
see it the idea is to incremental irre
plac best areas so that all track and
have low low and low loss and also you
can get rid of scalable it's kind of
property CP yeah it'll be so much better
it's going to get Floyd is operating
length operator to see the value they
can build new product next when we have
two minutes why don't you cut to what
you're asking a Wiccan good you look up
next the point is there a need for three
twice standardization but what about
here is the thing to classify also who
can get it right here and this is a type
of eca so what would housing is to use
the ECT one coke going to do this next
the appendix of this drawer looks at
other possibilities threea showing is
tight
yes p + sen e CA donne 0 set1 see her
point as well surely I've got trying to
explain the reasoning is all recorded in
that appendix have two other
possibilities were quickly discounted
and so basically we pick East e1 Percy
there's more green boxes and next yes
dude we come on same with the minus
whatever so putting on 68 but on the ice
is the root area to drop in sales mom
with Michael talked about her GPA has to
be the same now what would prefer to us
through here because we want to be very
little different by proposing a new you
know but not quite birthday 3168
proposing a new service and in fact in
3168 it say we have decided to make say
oasis of search issued making
differently such doc this is that 40
years on this may go even saying many
PCM look that good so what holy is
directly a stake in spray bottle bottom
but we will standardize the draw the if
a package can be drawn with the square
now the square and from the pack all the
older aquariums were designed around TCP
square little wonder that square bombing
in for the future we get rid of that
square as where it and it gives you a
long-drawn whole system which is why
we're at very low life so in order to
feel this it's a no warm rock now we
write it for previous idea didn't get a
small so pop is an extra one love tsv WG
should look up next slide yeah
yeah so kinetic says what way choosing
this will disallow preclude one thing
years it would obsolete be easier nonten
it says why because there's otherwise
doing it but we found now and also
there's very assertive in collusion with
a potentially so now this is poor to
kick pick something and we'll be
discussing what would be the best thing
to do to there and we want to avoid that
discussion right I'm finally not the sex
life yeah more next steps I next add
your next steps don't you yeah I'm not
yeah we can oh no Anastasia so I'm gonna
have to say hmm thanks at the moment
experimental but they're good cause
confusion so I'd like a baby on the list
as to whether if we proposed standard um
you know when i get review coming to
please bear that you can sell they
talked about that on the list but that's
probably a bigger than thing to consider
than just document it on the list so I'm
talk about it first please do next steps
please review there was plenty of a
discussion when we first talked about
issue on the alienware list it's been
quiet since that we assume that leads a
robbery no but and thanks for keeping
roughly two tied where we finished on
schedule all right you want to see the
last slide is she's it's for fun then
please don't ask comments on the last
slide your questions are last night no
comments I'm afraid I have to close tsb
WG and at this point and thank you all
for coming we hope to see you again
please talk about the drafts on the list
and apologies from the chairs that we
did manage to balance the Aegean
the perfect at this time we'll do a much
better job next time and look forward to
seeing you all either in virtual land or
at the next to atf meeting thank you
you