up
sky
space
skills
arm yeah this is about
I'm Houari writers and what we found
when we looked at them
Sam throughout the slights you will
you have those sections lights dad
hunting strings from the actual binaries
from just for to show
how much amusement we had looking at
those devices
Sam let's start
essentially from why don't we look at
who are we from
some love you know dad I was hacking
Cisco for over a decade
I'm that good old you never learned and
so
they actually did middle from
bed nowadays through the second-largest
telecommunications vendor worldwide
is swallowing and its so much of our
Internet infrastructure now depends on
them
dead I thought well we shall back to
take a look
on devices in you know have a PR
so when you when you look at the company
it's pretty large company did
have like over 150 thousand employees
arm
three sections our temple networks
global services and devices did
must if you probably know accuse be
sticks and stuff the Global Services
Group
arm essentially operates home many of
the networks that run along the
equipment
and we will see why the late Sarah
this is Alton this is stuff to do so you
can see them
do you have like to full product range
from
of should tackles you read by word
you know prevented from buying from
byrds
we're looking at is actually do you what
they called the data communication
equipment so the rocks
dues to major arm major branches of
from serious still and network engine
serious threats to taken psych stuff NDA
are serious
it's more like your home routers were
branch of its routers
um like smaller devices arm there's also
more we 3.com
which is another company were used to be
another company dad
was actually acquired by HP 70
from we didn't know that for a talk at
DEFCON
and from yeah had to have to find out
wide
HP people were all freaking out over us
because we're lazy we talk about what we
wear what's your problem
so they actually sheer
from some code base would worries so for
now
arm and actually already provided
testing equipment
an interesting joint venture from the
past them
whose worrisome Antec what can possibly
go from
and I'm obviously dance this joint
venture
spot exist anymore am Sam
when it comes to practice your team arm
we
you know I'm for the deaf can talk we
went to their website and try to figure
out late okay so
oh here's a link product security yeah
the country and like long boner
dad how important this is by do was not
actually
the product security visible to the
outside by now I know that they actually
have one
am bed in our big day never deal dealt
with hackers before so there was some
any from any information in following
orders come talk to publish December
security practices paper
talks about their suffering security
practice cycle arm
in solicitor not entirely sure they talk
about the same company
am Sep
as I said the security handling arm is
now
afternoon um are def come talk a little
bit more visible so
do is actually a product security
incident response team now
and there's contacts and knows BBC
if you find what we all day you cannot
to let them know
am the product security advisory
strategy is still not what I consider
industry best practice because it
provided only for customers
I actually wonder how they know who
their customers is hard because
we buy drivers is some reseller
and I don't think to keep track of you
know who buys routers
am so we were provided with arm
preview worsens of the advisories to you
to box word
will be discussing your am in PDF format
anyone else feeling funny when you get a
Chinese PDF
am sec am
you're not dead down may be morbid
movement
weird from Sam didn't do you
product security patches are not really
easy
to to tell on this offer so it's really
hard
to know if you have a viable so far not
am
and there is a uk-based why we Cyber
Security Centre dad
on according to their own statements
activity on its why we called
maybe am as you can see
by desist two days ago this is the work
in progress
so the website now how's a security
advisory sections
contents upcoming
Sam let's talk about European your be
is the first I routing platform am do
is multiple branches known and from
by now I would 'em when a clear up this
does move
about why we having storms is growing
less
man no body parts shipped Cisco is happy
if they can compile it for their own
machines
so it it was very unlikely from the
start
so according to Cisco's League arm
documents am the problems in school had
mostly was dad the Enhanced IGRP code
was
heartbeat but im including box
them and someone react to try to make
this your life
command line interface look the same way
as Cisco some people would not need to
learn new shit
I'm unfortunately some lame house
been decided 10 that no means did
documentation actually looks like
our documentation copycat so
dad apparently was the only good from am
in its own settle so what we deal with
today is your P three and five
Witcher VX real I am weeks work space
from respectively three in five the
ex-works
from according to from some messages I
received from where we
d DVR p5 is a large refried
am and we will see about that am I've
also seen references to have your p
aid but I have absolutely no idea what
it is
Sam when you when you find file it looks
like this
two sons force which so you have to
platform did you have to be RP
in this case 52 52 and then some
digits and numbers generally don't make
sense
in Enders also from different names that
you can find itself around so
for OEM's it's called home where and
sometimes it's called VXL as
and you know I'm him different names
sound thanks to you to you two brilliant
from man age 21 I actually have some
solid eight up on
from how diversions a distributed so you
can see Dad
5.5 is by far to most use worsen
23 serious it's also still around
and then I grouped am today die
half which is like a hundred thirty's I
wasn't IP addresses
plus worsen information arm
into did equipment and what you will see
is
home did more to switchers because
gonna to you then it switches am what
you see then
is its all large-scale tackling
equipments
thinks that filled an entire rack
um that is because DVD financial
difference the cost difference between
large sis Commission March worry machine
is the greatest so shoes the incentive
buying is because d quit minted costs
you shitload of money
suddenly gets significantly cheaper
answer
%um it's good for the bottom line India
in the stock market good
and everything else there is so good for
mankind
am some when %um when you wanna do you
wouldn't with a writer's wave
what you're looking at is standard
interfaces that every router Housley
command line interface through SSH
Telnet console
web-based configuration netcom as an MP
tenders some weird stuff by d
branch intelligent management system
bins
from n if you're determined sums really
funny
am SEM and this is actually
arm laker client-side system so you can
triggered
by DHCP and then it goes out to you be
pimps
server I am the only 1i could find a
factory made by HP
in and gets additional configuration
settings
my are different DNS server
whatever the language settings for
tissue
ard you considers to Chinese or English
in here comes the reason why everyone
house why would people operator
track because Deepak functionality if
you ever to set up a network that is
bigger than one writer
you know that you need two documents you
know debug ID sex barred
executive reports so in order to do that
you turn on debug commands
but you don't see shit because there are
only available in Chinese
that's pretty good strategy if you're
selling professional services acting
so once your im in a speaks English to
you
am you find from you find
couple levels of hidden commands the
most important is
underscore and a score back to you gets
you
into developer commands are quite useful
for
Export Development and then depending on
a platform
you half you know special diagnosis
commands to duty wanna password
always try to vendor name vendor name is
usually one
with passwords so in this case once more
with
Freecom
when we look at dimensions
you can download em actually from from
the website do some
authorization process involved I have no
idea how that works because I don't have
legal account
am so essentially in order to get to the
image is the easiest way is simply by
runners because default configuration to
come up would
have to pee sir and you can instantly
have to be damaged
and in your you have the image Sam
that's what we did because it's not
illegal
am and and you look at the image format
to hackers in indeed image formats
differ greatly between platforms
its it's actually fun game it usually
takes just a couple of hours to
first formant am but it's really
interesting
from I was wondering if to maybe have an
internal competition
on creativity in you know handling of
Fine Arts
so when you didn't you
would you have is different archive
formats all look alike
from home Chan builds grandchildren of
top
ride do ralph reed worsens hard some way
or the other
we haven't found any cryptographic
protections
which doesn't mean that there are none
from
I just haven't seen Ford for really
small devices you get one binary
out to be good advice gets the more
stuff in cinders
like to any from in forty like to be
tapping machines
the load 256 different find some
different
reports arm para pc what have you
also decompression algorithms from
greatly Mary
energy anyone remember AG from the 90's
really love using energy we have seen
7-zip deflated what's really funny
outside ass am because we couldn't
conference
summer after summer images in really
didn't find decompression coat
I'm to know from my coworker Greg points
other
welp disc you speaks IP sec
so it needs to do decompression so maybe
that's what they use
some point for well I have my key
compression implemented I could use that
for the images
come can be done fight so when you on
Pacha
some of those archives have descriptions
to the individual files
dis is like to dance
third column here it's that description
as actually in file
so you see that their developers are as
lazy as someone else
because they didn't put any description
some
and you see that you have variety of
interesting stuff
in there so
am in terms of hardware this is all
power PC based
said this morn boxes from you're 18
Aidan that type stuff am
a pretty similar to shared memory
routers um
from Cisco or anyone else right tunes
you know little and then it device add
bigger ones
are more mike d Biggar our platforms
modular from Saudi to carry
additional code for chipsets in
and yes am and what have you and and be
platforms actually really interesting
arm
an I'm gonna look into them more because
the user ID empower
NP network processors do classification
encapsulation
that type of stuff in hardware and get
programmed in
decal code which and whatever does
in peace then dude gets handed over to
the application Cebu
this is how you get performances to use
isn't very smart design for their backs
but it gets more complicated to bigger
box
sim what default service to wear usually
by default with the with the smaller
boxes like
with OtterBox you have as age enough to
be open
would two small boxes you also have HTTP
I'm for what management based management
you often see town it's XLT
is very common interesting some
branches of Europe's also automatically
load
arm h323 codes and open like 10 ports
from what can possibly go from and
its age 323 is really easy to parse
from them fired at home am
the the functionality that you can
disable default services
is relatively new so even into you from
in the security advisories that we saw
am 44 older platforms
actually from older customers to use
ACLs to block traffic to port 80
because you can turn off towards
and as I said bins -ism his client some
government good quality
am you find a shitload every
implementations front instead
we actually don't use in the century
anymore so
from everyone seems to have their own
implementation of men copy
do is variations of string copied or
really interesting
from and so for example the number of
calls to sprint half need to reassess
function is actually a linear function
over device price so bigger damaging
mourns products so 42 for small
34 European weird talking ten thousand
calls to sprint F
the next bigger one house 16,000
your pee 5.5 can be every right
was apparently refried done with the
same coding practices
because it has 27,000 sprint off caps
and Asda the main image am
X Server is refried so
that's really great I can it took us
decayed to get ok message right
from and we're still not sure about from
reef writing it is not really a good
idea especially
give like you SSH in this is 4v mp3
just failed to test it for five am
yes age in in Europe as a stage Klein
says no
I'm not gonna talk two distinct because
slide
RC models is too small so you actually
have to force it
to even connect
and then you now am the knowledge
which united in our page in memory which
is fairly
important for not point to the
references and some more stuff
it's not just mapped its retried execute
mapped
someone was really nice to hackers
so let's look at Dean what management
interface
so and desist this is %um 13 come as you
can see him
not much difference this is how it looks
like
home in Chinese obviously I'm and you
can't switch to English spent I wanted
to show how Chinese
books on this pretty nice am
and actually only works in Internet
Explorer somewhere Shinzo vereb your
actually it doesn't work at all so my
you get fragments of JavaScript
am it has a session ID cards user ID
that session ID is 4 bytes long one of
them is ignored
one of them is fixed
one of them counts two concurrent
session and the last one comes
cell am that is
pretty much as predictable as it gets am
so if someone is already locked into the
router
you can as well obviously which gives
you
director for administration control and
this is me stealing
the configuration from rod am
yeah but if you have what management you
also
I think of guys you referenced your said
you also have arm the web server right
Sam web server am
tries to determine right in the
beginning before logging before
everything else
am whether it be resource you're asking
for
is something that you need one of those
complicates matters for
so it happens all the web content
as a file so the of his way to do it
would you to take to the fine
from mmm dictionary
and see you know which fighter in there
if it's one of those files
a given out for free otherwise what 12
session ID no
some what they do is the serious string
compare functions
and if it turns out to be resource Ted
is probably not requiring any
authentication
and do you are now gets copied into a
bath
that one is on stack and it is too small
so we have a very classic State baseball
for overflow
am any of those will work
am weekend pretty much direct
from control of a shitload of registers
and double stack everything that's right
here
am so that's really nice back to play
around
same the only thing you need is a time
targets when we come to
from obviously we can't use my by its
this being a string copy am Anders
United image pays small bites Poisson's
we can truly Ustad am for him
for the purpose of the exercise you
reduced the image dependent
an we simply reviews a few
move to can reduce the branch to can
reduce their
instruction sequence that we find
somewhere in the count
you know return oriented program for
kids
said should come to only one sequence
from
and then we are many checkup right
Sam some
for dish codes from one was nice enough
to provide
a pair of functions dad
have no privilege tech involved and
execute whatever you give them
as an argument directly as if you were
locked in
would for administrative privileges on
the ground am
does pretty useful I mean functions are
I'm did addresses of those functions are
image to Penn am
however funnily enough I couple you
expect I Broughton
and published arm dissembling show code
for Cisco dad disassembled to code in
memory and fines two functions
by building strong references am
that works for you because they're both
you can help you see
and so I'm if you wanna be image
independent
am do some of my earlier mark said the
strategy essentially for exploitation
is we do some blacks were encoding to
get rid of all by tissues and spaces and
other things the fuck up HTTP
week we do code is all inline and
home you know sent a command sequence
and this is a big man sequence to
said a password for the administrator
and then
being my host use I wanna see weathered
is worked or not
right come and that's optional could you
need for
it's really not that complicated I mean
home
very almost BC from PowerPC exploitation
if you've ever done PowerPC exploitation
on all to make books
this is exactly the same thing Sam
you know you play some tricks with the
instruction encoding
to for example to housings to get rid of
home issues with the cash it's and an
you know
you iterate over to commence
just that looks like %um do
Sen Durex DB request you gonna echo
request them
sent back a reply from new talent into
the machine
you get so
am now stack overflows
are easy we wanted to also see how he
performs from
work where you keep corruptions am so we
started
two more for fun abilities home then our
you overflows it is very difficult
because everything you find stickers
perform
so after long searching we found two
spins client
and I find it interesting because
client-side exploitation grab this is
pretty rare thing
answer my coworker dracula an mom
how to actually exploiters so the
viability is pretty straightforward
been scoring is actually an HTTP client
am
so what does is it since on request
with the funny statement this is gonna
take less than 10 minutes
I don't know how fast the Internet in
China as per 10 minutes for an HTTP
requests
reducing am Sam
wanted to stand is it takes the header
that gets back takes the content-length
provided by web server
trust and advocates from
memory accordingly interestingly enough
it already has stayed in hand
namely to Hatter which used and copied
into different
so we provide the size of my cock and
we provide to dade overflows pretty
straightforward
now the only thing we need to do am
is we have to look at the allocator
am when you look at alligator and
disassembly
becomes quickly cleared disses from
discipline allocator because there's
like six numbers
and then our that are compared and
Anders different free lists
in use lists and stuff
cell arm you look at you
d allocation and see what would sanity
checks where we have in their
am dues some magic numbers
from there's a pointer to allocate a
structure
and so on um in
then you look at the free and to free
actually
goes to Howard in does a straightforward
point exchange
som on this is how you the trampled look
like
do some do tank entered in the pointer
from
dan you set it up war if it's a free
block
dues additional data that manages free
blocks
very typically play out from from the
90's
so am as I said it's been telecommuters
each been has its own free list from
these this structured PG each structure
um house a pointer to the respective
list
an malloc essentially I'm
then if it takes I want block out after
fruitless
essentially again just takes the first
block and performs porn exchange
are which gives you opportunity memory
right if you provided
2.6 so
its cool DMN talk arm weekend
reviews for a car to goldstein we
haven't looked had
yours from so
we simply over right am committed you
know of a free tank
in when the next ranks now locked in
everything is fine right Sam
just to illustrate this is how it would
look like would
would free box and
we take some assumptions on on the size
which we can because we can control it
and you know arm when a block bomb is
now locked
it is taken out of two free first and
then
am WEM in when
free am when it is free damn can be
knocked again in year weekends our
control because we can write some well
you into some
important piece of memory two weeks
don't have to determine
there's a couple things to take care of
obviously
Sam we have to make sure that the sanity
checks go through
but as you have seen they're not very
extensive compared to you
what mark explain City on
iPhone heap this is really simple this
is really predictable
cell um the the next question is like
how do we make to the heap
army out some more predictable
so we're looking at different bins one
been turns out to be 512 bytes
am and you know we can allocate
more of dole's so we can feel to you
and essentially massage away
to he play our dentist the way we want
from luckily enough every time you make
a TCP connection to
such a device that allocates 512 bytes
for control structure
so this is how you control do you
allocation remotely
am due to strict two parts
am now I'm we'd we need a couple of
mattresses
from dead you know we predict from
and that usually doesn't work too well
pictures
there's dues lot of variety in
images even for why we it's not as bad
as it is with Cisco
perhaps you know having a target listen
hard coded pointers
a chance stocks from Greg decided to
make it even more
and reliable as he said in actually try
to keep spraying
on the device so from
in due to the nature of that back it's
really really easy to use play
am because you know you you provide to
contemplate and you provide to date on
so using multiple connections from
you can just esprit de entirety am
Warren dinner other strategies suppliers
well ride
if you have a memory leak or whatever
then you know you can you start
and Anders to question what would be
effort from
that would again be a much dependent so
if we weren't
try to patch the code word right into
some data structure whatever
from Baudouin from remembered that I
sent it did not pitch
from is mapped so
tomorrow page contains PowerPC interrupt
handler routines
I remember in MS DOS days you had to
interrupt vector table
we always have to modifying order to
right code nigga want me to find right
signatures for
am bad is similar
however on RPC you actually have to code
out in those places so I'm you have 256
bytes
space per interrupt to hang
am and so we can essentially just
right somewhere there
now we have to choose an interim we
could use something that is triggered by
timing
from however dues also do you do
interrupted gets triggered for
arm invalid memory access you have I'm
and sons were fucking around with you
you quite a lot
this might be you know good place to
start
Sam is since argued
is pretty much guaranteed to cause a
crash soon or later
we just fight or chrome from directly
into to interrupt handler
home in you know it gets triggered by
itself
some to see said once we have cut
execution
we can clean up to keep if we want to
from
do whatever we want and then you know
exit in for a tender
another good thing in a scene from 10 so
we don't get to corrupt
that is awesome and
this is the system d exploited Greg
fraud
it is called the visitor because wind
turbines point activates did
we'll see now visiting the BIM server am
Sam this is the visitor and is begin
gives you can execution
I'm executing after complaints
now some we come to you do you
question dead is always given around
from when to talk about what we
United first question is always actors
Sam
to speak to save you time asking
is what it is am it is very often
claimed
want me back doors every devices and
then the Chinese government can read on
your email
in which all your porn as if they don't
have their own
am in
so far nobody has actually discovered
back doors in hardware
your in the your peacoat
seriously given to supply your fine
abilities
in to you relative ease of exploitation
I don't see why you need one am
you know it's it's a question of
interpretation right so
so even Anders senior VP said what they
have been common factors are actually
box in our software
perfect deniability right Sam
from actually would so many carriers
having
operator networks I would be more
concerned about the network management
systems
and to you remote access to them and
everything that comes after
use arabs you don't need to break into
something that you have the root
password for
right which uses operations is the case
that sent
from when I looked at the bootloaders
I'm between two string password and
password
I found funny-looking strengths here and
say no
by definition of a back toward the
hidden method of bypassing on a computer
a vindication systems dat pretty much
fit the bill
so would you see to ride is a very very
streets
operation sir what we have here is
am so what we talk about your is the
bootloader password
right so what we have here is a use and
provides
gans the password is stored in flash and
a string compare
if that worked if that didn't work
it takes the user input and extreme in
his keys
807 home BSP string compare
if worked also got
in mind that's what the victorious
now what does give you that back door to
the house
from bootloader password is important if
you deploy
machines outside of the premises begins
well Yukon selects in order to get to
in when %um when you have no bootloader
password you can
interrupted your you can say well
without configuration
an app gives you access to committee am
altered his passwords is also use do to
fix password is also used
when you reset the password ask for your
password
damn you can also use that fix password
for
am and that's really useful if you buy
used to our equipment there that
actually had
password set and United dissenter
fail to recognize that you know you two
passwords
am if you buy a used one week whitman
1/2 dose am
so we're we're still collecting them
from I'm not entirely sure who
supplement his
from and yet its
it's interesting because they're did not
document
obviously and we're still collecting for
for other platforms but
murders ard pack differently as I
mentioned with images
sound that kinda sucks am
get some perspective on this so this the
specter only works locally or on through
termin summer
if you have a terminus around someone
gets to determine its summer
you're fucked so you can load to be
reviewed image
without conflagration then changed
password for example
reboot the machine with configuration
and urine
Sam if you have equipment deployed
your premises not
it ought to be noted distractors
of having vendor backdoor passwords is
nothing you need for
what we PCB bias is used to have that
for a long time
other vendors to dad are famous Siemens
in Germany
ads probably more back to password
sternem regular ones
under equipment am in all their daughter
companies as well
from however begins of you know dis be
network equipment and usually
deployed all around to place there's
really good reason that Cisco at some
point introduced
no service password recovery which is
exactly dad
it to say boards the possibility to get
into drum
include a machine without countries
something to consider
and already brings me to print version
some so Europe ya Q suffers
from ninety Starbucks in
respective exploitation from Sam doctor
from they seem to be ramping a product
security now
but see when it counts from the current
state of our research
you know you never know it's a lot
account but the current stage
instead the fear of government factories
is
pretty much exactly gated from however
anything local access is on the van
right now
make everyone can read include a code
and find a string compares
in with that um I would like to two
times
and come if you now
if you're concerned about juror juror
network security now because you're
running
recruitment don't yell at your network
people
for use your fellow that's the guy who
made a decision to buy district
okay thank you any questions
this
sleep