for this
space
on basically the things that
I'm good to talk about here this is like
a joint research between me in phnom
a friend of mine in Russia I'll let the
american arm
limit works for up a big company where
he manages to seem like a lot of traffic
are not not an ISP but the also
up we get like a lot of visibility
a on russian cybercrime basically
through the looks he captures
plus saw we get some traffic for ordered
from
Russia and I'll explain it
in a little bit what but anyway arm
I roughly have like three sections and
representation
arm the point representation basically
is I'll to show like what the situation
was cybercrime
like or like unlawful or like
and ethical interactivity is in like
ex-soviet union area is as of like this
year
arm to liken pregnant talking about
stuff someone
I'm trying not to cover two things that
appealing
talking about before and arm have a
couple
text running are basically systems that
rebuilding
I'm still are trying to graduate
basically a my
PhD student in are in the newer steamed
I once I need like
interesting topics to write papers on so
are we have like
up basically are have two projects which
we
are working on I'll
was the objective on eradicating like
some of the problems that we seeing so
nooo just walk through this project
um are if you've seen
I'll this morning sold by our
full week she arm than up
this point like this part would be likes
roughly a related to what he was talking
about cuz we also do like
in this traffic analysis and stuff and
anyway
arm a brief like
I'll introduction what's going on in
russia
like some to certain extent its spreads
sought to the west as well
but there are certain limitations like
the reason why for example we're not
seeing much of this kind of acuity
if you connect the same site I liked the
same you're all the same web sites
are from Russia a is because a lot of
criminalist due to happen through the
by their networks like advertisement
that works and buy another as they
waited
re: ghost so I'll we not even being
redirected to the malicious advertisers
if we are with it particular
our resources from like taiwan is hong
kong like Malaysian IP addresses
so on what we do we have like be pinched
are was in points in up in russia
like proxies so in order to connect some
some other statistics arm but I'll
still basically like what missus like
big thing and
arm in particular was like botnets lol
arm
there was some outbreak of like p2p is
like based algorithms for the
apartments I'll nothing like a year ago
but what we're seeing a lot this year is
basically
up on like that what what does that make
you look at what that is basically like
a piece of software
which somehow ends up on our arm
a bunch of computers and this somehow
could be like can exploit
or could be a social engineering tricks
no-show couple 3d is where you can see
I'll were will see that like it
other and exploitation of target system
like
technical exploding on ability is now is
not the only means and
actually is not one of the most common
way so far
getting to control but basically solely
a
you end up having like banja I'll are so
for instance running on
up those computers and they basically
called back
so in order to like so that the person
who orchestrated the whole thing would
be able to
I'll are conduct the machines so
other communication between the a
machine and
the arm like so-called like C&C
going to control books is like one of
the essential components so
was getting big this year's are arguing
the main
are what that control channels and
the resource that we doing is basically
up aiming at detecting did
part of things infrastructure I'll well
should be more details in a bit arm one
of the reasons why
like other kind of like crime missed you
I'll keeps the kennel promised you like
where originally bases not because
its more difficult to compromise
machines in the US or like
more difficult to compromise machines
and i won and actually like
when you compromised machines as a part
of the botnet like that for at least two
happens
but one of the reasons is because once
you
arm infected machines unit you like me
the reason why people do this is like
for money
and once you in Fig machines you have to
like me monetize it somehow
and the limitation is basically the in
manipulation schemes
and was in russia's like Wat user like
if you have someone for number
it's way easier to make people to
transfer money to you or next to money
by just saw either infecting the are the
mobile phone
or using other schemes that in wolf
mobile for
select mobile phone is basically getting
one of the main
medium so fund transfer
but I'll like driver download is like
not only like don't like
I can people like our notion this year
quite a bit
is I'll like more its look like I wanna
go like
targeted email spam but it's more like
of for example
are website I which is
among accountants gets compromised and
then
arm the database of the
users wasn't that website's get dumped
and then there's that up
%uh this list of email addresses gets
spammed
was an XE file and contend that is
specific to the accountants
it would be like an account in
conference so like which in this league
outbreak and basically
arm once email gets executed like the
panel it could be like
are wary but I what we've seen months
ago basically they would be inevitable
that just get %ah starts running I look
for all the like PowerPoint
PDF I were documents uploaded to the FTP
site
and this affectionate like this attacks
cuming
is very similar to what we've seen I
think your health like
problem was two years you go one the
same see nothing was sent to like
by 25 use government the official
dresses
was a cop are congratulations it was
like I'm on Christmas so there was like
congratulations from Obama that you
needed a good work for the country
please see this postcard an executable
so I think like
the only problem was like use it is like
to use a dumb whatever you send them
if they reckon is likely to meet if it
comes from like Obama or if it comes
from a
account what side they gonna run it so I
think say is like
with all this legal business and stuff
it's not even the point of fixing
like technical flaws because like the
problem is like fixing
the like mind over videos and home
yet people still the hot stuff and
basically the tendency that we see this
your dad like mobile platform
is like becomes a lucrative target
we haven't seen much of the exploitation
going on are the worse
are mobile phones & what is a mobile
phones want to see this year's most
Android platforms are and I think like
that there is it
a reason for his kids like it's more
like open its easier to
sneak a pic Asian arm
Google is doing some are analysis on the
on the supplications but
motion paper I think by Terry Miller as
well on
are like there are so many ways to
basically up by
bypass on books on it is a hundred
applications and
others just like budget like fake
applications that are
was getting installed on our mobile
phone either subscribe the user to
particular there was an L
also like one of the examples here or to
simply start like
thinking offered which is the Primus
missus like this thing is
likes sort of getting duplicated because
like many platforms that equally
confirmation
our vision for like all old versions of
mobile phones though the league games
which like
get union would have licked licking okay
like so you play the game
and as you start playing the game that
was Arbys are sending is missus
but we don't see that up this kind of
games this much in Android platforms
so that like there are other rectors
so all on this is like a screenshot from
%ah blackballed Chu
up they can like be with 23 days ago
also like this I think pretty fresh
just to give you a visibility on are was
what gets exploited in their own it and
how
so this is like a 36 from mom off from
an exploit pic and you can see that like
eyebrows arched you like being most
popular
so what we do here is like browsers
number of like browsers loaded on on our
on this exploit pic number of like
unique IP addresses
and once exploit is successful
it features an executable in executable
calls back like
yeah I'm I got executed so this is like
number of like
successful call back so you can see like
that I used to like
holding the first place there's like
Firefox there's opera
this from their Safari and what he will
not is that like most other brother gets
exploited
like regardless of are the security
features but if you start looking at the
what exploits were used in the attack I
think this like opportune for me that
this was like Joe a
and Oracle a bit a big favor are
i think im I'll months ago when it took
him quite a bit you %ah
fix publicly up released on ability so
you can see like most other stuff
and I think this like Joey just like
very convenient
like multiplatform I'll to browser milem
I'll do whatever
like there's still some mom PDF stuff
happening but like
that's about it then in terms of like
platforms you can see that like
it's mostly I'm Windows machines
so I'll the main components that like
this is basically the crime so the main
companies a are
people haveing in order to orchestrate
dislike this kind of like malicious
attacks
you'll see a is a C&C or like
the machine that usually it would be a
CNC plus an explosion machine
and usually it's close to the same
infrastructure it would have different
domain names
because domain names get blacklisted and
up
and the domain name they would be using
to connect to see if she would bill
I picked a different from the the main
in the cervix put back
but I pity it's the same infrastructure
so one of the things that we want to be
able to find
automatically alexei mathematically is
like where all this like to see
seems user and be arm one of the leak
movie mechanisms of awe
and the growing economies extra traffic
so if people
i'm not respecting those web sites with
expert picks
nothing happens but let's don't don't
get built on
they don't get infrastructure the don't
get
are stolen credentials for them get
quick cars the don't
show stuff to users user don't be money
and I'll economy doesn't work
so I think the KU the K like working for
some the whole thing is
is traffic so you can see you'll see arm
the a lot of arm online abuse like from
the spam
you like %uh search engine optimization
like
black-and-white happens with a single
point of getting
traffic to particular web sites and
10 the like what a common things is arm
flick how many people in this from run
for president bill ok
one to you well apparently not so
popular but
if you if you took if you take in a
virtual up
user who wants to be known through the
internet
like I think it's like 90 percent of
them would they would probably be
running WordPress just because
like its a it's like one of the default
options when you
when you buy hosting be just so easy to
run
and its wanna be like most compromise
publications
so on what was basically happening is
arm bustle web sites like artwork Press
West commerce opts open X is actually
pretty
particular interesting thing because its
arm up next is I'll I'll if you want to
run your own
like me by noon serving at work was in
your
arm are your website
you get Google run like open XO and then
you can interconnect was a
other are by their networks but the
thing is open next
used to have like someone you up bed all
abilities were you can like
you can have admin control the thing and
then once you have control over the
database you can basically stark
injecting malicious scripts into the
thing be you can compromise the
open next year we're told and let's
order soon as well
and either you like are Lord
in about your moto which like this thing
gets likely difficult to find
his no files no files on the filesystem
get changed
except for lookin additional Apache
models being
loaded into arm Apache web server
and every time the like the text group
has been served its Bing search was a
pending
are JavaScript that a are
redirects stuff to the infrastructure
and when I'm
talking about infrastructure it will not
be mystery and exploit back right away
because
arm in Dresden like this the situation
is like a bit more
complicated up the people who
a paid to bring traffic to particular
sources they pay to bring traffic to are
two TDs
traffic distribution systems and people
who build what minutes they buying
I'll stop from the tedious but anyway up
so basically compromised machines is is
one of the like
arm key components are in bringing
traffic
so we want to be able to I'll rapidly
quickly
I'll at large-scale identify which
machines could be compromised
like maybe I in a scriptable way and
thats also like that one of the
prerequisites for like in %uh one on the
project which I'll be showing here
up by their networks like I think this
like very difficult
Hillis starting from the point arm the
better look at
asthma network itself is very
complicated and it's very dynamic
so the the way and it has been rendered
depends on your IP address on your
could be could depend on your cookie on
your time zone a
are which are is disclosed by up
while web browser heaters and even if
you thought the same
your old twice you it's like you cannot
entered the same
the same river twice like the thing
always moves and because there's like
this
they namic beating arm it's very
difficult basically to trace malicious
conduct
content in binder networks and I'll be
showing what want to be due to my
examples were
up we can see are one of the things
I'll like by their network like money
should monitor connection
another thing is up dependency that we
see happening in russia that there are
shouldn't buy new networks like guys
went agencies which like
on the legal side that you taking offers
for advertisements
and looking for publishers to place
their banners but the sole purpose of
those companies
optics East is to distribute Mauer
and the weighted op the whole thing
would be happening like
on the first round of the page are
you'll be sure from exploit back
are every Asian of exploit back
all and all on the all the consequential
are in there so the same page like based
on the cookie
are you Bashar regularly call up and
with that
advertising and up content and
the what what is like getting difficult
for its like injury company
but the thing is they distributing our
book if you start
E if you basically start up trying to
persecute them
on it's not worth the effort because
like
are there were like certain cases wanted
to say I'll our machines were compromise
and there's like
no proof that the redirection to exploit
back
have actually any links I'll
with this company was exception of
statistics 0
when when we run ascend books Lake
100 times and roll was it like fresh in
our own with the first AP
we we get get my word sure every time
but other than this and this been going
on for like a year
but other than this kind of like
statistics there is no
like obvious proof and like this this
kind of statistical proof doesn't work
well in court
and this also like the reason why I
disco politics
so arm arm what I've been doing like
before
are we were like building like our
behavior-based are
analysis platform for Mauer so been
looking into this thing for maybe like
couple of years right now but what's
good different like this year
is up they said those guys this for
another
effort on ARM on preventing automated
detection
and well the point when things get
difficult is
when malicious behavior only exhibit
itself
in like behavior analysis model are only
when
there is a human interaction like this
is like one of the simple example
but we've seen they would be like arm
the JavaScript
other the direction of only happen when
there is like a mouth moment
and this kind of thing like if you if
you know the like doing this kind of
stuff
this kind of thing is like real easy to
simulate important you can just like
community must warn
but arm like their critique creativity
doesn't stop here
what are the things that you'll
frequently see is up
like a pop a boner done was like did
JavaScript
inches was a click click here and
if you don't have like what's your
recognition system
that would recognize that like user is
mature waited to click here
then you will not be able to be able to
you
%ah make the like particular website too
exhibit malicious behavior and hes like
most other like internet monitoring
arm systems are working like what we did
it my previous company but
I don't like other companies which like
they did basically the same way
you wish you could have like a sandbox
farm the continually kroll slick
internet
renders it in in real brother and then
you'd like have Petters
on detecting malicious behavior but like
this kind of thing doesn't like always
work
so arm in this case I think the the best
option is
to have some sort of like many touring
mortal in the browser
which would notify arm
headquarters when they were like part
are whenever
malicious behavior was detected but then
you have to make
users to agree to split gonna stop and
so on
but like nothing that arm would you like
a love this year
arm when it is it like the matches
monetization scheme
are there used to be like a prime SMS is
full like used a lot
are Bob years before but like
as a this year like you don't see this
kind of stuff that much but subscription
to you
a complaint pro like content is like 10
the are big thing to know I'll be shown
in the video that like
there so in like social engineering
tricks which being used
are to get people to subscribe to
particular content are other thing
arm know also that this thing on DVD as
well like just where to direct
arm your computer has been locked
I hear the phone number send me like
2,000 rubles
I'll send you a lot caught your you
would be able to use the San all should
in a moment but the thing is in Russia
in order to have like
mobile phone the only thing that you
need is a popular passport
which is also available for like five
dollars per copy
and in one hand so that technically if
you want to have absolutely anonymous
phone number li that's where it would be
possible
and then what you do you have like a
phone number you make people like
sending you money
and periodically you got Utah the telco
and you can
are you can say I don't want this number
anymore I one catch or you can like
transfer your balance
other number and click can work together
but their ways of converting your phone
number Bella do cash arm
nothing that we see up as well like did
distinguished taken directly from %ah
arm
an Android application were up
on there is a called the Gateway were
together
arm numbers are SummerSlam
were to get the numbers to sent this
message do but
that's like one other thing that we see
as well
like mobile scams like with what to look
for a couple occasions
I think this year like it's a big one
this like one of the examples like
Opera Mini which is are
arm it used to be like on law
up market is wall are you can also
download directly from like %ah
this particular website like some song
blocked 325
are you which support to be an
application distribution worked for up
arm I'll for some some like mobile
phones
but if you start looking into the cause
like Arctic
a unicorn you one thing which will
notice like is
most of the arm joke what is like skated
like if you see
arm like we could be compiled the stuff
on if you see it like most of the
classes they basically
are being loaded dynamically so doing
likes thick
analysis on this gonna publications I
would say would be very difficult
and I think that we've seen are on
Android application is basically
there's like multi-stage lot so arm
application that gets
loaded through the app market right away
is some
cleanup ligation with doesn't have any
malicious function was
X exception for that it a Lowes
user to install updates and the
malicious payload would be like
wasn't update and the thing is like out
with this kind of model we like so
difficult
if you'd like to hear are not as good
you have to be able to simulate
real user using the application in order
to trigger
update mechanism and then yeah gets
difficult
but then nothing which is interesting is
actually haldeman is a sure thing is
happening here
so basically um
E in russia like there's a way to become
a content provider so anyone can become
a content provider
if I have particular content I can go to
telecom I can
arm arm I get and I D
and arm document for the API and the way
it works
through this API I sent a mobile phone
number to the telecom
and I can also specify right like the
content of the estimates which will get
sent to the up disarm of mobile phone
owner and then arm the pellicle will
send a confirmation code
to this mobile phone owner so a son the
mobile phone or near provides me with
the
arm the confirmation code number I
through the API I can send this
confirmation go to the telecom
and I if the confirmation code is
correct I can subscribe user
on content which technically means I can
build issues are like
in this particular case like 300
rubles which is like so didn't get per
months
arm I'm on
on a limited period of time so unless
user discover that skews been subscribed
to the content
and apps apps unsubscribe like I'll be
like new key
and this kind of abuses like very
widespread
arm telecoms I think telecoms in this
situation dick
they sort of like on on both sites on
one side there's like
supposed to be protecting their users
but on the other side
more users pay Mo Money telecoms gets
all they make
like they have bit in order to show user
that they actually
like good guys they have requirement in
the API specification that
whenever someone installs an application
which of Christ you look at the content
there should be a statement saying that
you will be built
and the amount of money an actual I can
do for you particular application there
is a statement
arm if you look at into the applications
through Android phone
just like some HTML content the dish
shows to the user
and just what it basically say that
though the application is still
but if you start looking to HTML code
arm
there is there is actually a notice
saying that itself up
paid for our content and that's how much
your you gonna be built
and what you will notice your is up
that dick this content is being
displayed displayed was a
on style on so it's not for being shown
arm when the application is actually
being installed
and that is how like the malicious
applications find disc
this balance 0 on one hand that you
provided information
on the other hand the user who saw the
application doesn't see but the
requirement
is that by the telecom is that they
should be the statement
the requirement doesn't say that should
be visible to the end user
and dynamic lot of stuff like this
so arm I think like a creeper couple of
reduce
I'll last week at to russia so are
we just recorded like arm read if you
experiment so
one thing which we did we went to the
young bucks office
and Yandex is basically a Russian Google
sort of thing it's like
biggest %uh search engine to do are
mal were not as though the basically
whatever Google Docs gender doesn't hold
it does have Google Maps
arm so we did a couple experiments arm
a arm look at least of our
up binder networks which we know that
are they serve malicious content and arm
everywhere I'll we were running like
arson books
environment soda i can text that works
even
would get infected and under like
ninety-nine percent of like occasions we
would not be served
any malicious content and there is a
reason for this and
the reason is that all the young the
tape addresses that was in the Black
Keys
arm I'll probably start the video so we
can
I'm not very good
so basically arm what also others to our
of things that like you will notice
that the guys up arm like to stay with
the guys that they can in order to
provide
31 automated analysis so what are the
things is on
you know there's a particular euro and
are
it will also malicious content through
the banner
what are the things that up we got it
just think that you're a new diaper
directly to the browser
you will not be sure my work I think
it's
that again yet but
are so basically you have to to find
that web site through search engine and
that's what we are
up gonna do here I'll
star DVD a and also like I'll
okay
will
so basically pretension on on ARM on the
process lives here
so you'll feel like up what arm yeah
I'll probably go back so good
some other you
up
a look
so basically up pay attention on this
thing so this is likely for the
processes we just saw
up last are like though proxy
and like a the process monitor so you
can see what's happening
and on so on
what this website is basically all and
mom like medicine
trading like website so long sure will
order the
in search engine like we young pics here
because
up like that so Russian search engine
but like pretty much
don't text Google being like any search
engine
as a sinus the search engine is in the
river the malicious content will be
serve and what will happen here like we
basically just click on
arm like online medicine
website so the trick happen and start
paying attention on
on the process least hopes so
are what we see here already like this
is also like a blackhole exploit back
it launches the Java exploit you can see
Joe is being loaded
arm operate is being executed
the good thing about are up
this particular job on an ability that
it's a where the reliable
home there's like and there is no impact
on the
VM what you will see it at this point so
at this point these guys already
compromised
so you consider executable being started
and in this particular are like
the type of it I'm basically people who
corn exploit pics in people who run who
up all the executable some usually like
two different
group of people so up and the way it
works
arm the share was are people call
who ride I'll this executables dictated
by cher was from the
are like exploit back owners or
addiction expert like itself is also
like paid for sure was
so you can basically say I want to
disturb it is binary through this
exploit back
and through this up %ah tedious traffic
and like did this particular website
are either he's compromised or I
YouTube on your network that so are the
also
traffic too tedious so um was the binary
is being executed
are this guy basically like continue
shopping but
arm %uh there's particular delay here
before
his machine gets locked and arm
I was showing it'll in a slight drizzle
are
yesil let's get to the delays in like
technically nothing happens because like
this like the guys basically just like
candy is browsing and
there's just are a particular style
sleep time before the machine gets
locked so
what happens at this point are the
machine gets locked
and in order to get the unlock code you
have to like
are the balance transfer to this phone
number that the the thing which was
showing
and on the probability of like
catching this is like up
extremely high cuz like up the key word
that we were using for to
search engine is is just online like
shock for me to sing like
up one of the like popular key works
and like this is just like an example
above said they're like
a bunch of them cuz what the thing it
here is that the conflict is not being
served
through this website the content is
being sure through the banner network
that
uses this website as a advertisement but
for
and I'll show
arm another example where they actually
has
we were running the whole thing on om
their job auction in this example
and arm just and other
are arm opener online like worry
also like this kind of content if you
like we did experiments were rendered
full like Hong Kong Taiwan IP addresses
you not being said served a malicious
content and
are that's also the reason why like in
young dicks or
in Google or in being you will not see
this content
arm being marked as like malicious
because
day limit distribution like the target
distribution
only to the IP addresses which they
believe they can cash in and
are also dodi's only particular time of
the day so for example
in Russia people start surfing web
during the lunch break
when they can go online and start
reading news and arm
so this up on your network which you um
let's get to the website
so on
forget I'll basically get to the library
arm
and are better so on like the cold like
I desert ok are it's about a network
which will display advertisements here
so um aidid the teaser don't buy network
like technically I'm I'll believe that
the sole purpose of setting up this I
don't Eisman company
or dip on your network ease to
distribute mahler
but the reason why this to you can
protect your like
as the running Lidgerwood businesses
because a malicious content
only showed once per IP op per cookie
be the content the malicious content is
only sure do in particular time of the
day
so I don't like nighttime with a body
like and these people are sleeping
or and other the rest of the world is
not
relevant because saw don't distribute
the content to particular IP addresses
and be up lunch
so and what you'll see here use like
very similar thing it's also like
arm Joe exploit you can see the like Joe
adjustable was started
then up does the whole process of
dropping an executable actually happens
in two steps
so the Java exploit will fix the loader
the purpose of the law order is to be
able to execute on multiple number of
platforms
so Windows XP Windows 2k our windows
8 up and then the laudable fish the
actual
payload was a use a full content
and are in this particular case arm
their job but binary had go you can see
the
arm there is a binary star Dirk
here the Pioneer had dog your
fertilization addiction salon
executed like on all nope court which
other VirtualBox generated saw crash
and this is basically the whole thing
just like to print ultimate analysis
but nothing which I want to show here is
you want go
arm this thing is over the money issues
because he was sure through this website
automatically executed in our machine
start arm if you like due to
antivirus scan for this thing I'll
probably just skip directly to the
and you are
so basically what we do every we went to
our struggle right away
got the binary up a little I'll refer to
website
and you can see like are right now we
like
on that is a scan
happening like in it takes some time
and you can see the dick detection rate
of the the binary like
was your out of luck with you 41
underwater singer
and that's basically the like the
reality order
cybercrime thing happening in russia
like on most dangerous is that like
people have installed on their computers
that like technically useless arm
another thing which I want to show you
on
i think im overspending my time one
this thing instead of west lies with
like I'll just
briefly show our another video
on demonization think
and this thing like we basically just
recorded like yesterday
us to projective it's the same thing on
you go to like live so you fight it
through the search engine but in this
case
are they not bother like trying to
install any by noon you
what I will see here you so
I'll just keep directed to the content I
think
so one thing like there's an offer to
download updates
to an offer don't put on what update for
up
was your brother and that's like the
whole thing is obviously fake
but up how this thing gets monetized
one flaw there's an offer to you like up
download an update arm you start alarm
the whole like the whole process is
stimulated with JavaScript in your
browser
and that there is a pop-up window are in
order to like
complete update please do was up the
phone number and
like information got and what will
happen in this case
is there's like there is no malicious
payload there is no executable
it just the whole thing just like pure
social engineering so what will happen
in this case
your entered and up the phone number SMS
will get get sent
are to this number are the user enters
the
up subscription code like
the durations like it you can see one is
like the update another one isn't your
thing
but basically the mechanism the same you
entered the code to get subscribe to the
arm to the content
so that's basically like on like
if you like ok arm the common thread
that you'll you'll see was the like
cybercrime are in Russia in
I'll just go back to my size and I'll
show you I'll
what else we doing with this stuff
so on what we basically trying to arm
built here is arm two projects
one is are we trying to be I'll ultimate
detection of the C&C
once machines get infected and and
nothing that we do we tried to
ultimate detection of Rick targets
and have some automated notification
mechanism
for the Rick target owners before of
questions get compromised
so basically we're trying to pay are
killed infrastructure
and be killed up like the week
week about the rebel targets for the so
one other thing that we do is up
are we do %uh C&C are
arm 16 CR other difficult issue
for the I'll DNS traffic analysis
this morning there was like a tow
compressive DNS if you were the doctor
probably know what preceded missus
if not in short we have an ISP that
sense
up every get us back at the troll
through that it is over
descent a copy of the picket Ross are
and
on we do %uh processing of that stuff so
our
input is basically Guinness packets one
thing which on
are technically you don't have to
actually a
have your aunt Eunice connectors was I
see the dorky
you can get access to draw traffic but
I'll one thing which
you'll be missing their is in order to
do notebook that correlation you also
want to see
are IP addresses of the machines which
looked up this particular the mains
in addition to like what the mainstay
looked up what was the result of the
look up and so on and up um
I see they have this %ah our privacy
policy so they're not giving up
away the IP addresses of are the
machines which I were looking up to
the domain names and that's one of the
reasons why we decided to build
are on basic do nothing arm
and was a spike over are generated the
mains that's like
one of the common ways for the botnets
you are call back and find their
control center but that's not the only
one
I don't think anyone recognize what's on
on this growing in an hour
it's like a twitter-like social network
very popular in
asia-pacific but like that like another
way like we've seen
this year as well arm basically they're
like
in court up posts on like teacher like
playing
which is basically all a reference to a
sincere
address but we're not looking into this
thing
so on if you start looking a bit road
traffic
no traffic goodwill will look like this
I will have like a bunch of are doing
this
Aquarius was al- up
our responses which other would-be up
nonexistent the main which like orkut
get aspect or our names there were frail
which will be like three
and then only a few are the main through
wasn't a
similar group would return like
successfully returned IP address
and our detection mechanism is basically
all based on this principle so
ever tried to identified this kind of
nice
and grew by that the brain similarity
from the dog in this traffic
be up we're trying to identify
arm like 813 identified the group like
the cluster
be were trying to identify IP addresses
which my
your so we have like links for the
infrastructure and
us since we have like preserved are are
preserved in is that are based
we can do up back in force look up on a
vacancy
so for this IP address I what were the
minute you seem like
week ago or like so far for our which
ever pointed to this IP address and then
we can basically start
recourse if a recursive mining of the
infrastructure this way
and arm I'll just show like a couple of
our
screech of are one of the like but thats
which was like popular this year
September almost like cock Arbor arm
typical distribution is like drive-by
arm
I have their growing waistlines like but
I think it's like
well up where'er
on komen for for like the stuff that I
was shoving on the media that basically
of one of the few examples and I'll just
give directly to the
to the detection saw roughly like work
arc
architecture looks like we have and ISP
in Russia
which agreed to send us all there DNS
traffic we have a collector
at the collector point we do some
filtering do some
one of the things we shoot which you
will notice when you get are a lot of
DNS traffic
there's a lot of real we are interested
really likes to the starting point it's
failed craters
but there's a lot of for it quarters for
like in other other
RP look up quick reverse lookups there
are also a lot of
like Phil quarters for some of
hard-coded
domain names for like either particular
software wonders
or like chrome you just saw randomly
generated domain names
and on the collector point we basically
doing this fifteen
so we can minimize the vote on the rest
of the infrastructure
arm the rest of the infrastructure is
basically built on
three russians sleep like it's not like
Big Data sort of Leon is is but
and we clustered it would like to
integrate data by
the POC so we have a definition that
like for example are ready for his like
2-3 days and then we on with which to in
your arm
read his file and then we week arm also
do
historical indexing so we can see we can
sit have quitters like
foot show me which domain names ever
were pointing to this particular IP
address
and like that kind of stuff is being
done in arm
analyzer so what do we do on indexing
for
all I real time porque indexing reuse
I read this up for all historical
are breakers were you seen and machine
is basically running as a
arm like plus away so we have like
several policy asshole or not
and wish our data between them and
analyzer basically is capable of doing
are request into both things and I think
that we
arm that we are capable of
up what that we have in our arm system
is
lets you quise lookup because one of the
things we which we notice this year
a up by mining patterns through
who he's dating you arm you can
there's basically way so far like aural
exciters
that you can apply to identify
potentially malicious domain names
even before the being used so like what
are the types of things that we know it
is a
the mood for gestational but I prickly
one-year arm
only particular registers are often
being used by
arm botnet musters so we have like to
set of senator that we may have to
bequeath
there is also a problem with the co I
was quitting quiz data
a because it's %uh human readable text
so
in art there's like it so difficult to
do automatic parsing
so we just have like regular expressions
for whose data another problem with
wheeze data is
arm like for DNS traffic we just click
Post to press release
so there is no limitation on the
on the bottom but was the quiz data I'll
the biggest problem is if you if you do
ball clock up on the quiz you can just
get blocked
so the solution at three we have so far
we have like round-robin quiz proxy so
we can
arm balance are like we've
look up so deformations and be um
our quiz lookup is like lazy are with
we've done it in the lazy form so are
what we do is
if you wanna the main we were trying to
do who is look up arm
component the quiz logo lookup confident
control the threshold of
are how many we saw requests per second
we can do without being blocked
and then official whose information and
reported into
arm are ready stock component as well
and one other things was that like the
one of the reasons why
we believe it's necessary if you do like
a real time our
malicious the main analysis is to fish
with information because
the behavior that we noticed this year
and I'll I have some date on this
is some other quiz data is life only for
like 30 minutes
and the reason for this I'll like fall
for the bad guy
that's where like handy feature because
like the main Texas on the internet
space for 30 minutes
was the winner of it like disappears
from the internet
so if you didn't catch it at the moment
when the main was in use
you don't have any information you don't
you don't you know which reduced our
the main was the biggest through up
you don't have any black you don't have
any leads to the actual identity
so other sure like a quick arm
walkthrough like this spring this whole
process automated
but if you were doing it step by step
arm you can just
directly connect or like Greg you saw
indexer
and you quoted the domain names
whichever similar arm
distribution was in the EPL so any
you'll notice that like
this particular group the maze with
particular pattern and where similar
distribution here
and in this case we have the main switch
our name servers are frail
which means like most other the main
aims where registered at one point of
time
so they were already used by Mauer and
either the good scene called
or are disabled or like abuse complaint
was filled in
but the more interesting thing is you
can also get the distribution for a
domain names
which are a nonexistent and the reason
why I think
like this is where useful beautiful
information
is if you want to take over the botnet
all you have to do is
you take like 11 USD
go to like the cheapest register
available regard to start is the main
aim
install the shoes the software on the
machine and the bookstore connecting to
you
and like that's like super cheap
legal and effortless so anyway like what
once you get the better of like
arm either like non-existent domain for
failed the mains
what we do we arm as the wind s
DNS pickets come in once we done all the
children begin to rate
we tried to cluster the way similarity
so once were up
once we index the cluster domain names
we have like
group of group for the movies which we
can start looking up by
by cluster number looks so I want to see
the main aim Group
which matches this group so um
and in Vegas we basically broken into
like three fields
so you have the man in question id: and
are Erica so we can
like look up things quickly so then we
will pick up like the cluster
on arm bill are like close are you to
that
we believe might belong to the botnet
and we get the Holy starved of matching
that the mains included
the main switch either like fail
pictures that and current
and also dislike big fish you actually
get to see
on shouldn't arm DNS packets which were
which at the moment when your morning
during are
which were successful and return IP
addresses from
and that's what I'm sure you here and
from this point you can actually start
doing
recourse if look up for the whole thing
and what we notices you want to like the
main aims were fresh
some other the right the miners did were
not registered on the winners were
failed
but if you google for this domain names
you'll find nothing
are they not in any triggers but if you
start looking by IP address which
these words are true belongs to you will
see other autonomous system or
in this particular case used up IP
address directly or what makes them
multiple triggers something this like
from semantic this is from the party
will trigger
and the same IP address foot like their
penises
as you should which cost in for starter
the don't change much but like the
domain names
of fluctuate a lot and from this point
because we were able to provide the
least
of the domain names which may
potentially be used by attacker
we can generate like a up on-the-fly
senators for the traffic monitoring
and we can like want them when the way
look up a successful
there would be a lot of like up ship
record for this euros which is
basically go back to the seen ceasing
and and nothing which which comes handy
when you
do this kind of like a corset lookup you
start was like
picking up randomly give you a domain
name is based on similarity and
and the noise at the CRI India's traffic
but you can also find a
at one point of time there were like
some the main switch which look what did
you read
all for example style of god yes that's
like just a Russian work
and there is no way if you are just like
analyzing the maze like this
there's no way you would pick this one
out or like LeBron closer look net
or legume Rd my Ltd which was showing
here
again you can see it one other
interesting things that like from
are like this do not you can see the
lifetime for each particular the main is
only like up to five minutes so the
mains have greater schork
life span and unless you like are able
to do like real time detection
there is no way you can do like if you
pick it up from the box and start like
writing your like final booking looks in
the evening
by the time domain is not in use anymore
and that's but also the reason why we
have so many
arm failed names are a family cap so
once the means were disposed there are
two ways a
I will should like the restricted the
main just disappears
and be out the name servers will be
pointing to like lou back or
are in case if if that the way to a sink
all that will be pointing to
like cop Conficker sync all I Peters
and sought so wants you to the
automation Richard able to do like
this is basically the gruff but Tom
withdrew from the outperform like our
automation script
and if you do in bed with you hollick
it'll be interesting closer would look
like so you have like
a bunch of the main aims ritually
basically pointing to
more or less all up either the same IP
address ok it could be dangerous with
the same
chic sick last summer and that's like an
hour detections group we can
like have all the slick ball that we can
whether we want to be fixed for
particular IP address
because it's still like try and there
are sort of thing in some cases are
in some for some IP ranges the whole
c-class could be malicious
and me up in this group would you that
we
we want to look up for all the domain
names that point to the same c-class
in some cases will be a single IP is
showed a screenshot
so are and I think through like we're
playing around
Russian business network apprentice to
active like
the traffic that we get start collecting
traffic from last year jewel now
so and you still see the up IP addresses
like if u
look into your ok where there's a
reference to it that belongs to
on like but was local RBN
in terms of law like for it's a a small
well reducing disp in arm
in Russia whole and in terms of what we
only get like around
2000 packets per second like not that
much so
um the initial collector we only have
like 30 to Dec so from
and be able to like and older
all so this like roughly like how much
biggest for dairy receive arm good
a model the like militias the main its
roughly like well all those were the
ones who are like
love them but but other things all since
it's like an irregular means we can see
actually the tendency of like recurring
I'll
look up so for your particular domains
there would be up to like
saw 100 lookups like we're currently so
if you want to my like unique aw
demands for mean it like that de verge
we get
and how can you use like this data
obvious like you can runtime: you know
it but was that you can book on
firewalls
yeah thing a ma I'm running of time so I
want to finish this
are nothing you can let's start doing
like a book that's in Corning taking
over the botnets
arm like other stuff as well
this isn't like one of the interesting
things like for sale I'll ask you a
question there may be a up
I'll explain 10 things which we start
like noticing this year
is there's a number of the main switch
jobs also used as a CNC for the botnets
and the way they look like you just put
a concatenated works
but what's special about this domain is
not like you in the zone where the
register but
I'll if the main is currently being in
use for you can actually see 289 DNS
traffic
you look it up you get the dinners data
but if like
if you start looking up like an hour are
after the the main aim is a
like not appearing in DNS traffic
anymore just get up
the mayor on like we've not found how is
this possible
like good for us we'll initiative we
didn't have like a clear answer to this
later we talk to one of the biggest
erson he pointed us to one of the
lick possible ways but like we believe
probably like 10 the registers was
compromised
but I'll nothing but like what are the
biggest your cell attract attention on
is a you can actually have like if you
buy are shoes in the shop right so you
can
take the shoes you can try them on if
you don't have it wasn't like seven days
you can return the shoes
the same thing you're going to do with
domain names and that's what
I think that's the future the guys
figure out what particular registers
so you can take the men on trial you can
use it for 30 minutes
and then you can you can cancel the
order and want to cancel the order
are the information like one other
things like how to pick up the went on
trial is
but the money will be like up in Queens
up with a would-be
in ut period which means the mean was
just purchased
and then was in the trial period of time
they can return to the main
like automatically with the script this
this whole thing is done like were
descriptive like
was in the day that could be like over
300 domain names and I don't think it's
possible to you
like do the whole thing min early you
can cancel the transaction
it's gonna cost you roughly like if
you'd the win in court like eleven
dollars
you bitch to charge like roughly a
dollar but for a dollar you get
disposable domain name
which leaves no trace from the internet
so if you didn't catch this thing
when the main was active there is
nothing
saw this is basically on the Guinness
face detection
arm nothing that we do we also do like
proactive
network scanning per region very similar
QR
what up and I was showing our last year
arm our basic risk any particular
religious
of IP addresses for server sis and soft
or running the dispersions and indexing
this
we like also used for producing and very
sticky like
you can scan the whole wheat bread like
this like some 36 from a paper was in
like
100 they say it's technically possible
to have it database
but was in arm 100 days H
can index like share with us on all
Internet for us we don't we don't
we're not he doesn't in the internet per
se but yet more interesting
graphically focused IP range just like
was can't I want to risk in China arm
was tore all the data on info database
and one of the things like bill bill
items which are universities
SN with the owner of dinner of the
network or the IP address
which country belongs to are you think
your IP location right now which is not
very precise but
we also lookup up get the location of
particular IP address
and we do some application
fingerprinting for if there is a web
we are some replication fingerprinting
too so we can up
basically fire equator saying I wants
you
all the people running arm
all oil skimmers of particular worsen
was in Taipei City
and like with this verified database
like that's where
possible well just like rough air
architecture
arm like we have a UI but would like we
don't really use it
you I just if you wanna see from your
data is entered
but basically you can are we have also
API that were conscripted
on lovers for repair work in query
IP addresses way any combination of like
software regex
are like I so far been a regex at and
get a graphical occasion
and ass and and and this happens like
immediately so if you want you know like
people running arm volatile weather
channel 4
op de la Cruz in Taipei City like it's
like really like less than a second you
have that is the day progresses
and then this guy whole thing you can
basically like one of the you just like
you can automate your script of like
once a new warm is been announced for
like
particular well plication your car you
can automate you screw that will
just Fitch all the people running this
particular version of honorable thing
and said automated up warning messages
but there's like a lot of other things
if you doing
been testing you can say show me alder
although vulnerable boss commercial
installations
that belonged to malaysian telecom and
it's like a second query
saw nothing I'm roughly out of time so
but if you have time for questions but
if you do
yeah like to have some
weekend extended we could coffee break
right now
if you have questions we weekend doing
that during the coffee break
but I do have to say we are starting at
4 o'clock with the next presentation so
or if you brought like Rotten Tomatoes
shoes you can start rolling them as well
any questions any tomatoes
so you know they have questions we can
have coffee alright well
what you want farm if you have questions
later
that's hard to find me thanks
thank you very much cuter
ok
this
sleep