up
space
school
skills
thank you this like psychic
okay so a little back to be working as a
lawyer for
four-and-a-half years now easy mostly
focused on building security and privacy
features
in a big car that for me as being
developing
the Firefox OS security model so this is
probably going to be a pretty dance
presentation cuz I mean
no West cover a lot of stuff right so
all jump right in
I'm something we start with we talk
about Firefox OS
are you know what are the principles
what are the most important things you
wanna designed a system from the
beginning
and then how do we determine that we
actually met our goals
so we said I was going to protect the US
from malicious at
a compromise aP's you want to protect
caps from each other
because otherwise developers have a you
a whole lotta work
on we only wish you use private data
with
user consent so the user has to be
involved in decisions that
at impact their data a
some Creek definitions so Firefox OS
is related to Flos also if you heard BTG
those that are internal codename for
what became Firefox OS
so if you confuse that's all the same
thing
so Firefox persistent
consists of a stack have layers liked in
each row s
it's actually a bunch of different stuff
so underlying everything is what we call
gone
which is on the 8th the the basic Linux
operating system and all the hardware
abstraction
so it's it's what a scare the radio
interfaces the video the audio
I'm storage US P E Bluetooth
all the local stuff a on top of that is
gecko
which is the core runtime that that
drives Firefox Thunderbird
FETAC gianna is what we call our you eye
layers
it's all the visible you why it's all
CSS and JavaScript
shemale somewhat better but your app's
and abs are all once again CSS a single
JavaScript
so guy is
the user interface for Firefox OS it's
also interface
model its 10 laps go through they talk
to the user like dialogues are all in
guy
for example system dollars permission
lol Center as part of a guy a have a
buncha perhaps these are
built exactly the same with third party
apps are built so
the system at the home screen app all
core abs
Tyler sms/email camera music it's at our
are all written CSS AC Milan JavaScript
the
only way they talk to the OS is through
all the funny PI's
its ok echo supports a Sat APR exposed
to different classes applications
as the only way any app can talk to the
US and
in this model obviously we support
third-party apps
so developers can write absence to lapse
and they are
essentially other than the permission
bits are exactly the same as as the app
spun wool
on the phone so below guy is ghetto
break echo is the engine and we say
echo is exactly the same engine we are
putting into Firefox
so a lot of the stuff they were building
in Firefox OS
is actually in Cork echo and knows
exactly the same code
that we ship with Firefox test of their
worship with Firefox
mobile and that we ship in Thunderbird
other produce these gecko
so we're not branching echoing are
creating a whole new platform for
Firefox OS rush
reusing have extending its what this the
Slayer
so this includes all of the
the HTML CSS JavaScript engines
although I'll OS abstraction
stuff that I mentioned earlier like
maybe your eyes when we think about
developing Web API to expose
access to contacts for example or
to you for a geolocation or a bunch
other
if he has a going to we think that we
think I've how to do that across the
whole
stacked with the Great Wall if and
develop a context if your house is a
behavior on mobile has a bf on desktop
kids behave
on Android we have Firefox rendering so
initially Kong
is the very lowest layer raises all the
hardware abstraction
so the next colonel on its most to you
existing open source of further using
we're not inventing
we're not writing off on you colonel
already a hole in you
abstraction layer there's no need to
and so when you think I've gone in our
model
its the underlying OS that is
targeted by gecko right so you can build
gecko
for Mac OS you can build
for a sec to rate you can build echo for
Windows
different versions of Windows you can
build it for Android which is what
sendak does on Android and you can now
build it for
conch
and we are going to a lot of details
about third-party apps but
as I mentioned they're all the same
they're all CSS AC Milan JavaScript
so the type so that's in the world right
if you think a
the kinds applications that exist
there's web sites web sites really are
applications
like whether gmail or group are
or air BnB you or whatever
their complex for applications that
happen to be hosted
on a server below the code when it runs
it runs on a client
it just gets not install but it gets
delivered dynamic
every time you visit the site love it
runs on the client
lover and the server
and so it's not a stretch to bookmark
for those things and say well
nyren application on my device
that so much of a stretch to take some
the code that would normally be
delivered from the server every time
and persistent locally on your device
see you have to go we fetch the same
interface over and over again
its space be cashing it just explicit
Cassie with guarantees that
icon to will be there when you come back
and then there's no reason you can use
all those abs new computers while in use
in
right exactly same application the same
language the same content
says a picture motorcycle because it
carries a cool just in case you're
wondering
no other reason but we're developing
applications
we one those applications to run in
Firefox OS
want to run in where party which is our
run time for Android
so if you get an apt for PDGF Android
phone you can choose to run the same app
on your Android phone we have away party
installed
and for desktop run it's a map in
Firefox in a dust-up
so for Firefox OS
an hour apart from this basically we
think Ive
four kinds of applications right when I
guess that is just
web content a website running in your
browser is an application
it doesn't persist but if you take an
application
that's on a Web site and book market
your home page
as far as the user device is concerned
it's an application even there really is
just a link to a website
I'll so the next iPad application is
a website where developer the website
as explicitly chosen to have it be
treated as an application right in our
case in our model it is really creating
a manifest manifest as a file that
points to you
something says describes a location
application
the next door work is over calling a
privileged happens approves after more
similar to what you use to for example
with existing
a mobile operating systems so it's an
explicit bundle of stuff
right as access more API's as code
signing
as certain guarantees and properties at
the web doesn't have
because I have in general doesn't do the
great
really the world's best Java preventing
code injection for example
by default it's pretty easy right axis
as is just code injection
yes have certified up so if I taps are
core parts of the operating system
necessary for its correct functioning
so to go deeper
when we think I've designing with API's
you think I've design each AP any way
they can expose
as much as possible to interesting
content
right so say we want to design an API
for having access to
your location or your camera whatever
your we think first
how could be safe exposes to web content
and then you know there's some
properties about that are interesting
for example for camera you might wanna
exposed web content might have to be opt
in for every use
remain on to persist ability for an
arbitrary web site have access to your
camera
every time you get slower in some iframe
because maybe that's not really a great
model
but see safer web sites maybe we'll
expose
camera access only through some explicit
user often every time
but maybe if it's going to be. a
different an application if you have a
different access model to the camera
going to turn the moment
so jump work on them by the folk we
don't remember decisions you make if
your website you wanna give it your
location unit
I give it access your camera or or your
contacts
that decision is not persisted next time
you go back to that side
you'll have to ask again if you was have
access to your camera your contacts your
location
you can override that but that's the
fault state
when we take website in turn it in to
install the application
we don't really wanna change the
security properties because the
underlying federal has really changed
right like
that that say could still have excess
bugs
it still be delivered over plain text
you could have
service I injection issues and other
crazy stuff
i mean the cervical just be really
poorly configured to be easy on anybody
owns a server obviously owns
the application so
when we make website an application we
don't granted
much additional privilege merely all we
do is we give it a little bit if you
like candy
right we can see go fullscreen about
asking because these has chosen to
install use an application expects you
to use a city full screen
um henry give you the ability to store a
bit more data than you normally would
for rent a website is there any website
like you just visit some website you
really want to stir up into the air
but if you chose to install something
you've said have imply that this
something you wanna keep using
in you are willing to grant a little bit
more leeway in storage
um so we can access the same thing that
regular web sites can access
can repress actions location sensor
API's K
alarm API FM radio
sir privilege applications are different
for this application is
come in a zip file nom they have their
own ski
ap Colin scheme they have a constant
security policies
so if given her cunt is very policy
should read up on it
it's something that we came up with
essentially for its core purpose
was to address code injection attacks
so it's a way for developer to
declaratively to define a policy
that controls were cooking come from
that disables inline script disable was
a or restricts
loading love script files from only
specific
locations so use this in
a rat model to essentially change the
properties approves applications
to you preventing any cogeneration
so what happens is that you can load
JavaScript
from assets they came in the zip file
basically
a few total to do a scripture siegel's
from another server it won't work
we try to do in a valve archery data it
won't work
no window set I'm at work a new function
and obviously this distrust disrupt some
parents before Houston development but
those aren't we have
et cetera documentation a building that
the demonstrates how to work around it
so these are not in
insurmountable issues but I give you
some really nice properties you can now
say that
because that is running its application
is definitely the cody came in a zip
file
those deficits aim so that you reviewed
and approved
in the App Store and so because that you
can granted some more privileged because
if you use it makes the trust decision
to trust this particular application
with axes this API you know next time
you run the application
you running exactly the same code UN
before
and echoed is not trivial to inject code
into so therefore there isn't some other
third-party
running inside you can trust so this
means
they can have access persist in access
to high risk API's like alarm API
they can do raw TCP raw sockets I have
persistent access to contacts API
device to your GP I a browser API which
are going to bed
wifi information API I'll
and is also detail about how these are
made available taps that
I'll go to in a few size because it's
not that every app just has access to
all these things
so certified apso really very small soda
maps
these are things that are essential to
the operating systems correct
functioning
so it's tough like a dialer it is
vs an asset it is the Settings app is
the contacts
these are things that need to work
and they need certain API's
in order for the device to work so we
don't ask the user
we don't prompt the user about whether
or not a surfeit applications have
access to the API's that it needs
because for example if you ask the user
with the Settings app should have access
the settings API and they say no
you have a broken device if you
ask the user with the phone app should
have access to tell if a knee
you now have a broken telephone if they
say no
so these are things that from don't ask
for permission
which is also why is a very small said
about said what we do not want this to
be a common use case
this is only for things are essential to
the device correct functioning
as a lot of them you can see that it's
tough to bility to launch and manage
back on services
its direct access to the SMS API to the
telephony API
Bluetooth connection settings power
management et cetera et cetera Center
so weird about how data is managed so
each application has its own data store
this includes cookies right so
I'll is has a nice properties one of
them is that
you we can keep track of all the data at
the apt
creates an rights to the device say
means
when you wanna either legal that a road
to the the application we can guarantee
you can delete all the corresponding
data
the app created it also means that
cookies are separate from app to app
so they do not sure the one cookie store
so an app that loads an iframe from site
a
and have a different set a cookie is in
a different app that loads and I frame
from site
this is you know it's it's it's a
decision
we made design decision we decided to
favor privacy over
use cases that was that would be better
for having a shake with the store
at than those in turn result in coming
Ling
that makes it impossible to actually
told what ap what cookies
this when you want to leave now
segment apso launched in this device
so abscam me started on you 11 number
ways mister by the user directly
by clicking on a nap on they can be
launched
by the system it's one other there lived
a privileged API's
a certified API's at the system that has
access to
they can be launched by web activities
alarm API application API
so web activities which I have
almost lies on later web activities are
ways that app scan of into handling
certain things
writes an app to say I handle PDS
if you click on a PDF in some peace in
an app says
have this PDF but I don't do PF I want
this to open as PDF in something you
know fire
where activity say open a PDF an app's
on the device is a registered to open
pts
through activities can is a I'll take
your
right side so we have launched an app
with a specific PC data
but a nap has to choose to participate
in that model
and to choose to consume no specific
kinds of activities
alarm API is maybe a bit of a misnomer
I alarm it does not like an alarm clock
API
alarm API is away for an apt to say
wake me up in a certain time have to do
something
right so this is it away an app can do
polling inside to wake itself up every
hour to do something go back to sleep
but that is we have launched you know
write the app is choosing to be launched
at a certain time
notification API a something similar in
a sense that
you might have indication that comes in
about a
a to a push notification rate so your
app has received a message in a cousin
to the notification bar
and uses ogo gonna go take your this may
click on the notification
notification bar that'll launch the app
to handle the notification
to ease you can't launch an application
wanna cannot launch another
sap a canned salmon launch p directly
only through web activities if the if
they know that
at p consumes a certain activity they
want it
passed to it they can launch an app
directly
and even though its Web Content you
can't actually launch another
she can't buy frame yes you can say
iframe
source equals ap colon slash slash
insured here we don't support that
an app's closing them is pretty simple
you too close indirectly
using a task list or
the OS will secure laps as it sees fit
as resources become scarce
so the way to to get a deeper is the way
that we actually implement this is that
the system app launches abs
inside have what we call on moesha frame
I'm
so only a system that can create these
kinds iframes he creates a separate
data jar so some essentially means is
that there's
tradition the browser and ap
is defined by an origin I do me we've
extended that model
to save that not only can origin create
a domain but also
an app I D can create a dummy so
when you when a system that creates this
iframe
moesha my friend is basic reading you
don't need a new context for now
an apt
run inside a constant process right
they're not actually privilege processes
and the profs the privileges as
processes have
are commensurate to the ATI have access
to
but no more your service
other kids second kind of special iframe
it's called a MAS browser
so this is for aP's that
intend to behave like a browser right
there to navigate the content on to
provide
you wanna probably provide were
displayed lots a different kind to
conserve the user that may not be really
design
the consummate be designed to be iraq
that app specifically
so this allow those the
at using most browsers have a little
more control than normally would over
overnight free and I finale of Glee you
can't see it happening it's okay
I'm in this case there's a couple
changes one is that
child when asked which we know that I'll
gets its own window back it doesn't get
the parent window
which is normally would happen the
browser if you have any browser you have
a window
they create an iframe and iframe
wants to know what the windows out top
is will actually get the parents
this case as far as the child is
concerned it is the top is no idea its
fame by something
and also allows that the the parent to
have a little more visibility what's
happening so can handle events
but we're loading redirecting et cetera
us to present its duties
is use a comedic effect user certain
browsers stay
related to what the the child process a
child frame is doing
was a pretty bad graphic attempting just
display this is a imagine that they are
on the outer
border here are the winner is a system
right and so it's decided to you
I launch an actual third party app
call casar com and that embeds
and I framed it also suffering cats are
in this case
they have the same cookie store workers
are in the same app in the same to me
but if there's
if if in return that actually uses
a must press right frame the most
browser
because it behaves like a browser will
create a separate editor for that so the
the cookies and all the data that is
stored to be treated separately sorry we
spent
for the book but I mean one thing that
was interesting at this process is
my ghost designers in the public domain
so if you know why we came decisions we
came to about the camera repair for
example
there is a 120 email thread you can read
on missile it have b2g
about how we came decisions around the
camera Commission model
we spent a lotta time designing in
discussing how to build the Commission
monica is really
or what manifests a secure email to most
people
so if you think about how a nap
asks for permissions arm there's a
couple
hard properties about this by are a mean
not flexible
they need to reinforce so all
permissions all
API permissions and happen each in each
care in the manifest
if an app ask for permission it's not
declaring the manifest
you'll always be denied news on every
front at fort are the value there is
that
if you as a reviewer as a user wanna
stand what nafta possibly do
you can search just by looking the
manifest know that if
it's on the manifest the app can do it
you can ask for
and insider that mister commissions
in the manifest the basic be opinion
that type of application Nokia
there's two kinds of emissions is
implicit and explicit
all that really means is whether or not
they're prompted for explosive
conditions require explicit user consent
before the granted implicit ones don't
send up a submission
if an app as an implicit permission it's
manifests and is being
concert approve appropriate approval
process for the type of application
then it will be granted at runtime
um if its explicit type commission which
are most privacy sensitive permissions
then you'll have to be the manifests and
it has to be approved by the reviewer
the application will be and it has to be
granted by the user
runtime: so
one thing that might be different from
your use to you lectures on the from the
US model is that the permissions are
a time use so if an app needs three or
four provisions that require prompting
for
will usually not see a three or four
Commission problems in the first
launched yet
because all sorry doesn't need all those
right away
we only prompt for permissions when the
apec tries to use the car is funny
yeah rights if you're going to nap it's
like a social efforts and say this
ap points at access whatever I want want
access your camera
to take pictures and stuff whatever
eating for lunch right
he wants your location to find you on
the map
and maybe once access your contacts you
can sure where you are with your friends
it won't do all that when it first
launches
right only we want to do this activity
we get a prompt and the way that the
application
prompts you is doesn't actually say ask
his permission
he just simply tries to use the API
so once in at ask relocation
then we handled permission problems and
the in the developers have to worry
about it
so this is essentially a
not the final you excuse us a little
rough but this is the US for permission
problems what it looks like
arm and you can see is that one
difference between privileged Epson on
for these applications is
that remember my choice the fault is
different for privileges ap sweet
because the code can change
without being be reviewed we're pretty
confident
issues aside to grant an application
access
to something you will make it
decision most likely again and again and
when we don't want with prompting model
Lisa always keep asking the user
repeatedly the same question
about them be up to basically say don't
ask me again just my decision
you can always change this later so if
you make the wrong decision is a
grant access this thing and remember my
choice
and you say week later like that's not
what I want
you just go change but the main
difference between club was absent from
his abs is that
was abt by the former member their
permission
responses so once again
if you change your mind if you going to
the wrong permission to nap we just
don't have access anymore
whips then you can just go
into the Settings app find a
corresponding ap and
change permissions to what you want or
just simply inspector si with the
permission is granted to that
application or
we also arm
try to do you as much as we can
persistence
a background and get notifications on
commission usage
so if n application is using location
it'll you get this icon and miss not
that to rate this is in the role very
good location
look notification is using your location
but it's true for camera and a couple
other API's
so you can always know if you're not
sure this reminder there
that this app is using this API you
previously granted access to you
so it's a certain web activities before
this is actually a lot I've caps will
get access
when they don't have a lot of privilege
right so if you are at this social app I
mentioned before
your it take a picture of whatever you
having for lunch right
yeah you could implement a whole camera
at inside your social API
inside your social probably a better
thing to do is just simply fire with
activity says
these organic picture raises example how
effective is work is a you have
the fall camera app will be registered
as net as a handler
for the take a picture activity give me
a picture activity
and then the social app it simply go I
wanna pictured fire affectivity
I would start the camera app a camera
you should go take a picture with a
camera app
and no that picture be there and it back
to the application that made the request
in the first place
what's nice about that is that the
developer doesn't have to
credo camera happen so the social app
your have to grant that ap
camera access rate if
it fires of web activity event for a
camera you know when I take a picture
you just cancel
there in you can take a picture so it's
a very simple model enables a lot of
functionality for autographs about
having to
worry about granting them direct access
to those API's
um so
we we do think alike piracy winded
developing a small received you know
track as an option there
but the primary things there we we
always ask you
for access to privacy sensitive API's
every after was a tax issue occasions
your contacts
to your camera to a few other API's
unless a surfeit up always has that
asked the users as no surprise
right if an app its access your contacts
to be only because he granted access to
its
to your contacts at some point
and as per their you can always change
your settings you can do is go
here the day different application and
you can always there is always a race
win you
on its all the applications while
as part of the US have to figure out how
to clean protect the OS as well
so we've done a couple ways if you look
at the boot sequence just give as a
server high-level review
when it boots up have the next are
afraid
you have kiko starts we censor its shell
dubs dual
which is a container essentially for
what Lose a Guy system
which then Lowe's the home screen app
which then
registers the core system installed
absent handle stuff like with activities
for
event activities for our system
activities for
um SMS and being telephone handling
radio state wifi too much other core
system
operations what this looks like an code
is that a basic a window which is the
Gecko chrome shelled out sole
inside as an iframe that is a system app
is so there's a knife a which is the
home screen app and so forth
so if you want to visually presented it
looks something like this we have
in Firefox we've actually visually
three diff 3d defining
layout right like window Leah and that
cute idea I've
others actually built in memory
so very we look at protecting from each
other's
is each other princes no in its own
content process right so
is a kids each other's dater cookies
they can't Sierra process low
an app can launch a frame another app
and with the process permissions are
equivalent to the manifest permissions
which means that
if you're at doesn't need access to a
camera
the process itself has no access the
camera anyway
so the way ap stock to the OS is over
APC
right so each app process a little
rights process
if you don't have access to much if
anything it has to go ask echo Ford
and it doesn't through this basically a
a pipe and I PC channel
and well that's it
there is and OS update moderate and the
update models actually different
depending on what you're talking about
gone
for SES gecko versus applications so
the underlying OS the the next
layer is basie up the rover
OT update over-the-air updates or USB
you can plug it into your computer in
Flushing
taken geyer are actually kinda the same
you can
they're basically if our normal these
process the way
release Firefox's re-release gecko
updates
Hurley's Firefox OS updates and
likewise neither do you the over-the-air
updates which is 702 update or you can
have an image on your device you flash
directly or you can be your flesh is a
vice
an app at updates are handled
individually which is to say that
because apso neck chip to come from a
certain app store
each app can be responsible for its own
up the process
the mechanisms the same but taking the
fine with the updates are posted
the notification mechanism
et cetera I love I wanna give lots of
times for questions and cue way
Santos is kinda crazy complex model and
I've blown through pretty quickly
okay
I got most except the very last part
okay so we so we we've taken a different
approach their
on abt can change the policy
so the policy for privileges absence or
perhaps is actually enforced by
by gecko and it's not modifiable the app
we have
we have a bugger working on which is the
ability for
an app to specify turns his piece of
policy that pose in Rome OCSP
policy intersection rules which is
actually means they can only for the
restrictive
rights right now if you have to UCSD
policy somehow
in a browser you can only well
you don't have the intersection love
their privileges
right or the Union other restrictions I
really think about it
we as a society we actually have a
minimum CSP to prevent any dynamic
cogeneration and restricts code loading
only from the app package and the
developer can
can't lose
you're so we have a we're the source had
a project for PDF JS for some time
it's actually you can it's carnival was
an extension events for you
in a building to the browser once it's
fully bakes but it's a way of rendering
PF entirely JavaScript and
that is this an implementation of that
in BG in Firefox OS
that is registered as a PDF and city hit
a PDF file
basic PDP if such as really registers
registered itself
for the PDF handling activity
it is possible and the user with an the
printer a choice
Mon
a lot of problems with the Android app
sees
might for example the makers like
Samsung install these unseemly highly
privileged applications that totally
defeat the entire
permission in security model how do you
see
Firefox OS protecting its carriers and
makers doing these types of activities
it's an excellent question so its
he answered it is for gonna seem a
little
obscure but I think it's actually one is
such a question a brain
right so for gonna ship something call
the fire for
Firefox OS device were you want to make
sure that manifests
are police radar brain everyone to
protect user
which is not one with atomic crap that
the user doesn't want to think and to
the
so anything that we what have brain is a
Firefox OS devices users gonna be
always basically top of the food chain
so they have ability to uninstall
eighty others think or critical
privileged a certified applications
necessary for OS operation a buncha
stuff on that uses one thing just delete
it
yes you don't want a ton I've random
junk on their to begin with because it's
just a great experience
that said it's an open source project
rights or something to take the code
and implement something based upon a and
not using you for bringing
you know like that's open source right
am i do that
but then it's not going to call Firefox
I have a question about permission model
so
when you say for instance yes the yup
request internet access
if I say don't though with the up just
say no and exit or we'll believe think
know your two questions to know so
there's
the model for developing
farrell for developers is that they
should
the need to handle the case that
every explicit permission may be denied
by the user and the need to continue
running
so we do not want people to be
browbeaten into granting permission
saying where you get his permission I'm
gonna quit right we handle that is for
privilege applications you go through a
review process
and we find applications as try to bully
the user into saying yes
we will not approve and so you don't
approve them
you end up with a nap you can't do much
anyway make it to care for these
applications that I have access to very
interesting API's and therefore user
just
probably even install along that same
line so what happens if you want to
it's in applications requesting internet
access or access to a third party
it is it going to display this site that
is trying to access
that my concern here is that a lot of
these applications
have this basically adware spyware
whatever is installed
you granted permission for maybe
internet access but it's also
using that seem chain or that same
permission to send it to a third-party
for
whatever reason yes we we face some
a tricky choices when trying to decide
how to
implementers so that
we well
I'll take brief I was actually pretty
explicit that I wanna have
et cetera a huge their permissions now
2010 by people about
this is trying to do is very specific
thing to this particular site because
the sheer number positions will
just cause people to totally 29 not
really treatment decisions anymore I'm
so
we don't from for internet access in
jail for example does not have
permission we think is meaningful
you know where because the web is you
know it is what it is but
the nation the web is it that that
communication
patterns are essentially managed by
site opting in to communicating with
each other not the user saying I'm gonna
allow this site
talk to that site rockers like like
cognitively that's impossible for users
to manage
so we try to only ask for things that
are
really piracy impactful and for the rest
other things
we rely on the review process rate so
unprofor's applications like I said
are really just like web sites says the
same model
I don't ask for a lot but they can't do
much you
now if they wanna do more then
that you go through different model
requires an approval process review
process
and we rely on the review process to
manage their
risk from a low level security
standpoint rights of Annapolis have
access to like raw socket
in issue for those that we'll take a
look at that is like
why are you using cross-eyed is a really
responsible for you to use this or are
you just
using something with the SKECHERS case
you know I can be approved
she won't have that privilege and then
when we asked to use when I only ask the
user for privacy impactful things we
have a chance
action is anyway it's about one thing we
do is we actually
we have the ability for the developer
matching cars
uses to specify recalls an intended
usage
so when I say only use I need access
your camera
I can't you see I'm gonna I want you to
access your
ever for the purposes of love taking a
picture
love love your avatar for the social
network for you whatever
on and thats further review process
so you say I want taxes can for purpose
I love which had actually make sure that
that is actually using it for
and then that did
communication the uses of a meaningful
because you not just askin
API access question we actually asking
about access to information
these is put in a better position to to
decide about
thank you know one final question
have you thought about how that review
processes
is going to scale yes
so there's a couple characteristics one
exit we don't wanna
have it on us right arm
to use it there time with use and so
it's unlikely you'll hit these over and
over again at the same time
right I would say that we have because
you the ability to persist that decision
it gives a lot more flexibility user
decides that yes this is a decision I
wanna persistent
rate like I use you know had an iPhone
for a while and as an inservice was a
very simple app
or the next bus app it's a web-based or
tells you
is like what causes it to be showing up
soon for your location
so easy location to do that
in every time I run it like it always
asks me if it's okay to have access to
your location
like the only reason to run this app
said access to my location data buses
are coming
like I will never say no to that so
don't ask me so like
we've built in these better flexibility
with the using make a decision
and they can say for this thing always
I'll
this thing always denied for this thing
house me
and so there'll be some maps but still
like you look at the total number
Commissioner Christmas absolutely
like even very complex ones you talking
about maybe like 3
over the whole like over the whole all
the could pass near
right off or at most so it's you don't
ask for lost
know what order there than there yes
ever-growing it's like okay I'll make
friends
win I'm last question I had was
specifically around the
iframe and the malls browser frame the
described
say he said permissions you know it's
the weapon
everything like that say heavy thoughts
about
where sites literally in bed other sites
get these
authenticate them for example still the
cookie because at the moment seems
there's nothing stopping that's on life
re skinning a fake browser for example
and having access
so you don't have access the cookies for
you in either the I
in I the case they're not stored in some
addressable
local storage mechanism within the app
that's correct so we still manage all
the quirky
we so amazing he's receiving have this
from the browser right the browser
you have the window top top
right is the the witches in Europe or
naked in bed many iframe sure
and he has no access to you anything or
the cookies and I frame because
that his party the principal we look at
whether does
the code in principle a have access to
code in principle be your window be
with the principles compare them with
the same in tonight if they announce
that sells
say on in the most brands a frame Snorri
do you
on a the sites for example framing
policy
so sick Africa FIGS if they get the
exact
HTTP header restricts was not like me
for extreme option yeah that's it thank
you
yes that's a good question so over to
the state the
the only purpose so most browsers
actually a privileged
UK for this reason wanna make sure to
use responsibly
in the only purpose for is to be generic
browser type application read either
because europe is a browser
or your app is some sort of feet
consuming
thing into space things in sort of a
browser
is it acceptable though from the parent
II I'm not sure if it is because the
parent doesn't have
country was truly a remmy
have to look at it but that the reason
that the short answer is it's a protege
exactly for that reason because we don't
want to change the security contract
between a parent and a child without
having oversight right and if you start
seeing it would be sketchy things we're
gonna
get to see interview process and try to
figure out why they doing that
and begin to
so when a developer some meat and naps
through the App Store whatever would be
how do you check that out how to make
sure that
that abnormal issues resulting
somebody's
files happy yeps Chur so we're still
refining the review
guidelines but this sure is actually we
do this for quite a long time for
extensions
right so even extension ecosystem
and everything that we host its
available for download
is reviewed is reviewed a couple
different ways is
there's a bunch of like tools we use we
run against them
so we have third party actually and
servers companies ago scanner repo
it also visit the unit sketchy like
nowhere
we have a bunch of our own scanning
stuff runs mostly for
for looking for either that known bad
militias patterns
coding and it is actual physical review
people actually look at the code
limit the the downside to that expensive
are there right now is because no actual
manifest for permissions right so
everything's kinda from privilege in our
current extension
that is very risky because you have to
review all the code
now with a rat model what happens is you
for sure looking at the privileges
right if you don't see any scary
privileges I couldn't ask for anything
interesting:
then all we have to look for is have
typical fishing and just general quality
love
experience issues
if you do see specific API's
their Tenshi dangerous you can focus on
those present a good for you
so it actually it's the same ProSeries
for extensions
but way more if made way more efficient
by the fact that we can actually lively
predict application
thank you
or questions
back
just to play devil's advocate I think
that the the levels lower
I think the model you have where
basically chap is protected from each
other is really great
but what about the user experience that
i think is becoming more and more common
on the web where you're using
a single accounts to sign in to many
services where you can sign into
different Apple different web sites with
your Facebook account
with your Google account and where you
would have
then free the user and an application
that
if they were signing in through a
browser they would have a single click
but a in Firefox OS they would have to
re authenticate with those credentials
for each individual
at what's your response to developers
who
kind of like that user experience sure
this is a good question so
that's where the trail suite had to
consider in
designs that the data management reset
when
the more privacy sensitive side for now
but I think
what's pretty reasonable is in the
future having explicit API's to handle
those
cases rights having apt of into the
model with a willing to share
you know some set of tokens amongst
themselves may be in a specific
of indications store right and that
would have
functionally the same benefits without
actually just trying to just shovel the
cookies back into one huge
store
no one questions
no more questions so that's it so a big
applause
thank you
this
sleep