think alright let's do this thing
so my names Charles hearing we're gonna
talk about eye-catching breaches
n dad does anyone have any idea and dad
is anyone ever heard the term in bad
think it's an old Michael Jackson song
when
get so I'm little bit about me and how I
I got here I spent in years on active
duty in the Navy
my last gig was as a network security
officer for the Naval Postgraduate
School
in at those view that may have studied
intrusion detection system history
which is you know three people in the
world %uh
there was a paper penned by doctor
dorothy denning in 1983 called
intrusion detection expert systems so 83
the whole idea behind catching reaches I
was first
I and then it and that doctor deming
as a professor at the Naval Postgraduate
School she was there
I when I showed up up for duty in 2000
and
well one of the things we found inside a
military installation that had a class B
if I P space without matter firewalls
was very easy to rob us and become
became much easier when we started
taking exchange students
from other countries who were
essentially spice
made it very easy bring them on campus
they just couldn't access it's directly
from the internet so I never be a row
now a detection
is a school of thought on how you catch
things that are currently I'm catchable
I'm answering to go through the adage
that the area n bad
I'll how can you do in bad and really I
the book with the talk today is over
some breaches that I've been a part of
both
a the last a year and a half that
anomaly detection or behavioral
I detection has allowed us to catch
something really how we caught those
so our full disclaimer I work for a
company called Lanco portrays basically
is the only copy in a world that
actually does and bad
but I promise not to pitch you on that
nonsense
so will do this and definition so you
know what words mean that i'm talking
about. we'll talk about that
specifically how in bad goes around I
goes about the texting breaches
and I will talk about the actual
breaches so
what is in bad weather NetFlow and water
detection schools
so are dimensions network behavior on
our way detection
is in bad I generally speaking and
monitored and batted side the data
sources net flow
at the reason that came about as when we
first started doing research
and in bad around 2,000 there are
basically two major hubs at the time
there was a bush graduate school working
on a project called terminator
and a at Georgia Tech doctor copeland
was running a project called
a stealth watch which is the became a
product that I pedal
um by I those two
those are the two and now appear on on
detection schools but those days it was
a probe centric meaning we put a a probe
of a spanner put it in line it look for
traffic
there was anomalous or or abet not bad
behavior and alert on that
around 2004 I we discovered at
sense and that is a really looking
inside the package is looking at the
distribution of packets
on how many bytes generally moving
between email servers and clients how
many
send packets are only in that nixon so
it's really a metric based game
and it didn't really matter what's in
the payload so NetFlow became a great
source for that because it's meta data
on what is happening
on and it made it much easier to deploy
set up putting probes everywhere you
basing sped up NetFlow pointed out of
things to a processing
in able to do in bad very quickly and
that also allowed us to look very deep
into the network
I'm access so workstation a workstation
workstation a server server to server
instead of limiting visibility for
detection at
egress and ingress points already
mentioned quality metrics
I sometimes because NetFlow is the main
I data source anything that it that
parses NetFlow
gets group 10 with in batter NBA or
something something like that
but up processing NetFlow doesn't make
you and Dad
I machine anymore then you know a human
being as in
air processor writers more to experience
just the dating process
I miss you want to start out doing this
on a roll there's a great set a tools
I'm from Carnegie Mellon concertina
called silk and so you can go out the
cert dot
racer decor yep seniority that or
and uphold out so & Assoc has a set a
library scope ice ok which are the
Python libraries Associated
I with parsing silken I what's ok is
that allows you send that flow into the
engine
it out parses it stores it allows you to
query it
against a different type 2 checks or
talk about the day
and Python up I sell kisses settle
libraries it makes it much
easier had to get into that dow stack so
check that out um there's really no in
bad
I am Magic Quadrant if anybody here
cares about that
I'm but there was an NDA
or network behavioral a network behavior
analysis
a a market breaching 9712 from I'll
Gartner and these are the folks listed
on a on that so and we'll talk about
their for MBA and bad here in a in a
moment so
when I talk about NetFlow net flows both
a specific thing and a category
I grew up in lower Alabama LA that's
what that
LAX means i sorry or let's go all right
all right let's also say roll tide about
to lose it but I so
I'll in Michigan who would've thought
they could actually have a
no but so when i sat down for supper the
waitress last
on what what do you wanna drink and I'll
say I would like a coke. and she would
say what I cocco can also have a doctor
pepper
because I and I in the southeastern
Alabama
so coke is both all soft drinks
and it is the deck soft drinks and that
flows same way there's a specific thing
called NetFlow NetFlow b5 b7 b9 came
into production
it was a standard created by style Cisco
and they issued information are a season
that will be nine hits and at RC listed
ipv6 is largely the open source version
of NetFlow
I've never be nine is actually a little
bit better than that so denying
a couple regards but that's our see
attached that and so when I talk about
NetFlow in this conversation by my
meta-data
going across the interface so is traffic
routes across a router or switch or
firewall is aware that conversation
it's gonna create a blog entry about
that in Alameda data format
I'm them a call floor NetFlow juniper
has J flow which
if you do a pee cap on it looks exactly
like NetFlow person 5
except Juniper's would die before they
gave
Citrix are such Citrix Cisco any money
on that so it is J Flo is not NetFlow
I see flow that strain anything meta
data about a conversation is we're
talking about here
and see what you think noticed the
bottom
I'll really the basic NetFlow records
this IP talking to this IP on this port
from this court for this many bites
at this time across its entire face
that's what we're talking about the raw
data
so that's not flow in a nutshell we can
talk about that more some other time
when I haven't had for those things but
the I
there's three ways to catch anything in
information security
the first one in the most general wanna
signature-based detection
and so it for looking at this from a
physical security around
this is really inspecting the object
before it's ingested by the victim or
the target
so I rece
wonderful frosty beer and I look for
things like mold floating on it I'm
inspecting
object before I take it in see me a
second I'm sorry sir thing about the
beer
love Grand Rapids
um so you inspect the object before you
ingest looking for things that you know
or bad
chemicals composition things that you
know will hurt the target as ingest them
signature-based detection to an IPS you
looking for the packet there's something
about that packet you know it's bad it's
attached to exploit si vede XYZ
holiday and antivirus inspecting the
object in this case being
file that file has certain markers on it
we know its associated with specific
I i'm our area content filter same thing
going you're looking for a request to
view or else that are known
bad a behavioral detection
is looking for what happens after you
ingest it I'm
for instance you might not need to see
that beer on my
podium to know that I've been drinking a
beer I you can tell a little bit by my
behavior
right now the fact that I'm corning a
lot is one thing that apply what do it I
would have to bear
but what happens after the object is
ingested how does that impact
the behavior up the victim or the target
and
man-hours and boxing is a lot like the
old cut bear
I approach to to a cane right you have a
cup there he would drink it
the king would look at 'em if the guy
for the foaming at the mouth he said ya
pass on that
that's not something I really want to
get involved with right now let's bring
out a new cut area and who
unearthing a wine says bring our sandbox
and put it in a sandbox watch what
happens if the behavior is unknown bad
behavior
on then you can assume the object was
ingested is bad so
sandboxing I'm in bad as a good at this
stuff but you don't need to know what
that
in point ingested to know that it should
be scanning the network
on that he shouldn't be breaking policy
that he shouldn't be going on in routing
write those types of things are
behaviors that follow
the ingestion up about objects and
anomaly detection you're still watching
the behavior of the host but you're
watching it for deviation against known
good behavior
so if someone shows up to work every day
at 6 a.m. in the morning
and then one day to shop at 6:30 that's
a little
dat weird if they show up at noon
carrying an ak-47 wearing a meatloaf is
a hat
really weird right so you're talking
about degrees
deviation me check actually it
mathematically they just never works
I make you tryin to it does work I am
so when you break down how to these
detection mechanisms work
I'm II in concert
a signature-based detection is the best
for catching known exploits
so when I go to O'Hare I take my freakin
shoes off
and they look for a bomb in my shoes
they don't day but they know what to
look for
if I put something else in there like a
popular
they don't know what to do about that
but they know to look for thanks to
Richard Reid
and i got really scared by the way at
they started doing that and then the
that underwear bomber showed up my home
in 20 hair kit I get any worse
than this whole thing I'm a shop in a
row at the whole thing
so but I know nyse: signature-based
detection is very good at detecting
known bad thanks
behavior detection has become very good
at zero day stuff because even though
you are using a new exploit you're doing
the same old thing
you're going to steal data you're gonna
try to propagate internally you're gonna
try to pay that
the behavior the bad behavior that you
do with the host what is compromised
it's the same
so a few don't know what the exploit is
you note the behavior is not follow
so I'm our sandboxing I never be a row I
detection on the network in helping NAT
so
through nearly 10 the exploits this is
the best I've
while the best place to catch that and
then anomaly detection is very good at
catching stops
I'm there really has no signature
when you're abusing credentials might be
up a little bit about this when I did
this
last a last month's about what his
credential abuse what I mean is someone
has
the ability to login issue or the person
logging in
is
be an a-hole right so I
you have a username and a password in
using those credentials in a way that
are inappropriate
so ever snowden is a great example this
he's an administrator he logged in the
machines he supposed to log into
machines
a Booz Allen paid him to log into
they did not however want him to suck
down all the NSA's
data and walk away with it right and so
you can't alarm on
signature bullying detection assay when
I don't measure logs and trigger alarm
what you can alarm on and I an
administrator can only access is less
than a hundred max data
in a day if he it if he pulls down 10
terabytes the data
Tay's that dude and I'll let him out of
the building right that's a
a proper incident response and so
anomaly detection is watching for what
is normal and then when someone does
something abnormal
you're going to learn of so how does how
does approach is applied to I
in bad I Resort limited in and add for
using NetFlow as your data source
you don't have the benefit of having the
full packet to get in there and look for
sequel injection patterns and no such
things you could do if you're looking at
the Internet brings
I but there are some things you can do
and meta-data I'll
at about this event earlier I mean
earlier are going to an earlier
I went to a 10 minutes ago okay thank
you
up by Tom I got that in a bit no but I
segmentation
violation a vendors lie I'm a vendor
we actually have clubs we get together
we talk about how we're gonna lie to you
we actually have really great meetings
on that's not true
another like that I just sold as a
vendor I'm by I
I I did spend a period of my life
working for and for all magazine testing
network security stuff
and so the vendor it's a one thing we
test a busy on this end
not exactly what you said pro you know
what's that had geriatric
and inside oven at work the same is true
I am you have it's good to trust but you
need to validate it
and so we're going to make some examples
and yes but if we put segmentation in
place that a hoe that
um the guys at HR shouldn't be able to
access
I'm the protected trade secret data we
need to know what
if that ever happens right we need to be
alerted if something breaks down somehow
as and
in HR person doing that is crazy but
let's say they did it
we need to know possible violations
we don't allow onion routing that's a
good policy you know
a it's also possible here by the
government of Iran but whatever
you know this there's some things are
not OK people agree to an incoming in
the network
so if they do those things need to be
alerted to it and someone that's gonna
be available NetFlow
and I'm the meta-data inside an up-close
just meta-data
there's nothing magic about us you can
put anything inside and that so
jeanine right he fix it you want you
but the user name in there you can put
the URL requested in the NetFlow data
I'll you know you can but the horoscope
with that whatever you want can be put
inside at the meta-data
so one of the ways has been used in
several deployments
I is grabbing euro information putting
an end to the meta-data and they're
looking for
I'll blacklist URL so that your else
associated with
I'll Saran somewheres
um so there's an
one good thing about army one good thing
about
give me a second spot in my mind you
guys are actually cause right now
I'll so bullying detection is a very
smart way
offloading a business process to a
computer
on when we first started doing signature
detection
there were just so many alarms coming
out these boxes
and so you does not know what have the
time to deal with it all seem like noise
and so one of the first things he
started to do is okay if there's a
sequel injection coming in
is that machine it hit that that it is
hitting is it even possible
as its not I'm gonna continue to have
another dark beer
and I do something else I don't care I
need to do anything so
that logic that really is I associate
with its a response plans
could be mapped into terming the
relevance
I i've detection so in this case
IDS signatures triggered is the machine
it the target vulnerable
um after it was hit did it start
disclosing data if so
trigger wake everybody up and ruin their
regional are
right and so it it's good for offloading
data
there there are some challenges though
one requires you to know what the bad
scenario looks like
what are the steps that need to be
triggered are
for Nick that and a hacker's if they
figure out what you think the at this
the the events are they can just change
it right was too little bit differently
I'm it also requires highly processed
data
intrusion detector Detection System
Center basing
system has to download signatures it has
to
parcels on the wire a cat has to not
drop packets is a lot of things that
have to happen for it output CPE
exploiting NCTE XYZ just happen so
that's another challenge
I'm you have to know what it is
right there are more exploits it is
sadly I saw a lot of my time working on
the department if that's their exploits
that we will not know about
for a long time I was on a panel
yesterday and people say you're patcher
machines and one antivirus
said that only catch is a really sucky
malware right
the good now where this really scary
that's not going
it's not gonna catch any hacked right
and so there are you have to know what
to look for in sight as I was pulling
detection mechanism
and I don't know exactly why put the
last load in there
so moving on to something that and that
is very good have
as behavioral analysis so this looking
for things and that this becomes
challenging when you try to do this
yourself because you now have an account
thanks
if your gonna count a machine is doing a
slow address can
yourself that's once in packet then
there's an arson packet
and so you're on every host now you have
to computational each count
and and and maintain counters on every
host as for doing those things
and you're gonna trigger that's an
address can TCP do something like that
but it is very good at catching scanning
if you are doing those counters is good
are looking for floods have data
associate with the DOS or something else
slack sequences like normal you don't
start a TCP conversation with
you know Acree Sat is pretty weird the
way to start a conversation
I'll the the pros at this
is you don't have to know the exploit
used us behavior comes after largely
connect with rekon
I inside a vehicle detection it's almost
always gonna be some factory time
behavior
I'll and that of course a comic
convention is
computationally becomes complicated when
you have thousands of posts inside the
network that you have to have something
in every saying
0 send packets and once in Pakistan at
some point you have to learn about
anomaly detection the pros are
they can catch really hard impossible to
catch stuff
the cons are it's magic
and eyes so there is a lot of
computation has to happen not just
counting everything
but base lining everything grouping
everything
and putting them in proper context
because there's not one normal in any
network
on there is normal for the clients to
the email servers there's a whole other
set up normal that is the scanners to
the
I'll to the data center there are many
types as normal
so enclave ng Iran or close grouping
inside those eyes spaces are very
important
and its it and that changes to write
it's not one time to do that
there is a lot a date or talking about
now
we're talking about communications from
servers to servers clients to clients
clients
certain is every potentially every
communication inside the network needs
to be processed
I stored and analyzed a and then we also
have to do something
I caught out with my calculation here
but it's really a index-based
alarming and so what this means is you
know I mentioned guy shows up thirty
minutes late for work
does that mean call in the answer
response team free if you bought that
house
it stirred some things are more abnormal
than other things
and so how do you deal with that inside
a a system a computer system like
a like in that system and so
wanna one approach that 1i advocate is
doing it
index based approach is something that's
a little bit anomalous for a little bit
suspicious
we recommend a counter a host countered
this host
just had a TCP reset imagine getting an
email every time the city should be
reset
but if you see a TCP reset and then you
also sir sings address scanning
or researching possible violation on top
of that the cumulative behavior
becomes increasingly concerning right so
to do that mathematically say that's a
little bit special
this a couple points to the index is
very suspicious tana points to the index
annual arm when the index exceeds
acceptable values
and is accepted as a chain Trader some
things you don't care about
dudes on guess that means of his mind
little destroy yes net
um p.o.s machine losses
you know is that a little goofy wake
everybody up writers different levels of
tolerance based upon
how those indexes impact business
so here are some other things either we
can look at
a look at some histograms and by the way
should make a disclaimer all these
things had to go through legal so many
times or
this brief was almost computer thing
happened at the end so
I had to release their ally sisters no
company names left in it
and I had to reproduce all apps the the
data graphs
as well a so that
I didn't say that very funny way certain
things that suck but this is
this is where to the human eye right you
know might not so we know what this is
looking at it um but it just looks weird
and you're looking at this is a a
histogram
up the bytes per second are bits per
second I relationship
and really the above that line is
the traffic coming into a
in this case coming into a server a web
server
web server farm a group web servers
and I'll the line going down is the data
leaving
those web server so it looks like a
hammer ways
so with the knowledge a texan other Khan
is there's no CV
output its weird thing just happened
with the web servers and so you in this
case look at it it looks that is weird
II says it's weird but I don't really
know what it is
in this case is actually a sentence it's
a sense like de dos coming into the web
servers
with the data exfiltration connecting to
a sequence action
sucking the data out so from that's that
um enjoying his house is one nice thing
within bad with the knowledge a texan
particularly as the human eye is very
good at picking out these types
anomalies
if you have specific scopes so this one
here is
internet to web servers right so you're
looking at a very specific
a Sat data it looks funny
and so now you can zoom and also get the
records that led up to this so I can
make a determination
this is a change and
I service type: um particularly in like
PCI environments or hip environments
computers are pretty you're pretty
boring
like they will do PCI events all day
long the
credit card numbers don't get longer no
dude ever walked a lot there got a
credit card has
450 digits on it they're all like 16
digits
so its exact same transactions all day
long and no peace IPOs machinery says
you know i i think i wanna
check out YouTube today are heard shes
cool
let's do that let's see what it looks
like so it's very boring and the service
profile
have a tight tied up a nation so in this
case is I'll
I classified HPS which means I'll
a compartment net flows the ability to
do deep packet inspection
so with HTTPS if it if it is a steep yes
you're gonna see
I'm SSL exchanges um
but officials 443 TCP something else
going on you're not gonna see those
exchanges in a check classified as HTTPS
on this case
there's both the check there's both a
change in I volume
and also change in the traffic profile
and that there's something else running
I
net this is my favorite
I geographic traffic anomaly
if all of a sudden if you've never done
anything with the ukraine
and now a hundred Magyar traffic is gone
ukraine that's weird
right a and is really also one example
if you're a at your local government
that's really weird
on so looking at that time a day at all
your traffic happens
925 and then you start seeing ru major
transfer and transfers at different
times a day it's also a reason for
concern
maybe not as bad as ukraine and then
applying this to the user
I'm if the user is in atlanta 40-man and
log and 40 minutes before to log into a
machine and Boston
that's an obvious it's even worse if
you're in atlanta and in Beijing at the
same time
right so those are those are now is
actually
impossible this is a fun one I
hi this is a metric so we talk about
counters but what if you counted
every bite that a host
a collection the network every day I
will I come into work I collect maybe
10 bytes maybe a hundred minus take part
in bytes
maybe ten Magus maybe a hundred make
whatever it is what is a normal person
doing today
and then you see a guy like this who dis
as you know it's gonna take 11px today
and I'm I'm 11 get the data don't tell
me that I can have long its data
I was actually on site and in Chicago
and i just i three weeks ago
and i'm looking at this time explaining
to that folk and I don't have no idea
what they'll
but because it says I said no me when I
see this someone is quitting
I see that LinkedIn profile changed I
see them suck all the data the network
and then a letter of resignation cops
right there collecting all that stuff
they feel like it's theirs
and so in that case is actually the
chief information security officer
and he didn't leaves if anyone needs a
new CISO I know a guy
I'll can't recommend them but I know I'm
I N I data disclosure how much data is
leaving the networks are counting how
many bytes someone send out the
networking today
there's something that's normal there's
something is abnormal or something
that's
all crazy abnormal right so there are
different degrees here that we can't do
we can mathematically compute those
you that our fans standard deviation so
some with that said are there any
questions on any of that noise I'm
asking is because if I ask your
questions I can reach for the beer
while I wait for you to raise your hands
okay yep
it depends on the metric
so if you're a if you're doing bits per
second that's gnarly
you can do an ollie on that I something
more precise like I'll
a saturation as send packets that's
going to be tougher to calculate as you
can be you don't know if you missed this
setback or so it was a %uh
offices sample so but most a modern
stuff can do
line right now nesler
the good stuff can okay
Ruis so yet you have a whole other set
of problems
and I'll
all yeah was you're right so
there are ways in doing that and and
NetFlow might not be the only data
source you need for %uh
for doing aggregation and I at who had
that IP address at a given time and
getting down to i
getting on those metrics are gonna help
as well but yeah
bitrate: stuff you can do but the
problem is you don't have all the I
if you don't have all the data you can't
visit cockpit set
the I'll
sec you can't give it to the app for
into GObject
there was concerning and that's actually
a really nice thing about NetFlow I'll
is that you could potentially have
forensic records everything that
happened in the network for
a year at a very low cost I compared
trying to do
you know 32 32 32 you were so happy chap
and so began a becomes much easier to
query but if you're doing sampling it's
like having a camera
that you know a video camera that takes
a picture every two minutes and you hope
thats
hokum be in rock band right add that the
guy comes in at that moment and doesn't
know about the sample rate but it is a
challenge sampling
it can it can help in the calculation
but it's just telling you how screwed
you are
right i mean that's all it says is being
honest about how bad the
out that it is all right let's go
through some examples this is the fun
part
on notice I guy I can even mention
I can mention a customer I came really
mention the country
I because they're scared of jail
I but anyway
so that's always fun for me I got a call
at 3:30 in the morning I'm
I sleeping in the suburbs that I
Minneapolis
and I'm they're screaming
E ENB as broken
ass okay a lot and by the way if you
ever call me at 3-3 in the morning and
me being sober it's a crapshoot
okay so good I mean it's what is its
1:30 in the afternoon now
yeah so the
a that's what was going on I E and so we
go back we start looking at what is
happening and they had
but they called mainframes roads bleed
Massa computers with Petra vines and
Petra bites where the patient data
and they had built very tight
segmentation
that meant only a couple segments
insider that now
I hope I'm here unfortunate wanna be ok
after dongles
have a yeah people hating a backup
1/2 the video capture devices
throws hope they're in the process so if
you look at me
whenever you of all
me anyway when my video devices growth
%uh
so we have to stop stop the video but
the audio actual top start back up very
very shortly
thank you sorry for the inconvenience
he organized criminals who were
collecting also formation
I really wish I could tell you what
those profits the what think our core
stuff the store but you're at Wheeler
beer to
and the cameras collapse cost I'll
so but I so the
so the couple things here one I web
servers don't normally say
nor am I to do today when she starred on
FTP uploads
and if they do that they don't normally
say less to FTP uploads to
Eastern Europe right
especially when you're a small
municipality Shirish
who'll
large FTP Upload
going every thing about every eight
hours
your this most fun I really wish I could
say this but there are
this is a trade secret deal there are
some special foods that we all
eat that a country and in
and East Asia wanted to know how to make
peace
foodstuffs okay
and so the way they broke it was
actually pretty neat
they went and mister fisher really
stupid administrator
and so I think you're out rhythms now
for finding the stupidest administrator
IT guy inside the organization I think
there are forums I haven't seen them but
there has to be
because almost three out of four these
things are going to and I said I talked
the guy
he's like fourths cop except the way
less likable
right and so I'll
I'm a skill can play pingpong either but
um so they Spearfish demand it was for
it was little it was let this is ninety
guy
your password is expiring
change change your password and so he
clicks on the link that and he has and
he's a guy that actually changes
passwords and people forget passwords
and again I S may have ever do in as I
make my life easier and he clicks on it
and and ask you know what your old
password input is all password any but
the new password and
and the the site comes back and says
that's not complex enough
style school right there lay that the
hackers you like to try harder
of and so he puts in a
like more complex one the attackers get
it sunday I'm
they log in via VPN the changes password
to this new complex password to make it
harder for the next set up attackers
I am and then through the VPN they take
control of the machine scanning the
network
so you you keep gmail if you ever have
ever been in said a responder and you
get alarm so much as a VIP some some
some
is you know me by a Reds the scanner
elsewhere is a scanner
are you even look at it you're so used
to telling people it's the scanners or
13 scares I think months entertainer
some numbers scanners
inside the inside the network all of
them
they were scanned the network like this
post to but they probably shouldn't have
been doing my secord ops across every
single
datastore inside the network and then
they probably should not have been
staging that data
for FTP retrieval to a comp to our
country
that makes great takeout wall
cool so every kind look something like
this: its address canning looking for
SMD file servers
I'm and then I she repentance I'm ready
sean is exact same graph so that's a
the day that leaving leaving the network
I am
this was a little cook your night this
one doesn't really make sense
because it may take all the hard about
this one but there is a
University they're doing
a.m.
ramallah say sensitive research
and the state-sponsored attackers
was apparent that came in Tehran the
road they are on this one I'm
they found the remote desktop
servers and in a distorted brute forcing
them until they get
I get into I'll get into the servers and
other thing about remote desktop use
that it's very start the bites coming
from
the server are very high compared to
the bites a client sense in a type and a
couple she's going you're typing
or the updated the position your mouse
so it's very small data going up to the
server
an early screening I'll what's on the
screen
I'm so 10 things we saw was a spike in
other traffic profile
or a deck that later I eso the traffic
profiles
a change to where the client part of the
conversation was very high
and I'm and is also an abnormal amount
of RTP traffic
and if any have you working University
you have all kinds of problems to deal
with I sympathize with you like
having a class B year to space that has
not napped
or firewalls and
the laws of nature dog played a tenured
professors
so its top securing Networks Inc than
their
so and this you gonna see this is
basically is the best I could do for
graphs to show this but
I there's everything going on everything
total
and then that blue blip %uh remote
desktop traffic in comparison to it so
is a very anomalous Amalco
data coming in on the inbound side so
order or more when
this is easy so okay there's a
manufacturer
not far from here East guess which one
it is
they pissed off some people
they said things they should said
and so the activist for activist decided
that they were going to embarrass the
manufacturer
so they did a single injection against a
customer portal published all the
customer information
and paste them and
I was at attack but I was actually
pretty I was easy
actually attacked again address canning
I'll
is very hard to do an exploding as a
server as we know what it is
and so you have to find server space
surgery Connie fingerprint at
is that Apache is that I asked what CMS
running at once you get all that done
it's very easy to exploit
what you have to do a good that every
time a set so that was easy enough
in this craft is horrible seeing I'll
but on the left this is traffic cool
i leaving the web server going to the
Internet so it was very is almost
nothing
and then a lot quickly leaving at the
same time that date is quickly leaving
the backing onto the front and so its
data being sucked out the back in
through the front and that's what
sequence action looks like when you put
it together
or something some type a drive-by attack
so that was easy cash from the beginning
to the end and the friends records put
that all together
are there any questions
quiet
and
go sure so yeah like to tell people that
I'm like a doctor that comes and
explains
broader cancer is and I show you how bad
it is
and then I go drink beer angle of rights
so
somebody else's problem to fix all this
nonsense it is possible if you become
aware of I
if you become aware other debts you can
do
there's a lot of things going on for our
systems communicate with each other you
can send
old school would be like in or out going
to something I
or shot onto a firewall something along
those lines
you can't do anything in line when using
a distributed
sensors net flow coming in see can't
knock it off the wire like you would
with the trade show I P S
those are one option other things come
up this island
integration with a course that
mechanisms like I'll
I back like a cisco has a dirty services
engine
so it gets permission to host figures
out how risky it is and says okay your
employees access
and so when you text him an abnormal
behavior going on you can come back and
say okay he's no longer employees
accessing is to be quarantined
or internet only accessed by a sending
out command over to
I S E I'll nor thing that
Cisco's been sponsoring SPX readme which
is that it's
you know it's it it's an open standard
open I
open standard on health for devices to
pass information between each other
%ah and deaths of right pedal
participates in that so he can pass
information but I it again its
visibility really and so
when you talk about the information
security compared to martial or physical
security
I'll surveillance is the first thing
that we do
right so you know when I'm knock over
the liquor store on Monroe
and after this talk it's not only lasers
and drop
floors that are gonna stop me its it's
going to be
I'm going to be recognized and they're
going to arrest me and put me in jail
right it's going to be the follow-up is
coming surveillance and deters my
behavior
and so really I in bad as in that
surveillance space or should be
I'll and therefore sadistic and to
answer response
processes how to what do we do with me
well we detect something
and you know wait what
well you have to well this true I mean
but if I'm in Iraq law enforcement
doesn't stop any crime
right the cops grad they've never stop
me
I can tell you that aircraft its they
they've shown up afterwards
and they've had told me it was a bad
idea it but I'll
all me money to bail bondsman in Grand
Rapids I know couple
but I am the all and
I
but there is a tie and though because
you know we move from his place were
when I was working from for world we did
at the whole movement was that stop
bad things before they happen let's put
in for some mechanisms and policies so
that bad things can't happen
so but the thinking the on said
corollary to that is so we don't have to
deal with all
and so what happened in that I was
really stop monitoring
we we had no way a validating are are we
being successful in stopping them
on it this morning I was working with a
a company that
mostly make sheetrock and there were
they were were routed they had no idea
for my rights
I without with attackers inside because
you're not breaking anything
I there are still in trade secret
information
and they're sending it out its sending
out the network and so you start really
looking for those things are never going
to find them
in the eye I was joking earlier that
your church bad now where and that's how
it should be
if you're any good at breaking into
something you shouldn't get caught
that's
that's the way to do it don't get into
crime if you're going to get caught that
makes it much harder
sexy right so I'm but surveillance is
important part
surveillance enforcement and then
response and all the things are going to
happen we're gonna have breaches were
gonna
then how do you deal with them and an
add next year may go to a talk on
how operationalize all this what do you
do when something happens cuz I was
talking with a customer
few see month ago
and I so what do you guys do when you
find out that there's a botnet infection
and they said well you know we going to
memory forensics leopold the network
research on
peach apple gets a into the dry eyes I
start going in a friend's ex
figure out the indicates compromise on
the published data microfiche
I know you guys who knows how to do
memory forensics here which many you
guys
you guys really know how to start your
car's there's no one here they can do
memory forensics and if you could
you do not have the cycles because I
know you have about a hundred thats
per month there's it is mathematically
impossible
okay we wipe the box as okay you wipe
the box at your process
write it down so we can be mostly most
the time right
might wipe the box so it so it really is
the biggest prominent Pesek is process
connection when we detect something when
something fails
what do you do in their sisters is fancy
that goes on that were not realizing all
three parts are very important
surveillance response you have to do
something nearly enough to do before
thing comes up on as a retro eight other
people there
anyways have any questions yes
what attacks are we missing
what um
it so mosser analysis is very a bet
centric toroto centric
I almost half its attack focused meaning
I so I went to something I showed you
there's free time
right as a part of the cyber kill chain
we should believe the Sabre Hill change
the way that we
actually doing attack on but we're not
doing as correlating all those different
against
as a map to the kilt chained together
and we start doing that we find that
what's our seemly to spirit that's map
into
a bigger I'll incident right so
and what are those incidents as I think
what your question is is largely
it's a lot a trade secret trade secret
theft is a hard thing to catch
I'll and because you don't like to cart
because
geopolitical ramifications glass or
being caught
I'm I'll and the other thing is the
human factor
I think when we talk about cybercrime we
like to think about a dichotomy between
cybercrime
and everything else criminal there's
nothing keeping
a cybercriminal for you from using
traditional I O
attacks on me like extortion
or a bribery
right why spend 50 weeks trying to break
into a network administrator will accept
a fifty thousand dollar bribe and so
if the administrator is the guy who has
access he can easily also cover-up
the audit trail and most most scenarios
so
the layer 8 is the easiest thing to
exploit
being a human being is easiest exploits
the hardest audit
I'm but is it is mostly trade secrets
the credit card stuff we eventually
catch
there's a way to catch that because
business process at the telly and shows
us
you know charles is popular helicopter
right he's probably hitting bottom
helicopters is monthly price should
can select card and so
but trade secrets as much blurry or miss
longer line but to someone do with the
trade secret think figure out how to
make toritos or whatever it is right
what does that mean how do we catch that
how do we know that I was actually
trade secret test and china doll back is
much more complicated
I'll so secrets I think secrets are gone
and that's a problem I from a business
perspective as well as a personal on
yet wall
so I A
and the first thing ever did
we need to do is have a process period
and I think I so flowcharts heard your
best friend any answer response plan
and dads gonna fit into that into that
France's on detection in that as a texan
is gonna catch
I'm those insider threats almost this
from your best cat
your best case for catching those guys
inside decided they're moving on or
it they did accept a bribe or other
family is in a basement somewhere until
they provide the data right there
I those things can happen so for
catching and cider and almost rats
it's important to do it but its only you
have a way to respond to it
I'm bringing it to land in bad tool and
turning it on doesn't solve
any problems it has to be connected to
what are we doing it or come to this
thing
and I'll I'll it shrink became
can shrink see at the time there and
know nothing about him back he noticed
these
we're not stopping anything or check the
exploits already happened a
is that you already have a compromise
machine you're catching at waco
later in the show psych an actual change
right and so on but we still need to
catch it and it's much better to catch
it later than that to catch it at all
and it does dusted in there
and it also helps validate enforcement
and I'm when you go back in time you
look at this French records why didn't
this attack work
like with the the case up the l2tp
tunnels how did that actually what can
we do to change things in that case that
organization
they want to talk and iced I'm
authentication is one
wait to prevent that from happening
again and so looking at those
that's because you're able to catch a
min actually have a frenzy trailer what
actually occurred leading to breach
but you can Aliza failure into you have
the data the evidence do that
that's a good question
really quiet in here was quite my short
what my time at a time I think it going
what do you do if I keep going
what is your hook early smiling I'm
early scare to view
I can just keep on York my head
I'll thanks guys I appreciate it a
that's me up there