hello everyone II arm
so this video is playing right now if
these guys on there
there these on hackers video gamers that
arm
are playing Team Fortress 2 and their
under the mat outside the enemy's base
and they just building hurts their so
soon as the enemy spawns
up they get classes with rockets SEC and
one glove great little quote from this
video is guys like but
after you doing and the like well I mean
like
it poppin want us to do it they would
have put it in the game
and %uh that's why I feel about a lot of
things anyways
effective it is pretty funny another
whatever
so ok
I'm putting up this talk
is redeeming back and forth back in by 5
ever
so sometimes I play a drinking game with
the stock
and it normally back tires for a plea I
get way to drop
about halfway through the talk and then
unites has on the floor
arm I'm gonna try and just play with
myself
I the bartenders were nice enough to
pour me a nice class if not water
and Dom if I say for
instead of five and I should always say
five on
feel free to call me out on it but not
too much be gentle
so quick survey who's up who's reading
here
regulars who who breaks things two big
things an accident good
up who's routine
defending defenders code auditors that
don't break things but have to clean up
things that people break network admins
all participants said anyone on track
team
you better not be defeated scope its
pretty early om
I bet people run drug team last night
though right yeah
so outline I wanna talk gonna talk about
red versus blue a little bit what that
means to me
a penetration test why they suck
sometimes I have a philosophical
anecdote that may or may not
make sense and then I'll talk about some
360 no scope hello swag
and her two a bit of a show-and-tell are
i've a twelve step process
and they'll be demos are all of my demos
by the way
are going to run through my phone which
is tethered and
I but one bar right now cock
we'll see how that works and then is
going to have missed you you hear
her see is an EQ more soap
bad at Penn has think the pen is
tested and gather some turning issues
there but whatever
worst-case Penn worked fine
we check your check box and tested great
are hoping this isn't you because it's
frustrating and hopefully
you're not the one has to do this hope
leaning on a on the receiving end of
this
its it's frustrating if you've ever been
on a contest like this
what happens is you rollin and your
hands are tied you don't really get it
you anything you
you know you could probably hacked them
you know you could probably
getting a different way but it's not in
school so what are some ways that you
can find that your
you're not really in school if your
users to the user base is out of scope
well you're missing up big part in the
attack surface there
and if you don't if you don't really
demonstrate impact
if you're just reporting on things that
you found
then how do you know like what happens
is you get that pen test back as the
receiver ovett
you get that contest back and you get
the report and you're like
now this one doesn't apply to us yellow
toner duties there but is exploitable
now so not so good and if you can't
validate the findings
also that so what about but no results
with you any word so
other people who have been tested or
receive pen test you ever have a pen
test with no results
what would you do about it
was there anything you could do about it
so I think there should never be a
penthouse with no results
because if you're getting all results
your scope is too tight
you should talk them into widening the
scope
because if if your school too tight and
getting no results they're paying for
something
and you're not eliminating this path
that could have happened right
you not eliminating the fish that what's
gonna happen
not a limiting any of that stuff for
them and dear
you know pen testing checking to Cox's
and I think they do this
mainly because of Europe acknowledging
the security flaws rated easier to not
have to deal with them
but they need to get the pen testing
this so
I think we'd be no when that happens
here's my here's my philosophical
anecdote
up writer I'll economists
philosopher nassim Nicholas Taleb wrote
this book called The Black Swan
and basically with the Black Swan effect
is
she with the Black Swan effect is
is this event totally random and
after happens you overvalued the
likelihood of that happening again and
it changes
and has a huge impact on changing
significantly
so like
he has a problem
them with this word random though to
because
randomness people like s randomness
nice throw the dice 16 sides its random
well no it's not its gonna land on wanna
six sides
if the data million sides is that random
know I'll up
billion now brandon is
throwing the dice and this projector
rose likes
and then each that piece at that pace
and then spit it back out
and the dice lands on potato that was
random
the dais is potato now and it's free my
copy
none of that stuff is in the scope %uh
but I stroll
and suddenly it happen so what happened
if that happened suddenly we be afraid
of potato that's
all the time would you like all crack
don't touch the dice you know get your
body scanned
patch heart bleed patch shell shocker
this is everything it's gonna happen now
we do need to
to worry about these things happening
but we need to be careful that we don't
over value them
so another guy umberto eco
burger ago
is Italian philosopher and he has an
extremely large
library about 30,000 books
pic and this thirty thousand book
library gets visitors
people visit his is T and they say wow
doctor Berto echo tyson's Spanish retire
something
and they say you have such a large
library
how many books have you read and so he
classifies people into two types:
the dumb ones that ask that and the
other people
because it's not about how many books
you've read
if you have a library of 30,000 books is
your goal to sit down everyday and train
read as many of them as possible no it
security your library
illuminating the things that you don't
know the things that are in the library
the books that you have internet there
those are far more valuable
because the books you have read you know
what's in them
you know that knowledge now but the
books that you haven't read
might have something really important
that you don't know yet so
this kinda pertains to to pen testing a
little bit rate
because it's the vulnerability that you
don't know about yet
it's the vulnerability book but you
haven't read
so I think it's about eliminating the
unknown
and I think the value of things that you
do know far outweighs the value things
you cannot
so type wrote Richie that make sense
no an indexer up
but that makes sense so talking about
the red team
360 no scope your site and what I mean
by this is
this is how I felt going from a
consulting pen tester
into a role where I'm reading all the
time and suddenly like
scope out the window and the goals are
different they're trying to snuff C
mealy
threat actors instead of trying to get
to sleep the network find the
vulnerabilities
your you're just playing back and for me
I was Forza
crazy it's the best thing ever and
yes got anything now you're also testing
defenses
you you you also testing defenses
because as your internet work
as you read teaming there should be some
defense in place
and that is something that you want to
get feedback on
break we'll talk about that later here's
my twelve steps to read cover
and I said four yet scrapping 5
gets me every time so
here scenarios got nice sort of Mike
okay with the goals when you doing
Pettini and I came up with a key hack
everything up
cause damage compromise intellectual
property right
and like I give the talk once an aside
was like that again haha
karach those those goals are yes the
school
but but really what's the purpose where
the actual goals
national goals are to be a change
catalyst for
your target because somebody somewhere
needs the funding somebody somewhere
needs new budget
and you're gonna help them either
realize that security is a big issue
or help them help someone else realize
that and then
you know leverage rate in the within the
business within the organization
the they need that leverage same thing
and then like for yourself
looking like a badass right cuz you want
to come out and pack everything
anyone have the results anyone feel good
about it now
couple restrictions note in our service
nope getting caught when you don't want
to
and no actual physical violence
II on my team ends up always
like is a was kidnapped in copies Han
mailed his family
that's how we'll get the domain admin
password well
up
maybe well let's no no physical violence
I mean it
so it's tough one week on
its step on it always week on you you
always have to refund your card and
would I be my this I do I mean like
scope them out on the Internet yes but
I think you should also him a call see
who answers the phone when you call them
see if anybody answers the phone i'd a
problem recently
work couldn't get ahold anybody at the
company because they're also
busy that's a problem I had to carry a
scenario in which
I'm important enough that they're gonna
call me back so you know if your
always worrying that your phone's going
to ring and you need to answer it and
pretend to be a different person
it makes for a stressful few days
anyways I you can stop by five the visit
strollin see if you can walk right in
the front door
see if it's a place that but everybody
walk right into the front door
if not maybe you can schedule an
appointment there
maybe you can find a way that they'll
let you in and then you know roseanne
stuff of course
a big part of this scoping
is identifying moments opportunity and
this is things like if the company has
an event going on
something outdoor where people are going
to be at publicly accessible
that's that's the way it if a company
has
recent press articles that say things
about them you can leverage that
information
you create a sense of mmm familiarity
for them
right slightly estabas slightly
establish trust
because of something that's happening
and you're talking to them about that
%uh
when companies get acquired it's great
everyone super confused
arm things are getting integrated
new people are showing up all the time
great opportunity
benefit enrollment periods for some
reason always working writes like a
your new health care provider is at this
link you go and register
and I also either use this companion app
and down i mean like its
people do anything to keep their
benefits we're they want healthcare
whatever so with Sep cue
after you scope your target Accu
figured out what kinda computers they
have after you figure out this kind of
stuff if took
roll some hour for them do you fire up
Metasploit like pop out a module
meaty if it's the right target
environment if they don't have like
treat detection if they don't have six
that are gonna sing on notice what's up
you're capable of getting something
that's gonna bypass things in their
network
totaling ayala I've been targeting a lot
are networks
works like start-up everyone's on wifi
there is no corporate network everyone
has a Mac Book so I decided to you
brought my on our
and I wanted it to be I want to be
flexible
I wanted them to be like over in a block
that IP when
and I just be able to move it easily I'm
so I ended up going to the cloud
using Amazon but also wanted to be
portable
so use papon so it ended up not portable
at all
but up and I wanted to be a lady to
troll
and we'll talk about that later also so
symbols good
because I'm lazy on how I feel about
that maybe you're lazy to you
so here's what I did: I made something
that runs in their box
use papon drops SSH keys
goes out to Twitter crowds a tweet from
a trigger handle
d called that into an IP address and
then sends a reverse
SSH tunnel up to Amazon Web server
wherever that IP address
results to then when I do with isse jin
et servers well
and that reversed hun allows me to ssh
directly into the box
using the private key and public key
pair that I drop on the box
super simple your some benefits
all my topics infected SSH Amazon
doesn't look super suspicious om
detection teams end up having a pretty
hard time with this
which I was glad about so here's a tutor
toxic let some
let's go for a double ok let's go five a
devil
thank you sir I could use a drink has my
steps to
giving a talk try to get one demo to
work so what I have
is a scripted that writes another script
because like I said I'm lazy I'd rather
run a script and get my output every
time
and not have to like go in edit hold
because I'm gonna mess it up
I got if I die
on stage I want to be buried under the
stage
so
here's it's an ugly scar I think I need
to write a script to write this script
because it's starting to get pretty ugly
and when I wanna make changes it's just
a
so here's what running the script click
in
so up in
good
it man re: and that's my demo thank you
so here's my cell maker and in here
there's a Python script called
snail maker scary isn't it
on I call it snail I honestly don't know
why it's not an acronym
I like adventure time and I like finding
the snail
so I thought blue team might like trying
to find myself so
that's why it's called that so I have a
lexicon
this lexicon is basically a dump upwards
I took something from the
I I actually don't even remember where I
took it from
trying up hey guys
knock it off an extra key
would you guys like to use as the XR ke
alright will make
will make five fives have heard
yeah hope the user name I'm connecting
into my server with
is called snail I think and the Twitter
handle is
for once an your
white by the way you can add
once for once in your life I want in
your life
to the end anything and make it funny
Lake I hope my demo words 5 once in my
life
kinda like that oh my god this is
red team says or something
i DK and what these are up is
tweet two letters so I just packed these
words on to the front and and
love the two weeks from the Twitter
account I first I was
lick scraping the the website Twitter
and just like finding the tags that
matter to me
and then describing the tweet from outta
there that works like a week until the
updated the site and the market changed
up issues my aunt letters and the
these are customizable course OSX
persistence
why not now
the way 2006 persons works is there
something called the launch team in and
dislodged a min
has a utility called launch CTL and
you can write a key west file and then
taught to load and the fewest file
basically like determines how it should
look so shit run
all the time yes it should run all the
time at startup
yes so what will happen is the operating
system will keep my python script
running in 20 yuan load this much
and if you don't know to look for it
kinda hard to find you see the weird
process heat up a conscript you kill it
find I get a new show on a second so
pretty
need persistence in
the
so obviously Asian
I'll show you what this ends up doing
well it does it has the second layer
text takes a bit to run
so here's what the script when it comes
out looks like
if you see here
I didn't want there to be any strings so
what I doing is I have my
X or encoded lexicon which is like the
64 X or an ice pack on all the letters
and numbers at the end
so that I have everything that I need to
form any string that i won
and the script will generate this
automatically as it gets compiled and
will happen is artistic indexes
into the string thats gibberish an
encoded
and then I'll construct my strings using
that string that way I have this
and right now are saying look at those
variable names that's pretty obvious
it comes out here here's my has me
running commands to electrophoresis
such round one about his cation gets rid
of those stupid stupid variable names
but you can still kinda see what's going
on
it's pretty easy to the park despite
print statements after everything
papon script after all
surround 3 does this you
this isn't that hard be 64 encoded
lambda the compact tax everything
together all the functions get the code
it in time and run
have the targets that come up against
have been able to decode this
which is good because there's some troll
ability to be happening at once they do
on figured out and I think ur
think I'm hours time minute printing out
my stuff
give me any 5's tells me all the stuff
that I typed in because I clearly
are ready for got it and the script as
many
I'm gonna wait to don't the script I'm
gonna the most mothers
at the same time okay
so here's what tweets come out
looking like but he says provide Pelican
pipe built
transform acid configuring york-new or
something condo
up
having a lexicon you use sometimes they
come are really funny sometimes not so
much
so
step 3: be like I got in and
how do you get in well you have to
normally fish someone
that it almost always comes down to that
for me either that work physically
showing up
up his messy sample show up
be there to you interview them
about their office because it's
beautiful
you wanna go around you wanna see
everything that they have one take
pictures
learn about their culture gonna learn
how often employees come into the office
at late at night
has it might be useful to know that you
get to see
all the computers that they have and
then you can view the photos here
okay on have a photo consent form you to
sign
up I didn't print it I'm really sorry
stupid
but could you please print this for me
and I'll be like yeah
and then you can the track to them they
plug into the computer and then you're
like
I'll I don't really remember where I put
it on the drive empty mind
great thanks double-click Mauer
the booklet PDF yet there you go works
every time
sixty percent of the time so
a couple other P text that I really like
being like I'm an IT
you have a problem on how to fix it ice
or
I'm from a company that you deal with so
you kinda party know us
a good one or I want a job and I'm so
awesome that you wanna hire me so bad
that you're let me come to your office
to interview or your except
any type up jar I hope based
demo that I've created because you wanna
see the cool stuff that I've done
one interview we talked about
or on a friend now you can
if the company uses Google Hangouts for
their communication which
a lot of them are starting to do now
you can't create whatever it gmail and
then
yes the company guess someone in the
company's email which is normally pretty
easy it's like first dot last
or you know first name first name the
last name
at if you get that right you'll
plus will pop up and you'll be able to
see up the person's
picture and what their name is on it and
then you can go to their profile
and you can literally copy everything
into your profile the photo
where they went to school any
information they happen Haasan
and how much you can do is you can just
message someone
in the company and what happens is
though at first
if the settings enable get things like
you want this is bottle of
but your email looks like their personal
gmail account like an iPad course
except and you're talking to them and
when you talk to them they don't
even see the email but you can use all
they see is the picture and Anne
so this works in till year
talking to someone and they're standing
right next to them literally
how much one time I was talking to
people
and I'm like hey mighty I needed to run
this
I'm okay course and then right is there
clicking it
ago security test like
home course not and i'm looking at her
always
has thing at a time like he hugged me
you that
things for your shell thanks 5 your
shell
thank those members the appear such
message okay
I think it's about time for the
collective Devils wish me luck
ahead now you guys are getting it
keep
good
solution here be fun okay so this one
Rd timed out good luck for me 5 me
is hard enough okay this is the cell
phone sucks going on
is gonna the bed who
okie
here we go obviously
keep in stock more than once and I
is five 5 now the way I drop this is
usually with a char
and I have another script to wrap this
up into a jar
and drop it and execute now it's by
highest can you count 123
pot okay so here's my server it's a
saying it's
I like him ready doesn't care
me it's just the server not better
I should be able to ssh
back into this box great it works
yeah hey miss hafer my cell phone come
on
I didn't think that was going to work so
here I am on a server
her on my box on Hum
dewey
okay on a demo what I'm gonna talk about
next just in case
%uh this connection dies so there's
something that
you can do right everybody what is the
easiest way to get someones password
after import great ask them
fight great in
so I'm not a script what this does
is generates it's a script to write a
script see anything here
it's a script that generates also script
commands both a script
is AppleScript interpreter for the
command line
it will run AppleScript what the
interpret for the fact checker
as I get better what it will do is
you can a tell any any application on
the system
to display anything or interact with the
goin
basically anyway so what I do is make a
pop-up box
here's what this looks like so I'm going
to pick an application
on my system top performers me and a
but see the pic something's going to be
on our target for sure
Hall ball 5 sure
how about guys have any preferences how
about System Preferences
someone
what we want to ask 5
heard right now
in reality what I would do is i'd say
software update requires that you enter
your password to continue
or KeePass
requires your password to continue or
name
anything you know 1password requires
your password to connect
servers down update like anything you
want you can ask them anything you want
and you can give the box any tight over
in a sec
and then here's mcmahon
and it's already been copied to the
clipboard for me because again
BZ here's what here's what it looks like
5 me
home chest yankee you come around
now
when I first did this you'd run the
first the run a simple dialog man and
you're saying tell ap System Preferences
to display dialog
I'm asking five your password default
answer with a Nikon
with hit an answer title5 and only the
OK button
that poppin is also OK now what will
happen is
it will bounce down on the dock and when
I see a bouncing ball click it
and I'll see the dialogue and me beat
reach out to me is like a like
how do you get it like Papa to the front
some like you can pop it to the front
that easy
I was not easy because system
preferences in particular
you tell it activity which is exposing
pop to the front and what happens is it
possible from
and then immediately goes to the
background so to the five ground and
then back to the background that so good
the worker home then I figured out is
you tell it to activate twice
and that works why I don't know
doc science
low all that's almost the whole command
strengthen
ok we'll get this I believe in us 0
okay and then here you have
password great super success
now let's go back to the presentation
I risk tonight her
so
what happens when you get in rate that
first step the first drop the shell
you have the shell everything's working
would you do normal guy
normal walk act natural play it cool
because the last thing you want to do is
drop into a box and then start scanning
the network by them if you've never seen
this video its great
not just that it's normal guy on a walk
or going to the grocery store
really good stuff and Om the thing that
takes YouTube videos and turns them into
gifts
is my best friend now some
so um the more you can commit normalcy
the more you learn about the environment
and then the easier it will be to move
around
and get access to things that you want
so your general strategy
is to going to be too in said public
final what there is
but instead of attacking the white find
the person who normally has access to
that
based on their wiki entries based on
their blog post based on their title at
the company
and then go after them and then just
follow them
we need to go so how do you figure out
where they go and what you might have
access to
dropper tool box look at bash history
see where pssh
anywhere has thats gonna be easy way to
get in
%uh you can look at nine holes another
good trick is
he paced so I use PT copy to get my
script by also script in my clipboard
pp case does the opposite peace whatever
you have in the clip or two
the mainline and that will work over SSH
session
so what you can do you is poppin their
box what's the last thing in their
support
I don't know let's find out he paced you
know what happens to me sometimes
their password thanks the way every
Password Manager works by copying things
into the court for a little bit
great also people send passwords to each
other
I was on site and engagement
the one girl ASCII other guy
Haiti what's the wifi password again for
our
private secure one he's like there's
trainers here
any I llame I'll send it to you through
the through the secure chat
just okay so then
are in in here you
wounded men take a drink on
and I would end up happening is he sends
it and then I get a show on his box
because he needs to print my for a
consent form has my photographer just
my photo consent I am a
my five harder for just took a picture
of him
and he does that I get the shell weepies
getting it my password thanks sonya is
her pickets
good way for lateral movement there's a
lot of information on that
I'm not going to give you any of it it
up there here's something that you may
not be familiar with
message control master to know your with
this
anybody yes so anyways
message control master is multiplexing
for SSH connections into service
so what happens is i connect I'm Joe
admin
i connect in and then I also need SEP
something
I don't get asked my password because I
already have an active connection
it uses my existing session with this
means to me
is that if I'm on your box and I see
that you just SSH someone
and the settings enable all I do is had
the same command you type
and I get SSH 10 I don't get prompted
for a password
market prompted for to them propagation
out a proper
anything he said 5 anything tomorrow
night at the string
perceived
sector in more spice
you have that new shell in there hope
up a socks5 proxy on it socks5 proxy is
made up US server now
I'm able to browse the internal network
I'm able to browse their internal wiki
I am able to find out things that they
don't have access to you
you wanna do the whole re concept again
their cheney this point now
and I've already said most this
you get but but seriously internal wiki
number one target after you compromise
an environment because
it it tells all everything that they
need to know to be an employee there
is normally on their wiki and we he's
almost never have to doctor of so soon
as you peace their password or propped
import
I did with also script you
you are on internal wiki and man
everything where the servers are how to
connect to them how admin them
perfect
on the next this is how I keylock
it is the most jane ki way pepper
%uh there's a command cop show key which
echoes out key strokes back to the
terminal
it runs for 10 seconds if there's no
activity so I wrote a paper on Raptr for
it
two stops into a file means it up a
little bit there are definitely better
ways to do this
here's the whole suspect stuff we talked
about and more importantly
this also works with Windows %uh I think
it was great cost
who saw my presentation was like that's
awesome
I'm gonna write a partial persian so now
there's a partial version out there
and then right before last night you the
stock cause was like
a or some NXT tech to clean up boom one
command
pop-up box password effect back to the
terminal
great look portability of a sign in
but I really okay so step 5:
on if you notice but every step has been
step 5 after step 5:
at a certain point
this tactic a following people is not
how work anymore
there's gonna be to thank her off that
you can't bypass
there's going to be something that you
need to know and you
won't be able to get it from the wiki so
how do you do this well you have to
learn
everything about the guy that you're
hurting see take screenshots
this system display equals Collins euro
gives you the screenshot of the user you
can't do you the screenshot command I
was using important this is for the
Knicks
it exists in OS X and other operating
systems well
I've links me
now there's a couple there's a couple
coppia
will talk about but you might need to go
harder than screenshots you might need
to just proxy all of their traffic
through upper plugin that sitting in a
WS
which we did so they may be
are you peeing into another box and they
do it from
their laptop the RDP into their my next
stop something like that
so which you can do is
if they're not really using RDP session
you threes the process
the screen doesn't change until they
realize its pros and kill it and then
you can
RTP while you're there now the thing
that sucks is like
they close their laptop they go home
like
you lose so you gotta do it while
they're there during the day so lunch
break free
trees are processed go in do whatever
you need to do you set up everything
back the same way it was
and a hope we can hack it cut now
hope we knock it hot like
people going to get suspicious if you
didn't switch shots if you're
as a teaching tool box you doing on a
stop if their admins
they're gonna have the know-how to
figure it out so it ends up happening is
some
the first time I did this a screenshot
thing I'm smart was like
you know what there's probably a sound
plays every time someone takes a
screenshot
so I'm gonna go on rename the file an
they're not going to hear the sound
throws me that's exactly what I did
it works great on the one person that I
remember to do it to you
so disliked by people trying to figure
out who goes where who has access to the
secure environment
and these guys they're listed in the
Spotify or whatever and
each sheik sheik all day
some hope and they're like my heart EP
sessions
frozen again and and then he'd they look
at who's a cessation I like
that's weird that this other admins as a
teaching in the white box like
up
so hike hey security at company
screenshots are you picking up my
computer
I find this hi We suspect very classy
right
so already can help don't worry
her mind by mistake sorry you not a
security from that guy cuz we have
access to everything including his
email and quick side note
you know you pop on OS X Box Linux box
dump cookies throw those cookies into
your browser
you're locking in their email doesn't
matter if they if you factor of
whatever so they send this mistake
hey are we send a mistake for them I
guess and we also
do a little maintenance on your inbox
any most common back from security
doctor any emails that say that word
screenshot just in case we miss it
filter for such good
helpers so moving on to Step 5
get hot but has yet he said
Kit Kat well yeah don't get caught you
don't want to you
however you should want to at some point
some point you gonna get access to
everything
or you're going to get as far as you can
and
you you check your cock there's value
for the blue team
5 the blue team hot skillet are done
playing the game
now his so-called on artist TRICARE up
if you need to make extra noise to do
this if you're if you're not stealthy
and they're still not detecting you
agree
like make extra nice you could do this
by network scanning
if there's an IDS device great it's
probably gonna pick up a nap stamp drop
in Metasploit better per bottle on a
server
run things against but not like do
whatever it takes to make noise to do
those things that
you know you're like this is going to be
cut do those see if you cut because
if you do those things that you thought
would get you hot and you don't get
caught that is a finding
an important one because they have a
incident response team they have a blue
team and suddenly you're like a poutine
why did you catch this and not OG's like
I we all know
so any define a treetop
you define that threshold and then when
you do get hot something really
magical happens it's my favorite part
because
you get caught and suddenly the game
changes for you
it was all about attacking in
penetrating before and now it's all
about persisting
summer that step troll ability this is
where that comes in
because they find him our and they
figure out your
depiction great the first thing I do as
soon as in an
everyone's knee-jerk gut reaction when
the final like and ensuring our system
is to just start playing whack-a-mole
killing every single thing they can find
great I'm hours got persistence is gonna
keep coming back
until you are able to get to that user's
box
figure out what the Mauer does figure
out how is persisting and remove it
or bottom of the network their mole use
it it's not an easy thing to do
if you don't it's a response it hard so
if I prefer whole
my IP address is fluid exchange with
Twitter buddy in the book to better
AB no one's done that yet he did on time
they called Twitter up
got a slight the account taken down so I
was good
and you know be random so maybe mine are
on our calls up for Twitter & they look
like
okay who's talking to Twitter and who
has an SSH connection and logic
that's gonna find people with them our
well I know all
that you copy because you're playing
whack-a-mole with my shells
so I made a new shell
on another system and it's completely
different
great go ahead please optimal figured
out so
here's what you T mchugh it you reverse
them our
got a good team your personal our your
great call up for Twitter to this IP
address here's what we're gonna do
or not blocked them in real-time
to be dismayed that's the new CTU we
called it
bucket perfect
any problem with this you autumn
aqui blocking IP address that I i meow
a problem cool when you IP is this
menu appears that might expect his
Google my neck said he is your company's
website
my next five years any resource that you
can only access
who that's what dost I'm not doing it we
teams doing it
next trolololol
so
next to last at I think Sep 5
is to rampage because at this point
is still got that one little extra shall
I didn't find great
now's the time to do every risky thing
that didn't you before because you were
trying not to get caught your cock
you're still in
this is Hannah suck down a source code
x2 all the deities
do whatever it takes to show them
that use it in UN
right must look like a badass hope we
don't do this but if you are able to do
this
big finding thing is he with you in some
spots maybe
but everything is to come to an end
I'm
and the last ep when things do come to
an end
is to drink and drank what you should do
is you should take
blue team out for Richard if your red
team you've been making blue team's life
hell right and retaining its not about
making blue teams like hell
it's not testing the security of your
organization rate
or your target organization so their
people to you on the other side
rate is not red versus blue it's well
it's reversible
but you're still people its people
hanging out with people
you have a drink yet get to talk about
what went wrong
the stupid things that you messed up
one-time I was wrong on my see to use
use in like Twitter in the last text up
a notch
yeah but you would just copy the
Amazon instance and you never change the
certificate that you used for an HTTPS
postback
so we just could assert my how out
so now I'll and then I'm like and we did
this and you can find
up a dull an hour of friends additional
yes but or friends
in alright your Bilderberg
backup job who cobbling
that was necessary right does anyone
have any questions
ok
inspired me back there arm
so back
with netcat doesn't meet my other
question was you notice that
iSSH back down into the box instead of
just receiving
forever shall up the reason I did it
that way
is because I want to use SSH has
built-in
if I use netcat made it on a system
perhaps
by it is not accepted so I accepted
version of.net cap it's going on system
that isn't on the system by all so
message was accepted at it with easy I
could drop the keys
and work like that arm the receiving the
river shells
there's ways to do it I'm lazy this was
the easiest way
that's why
18 don't care yes yeah
arm
she
so the questions that have you ever
heard dealt with having the external
data
and it's Nick regulated data I assume
you mean like things that are
extremely sensitive PIII social security
numbers eccentric such a researcher
up yep hey don't get hacked %uh
the ideal thing is that red team get
signed off in a way
that CEO says you what hackers with you
thank you for that school because we
will do what happens with you if you get
to take that data
you make the impact do they have to
disclose it
no I still technically work for them or
I'm employed by them
yeah I went to a server yeah wall fell
PCI if they find out about it
but server gets crop everything it's
tweeted shredded
no harm no foul docket hacked I guess
yeah
we don't talk about that a good question
s yet my problem
that's why they cannot find a date on my
thing that's why
you know i mean yeah if I cared about
compliance and regulation
I wouldn't be dredging
you know I don't know you're right
but I guess I guess it be interesting to
try and you are a team engagement where
you stay like compliant with
every law kinda oxymoron
I guess and the questions
the new
because thank you