people know me as UNIX Rick's JP
sometimes have a problem what this light
the size is not match okay this is gonna
be a problem
god this better and then right now I
have okay I'll be honest with you I have
90s lights and I have 30 minutes so you
have to follow my speed and then let's
talk about the questions outside so
introduction is I'm an IR person in real
life in the cyber emergency center I'm
handling also the advanced cyber threats
and research team and representative of
my JSOC in the first member so my
community give back is in mellow burst I
try to let write many things in Japanese
and in English in in different blocks I
do the Linux malware research and right
now I stopped blogging in the power bus
die block but sweetie to read it
I make Linux more raided mods over there
so feel free to put your RSS for
following over there
I'm research I'm a lecturer I have one
student from Japan coming here and for
the malware teaching University students
about how to handle my wares and
teaching in the about the ICS securities
for the government so activities in rad
arise not so much but together with
pancake we built our 2jp hopefully we
will start to do to do something soon
and we still learning much but run away
from you guys and yeah introducing
rudder as much as possible too
and then I'm the only lecturer who
actively using Radha in the security cam
in Japan the old Japan security cams we
pick like 80 genius gets over Japan's
and we we try to I try to tell them but
rather and it works so I'm a UNIX person
open source and then the free bears
previously users so there are some stuff
what free basically over here and not
rudder in native please forgive me and
then okay I'm a I'm a block you in the
Twitter but maybe not me my script maybe
so if you are broke please ask to me
later and then I feel happy to get out
from the users ports and make uninstall
the radaway over there and then go to
the github but I have the night better
after that and then yes these are the
person that I met first time is a Zillo
warm and then through fire a pancake and
and Antone thank you for coming to Japan
and then yes through fire is never
sleeps and I am known now as a garbage
55 according to my discussion with my
Jean so in what corner Paul was greeting
to me I never had the chance to greet
him back so this is my grid for Paul if
you see this light later on so I'm
talking about its binary Packers and
then yeah I will share it to you but my
methods in analyzing the ite W Packers
in the realistic ways so there is no
anything just a practical easy
and fast my mace at all out and then all
methods presented here are with the
screenshot so most of the peas are
screenshots so I can I think I can make
it in the 30 minutes so let's go
okay the contents is separated into
three parts at the visor some soup main
course main course is long so appetizer
is a buddy we expect her but there are
so many
final hour you pay expect our cannot be
wreck by by some people so I think yeah
you have to Jen but you have to fire
rather a first then everything would be
okay then we will go to the first part
now there are three types that are seen
so far about the final ie pigs you
people hackers or attackers are messing
with the bytes so you have to fix the
headers either the elf healers or the
program header so you have to know
exactly but what the haters are number
two is yes dynamic analysis is very
important for the spec analyzing pikers
too and then there are several ways in
the memory packing and generally can be
applied to all well the rest is you can
read it later in this light and then
there are three parts that I want to
share here you pigs header rewriting
methods the second is a source code
modifications and then the unpacking
method if it doesn't work in the post
cases so this is elf headers what's
wrong with this header do you anyone
knows okay make it fast these are how
the correct way to read the headers so
this is the upx type kind of tweak one
actually the the upper one is the elf
headers and then they are having a fee
program headers entry 0 and 1 and then
following by the upx header you have to
know this otherwise the the little kid
hacker can fool you and make big your
time like 3 hours you're not putting in
things in the right place so ok this is
the right way to read headers in Arad
ourselves thank you for the my Jean
untold for showing me this command I
didn't know until I had the training so
practically PF p f dot the elf header is
very powerful then this is my way for
doing it I use a elf dump in the freebsd
openbsd netbsd it has it so
practically the result is the same but
that is the way you see it is a quite
different end up in the elf dumb part of
the form of the data are decimals part
or hexadecimal so you have to count it
back and it's okay
you can do that and then therefore the
program headers this is also the right
way to read it by the right error and
then that you can doing the same with AF
them this elf dumb is using the - P the
first one is a - E so where am I
okay so many unlimited variations of
this kind of the tweaking elf - for the
upx so you have to really bear with a
header what bytes by by bytes and for
example sometimes you just loading the
elf by your hand on worry you don't have
to do the for example the - n or - an N
but you can search the magic and then
you can start the PXA from there and
then rod array will be kindly show you
oh this is for the header stuff like
that so you can do it there very quick
but this is the correct way to do it you
you just load it with - N and then you
can make it a breakdown like this this
is a very beautiful one so understanding
those and then you can check with
whether the devel is correct or
incorrect so you can have to fix it one
by one so I'm gonna show you how you
have to remember this and then that is
the only way this is for the interest
rate 32 bits header of the EPX is having
stuff like that most mostly all you have
to focus it says this part because of
they cannot mess so much with headers
because of the program should run anyway
this part is our the one with the mark
with the red color is our the part that
they are tweaking mostly and then for
example in this case is if we put back
to the right places and you can dip a
kit easily with a - D
just like that and then if the things
gone wrong
just check which bit it's not in it's
not correct and these are the comments
that you can do for it and you can route
it like that
use this the middle come on over there
can be used it has the YouTube video
here feel free to take the picture
during I'm talk for the screen if you
need to see it soon this light will be
edited a bit because there's so many
pop-up and then I will share it within a
week then some hack of the source code
also exists in that case you have to
down you have to debug it and find
weather which one was crossing it or the
error will come up and then after after
that you have to compare the source code
in this case the pack header size was
tweaked into the another custom one so
all you have to do is record it again
and then you have to compile the effects
and neuron the - D and 90% should be
working if not then you have to try
again well on memory packing with the
archer is quite easy
I'm not having any kind of the fancy
environment in my email work I'm using
only BSD servers so I access it from the
term it is the only way that I'm doing
Marvis day until now so you are running
like a dis process it's running all the
time all you have to do is put it in the
debug mode or you can do it with SEO
depends on the matter like per explained
if only independent cause being used you
can simulate everything with the AC and
I prefer you to do that and you can
stepping in the hood mode like this so
this is a debugging Rada in the
environment of the UNIX OS and sample of
the panel I youpix was there if you're
running it correctly in the part of the
memory you can see the elf and then you
can see the header and then the you can
unpack the elf directly to memory and
this is the way to do it step by step is
almost as is
also the same with the windows 1 okay
these are the binary that if you want to
practice you can take the picture of it
so you can stick it in the virustotal it
was there ok can I continue yes ok so
everything is ok now so another peckers
is not only PX i analyze about the burn
i there is a f encrypt errors there is
siva
there is being protect burn is a good
for practice has a cryptid password
protections and basic packing in elf of
to it I'm not so sure whether open
source or elixirs and but it has a the
compiled applications in the sequel's in
many way so it's a very good for the
research FN pepper is also good but
doesn't do much sophisticated one it's
used a virtual virtual address here and
there and obfuscated again in office
case unification it's not very fun but
it has a password protection sefa is
interesting and and III recommend you to
have a safari and and you can of my 27
minutes seriously ok ok this is the
table you can see it later it has a good
Simon really good source these are the
site that you can see where are be
careful because of in the filtration
will be blocked probably it is the site
is still up VM protect is a very
sophisticated one I think much of you
know see it and then you have to
download it to the forum for the Linux
ones and then in this interface it will
be Rossia languages and then you can ya
know tweak it any kind of level of the
vm Baccarin with this packer ok these
are the cool backpackers that actually
exist now is in the get help like it has
to make me get back nigga space is very
good because it has such talents and
response I hope I connected to the
Internet
if not then you have to take the picture
and then okay it's not connected so it
has also the polymorphic of frightened
one this is a very seriously important
backer and then every time you you
execute it there has will be differences
there is a Packer l4 is this very simply
six up for you for example if you want
to really build something and then we
want to develop the Packer but you don't
know the base you can use this the other
one is if you love ps2 there is appears
to specific micro and it is very
interesting because modular design was
used and the last one is a very
important kind of wrapping up from the
old packer and then I've being used
again so I'm going to the how many
minutes okay this this is the the main
course I don't know the name of the
packer I I'm not so sure and I found it
in the world so it is fair it is
impossible for static aesthetically
unpacking this one so I named it this
way for for this conference
only then the spot in the thread public
secrets health sector probably in the
some targeted sectors to and then it's
really file elisa for forensics and then
obviously it's hiding a very important
informations in the original binary and
then that is a reason why make it even a
little bit difficult for packing
unpacking this one
so the elfis look like this if you see
it correctly it looks like a plain elf
but it is not it is actually back you
can analyze with like you are analyzing
the upx before it has two sections over
there and in this excerpt very important
is the base address was in this always
be in the section program hitter zero
and the actual execution will be running
in the entry one but it's not one this
is the if you were reading in what the f
is going to be like this if you see it
with the object down is going to be like
this
there's not so many clue for this pecker
it has no string at all so you'll be
probably what the hell is this
I was said like that in the first time
so I'm gonna explain to you the
character of this Packers so it will be
easy for you to recognize the first goal
is to the area where the unpacking
function is actually exist and then
afterwards that is the this is the sub
proteins that will was being called in
the first place in the entry is 0 and
then it will pack it will load evil
called
unpacker loader and then the antico
Luger will load the data in the loader
program it was addressed in here it was
under that there is a little blob of the
data and after that the loader logic
will load the pack data from the address
this is the exact address that will be
used with this Packer and you it will
operate under the reserved address of
this and then the after the unpacking
successful it will push the the the de
pack binary in the 400,000 hex address
and if you see the loader that actually
being loaded in in this part here the
the function I cannot read it 0 0 5 0 0
5 5 e C 2 T function is actually having
the good sequence of the M upload exit
right exit stuff like that it's never
changed so after doing those and then
the the de pack binary was loaded it it
will be in the office cated form so the
next step of this n 3 0 will be office
key D obfuscation the binary and it
looks like this in red array it it's
really stressful so the text is very
very small like this so you can imagine
that the first time seeing is like this
so I have to borrow another stuff the
graphical for this to understand this
office keys in layer like a 5 or
six like this so it is it is the reason
of up the obfuscation aloo player like
this is a to avoid us using the
emulations for the de packing proposed
lady said way I'm thinking about so in
this point probably it will be better if
we just debug it and then a put the
breakpoint in somewhere down here and
then just dumb the result afterwards
I'm not so sure is it working or not but
it works then the unpacked binaries
written and exact in the base address of
four hundred thousands with the same
image name and then you can use ACL to
see the process mirror like this in the
bigger part this is the one of the
characteristic of this a packer that you
can really really want to detect and if
you want to make a signature you can use
it and thank you for the PD DAA
this is a very very easy to analyze with
this kind of you just see there the
right side and compared with the left
side I really love this one so huh
then after you you you found the the the
binary was successfully at the back it
will form the real elf and then you can
see the string is really fully defect
and then the result is like this and I
found it it's a tiny egg xmm owner there
is only one analyzes about the tiny XML
moon or doesn't even showing about how
to re dis Packer so probably nobody
nobody can do this for before or doesn't
publish it I'm not so sure but why the
tiny XML mooner is not having the source
code to be you know as a miner for
example because of this elf is also
having own decryption functions I saw
and then I was thinking after doing some
running it with the debugger so we found
that there is some identification
over-the-air up there
well actually the mining ID and pull
server address was encrypted so in some
cases our planes into but most are are
in
that one so actually this this elf is
actually electing the user mining with
preset configuration the pool server
with abusing the donation functions it
is grabbing all of the donation
functions of the XM Ric which is not
supposed to be changed so I am as an
open source guy I think this is an abuse
for the miner program so but I
understand that why he is trying to
cover this with a packer so this is the
I try to exactly this much as possible
and it will show it over there the data
then yeah after you're running the
program and then you make us simple
analysis this is what actually the DISA
XM air are tiny exam our moon er is
doing and then the next questions how
many of the dispatcher is actually exist
in the internet quite a lot I found
another one
another type of the binary was back with
this I found me I was back with this so
I'm not so sure what the source of the
this Packer well when I found first Mira
it wasn't really packed but the the
thing is there is no reference at the
time but when I saw the inside of this
Packer is me right so it's probably not
so expensive to for the hacktivist can
can use it right so if you see this
Packer if you know the name just name it
and then the let the people knows in
this matter it goes for the first
loading loader for the unpack it goes to
the dysfunction in the same way to load
the binary for the loader after death
the loader is a having this the same
steps like a map load exact right can
then go to the exit over here and then
the actually the actual a pack data is
always be in the this addresses and then
yeah it has a this supposed to be elf
but sometimes it doesn't sound EF though
is this in the obfuscated state it
so this is not the upx Packer I'm sorry
but here so if you do the debugging you
can see the its it is executed in the
same base address as per previously I
explained with the previous samples so
the inside is XM rig and if you unpack
it good you can see everything in the
memory well I just run it afterwards to
make sure so this is the one I don't put
any kind of users and in config even in
it goes not the donation one but good
exactly the pull server of the attacker
was really implement planted into the
binaries so this is the POC that it's it
is using the user some not login
something and in the pass is gonna be X
something like that and these are the
blockchain of the this what attacker use
I'm not so sure that whether the bone
arrow can be traced from this point but
this is actually that the the part of
the XML burner or XM Rick was abused as
per said over there this this donation
part is you know it's a only for
donation but actually being used for the
hard coding diseases access for the pool
ID and what yeah identifications and the
pools River I tried many things okay I
was in Japan quite a lot so like I food
I put the users of food like that and it
goes still do the same one just to make
sure it is not working in the the way
that I analyze it in the statically or
debugging before and this is the sample
for you so you can put get it with the
picture if you interest it and then you
can get it somewhere in the virustotal
so the conclusion is a health pack or
packers are a full thing so
we don't have to forget the basic of the
executable f itself in order to
understand about this stuff Pegasus will
be always be there to protect binaries
and I agree with that but though we
don't like it but we have to you know I
learned to enjoy reversing them and then
just do it it with r2 and then
everything will be okay so there are
many recommendation for the reference
but III always strict the basics for for
it and then I strongly suggest you to
use this reference and these tools the
the first up one are using in a very
much Idid FN reference for the Linux
itself and binary itself
yeah in the practical level this tooling
is very good and if you want to install
yourself dumb there is a source code of
it in here so you can just grab it
I think the the the fight on elf tools
is a very powerful but you have to
install it by yourself I don't use it I
saw I don't know about that there is
also the elf two tool chain that
probably very good but it's not quite
new so thank you for the pancake for the
invitations and then to the rudder a
team over there who is always helping me
showing me the wrong commands and I try
to fix the presentation with new
commands so yeah so if you see the
packer blog it in from people's and then
try to put it somewhere the hashtags of
the rad array and presented in the net
next article that's all are sorry for
I'm not so quite good in talking in the
public so if you have any questions you
can ask now
or else
[Applause]
questions okay thanks
bodyguards in ops
[Applause]