right okay sorry about that so I've been
working at a company designs processors
for 13 years now and something that I'm
more and more amazed that the longer I
work there is this simple fact that
processors are incredibly reliable I
mean they're not completely reliable
right I mean they do occasionally fail
you know we hear about bugs and
processors but it's such a rare thing
that if you and I were to make a list of
all the processor bugs we've ever heard
of we would probably have like 9 out of
10 things in our list would be the same
fact we probably wouldn't even get to
tend to be honest so I'm going to be
talking about how it is that processors
are actually amazingly close to being
you know completely correct how do we
actually achieve that so if you want a
more technical version of this a over
the information this talk I've put links
in the slides I put my slides on my
website afterwards you can grab the
links from there
Mattie Suze talked a yesterday is also
related to this and I wonder if anybody
was in Johnny Austin's workshop
yesterday where we had a bunch of humans
pretending to be a different parts of a
computer modeling a five-stage pipeline
I was also kind of quite quite similar
and good fun so ok so processors always
work this is because there's a sort of
tension going on so it's a renewal in
this so these are a atten going on in
creating a processor on the one hand you
want it to be correct and another you
want it to be fast and these things are
completely in opposition to each other
it's really hard to make something
correct and fast and so this is a talk
with a villain and a hero and the
villain in this sorry Sam maker face
also bad news the villain is in fact the
designer he's trying to make things
faster and unfortunately as he tries to
do that he inevitably introduced
introduces bugs can you turn down the
sound a wee bit I'm getting a lot of
echo it's a bit distracting okay
well that could work too so a the
designer is busy introducing bugs and
making it go faster too meanwhile the
hero is the person trying to find those
bugs and help fix them so okay so the
verifier is pushing back against the
designer and in our commercial processor
the verifier usually wins because a fast
process was nice correct processor is
critical you don't have a you know no
one's interested if it mostly works so
the verifier will usually win the battle
over is this too complex a feature to
add and the verifier is helped by a some
useful tools which I'll be describing in
this talk at a fairly high level they're
called Sat solvers and bounded model
checkers not very sexy names but there
you go okay so what I'm going to do in
this talk is I'm going to kind of look
at this switch back and forth between
correct and fast and I'm going to start
with a very simple processor and I've so
what I've done here is I've taken a an
early MIPS processor and I've tried I've
simplified it down just by kind of
piecing over some of the complicated
features in it so it's probably so more
or less correct with my book Sharia
applied to it let me just quickly go
through the main bits of the processor
so working from left to right before you
can execute an instruction you need to
know what instruction you're going to
execute so you take your program counter
from the green box you hand it to the
memory and it gives you back an
instruction the Zener you then have to
figure out what the instruction means so
you decode it as traditionally that
block is shown in white in diagrams like
this and so I followed that from a
tradition of the decode logic is
and white so that you can't actually see
it it's the most complicated part the
processor we always leave it out the
pictures
so once you've decoded instruction that
gives you all the control signals to
control all the rest of the circuit so
the next bit is from the dream bit in
the middle the register file you read
some inputs and then you hand that to
the ALU which can do arithmetic addition
subtraction comparison and the values
and you can also pass the values to the
memory if you want to read a write
memory and then when you're all done the
results are go in this big backward a
path back over to the register file
where a you can update any registers
you've got okay so that's that's very
quickly what processors like oh I should
also mention that there's these little
gray boxes I don't know if you can quite
see them they're labeled mocks or
multiplexer they were switch which
selects different inputs and and those
are absolutely critical when you're
worrying about a process are being
correct because if something's already
always connected to the same thing
there's a good chance you'll spot when
you get it wrong you know if you're if
you got the wrong information there if
you keep switching from one thing to
another it's very easy to switch to the
wrong thing or to sometimes have the
wrong information and on there on an
input and not really realize it because
you're not selected so the Mocs is again
little itty bitty boxes don't look very
significant that's where a loss of bugs
will occur is in those little boxes but
anyway we've got a processor I've
simplified it down so it's really just
getting one pipeline stage one time say
taken to go from wanting to fiction
instruction with all the way around to
you've executed instruction and written
back the results the register file so
it's about as simple as you can make a
processor now having done that the
remember the hero is the verifier and
we're wondering well does it work so how
do we check if something works well we
test it
so what what can attest we run I I'm
guessing most of your more software
people and hardware people but it's the
same either way if you want to check
something you just kind of make a list
of all the functionality you might have
all the weird corner cases you're gonna
worry about and that gives you a bunch
of cases that you ought to consider
testing and then once you've got that
you then decide well how many tests so
want for each case and if it doesn't
matter matter much whether it works or
not
then yeah you know maybe one test for
every 10 cases is good enough right you
know that's what I do in my hobby
projects if you're a bit more serious
maybe you want one test per case 50,000
you need a million how much is it gonna
cost if it goes wrong yeah how bad how
hard will it be to replace it so you
come up with you play around with this
and you decide how much tests and you
want to do so that's the traditional way
of checking the processors right oh but
before we get one to the less
traditional the modern way let's think
about we've got our tests now we need to
think about running them so we've got a
processor and we can run some programs
on them but how will we know if the
program did the right thing
well organ at one cesare a reference
that we can compare against so this
might be a simulator or it might be your
friend is also implementing the same
processor and so he's got another
implementation and he's smarter than you
so maybe he's put less bugs in it or
maybe because he's smarter than you he
got too clever and he put more bugs into
it but either way you're hoping he's got
different bugs
all right so you've got a reference to
compare against and then you can just
take all the individual parts of the
state of the processor and compare them
and so we can run tests through that and
we're quite happy but instead of just
running tests there's another way using
a formal verification air tools which we
use so there are tools which will take
two circuits and compare them to tell
you whether they're exactly equivalent
to each other
okay so in the industry those are called
logical equivalence checkers you also
hear people talking about sat solvers
which are slightly more flexible version
of the same thing and what these do is
you see well let's take every possible
state we could a sarten all possible
instructions we could think of executing
all possible contents of memory and then
just check that these two circuits are
going to do exactly the same thing no
matter what so the beautiful thing about
this is you don't have to think about
testing right because it just tries
everything it uses it doesn't brute
force it that would be too hard it uses
sort of various mathematical tricks to
try to reduce the number of things it
has to err check but it's doing
something privileged checking for all
possible inputs that these circuits are
equivalent to each other so you don't
need to think of any test which is great
because I hate thinking about tests it's
just not fun right so this will make up
the test for you and think of all the
things are things you should have been
thinking of testing that you forgot the
really nice tools when you can use them
okay so that's us at the start of this
cycle so we're on the end of we've got
something that's correct but possibly
slow so now I'm going to look at a
simple optimization which people always
do to this kind of processor which will
make it a bit faster so the processor a
kind of did a the work in two stages
remember it started off by fetching an
instruction and decoding it and then in
the second phase of execution a it's
it's kind of adding results it's writing
them two registers and so on and plus
it's fishing you don't know what the
right-hand side that they ALU the memory
be doing suicidal and once you've
fashioned decoded something you can't do
anything because a you know you've got
to wait until they execute unit finishes
and so designers hate this kind of thing
Hardware sitting idle I hate that so
standard technique is say instruction
pipelining and with instruction
pipelining what we're going to do is
we're going to double the clock
frequency and and then while we're
executing the first instruction doing
the arithmetic or memory access we're
going to be at the same time fetching
the second instruction while we're
executing that second instruction will
be fetching the third while we're
executing the third what we're facing
the fourth and so on
you get read double performance all
right so this is a technique IBM came up
with in the 60s it hits micro processors
and the mid-eighties a very common
technique and so here's the the
processor with a little bit more of it I
was looking over a restored there's this
green bar down the middle and that green
bar is a bunch of pipeline registers
it's remembering a can the first
instruction it fetched a while it's
executing that and that leaves the
left-hand side is now free to start
fetching the the second instruction so
instruction pipelining is a pretty
common thing and what we want to do now
is a check to see if we've introduced
any bugs in there in doing this so how
are we going to do that well let's start
with the the reference circuit so we've
got a reference circuit and the
processor is going to be executing two
instructions at a time
so I'm actually going to want to check
both instructions and so I'll put in two
copies of the a of the reference circuit
and I'll just connect the output the
final state of the first circuit into
the a starting state of the next circuit
right so that's just going to execute
two instructions in sequence and then
I'm going to do the same thing with the
processor that I want to check so I'm
going to make two copies of that and
again I'm going to add in some data
paths
so that the final state of the first
processor gets copied over into the into
the final and intermediate state so that
first processor gets copied into the
next processor so I'm gonna forward that
to that data over and then I'll add the
checkers
so this that's probably feels like it
might be a little complicated to do
fortunately there are tools which will
do it which I'll mention a bit later on
but what I have now is something where I
can feed you two instructions into this
processor and check that the board is
going to execute correctly and again the
is formal verification tools will just
check for all possible pairs of
instructions all possible initial States
so I don't have to come up with tests
but as I say I can also use testing
right I can just run one processor
against one reference and check for bugs
the usual way whichever one I do a
problem is probably not going to be very
long before I run into a bug that looks
a little bit like this a branch
instruction followed by well pretty much
anything because that style of processor
that I just showed you is prone to our
bug that occurs after branch
instructions so what goes wrong in
branch instructions well let's think
about how the pipeline is going to be
executing this so at the same time as
let's say executing the the previous
instruction I was fetching the branch
then next clock cycle I move on and I
start to execute the branch instruction
to figure out where I should branch to
PC plus 100 and at the same time I'm
fetching the add instruction then in the
next cycle everything moves forward and
I go to execute the add instruction but
why am i executing the add instruction
because that branch sorry I shouldn't
point at my screen I should point there
perhaps the the branch instruction
is telling me not to execute the next
instruction it's telling me to go off
somewhere else and execute that and said
but what's happening is I will always
execute the instruction immediately
after a branch so the several ways of
thinking about what's happened here one
is and is to say that this is a bug
that's a pretty common opinion these
days that you're after a branch you
always execute an instruction
immediately after but they tighten that
people started pipelining microsensors
there was another opinion which was say
it's not a bug it's a feature and they
give that feature a special name so that
you would know it was a feature
definitely not a bug so it's called a
branch delay slot they were very popular
at the time in earliest processors they
kind of fell out of favor later because
if you try to claim that every single
bug you put in your processor is
actually a feature then it's very hard
to make the second processor have
exactly the same set of bugs and of
course it's gonna add some new bugs of
its own so then your third process
becomes really hard you've got to get
all the old bugs and then persuade
people that the new bugs are features as
well so nowadays people tend not to put
this kind of thing in in a processor
architecture they admit it's a bug and
they fix it and I the usual way of
fixing it is that when you see you
already execute a branch instruction you
say well let's just hold off and
fetching the next instruction until I
know for sure whether I need it that's
one solution so that's called stalling
the pipeline and another one is to go
you know what I'm just gonna go ahead
and fetch it anyway you know what I
might even start executing it a little
bit but I'll only go so far in executing
it and hope nobody notices if I end up
having to cancel it so you your guess
that you might want to execute
instruction and then if you didn't need
it you can select quickly before anyone
notices and that's called speculation
which has been in the news a lot
recently by about this year because it
turns out that some
people can sports speculation and turn
it into security calls so well less sure
how to get around that one okay so so
we've seen we added an optimization
various ways of testing and verifying it
and we've got a bug and let's imagine of
putting a fix for it now having fixed
that I want to check this one did I fix
it and two other any more bugs I should
worry about so what am I gonna taste
well I've got all my original instructor
air tests I started off with right you
know it doesn't add really add can add
big numbers and small numbers and so on
obviously I'm gonna add a whole lot of
tests for branches because I now know to
be worried about that but is there
anything else I should be worried about
in that processor huh I'm not sure my
confidence is a bit shaken now so I'm
gonna try and think of what makes peers
of instruction interesting and then I'm
gonna taste all of those and this is
kind of black magic experience asking
your friend what he tests you know it's
a you know it's it's hard to know you've
actually tasted everything you need to
and that just so it can emphasize it
that's where the formal verification
techniques are really helpful because
you don't have to come up with lists of
peers of instructions it will just test
a lot okay
so I've gone one round through this
cycle take a create process I'll make it
faster but broken finds and bugs and fix
it so that's an added that by going from
a one stage quite plain to a two stage
pipeline well what would be better than
a two stage pipeline for most people the
answer is a five stage pipeline so that
with five stages we take that original
diagram I had and it had about five
major steps in it and we make each of
those be one major step in execution and
what I'm going to do then is have my
five pipelines each row in this diagram
is busy doing one of those five steps
and
is that once it gets up to speed I'm
executing five instructions at once I'm
working from the bottom upwards I'm
racing back the results of the first
instruction while I'm doing the memory
access for the second instruction I'm
doing the doing the arithmetic for the
third I'm decoding the fourth I'm
fetching the 1/5 so I'm keeping all the
bits of the hardware busy and this makes
a designer really really happy and it
tends to make the verifier a bit less
happy so let's just here's the here's
the original sacher as I downloaded it
off of Wikipedia with all the pipeline
stages they're shown so the pipeline
stages are these big vertical green bars
that just capture the bit that was just
calculated and make it available in the
next time step to the next part of the
circuit and what can I do to verify this
well I've got the same option as before
one copy of the reference circuit one
copy of the processor and then I had
some comparison logic to just compare
them and then I can run all the tests I
want and this I can a yeah I can run
lots of tests on it so I'm a perfectly
happy with that but if I want to do the
formal verification then I'm going to do
something similar to what I did
previously when I had two copies of the
reference two copies of the processor
but I'm going to have the same it's a
five stage pipeline so I'm going to have
five copies of the reference and five
copies of the processor so I can model
five instructions at once except this
may not be quite enough because if you
remember the fix for that that's a
branch err related bug was that
sometimes instructions could get stalled
and if I'm stalling instructions they
may not take five cycles to get all the
way down to the end of the pipeline they
may times sometimes take six cycles so
I'd better add another stage and well
maybe I could have two instructions get
stalled or one gets stalled twice as
long maybe I should add another stage so
I so I play around with that try to get
the
the right number of steps I'm checking
so another site of I've labeled this
with its official name this is called
bounded model checking not going to try
to explain what model checking means but
the bounded bit is simply this number of
how many copies I make so I started off
with a bound of five I've increased such
a bound of seven and as I say there are
tools that will do this little
transformation of making the multiple
copies and forwarding data between
stages they'll do it for you those tools
like OSIS which if anybody is into doing
open fpga work you'll probably know
about the the OSIS air tools those talks
about using bounded model checking that
say you can get hold of those there's a
paper that i mentioned right at the
start that I wrote you can get hold of
those blogs so there's a bunch of links
there that you can follow I'm okay so we
run some tests we do some oh and let me
just emphasize just once more that what
this is going to do is it's going to a
test any sequence of instructions in
this case any sequence of up to seven
instructions are going to get checked
and for all possible inputs so it's
going to run through the first check
then the second and third and so on and
if it manages to get all the way to the
end then you're going to know that any
seven cycle sequence anywhere in
execution is going to behave correctly
so and you don't have to come up with
your own tests so either through testing
or through this bounded model checking
you will find another bug and this is
another well-known bug in the style of
fare processor it was actually fixed in
the next generation of process so that
the picture I'm showing is of the MIPS
one the MIPS to fix this
so the bug involves a load followed by a
store so let's just
think about what's going on when you
have a lord followed by a store so I was
kind of assumed forward to the point
where the Lord is in the memory stage
and the stories behind it in the execute
stage and so the Lord is busy it's got
an address it hands that to the memory
and it reads back a value from the
memory so now you've got a value from
memory at the same time that that's
happening the store has finished reading
some values from the register file and
it's sitting in the execute stage
waiting ready to execute so now let's go
forward one cycle at this point the Lord
writes back the value at got from memory
back to the register file and the store
starts to write something to the data
memory but what is it writing if you
look at the program you might expect I
loaded into register 0 and then I stored
from register 0 so you would hope it's
storing the value you just loaded from
memory but that's not what happens
because the store had already read some
values from the register file before it
got to that point so it's gonna store
the previous value from register 0 to
memory so I would tend to label this a
bug and you know the next generation the
processor I chose not to do this but
again the the first generation they
called a feature and they gave it a
fancy name they called a load delay slot
and they said if you do a Lord then you
must wait you know at least one
instruction before you actually try to
use the results of that Lord so so
that's one way of fixing it is to see
it's a software problem it's not
hardware that's wrong it's it's
programmers need to deal with this they
need to find something else to do
between the load and the store or they
can maybe get a compiler to do it for
them but either way it's not a hardware
problem definitely not a bug it's a
feature so so now if you disagree with
that and you actually want to fix a
problem you could do is we did with the
branch and just stall the process so
just wait up
until the value has made it back to the
register file and then you're all good
but the more common one is is not to
stall and try to maintain a bit
performance and the reason for that is
if you think about it at the point when
I went to execute the store instruction
I had actually already successfully got
a value from memory the only problem was
I'd already got a value from somewhere
else and there was no way that the value
I had which by this point was in the
write back stage that was all gray mocks
and the furthest to the right hand side
that's where the value was and if only I
could get it from there
into the memory everything would be good
so let's just add a data path that will
do that all right so we just add a data
path would add another mock sir to
select which share whether to use this
forwarded value this bypassed value or
to use the value we got from registers
so we do that but oh there's two inputs
to the memory well maybe we wish to add
another forwarding path so that it
doesn't matter whether we're using the
value we read as an address or as data
either way it's going to work so that's
that's good let's fix it but
unfortunately that there's another bug
is any use of the value will break
things so if I have a load followed by
an ad that will also not work same fix
works just a different data path so we
add another path going a bit further
back
it could affect either input of a of the
addition so add another path it turns
out is yes another bug which is an ADD
immediately followed by an ADD will have
the same problem it takes ages it takes
two full cycles for the result of an ad
to get all the way around back to the
register file and be ready for an for an
operation so we can fix that by adding
another forwarding path and another
forwarding path and is and then one more
a final bug that I can spot in this
diagram which is if we have a load and
then we branch to the address that we
just loaded you might do that in your
turning from a function then you've got
another bug so we add another path under
nisha of key in each of these cases if
we decide it's too expensive adding an
extra data path then we have the option
of stalling in this circumstance so so
for each of these potential potential
bugs we've got a choice of stalling or
adding a forwarding path and then we've
got to make a list of all the times we
want to stall all the times we want to
use a forwarding path add in all the
control logic to select the right input
at the right time or to stall the
processor at the right time and and what
we end up with is a lot of new corner
cases a lot of different things we need
to test because there's so many
different situations in which this
forwarding logic is made to trigger or
not meant to trigger so back to what
test should we be running well all our
single stage tests all our two
instruction tests a Lords followed by
well pretty much anything because when I
was scared of Lords going wrong and then
well how many instructions see how long
does an instruction sequence have to be
before it's guaranteed not to have any
new bugs you haven't seen in a shorter
sequence you know what's can you get
four instructions to fail I think you
can get five instructions to fail you
know a chain of five where the last one
is the one that goes wrong so you come
up with your guess of how long in that
sequence can be and then you try to
figure out what would make a sequence
interesting and write tests for it or
again you rely on formal verification if
that's powerful enough to cope with the
complexity of the design you're working
on okay so that's me I've now done two
rounds round this say writing this cycle
start with something right that's
correct
break it but make it really fast fix it
then make it even faster and even more
broken fix that and hopefully you now
have a working processor because you've
got good ways of testing it good ways of
applying formal verification to it so
I'm not going to do any more it's
on processor a optimizations gonna think
about what's happening with formal
verification so what's going on here
well you can think of formal
verification as being we saw it from one
point and then we try all possible
instructions that could happen next and
then we take another set and we think of
all possible instructions that could
follow on from that and then all
possible instructions that could follow
on from that and we can keep going like
this doing this read first exploration
but if any of you have played around
with read first exploration you'll know
that the the state space here is just
exploding and eventually you're going to
hit some limit where you just can't
explore any deeper right you've been
extremely thorough and what you've
checked but you just can't get any
deeper because you've run out of memory
or it sees it's going to take another
day to run it's gonna take another week
another month whatever to to run so so
you kind of stuck at that point so
testing is a good technique as well and
you know I've been saying for more
verifications great but tasting is
really good because it has this nice
property that you can take your starting
point and then just run a big long
program and a million cycles later you
say look um I've done enough of that
I'll try something else I'll try
something else I'll just keep trying
different things and I'm not exploring
very thoroughly right you know this I'm
not filling in the the screen with you
know solid blocks of color but I am
getting really deep I'm getting into
interesting complicated situations at
least I have my tests are any good I
hope I am so so I've got formal
verification which is bread first
I've got testing witches air depth first
both really good for finding air bugs
but more recently what we've been doing
is switching to our kind of mixed mode
we will start off with the formal
verification doing that bread first
exploration seeing how deep we can get
but then once we reach whatever the
limit is we then switch to testing but
as we
but then we take some of the paths that
we've a phone by testing and we see
let's do a little formal verification
around that and we try to broaden note
around each lane so we're kind of able
to fill in more of that search space get
to these deep seats and then search
around there and so we keep doing that
for a while and a and we we gain a lot
more confidence not just that we've
searched short sequences really
thoroughly but we've also seen a lot of
fair depth as well okay so I started off
by saying that processors almost always
work and I hope I've given you a bit of
a sense just in those simple
optimizations I described of why this is
actually an amazing thing because just
going to a five stage pipeline things
were getting I think kind of complicated
and the testing for them is getting
complicated so and then I talked a lot
about how we about how we go back and
forth between the designer and the
verifier and the site I said the the
verifier tends to win the fight over
kind of how much complexity you allowed
in the processor because you want the
thing to work using these formal
verification techniques were able to
check processors much more thoroughly
and this lets us shift the balance over
so the designer is able to push much
harder towards what he wants to do which
is make the processor fast without
making the very the verify are unhappy
about what's going on so so let's see so
just in closing i I've been showing you
processor designs from 1985 so just to
bring it a bit more up to date if any of
you like playing with microcontrollers
this is one of our more recent
microcontrollers it's cortex m7 so this
is
an ACH pipeline so increasingly from the
five stages we we saw earlier and
there's also five separate execution
pipelines and said just being able to do
memory and arithmetic and it can
actually issue two instructions and
parallels so it can be two instructions
can be executed in every step and if you
remember from the five stage pipeline I
did what was a six seven separate
forwarding paths so there would be nice
and fast and wouldn't have I wouldn't
have to stall too often well imagine for
each pipeline I'm going to add a number
of forwarding paths probably about a
maybe about four six separate forwarding
paths for each pipe line and between
pipelines I'm good to add some
forwarding paths as well so let me just
give you a quick glance roughly what the
forwarding paths in the court xm7 looks
like so it's it's quite complicated that
joke is actually due to one of my
colleagues will keen who came up with
that joke so but this is not completely
unrealistic it really is incredibly
complicated I'm trying to make a
processor of this complexity that's
actually going to be reliable let's
design felissa land bedded systems so or
fairly big embedded systems actually you
want it to work you don't want to have
to go and replace it so correctness
really matters so yeah so I hope we've
given you a bit of a sense for designing
and more importantly verifying Chris
it's like thank you very much for your
attention and yeah you got any questions
[Applause]
thank you very much for the talk what
methods do you use to decide when the
verification is complete what have you
done your job so but there's a whole lot
of experience right so arms I think they
all the first ARM processor was designed
over 30 years ago so there's 30 years of
experience of just kind of like we did
this much last time and we were happy
with that or we were unhappy with it so
let's do more or the same there's
there's a whole lot of people who think
really hard about obviously there's a
classic thing of measure you know just
the number of bugs and you look at the
bug curve and as it starts to tail off
you you think you're looking good so
there's a very long kind of so testing
period at the end with the formal
verification you can also see you can
try to come up with a property which
when it's true will tell you that
there's nothing more interesting to find
that they're all instructions have made
it all the way down the pipeline for
example and so you can kind of prove
that that number is less than seven and
then you know that seven would be the
right number to use so there's there's a
variety of techniques like that I should
actually say I'm I'm actually in the
research group I help people I hope the
people who were developing this I did
part of the work in developing this
formal verification technique but but
I'm kind of a fake you know they the
guys who actually do their verification
of real processes they are they they're
the heroes I was talking about not me
do you think that the recent speculative
execution issues have put a greater
focus on the formal verification stuff
have you seen a shift in sort of day to
day as a result I think we'd already
reached a point where the traditional
testing was kind of at its limit you
know and it's really important a
processor works the process when you're
foreign has a problem then you know we
can't change all the software in the App
Store right and it's really expensive to
recall phone so they really have to work
so we're already kind of you know I know
processor vendors are doing this you
know pushing really hard for really high
quality this may be pushed a little I've
got an idea of how to use formal
verification techniques to look for
particular kinds of security rules I'm
thinking of applying but yeah this may
be push this a little but we were kind
of already there so how many cycles
severe cycles can you actually verify
these days with bonded modeling
techniques it varies with which
processor you're working on so I was
working on a little two and a half stage
pipeline and there were some things get
like 80 cycles deep and then we kill it
because it clearly was never going to
find anything else others when I was
working in the project we get stuck
about maybe 10 cycles 12 cycles it
varies and what what does a cycle mean
like this processor here is executing
two instructions of recycle so if it
gets you know if you can get 10 deep
that's you're done 20 instructions but
then again it's more likely to have
problems because it's so complicated so
maybe you really do want to get 20
cycles deep
so in your experience has a problem got
out into the wild and having analyzed
that problem when it's out in the real
world have you had to modify your formal
verification techniques as a result sort
of what's the most embarrassing incident
where this has actually happened um I
think I think we we applied this to we
were doing it about three years ago that
we were developing this can over then
that egg was kind of tailing off over
the next a year or so so it's maybe
about two years ago that the alias
processes we did this too were finished
as far as we were concerned and then
takes another year or so for something
to make it in silicon maybe another six
to twelve months for it to actually kind
of appear in a package that you can
actually buy so so we're about to find
out I guess yeah
we do know it finds a lot more bugs if I
use them much earlier
which makes it cheaper to fix them
because the cost of fixing a bug goes up
exponentially of course with the you
know the length of time it sits in your
in your code base so we find them much
earlier we find bugs which we're not
sure we would have caught by testing so
we're very happy with it as a technique
but yeah I think I think we're still
learning how to use it even though I
think that's all the questions so thank
you very much indeed else to read thank
you
[Applause]