the next talk of the day is starting now
it's anti vine here to tell us how to
climb a mountain
[Applause]
[Music]
hey can everyone hear me all right yeah
good good okay so I'm going to talk
about two climbing expeditions I've been
on one in 2001 which was to India and
Hammar Child Pradesh and the other was
actually straight after the last EMF
2016 and we went to the Coulee Region of
Kyrgyzstan first I'm gonna say a little
bit about how I got into a position to
think that this was a good idea at all
so I a lot a lot of people coming to
mountaineering from either Hill walking
or rock climbing or a combination of
both so I I did a combination of both
side did a lot of walking during my
levels I studied in Devon so the 10
tools event was on there and I
participated in that and then at
university I started rock climbing and
at the end of my my first year the club
I was involved with was going to the
Alps so it's the Alps the ekran region
which is still my favourite region and
climbed up to about 4000 meters several
mountains a full vu and Alfred and then
at the end of my degree because I've
been to the Alps every year during my
degree I started thinking about an
expedition and that was made easier by
the fact that there were other people in
the club ours member of that had done it
before and that's kind of how most
people get into doing this sort of thing
they join a club and sort of follow that
career path so a friend from the club
suggested India because the research was
relatively easy and the infrastructure
in India is a bit better than the rest
of the Himalaya so next slide
okay so the reason that the the research
is a bit easier is because the Alpine
club based in London have a an online
database of all the mountains in the
Himalayan climbing hopefully all the
ones they have records of and they
really do have extensive records and
they've got a big library so you're able
to search a sort of latitude and
longitude square and come up with all
the reported climbs that have been
reported in various Alpine journals so
searching around we were looking at this
area and we found that the mountains on
this side of the river the CB Range the
CB and then a number they'd all been
climbed and reported so he had an idea
of what conditions were like in the
region but on the other side of the
river there was nothing at all in this
whole big area that been climbed and
only this one mountain that had a name
tag knee and on the previous map we had
it was the highest in the region but on
this map it's it's not quite as a peak
6501 name peak that's a little bit
higher this was the best map we managed
to get hold of remember this is back in
2001 so we tried to get hold of
satellite images and we couldn't I went
to the RDS and their maps were based on
the the 1800's Survey of India by the
British so so this map which is better
than the map that they had at the India
mountaineering Foundation in Delhi we
got out of Stanford's in Covent Garden
really fantastic place Stanford's
because you get the feeling that there
are so many people going to interesting
exciting places that sort of pass
through and you never know where they're
going
so I kind of like Stanford's for this
and also the fact that you used to be
able to just go in and pull out of a
drawer a map of somewhere where nobody's
ever climbed before so yeah we resolved
to climb techne it being the only name
peak in the area and we call it a
technics petition so so this is us
trekking in we started on a pretty
precarious bus journey actually over
some big precipices with the tires right
on the edge of the road but eventually
the rose deteriorates into paths and so
we'd arranged to have ponies carry all
our stuff there's quite a lot of stuff
as well climbing the Himalayas to end up
with a bit of an entourage of a cook and
you know various people to help him out
and it's it's a bit of an unusual way to
climb if you're used to the Alps because
it's just two of you there generally
okay just gonna say a bit about glaciers
now forgive me if you already know this
for the things were saying so obviously
when the snow falls but it isn't cold
enough to melt it it subcompacts into a
big ice sheet and then the ice sheet
flows down the mountain like it acts as
a viscous liquid moving very slowly you
flying down the mountain but when it
goes over a bulge the top of it goes
into tension and that causes cracks and
they're big cracks grasses so it's
always really important if you're on a
glacier that's covered in snow you stay
roped up because the snow forms bridges
which sometimes don't give way but in
the afternoon when it gets hotter that
bridges can give way and come fall into
the crevasse
so you've got to know how to get out and
make sure you ropes up whenever you're
on a white glassy like this it matters
less when there's no snow on the glassy
like this one in Kyrgyzstan but um a
reference to that later in the talk so
okay how well does that come up yeah
that's good so this is tagging II we we
made it we actually record several
different glasses on the way there and
worked out this was the best approach
and our line was up the side of this
Ridge here rounds here to the Col here
and then up here over several rock steps
and then a
no down to the summit and that's about
500 meters of height gained from our
camp which is down here so this is us
high on the ridge our tent is just that
little dot there and so we've come up
this Ridge around that amphitheater and
you can see that the glacier is pretty
impossible as well the glasses can be
quite dangerous if they're like this
because bits can break off and ice can
come down them down the mountain at you
so it's well worth avoiding them and
staying on the ridge
this is Narinder Singh he actually
didn't come with us from England because
in India you've got to pay to climb
mountains so he's a representative of
the Indian government who's there to
make sure that we only climb what we
said we climb and we pay for everything
that we climbed normally they send a guy
from the military but we are really
lucky
no Indo had his own trekking firm when
he was he was a climber just like us we
hate we had a very similar mindset and
got on really well so he's climbing the
mountain with me and we got to the top
in the end and so here's the view from
the top obviously the view no one's ever
seen before apart from us at the time
anyway
and here the Seabee mountains from over
the other side they're bigger mountains
so that their people are more interested
in climbing them that's why that sides
are already been climbed and this is me
on the summit by pure coincidence on my
23rd birthday so great way to spend my
birthday ok um quick word about altitude
so I think most people know that the air
gets thinner the higher you go but
what's worth pointing out is that it's a
really big effect so this is a graph of
altitude versus atmospheric pressure and
you can also see this as a graph of
oxygen concentration because when you're
down at sea level it's 100
but obviously as it drops the oxygen
concentration compared to the baseline
of what you're used to drops as well so
on the summit of Snowden about a
thousand meters
you've lost 10% of the oxygen that you
normally used to on Mont Blanc 4,800
meters probably about 55% of what you're
used to and on tagged knee 6111 meters
down to well under 50% probably like 47
46 % and you really feel that it
basically means you you've got to rest a
lot you take a few steps and have a rest
breathe heavily obviously your body
adapts to it so you breathe more deeply
and your vall reproduces more blood
cells which you've got to be aware that
can that can possibly be a risk of
clotting and also you've got to be aware
to acclimatize really slowly which was
why we did quite a long walk in for this
trip we didn't need to walk quite as far
as we did but getting some exercise over
3,500 metres was really useful and
making sure we were really well
acclimatize on the day so this is the
other mountain that was climbed on that
trip I didn't climb this one it was the
other guys in the team so Alan geared
John Ellis and Steve jolly summited they
went from our camp here all the way out
the glassier and then all the way up
this ridge which they were hoping would
be a nice snowy Ridge but turned out to
be actually pretty rocky and quite
difficult climbing I think they spent 20
hours going from tent up down back again
and we're a bit worried about them and
quite quite pleased to see um head
torches coming down the glassier quite
late at night but it all worked out in
the end
so at the end of the trip we made this
map it's it's pretty rough but you can
you can see the important bits this is
where we made our base camp then we
carried local to go back
No then we carried loads up to advanced
base camp and then we recce these
glasses and climbed on cigar and tagged
knee from the south and we identified
some passes as well so this is based on
the Lehman's map so you saw earlier that
ridgeline map are the Greenies ridge
lines but with a little bit more
information from us so that's India and
now I'm going to talk about our
Kyrgyzstan trip so this is a this part
of the talks adapted a little bit from a
talk my climbing partner miles gave he
he couldn't make it here so he thought
mountaineering was a little bit like
doing maths research unfortunately not a
mathematician so don't ask many
questions about maths and and so I so
okay I'll tell you some of his thoughts
and some of it I can back up with my own
experiences in engineering research so
some questions that you can get quite a
lot particularly if you're involved with
maths is do you really do this for fun
and secondly is it really possible to do
new stuff so yeah there are plenty of on
climb mountains left in the world and
probably if you follow this kind of
thing a bit more you're aware of the
people that are right at the cutting
edge you know the the famous mountain is
doing the really difficult routes but
actually there are there are plenty of
mountains and plenty of interesting
maths that are well trained mere mortal
can approach and perhaps find solutions
to so once you've decided that this is a
thing that's possible and you want to do
it then you need to pick a general area
and in this case we picked Astana
so this is the sort of tail end of the
Himalaya borders China and Kazakhstan
and it's good because there are no peak
fees
and it's quite well-developed as well
and there's lots of unclean mountains
that aren't too difficult drawback is
that the research for this area is
really hard so like researching other
put in other subjects you have to start
the literature review and in this case
it's all in Russian
so so this was a bit of a barrier but we
did the best we could and like other
areas of research it's kind of hard work
there's a lot of inconsistent notation
same names names for different things
different names for the same things and
what was actually done can be quite
poorly reported and it's quite difficult
but eventually we came up with an area
that we are really interested in the
kindig valley Kandak glacier and we
identified some mountains we wanted to
do so this one right at the head of the
valley objective a this one off to the
side Objective C Objective D's their
objective beers they're our base camps
way back here and we're planning to
carry loads about six kilometres up to
the snouts the glassier
and then make a camp there and from
there we could do all the other
mountains so once you've decided what
you want to do you've got to raise some
money again
a lot like research so thanks to our
sponsors Mount Everest foundation elite
man supplies gather foods high spot high
5 sports nutrition and wrap some
provides equipment some fright of money
the Mount Everest foundation is the one
that's really worth having because they
give you a lot of credibility if you can
get approval from funding from them and
also they'll help publicize you after
the trip so this is a bit I added after
you've done all that then you want to
get the snacks and supplies it whether
it's research or mountaineering so this
is the good thing about Kyrgyzstan this
is a Coca supermarket and it looks
almost exactly like a normal supermarket
which is great because it makes shopping
really easy you know there's no there's
no complication involved and it kind of
blew my mind a bit because a couple of
days from this supermarket there are
people herding sheep nomads living in
yurts and on climb mountains two days
from here so this is why kyrgyzstan is
brilliant
so quick word about what we eat so the
trick is to carry plenty of really dense
calorific food and it but it also has to
be palatable as well so one thing we
went for quite a lot was the Thai
curries because you can buy individual
pastes Thai curry pastes Shaye's and
then you can get this kind of block of
coconut milk which looks like a bar of
soap and you just melt it down add water
cook it up with pasta dried mushrooms
and some local dried meat and that's a
pretty tasty meal get a lot of calories
in you that way likewise you can get
pesto in individual sachets cook it with
pasta Parmesan is really good loads of
fat loads of protein and again salami so
we're a bit sick of it by the end of the
trip but it kept us alive and kept us
moving so next thing you obviously have
to do is plenty of training so again
like other areas with like other
research into new areas you find you
have to practice solutions to known
problems so clients but other people
have done before so that's perhaps in
the Dolomites or maybe in Scotland which
is definitely cold enough to freeze your
beard and after all that you can get to
Kyrgyzstan and get into the mountains so
yeah this was our this was the first
sort of when we got out of the van it
been raining the rain cleared got out of
the 4x4 and had a good look around it
really amazing this is a nickel-iron
sergei nikolaivich the driver and
as a translator so when you get stuck
into the problem you'll probably find
other people already working the field
and its really have handy to have
someone to translate what on earth it is
they're saying and make some
introductions and that was that was so
nice job I quite liked the horse getting
involved in this conversation and at any
stage in this you may find something
that you really weren't expecting at all
like maybe camels yep that's a camel I
wasn't expecting to see camels I don't
know if you expect to see camels on a
talk on mountaineering but there were
camels so this is Beck who helps us out
so we're talking to those guys because
we wanted some help getting our kit up
the valley and these Shepherds have
ponies so we're hoping they could help
us
Beck looks after 502 sheep which he
counts since the Sheep pen every evening
and this is his mate Tala who helps him
out with the shoot with with the
shepherding they live here this is the
the Hut that Beck's grandfather built
and before that he'd lived in a year and
it was really nice and cozy inside with
this stove that was fueled on animal
dung didn't smell weird or anything it
was great really cozy sort of
traditional felt on the floor and their
top tip was if you've got black tea and
jam you can make fruit tea by adding
them together brilliant so the next day
we set off for the kindig Valley now
quite a lot of current climbing areas
have cool-sounding hard names like Death
Valley or the nameless valley so we're
walking along with beck and the horses
and he says you know how kindig is it's
this so we've planned a trip to the
valley of the bellybutton
oh well so as we went the ground got
harder and we ended up leaving the
horses miles had some difficulty
establishing a rapport with his horse
because his horse just wanted to eat
grass but eventually we made it to a
point where the horses couldn't go any
further and we made our Basecamp
so our tents here the reason I'm so
excited is because I've worked out a way
to stop all the marmots eating our food
by hanging it off this big rock in the
panniers that we borrowed for the horses
so I TMC are a company in Kyrgyzstan it
helped us a lot and they're very keen
for us to take a lot of kit with us that
we didn't really feel we needed so he
said no to the mess tent and we said
knows the folding chairs and we said no
to the cutlery and crockery and all of
that because we bring our own it's all
lightweight and that's great but they
insisted that we we take a stove from
them so they supplied us with this stove
which is absolutely huge and has this
massive gas bottle my mountaineering
stove is 125 grams and it's made it to
take em and they gave us this on top of
all that this ring we couldn't turn on
and this ring we couldn't turn off so I
had to turn it off with a gas bottle it
all felt pretty silly but you know we
managed the stove works in the end so
then we carried quite a lot of kits up
the valley and made our camp here just
just before the end of the glassier and
all the way up we could see this big
mountain here which is objective a and
incidentally this is the tent that tent
man the Y actor that played Tin Man
Stadium when it came to EMF yeah we
didn't see a lot of vegetation or
animals we saw some marmots we didn't
actually see any ibex but this is an
ibex cull it's a pretty big one these
big curved horns serrated horns so
so all right the climbing begins
this is objective-c and we start from
the base camp went across up the glacier
through some chorus fields up onto the
ridge and then along the ridge of the
summit past two or three places we
thought it might be the summit and then
we kept seeing a higher one but
eventually we got there and that's
really good because once you've got one
Mountain done then you can say the
expedition was a success and all your
sponsors will be happy hopefully and so
miles said we should get some
promotional shots for the sponsors but
he he didn't think I was really taking
this seriously enough but actually the
sponsors really liked this photo and
retweeted it okay so I'm around I said
before we can get satellite photos
before well
things have moved on because now Google
Maps is amazing
so this picture here is actually from
Google Earth and this is the real
picture when we were there and you can
see it matches up pretty well you've got
this big snow face and this bike big
triangular face the plateau here much is
this the problem is the resolution
because we were hoping to go up here and
along this Ridge and you can see from
the reality one that it's a really
pointy serrated jagged Ridge and that
would take us far too long it was just
more difficult than we really wants to
do on this trip it didn't show off at
all on the Google Maps image so I guess
that's so a way that um climbing is like
research as well you find things that
you just didn't expect something
sometimes things are harder than you
thought likewise we were hoping that
would be able to so okay next Mountain
objective a we were hoping we'd be able
to come up this easy Ridge and climb
over this rock bulge and then make it to
the summit but this turned out to be a
bit more difficult as well
so this picture of miles on the ridge he
climbed further on from here up some
quite poor snow
he made it to top of that rock bulge I
just showed you but we couldn't get any
further without committing to an Abbe
sale where we'd have to pull the rope
down and then we wouldn't be able to go
back the same way we'd be committed to
finding another way down
we didn't fancy that so since the
weather was coming in as well we
retreated off it to try and find a
better way and setbacks like that should
be treated with food and tea fruit tea
yeah why not if you've got some Jam it's
okay this was our successful approach on
an objective a we're a bit concerned
about this steep face here but it turned
out to be fine so up the glacier up that
face and then it's just a really nice
Ridge walk on the snow all the way up to
the summit so yeah sometimes you try and
approach it doesn't work out you have to
go back to the start and then when you
try the right approach everything seems
so much easier and that's me on the
summit obviously we had to take turns
taking pictures on the summit but
there's a selfie of us both there okay
so the last climbing day we decided to
have a go at this peak which was just
before that jagged Ridge the jagged
Ridge goes off behind this so this is
the highest point we could get to
without committing to that quite
unpleasant Ridge so we came up the
glacier here and then went up this Ridge
which is probably a bit more than it
looks on this goes a bit foreshortened
and eventually made it this summit that
was really good so then we came back
down and came back down to the Col here
so you have to get up really early
because the snow is frozen then and it
makes it a lot easier if the snow is
frozen
mainly because rocks won't be coming
down the mountain at you
so I got back to this point it was about
nine o'clock my Miles said that he
thought we should do something else
because he felt like he wanted to do
something with his day as that miles you
just made the first ascent of a
previously on car mounts in the
changshan and you're saying you want to
do something with your day okay we'll go
on the ridge so we went on the ridge so
we went all the way along here this
turned out to be a really nice rich walk
you get these pillars along the ridge
that sometimes called Jean Dom's and the
first one was sort of white marble and
then the next one was black nice and
then we got to this bit where it was
these weird bands on the on the ground
it looks like we've raped this out but
it was I promise it was like this when
we got there I've never seen anything
like this if someone couldn't explain
what's going on here I'd be really
interesting but I really like it
and so from once you get to the end from
your new perspective you'll be able to
see other objectives that look really
interesting and you you might on a try
so all of the mountains in this picture
haven't been climbed as far as we know
this is the Arroyo Valley it's the one
just over from us and we're looking in
from that Ridge and I didn't want to ask
what our raw means and this mountain
looks particularly nice and accessible
with the all the multicolored scree
again but looks like it wouldn't be too
hard so on the day we arranged Beck's
showed up with his horses and the horse
pulled this weird face and I put it in
the presentation yeah that that will
worked out really well back to goose
home so this point you probably want to
crack on with those new objectives but
you can't do that because you've got to
write it up and this is the point this
is your opportunity to correct all those
horrible reports which weren't clear
enough and you have to put everything
down as clearly as you possibly can and
so that other people who come to this
area after you will be able to have a
more pleasant time when they do their
literature
and it's normally at this point where
you find the one reference that would
have been really helpful at the start of
this whole process so vladimir commissar
o of his earth sort of big name in
russian climbing he runs the Kyrgyz
Alpine Club he used to be a master of
climbing in the Soviet days and he put
this map together for us which is really
handy but at the end of the expedition
ah so you can see that we've added in
the mountains that we climbed but I mean
you know if you're planning a trip to
this area this is what you want this is
what you want to see and he was able to
research the Russian internet as well
because he's Russian okay that's nearly
the end but I've got five tips for
camping in a small tent I've realized
actually camping in a big tent is a is a
slightly different set of problems but
yeah if you're camping in a small tent
this is what I recommend
number one at night use a head torch but
dip it down when you talk to people just
like car headlights because I won't get
the lights in their face number two when
cooking if you can use a pan with fins
on the bottom because it's a lot quicker
to boil that way and you'll save weight
in the fuel if you're carrying it and
obviously use a windshield on the lid
and make the windshield out of one of
those full catering trays don't buy one
no one does that
use a tent loft for storage drying and
watching TV so this is the top of the
tent it's just a bit of mesh fabric and
you can put stuff up there you want to
dry or if you want you can put your
phone up there lie back and watch Doctor
Who at Basecamp like we did bring ten
lighters because light has always go
wrong and the further you are from home
more important this is and if you camp
somewhere rocky don't worry about
pushing the tempo into the rocks into
the rocky ground find some big rocks
loot the guylines around them and peg
the tent out that way no promise all
okay that's all
[Applause]
do you have time for some questions so
what sort of particular kind of skills
would you say a particularly important
and they coming from small expeditions
maybe little bits in Scotland to then
going on a kind of more significant
expedition like that what sort of thing
would you say is kind of the most
important that you kind of built up over
that process say how am I still might
yeah yeah I'd say it's important to get
somewhere where there are some glaciers
I probably recommend going to the Alps
if you're familiar with Scotland the web
there's a lot better so you have a great
time but yeah go to the Alps or
something knows what they're doing
once you've had three seasons in the
Alps or so then you're good to look at
the greater ranges and Kyrgyzstan is
probably a good place to go for your
first expedition it was Martha's first
expedition and neither of us had any
problem with the technical difficulties
especially now you can identify the
mountain so well with Google Earth is
that wind so yeah great thanks ok so I
get another round of applause hi I was
just wondering what you used in terms of
sort of safety comes equipment like
iridium foams re perp's or anything like
that or if he just didn't bother that's
a good question yes so we hired hats at
phones from IT MC never hire a Sat phone
ever don't anyone ever do this what we
need to do is buy the Sat phone and then
sell it after the expedition because
that gives you a chance to get really
used to it make sure you've got the
right charging cable which we didn't
and make sure you can actually use it it
was a real problem we we ended up sort
of on text-only and having to really
conserve the battery just in case we
really needed it to call for help so
yeah we we did use some probably not
good enough satphones so I recommend
buying one did you get to name the
mountains yes so so the way it kind of
the way you named mountain is you start
using a name for a nun named mountain
and hope it catches on so cigar the the
second one we climbed in India that was
unnamed that means ocean in the local
name Hindi and then that's because it
was this sort of rippling ridge all the
way up the ones in Kyrgyzstan we got
translated into Russian objective a we
called crow peak because there were bird
footprints on the summit objective be I
can't sorry that we didn't flow my
recipe it ejectives see I can't remember
but then the last two we climbed we
called camel peak and Marmot Peak
because the things we'd seen on the way
anymore
how much weight did you lose by doing
this we didn't actually lose that much
weight on the Kyrgyzstan trip on the
India trip you all lose lost a ton of
weight it was really noticeable in the
photos like whoa this guy's looking a
bit skinny now and actually the trousers
I bought these the border food trousers
I bought but they arrived the day before
we went and I thought they're a bit
tight by the end of the trip no these
are nice and comfy now the kyrgyzstan
trip we were we were fine until we got
off the mountain and then we we went to
this restaurant where he had a big sort
of pie thing with a pastry yurt over the
top
and that made miles really really ill
and he lost a huge amount of weight but
yeah we kept away all right mostly on
the Kyrgyzstan trip we had a lot of
energy bars of it this too from high
five so that was quite good what are you
going to climb next I'm not quite sure
and now's a good time to be thinking
about it because the MAF have their
deadline at the end of the year so we've
got to work out if I'm gonna do another
big trip or not there is a mountain in
the pool which I'd really like to look
off we're calling it nice Ridge at the
moment because because it's steep on
three sides and then it has a really
nice Ridge going up to the top I think
that'd be a fantastic climb but that's
just an aspiration at the moment cool so
uh thank you you very much
you