we are very nearly ready so coming up
next just to let you know you are in
10th Alton
see I had no idea this is my favorite
tenth of of all of them don't tell 10a
it'll get jealous but 10th a where
you're going to be seeing an amazing
talk by barney Livingston talking about
his poet ID lyric kam have I pronounced
that right yes sure why not
so what I need I need you to start
clapping but very very gently can you
start clapping very gently and yeah now
just bring it up a bit
a bit more a bit more bit more please
welcome Murtagh lyric cam thank you um
my name's Barney I'd like to talk to you
about this I was always there a camp
thing that I made before I start I'd
like to give a disclaimer in case there
are any real poets in that in the room
and what this produces is probably best
described as prose poetry or free verse
or maybe bad poetry if there are any
actual poets I've quite interested in
collaborating to improve the poetical
nosov it
[Music]
okay and so I'll start with the
demonstration I'm going to take a poem
of you all and in case you're worried
about being photographed there's the
actual images only kept briefly and then
thrown away and there's no net hook or
anything and if you're still worried
then hide your face now have to wait for
it to develop and have no idea what it's
going to say I apologize if it's a less
than complimentary okay the city a group
of people sitting on a bench many images
of people on a city street people are
sitting while standing in a street under
flags City standing kids the woman is
talking near other kids standing in the
street kids
okay so how'd that work inside there is
a Raspberry Pi B+ until recently there
was a 3b but I seem to have killed the
serial on that recently as a PI camera
in the front and nano thermal printer
from Adafruit
- 18 650 lithium batteries own series to
make about eight volts as a pin Maroni
wide input shim attached to the PI and
so the printer wants five to nine volts
and the Pioneer wants three to sixteen
volts so they both work within the range
of the batteries batteries tend to last
more than a day I find so for the camera
itself it's it was originally called
super color swinger by Polaroid
made in bout 1975 it was pretty terrible
camera and the film's no longer made so
I don't feel guilty about gutting it
it's that there's a as he advanced
having a lot of space inside and I was
able to keep the shutter button working
and it has a handy locking function this
is the third version of this the first
version I made for EMF in 2016 it used
to send the poem to a server in my house
via the Wi-Fi and if you remember EMF in
2016 the Wi-Fi was not very reliable so
the camera wasn't very reliable so I was
determined to make it entirely
self-contained which I've done the
second iteration was a bit much too slow
it took about close to a minute for a
poem to come out and that I've spent
quite a lot of time fixing that and as
we saw is quite a lot reasonably quick
and hell so before I talk about the
intricacies of the software I'd like to
go back and have a look at the history
of how this project came about
19:16 during the second world the first
world war so a group of artists refugees
gathered in Zurich the reactions of the
horror going are around them was to
abandon the usual forms of art and
embrace the absurd
they chose name from their group by
selecting a word at random from a French
German dictionary that name was Dada a
prominent member of the group was the
Romanian poet Tristan Tzara the Dadaist
wrote a lot of manifestos in 1920 he
wrote the manifesto on feeble love and
bitter love in which he gave
instructions for how to make a dardo his
poem to make a dardo his poem take a
newspaper take some scissors choose from
the paper an article of length you want
to make your poem cut out the article
next carefully cut out each of the words
that makes up this article and put them
all in a bag shake gently next take out
each cutting one after the other copy
conscientiously in the order in which
they of the bag the poem will resemble
you and there you are an infinitely
original author of charming Sensibility
even though unappreciated by the vulgar
herd yeah this became known as the
cut-up technique several people across
literature have employed the cutter
across the literature and music have
employed the cut-up technique The Beat
author William s Burroughs used in
several of his books
after his friend and collaborator Brion
Gysin rediscovered the technique waxed
and blanket while cutting out a mount
for a drawing with a stanley blade on
top of a pile of newspapers Thom Yorke
from Radiohead used in radiators kedai
album and also this chap when we were in
Los Angeles and some of you were still
using that technique of cut-ups do you
still use it or do you do yeah yeah it
increasingly so to a great extent on
outside you can say on the new album
earth
if you put three or four disassociated
ideas together and created awkward
relationships with them the the
unconscious intelligence that comes from
that those pairings is really quite
startling sometimes quite quite quite
provocative a friend of mine in San
Francisco developed a program for me on
the computer which enables me to do it
really quickly so instead of going
through the laborious process of cutting
things that you use your computer and
you go and you come back with far more
material so I'll take articles selling
newspapers poems that I've written
pieces of other people's books and put
them all into this little warehouse of
this container of of information and
then hit hit the probe the the random
button and it'll randomize everything
and I'll get reams of papers back out of
it with interesting ideas and then I'll
either take sentences verbatim as it as
excused them out or there might be
something within a sentence which
triggers off an idea a lot I please user
event his program I think I'd have liked
to have been David Bowie's software
developer around all this during all
this time I was born and growing up I
suppose the influence of the da duyst's
was came to me through the country
tradition of absurd his comedy Spike
Milligan Monty Python they can Bob all
that long probably my first encounter
with generating text came in the form of
mrs. Hathaway Snickers this was a
children's party game invented by my
grandfather
each child was given a piece of paper
with a noun or noun phrase with nine
yeah dog would start reading from a book
at some point they would point to a
child and that child would then read the
word for example mrs. Hathaway Snickers
mrs. Hathaway being one of my teachers
this was hilarious like menu here at my
age I learned to program on a baby's
dial on a BBC micro so that in fact the
exact BBC micro is over in the bar
showing Twitter at the moment when I was
about 13
my friend Peter Jones not that one and I
collaborated on a program called ode
I'll demonstrate it now so as you can
see the first lines based on the the
title of a poem by the poet master grant
us the flatulence of the özgür Supriya
the second worst Persian poets in the
galaxy from the section on Vogon poetry
in Douglas Adams as Hitchhiker's Guide
this is basically a more sophisticated
version of mrs. Hathaway Snickers in the
it as well as nouns it incorporates
verbs adjectives and present participles
it consists of a large amount of very
buggy's spaghetti code and you can
probably see some bugs sometimes but
it's at its heart there are two lines
two lines of template's with placeholder
variables that are replaced by words or
chunks of text selected at random from
lists of the appropriate type this is
similar to the game mad libs with the
right choice of templates and carefully
crafted lists this technique can be used
to produce some interesting and amusing
results much better nodes certainly
thank what one is a Twitter bot written
by Eric dress which displayed which
plays with the idea of that people on
Twitter generally
and generally will believe plausible
sounding facts this pot dates backs it
before the current fake news disaster
you can hear more about a Raymond fact
shortly after this talk in stage B
frequently it's not quite as plausible
then Yoko Ono bought by Rob Manuel of
the beaters combines templates based on
Yoko Ono's tweets and writings with
texts of several lists things like foods
computers and celebrities tracery is a
JavaScript library written by Kate
Compton which uses grandmas described in
Jason which so produced they produced
text in the Sims in a similar way so the
there's these words are replaced by
items from these lists and the results
come out like that this is used by a
site called cheap box done quick calm
created by george buckingham that allows
anyone to make twitter bots easily and
and many have and i would think they
tend to make twitter slightly less
horrible than it is generally these are
a couple of my favorites this is a like
a kind of a Dungeons & Dragons based in
like here there have some tasty bargains
so I go back to stuff I made and Markov
chains I first discovered these when
playing with dissociated text program
built into the text editor Emacs which
is very strange in itself as on the by
user Markov chains have built from
existing bodies of text which are cut up
usually into single words and then a
graph is built by creating which encodes
the likelihood that a word we followed
by another word the graph can then be
traversed randomly to build a new tech
same as the original and usually
somewhat grammatically correct it's
probably easier if I demonstrate this
right so at the top is a word is a
sentence that we're going to take apart
and turn into a graph so stock with a
and that's a so we have an edge going to
a and then we take Markov that comes off
a and chain is and then from his we go
back to a and stochastic from a model
and then stop that's the end of the
sentence so help you out here okay and
then we have another sentence so same
thing we start start node then we have
Andrey Markov we already had Markov so
we go back to there was yeah
a again back to the a note it's popular
note Russian mathematician and stop okay
final sentence the cat is a furry mammal
so what happens this time start then to
a but you really got a from story
already halves from start to a so we've
updated the edge to and then cats comes
up a and then he's and then we already
have an edge from his to a so that comes
to and then very mammal stop okay so now
we have a complete graph about text we
can I can show you what it happens if we
to reverse it so you start at start then
for instance is quite likely to go to a
cuz it's to go as one to a then we could
say go to cat then we go to is then we
have to go back to a and then we can go
anywhere we like so you can say
stochastic model a cat is a stochastic
model there again okay do again start
because it's fine maybe we go to Andrey
Markov was a very mammal and so on yeah
that's that's how Markov chains work
with generating text generally the
larger the body of text you feed it the
best of the results because they have
more variety and Sam Hogg cosgrove was a
twister broth I've made based on Markov
chains and what it does is it regularly
searches Twitter for hike in the hash
tag haiku and records what it finds it's
been running for several years now and
is accumulators close to 900,000 haikus
it then uses these to build three Markov
chains one per line there's another
example of its output here
Jimmy
okay inspire ration is another Markov
boss I made this one feeds on thousands
of inspirational quote Thai text typed
text Markov chain text tends to be quite
incoherent but sometimes it will spit
out the occasional Jim eventually I got
bought at Markov chains and moved on to
AI I thought we were playing with
character recurrent neural networks
charmer Anand in the torch framework
these can be used in kind of a similar
way to Markov chains and that you feed
them a large quality of text and then
they learn how to produce text that
looks somewhat like the original so I
had a laugh with that and produced some
bizarre new episodes of prints
okay then I found neural net neural
torque to model this is a neural network
that takes an image as input and
produces captions its trained on the MS
koko data set which is a set of about
300,000 photos with five captions each
this is what I used to create the
original lyric am i I noticed that the
captions and I was playing with a
haddock and a vaguely poetic feeling in
November 2016 I took part in the nanogen
mode National Novel generating month
similar to NaNoWriMo but the aim was to
spend a month generating a novel of
50,000 words this is the result
ai ai this is a an AI steak on the film
AI I extracted 5036 stills from the
movie and had neural talk to produce a
caption for each then I formatted the
captions into sentences possibly joining
to then paragraphs from sets of
sentences and chapters from number of
paragraphs chapter titles of are the
most common five or more letter word
from the chapter that's not already been
a chapter title find out if I'm a today
all through latex abuse jpg JPEG PDF
then my friend Libby was kind enough to
get one printed for me I'll read you a
sample chosen chapter 9 picture the
nameless are located on the slippery
side of the indiscernible a man is
taking a picture of a mirror lighted man
with trained by clicking bed at window
and a man is taking a picture of himself
in a mirror there is a man in a
restaurant using the phone
a woman is holding a cat in a kitchen
I'm afraid you can't get much sense of
the of the the film from the book the
occasion he talks about children and
teddy bears which like gathers in the
film I've now actually seen it
so now back to the camera torch doesn't
work on raspberry PI's so I had to
switch to using tensorflow again this is
our nem to text model which is the same
as a neural talked to but and are
similarly trained on AMS Coco's datasets
so when the shot is pressed an image is
captured and stored in a Python array
this is then passed the neural net and
for captions are generated neural talk
to had an option called temperature
which he could use to adjust the
sensibleness the output I Jerry had it
turned down to a quite insensible into
text is more sensible and it always
tries to create most accurate captions
possible so I had to modify it to to
dumb down the search code and introduced
a random element captions are then
cleaned up and fed through the Eng
tagger library which tags each word with
their parts of speech nouns verbs
adjectives prepositions cetera then has
a random chance that it will break the
line on our on our verb a conjunction
like and or or preposition like for of
this kind of makes a vaguely poem shaped
block of text some so sometimes it will
repeat repeat some of the were the nouns
in list form finding their results into
the printer so that's it there's as I
said at the start
I'd love to improve the quality of the
poetry and I'd be interested in
collaborating with people on that
there's a lot of scope for employing
various techniques for transforming
captions I'd also like to investigate
changing the the neural net to be more
poetic the only reason I haven't looked
into this is that on the hardware I've
got training the model from scratch
would probably take weeks so I'll be
wandering around for the rest of the
event is my poet's hat on taking poems
if you'd like one
please ask these are my contact details
I also should thank my employer lobster
Pictures for being understanding while I
prepared this talk and prepare to the
EMF thank you
[Applause]
does anyone have any questions for our
speaker myself II have to wait for it to
develop anyone else have a question we
cannot I can read it off - its hi how
big is the database of images in text
that you use in the raspberry pi well
the original database of images was
300,000 or so but the model that it
produces
I think the file the the checkpoint file
is it's about 118 megabyte or similar
which fits quite comfortably in RAM it
takes about a minute to load onto you of
the SD card oh okay we want to hear this
owed to the two glasses of wine an older
fellow is wearing green and white looks
like a tie a man wearing a tie and the
hat looks at their teeth for the evening
an older man wearing a yellow shirt
taking two glasses of wine he holding a
glass hair
[Applause]
any other questions well then I think on
that lovely note let's have another
round of applause for our speaker
[Applause]
you