but good boy everybody welcome to the
first session can be this is Chris Chris
was about Vigo counters and stuff good
morning everybody thank you very much
for coming out
unreasonably earlier this morning so you
guys understand Sydney I'm going to be
talking about counselling probably
probably guessed by now specifically
some reasons why you might want to
actually do your own how easier than me
to build one yourself over 20 and by
specific reasons to give you a six which
is one of many subjects about which I'm
totally unqualified so very real
physicists in the audience and I get too
far off the mark
feel free to wave at me and tell me
what's equally pure if you say Amen let
me know I'm making the clear so some of
you may recognize this this is a sort of
cliche version of radioactivity he's
green money flows and this mostly dates
to media the early days of the discovery
of radioactivity specifically radium
which is one of the first elements
radioactive elements to isolated and
then was what amount of a fad for
Arabians useful
dodging things and one of the things
that it was used for was it was mixed
with zinc sulfide and incorporated into
paint used to to labor like dials and
things for cheese and it became lodged
in the public imagination that it was
green and glowy the reason why it was
was below is because radiation
stimulated phosphorescence it may be
sulfide and that so that made it glow
having said that there are actually some
radioactive evidence which do go back
tinium is one of them if you have
something back to you in the loop but
again it's not actually the
radioactivity that's doing that it's
ionizing the air around it so if you
have you're acting in a vacuum never see
anything which is why you need Geiger
counter this is one Hyundai will all
with me
so I'll give you a demo little Aegis
ready to work so I have some reasons why
you might own one this is some sort of
radioactive a team that you might call
background that you work you're exposed
to every day and as you can see about
eighty-five percent of that is natural
only about 15 percent is down to things
like x-rays practically negligible
amount is down to who have to fall out
most of these radioactive natural
radioactivity is down to three elements
which is uranium 238
thorium which is 2002 and potassium 14
which is the radioactive isotope
potassium
now as you can see about half of me
exposure to radon gas which well as I
planted the ground
so this point stop talking for me and
you have a little this is my counter
picking hopefully picking up the
background radiation at least
microphones I'm actually not here
clicking counting the number of counts
per minute at the moment and currently
we are sitting at about 24 which is
towards the upper end that what you'd
normally expect is between about 525
normally okay and this is where the rain
comes from its decay products of uranium
238 those three radioactive elements
that I mentioned are particularly
important because they happen to have
half-lives which are comparable with the
80 years which means that a large
proportion of it there was it was
incorporated when the earth when it was
formed is still been around and this is
the they called the decay chain for
uranium 238 look at the case case anyway
this one of the products of this is
radon-222 which is which can be quite
dangerous in some parts the part of the
world and I said I've come up with
reasons why you might want to own a
Gurkha camel I have to admit that my
Geiger counter is not that he not the
best thing at the detecting radon
because it won't pick up alpha particles
and radon is now four emitter
but you can see from this chain of some
of the products of radon that when the
radon decays it produces elements which
you make beta particles and
it will pick up betta so you should be
able to detect it operate this is this
is actually a radon map there's produced
by the government
and it shows us the country way or
you're more likely to be at risk of
exposure to radon it tends to pool in
low-lying areas so if you've got a
people basement in your house and you
live in one of these areas then you
probably need a radar detector to be
installed you can see the pool wall is
very dodgy when it comes to to read on
there's a lot of various folks where
it's a risk and in fact Cornwall is the
one county in England and Wales where
they're not allowed to build nuclear
actors because the background radiation
is all Britain us that you didn't exceed
your revenue sort of recommend you sir
and you'll go see so they have to keep
away and as it happens you probably
spotted this is a this is a zoom in on
be snug and we're in the radiation black
spot or a radiation brown spot but I
should say because the mold and Hills
are very close and they've got a lot of
grains in them the Iranian decays and
four gradients regularly so this is one
of the areas where you might watch out
there's probably the thing I tend to
learn too late in with this is another
reason why you might wanna have a Geiger
counter if you if you got fancy new
kitchen and it's got browning worktops
then some of the groundedness as useful
workshops can be actually contain a lot
of uranium and people have tested tested
a lot of them at about 5% of them
contain enough uranium to actually pose
a hazard health
Europe you know living around long
enough so watch out and these are these
small railway sleepers and one of my one
of my friends at Lucky's makerspace
gives away the purple he's some he's
asked heaping borrow my Geiger counter
as he says it's got some of these then
he's heard that if you get them from
Eastern Europe then some of them might
actually be radioactive so he'd learn he
likes testing before he hasn't hanging
around too
and bananas famously radioactive you may
may or may not heard that it is true and
it's because they've got quite high
levels of potassium in them but
effectively you're not going to be able
to detect it
I have actually tested a banana at my
with my Geiger counter and I can tell
you I'm even able to say I find a
statistically significant difference
between banana another was a high
potassium Emma so II you the average
human beings 440 grams of potassium and
that about point one percent I think his
is actually SAS importantly which is the
radioactive form of it but that's enough
to use quite a lot of radiation at this
point I was I was going to demo it again
but soon as I say that my my going
accountant microphone don't like each
other very much time just waiting this
idea you might recognize this this is
low sodium salt it's about fifty percent
potassium chloride and potassium
chloride about half of that is by ways
potassium says about 90 grams of
potassium in this this kind of stuff and
my guard account can absolutely detect
radius
this it's something like quadruples the
rate over background if you put so if
you've got this close to the closer than
GM tube so you can buy stuff in the
supermarket which is pretty regular
active really that you probably like use
very much the time so it's not going to
be nearest and then I've also got some
medicine rather more radioactive samples
completely passive morning
this is them this is the guts brominium
smoke detector and you can see there's a
little sample of Maryam 241 buried at
the base of this thing and that's the
meeting a constant stream of lava
particles which which ionize the air and
smoke to sex up this this condemning it
if I applied to the back there I would
say the the counts about doubly spun up
to that it won't double six fifty sixty
it's still fine I don't know twenty
hundred twenty counts for me something
like that so I'll pop it back at this
location it's not detecting the the
alpha particles in this case but there
are some there is some secondary
radiation when she picks up this if I
have an alpha detective and it would be
going desert but this is this is
something else but you might find in
your loft
if you parents friends camping these are
gas plants awesome and they contain a
lot of thorium so I plug the back and
it's not that's it's it's climbing up
two hundred three hundred four hundred
minute these things are pretty
radioactive which is why you come over
they if they have supposed a risk some
people in factories the manufacturers
that's why they've stopped making them
it's primarily a veto
featuring each other Solis was picking
up here so we're up to 1200 pounds per
minute now I happen to have those things
like around maybe you can definitely
take it too far
this is a book about a guy maybe may
have heard of his name's David Hartman
in 1994 he was a boy scout in America
and he decided for his one of his merit
badges he was going to build a fast
breeding nuclear reactor and he tried to
do his most potting shed and he came
alarmingly close because somehow the
various radioactive sources EP bought up
hundreds of old smoke detectors and
thousands of thorium gas Mantle's and he
rented them all down and used to be was
trying to build some kind of green there
but whatever he did he emotionally
pepper neighbor that's a point where you
could detects the radiation from about
four houses away and he lived in a
wealthy neighborhood he was declared the
sort of nuclear hazard zone by the
governments of may yep and about those
two months gardening carted off to a it
and you can't waste them
yes so this this is the this is the
reason why I built my character cancer
this is a X camera specifically as a PET
CT scanner and pets and positron
emission tomography
positrons are basically an electron so
this DC antiparticles I promised in the
title of the talk
as hospitals do not like mama matter at
all and when a positron is is created as
soon as it comes into contact with an
electron it's another latex and rather
violently and generates radiation we've
got here what was kind of picks up
nowadays they tend to be combined with a
CT scanner which provides a detailed
image of your body and then the last bit
will pick up the budget interest which
in my case was prostate cancer and I was
deduct this last year the 2017 and they
operated on it but unfortunately the
cancer returns so they decided they were
going to give me one of these handsome
about a week before the scan I decided
it would be interesting to have a look
to see and find out just how regulates
and they were gonna make me fortunately
this is a decay curve of the element
that they use she's blurring NT and as
you can see in the scale at bottom look
ammonia I wasn't even scared awesome in
hours from the time that you you
actually get injected with the stuff
within 18 hours it's pretty much
undetectable again but the swings that
they used is slightly alarming they
don't inject it but they do they do it
run away brief us what they specifically
injected into me was an organic compound
called Xena's kohli and choline happens
to be taken up quite strongly by the
prostate cancer which means that you can
you can highlight it quite precisely one
of the problems about that is that the
process that created
we're in a team that will destroy
organic molecules is paid in cyclotron
say you have to manufacture the 1318
then label your all curly molecule and
then rush it to the patient within about
an hour
otherwise it is useless so it s
occurring around the country from your
local site from to the hospital and I
don't know if I'm skipping this skipping
pages okay so this is a this is a
process that goes on inside the that's
Hannah it's rather clever they they text
the positron emission annihilation event
it creates gamma rays which actually
travel in opposite directions okay so
they've got this circle of detectors
around you and it will they know you
register gamma rays that emerge
simultaneously in opposite directions
and that's that generate future so this
is V go this is the council I came up
with which my friends were recognized
because
fortuitously when I was when I was a
radiating it happened to be one of the
meeting place but make a space so
immediately after my scan I rushed over
to the year
make a space and irradiated every group
there so this this is so this is sitting
at the edge this gym it's you took this
in Europe and sitting at the edge of the
makerspace and I got somebody to say on
for me in there started working towards
it at the time
in three meters it was going nuts so
that's why exciting and this is the this
is the safety point inside it obviously
the most interesting thing about it is
that nice peak property GM to become the
tomb at the top the reason why it looks
kind of old is because it's ex-soviet
Soviet Russia the various components of
the former USSR are selling these things
off in the thousands great keep on eBay
so you can pick one up for a tenant the
circuit of bottom is he straight forward
really they there's a check out that
awesome of the bottom left-hand side is
Texas permits possible population
controller and that actually controls a
simple boost converter which texting low
notes visited up for about 400 volts
which is what the the GM tube needs when
you put 400 volts across it and then you
get so you got a radioactive particle
entering the entering tube its ionizes
the the gases inside with you which then
has a sort of cascade which generates a
very slow pulse the it's on the
right-hand side all stretchers basically
it's a triple five timer which takes in
a short most of about a few microseconds
and stretches up through milliseconds
which is then fed to that little work a
little black Ito speaker at the bottom
there so this was very simple in it it
works quite nicely program for
demonstrating but a few months few
months after that I had chemotherapy and
after that they wanted to know how it
had done so they could be with me for
another scan and this time I wanted to
know just how much radiation I was
getting so I decided
an actual cancer facility - so this is
this is mark - which is one of up with
me today and I reuse the circuit you can
see the back that's the yeah that's a
circuit from the first all I simply
incorporated a new circuit board please
various boost converters an 18 650 to
provide the power and beautiful LED
screen up front that's mostly free here
prepackaged them they're sort of cheap
Chinese vision glasses and things that I
picked up for really any really and this
is a view of it seems there's a couple
of mystical verses there there's arduino
nano micro controller and there's a
charging circuit for the 8615 so I can
reach out and see ended up opening it up
and there's a close-up of the the OLED
display which looks pretty smart
it also looks vaguely like it's all
color one that is actually monochrome
the Chinese just a couple of color
filters over actually you start with the
inner stripper lots of a bit at the top
you can get your piggies up about 150
off the expressive so that they're very
useful you know and creatively put small
so please be a roofer a big display and
so he's together at the other nodes over
comes per second and I also have a the
battery voltage monitor well just
because so having done all that and only
radiated my my friends another another
time yeah if you've got up to my press
account was about a hundred and ten
thousands pounds per minute when I was
first injecting the thing I did take a
count room
both times they didn't they didn't seem
to object too much so those recent thing
is like just had to of course the
radiotherapy that finished about three
weeks ago and this was machine that they
just doing which looks extremely sweet
and it's it's a rather impressive bit of
kit they the big thing at the top is the
actual essentially a linear accelerator
technically it doesn't use gamma
radiation in produces x-rays x-rays are
nowadays really because depending on
which build your during their classified
in different ways if you happen to be
instrument then they want the
traditional way of doing this thing is
the electromagnetic spectrum runs up
through visible light through
ultraviolet up to 2x rays and then
finally to gamma radiation however that
has kind of changed in recent times
because of things like this linear
accelerator it can actually begin x-rays
or she'll have short wavelengths
energetic gamma radiation that's used by
radioactive materials so technically it
was like this an x-ray device because it
got to x-ray this is because the thing
on the right hand side is a CT scan up
this is very sophisticated the kits in
it so when you rely on the platform that
black platform is actually pure carbon
fiber and it's made of a carbon fiber
first of all so they don't drop you
endeavor they used to look coming out
over the edge of the thing and secondly
because carbon is radio transparent or
pretty much soap and therefore they can
they can actually send the beam in from
underneath you as well as on top so it
gives them a lot of control
this is the this is because a machine
behind the time the public face it looks
a lot more like a physics experiment and
the way that the radiation is produced
the the yellow thing at the top on the
left hand side he's actually a magnetron
it's because it's the radiographers the
essential where I was being treated up I
was eat and they very kindly unlocks the
doors and let me poke around the only
thing which is kind of them and the
magnetron actually looks a lot like a
scaled up version and why do you try to
microwave oven and the way it works
Basin is via the magnetron policies
microwaves into the the long tube which
is a which is a linear accelerator and
there's a source of electrons at the
back of the thing and the radiation
actually accelerates the the electrons
are injected at the basic thing up to
multiple megavolts they hits a tungsten
target the head and the electrons
decelerate very rapidly and gamma rays
are emitted well x-rays are busy sorry
I'm mixing my technology yet and that's
that has been in focus and creates the
treatment Li so this is a rather clever
little thing for a multi-use collimator
and this also sits in the head these
these little flaps are slices of
tungsten and each each slice except
little motor and as the thing is
spending in the motors
push these these leads in and out
focusing radiation exactly very easily
so nothing gets irradiated that
shouldn't be which I was very much in
favor of so after after I take in my
character counts after the obligatory
check of the scouting process I thought
part of the problem was you have to stay
absolutely still when you're when you
being treated and I couldn't actually
see the display of the going to counter
it was sitting on the chair about three
meters of that so I decided to upgrade
firmware so that I could get a record of
the camp and so I rewrote the phone and
took it in again and the hope you know
she hasn't got a okay of EEPROM a
non-volatile memory so a reporting
facility which tracks the amount of
radiation receiving area every second
and it's just about enough to cover the
whole treatment and these are the
results the little the left hand side is
the CT scan on the right hand side is
the after treatment and I was surprised
to see that the treatment had much less
apparent radiation than the the CT scan
but a little having it a little thought
the beam is much more focused for a
start so not a little bit the spinning
or very little of it really relatively
speaking as convincingly at the GMT
also it's it's highly very high-energy
radiation and it's in wall tube so most
of the radiation
and it will get sexy so what's actually
being detected there is probably
secondary radiation where the gamma rays
hitting items in the in the road and
then they're stimulating the detector
you may notice that seems to be a kind
of seeing those sort of max analysis
that some points on there and I have no
idea why that is so if there was a
physicist actually resident on the
treatment center and she was kind of
intrigued by this so that apparently
this graph has been passed around the
physics community so they they kindly
gave you some explanations to that's why
Oscar I don't think they've got
definitive answer as to why they won't
get those masks awesome so I mentioned
that these things are cheap and this is
one which I picked a few days ago and
but you know sort of the sort of on the
eBay as you can see it's incomes 40 I
think something like that looks like on
YouTube they call SPM 20 so the the
labels in Zurich and this is the this is
the code for the council that I roots
are putting on github so if you're
interested in building your own I'm
gonna try and provide a safety for it as
well as some points I've got around to
that Chris yeah but the source code has
been open sourced and is available
there's also as a Python program there
which I use because I've implemented
it's a rudimentary form of compression
to fit more readings in and that's
additional decode that's you are
compressing and so I briefly briefly
mentions and possible upgrades to the
end so the thing this is one of the
upgrades which
unfortunately didn't arrive in time for
the EMF camp this is a
exness bt9 I'm not very good on sorry
this is what they've got an end window
detector it's got very thin
Michael window at the end of it and this
will pick up Alfre particles as well as
as well as the meter on camera
they're a bit more expensive I think
this cost me about 30 pounds but the
nice thing about them is that they will
work with exactly the same circuitry
I've already got so I can just basically
tweak our bourbon plug in hopefully so
that's pretty much it so thank you very
much for coming and listening to me and
I think I've probably just about
exceeded my mu I have exceeded my Lottie
time so if you've got any questions
about it however milkie's makerspace is
just across the across the way of that
so you can comment now my chapter
chapter to me and we have any questions
that you've got there Thanks
[Applause]