all right welcome back to stage C in
just a few moments we'll have Chris
right excellent Chris Wright who is come
from Switzerland and we'll be talking
about reinventing invention and I hate
tail he's an inventor himself so he has
a lot of experience with this so thanks
very much Chris and please round of
applause to welcome Chris thank you
thank you for that
so yeah just a bit of an introduction is
that I've been working for this small
company in Switzerland for the past kind
of two and a half years and called I
Provo and what they're doing is is kind
of trying to take a new approach to to
inventing and inventions by trying to
work out what what is the science of
invention sort of how do you invent
efficiently and effectively and also how
do you use new tools that are available
to us now to actually augment the human
invention process and just a bit of a
disclaimer I know some of these slides
have the company name all over them but
I'm not trying to sell the company the
talk is going to be more about the kind
of background of what is an inventor
what are inventions how do we how do we
make them and how can we facilitate that
process using AI so so the first
question is is what is an invention
people seem to have quite broad ranging
conceptions of what an invention might
be and usually people think of some some
famous products like the light bulb or
something like that that is an invention
in itself but an invention should be
really conceptualized as well yeah at a
more conceptual level it isn't a product
like a kettle or a car these things
actually consider consists of many many
small nuggets of inventions and this is
sort of the
the elementary particle for an inventor
is the inventive step is what's what's
the elementary new thing that is in your
idea that hasn't been seen before in
human knowledge and so that's that's the
one of the first definitions of of an
invention which probably the best or all
most widely accepted view of invention
is is from patents and of course patents
protect inventions and the invention
therefore has to fit several categories
several criteria the first one is that
they have to be new so novel it can't
have been seen before you can't reinvent
the wheel the second is that they have
to be useful you could easily invert
invent something new that solves a
problem that doesn't exist you could you
can invoke invent something for
traveling between Mars and the next
Galaxy or something like that and this
would not be a current use it wouldn't
be currently useful because we haven't
gone to Mars or in fact you can invent
magic and that's not useful and it also
has to be non-obvious so this is a this
is a really important step and it's what
kind of filters out a lot of the a lot
of the patents and all of the inventions
that are not actual inventions they are
new but they're not but they are obvious
so if I know about a microwave for
example and I know about cars just
sticking a car on a microwave combines
the two things in a new way nobody's
done that before maybe but it's obvious
it's just a current of microwave
together nothing new has been added
there the the the the the two elements
create not just for not more than the
sum of its parts and this edge brings me
to the to the most elegant description
I've found a bit of invention which is
at the bottom there that of the slides
that two point two plus two needs to
equal five or more for it to be an
invention
you need to have started with these
ingredients and you need to combine them
in a way which creates
a product that's more than the sum of
its parts
and that that really to me is the most
elegant way of defining the invention
but how do you come up with one what is
what is this lightbulb moment that
people talk about for me that that
describes this this edition so if I'm
the first person to consider putting
these two elements together that have
never been combined and I think we'll
okay so I'm putting two things together
maybe that's slightly interesting but
the invention is when you realize that
there's something more to it that you
can do you can create that the some new
system or some new mechanism which has
never existed before that that increases
the value of that product or invention
so the second question is who is an
inventor
can Eddie Murray invent people have this
conceptualization of perhaps an inventor
as a crazy guy in a shed that
inspiration just comes to them out of
nowhere out of the blue and this is a
this is a perception that I want to kind
of try and dispel over the next 20
minutes or so and what I want to try and
get across is that anybody can invent
anybody can be an inventor it takes a
human mind or at least an intelligent
mind to to put things together in a
clever way but there's a lot of smart
people in the world and they're all
trying to solve all of the problems that
humanity is facing so what
differentiates an inventor from someone
who doesn't manage to create that
invention and the answer is the
invention triggers the information that
they have if you look back through
history it's always not the smartest
people who are the most successful
inventors is the people who have access
to the most surprising the most useful
and the most distant information from
different domains create the most
destructive and amazing inventions so so
this is known as this can be illustrated
by the inevitability of invention
and these patterns seen throughout
history where you have inventions that
are that are made simultaneously in
completely different countries or
different continents with no
collaboration whatsoever the invention
is created by the by different groups or
different people who have the same input
information so again it's sort of
reiterating that the and that the
inventors are not special what special
is the information was quite as the
information so this is an example here
of the CT scanner where of course there
at the time in the 1970s and 60s there
were there were huge advances leaps and
bounds happening in terms of
high-performance computing and there was
also research and growing knowledge on
x-rays and x-ray imaging and so these
two people Godfrey Han field and Alan
McCormack both independently came up
with the idea that we could combine
these two things and we could design
algorithms for high-performance
computers to actually resolve an image
in three dimensions using a series of
two-dimensional scans around a person so
this was a fantastic invention but it
was inevitable given these advances in
this information that was becoming
available from the x-ray field and from
high-performance computing it was this
combination of two distant fields that
created the the CT scanner and the same
can be seen time and time again
throughout history there's lots and lots
of examples so this isn't by any means
exhaustive but there's some famous
examples but of course Newton and
Leibnitz both independently invented
calculus the same information was
available to them in mathematical papers
in different places around the world
Alexander Graham Bell and Elisha gray
both filed a patent for the telephone on
the same day within three hours of each
other again reinforcing just how
how time critical these inventions can
be as soon as the information is in vain
available to people people will make the
link so it's the information that
matters and and of course Edison with
the most famous example of intervention
the light bulb there were actually 23
people who had built prototype
lightbulbs before him and in fact all of
these diagrams here are all patent
diagrams for different people who have
invented a light bulb and these are just
the different embodiments for how they
thought the light bulb would look so all
inventions are inevitable but all
inventions are not created equal so in
every field like cars or run or
packaging or semiconductors in every
field that people work in incremental
inventions happen so ideas are
recombined within the field
that developed incrementally people
improve upon them and this creates a
growing wealth of knowledge and products
and general improvement within that
individual field and that's great and
that actually creates the vast majority
of patents that that that are put
through all patent offices in the world
but these are not the most disruptive
inventions they don't change the world
they aren't surprising necessarily so
actually it's been found by a lot of
different studies and observed by a lot
of famous people that the most
disruptive inventions actually happen
when insights come from very different
areas very different technology areas or
knowledge areas where you get surprising
or unexpected insights from a from a
completely far-off
area and you're able to make a link
between two very disparate areas that
nobody else could because you were the
only one with that combined information
so the the rarity of them is actually
being able to have that knowledge
from two distant fields and this guy
Clarence Birdseye is a is a fantastic
example of this and he's got a really
great story
so here's captain Birdseye of bird's-eye
Fame and he started the company and he
also invented modern freezers basically
so frozen foods actually existed before
mr. bird's-eye but he was they weren't
very good they they didn't keep the food
fresh for very long and they didn't take
off they weren't popular they were being
used in New York and so Clarence was
aware of modern freezer technology
thought it was interesting but he was
curious about it but it wasn't his main
area he was a taxidermist actually so
really interested in other forms of
preservation of biological tissue and he
was working for as a as a biologist for
the US government and he got sent to
Canada and in Canada he was living there
for five years while he was ice fishing
he the the Inuit showed him how to ice
fish and he's in these in these rings
you cut out the section of ice you fish
to take the fish out into the cold
arctic air and you take it home with you
and it can keep for months and months
and he realized that actually this fish
stayed fresh for much much longer than
than the previous freezing techniques so
he realized it tasted much much better
than the techniques that they were using
in New York and he did some
investigation and he actually found out
that it was the combination of the wind
and the and the instant flash freezing
and of that fish that was brought out
the water and it froze instantly and
that was what did it that was what
creates the conditions for keeping the
freshness that created small ice
crystals that didn't break down the cell
walls of the fish and so kept the
texture and the flavor of the fish and
so he subsequently went on to found
Birdseye patented many over 300 pounds
in modern refrigeration but the original
insight was this unexpected distant
there's a piece of information that
nobody had so nobody had those two ideas
in their head at the same time apart
from this guy but he had to go to a
northern Canada to find it which was
obviously a bit of a trek and so as we
progress through humanities as through
history obviously Clarence was a you
know he was inventing maybe 50 60 years
ago and as we progressed then the volume
of information in every single field of
human endeavor is is massively
increasing so just the amount of
information that's out there
the amount of ideas products mechanisms
tools everything is just in its ujin's
much therefore much much more difficult
to make these cross-domain links so
someone who works all their life in
electronic switches for example is gonna
is never going to know anything about
gearing mechanisms or something like
that but perhaps something in that in
that field in that distant field would
actually be hugely disruptive to what
they're doing and at the moment that
process is is completely serendipitous
and this is what I'm describing here is
the paradox of convergence so as you
have more ideas more information the
availability of invention should
increase because there are more
combinations that are available to to
create new ideas just the more
information the more combinations of
them you can have so you should have
more inventions but the invention
disruptiveness and creativeness is going
down and down over time
and so why is this and the theory is
that this is because there's this huge
burden of knowledge that what people
want is just this knife but what they
are presented where there's this huge
Swiss Army knife that has everything on
it you don't know what to pick and so
how do you filter down through that and
the other thing on the side is is of
course the power of convergence forever
you've seen one
one of his obvious example of
convergence and incremental invention is
with the car with the automobile so the
past hundred years the car has been
incrementally improved getting better
and better
going faster or further sounding better
all of that and then this a disruptive
connection between two distant domains
occurred and now this is what a car
looks like in ten years
after after ten years of change and so
this has been hugely disruptive
massively rapid change compared to the
past hundred years and that's the power
of converging domains and so of course
you also have an increased demand for
convergence because people are observing
this is happening a lot with any
technology with software and AI it's
being applied to absolutely every domain
available but these aren't the only
points of convergence and this is this
is just an illustration of how companies
are kind of perceived their products and
they're afraid of convergence so they
want to be the ones to create this
disruption but at the moment the process
is still totally serendipitous it's
entirely reliant on good luck so this
analogue front end of invention
I just just doesn't keep up with the
ability that should be there to create
points of convergence between domains so
the obvious question is how can a I help
and what we know about AI is that I'm
sorry wait now I've missed the slide
just to highlight the the kind of drive
behind what actually set up the company
that I work for is is this realization
that we live in a completely digitally
driven world data is everything the
marketing that sent you is driven by
data and algorithms and even the
financial systems are completely
dependent on on algorithmic trading and
and huge amounts of data to find out
these often very subtle or difficult to
find patterns in vast amounts of data so
we we do this for really important human
endeavor domains but we don't do it for
adventure
we're still relying on analog invention
and human good luck so just to
illustrate this the head of IBM
corporate strategy Colin Harrison had
this quote from 2013 but actually he has
no idea where a inventions come from but
even the head of one of the biggest
leading tech companies in the world five
years ago was saying we don't know it
just sort of happens so we we want to
try and put a bit more science into
invention and try and find out how we
can codify that science of invention
into algorithms to try and invent faster
and more disruptively
than before and so what what we think
that AI can do here is is to really
leverage the convergence so there's
growing information more and more
information and actually it's this
breadth of information which is
essential for creating disruptive
inventions you want to know you want to
know something from sport to be able to
solve a problem in medtech or vice versa
so they're completely separate areas of
science that's very unlikely for someone
to have those two pieces of information
at the same time but using the AI
solution we can now address this problem
so just some very brief summaries of
some tools that AI is bringing is
natural language processing of course
enabling us to digitally process and
comprehend text in a in a completely new
way that's that's totally scalable and
automatable so you can process all of
human knowledge and understand it to
some extent or recognize patterns in it
at least and the second one is machine
learning where perhaps you can find
patterns that people even people can't
find they're more subtle you can't a
person can't look at vast volumes of
information to find these patterns over
lives
but eh I can so if I'm trying to invent
in a particular area what if I have
access to exactly the right ingredients
at the right time just when I need them
and so that is what our company is doing
it's taking AI software and it's using
it to process volumes of information
from the internet and we then using that
filtered information and and processing
we're able to augment the human
invention process so that anybody so all
the people in this this is our invention
team and all the people in this team are
are not domain specialists that they're
not particularly knowledgeable about one
domain or another but they have all
invented or they have patentable
inventions in many many different fields
so I personally have worked in it in
baby products in satellites in finance
in all sorts of different domains that I
never thought I'd find myself in and I
have patents being filed in those
because I was able to use this tool to
find the right information at the right
time I didn't need this huge in-depth
knowledge and education because I could
use this AI tool to find just the
information I needed at that time and
just to illustrate the kind of power of
this approach that's being applied is
that the average inventor in their
lifetime creates just three patents and
this is actually incredibly expensive to
companies as well they invest loads and
loads into their R&D departments and the
average inventor just creates just three
patents but it's worth it a prolific
inventor is a is a five Sigma change
from that so it's 15 inventions
so you're classified as a prolific
inventor if you have more than 15
inventions and everyone who's worked for
I proba has managed to become a prolific
inventor within their first year of
working there I personally have over 40
patents
in the last two and a half years so yeah
just to sum up that using these
data-driven invention tools we can
really massively augment the invention
process and move move invention into the
21st century and change it from this
analog process to a really data-driven
process so thank you thanks so much I
think we've got some time for questions
[Music]
all right I'm gonna run around with a
microphone
hi there and I just wanted to ask about
what your feeling was of software
patents and how you know do they enhance
our society etc or is it actually more
detrimental to have software patents but
look at the software wars at Apple and
Samsung have been in so so typically
software patents are actually quite
difficult to defend because there's no
there's there's nothing you can point to
and say that this is a thing that we
invented this is the crux of the
invention and a lot of these a lot of
these patterns actually do kind of take
advantage of the fact that you know
they're kind of taking advantage of the
legal system rather than rather than
actually adding something definitely new
but the flip side of that is that a lot
of these algorithms are potentially very
difficult to to create and they might be
easily backwards engineer able so how do
you protect that idea how do you how do
you protect that so I I don't know and I
don't I don't know if I have a solution
to the problem but I do agree that it is
a problem and and certainly some
companies to abuse it for the detriment
of society
but actually our company doesn't doesn't
work in software or or a couple of other
domains simply because this kind of
information processing that we do just
works much better in the kind of
physical sciences and technical areas
like that so typically we would always
have some physical mechanistic element
to any invention that we create so I've
got to say my expertise on on purely
software patents is is quite limited
thank you very much any other questions
I've got one so a lot of the time it
seems to be a lot of technology that's
out there purely for the sake of
technology how do you make sure that the
inventions that you create are actually
things that people need rather than tech
for tech sake this is a good question
because that's that's often one of the
first things that you think of now that
you have this ability to automatically
generate ideas that's just a photo for
patent troughs
so the way we differentiate is just the
business model that the company actually
works with where we ask companies what
are your problems and we we basically
work out what the area they're trying to
work in what are they trying to solve
what are their problems and then we find
the most relevant kind of insights and
triggers from just distant domains to
match that project in there we so we
create inventions that there is need for
and we wouldn't work in a way that
creates the inventions first and then
finds someone to sell it to or to
protect it from or things like that
but in terms of will this happen in the
future maybe I don't know I mean the
capabilities there so it might it might
well be a matter of time okay any more
questions if not he please join me in
thanking Chris for this very interesting
talk
[Music]
[Applause]
you