I'm very very pleased to welcome dr.
James Bailey from the University of
Glasgow he'll be talking about designing
custom chips and sensors and lemon
appeal technology thanks very much thank
you can everyone hear me okay I'm going
to talk today about the process of
designing and fabricating chips and I'm
also going to talk a little about some
of the research prototype chip projects
have involved designing so I'm basically
going to look at the process of
designing applications difficult
aggression circuits Asics we look a
little bit at chip foreigners and
processors I'm going to look at the
process of designing and verifying
analog chip hardware and digital
hardware I'm going to look a little
reverse engineering and fake chips then
I'm going to look at a couple of
projects I've been involved with and
which are capsules for doing
autofluorescence and ultrasound
examination said the human intestine so
the first question is if you if you
looked at a check what would you find
okay if you look around the edge of the
chip and you will see a pod ring and
you've got little bond pads and these
allow you to bring out bond wires to a
chip package or to a circuit board and
they let you bring in power and bring
out signals and this is an RF chip it
wasn't a quite prominent on the chip are
in doctors in the middle of the and to
the right these are these are fabricate
on the metal layers the chip there's
also a digital block on the left this
has been fabric this has been
synthesized by digital synthesis tool to
fit into the space and left the chip and
chips are built a number of different
fabrication technologies okay the most
common the most dominant is silicon
the really dominant technology is CMOS
and complimentary metal metal ox oxide
this is where the most widely used
technology used in the great bulk of
digital chips bipolar analog is also not
uncommon and they're also more
specialized silicon technologies like by
CMOS which combines bipolar and CMOS in
the same shares only amps RF rock it's
also BCD which is used for power
electronics but CMOS is really the
become the dominant technology the
simple reason being that the the two
main transistor types a bipolar
transistor this will if you're using the
your devices as a digital switch a
bipolar transistor will draw current and
when it is switching and it will also
draw a current in the steady state a
CMOS transistor will only draw current
when switching when it's switched on or
off it will draw with no current and
this is really why CMOS has become the
dominant technology for digital design
simply because the power consumption is
much lower okay
and because so many of so much much of
the hardware design design CMOS and
there's been a great emphasis on putting
other functionality into CMOS chips so
there's been a lot of interest in
putting an analog functionality onto
CMOS chips and produce mixed signal
chips and there are also more
specialized technologies and for example
silicon carbide repair transistors
silicon germanium for radio frequency
work and for LEDs light emitting diodes
there are a number of different
technologies gallium phosphide zinc
selenide etc okay but the really key key
thing with this is although CMOS is
dominant there is no one technology that
will do everything okay
so although that the semiconductor
industry is heavily geared toward CMOS
and there is no single technology that
will do everything that you want to do
if you really the main the main building
block of a CMOS chip is a MOSFET
transistor okay the picture it basically
shows what what you get if you took a
vertical slice through a CMOS transistor
and and it's basically fabricated I am
on a silicon wafer and you're basically
fabricates when you're fabricating
you're basically using a series of masks
and a series of itching processes and
you're basically implanting and
impurities into the silicon to create
the injunctions and in the case of the
the CMOS transistor also fabricating a
poly silicon gate on top and when you
apply a voltage in the gate the source
this will cause a current to flow
between source and drain and in fact
immediate CMOS transistor is a voltage
controlled current device and and the
main defining feature of a CMOS a CMOS
process is what's called feature size
and feature size is basically the
smallest gate width that you can
fabricate in a given process and this
vessel theory current approach it might
be 0.5 micron in our process right down
to 7 nanometer in a state-of-the-art
let's say until processor there's a nice
talk chaos communication congress my RA
who enters this in a lot more detail so
I'd strongly make it recommend look at
that and on your chip you've got
transistors you'll have resistors
capacitors inductors note
interconnecting have metal layers okay
and coming up from each of these device
you'll have vertical metal wires then
you'll have typically between 2 and 12
metal layers and now your chips will be
fabricated on a silicon wafer which is
typically 30 centimeters diameter and
after fabrication the chips will be
separated and using a dicing saw now
when your protein or the the set up cost
of process is very high the order of a
hundred thousand points so if you're
prototyping and the work I have done is
basic basically in developing early
stage proof of concept prototype
chips use a multi-project way for
service and in this case anyone choose
PCB pool or similar and basically the
the mount mpw serves they'll basically
do a wafer and it will have a number of
different chips a single wafer and this
will bring the cost down from 100,000
pounds maybe ten fifteen thousand pound
in other words to what a university
research budget can afford okay you've
got there's a whole range device you can
have on chips you could have resistors
which should we fabricate in poly
silicon and you've got you can fabricate
capacitors using to eject the
capacitance win to taste metal layers
you can have inductors which are tiny
coils made of metal and you almost got
bond pads to bring signals out and you
can also do sensors and for example
charge coupled device or CMOS sensors
and for light sensing photodiodes
aspired single photon Avalanche diodes
for sensing very low light levels is ver
sensing pH and there's a lot of interest
in putting sense and CMOS because it
means that you can put the sensor and
the processing electronics on the same
chip a lot of the old digital cameras
use CCD charge coupled device charge
crumpled device needs a separate chip to
address and process signals the CMOS
sensor allows you to put the imager and
electronics on the same die with a
resultant saving and cross in size you
can also process up thanks for example
obstacle-filled on top of the chip so
we'll talk about about the design
process is what i do for a job and there
are really only three major of dominant
manufacturers and there's basically
synopsis cadence and Mentor Graphics so
the problem is because it's quite a
specialized process there aren't a lot
of companies and the software is fairly
capable it's expensive and it can leave
a bit to be desired in terms of
usability and open-source support is
very limited there is magic witness this
is quite an old and limited open-source
package but basically pretty much
everyone will use a commercial package
for one of the three major manufacturers
okay one side obviously is
design Sofra the other side is a design
kit and this is supplied by your chip
manufacturer chip for Andrew and it's
specific to the chip design process okay
so thus they will basically give you
they'll give you a set of simulation
models they'll give you digital standard
sales for digital synthesis they'll give
you design rules cuz each process has a
set of rules in terms of things like
gate would track with spacing between
structures and these are manufactured up
manufacturability rules that have to be
adhere to pretty strictly if you don't
meet these rules they won't even try and
fabricate your chip okay the other
interests other thing is that a lot of
the devices are parameterized able so
that you could for example of a
transistor and you could define a width
length ratio that define its gain or you
could have a resistor where you define
this resistance and the other the other
thing the other thing that you can often
pick up from other manufactures are I
people of intellectual property blocks
because of the expense and complexity
and risk and designing and chip hardware
and there's a strong emphasis on design
reuse in other words if you've got
hardware that works or sub-block that
works you would tend to reuse that and
it means that there are many companies
who were there actually selling
validated and verified third-party IP
blocks again these could be parameter
about proper amortizable so you might
for example buy in a ROM or a ram block
for a processor and when you buy it you
would specify and specify the RAM they
at the ROM depth and then data bus width
there are three two kinds that you've
got hard cores hard cores are specific
to a particular chip process you also
have soft cores they will come in a
hardware description language and you
can put them through your synthesis tool
and you can synthesize them into your
own process and so there are all sorts
of blocks for example adc's deadlines
little converters op amps buffers
phase-locked loops there are various
boss cores for example PCI Express can
bus for automotive USB which again which
will be Provera fight
and you can even buy an entire processor
this is really hot this is arms business
model arm don't actually make processors
arm sell processor cores to third
parties who integrate those into their
own ships along with other functionality
so if your designer chip your starting
point will be a specification you define
what you want your chip to do your power
budget inode etc and that will take you
onto a particular fabrication process
then your partitioning your design down
your partition it down into manageable
units into analog blocks and digital
blocks and then you carry out your
design and you'll spend a lot of time
simulating and verifying because the
problem of the chip is with us it with a
circuit you can you know you can pull
out your craft knife and so during ion
every rocket if you write a piece of
code in this buggy recompile you cannot
do it out of the chip so with chip
design you spend a lot of time and
verification you spend a lot of time on
simulation analog simulation their
digital simulation next signal
simulation and design real checking I'm
Laird versus schematic checking so
before you submit a design you want to
be very confident that that design is
valid is going to work and in the real
world you often go through multiple
iterations it will often take you create
a few iterations to get something that
actually meets spec so don't know how
many people who have done PCB design the
analog entry process is very similar you
have a schematic tool and you have a
library of transistors resistors
capacitors at saturation supply they're
part of your design kit and you'll
basically enter those in your schematic
two occasions virtually over so for
example and you'll parameterize that you
will set the value of a resistor you'll
set the width length ratio of a
transistor etc then you simulate and
each of the design tools that will it
will incorporate and analog Speight as
like a piecewise type simulator and
cadence case for example ad respect our
synopsis to H spice and you will define
and purse you can do it basically a a
transient sweet for example would you
define inputs at times and then you'll
get a waveform okay you're basically to
look at that
and see a fat meat spec you can also do
things like frequency sweeps you can
also sweep and over a range of
temperature because obviously device
device behavior will vary with
temperature and with process tolerance
and the supply voltage and you can also
look at things like phase and gain
margin for stability amplifiers and
again
your growth iterations once you have
something that meets spec then you move
into the layout phase see based on
analog layout tool so basically in your
schematic so you're basically pick each
device and the layout tool it will
generate an appropriately shaped
transistor resistor inductor etc you
then have to manually place them and you
also have to when you place them you
have to consider carefully signal
integrity for example keeping noisy
digital circuitry away from sensitive
analog circuitry you will then have to
manually run wires on the metal layers
vias and wires between those devices
then you can do a layup versus schematic
check ok that will check that your
layout matches the schematic you're off
to design real check that checks at this
layout matches or it complies with the
designers design rules ok the other
issue you have is parasitics you you've
you've so far you've simulated
transistors with ideal connections
between them ok you have no know you've
done a layout you have no added extra
metal wires in the metal layer these
will bring end straight inductance and
capacitance and resistance and these
will tend to have an effect particular
RF circuit so then you run parasitic
extraction this will add to your
simulation model it will add additional
capacitors inductance is so you then re
simulates with parasitics and and once
you've done that again a threat to few
times you have a valid analog block the
digital design process for anything but
the simplest designs is built it's built
around hardware description languages so
you're basically you're basically
written writing a programming language
description of the functionality you
want from your chip so common languages
are VHDL
they're a log system see system very log
and and you're like you're basically
coding up a description of functionality
of things like counters buses addressing
state machines etc now these language
unlike conventional coding they're
inherently parallel because you're
coding up a number of functions in
hardware which will operate
simultaneously they are thinking to be
careful about is each of your synthesis
tools only implements a subset of
errorlog a vhdl so you could I mean you
could quote something in C or Python you
could write it five different ways it'll
work véra lager VHDL you could code
something in this entitled invalid VHDL
or Verilog but only a subset will work
so each tool has its own subset so again
you've got to read the documentation you
really need to follow let's say cadence
or synopsis recommend way of coding ok
these language are all they're also
modular to a low design reuse to later
ease IP blocks and an important fits a
test bench a test bench is basically a
top level you basically instantiate your
design as a module the test bench
provides base a set of inputs for
testing ok which you'd use in simulation
c so once you've got it's entitled valid
VHDL you'd put var and your compile on
your test bench into a simulation tool
like VCS or NC sim this will give your
waveform output ok so you would
basically define all your input signals
to find your clocks define your reset
define your data buses this will give
you a waveform output ok this allows you
to verify that your code is functionally
correct at this stage it doesn't include
any timing delays and again accelerate
this multiple times until it works ok
your next step is synthesis once you
have a valid VHDL description of your
circuit the synthesis tool this will
convert that into a netlist of gates
because the gate the gates are processed
specific the gates will be provided or
gates or blocks they'll be provided by
your ASIC foundry so you'll basically
you'll give your synthesis tool a very
load of HDL netlist input and you'll
give it the timing information for the
gates and you'll also give it
constraints you might you can
constrain power and you can you might
see this appends a clock and it works at
50 megahertz you might see this pin has
to appropriate this output has to have a
clock totally if not more than five
microseconds you give it those
constraints the synthesis tool will then
attempt to meet those and again you may
need to iterate this a few times and
assuming since the selector is
successful it will generate a netlist
but you now have a netlist of gates
provided by this manufacturer okay
you've also got a standard delay file
SDF and this provides basically provides
system time delays in others the
propagation delays within each block or
gates
okay now the SPRO because it requires
iteration the process is heavily
command-line driven okay you can see a
graphical interface there but a lot of
the commands are come are a lot of the
functionalities command line base and
this is so you can script it because
again you often go through many
iterations so the whole thing is
scriptable using TCL tool command
language so you'll basically take your
commands from your first iteration it
goes into a text file and that will give
you a script that allows you to rapidly
reiterate where you never have to go
back and make design changes from your
sent from your netlist you've gotten so
you've now got a netlist very long a
VHDL netlist of gates untain him you'll
put this into a place in route tool for
example cadence encounter the place in
route tool it will take that net list
and it will physically lay it out with
an actual silicon ok so your starting
point you'll define the boundaries of
your digital block see think think back
to the foot leaves and seconds later put
up of the the chip there was a digital
block which had irregularly defined
boundaries you can actually you can
shape your digital block to fit around
other devices so basically you determine
the boundary of the distal block you set
up power and ground rings around it and
and there and you'll import your netlist
and again you'll give it timing
constraints you'll define which signals
are clocks which are recess which are a
Cygnus a synchronous and
[Music]
then these the place and route sale at
will also a place those cells in Rose
it's basically row based if you look if
you were to look at a additional chip
very closely you'd see row row row chips
it will auto place and it will then
generate a clock tree okay the clock is
the the clock is basically the source of
synchronization for all the synchronous
in the in the circuit and the goal of
clock tree generation is to is to
minimize the skew or the time difference
between different clock signals within
the chip so the beta it'll basically
it'll basically place the clock net and
clock buff right it will basically
prioritize that first and then you run
the authority' the auto route will
attempt to off to a place tracks
what interconnect the cells then then
you run a static timing analysis this
will basically check each path through
the system and it will check it meets
the constraints and if it doesn't meet
the constraints the the tool can it can
to a certain extent fixed timing
violations it can insert buffers into
clock paths or signal paths and but
again if you have major timing issues
you may just have to go back and
reiterate design okay assuming you get
through place in route successfully
again you run verification and you'd run
design rule checking and then it will
generate an output block and cadence for
example the ASIS format which you can
import back into virtuoso and then it
will give you an output netlist which
you can use for simulation and an output
timing timing signals it which mean and
this means that you can then you can
then do a post place enroute simulation
okay it means that you can re simulate
with gate delays and interconnect delays
and again you want to check that meets
your specification and if not again
reiterate your next step
once you have valid analog and digital
blocks is chip assembly okay
you're basically late you're basically
layer at the complete chip you and you
basically you'll have bond parts analog
input and output pads you're basically
placed up a pad right around the edge of
your chair and you will place your
analog and digital blocks on the chip
again taking care to over signal
integrity taking care to keep the
digital signals are noisy and we've mine
look signals again you will manually and
why are tracks to connect those blocks
together and again you'll do a lot of a
lot of time a lot of time spent doing
design rule checking Lea versus
schematic parasitic extraction makes
Sigler simulation etc the stages you're
simulating the whole chip the stage is
slowing you're often rushing to do this
to be a chip deadline okay once you have
a valid chip the process if this was
done years ago in Tate that still
referred to as tape out so you'll submit
our GDS to file to your chip for injury
to to your manufacturer you'll then wait
in our case wait several months you'll
get a small number of chips back and
spend a little time testing no a chip on
its owns not a lot of you so it needs to
be bonded and onto a circuit board or
into a package okay the bulk of chips
will be wire bonded into a package it
will be a dual inline or a pin grid
array a ball grid array package and
you'll have local bond wires which it's
up in girl they're aluminum and these
are bonded by ultrasonic bunhead and if
you look at the picture on the top right
there's a shirt which is born to a
package with little bond wires they're
basically bonded from the chip bond pads
on to bunt pattern on the on the the
package and these pads on the package
these interconnect depends
no traditionally the sessional packs has
been dual inline package with pins at
point one inch spacing
the limitation of that package is
limited Pino you have a look at number
of pins the other limitation is stray
inductance and capacitance which tend to
impact badly on radio frequency circuits
so a lot of chips know will tend to use
sawfish moment they'll tend to use ball
grid array in this case and you have a
chip bonded to a substrate and then
they'll be little solder balls on the
underside of the substrate which are
basically ball ball grid bonded to the
circuit board you can also have multiple
substrates on the are multiple chips on
the same package as I mentioned earlier
no one chip process is really suitable
for all functionality so and the bottom
right is a ws2812 I was in as a new
pixel and this is a multi assistant
program with multicolor LED it was on
the EMF pass from two years ago and if
you look closely you can see they've
actually used they've got four Center
substrates there are three chips at the
bottom these are three LEDs and
different colors and the top chip this
is a CMOS chip so the CMOS will
basically take a serial and put command
it will then and drive the three red
green blue LEDs through the program
color there's a hole there's a whole
industry devoted to reverse engineering
of chips and whether that's hobbyists
whether it's people looking into
painting violations people trying to
figure out the competition they're doing
though most chips are packaged in resin
no to get the resin off requires nitric
acid which I wouldn't recommend for
safety reasons and beyond that once
you've taken off once you've actually
exposed the chip you can then strip away
the individual layers and step by step
okay again if you want look into this
couple of nice websites rate or coms up
to a bars they've got some very nice
chip pictures if you want to look at a
chip yourself there are metal case chips
there are devices for transistor you can
get them off eBay
the case will easily come off with a
hacksaw or Dremel so that will give you
a fairly safe way to if you feel like
decapping a chip yourself it's quite
interesting issue of fake chips
and this was something that turned up on
the scepter bar site they've actually
they were looking at Nordic NRF this is
based on our UHF RF transceiver and the
original chip comes in about ten dollars
okay and they've come across a fake
somebody's obviously somewhere looks
like they've got a bootleg copy of
cadence they're actually they've
actually managed to reverse-engineer the
complete chip again most often zip to
bars and bunny who hang has quite in 20
hindsight switch thoughts in this okay
don't know about some projects I've
worked with and this is the fluorescence
image our capsule no this is a project
which I was I've watched on a Gloucester
University no you may you may have come
across whitelighter magic at its base
like a capsule you swallow and it has a
camera LED and it lets you image the
entire intestine it's basically is too
much disease and it will cover a part of
the intestine that endoscopy won't cover
because endoscopy will only cover a bone
to the stomach or below the stomach and
the large intestine endoscopes won't
cross the small intestine and no often
fluorescence if you eliminate intestinal
tissue tissue with blue light it'll
fluoresce green you get weak
fluorescence this fluorescence lets you
see early signs of disease that you're
not going to see with white light so we
developed a prototype capsule and to do
fluorescence imaging the intestine no
there isn't the resin well-proven and
fluorescence endoscope but only goes
down to the stomach and duodenum okay so
basically we did our 32 by 32 single
photon Avalanche diode s pottery and
para measure and pulse current to a chip
and we basically integrated it into a
miniature capsule and we've integrated
with an FPGA for control under an eight
six eight megahertz wireless link and
and the it this and we and we basically
we've so far we have validated this on
intestinal tissue of a pig and this is
I've done a lab bench I had to go to a
slaughterhouse to pick up pig intestinal
tissue which is kind of fun
and and this is the fluorescence image a
so we did this and 0.35 micron high
voltage process higher voltage in the
ASIC world means another thing about
five volts
little chips about three point seven by
three point seven millimeters and you've
got a single photon Avalanche diode
array this is an array of very sensitive
I basically have a pulse each time it
gets hit by a single photon from
autofluorescence we've got pulse cantos
we've also got a charge pump that
generates 37 volts from a 3 volt hearing
aid battery and and this draws about 1.8
million average imaging one frame per
second and the capture runs for about 12
hours which is ample to work for free
human testing our project I'm involved
that moment is a sauna pill the basic
idea is to do ultrasound examination
below the surface of human testing
because you can look for outside the
body with with ultra certainly 2 5
megahertz it will let you see through
the whole body
for example the ultrasound used in for
an imaging pregnancy it doesn't let you
see much detail if you increase
frequency you get less depth but you
have much greater detail so the goal is
to put 30 megahertz ultrasound inside a
capsule to see a few millimeters below
the intestinal surface so the basic
basic ideas we have eight ultrasound
drivers a 30 element receiver array and
theater acquisition embedded processor
an ADC on chip okay so this was the
check we designed again that the sister
and a one in a point one eight micron
high voltage process I've got a nun yet
processor and we've got a dose of
oxidation block we've got 32 and
low-noise amplifiers receivers and for
acquiring data from the receiver a we've
got our own transmitter and we did this
we did this in a EMS OSHA mycsustan
process about 16,000 gates and this is
currently bench tested were currently
tested friends with transducers okay
it's showing good sign so far um I'm Ben
government tends to finish quickly so
this is just one more project I've had
someone vocalist of the multi corridor
and the idea in this case was to put
multiple and medical diagnostic devices
benchtop devices
and on a single chip a single hand Hill
disposal check base looking at pH and
luminometer spectrophotometers and to
look at the base look at metabolites
that metabolize which are indicate
macros for disease okay and this
basically had a 16 by 16 or 32 by 32
array of exits are basically s pad for
low light imaging pH and photodiode okay
and this check basically had enzymes
abundant the top and it's actually
proven with two different processes one
well as an enzyme and which there's a
color change in relation to cholesterol
level and the second which was a pH
change in relation to blood glucose so
it's beta this is basically a research
prototype and to demonstrate a small
handheld device that can be used for
disease diagnosis right I'm be giving
more hands to finish so these are just a
couple of sites you might to look like
look at further reading if you want to
look at more decap chips okay thanks
guys who might have time for questions
I'm afraid we're probably not going to
have time for questions where might they
find you if they want to come and ask
you questions right I'll be outside
outside probably towards the bar right
I'll be over there okay thank you thank
you please think Jane's very much for
this fantastic talk thank you
[Applause]