so hello everyone we're here to tell you
about the adventure we've had over the
last year building sites the
infrastructure that you've been using
show you how we built it the challenges
we faced and how you used it and since
everything started from the site design
I'll start by introducing Russ from the
admin team who is responsible for it
yeah so I'm for the first time in an
infrastructure review I'm actually going
to talk about something and mostly about
the bits of over engineered technology
that we use to actually design and plan
the festival so this we we signed the
contract for the site almost a year ago
actually I think that was it seems like
a really long time ago and we've had a
couple of site visits up here where
we've come up and camped for a weekend
and gone round and so it worked out
where everything might go and it's a
it's exceedingly difficult with this
site because there's a lot of light it's
everything has to be on something
approximately flat but that's that's not
many places around here and it also
doesn't have to very importantly the
tents don't have to go on top of water
mains as we found out in 2016 and and
various other like more practical things
like where do the roads go how can we
use the road so that we can't that we
don't have to rent in so much trackway
and so on so this is one of our planning
sheets that we did back in like March or
something where we kind of drew in what
we thought we had to do and then this is
our CAD plan with all the layers turned
on so it has like the underground
services and the power and network and
the lighting and ducts and pipes and all
sorts trees stumps and that's that's how
the web map has generated it's generated
directly from that CAD plan it did that
we have this increasingly sophisticated
pipeline which we can use to turn a CAD
plan which is good for precisely
planning where things go and making sure
that you know the tent is not too close
to the track or things like that and
also and then that turns it into a web
map which I completely rewrote this year
to be
vector and fancy and it mostly works
except in some people's weird browsers
but this saw my fault oh yeah there's a
diagram of that because which used to be
much more much more complicated but this
this is the kind of simplified new
diagram which isn't quite as as annoying
and yes the doctor Doc's are out of date
sorry
as always we also got signs this year
I'm not sure why I'm talking about these
but it's quite exciting actually the
council were like you should have some
signs to tell people to slow down so I
called the AAA and I was like do some
signs for us and they were like sure and
and and it was like the easiest supplier
I had to deal with and they didn't even
charges very much so I hope people found
them helpful we didn't really need or I
don't think we needed all of them but
but they seem to work pretty well and
then the day before we came on site
somebody delivered the bins which was
kind of them but they put them where we
were going to put our initial logistics
area so we only had to move about I
don't know 10 tons worth of bins
probably not 10 tons and then they came
around a bit later with a bin washing
machine which was which was exciting so
it was exciting so now I'm so now I'm
going to talk a bit about our power
infrastructure which I've been perhaps a
little bit too much involved in
designing this this time because I
decided to completely rewrite the
software we used to do it there's a
common theme with EMF like oh this
doesn't work it doesn't quite work the
way we needed to let's write into a
completely new system so we have this
computer-aided power design system which
which takes up our main plan which I
showed you before and converts it in
work cell if the if the plan is valid
and the right things are plugged into
the right people the right the right
panels and so on the right people yeah
and and then it spits out some lovely
graphs so this is is this is one one
third of our power this year I can
barely see that so I don't know I don't
whether it's coming out on the expensive
projector so that shows like every
single piece of distribution equipment
and the links between them and how much
voltage drop and prospective fault
current and all those things that I've
been nerdy about for the last six months
so we've been trying to get because the
EMF powered system is entirely done by
EMF rather than an external company we
have to make sure that we do all the
testing and validation of it so this is
part of that and it tells you whether
the cabling is not big enough for
various other things and and flags it
all out in this huge diagram and then of
course no plan survives contact with the
real world so we we did put our power
order in quite late our supplier temple
on our fantastic they're actually one of
my favorite suppliers and I do have a
list of my favorite suppliers and they
they were like oh yeah we're going to
have to substitute a few things and and
and move these things around we don't
quite have enough of these and we don't
quite have enough of those and and then
we ended up with this mess so we had oh
that's clipped it should say 119 Power
Distribution boards of more than 16 amp
fives that more than 5200 meters of
power cable three generators two of
which were 300 kPa and one was 200 kPa
so that's 800 kPa or about 800 watts of
power capacity of which we had 130
kilowatts total peak loads like we
didn't need those big generators and in
fact we didn't order them they were like
sorry you'll just have to have these
vast 300 kV a generators somebody went
round just now and counted counted all
of the people plugged in and and
apparently there's more than 400 I
didn't I didn't verify that number so
this is this is the main supply of one
of the generators that's the one up
there and we have these juicy 400 amp
cables going going away from those and
that that's a container full of all the
power distribution that we have several
tons of it
and we did a bit of aerial power rigging
with some very heavy cable which was
yeah it worked a little bit wobbly it
didn't fall down which is good and yeah
there's there's there's a small sample
of the 400 connections plugged in and a
fire extinguisher because safety first
so in a May of 2016 we had a bit of a
problem that we didn't tell you about
over the weekend
we weren't realised that we were getting
really close to the wire with fuel and
so we had to get Benny under this telly
handler and get him to unscrew that fuel
drain plug and and siphon the fuel out
of this telehandler into the generator
so this
[Applause]
this time we didn't want to do that so
we got we got some bigger fuel tanks
much bigger fuel tanks and they all
arrived and they dropped them off and
then they were like oh yeah we've just
gotten picked these up from another site
and they're all empty so it was his last
Tuesday they just turned up with all
this equipment and like all the
generators are empty so we we had to
find somewhere to buy seven thousand six
thousand litres of diesel which is quite
a lot of diesel it's about five grams
worth and they couldn't come until until
Friday actually they came and so we had
to get a temple on to chuck us over
another fuel tank to kind of make do
that's that's what an empty fuel tank
looks like in case you hadn't seen one
before
that's what an empty fuel tank in
generator internal fuel tank looks like
on the left and yeah putting the
lighting in was a bit of a challenge
this time it turns out this particular
site is very very hard and usually we
put these bits of metal in called put
logs which hold the festooned poles up
we had way more festoon that we could
have put up but we could we didn't
because we couldn't get these things
into the ground and we kept bending them
or just didn't work or the tele handle
would tip over or something like that
but we got I don't know if one kilometer
is the amount of installed lighting but
for the first time we used LEDs rather
than incandescent bulbs which saves a
lot of power and it's also makes let's
see why them in the longest rings so
that's why they all look cool white we
did a bit of site lighting finally
thankfully last Lost's last year I lost
EMF I volunteered myself to try and do
some of this but I was way too busy and
we got a load of lights out and then
some hartnett problem happened and never
worked but now we have an actual site
lighting team and they've been doing
some pretty stuff and next time it will
be even more pretty that's a guarantee
they're using these off-the-shelf
Ethernet to artnet to DMX nodes and a
load of DMX cable and and a laptop
this this presentation has been
reordered since I last looked at it
which was eight minutes ago or something
this somehow got found somewhere I'm not
sure what was going on there did they
try and stick it in the song it was in
the socket I'm informed so don't do that
like they're not compatible and I know
I'm going to be with David
[Applause]
[Music]
yes sir hello again I'm David see from
the NOC team and I'm going to talk to
you first about the uplink some of you
have been to EMF before will recall the
first few events we were running
wireless point-to-point links and every
time we ran one we swore we're not going
to do that again unfortunately this time
it wasn't even an option because you may
have noticed that there are many hills
around here which would make it
basically impossible even if we had
somewhere useful to go to which we
didn't because we're quite far out here
so planning for this actually began
around about the time that we first came
to visit the site an investigate in
August last year and we quickly realized
that we're going to have to get a
circuit from a commercial provider
somewhere out of a site but wait what we
wanted to do was make it really easy for
the supplier to put it in
so we built a cabinet right by the road
ran ducting for them right to the road
so all they'd have to do was in theory
was connect up their doctor our ducts
pull some fiber three with the rope that
we provided so we were here in January
digging in some very hard ground getting
trenching in for the ducts to the road
power to the cabinet some sheep were in
the field this field was not actually a
camping field at that time of year so by
popular request someone keeps tweeting
EMF webcam asking for sheep Harris and
sheep the and this is in fact a Deer
Park we saw deer in the adjacent fit in
the adjacent field as well we were
careful not to interfere with them so
this is what we ended up with this is
how we left it and
it's how we return to it full of covered
in weeds later well a couple of weeks
ago in good condition in the meantime
that provider had come hooked up the
ducts and excuse me here's an example of
just outside that cabinet in fact you
can see branching off to the left two
ducts for a circuit providers one we
used one is in reserved for future years
the ducts going off to the right which
was hastily added a last week in fact
with some PVC bonding cement and geto
homemade swept tees actually comes all
the way up here to site because what we
discovered using the documentation
fairly fairly illegible documentation
provided by the site but actually
walking through and actually looking at
manholes and seeing where things got
went is that we would in theory be able
to pull fiber all the way up to the site
backup plan same as usual throw fiber in
a hedge run it down the ditch throw it
away afterwards so here we are this is
about 1.2 kilometers of fiber we rotted
last Sunday it seems like a month ago we
the manholes are every hundred to 150
meters sometimes a bit shorter but for
each one we push this yellow very stiff
rod through pull back a rope and then
pull the rope back through again all the
way this on the right here is is the
main fiber a cause just in case
something goes wrong
[Music]
and apparently we energize team synergy
to assemble an enterprise-grade fiber
school unspooling solution there we go
and yes this was splicing in the back of
a van down by the main gate
to that in here is our network operation
center which we got running fairly early
it was the staging point in the
distribution point for taking the
switches sending the round the field
with the access points to be installed
in the dart Enclave and as for a
datacenter well we've tried a few things
over the year 2012 we had rented scout
tents with full 19-inch rack which
worked pretty well accepting was hard to
cool and kept getting bits of field in
all the equipment 2014 we had a
refrigerated shipping container a reefer
which was great it was so cold problem
was it was too cold you couldn't set the
setpoint high enough to stop it
constantly chilling and because the door
was opening frequently people going in
and out of produced a load of
condensation
there was blown over all the switches
and servers which had to be covered in
tarp so cold but side effects 2016 we
went for what the buyers which is a cool
room basically we didn't realize at the
time that the inbuilt chiller unit was
mostly designed for keeping already cold
things cold so food drinks rather than
actually cooling enormous amounts of
thermal output from switches and servers
so we did actually have to buy aircon at
the last minute but other than that it
worked really well so that's what we use
this year this is the Assembly of the
quorum the cloud services datacenter be
at the former location of the inadequate
cooling unit has been replaced by a
fiber and copper entry port and this is
what it looks like inside heavy stuff on
the bottom UPS is very heavy and the
servers and then from left to right we
have the wireless LAN controllers and
some of the Vox video teams servers and
the middle we have at the bottom we have
the core switch where every fiber around
site is plugged in
we'll get that out in a moment and on
the right are those fibers yes you may
have noticed that there is no flat on
this field so bages had to be involved
in certain points to stop the
air-conditioning tipping over on to the
server's now the the NOC DC was actually
positioned where it is because we wanted
to use the manhole that runs all the way
toward the duct from the manhole that
runs all the way down to the front gates
so unlike previous years we only had one
power feed in previous years we've had
feeds from two different generators at
this time we didn't but everything
worked fine we had a resilient pair of
UPS's and an automatic transfer switch
for the service that couldn't take dual
power supplies and we had no outages at
all and I will hand over to Niels
[Applause]
Thank You Anil and I'll talk a bit about
actual stuff out in fields this diagram
comes from the same CAD system as was
used for a power distribution lots of
shared development there purple lines
are the fiber that goes across the
fields so from central places to data
close the circles are roughly 50 meter
diameter circles around these Delta
cloud being 25 meters kind of a rule of
thumb you don't don't really expect
people to bring along your cables than
that
so dr. Klaus spiced us on the fields so
the circles just almost all flap and if
you pay attention to where the purple
eyes go here you will have noticed that
these are all little islands and one of
the big features of this field is that
there are there's infrastructure between
several places that we could use to
transport data where we didn't have to
cross roads because road crossings are
really annoying to do there's lots of
traffic always and vans and stuff so gun
food fibers there you have to work with
Rams which are expensive and heavy and
this way with with lots of cores from
between three places on the field itself
there's a lot of hassle in deploying
working infrastructure here this is the
the Ducks plant there were three
manholes and we we had up to 12 cores
between different places basically these
these little LED signs are splice boxes
with a watertight scoffer offer them and
at each side we would break out a couple
fibers and the rest would go on so from
from the core we had a store network
from the core we could patch everything
all the way through to the end of the
field without having to have any access
equipment although for the place where
are right so this is how the network
plan
this is the logical diagram as you can
see everything is connected to the core
switch to the core router East nor I'm
assuming a non-native English speaker
wrote that down after hearing a British
person say it and the couple places
where we didn't want to run fibre
because there are really short distances
and we had a you know ten meters of
copper cable and that is the the bottom
layer you see in this diagram
yeah it's site wise but you know
landscape this is the physical diagram
which you can see is different and these
are not switches but these are the dots
and clubs all over field so for example
you can go from the left to the right in
this diagram and follow the cable from
one data to another all across the field
with no active equipment in between
except where it says copper so again
this is coming from a single source of
truth which is really helpful when when
ya troubleshooting problems and making
sure that everybody knows what actually
is the network design that is being
rolled out what feelin's need to be
aware and just finding out what is where
this is one of those splice boxes that
we had a couple of three fields on the
right side you see the the black multi
core fibers outdoor fibers that run
underneath the ground come in then
they're spliced onto pigtails in in the
the white bit with the laser warning and
these end up on pigtails that are then
put into connectors on the left and all
those cables go to the switches the
connect zone right stop playing connects
on left or go to field there's two
cables coming into this and we got two
more of these out in the field and when
the event is over we roll up all the
cabling inside and put the top over it
again
and put it back in the trench and then I
you know maybe in a few years we can
come back and we don't have to do all
this spice work the Dave shows all the
photos from the Dalton Club for four
people who's who was before who this was
the first EMF originally I think
invented by the Germans copying a
concept from the Dutch we looked in
because we don't want people to mistake
them for what they acts we are normally
this you can see there's power going
into it there's fire extinguisher next
to it because this is a nice central
place where you can have them the the
little woods power on top as an access
points in a container box upside down
and on top of status and home lights and
you will have seen those this by fire
they're very good very useful because if
you're walk around fields you can
immediately know oh there's the nearest
network access point and you can run
your cables there and shoot it lose
internet connection then the the fire
flame animation will stop and you
immediately know oh there's an outage
there that will need attention this is
from the inside cables coming in on the
bottom one going out to the access
points and to the own lights they're
switching there there's a Power
Distribution unit there and this one I
think I took this picture on like Friday
afternoon so not many people around to
it plugged into this one yet I don't
think we ever ran into a situation this
offense where we needed to add a second
switch because we had needed more than
the 48 ports it's a couple of these
ports are of course reserved for own
stuff like own light needs a connection
the the DECT phones need a connection
gsm base stations and the access points
we had some power over ethernet switches
most of the access points were connected
via be.we injectors but this was police
which I think write stuff that went
wrong one of the challenges is you start
out and you Bill you arrive on site and
you build out this little temporary
network just because you know we need to
be online and the Oregon is breathing
down your neck going can we check our
email yet and everything we need this
for production so you build something
temporary and then as the event starts
you need to move from the temporary
setup to the final setup we had one
little device in one of those cabinets
that we had built up the roads to serve
as a media converter and that we had to
take it out and whenever we took it out
the normal equipment couldn't take over
because the traffic just wasn't accepted
in the remote ends so this was a link
that had three different suppliers
involved so we had to contact them all
have them all debug their little part of
it and then eventually it turned out
there was probably some display bug in
the switch on the remote aunt in London
that was dropping all the traffic
without actually indicating that it was
all the traffic so this is why in
practice for for you to notice ipv6 took
until I think the afternoon of day one
before IBC six would work because we
needed the new final equipment there
something else we worked for like two
hours on getting the switz online via
Cooper uplink and we changed everything
like the cabling we crimped it and then
finally we're like okay let's not use
the copper SFPs this particular switch
says ten gig ports and we put one gig
pluggable in there and normally that
works these are multi right slots but
after we took them out you can see that
the lights the green lights on the
bottom row that are lit up are the link
lights so this which is currently things
that these ports
for working a link which is obviously
not the case since the bloody balls are
lying on top of it so yeah two hours of
V crimping cables drawing in craps is a
hobby that certain people took up where
if you have a public craft then you know
it goes up and down as the day
progresses but if you have significantly
more capacity available than you have
uses and you have a place where you can
send a lot of traffic from you can
create a nice spike and it goes up and
then you stop sending traffic it goes
down and it's so fine and dandy until
you don't have much capacity available
and you DDoS the campsite that way which
is what happened here we only had a
gigabit it was enough for everything we
did here for all the traffic that the
people did for all the streams to go out
and all that but it this didn't really
have much capacity to catch incoming
DDoS attacks so the node had to spend
time and efforts contacting our extremes
having identifying source destination
and we ended up having to take the
public dashboards offline from from
being able to be access from the world
because that was the target of the DDoS
attack and the source was somewhere in a
group in Germany who deal with open
Wi-Fi network developments so to speak
so yeah please don't do that
it is annoying and it inconveniences
everybody on the way on the site and
creates work for a knockin and finally
is this wiring that you guys have here
luckily somebody brought stickers to
notify us of the problem which were
widely deployed and I think these were
good safety measures this isn't my first
visit to the UK and I know that you guys
like warning signs and safety signage
and everything so the the European
mainland Federation was glad to help out
of course you are being Europe we we
also proposed a solution that we will
help you implement two years from now
thank you very much
yes this is the problem with having a
presentation that you need many teams to
work on simultaneously and opening it up
someone will put in a troll slide thank
you well Wi-Fi so hand over now to a Kay
who's going to talk about the Wi-Fi
distribution through the camp and some
give you some stats so Wi-Fi well it's
about putting up lots of access points I
guess this slide didn't come in too well
ok ok so some of the photos are not on
here worse that are supposed to be on
here but yeah we put have a lot of
access points around around 70 of them
on the left you see a few of them when
they're being staged when we were back
in the Netherlands on the left you see
an access point mounted to a fence and
on the right you see the access points
we have mountains on all the other data
and close so that's actually an indoor
access point that's mounted into a
plastic box that's used for
waterproofing it so that's a fairly
cheap solution to use a cheaper indoor
access point and making it waterproof
and on the top here you see also the GSM
antenna and one of the arc net home
lights and it was supposed to be another
photo on the right but we can see that
though some statistics about the that
Wi-Fi deployments here so we had 72
access points deployed all 82 11ac aruba
access points 2800 concurrent stations
that were concurrently connected to the
network and in the course of this four
days we've seen around almost 6,000
unique devices on the Wi-Fi network and
actually most of the device is connected
to the network or actually on Wi-Fi
about a nine
4% of them so only 6% of those devices
raksi connected to the wired network so
yeah yeah we also had a number of SS IDs
[Music]
well most of them were encrypted and
some of them were unencrypted but almost
70% of you guys used the encrypted
network so that's good and 80% of the
stations were on five gig
I think the badges they kind of do five
gigahertz so that maybe they are taking
down the percentage of stations on five
gigahertz and of course five kickers has
way more capacity than 2.4 gigahertz
we're also here in the UK they Ofcom
opened up a little bit more spectrum so
they added five more five gigahertz
channels so we were able to use twenty
four five gig channels opposed to four
20 megahertz channels on 2.4 so there's
way more expecting to play around with
on five gigs so please use five
gigahertz and yeah maybe 2.4 can maybe
go away at some point but yeah some more
statistics in this slide you guys were
able to actually use a random username
password on the encrypted Wi-Fi but
apparently not almost none of you
actually try to do this so it's EMF and
anonymous and some at roam realms that
are in this top 10 so not much exciting
things going on on the different
operating systems we've seen on the
network Linux is number one so that's
good and for some reason there's Windows
98 there that cannot be right
[Applause]
right we also collect a lot of more data
about the Wi-Fi network like we can look
at how many clients are associated to
the different access points spread
across the sites so one thing we can do
is we can look at how many clients are
in a certain room so we can use these
data to see which presentations are
popular so we can see that apparently
the most popular talks were banned from
encrypting and the making of the tilde
mk4 and also hackers was very popular
yesterday so that's good and sidebar was
also crowded yesterday right now and and
Milly ways was also popular yesterday
something with wigs I guess so that was
it for Wi-Fi we have some other
statistics yeah so we have this one gig
uplink and we it was saturated so
because thanks for that yeah so next
year we have to work more bandwidth so
or next two years we have gotta go for
ten gig or something yes yeah this is
the so we see a couple of peaks there
and but that might have not been genuine
traffic but yeah we will get more I
guess next year yeah so temperatures
yeah was last night it was pretty okay
during night but the night before that
it was very very very cool so you can
actually see about a I think it's a 20
degree difference with during the day
and during the nights so if you're
looking at the temperatures of all the
switches we have on site so I think yeah
it's yeah probably 20 degrees difference
between day and nights so that was
pretty cool
I think that's it for statistics so
we're gonna move on to video yeah okay
[Applause]
[Music]
yes so some of you may have noticed we
haven't done our usual thing of having
very strange graphs like radiation level
or Club Mart a stock in the bar this is
mainly due to everyone being absolutely
knackered by the time all the logistical
issues were sorted out but now I will
pass over to 18 far more professional
instinct team line than her own
the CCC video Operations Center and pass
me over to paucity so hi everybody I'm
what he from the CC Rock which is we do
team after CCC from Germany let's start
with a few logistics of our live streams
so we head up around 100 viewers at the
peaks of up to 120 most of the people
were watching MPEG - live streams which
is like an adaptive live stream
technology and Apple devices mostly use
HLS and some legacy devices watch the
ice cast streams those are statistics
from our ticket tracker so overall we
recorded 117 events 26 events were not
recorded those speakers that didn't want
to be recorded or music and movie events
that aren't being being recorded and
overall that's almost 62 hours of video
being recorded by us and most of the
stuff is already online and you can
watch it
[Applause]
so we also faced some challenges at EMF
first those tents arrived late and we
had to do everything at Friday morning
and it was really stressful but we got
it so and during the build-up at 10:00
stage speed aware some power outages
which also didn't help for the first
time at this event we all normally
rerender our videos with an intro at the
beginning which is like a small video
which says who's the speaker and what
name the talk is the guys from EMF
wanted it to be like a transparent lower
third thing and we had to build it in
our pipeline and but at the end it
worked out and so now every video starts
with a lower third which has to be fancy
and overlays over the video one truck
actually had an emoji in its title which
was a little bit challenging but
everything worked expect automatic intro
generation so I had to fix this manually
but a parts net it's already up on
YouTube and on our own platform and
everything worked and actually on this
stage one HDMI splitter was pricked by a
Tesla coil and so on this stage we have
some problems like the video on the
projector but I think it's working now
so thanks for the appreciation we also
really like to speak lucky ket and you
can find all the recordings up to now
and some are missing at median rccc de
te end on youtube thank you
[Applause]
so many of you will already know for the
first time at EMF we have a deck network
that has been very well received this
was put together by the event phone team
who were testing out their new system
here unfortunately they have had to
leave early
they have kindly left their equipment in
our care but Sam will be talking on
their behalf and he's also going to talk
about the GSM network that he built so
yes my name is Sam I've been involved in
building the phone network mostly the
GSM but they've kind of as we'll show
you we had like a common core so I
worked really closely with Thomas and
the deck the event phone guys with the
DECT stuff
this is Thomas's presentation I've seen
once so this is kind of riskier and we
might have slipped in there so first
thing really we as you see one of the
big things that event phone put in this
year was self service for tech
Federation those who pin to Congress
before you know like signing up waiting
to get your deck phone online had to be
kind of a fairly manual process one but
one registration at a time so they put a
lot of work into building a service the
way you could just register to the deck
Lantana's were effectively always in
registration mode so you could just pick
up your phone and say register to
network and the default pin that kind of
gave you a temporary allocation on the
network with a really long number that
wouldn't route anywhere and then you
could register your number in guru and
just dial the activation code which
actually then like we provisioned your
phone so that was I think I was quite a
lot of work I think it's worked really
well for them I think most people found
that was that was fairly good it also
meant that that's number of registration
guru system we built was not just for
DECT but actually we extended it to cope
with the same for GSM and for well for
sip so you could just sit register a
phone so I've been using my iPhone with
just an application on it all weekend I
know she even got my dead phone on out
of the box but you actually had like
three different ways to access the same
phone system and you could have a number
on any of them and you can have call
groups and that kind of thing so yeah
that's that's work to do well the kind
of principles we could apply then from
decks to GSM
you know kind of unified experience
across the networks really we have one
phone system different access channels
things that they've learned for EMF and
the capture those of you who signed up
very early on in guru I think found the
capture significantly challenging
either that or everybody was a robot but
so there was a little bit of a yeah
we'll turn down the the aggressiveness
on the capture displaying sit details
it's mostly being kind of UX type things
in in like in any web application
they added call groups as well I
definitely found that but if you had
like you could get a number that would
bring multiple extensions
so if you wanted like a number for your
village that would ring six people's
decked and gsm phones in the village you
could register that as well that was
kind of a late addition so this is kind
of what the the IP architecture looks
like so we ran the in terms of hardware
all these servers were running VMs that
David currently provided for us as we
had these built up a little bit ahead of
time and then moved to site so there was
a yeat which is a yet another telephony
engine you might be familiar with as a
sip sip control platform so there's a
number of yeat instances which was gonna
be handling each segment of the network
for VoIP so the deck stuff gets
converted into sip as well as does the
GSM
socially I'm there so we had a kind of
VoIP the core server then we had the
DECT antennas you see on that cloud so
they were running as a private VLAN
across the site so all the DECT antennas
were plugged into a specific switch port
on the VLAN and then the GSM BTS is over
on the right there similar principle to
the DECT antennas we actually so the the
hardware for those of you haven't seems
on the other presentations the GSM base
station is a Raspberry Pi and an SDR
radio so we have a Raspberry Pi we have
a you know a dev of raspbian OS on there
we could just run an Open VPN so the BTS
itself just plugs in fires up an open
VPN tunnel back into our void core and
then runs the GSM over there what was
really nice was it meant actually I have
I've had one of these base stations
plugged in at home on my DSL what I've
been doing testing via the same VPN so
we can actually deploy a base station
anywhere in theory with that technology
and we didn't have to kind of rely on a
custom VLAN for that just some
management stuff over on the outside and
then your
a little no go over there so a quick
plug for my employer next mo who kindly
gave us a bunch of credit to makes all
the external calls traffic out so that
the PSTN was routed out through them we
have the two little gsm servers at the
top there the gsm core is the Ozma comm
core network in a box stack so that was
providing our flows you know the GSM
acronyms the MSC the BSC and the HLR and
the SMSC all running in one on that box
and that just has a sip interconnect so
that came out of a sip that way and then
the GSM services was just an asterisk
box for doing a few little hacks and
tweaks and we put a few little services
on there and test numbers and generally
it just gave me a box to do some
manipulation we also routed the outbound
traffic to next mode through that and
the inbound Soviet found the inbound
there was a UK number you could dial I
will just give you dial tone so from
your regular mobile and then you could
not anything as if you are on-site you
could dial people from off-site good
call oh seven five two oh six six oh
nine hundred and you'll just get dial
tone so this was what was on the the
network we don't know exactly how many
GSM device is attached to the network we
know we had 1900 GSM enabled devices at
some point but we don't have great stats
on on the traffic on there that could
have been literally just one location up
they've all phones attempting to
location updates so people's phones that
may have tried to register and be barred
or something like that
277 DECT phones 76 tensions and 33
people signed up for a personal sip
number personal GSM number so if the
Sims we gave you in the badges we use
the similar thing to DECT but actually
if I had a number which was that four
one two three four number you could you
keep that number just use it which is
what people that got the gist I'm
working did but equally you could have
like reassigned it yourself to a
personal number as well so the active
calls going out to the to the real world
and we have this little problem as you
can see here on I think it was well
started at just after 4:00 a.m. on
Friday morning as that through till
sometimes twelve o'clock basically
somebody hooked up one of their SIP
extensions to their sip server rather
than to a phone and their sip server
wasn't a particularly well protected
server so somebody out on the Internet
anyone it so puts a sip server on the
internet well no it takes about 20
minutes before somebody starts trying to
poke you with call attempts they poke
their server they found oh look
it can make outbound calls by our server
and that burned through about a thousand
years of credit calling serbia so i had
to have an awkward conversation with my
boss then on Saturday morning going I
have a thousand euros of credit you gave
me for EMF I've kind of lost it can I
have some more please but fortunately
you did I just checked the balance and
actually since we locked that connection
down and we put on a few limits we
blocked sip for our bank calls but from
Dex and GSM we've actually only used 60
euros of credit of legitimate calls so
without abandoning bug so yeah that was
definitely some fraud that we did only
allow UK Europe and u.s. prefixes anyway
which should have generally blocked out
the obvious for definite destinations I
kind of missed maybe Serbia that will go
in my band list for next one this is one
equation or thing from the deck network
so the DECT base stations all need to
synchronize with each other it's a time
division multiple access system so all
the base stations need to be on a
synchronized clock we don't have this on
GSM which is why we don't have handover
right now what the deck system can do is
they synchronize over RF links between
them so all these lines are you'll see
the spots are where all the DECT
antennas are so you can even see the one
right down at the gate so there's one in
the DK of the gate there and they
actually discover each other and even a
red link is a low quality mmediately a
red yellow green quality links but these
would all keep them in synchronization
so they're synchronizing over the DECT
RF band with their with their channels a
couple of plugs yeah the challenge for
event phone is they're trying to get
more followers on Twitter and YouTube so
they're clearly trying to break into
social media very quickly the GSM stuff
challenges we had the time frame getting
it all built really I was being pushed
you know we were brought up against
there and we were relying on so many
other bits of infrastructure so we got
pushed out there deploying the BTS is in
the real world we all the stuff worked
really well on
in the lab online SDR built the boxes
and I've had stuff running on my desk at
home for weeks turns out when you start
sticking it on a wooden pole in a field
some of the environmental things so
Thursday night I think it was was
furiously spent soldiering additional
five volt power lines raspberry PI's USB
power anybody's been there will will
know that and yeah man power woman power
I really kind of ended up doing nearly
most of the GSM stuff myself with a bit
of help me Thomas I'm a big shout to
yoga if she's here who helped putting up
the base stations on Thursday and then
we ran and took them all down when I
said actually what I thought was a
software problem is a hardware problem
and I need to solder some wires into
them so can you get them all down again
and bring the back please and then put
them all back up again again so yeah she
yeah so we can see we can see where the
GSM was busy surprised surprised not
many people are making GSM calls at 4:00
in the morning but you know there's a
traffic distribution graph there
[Applause]
so a DMF we're always trying to keep the
ticket prices as low as possible in
order to encourage and make it available
to as many people as possible and we
have to always balance that versus
things that we actually need like or
people expect like an internet
connection paying for an internet
connection and equipment and setup about
the size of a small is P that is used
for a weekend and then thrown away for
two years isn't really something we can
afford nor would we actually want it so
we rely on the enormous generosity of a
whole slew of sponsors to lend us
equipment services and other favors I'd
like to give a particular shout-out this
year to sky for business who without
whom we'd have no uplink at all uplink
goes via a circuit to a nearby town
where they have a point of presence and
they take it to London from for us we
had very few options there and they were
awesome
absolutely many thanks to them and I'd
also like to thank the others who I'm
just going to be that very quickly
because we're out of time event in for
flex optics so I guess a networks LAN
app contact clarinet babble and Arista
so many thanks to them
[Applause]
I also want to thank the volunteers who
popped by from time to time offering to
run around the darkened clutter plug
people in we need your help again to
unplug them and beginning tomorrow at
9:00 a.m. we begin tear down that's
bringing back all the cables all the
fibers all the switches if you're able
to help out please come by at 9:00 at
the NOC don't these slides will be
online github and here's our Twitter
you