right we've got a brilliant talk coming
up next I'm really looking forward to it
I hope you all are too it's called the
singularity classical ballet computing
and digital ethics so without further
ado I'm going to hand over to Genevieve
and Alex give them a nice round of
applause everybody so it is a little bit
weird to talk about classical ballet and
it's computing education and the digital
ethics includes BioDigital ethics but
before we get there I can't explain why
I'm doing this because it makes a little
bit more sense for you so so this is me
and all of the things that I do in an
infographic by a really wonderful Arthur
School Anneliese limb and so apart from
running ready sort of code which is a
not-for-profit creative computer
education CIC I also am a lecturer at
very Hampton in computing education so I
kind of come from from the classroom
teaching GCSE and a-level computing
computer science software development
games design into now teaching new
teachers and developing the creative
computing so when I was teaching there
was only me as the female in the
classroom so I wanted to find a way of
getting more girls interested in
computer science as well as being a
little bit more creative and not just
doing you know Python and the magic
8-ball that we all have to teach these
days so I went to dancing school when I
was very little and that's my passion
along with the dragon 32 and ice castles
that was my favorite game but
unfortunately I had a condition called
spondylolisthesis so I have multiple
spinal fusions I ended up leaving my
walking stick on the drive so I've had
to resort to use in a golf umbrella this
weekend so yeah so and so that's what my
kind of passion for classical ballet
comes from and I now use classical
ballet as a medium for teaching computer
science theory I've produced three
ballets along with Alex and also our
choreographer Camilla and that is a
fluoroscope of my spinal implant and are
you
use classical ballet because how aligns
with computer science theory so if you
don't know anything about classical
ballet it is very very strict and rigid
like a programming language so for
example a sort of half demo here so you
have positions of your feet which also
correspond to positions of your arms and
there's only certain ways that you can
combine them to be correct motifs so if
you think about how you might position
your foot and then certain steps that
you're allowed to do are a very rigid
and very strict the same ways you might
get with Python or JavaScript or
whatever language that you want to use a
very language agnostic and that is why
we use it as a way to sort of show that
the language can be algorithmically
created for the ballet our ballets use
secondary school students that are not
computer science students nor are they
professional dancers I don't dance I
just choreograph some of it and enjoy it
because it's kind of cool so it was a
really really good way to create
different elements that you could use in
for teaching computer science Siri not
only can you manifest or use classical
ballet as the narration and the data as
the storytelling we can also create
workshops and resources for teachers for
all the wearables that we do we did
projection mapping and Aleks also built
our connect server so if you ever want
to just grab some json data from a
kinect we've got a brilliant one that
just literally you just type in how many
key frames you want and it'll just slap
up the data so yeah I need easy stuff
I'm a kind of a mediocre programmer so
the very first ballet we did we Karen
sided with the introduction of the new
computing curriculum and it included
five different elements so boolean and
binary computational thinking debugging
big data and algorithms and we use
projection mapping live weather data and
also lots of wearables and so that was a
way that we could teach students Arduino
and it's a really really good way
electronics are really good way to
introduce coding as well so there's a
couple of we used torches and this is a
picture of the Kinect just when we would
do in binary tree structures just to
show you what it looks like it doesn't
have to look like stigma and it can be
really beautiful and what's interesting
for me is I know that that's Kate looks
like I can tell how she dances so that
was quite interesting from her from our
perspective so we did a lot of different
things so the very top one with the
circles is a hundred years of rain data
and then one next to it is signal
processing where the dancers are using
different motifs to represent the signal
signal processing algorithms the one at
the bottom with the Kinect stick figure
is for debugging so that's what we have
all this trace and errors in it and the
one at the very bottom represents
networks and viruses we use a lot of
wearable technology in the Ballet's and
these initially where I'm just
electronics wearables and pointe shoes
are not friends I'm just saying they do
not like each other at all so every
single performance they always break so
the perfect perfect rehearsals
absolutely no problem one little test up
go live all the connections snap and
it's literally is every performance yeah
everything yeah so we're kind of needing
to find a new way so this is using the
Adafruit Gemma and its own at the Jemma
the flora neopixels and the little
inside bit that looks like a piece of
black plastic is Vella stat so it's
pressure sensitive plastic looks a bit
like a bin bag but it's pressure
sensitive plastic and that's how we use
that as a trigger in the pointe shoes so
we could minimize risk to the actual
dancers we did our latest ballet is
called pain boat that was released last
October and that was about chronic pain
and biomedical engineering so the
dancers represented pain signals and we
had some dancers representing the
biomedical engineering technology my
implant and then we went through and did
what the pain pathway system looks like
and how we can modify it and use in
are features to create imagery so
audience consonant sound the hidden
nature of chronic pain we also created a
VR experience and then turn that into
workshop so this is the the technologies
that we use and so the daydream Alex
built using lots of different stuff and
the co spaces is a education platform
for building VR experiences using Co
spaces blocks block lis and JavaScript
and it's really really easy to use I
just had sixty kids build it up in
Sheffield having fun and it just works
with a Google cardboard but it's a
really good way to introduce coding for
students before you might want to move
on to build VR experiences in blender or
unity so it's nice to do lots of
different things so so our fourth
palette that will reduce it is called
the singularity and this is about so
from a computer science perspective we
want to talk about latency and
communication and augmentation of the
human body and so that's why we're
boldly going into space so how can we
communicate when we travel into space or
go to culinary and what will we need to
do in order to facilitate the human body
to do that do we need to augment it and
then this is where the challenge comes
in if we are going to do them what are
the ethical considerations that we need
to look at
so should we augment people or should we
just send robots what are the ethical
decisions of who owns that data if you
have a have a biomedical implant so
that's one of the things that we want to
think about with the students remedy
when we're teaching the digital ethics
is what data are you sharing when you
have your fingerprint to get your lunch
or book your library book which is fine
that's perfectly acceptable but you they
need to understand what's going on so
the reason why we're using we're going
to be using the Emotiv has Alex has got
on and that captures your brain wave
data alex is going to model the emotive
headset everybody little catwalk for you
everyone and so this has a five points
connection and the Emotiv do another one
called the park which has ten points
it's obviously no way in the air as good
as what are neuroscientists would use
but obviously we need one that you can
use when you're dancing it's very noisy
the signal it's not brilliant but you
know it's better than nothing this is
just an animate and an animation of kind
of what brainwave signals might look
like in a pretty way so when you get the
emotive headset it gives you an app like
this that you can use or a couple of
pieces a different software to download
either Mac or Windows and you can get
the raw data out unfortunately I don't
have that one because that's too
expensive as everything everything's
doing spensive but and but they're
brilliant they're really helpful as well
the staff and I've got a little video
that I recorded of my brain yesterday
panicking about this workshop this talk
so you can see it gives you like a
little kind of animation of how your
brain might light up it's obviously not
accurate it's a representation of the
signals coming from the brain and we
want to use this particular data to
create biofeedback so they will this
data that's coming out so it's in a
format called OSC you can use that with
many different things so including
things like sonic PI so you could
control the music using the brainwave
data I don't really know how well that
would sound but it might be okay so
that's one of the things that we're
looking at we want to create our own
music using all of our bio data for the
classical ballet so that we can also
minimize the sort of copyright of the
music that we're using we also want to
show how students can code their own
music and create their own music but all
with the understanding of this is
someone's hidden brain data what does
that mean to show this data to other
people what are the ethical
considerations when you're working with
that so I'm going to hand it over to
Alex because Alex built the scratch
plugin that we're going to be using in
the workshop later and how you can use
the OSC data from their from their
motive head set to control scratch
so I'll hand you over thank you Oh
so yeah I'm Alex I've been Genevieve's
technical provider so it's called for
ages and I'm a software developer by
bike raid so for me this is a really
cool opportunity to do stuff that is not
like regular programming programming for
performance is nothing like day job
programming with a day job you're gonna
have to support it in six months time
you get hopefully gonna be supporting it
in two years time and still have a job
whereas with the performance it's like
gone so there's a lot of hacking there's
a lot of just do it with whatever weird
technology you can find fortunately for
this project we saw it had an OSC
interface to the brainwaves and I've
done OSC before OSC is really simple OSC
is it's kind of it was invented for
contribs open sound control if you want
to google it it was oh it was invented
for replacing MIDI which was rubbish
it's great but it wasn't detailed enough
so it's basically a way of passing
strings and numbers fast across a
network and in this case the strings and
numbers are bits of brain wave of
information so you'll get there's lots
of facial recognition stuff as well I
don't know quite how it knows what you
know whether I'm smiling or not but it
does so it's kind of cool and winking
and blinking but you can also send
mental commands so you can train it to
pull and potion things so we're picking
those things up and sending them to a
little server that's part of our project
and then next slide yeah week goes into
scratch and you can have this data and
you can use it to move things around
with your mind in scratch gives you
control over well typically that cat is
it called scratch it's called scratch
isn't it
yeah and
[Music]
so it's about making it simple it's
about giving you control over it scratch
has had three iterations it's currently
in beta for its third which is big
relief to me because I didn't want to
ever program in flash ever again so it's
now available in HTML and that's much
nicer so we downloaded that forked it
and just added in some bits to allow us
to connect our module to the rest of
scratch and it's just you know the OSC
comes in it's just numbers and strings
and the little server just pokes it into
scratch and then it's like writing web
page it's just a bit of JavaScript that
connects to an API and says what's this
number and it says 5 so really really
simple but it's very very nice that
scratch has enabled this and made it
simple and right it's just just like a
green behind a 12 inch bar this is a
thing for moving the cats when whenever
you will it to go I think left left yes
it makes it walk but just an example you
could do anything you can visualize your
thoughts but obviously anything was
saying we use the cheap version of the
license so we don't get all the really
detailed data like this is going boom
and this is going boom we've kind of got
you know what you saw in the previous
slide but it's still a lot to show you
know how you can use your brain and how
you can use that data to yourself as
somebody who's maybe not particularly
familiar with computers so when you come
to the workshop do be prepared for it to
be a little bit broken I'm just
preparing myself basically yep and then
the other thing that we're going to have
a try with is sonic PI so veni veni if
you interested in codec coding
music that's a really really good
platform to do that so and this is only
just started because scratch 3 was only
released in August so it's only been
released to other developers and it's
still in beta and there's still a few
things that you can't you can't save any
of these files that you create and
because they are just live running on a
PC server just so you know that when you
go online but it's much better now that
it's html5 anymore
obviously the we're sharing the scratch
one here because we want to introduce
digital ethics to students but for when
we're using it in the ballet will
probably be controlling using the osce
data to control the the stage lights but
you is using an aggregate score of their
wearers
so that nobody's data is shown or
nobody's data's available to other
people so we won't record anyone's data
at all only my own Alex's in order to
use the headset as well you officially
have to be 16 but obviously if there's
some parents in the workshop and they
sign a waiver they can put it on but we
won't record anything but it's just you
might want to try it it's incredibly
uncomfortable it's really tight on your
head it's in your head but that's quite
useful when you're dancing because
obviously you move around a lot even in
ballet you even if you're not jumping
around there's still quite a lot of head
movements and stuff and it does say on
if you do like a pirouette or a spin if
you don't know what one of those are and
that was really important for us to find
a way that we could record the the
dancers data while they're doing it then
and then use them for the visualizations
the wearables and any other projections
that we might do we've only just started
on this we haven't quite kind of
formulated how the ballet will finally
be but it's most likely be sometime next
October to December when we do the live
performance so I just have some links
that you might be interested in we have
all of our resource
and github so for all of our ballets all
of the wearable code the connect server
code whatever code reviews they're all
in github
do not judge my programming do you not
judge mine either oh my god and also
it's so messy also the the Ballet's on
data driven dance so the three that
recorded I say three the last one isn't
quite over yet and if you were
interested in the emotive headset there
is other headsets that you can use it
was just this one was had enough points
on it to get enough data whereas a lot
of the others only have one or two that
are within my price budget so it's three
hundred dollars for one and when you're
doing so a classical ballet for one
performance so what Alex was saying from
start development to do in a single
performance is round about twenty
thousand pounds because if you've got
eight dancers eight sets of pointe shoes
might eight sets of costumes a billion
in one neopixels cuz obviously girls
little loads and neopixels
I'm surprised I didn't have any on me
I'm normally just walking around in
hundreds of lights so and obviously the
development cost of all the software
that we use the hiring and stuff so it's
important that so that's what it takes a
lot of time because I obviously have to
get the funding for that um but yes if
ballet is quite an expensive thing to do
if you're interested in that but may
need to do the costumes and things like
that that's where it comes from
I'm but yeah so I hope you found the
talk really interesting and if you were
all good if you hope you enjoyed it
oh so it's gonna say we've got ten
minutes if you any of you want to ask
questions but before we do that you
mentioned you're gonna be doing a
workshop later do you know when and
where that is yes so it's 6:30 in
workshop - there you go so do we have
any questions from the floor
nope oh one there
oh and one there I'll come back to you I
can state you and up again and can you
and can you support multiplayer type of
experiences with this sort of headset as
well as it's only one headset per
computer so the the OSC protocol is
completely Network agnostic so even if
you only have one plugged into one
computer you could certainly then take
that data and glue loads of it together
anymore for anymore
oh one here kidding you demo the thing
with scratch yeah that's what we're
doing that's in the workshop later on
okay yep we just can't do it now because
it's the different laptop what do you
think is the most interesting thing you
found from using the headsets on the
dancers so we haven't used it on the
dancers yet because I only just got it
but I use it on myself and I have ballet
lessons and I think the thing I found
was actually the other dancers where I
go to a dance class which has everyone's
over 60 doing it and so the other day
the other ladies were watching my
brainwave data and they found it
absolutely fascinating how that you can
see what your because we were learning
new stuff so you could see what you were
doing and how it kind of affected the
visualization of what's going on your
just the fact that you could see it and
that was one of the things that we were
talking about the fact that you can see
this and there is an ethical issue of it
because like Yuki imagine if you in the
future if they if they use your
brainwaves to decide what job you're
gonna have or whatever you know that
kind of thing say yeah whatever they're
oh sorry yeah that's right where are my
manners
why did you choose to do the brainwave
stuff thingy why did I choose brain
waves I mean and basically a little bit
came from the previous ballet where we
had chronic pain and the hidden nature
of chronic pain and the fact that you
don't see that I'm in chronic pain so we
trying to expose it and then to be
trying to find different ways that you
could and expose other data that might
help you understand
Ithaca decisions and things like that
thank you thank you
there was one over there so are you
aiming to get data from the way that
dancers dance in any case or to give
them something they can consciously
affect in control week that's what well
it's one of the where we work with our
dancers as well so they're part of the
whole development process so what we we
kind of want to look at what the when
you're learning the classical ballet
like what did the brainwaves look like
and then kind of once you know it is
there a difference and can it work can
we affect the wearables or the lights or
the projections basically so they may
want to be interested in how it does the
element that you were talking about the
kind of the kind of learning feedback
system we wanted to look at it as a
of a biofeedback maybe but we haven't
quite got there so we're still decided
but that's a brilliant idea thank you
thanks oh whatever then I don't even had
it long but how accurate do you find the
you know the brainwave hmm
neuroscientist but I'm assuming they're
not that accurate
is there any neuroscientist in the one
Ben Ben could probably help us they're
not oh you can play with it later
excellent I'll see for that later and so
you can't you can't get the raw EEG data
off it but it does require you paying
for another piece of software and
obviously one of the things that we try
and do is do free and open source stuff
so this is kind of limiting when we want
to try and put this out into the sort of
classroom learning situation but what
I'll do is I'll maybe do a comparison
with a profit EEG headset and treat it
like get subject and do a post on it so
we can see their comparison between the
datasets
there is another headset which is more
accurate but again that's double the
price or triple the price see oh one
over here and I think we'll make that
the last yet one there's really good
talk thank you very much and so my
question is what have you considered so
putting possibly the ethical side or
coming up with a way to aggregate it so
you you can't look at an individual
putting the headset on audience members
or the people who are watching or
experiencing the ballet because I think
that would be a very interesting thing
to add into the performance yeah that's
not my that's what we're going to do but
we won't be and where we're talking
about the recording that's only on us
externally and we will share the only
data that we'll share publicly as mine
because that's fine and we're looking to
use the audience's aggregated feedback
to control some element of the live
performance obviously that's going
but you know it'll be fabulous but ya
know brilliantly a brilliant idea thank
you thank you okay thank you one last
round of applause for Genevieve italics
and let's get another plug in for that
workshop 6:30 in what workshop - is that
right yes
go to it