hello everyone we're having a good time
obviously we are we're all nerds
EMS alright so in the grand tradition of
my EMF talks nothing worked by an hour
ago and I arrived here with basically
nothing and so we're gonna go on a
little journey of how I made a
ridiculous instrument as a prototype and
how has actually become a real thing
that you can buy in a real shot and I'm
gonna tell you about some of my
ridiculous and music things that I've
done with it
and with lots of other people as well
and and hopefully get you to use this in
your classrooms use this at home is
super easy and it's super cheap I've
tried to make it as is this as simple as
possible anyway so onwards this is the
mini moon and this is prototype 2 of the
mini moon it's a gesture controlled
musical instrument and that uses
chiptune and well a place placed about
for you in a minute and but I designed
this for kids to be able to make gesture
controlled instruments but more than
just playing an instrument I wanted them
to be able to make an instrument so they
actually so the whole thing they wire it
they code it and then they make the
music and perform it themselves it's
super easy and but it's just a starting
point so I'm hoping to inspire lots of
kids to just play around and have fun
with technology and so I don't know why
that just went for would have let me
touching anything but never mind and so
as you know I'm Helen I made the mini
Moo I'm a maker I'm a writer and I do
some education stuff I live in Berlin
and sometimes London and I like making
musical instruments and I think it's a
really enjoyable experience I would call
myself a fairly shitty musician and I
play probably 20 different instruments
all of them extremely badly and and
that's one of the reasons why I love
making my own instruments because I'm
the best in the world at playing the
things that I made myself and
so this is a story about how I made this
okay right so it's inspired by an
amazing musical instrument called the me
mu glove can I just get quick hands up
who's heard of the me mu glove I love
you okay cool
so as it says on the screen the me mu is
a very fancy pants MIDI controller now
thats a bit jargony and i like to avoid
jargon and but really it is just a way
of making music with the computer okay
so when we make music with our mouths or
where the traditional instrument and
we've got lots or lots of wobbly lines
that come over and there's like signed
ways but in a computer and they use
something called MIDI which is basically
a epi Dhoni instead of Wiggly and and
the me mu is a wonderful instrument and
that was designed thought of many years
ago by a musician called Imogen Heap and
she can do these amazing things with it
really kind of because so she's suitably
passionate about electronic music an
expressive instrumentation of electronic
music and she's she kind of was sat
behind her desk making these beautiful
concoctions and then when she went out
into the world to try and perform these
these things that she she made she felt
like can this complete disconnect from
her audience she was unable to perform
in the way that you might perform with a
guitar or a flute you just stand him
behind your computer and even though
electronic music is very exciting
actually visually to be preferred to be
performed it's actually kind of dull so
she sat a around 10 years ago to make
electronic music performance expressive
again and now the thing about being
ahead of your time is that sometimes
some of your ideas are a little bit
impractical so her Meenu glove is
amazing and has been on tour with some
incredible big names including Ariana
Grande I've got a short clip of her
using one later and but it's not quite
come to market yet because it's
that's complicated it has to work in
these multi date multi Arena festival
situations so the technology super
complex this is where it is okay it's
got all these different really cool
sensors it's got been sensors flex
sensors it's got visual feedback it's
got haptic feedback which means it does
nice busy things when you do things and
it's been really designed by musicians
for musicians really cool really nice to
where I've had a play on them really
amazing piece of kit um so yeah I talk
about here she is quite famous and she
does do cool things um so why did I
start doing this so I I kind of came
across through my music through my music
technology work and we kind of crossed
paths through Terry who's actually
either and I said do you know what this
glove is super inspiring I can see this
working super well to inspire kids into
technology I mean if you know me and
you'll know that I'm a big advocate for
Creative Technology and for the power of
creative technology in classrooms in
homes and just generally for fun I think
we sometimes overstate how much
worthiness there is technology sometimes
it's alright to just mess around we then
have my sign and gesture control is
really one of the things I particularly
like doing and I find it expressive I
find it really enjoyable and yeah I mean
that says it all really it's fun and I
like it and and I was doing quite a lot
of work with gesture control this is a
picture of something I did with one of
my friends we did a hack together her
name's Koko Sato she does really amazing
electronic origami and we did a gesture
controlled flirting device based on
Japanese technology Eric Japanese fan
artistry and it was a really cool hack
and I started thinking more and more in
my own personal work about gesture
control and nonverbal and signaling and
how cool it was and how much I wanted to
do more stuff in the classroom with it
so another reason I really liked imagens
work and wanted to do something with it
is that I know from experience that
teaching in a classroom is more
effective if you're giving them
something that's real if you're giving
them something
to you to chew on and you could be like
look at this cool thing that someone's
actually doing with this technology and
now we can do something like it it's
really inspiring to kids especially the
kids that don't really necessarily see
the point of the technology for its own
sake
so having real-world tack there's linked
to actual jobs actual outcomes or joy is
a really wonderful way in my eyes and in
my experience of democratizing
technology so oh yes so this is Lin this
is the glove in action so I feel like
I've talked a lot about something that
you have actually seen this is I'm sure
the younger ones of you all know using
the low
[Applause]
[Music]
so based on that I start coming with the
idea of a glove that's inspired by
imagens work and inspired by the work
that's been done by her team on this and
I came up with the idea of doing a
really stripped-down version of this
something I love doing with technology
is ripping stuff out of it and try and
make it its simplest thing it possibly
can be and also make it the cheapest it
possibly can be as well because I know
teachers got no money so I approached
Imogen through a mutual friend and said
hey I got this idea for a children's
glove there's an inspired by your glove
and I reckon I can do it for less than
50 quid and I reckon I can do it in a
family and teach you a friendly format
do you want to let me have a go at it
and she went well we've got this event
coming up in 10 days she fancy having a
stab and I went yeah right
and that's what came of it so this was
the first version of the glove and first
of all this is an interlude here and I'm
going to talk about this so this is
using the BBC micro pin which loads of
you will already know about it but if
you don't and it's a very simple micro
controller and designed specifically for
young people and but I've also used it
with lots of artists and people who
don't want to become specialists in the
way that and making your own PCBs or
even using Arduino to a certain extent
requires you to become so microbe it
allows you to dabble in electronics
which is one of the reasons I think it's
just a lovely platform and anyway inside
this little this little microcontroller
which is up here and we've got something
called an accelerometer which basically
it can tell where it is in space
it can't act like this I can't tell if
it's dan I can't tell if it's being
tickled about and I was like well you
know what that'll do
we don't need flex sensors we'll just
have an accelerometer and we'll make it
do something with that and so we
stripped it right back to that a micro
Pierce and everything and we see oh yeah
so in all of my workshops this is the
first piece of code that I cut a child
will write it's just block code they
just drag it across on shake start
melody badda-bing and then they upload
it and it does it and it blows their
fragile little minds it's very exciting
it's very exciting you don't need to
make something complex and then
basically two hours I basically just
have a sit down I have a cup of tea
they're just off making their own
melodies off doing different and
different types of things with these
things I mean that's it for someone
who's leading a classroom or leading a
workshop you're like yep job is done
that is over I'm having a cuppa and a
sit down
so thus this is this is genuinely how
simple it is and like it does blow their
little minds it's just kind of amazing
um so yeah back to the prototype um I
would say that even though it was
successful it was a bit bonkers to do
something take something from a little
seed of an idea to an actual prototype
they were presented a that I presented
in front of like 300 people in ten days
but you know I would do again
it was Griffin and so the making the
prototype I am here we are so this is
part of the prototype it's part of the
prototyping session for the first ever
version of the glove and and there are
some kids in the room actually he will
also at this prototyping session and I
wanted to talk a little bit about this
so I've do quite a lot of developing of
stuff for kids and people are all
waiting my clients were really surprised
by how much I asked the opinions of the
children um and I think that just makes
you know this is this is what I have to
say about that user testing really works
I just wrote a book on DIY electronics
for kids
I didn't choose a single project that
went into my books children did every
single project was chosen by kids and I
think it's really important when you're
making something for somebody just like
like a glove
anything for a kid I mean ask them ask
them what they think I mean it's not
super complicated I mean for the first
one I just sat down with five young
people we made different gloves and
rather than just asking them I watched
how they interacted with it and it gives
you an idea of what they find easy what
they find difficult how long these
things take to the let that you know the
kind of level of skills and then the
second version um I did I think there
were 50 girls in the class and I run the
whole workshop on my own and which was
financially um but you can really gain a
lot from what you what they tell you and
I always say hey you are my users
I'm prototyping can you give me all your
feedback and it makes them feel super
important and super special so if
there's anyone out there he does do a
lot of work with kids please do involve
them in the decision making I think it's
a really good thing to do and it gives
them joy and it gives them confidence
and it means that you actually make
something better at the end of it
sue I'll say yeah this is from the
second British Open session that was
absolutely delightful we had a lot of
musicians in this one people making the
Harry Potter theme tune and we had lots
of kids do you know what I haven't
played one yet that's pretty remiss of
me isn't it I think I should do that
would you like to hear one so this is
I'd say protein that the one that just
before we go to press this will this is
the almost final version and you can
have a look at at the front afterwards
and the crocodile clips to be a bit
shorter so it's really simple basically
the kids and they have a felt thing here
which has got them different size hands
on it they cut eight they sew it pretty
simple you'd think but actually that's
the hardest bit that takes like an hour
everything else takes about half an hour
and then they wire up three crocodile
clips it's very simple but it's
age-appropriate way
power and Grange and looking a little
bit by circuits and then they actually
coder let me play this this is so this
is code that was written by an 11 year
old girl and and I'll see if you
recognize it that's quite a lot all
people in here so maybe you won't but ok
so I think there's a really good example
of how gesture based and this was
actually done not just as a song but as
a choreography so she had this little
little dance that went along with that
anyway here we go
of course it's not working
why why smash day
I'm gonna have to be uploaded oh no a
USB cable with me this is very terrible
I don't know why that's not working
and yeah it's IMF I know nothing works
at you man it's probably just got dumped
or something it was working about 10
second it's not that kind of USB cable I
know I know it's a it's a micro USB to
USB yeah I uh EMF I love you there's
literally no reason okay where's my code
all right a little bit of light caving
in okay doo-doo-doo oh no it's not gonna
be a surprise my could you be able to
see what new it is I know I'm tricking
you here we go all right one second talk
amongst yourselves
[Music]
it works no this is why I love EMF I
could never go away with a anywhere
else here we have will premier coded by
an 11-year old girl
dear let's see if this works
legitimately you just heard that though
right
seriously there's no reason for it
[Music]
I spent too long doing this thing I'm
just gonna have to give up
[Music]
all right so these are all coded
individually and if I talk going to show
you this kind of code as well but you
had your time you wasted it you're not
getting any more of my attention all
right
so let's put the presentation back up
it's nobody no come on here we go let's
put that like over there that'll do yep
okay so the kind of things the kids were
doing where they were amazing they were
doing really cool songs they were doing
amazing sound effects gloves in fact
Phil who's over there did one of my
favorite ones and there's an effect on
micro bits which is free fall so if you
are free falling and it can't detect it
and he was like do you think that if it
fell off a building that it would be
able to know and I was like yes I think
it would and then this smile spread
across his face and off he scurries to
his computer and suddenly he comes back
with this globe that when you drop it or
fall off a building it plays you the
funeral march back nice good job fern
one of my favorites
good job man all right so the next thing
that we did after after after doing all
these amazing user testing and having a
really nice time in classrooms across
the country is that we ended up having a
chat with the lovely Paul 4 MP marine
and that's basically working with them
has been like the heart eyes emoji just
down the board
and they really like the concept and
obviously it's really easy to
manufacture
I mean it's largely some felt we've got
a lovely PCB that we made which is the
world's first so Apple speaker
and it comes with everything that's
including you know everything needle and
thread and all those bits and bobs it's
gonna be in a really nice shiny box and
all that kind of stuff so I mean this is
the first time I've had a proper kit and
I've done my own stuff before kind of
more DIY style kind of making everything
myself on laser cutters and 3d printers
and had my first small successful hit
which was a Robot Unicorn about a year
ago and had a modest number of orders
and suddenly thought oh my god this is
horrible want to be a manufacturer so at
that point I decided right okay the next
time I do projects I really want to do
it with somebody who knows what they're
doing because I didn't and going through
that experience as someone who's
primarily been a bedroom maker and a
hacks pace maker and then kind of
actually going to a small company but a
company that really knows what they're
doing has been really exciting for me
and I got to press go on a pick and
place machine which was box um yeah he
Maroni have been amazing and we are
gonna have this box as a kit coming out
I think in October I think we hope yeah
but we got no word which is I think
pretty good and for everything that's
included and based been my first thing
they've done taking it from and make to
an actual product and it's been really
eye-opening and understanding all of the
different things that could possibly go
wrong and although with you know it's
been buffered somewhat by being working
with P Maroney and so I was gonna make
some music but I did just wipe the code
on the thing that makes this go so
you're just gonna have to pretend and it
was working in the field over there and
so you just got to pretend that my robot
arm is doing is controlling these robot
arms so you can't really see because
it's quite dark you can come on up and
have a look but I have
got three robotic arms solenoids like
push-pull things and attached to some
levers that hit a really cool xylophone
and that I've had since I was really
young so let's let's meet that one let's
play that and see what happens and you
can check that with gesture and I really
wanted to show you these things as well
because it's not just about controlling
computer and it's not just about making
chiptune music this is actually feeds
into a wider ecosystem so the micro BEC
a 13 quid computer can control a really
really expensive and really professional
pieces of music software this is going
through Ableton Live and it can also
control GarageBand seamlessly and it
control your iPad and it can control
actual physical instruments that use
MIDI as well and and if I hadn't wiped
the code that we'd work so hard on it
can control a loop with my voice as well
so I can actually sing it can control it
continued alayich and debris web just
from two buttons and an XY axis there's
so much more in there you know there's a
magnetometer and slide there that you
can do really cool things with like you
can have directional based sound that
you can explore this thing I made with
my friend Tom know which is here and so
this is again this is just using two
micro bits
[Music]
two micro bits and some copper piping
and this is me this is the gesture
control then so it's basically angers
widget working I wrote some codes so
that the angles control the different
notes they're being played on this
copper pipe instrument
there's just being hit with solenoids
again it was really fun um let me just
play that game from the beginning look
so who are ya so this is this is radio
signaling different angles turn to this
other micro bit which is then sending
that data via serial to a free open
source piece of music technology which
is cool so yeah I think that is exactly
my timer but I think then if anybody has
any questions wants to come and have a
look at my little robot arm or actually
wants to come up here and see my
annoying this never doesn't work I think
it always works and but yeah and yeah
come up and say hi that was half an hour
apparently and thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you and I will hang around here so
come and come and say hi and ask me
anything
you