[Music]
[Applause]
thank you very kindly so mostly I hack
on things that don't exist and sometimes
I build things and sometimes they work
and sometimes they don't and I haven't
got my reading glasses so if I stop
staring I think that's because I'm old
and terrible so I'm going to talk quite
a lot about depression so if that's
going to be a bit painful for you then
please look out for yourself it's I'm
quite happy to talk about bleak things
because they happen to me and if that's
a bit grim for you these things happen
also this clock hates me but so anyway a
few years ago I was working in bath and
Wow was as Jeffro doesn't say all the
technical team apart from two of us left
pretty much in a two-month period which
was kind of terrifying and I took to
wandering around Bath just to get out of
the office and so I could stop thinking
about Zen or Redis or PHP or managers
that I hate it and want to die a slow
and painful death so one of the things
that bath has is parades of terrible
shops selling terrible things and one of
them was a toy shop and in there
there were enameled signs for things
that didn't exist in or didn't have
enameled signs and there were wooden
toys that you give to children and they
kind of stare at going well where'd the
batteries go and there were ten robots
which children weren't allowed to play
with because they had led paint or they
were just sharp objects big
they were just terrible things and
shouldn't have been in a toy shop in the
first place and I kinda wanted one so I
bought tin robot that looked like it was
about to have a psychotic break and set
about anybody or it saw with a welding
torch and so I lied to this we were
doing DevOps see things always generally
means that you're supposed to have one
of these two do your deploys with so
that's fine
yay lots of deploys yay big red switch
Hey however our deploy rig would have
needed this and this was awful
but we were kind of working on it and
there were only two of us out of a team
of seven left and we were going to catch
fire and die and in this state I thought
the best thing in the world would be to
build a robot that would be around the
office and discover who had broken the
build and calm the bollocks because
obviously public humiliation is a great
thing to do for employee well-being and
to make some public humiliation make
software better everybody knows this
that's sarcasm by the way public
humiliation was why my ex employers code
was in a terrible state anyway so amb
came together and I thought sweary bot
here we go and I ordered a bunch of bits
off the internet because that's what the
Internet's for and started hacking away
and it kind of all went really well and
it was great and I think so this is the
test rig unfortunate there's no sound
but what was it nearly mostly worked but
it had a strange failure mode where this
thing what you can't hear is that it's
mumbling to itself in bad speech
synthesiser and what it tended to do was
just rock back and forth
swearing quale to itself it would take
you know its beetling about my bathroom
it's just attacking the first thing it
can find which is my feet and it just
won't take pissed off for an answer so
it would just find a dark corner and
just hide in it just go marks and it was
at this point I realized I'd built a
depressed robot that couldn't cope store
that image away for later so the grim
thing about this is that there is no
happy ending I fell into a particularly
nasty depression at this point and never
finished it and what's worse is that the
bloody computers stopped I'd posted
about it on LJ and many of my friends
were like yeah it's very robot brilliant
idea that's completely huge HR and I'm
like thank you and back twelve months
later after I've recovered a bit more
it's just not playing is it or rather
it's playing but won't stop playing
let's see what happens
Computers right so anyway it was awful I
saw all these happy messages about the
stuff I hadn't done and it was like
awful and made everything worse and
reading that sort of thing can really
really make you hate yourself because
you then yeah I could do a thing it's
great and you now is like well I fucked
that one huh and you've let your friends
down and you didn't finish the project I
mean you never finish a project come on
who are you kidding
you never finish a damn thing your house
is littered with dead projects and the
computer works finally and you know
you're full of wacky ideas and madcap
schemes that never come to fruition if
it was a sitcom it would be funny but it
wouldn't be funny cuz sitcoms aren't
funny and you let people down you're a
loser
you shouldn't be allowed to do this sort
of thing you just shut up not bother
your friends or your exciting things
because they never turn out right
just stop don't bother your friends at
all be quiet shut up do your work do
nothing
depression isn't right fucking bastard
do not listen to it so the good thing is
I got better thank you so a few years I
mean was couple years ago now I'm
trashed at the bar having finished a
volunteering at a science-fiction
convention and the best thing in the
world
slipped into my head which was a cuckoo
clock that calls you a twat
I mean who on earth wouldn't want one of
those
so eBay is amazing
I mean eBay's terrified but eBay is
amazing it turns out that there are many
cuckoo clocks they come in pink
they also come as built I mean this is a
German chaps art project and he made
cuckoo clocks out of disturbing
buildings from I think the ex Berlin but
anyway and about this time I discovered
the joy of the esp8266 which is
microcontroller they're about nine
prints and they've got something much
more grunt than an Arduino but less i/o
but it was fine and that was just going
to be fun but damn things come with Lua
which is horrible I did write a thing
here about banging on about favorite toy
languages because I can't be doing with
Lua because reasons pearl drove me up
the wall pearl made me hate myself which
is just
I'm sure the design and designers of a
language didn't envisage that but he
does I it was the only thing for a long
time and anyway I discovered Ruby
because that's all the configuration
management stuff was written in and it
was night and day and there's I think
this notion for the language that fits
your head better he's less likely to
Gaslight you and he's better for your
mental health this is certainly my
thoughts on it which are worth whatever
you pay to get in nothing yay
but anyway cuckoo clock
I built this cuckoo clock now this video
will probably also break the same ways
the other one but very eventually oh
stop it
yeah we'll get that so while this thing
isn't doing thing there's finally own
don't worry about the next it doesn't
work no varnish was we gold by then so
[Music]
this thing bread boarded up bread
boarded up
sorry I don't know I'm gesture here
that's over there everything worked it
was great
how did cook o'clock it called you
bastard on the hour boxed it up 0 board
sold ring and it didn't work and it was
just like well you know there's two
black wires which is a our trigger I've
got them the wrong way up anybody could
do it we turn it upside down it didn't
work well again on a bit I need
magnifying hat to see small soldering
now because old age it'll be my Maggie
solarek anybody could do it I'll just
stare all the joints and it'll be fine
and it didn't work so that demon the
thing that tells me I'm rubbish came
back and said many things repeatedly
along the lines of look here you are
again it doesn't work your own Moffatt
what are you even thinking why are you
even trying nobody cares
it's just a stupid idea don't just
stop you can't yet don't know what
you're doing then we're here again so
the weird thing is about depression that
it comes along with impostor syndrome
and anxiety and a bunch of other stuff
which are rubbish and there's a thing if
I put the clock in test mode this is a
live demonstration the like of which
blue Peter have never seen if you're an
age to have ever watched Blue Peter so
an accurate representation of the inside
of my head when I'm having a bad time
and I can get the sodding USB connector
the right way up because hey I forgot my
reading glass is so you try and have a
conversation with the rest of your head
and there's a thing in the back of your
head is just interrupting you the whole
time you can't think straight you've
just got this noise and you're trying to
tell people things and it's your voice
telling you you're an idiot all the time
and everybody likes swearing oh yeah
just here
so the way I visualized the inside of my
head
II was a lot too UNIX now okay this is a
leaky abstraction as a rubbish idea
don't do this at home but thank you
one of the things that that models I
guess is an overloaded system and it's
thrashing and half your cognitive
function is running it in swap and you
can't do a damn thing because you're
spending all your time trying to shut
down out of control demons which are
calling you a bastard and your brain is
like treacle because you know you're a
few memories just thrashing and
everything is terrible and so the joke
here is that my demons are demons which
looks funny written down as indeed does
the ad-lib I wrote down so it's not an
ad-lib but yeah where was I oh yeah
that's nice so one of the things that
demons and I would like to point out
that this is nothing to do with it's a
phrenic syndrome symptoms or anything
like that
it's just I have this model of what's
going on in my head and it's shady UNIX
demons because I'm a spot and what
they'll do is get really busy and remind
me of some time when I was at a party in
1983 when I made it out myself
just as I'm over taking a bus on a windy
a road and it's like haha no you're not
killing me that way or they'll decide
that a slideshow of my worst moments
1986 to 1995 would be the best thing in
the world to show me at about 2:00 a.m.
when I'm trying to drop off to sleep the
little bastards
so here we are
imagine if you will a thing which
insults you with your own voice Exhibit
B and at this point
weirdly sitting in a cafe in North
London eating a salad
and drinking tea our mug staring out the
window I became enlightened I kind of
realized that actually what I'd been
doing is building automata that were
external versions of the things that
were in my head no no men in white coats
that's okay so this is actually a thing
I was chatting to an actual artist the
think she was wearing a beret and
smelling a rollup but and I described
this and she was like yeah what I do you
think you're special well and so I kind
it all came collapsing on itself and was
like right so I feel things to come to
terms with the stuff that's going on
okay let's stall that one awake too so I
was in class to read every month you can
just about see Glastonbury Tor behind
the Volvo with the reefer although ya
know anyway plaster was great
it's feel-good yards you know extra
railway bits and some shops and a tour
which is there there Darren
anyway so the thing the brilliant thing
about glass dope is that a shop on the
high street it's opposite the shop that
will sell you homemade faggots and
tips for about three quick and it is
filled with wooden toys and robot arms
and squishy little skittery robots that
light up and I wanted to buy one of
everything and send it through a time
machine to my past self and say it's
alright just make all of it
break it paint it green I don't care
just do it this is the best thing
however time machines are impossible and
my past self would be really freaked out
if at hand so I just sent a pile of
stuff to my brothers kits and I kept
more for myself obviously because who
would not wish for a flying unicorn and
I realized I bought another automata
thing and now I know how this stuff
works
what is going to come out and I was
driving back from Glastonbury about the
twiddly road to Bristol because of I
live in Bristol and driving to bristol
ii find it somewhere else would be
stupid exactly what I was doing which
was that
now some none or all of you may have
some notion of the significance of the
colour scheme or not so that happened
and I'm not sure yeah so
if there's a point here
it's that bugger depression find ways of
explaining it to yourself that might
help
those are my ways of explaining to
myself and that about covers it I
wouldn't actually ask me for any useful
information other than if you're having
problems with kubernetes because I know
about as much about that as I do about
depression so that about covers it
[Applause]
if anybody's got any questions you're
weird but fire away I was gonna Foreman
eight about oh right so um
we must call I was and this so software
and hardware will gas like the shit out
of you and it is really bad for your
mental health two examples one
kubernetes itself the liveness probe if
you read the documentation it says as
long as your container is returns
anything between 200 and 399
everything's good
kubernetes loves you and will keep your
kit running bullshit so the
documentation for this is in a 2015 3
year old PR on github at the bottom of
lot filing cabinet etc etc etc and I did
not find this straightaway and I wrote a
thing and I stuck it on kaa and it
wouldn't start and it was just
complaining because the return code was
wrong and it was look it's in the
documentation you're supposed to work
blasted thing and I struggled with this
for days and I thought I was a complete
idiot because I can't work simple
containers and the instructions said
they should work real hard he said it
didn't well google are never wrong so
clearly on the idea no Google can't
write documentation to save their lives
it turned out actually that I friend of
a friend works for them and I complained
mightily on face ache and he was like
but Google and they were wrong exhibit a
Exhibit B sort yourselves out that the
other thing oh yeah we must D 1 Pro
alleges to have 16 squillion bytes of
memory which you can't use this is
hidden at the bottom of a github peer
from 3 years ago in a locked filing
cabinet marked beware of the leopard
and I have one of these and I was
building a thing
and he wouldn't work and I thought I'd
blown it up because I'm an idiot and I
can't work electronics and I got a
different one and that worked because it
was a slightly different version with
less memory so anyway everything is
terrible
beware kid that tries to Gaslight you it
will destroy your brain and that's not a
useful behavior pattern for things that
people have made for other people but
anyway questions apart from is the bar
oh man will you shut up but is that
working yes thank you for the talk
that's lovely
the one about demons yes I'm quite old
to be a parent and I have some small
children and the question was so when
can I show my 8 year old alien okay now
so monster stories for children I was
feeling a bit guilty about this because
I thought well I don't know but I met
this woman from Mexico he's a good
Catholic and she said Peter look
Parenthood is just long one long series
of guilt trips don't worry right now it
turns out it seems monsters in
children's stories are a way of
externalizing things they can't
understand now I think if somebody
looked on Google which is never wrong
they would figure out the citation for
that but it's an interesting thought
that the externalization of things is an
important step in growth I mean I'd like
to pass that comment I fully admit that
I'm slow and after work things out love
and for a lot of this brain stuff
because being depressed for part of the
time doesn't help because your brain
works even slower and aids itself so
but yeah yeah yeah go at the bar name
last so now you sort of see the process
working anymore does that mean that you
can see CV or Thomas are coming earlier
ah maybe I don't know I work in progress
I shall find out the next thing I build
I don't know what it will be I suspect
now our own Durst and what's going on I
want to go back and build the slavery
robot out of a sense of spies if nothing
else because
maybe one more question really quick one
um you're flying unicorn yes does it do
anything that didn't start or doesn't
just have a somatically awkward color
scheme actually it's got stepper motor
in there which is whether winding animal
doesn't work very well
but if you use the stepper motor for
longer than five minutes it tends to
catch fire excellent it is a burning
wimp
flying unicorn yes I have worryingly
enough I got the colors slightly wrong
so it's got that vibe of as you say
ground attack or straighting people you
do not like but I love it species
because it's just like it's a complete
thing and it worked and I had a whale of
a time just because I knew what I was
doing what was in my head it was just
like no exactly like I would be weird I
mean that's probably close to Stuart Lee
or anyway somebody dragged me off stage
I don't know can I stop now yes thank
you
[Applause]
[Music]
Thank You Jake