hello everyone welcome to the now 1213
talk on stage a on burnout and your meet
computer it is about to be given by
Jessica Rose technical manager at future
learn host of the persuit podcast and
running karaoke here at camp but before
we dive into this talk just a brief
little reminder that we could use more
volunteers you could be the awesome
person up here having technical
difficulties or doing something else and
having tons and tons of fun please go to
the website and sign up and volunteer
and help make you a math an absolutely
incredible experience thank you so much
good morning love oh my hello it is not
even remotely look morning good
afternoon everyone I'm so excited to be
here with you Bay and I'm gonna be
talking to you about burnout I'm gonna
be talking to you about burnout while
extremely burned-out so this is going to
feel a little bit like bad performance
art this is gonna feel a little bit like
performance art just to get things
started I'm just gonna introduce myself
even though I've gotten a fantastic
intro from our MC my name is Jessica
rose I am do get to manage some
fantastic engineers over at futurelearn
but I also travel and give talks and I
do this podcast I do this other stuff I
do too much all the time and everything
is just fine but some of you especially
some of you who came to this for their
really hands-on great stuff was like
just because we're on a first-name basis
he's a desk that's great you're gonna
talk about burnout I've opted into this
talk but really why are you bringing a
talk about burnout to EMF we're gonna be
making things and breaking things why
should I care about my brain I hope you
care about your brain because it's part
of you your brain is absolutely magical
and your brain is gonna keep you from
making cool stuff or breaking cool stuff
your brain is this teeny it's so small
it's a tiny wet bag of meat soaked in
chemicals and you keep it trapped in a
bone prison your brain gives you
everything you've ever loved everything
you've ever feared that weird thing that
happened in middle school that wakes you
up at 3:00 in the morning that's your
brain your brain is fantastic your brain
is mundane your brain is beautiful and
your brain is so so fragile and easy to
break I'm gonna be talking to you today
about perk up occupational burnout a way
to break your brain and hopefully some
ways to not break your brain so I'm in
technology but I'm absolutely obsessed
with cognitive psychology and cognitive
psychology sort of became a thing in the
is where people started studying the
brain and studying the brain's processes
as though they were computers they said
wow we've got these computers they're so
modern they fill a room they're the
future let's look at our brains as
though there are these computers and
there are two big concepts I want to
talk to you about today the first one
should feel really familiar to most of
us working memory is the cognitive
psychology concept of sort of how much
working memory we have it's how big a
harddrive you've got but what bag of
meat terms it's the space you've got to
work with right now
whereas cognitive load is how much of
that working memory
you've got taken up right now and you
might think well I'm not thinking about
that much I'm not doing that much now
I'm just watching a talk the cool thing
about cognitive load is it's not just
the very conscious thoughts on your mind
right now
it's that email in your inbox you've
been ignoring if that brown letter from
HMRC it's that oh my god did I lock the
door every single back process running
in the background fills up part of your
cognitive load and to make this more
challenging your the amount of working
memory you have changes all the time if
you're a bright happy young
twentysomething and you didn't drink
last night and you've got a great night
sleep you might have this giant beaker
of capacity you might be ready to go you
say wow I have all of this glorious
working memory to fill with processes if
you're my age and you were up drinking
last night maybe you were at the karaoke
tent
maybe we're still that little guy around
noon today but it's not just about how
you feel right now age impairment injury
burnout can all change the amount of
energy you have so as this is an
all-ages show I got to take all of the
squares out of this talk so I thought I
would swap by drinking on stage instead
we're we're okay with the idea that this
is sort of like the conceptual amount of
that tiny beaker right we're we're a
long way from home most of us right okay
I got to get back
I eventually have to get back Sunday
Monday I'm gonna have to take a train
back and oh my god I have to go to work
oh is that meeting still on oh my god
one of my reports needs a new computer
and it just goes and goes you get every
single thing that you're concerned about
until you hit the top the really really
crappy thing about
emptying your working memory is you
don't get to just drink bubbles onstage
you need to clear these things you need
to get rid of stuff that you're thinking
about I want everyone here to not think
about axolotls don't think about
salamanders at all Oh everybody's fine
right you've consciously willed yourself
to clear that from your plate perfect so
we've talked about these two big
cognitive psychology idea we got working
memory and cognitive process
what's burnout so occupational burnout
has been a concept since the 70s an
Occupational burnout is just exhaustion
it's both physical and mental exhaustion
and it's exhaustion that you get from
doing too much people find themselves
burned out when they find themselves
facing protracted ongoing stress that
they feel is inescapable so it might not
be that you're working very very hard I
imagine all of you today are working
very hard yes I mean this has been live
stream y'all fake it like you all work
very hard yes do something in the back
is going nah I'm not gonna comply if
that stress feels inescapable if it
feels like you can't get away from it it
can make things worse even if you're not
working hard if you're in a toxic
environment if you're in a toxic home
environment that's still stress that can
contribute towards burnout it's not just
doing too much
it's doing too much that hurts you and
the best thing about burnout the most
exciting thing about burnout the most
wonderful thing about burnout is it's
absolutely terrible it's symptoms mirror
classical symptoms of depression and as
an added bonus occupational burnout can
trigger full-blown depression even in
folks who don't have a history or
propensity for it
Oh for folks watching on the livestream
we just got a I guess folks who are
really into psychology going yay
or like folks who are not very into the
human condition
so you suggest that's fantastic because
we're on a first-name basis we've drank
together how do I know if I'm burned out
and we're all very cool most of us are
adults we're not gonna raise our hands
please look visibly distressed and I
understand that we we all live in
Britain most of us live in Britain it's
2018 this has sort of become the
standard maybe up that little board look
look visibly upset instead of raising
your hand something like this if these
points apply to you hey my loves my
doves my darlings have you become
cynical or critical at work I was like
don't raise your hands for folks on the
livestream there's somebody up in the
front row jazz hands I get over there do
you just drag yourself to work and then
once you're there you're like oh come on
have you become irritable or impatient
with humans
I said become like if you started that
way that's not on me
do you like the energy to be
consistently productive like the people
who wrote this I got a little bit of
suspicion because consistently
productive sounds very sort of Horatio
Algar work yourself out of debt kind of
thing but who likes the energy to be
consistently productive are you not able
to see yourself in your successes are
you not able to feel good about the
stuff that does get done oh do you feel
disillusioned about your job
for folks on the livestream that was a
loud drawn-out moan have you my dear
audience or my dear listener have you
been using booze food snacks escapes to
to stop feeling or to feel something
different this live streams gonna look
so weird cuz there's tons of people just
going yeah booze and food what drugs as
well like you do you have your sleep
habits or appetite markedly changed
aside from camping are you troubled by
unexplained headaches backaches insomnia
some of this is just getting old but
like unrelated to age this stuff cool so
you you kept a very very careful tally
because I'm not counting for you you say
well you know it Jess I only got four of
those so I feel like I'm completely fine
I got some real exciting news this
survey was developed by the Mayo Clinic
and if you've answered one of these or
more you may be suffering from
occupational burnout
[Music]
we haven't miked the audience so it's
just gonna look like I'm just like
really suspicious of y'all over here you
say okay all of that sucks good job how
do I fix it the one thing I would warn
is I am NOT a therapist I'm not a doctor
and I'm especially not your doctor I
would have you drink and then sleep it
off in real life but I like officially
not a doctor please please if you are
suffering from anything that feels like
this immediately talk to your doctor go
and see your GP we for those of you in
the UK like enjoy the NHS while we have
it go and speak to a medical
professional the one thing I would warn
is that recovering from burnout is gonna
take a long time I burned out
spectacularly a year ago and I'm still
drinking and swearing on stage like give
yourself the time and the patience to
sort of ease into it
and I'm gonna break these two sets of
tips down into two different things
so anybody here who here has burned out
and you've got time and you could just
afford to take a big chunk of time off
work fab I have no idea what to say to
you people like take some time off work
go
I don't know ride your horses or
whatever rich people do like
III genuinely don't know what rich
people do if you could take a giant
chunk of time off work just like serious
and go do whatever weird thing makes you
happy like it's not that I don't care
it's just that your problems aren't
actually that bad you got horses for
God's sake just go if you're not super
rich and you can't take a huge chunk of
time off work to recover there are a
couple little things you can do if you
can't stop doing that thing if you can't
leave your job if you can't leave the
family life that's hurting you if you
can't remove that inescapable stressor
let's look at small things you can do
please do less in ways that aren't gonna
damage your life I want you to do
emotional energy triage oh wow
I've got a list of all of these things
to do that are destroying me which of
these things can you put off or which of
these things can you ignore without
damaging your life you probably got to
pay rent I bet you got to pay your taxes
please eat food and please shower but
like outside of that what can you just
sort of push under the duvet for a
little while
if you've got either the cash on hand or
the social capital' start outsourcing
some of the stuff that exhausts you
outsourcing doesn't just have to be
something you do with cash this
Christmas I got my husband who better be
in this damn talk son to do to do all of
the Christmas shopping and all of the
holiday things just taking someone that
you love I hope or who cares about you I
hope and getting them to share the load
a little bit more redistributing some of
that work can be an incredible way to
sort of give yourself a little bit more
emotional space everybody repeat after
me and say no hey can you do that thing
it feels
there's very clearly like a small pocket
of glorious contrarians over here saying
no is fantastic a lot of people I see
burn themselves out or become burned out
whether or not we want to passive or
active voice that they do it because
they're helping so many people they're
helping people do things they're saying
yes to other things they're helping
people and they're doing such a good job
and it's wonderful and oh god if I say
no I'm gonna be a bad person what will
they do without me it's so good to help
people but you can't help people if you
destroy yourself you really need your
meat computer to be yeah not on fire
right now if you are burning yourself
out by doing too much and helping other
people too much I'm going to beg you
plead with you fuss at you kindly to put
on your own safety mask before helping
others yeah you can't really do much for
other people if you've destroyed
yourself selectively emotionally invest
this is my favorite thing I've only
recently learned how to do it and it's
like absolutely cracking the code to
something glorious and when I say
selectively emotionally invest I mean
something really specific but as we've
already mentioned this is an all-ages
talk does anybody know what mom swears
are oh heck so mom swears are when you
really want to say the thing but you
don't want to teach small people to say
the thing when I talk about selective
emotional investment I'm talking to you
about sitting down and counting out how
many hex you've got left in your
inventory and those hex they're yours
you only got so many left you're only
gonna pass them out when you genuinely
care if somebody comes up to you says
hey hey Jess we're all on first-name
basis I've got this ridiculous thing and
I need you to do it now and it's got a
lot of urgency I'll say wow that sounds
like a terrible problem that I have no
emotional connection to
I really hope that works out for you and
it ties right in there we're saying no
it feels really gross the first couple
of times but then as the last fragments
of your soul slip away it feels so good
but coming back to being nice because
you do have to be nice if you want to
outsource if you want people to help you
you probably need to keep some of your
social contacts going so maybe don't say
though wow that sounds like your problem
say it inside ask for help when you can
when you're burned out it can feel like
you're drowning it can feel like there's
nothing left for you to hold on to don't
come to someone and say hi here's the
problem that is my whole life please and
thank you please fix it that's not super
actionable but saying hey I need a
little bit more time at work
I need longer weekends I need a break
around the house selectively asking for
help can really give you a little tiny
bit more room if you don't have the cash
and if you don't have the horses to take
a proper rich person break recharge the
whole point behind trying to recover
from burnout is trying to give yourself
a break from those intense inescapable
feelings of stress if you're super into
board game is their board games here do
you move today apparently those those
two people are board games Reed go
running do the things that legitimately
feel good to you it'll feel like
escapism at first but you've earned
yourself a little bit of an escape I
think one of the most important things
here is to start to practice forgiveness
specifically for yourself when we talked
about ways to detect burnout one of the
big ones was you're unable to see your
own successes folks who get burned out
it feels like depression it is often
depression you don't feel good about
yourself you're hurting yourself with
more work everything's terrible and it's
an inescapable loop of me not swearing
on stage I cute little kid
get patient with yourself forgive
yourself you're going to screw up but
you're caring a lot more about your
mistakes than you usually would forgive
yourself it's okay
statistically everything's probably on
an individual and small scale okay
globally that's not on you medium term
for yourself try not to be a jerk you're
exhausted you can't do the emotional
energy of like helping other people and
fixing their lives but man you're gonna
be burned out for a while you're gonna
need some friends along the way try not
to hurt yourself by lashing out at
yourself and try not to hurt other
people it's a really fantastic
opportunity to look around you and see
what people in your life maybe aren't
contributing in positive ways but the
folks who are there the folks who are
helping be good to them with the energy
you do have so for burnout please please
please if you can't do less reduce
whatever stressors you can this is not
an invitation for murder this is not an
arson thing like dramatically reduce
your stressors without doing crimes and
take the energy you have and invest that
really selectively so this talk has been
an incredible downer so far I say hey
burn out the thing you could break your
brain if you break it it's broken a long
time but I want to stop for a second and
tell you a short story and maybe suggest
that being burned-out can give you some
magic powers so for a really quick
detour I'm gonna tell you about the
weird magical superpowers I got from
being extremely burned out I get to give
a lot of talks strongly recommend talks
you can do essentially whatever you want
you can get him to bring you booze on
stage like please see me after class if
you want to get into public speaking but
I was in an event last year when I was
very burned out and I had a contact
somebody I'd met once or twice came up
and said Jess how are you doing oh whoa
I didn't know you were pregnant
so back in the day before I got burned
out I might have been really upset a bit
like oh my god like did I get sad
is it distress oh man
should I not be on stage what am i doing
but like burn out Jess does not care
about any of that so instead of freaking
out instead of getting flustered burn
out jess was just like oh anybody who
wants a hack for punishing other people
in social situations I love you
brittish's you will love this if
somebody says something that is just
beyond the pale look at them with a
completely neutral expression and stay
quiet for at least three seconds Jess I
didn't know you were pregnant I'm not
this kid doubled down like oh but
because you can repeat that pause it is
devastating oh no I I suppose it just
happens with age you know and eventually
this talk is gonna get around and
they're gonna see this and they're just
gonna go this talk is better with swears
my suggestion is that if you do wind up
burned out that glorious recovery zone
gives you the incredible opportunity to
get on stage if you're afraid of it
drink
obnoxious fruity booze while doing
something professional and just not
giving the hex when you don't have him
to pass out
even if you are burned out even if
everything's terrible even if it's going
to be terrible for a while for a year
for however long it takes you to save up
for those horses I want you to be
gloriously forgiving to your brain even
when it's a little bit broken it still
loves you thank you very much
[Applause]
oh so we've got time for a couple of
questions from the audience so I'm going
to throw this blue cube back and
hopefully it will work
cool actually works mine's not your
question but I'm gonna give it to my
friend after quickly for a question is
just that I'm also passed a part of the
first aid I've been with central nebula
I've been with Center on evidence for
awhile I've been around mental health
nurses and doctor for a while and even
though I'm not qualified I have a
message from them is what first one is
the fact that it is important to know
that at least that we know of one or two
four people in the whole world will go
through some mental illness most of them
depression even if they don't know it
through their lives so it's completely
okay to be to recognize that you're
depressed it's not abnormal you're not
different from anyone you're not it's
not the end of the world everyone almost
everyone will go through its other stage
in their life so it's very important to
know that sorry
inside it really got through me to learn
that statistic so I thought I would
share it that's one and - it takes a lot
of effort to recognize that something's
wrong with you and rather than be proud
like no I'm okay like you were saying so
actually are you proud of yourself when
you're not okay and you go through a bow
now or you're proud of you such
recognize I have a problem and I went to
work on it and I went to see my GP or
some sort of mental health professional
there is no stigma about oh there is a
huge stigma by mental health and there
shouldn't be because depression is a
normal fact of life so please please
please look after yourself
thank you that was lovely
I have a question for you Jess oh I
don't know where you are I'm here hello
do you consider complacency a form of
depression and if yes how would you
suggest a reasonable alternative to it
like I feel like I'm gonna stay with
this bottle come and get me a little
while like I'm going to need to ponder
of it maybe hard maybe sorry so I think
we've got time for one more
usually the questions I get after this I
can just answer by like see your doctor
everything's terrible but these are all
like weirdly deep I wonder you have any
advice for detecting burnout in others
people you interact with socially or in
employment and what you might do to
mitigate that and try help them so this
is fantastic like yeah just to repeat
this in case the cute softbox is is not
picking up for the live feed
oh I repeat nothing so looking for a
burnout in other people especially if
you're in a management role or
especially if you're you're sort of in a
leadership role in a community or in an
organization is incredibly useful so
look for things like look for sort of
representations of the points we touched
out but some out loud so folks who don't
seem to engage with their successes
folks who are continually saying oh I'm
oh I have no idea what I'm doing
oh I for me one thing I really noticed
with for other folks when they say
they're burned out is I'll often hear
people talk about I just need to get
through X I just need to get through
this project I just need to get through
this next project I just need to get
through this event I just need to get
through this other thing when you see
people continually talking about I just
need to get through this one stretch of
everything being terrible and my life
will be okay like I think that's just
how life works I think that can often be
an early
warning sign fabulous thank you all so
much oh and you can continue talking
with Jess outside and remember EMF is
entirely put together by volunteers and
so if you'd like to be part of making an
amazing event like this happen go to the
website sign up for volunteering there
are lots of ways you can contribute and
help
[Applause]