okay so I would now like to introduce
our next speaker which is Michele
Strickland and she's gonna be talking
about spider silk hacking nature's
strongest fiber thank you thank you so
it's great to be here
so I'm Michele Strickland I've been
working at the University of Nottingham
now for almost four years and if I were
to describe my job I'd say I look at the
backend of a spider for a living but
there's a bit more to it than that
and spider silk is my subject so
hopefully you'll learn a bit and enjoy
it I will say I am around questions
afterwards that I did mostly write this
talk yesterday so it might not be as
understandable as it could be but I'm
very happy to explain the stuff later
and I don't mind because that's my fault
not yours so spiders have been around
for a little while the earliest fossil
evidence we have the spiders goes back
nearly 400 million years and about 12
million years after that is when we see
the first evidence of silk
now if this isn't the use of silk that
we see today spiders have continued to
evolve from that but that's when we
start to see it and that's what we have
evidence for and I checked this morning
at the present time there are forty
seven thousand six hundred eighty
eight's recognized species of spider
that number goes up every week and there
have been at least 4,000 species added
in the last four years so we still don't
know today just how many spiders there
are in the world and we're still
learning lots about them but I'm going
to talk about silk and spiders have
worked out a myriad of different ways to
utilize their silk they're one of the
few types of animals that spin silk
throughout their lifetimes and they do
this to great effect so the top two
pictures you'll see spiders spin those
capture spirals so when people think of
spider webs they think of these
beautiful spirals but spiders use silk
for other things so they'll use it to
line burrows to keep them safe they use
it to wrap their egg sacks to keep them
dry to keep them protected from the
environment but my personal favorite use
of spiders and their silk
is as a physical Gil so the diving bell
spider is the only spider that actually
lives in freshwater in ponds and they
one of the adaptations they have is
they're able to spin silk they spin a
silk and web underwater they then pull
bubbles of air down from the surface
release that owns of the web and they
form a bubble of air under water that's
held there by the silk but the really
cool thing about this is this web allows
for gas diffusion so oxygen in the
surrounding water can diffuse into the
air bubble and carbon dioxide that the
spider is breathing the outs can diffuse
back out into the water so these spiders
can stay underwater for weeks at a time
without having to develop gills that's
what they use their silk for so I'm a
big fan of those they're very pretty and
spider stuff is very useful to us as
humans
it goes back hundreds of years hundreds
and thousands of years the ancient
Greeks used to collect spider silk and
use it in winds dressings if you apply
clean silk and Webster and open wounds
it can help with the e with the healing
process more recently individual strands
of silk have been used in gunsights
in micrometers one of the early
telescopes at the Greenwich Observatory
used spider silk in the micrometers so
they could measure the distance and the
movements between stars and planets and
you can collect spider silk and spin it
into a cloth as well about I think it's
about ten years ago now more recently
than that there was a beautiful exhibit
where a group had collected silk from
golden orb weaver spiders and they spun
it into this beautiful cape and also
into a kind of shore and that's been on
display and going around the world as
well but on a more sort of medical
practical scale researchers have been
looking at spider silk and say well
actually we can use silk in medicine
it's been done before we can do it again
we can use silk to promote cellular
growth so it's some basic studies have
shown that if you put in a line of silk
where a damaged nerve can be either with
or without stem cells you actually get
nerve regeneration and that's really
cool and I'd really love to see more of
that but to collect silk
it's a difficult thing so you have you
can't just milk a spider it's not like a
silkworm where they spin it out in order
to get silver you can use you have to
reel it from the spider you pin the
spider down and you can just pull the
silk it doesn't do them any harm and
pinning down just stops them from
cutting the silk and you can farm
spiders but the problem you have with
farming spiders is if you put all those
spiders in a box when you come back
later what you have is one slightly
large your very well-fed spider they're
not very good for farming they're quite
hard to keep and so it's very time
consuming and very expensive so one of
the things we like to do is looking into
making synthetic silk which we can do we
can make which we could make silk faster
in larger quantities and in such a way
that we can do stuff with it and this
has been done in plants and animals so
you may or may not have heard of a
spider goats which was a project over in
America and but also silk jeans have
been put into tobacco in plants
it's about hoe and potatoes but the
problem with this is you've got these
random bits of silks like it's floating
around plants take time to grow there's
other stuff in goat milk besides silk so
there's a lot of purification and
spinning to do that but at one point you
could buy synthetic silk marketed as bio
steel although I think the buyer still
you get now is slightly different so
before we go into how to make silk we
need to learn a little bit more about
what spider silk actually is and there
is no one kind of spider silk you could
take any garden spider anywhere on sites
and that spider will be capable of
making up to seven different kinds of
silk and these different kinds of silk
have different properties so if we think
of the capture web with that spiral on
there the radial lines that lead through
that frame that web there the frame they
need to be strong they need to hold that
web in place so that when things come
when flies come bashing into it it
doesn't break that web then holds the
capture spiral the capture spiral is two
types of silk it's a very stretchy very
elastic silk that is designed to absorb
the impact
but that's then coated in a glue because
then once you've got your prey you want
it to stay there
and these silks are held together by a
third kind of silk which is a silken
cement otherwise your silk she's going
to flop off it needs to stick to the
environments and there are other kinds
of silk wrapping silk is also incredibly
tough because you needs to restrain your
break you've got egg casings silk and
there's evidence that that science in
microbial because you don't want your
eggs rotting over the winter while
they're waiting for spring so it's a
whole range of mixtures and functions
and all of those come out of one spider
but not all spiders make all kinds of
silk you take something like a tarantula
which is which is a very basic kind of
spider they've only got one kind of silk
blinds they'll only make one or two very
simple kinds of silk the garden or
Weaver's we see have up to seven
different plans and each of those glands
is specialized to produce a particular
kind of silk but having said that there
are a lot of similarities between how
these different silks are made so a
basic diagram of a spider silk plant on
the left-hand side in a tiny tube you'll
is where silk proteins are made and
these are the building blocks that will
eventually become the fiber or the glue
or coating these are then stored as a
liquid inside the sack in the middle and
then when the spider needs a silk the
very long thin duct is where the magic
happens
and I say magic because we still don't
fully understand it although we do have
a relatively good idea
so as the liquid silk travels down this
ducts undergoes dehydration in the
individual parts experience mechanical
stress and there is also a change in the
acidic properties of the duct and all of
this contributes towards individual silk
proteins folding together and forming
the fiber that then comes out at the
ends and this is where it comes out of
the spinnerets of the spider they come
in a range of shapes and sizes but I
just think they're beautiful in each of
these nozzles in each these spinnerets
and spiders that innervated their
muscular they can be moved and the
spider can have control over the
thickness of the diameter of the silk
that it produces so the spider is
particularly hungry it might be more
inclined to make a thicker stronger kind
of silk to make sure that dinner doesn't
run away but what is silk
what is it really made of and simplify
enormously
Silke is just a collection of amino
acids folded together in a specific way
and to get there you take the DNA of the
spider which is the master code you make
a copy of that code and then that code
allows you tells you which amino acid to
stick on in the right place at the right
time and then you just throw that copy
away and continue and how those amino
acids form hello okay gave it the
different structure the different
properties so if those amino acids
spiral and round into a spiral you're
going to get a silk that's more elastic
and stretchy if they fall together into
a sheets then that silk is going to be
much stronger and much and tougher if we
zoom out a bit more if we take a silk G
all the genes share a common layouts so
if you imagine this as a bit like a book
laid out in front of you at either end
of the silk you've got the starts and
the ends of these protein building
blocks and these are important for the
formation of silk fiber this we know the
section in the middle is a repeating
section and this is what gives the silk
this is the part that gives the silk the
properties and this is just short
section whether it could be a short or a
long section of instructions that's
repeated over and over and over again so
silk jeans are enormous but the
important thing is this structure is
this is broadly the same irrespective of
which kind of silk you're looking for
whether you have a glue or a fiber and
this isn't this is enough that we can
make start to make synthetic silk so we
can take for repeating regions and the
finishing the ends terminal of a silk
gene we can move that into a bacteria
and we can use that to produce synthetic
fibers what's interesting is if you were
to include the other ends the other
terminal region this is how the spider
stops the silk from preemptively forming
a fiber while it's in the storage dose
so you have the end of the end of the
gene which says I want to make a fiber
and the end of the gene that goes no no
not yet
when the time is right but if we're
going to make basic synth
Silke all we need is just the fiber
forming part and some repeat regions to
give us the silk fibers and to get there
we need to modify some bacteria in our
bacterial grades and like plants and
animals you can easily modify bacteria
without hacking the genome so in a
bacteria you've got the nucleus going on
that's the genome of bacteria but they
also have these circular pieces of DNA
in which which bacteria used to transfer
information between them so if they say
oh we've got this antibiotic resistance
gene let's show with all our friends
they would do it on these circular
pieces of DNA and we can hijack that and
we can use that to you to make silk so
we can take this path leak we can take
these circular pieces of DNA out we can
cut them open we can paste in this
section of DNA from spider silk and then
stick it back in the bacteria and the
bacteria goes great I've got some new
information let's make that protein and
then so you can breed lots and lots of
these bacteria you can put them in big
bats you can ferment them and then it's
much easier to extract that silk to
purify it and then do stuff with it and
the nice thing is when you get this
synthetic silk protein it's still a
liquid so it hasn't found the five
minutes but with this version of silk
because we don't have that break we can
literally hold a flask of dope and you
can just tilt it and mix it and these
fibers just fall and I think that's
amazing and it's such a lovely things
watch but the important thing is they
are uneven they're different diameters
they're forming bundles they're not as
useful as they might be but utilizing
micro fluidics
we can take a very very very thin tube
and we can spit the silk out of there
into a bath which replicates the acidic
environments and the dehydrating
environment that is within the spider
and then you can just reroute this and
live a line of silk of consistent width
and diameter and that's really cool that
means we can make silk and then the next
step is to go and do stuff with it it is
appearing in industry
I don't say too much about this because
industries are a secret about how they
work so far to my knowledge there isn't
anything on the market where you can
walk into a shop and buy something made
of spider silk
they've been promises Northface in a
collaboration with company called spider
we're going to make a moon Parker with
the outside of it made of spider silk
but as far as I know that didn't come to
fruition bolts threads are another
American company they if you go on their
website you can apply to buy a silk and
tie but I've noticed that they've been
doing they've been mixing spider silk
with wool and selling hats so it's not
pure silk it's pretty good it's not bad
the best thing I've seen so far although
it's debatable as to what the product
actually is adidas and am silk who were
the current owners of as a bio silk make
these biodegradable shoes that they say
is also made from a synthetic kind of
spider silk and you could buy those they
were available in a diva's stores as a
limited edition although sadly I wasn't
able to get any but what I'm really
interested in is how do you modify silk
and the easiest thing to do is to take
something that's really exciting and
just stick it onto the silk and see what
happens so a couple of studies have
looked at carbon nanotubes or carbon
nano structures and the first study on
the left
they took just the bundle of spider silk
they took it straight from the spider
reeled it up and they just kind of
rubbed it with nanotubes a little bit of
water and then separated those fibers
out and while they didn't see any
increase in the tensile properties so
the spider silk didn't get any stronger
they could make it electrically
conductive so you then have a relatively
strong fiber straight from the spider
you can make electrically conductive and
there are things that you could do
that's looking at biocompatible
electronics or just very fine very
strong sensors something which I will
quite happily talk to over beer about is
this research where they fed spiders
carbon nanotubes as they then took silk
produced by these spiders
and they found that the silks were not
only these carbonado shoes were
incorporated into the silks and also
these silks had tensile properties ten
times stronger than the native silk
myself and a few other spider biology
people are they're suspicious of this
work for a number of reasons it seems
very odd that you could feed spider
something that they would then know to
digest and move into their silk glands
is a bit like me drinking a pint of this
stuff and then having graphene coated
hair there's not really an obvious way
how this would happen but if that is
something that could be replicated then
that will obviously be very very
interesting and something we would look
further into and something again that
cropped up which is quite interesting is
you can combine spider silk with metal
ions and this again seems to produce an
increase in tensile properties but I'm
not really sure where they were going
with that and that was a good 10 years
ago but it's interesting to see about
but my favorite one is we can hack the
silk itself so when we're making the
silk in the bacteria what we do is we
can starve the bacteria of a particular
amino acid and give it a modified one so
you can give it you can feed the
bacteria and modify the kind of amino
acid that has almost like an extra
structure on it so you can stick stuff
to this amino acid so when the bacteria
produces the silk there is no difference
in the overall structure of the silk
because this amino acid behaves in the
normal way but it does mean that you can
then chemically attach things to the
silk so that could be fluorescent
molecules so then when you make this
silk it glows in the dark but it could
be antibiotics
it could be growth hormones it could be
things that would change or advanced
medical technology so you could make a
kind of silk scaffold so that if some of
you were having a bone repaired you
could lay that over the bone sew it into
the body and then as the silk
biodegrades it releases whichever
medication
what's a gif so you have a very
localized load those medication right
where it needs to be that's the theory
that's something that's being worked on
we'll see where that goes in a few years
time but I'm quite understandable Sam
I'm very interested in that and I'd love
to see where it goes in a few years
that's why I'm gonna cover for today so
thank you very much for coming and this
thing is to me waffle you can contact me
on Twitter happy to take questions there
happy to take questions here and
obviously I should acknowledge the
people down the left-hand side for
various monies and supports and just
generally letting me indulge myself with
us for this so thank you
[Applause]
any questions of the people
um what's the earliest fossil evidence
for silk
so that was 374 million years ago I
can't remember the name that was given
to the spider but they didn't have
spinnerets as such and the spiders had
what we call ventral plates so they had
plates on the underside of the abdomen
where there were kind of these sort of
spigots the nozzles were forming and I
believe the fossils kind of show bits of
silk coming out of there we don't know
what those spiders did with a silk and
we don't really know anything about the
silk but there is say that that is the
fossil record that we have at the moment
thank you hi and it's spider silk
chemically different to the silk you get
from silkworms and why do you
concentrate on the spider is it just
because silk Chrome's only produce silk
at a certain stage in their life oh so
that's part of it yes so silkworms only
produce silk for one stage of their life
spiders use it throughout and silk roams
only used silk for one purpose which is
building that cocoon so they don't have
the need to use their silk to catch prey
or any of the things that spiders do on
a basic chemical basis they've made of
the same stuff so it's the same kind of
amino acids but they use a different
range of amino acids and the structure
of silkworm silt that you get is
different so spider silk you kind of get
the pure fiber coming out but with
silkworms you get two fibers and they're
bound together with a layer of glue and
Sarason coats which is that which i
think is how the cocoons stick together
so when you buy silk and clothing part
of the process of making that is you
have to dissolve the glue and separate
the fibers before they can be woven so
there is a small structural difference
between the two there is a definite
difference in the amino acids between
the two
and spiders do more stuff with it oh I'm
actually you've kind of answered what I
was about to ask I was surprised that
the silk had evolved after spiders had
split off from other arthropods but so
are the two silts evolved separately the
spider and the silkworms yep so silk has
evolved several times across across the
family tree so both within spiders and
insects they've evolved separately even
within arachnids there are some
arachnids that will use silk for a short
period within their lifespan I couldn't
tell you off the top of my head what
they are but silk has evolved several
times across the animal kingdom so it's
not a unique thing it just seems to me
that spiders are not themselves unique
there are one or two species of insect
that do use silk throughout their
lifetimes but spiders are pretty much
unique in there as a massive group they
do use silk from the moment they hatch
till the moment they die okay okay
thanks very much Michelle we'll
[Applause]
[Music]