oh and we could to go so I'm very happy
to introduce it EMF camp
yeah the Tim project making a relay
computer out of scrap and Rory mangles
so big big welcome so first things first
my campsite is right next to the baths
so unfortunately I might be a little bit
more rusty than I would usually be but
yeah this is the Tim project this is the
story of kind of how I learned about
computing so back in 2010 I was about to
start my GCC's like just finishing my G
cities doubt so many levels and I hadn't
really decided what course someone to do
but electronics looked interesting never
done it you know at GCSE level went from
before so had a look at that first
module is on logic gates and best things
like yeah that's interesting up there
that how those work but because I
haven't done any of the electronics
before I'll do some research before we
before I actually go and go on the
course so I started looking at started
looking on YouTube for you know videos
on how logic gates work and you know
just general information there was a
really good YouTube video on how to make
a half adder out of transistors it was a
half a bit that sounds exciting or it
does to me and so I you know roam around
the shed and wanted to make a see if I
can make anything I make a half out of
out of everything and the only
electronics or really electrics that
I've done previously as I played round
with a couple of relays couple years ago
previously just to you know make some
little circuit that's something I
probably work anyway but I had relays
and they're really difficult to blow up
so I was like okay well there's some
relays you know make me a couple of
circuits out of that so I said about
making this
circuit and sup on the screen it's
really not the simplest way of making a
half adder it turned out but at the time
it was only this way of doing it because
it was all done in transistors relays
are much easier to use it turns out so
yeah I sold together some relays and I
obviously I'm assuming everyone knows
what wheel is out if you don't their
electromagnetic switches that are
powered by a little coil in mAb just
split switch and just to the bottom
they're sharing a NAND gate so you turn
the 2 a and B lines on and it sends a
signal to the output phase based which
is it's fairly straightforward to
concept of which is why I was using them
because they're really easy to say so
yeah I got hold of a couple of relays
saw them together to make a couple of
logic gates and then sold those together
to make what became Tim one so this is
the very first bit of computer logic
ever made to be an afternoon and as they
please myself you know I added a 1 in
the Z row or a 0 and a 1 or a 1 in the 1
and it gave outputs on his old motorbike
lights that had lying around and it was
very poorly wired and as you know pretty
basic and much more complicated than it
needs to be but it was really exciting
to me because you know I didn't know how
any of this work before and then I you
know thrown together some parts and I
had something that was doing maths
really basic maths but it was really you
know for 16 year old me it was very
exciting yeah I had added a bit one bit
of memory in there that just held the
light on when you when it was turned on
very simple but you know I had a
computer with memory so yeah it was all
good fun so I've been made Tim to which
was basically the same thing but with
another bit of memory
Tim 3 I took whole thing apart and
rebuilt it found proper power supply I
found a box
made a little three bit full adder
really going up in the world so this
point I'd realized that circuit design
for a doe was a terrible terrible idea
and redesigned it and the whole of the
previous circuit was condensed down to
about four relays rather than ten or so
but was there that allowed me to put
together a whole load of extra bits and
make full adders instead which meant I
can now add up to sixteen you know
always please imagine in my exams but
not quite so this was a this was the
point where it's tough getting vaguely
serious so I was like okay this is cool
but what if we go bigger so this was Tim
five this was the most monstrosity that
was Tim five basically I got Tim 4 was a
just a Timothy with a bit added on to
make it do effect up to four bits rather
cream it's Tim five was Tim four plus a
load more memory and calculations that
are sequencing circuits and stuff so in
the middle there we've got two four bit
registers which hold data and it's going
through the computer those who were made
at a car relays the reason why this
project is titled making you compute
from scrap is because I didn't buy
anything for this this was all found
crap around the farm that was around the
place that we saw stolen stuff so a lot
of me the car really is a lot of these
are out of old cash machines it were
made at the farm and a lot of them are
you know like washing machine stuff and
my out of a microwave or whatever we
think I could find and this lovely item
was wired up pretty much I put down a
relay and then sold out where it was and
it meant you ended up with what you see
there which is amazingly it worked
and as a video online of it working with
basically it was it could count up so
and do multiplications so you put in two
numbers
and it would add the number of a person
and not another number to it
repetitively to you know basically
multiply it and it could it was four bit
so I could do you know up to thirty-two
in total with the carry MIT and yeah you
know it was it works but as I write kind
of need to rebuild this cuz I can't move
it because it's a pile of relays on a
desk or loosely wired together so I
built
Tim six which was basically the same
same idea but everything being rewired
and to give you an idea of the problems
are starting to get of not designing any
of this beforehand putting me list down
solving them up on the right there you
can see the wiring on the underside
which is not the you know a wyman would
scream in horror at that it's all
point-to-point wrap nest wiring rather
than any you know looming of data bus or
anything it's just what's the shortest
bit of wire I can use to avoid spending
money on it so it was yeah again all
found parts which is why nothing quite
matches and you've got different car
wheel is I'm left and right doing the
memory and then all sorts of mishmash if
stuff in the middle but yeah so this
this thing kind of worked but there was
a Fault in it turned out one of the
committee many months and why I was
thinking about again turns out one of
the capacity the top light wasn't the
head of dodgy cell joint but I didn't
know at the time basically the problem
was I had no second diagram and you know
when you've written a bit of code and
you didn't bother putting comments in
the menu come back a couple of months
later it's like I have no idea what any
of this does this was basically this
whole project up to this point so like
right I want to reboot redo this
properly so I want to do at this point
at this point I said I had a calculator
so it was it was just add numbers but
there's no program it just kind of did
what exactly what it was wired to do so
right I'm pretty sure at this point I
could make a full computer this was
about a year after this is about a year
later at this point so I spent up to Tim
six was a couple of months
playing around relays I was like right I
want to do a proper computer that I am
going to have to do some puppet circuit
diagrams so most people at this point
would download some second diagram
designing tool I open up Microsoft Paint
don't do that for your circuit diagrams
but I didn't know any better at the time
and say this whole thing's a learning
project in many ways more ways than one
so I was kind of trying to learn
computing electronics wiring solving all
at the same time so a lot of it kind of
Sherri's badly with that but things were
working off this point say you know the
other problem I had with build your
whole computer say I only have what I
could find I don't want to buy any real
ASA's cost money and I'm at that point
you know was still at school kid
there wasn't any much money so like I'm
not gonna waste any money on relays so i
scrounge grounded hard the kid found a
route managed to scrounge about 200
relays so i was like what's what can I
build out of that so I started designing
things and these are some of my
beautiful paint arts that I drew up I
still don't know why or how I managed to
draw such nice diagrams in paint but as
you can see that basically the idea was
on the left was the first design which
is basically Tim five with the 4-bit
registers and a much bigger more
complicated athletic logic unit the ALU
in the middle and that could do
different things you had this huge
markup text at the bottom to get that
all those different 4 bit numbers down
to one 4-bit number and put that another
register and then I'll say 4-bit you
know got some spare relays I could
probably squeeze out to 5 bit but that
makes ALU even bigger and at this point
you know just to fight the earliest
gonna cost me like 40 me lays and then
multiplexer bottom is gonna be another
40 rows using most miry layers like I
don't really like this design it's not a
it's not a neat way of doing things so I
came up with a 1-bit Lu which could do
actually only use 12 for you lays in the
end that I realized that if I switch
through every single digit in the
register
originally and just have a little bit of
memory the saves that the early status
it's going through I could actually just
do a series al you said there's one bit
one bit of time does so I which has the
benefit of a less relays but be variable
bit with so I could then you know have a
have a four bit have an 8 bit have it
32-bit if I wanted to have that many
emulators so at this point I say all
right well that's just saved me a ton of
relays let's go 8-bit so I designed this
thing to their full 8-bit
turing-complete computer and as you do
out of 200 relays whole thing runs on
punch tape so the main pump with relays
is trying to get memory memory is
expensive in terms of every bit is at
least two relays and you have to have
multiple registers of 8-bit wide and you
don't really want to do that so to store
the program I made this punch tape stuff
so we had a lot of receipt printers
around and I hacked one up to be a tape
reader and then hacked another one
different punch tape so what it has is a
load of LEDs and photo diodes that as
this tapes going through it reads the
tape it reads that program of it and
instead of most computers where you run
the tape tape into the memory and then
run it from memory this one runs
director of the paper tape you can see
down the side here there's a clock pulse
that clocks the relays as it's going
through so this meant I could have
infinitely long programs in my curing
complete computers I could do whatever
crazy things I want to do with it but
obviously I still had to build at this
point so I designed this great thing and
those like all these plans like never
ever ever going to get this built but
let's go just try so I built you sick so
first I built the ALU just to check the
obviously that one bit ail new idea
works it was great it worked you know it
but a bit of tweaking with debugging it
worked exactly as I planned so it's like
that's cool let's you know add some
registers to that so that made the ALU
unit then I say come work out how to
control this thing
so I had to basically hard-code I came
up with an instruction set which I could
which is as simple as possible to
implement so there's eight bits on the
punch tape first four bits are the
address for about instruction than the
second four bits of the instruction
itself and these were entirely designed
to be as simple as possible to code code
in code into a relay computer just using
the wiring so I sat right I've designed
this instructors say I've got to try and
wire this in hard wire this desert
designer instructure set into the relays
so I mostly get that me working and at
this point it took had to get the tape
meter working and that took me a very
very long time because for some reason
the filter transistors kept dying and I
say you know I'll add these two relays
which they don't divert anything that's
a stupid modern technology you know
being really difficult to use and turns
out the earthly did fall off my solar
garden so it's frying it all with like
240 volts
every time I putting it through
obviously very low current so I don't
where I picked this up in sight right
they're gonna do you know full
anti-static mats down and get the
wristband on when I was solving
something up and touching up and
devising ow ow ow sake that's that's not
ideal wise why is that getting what
feels like mainsville Oh
so after fix that the pate really worked
so that was that problem fixed and at
this point again it was just a pile of
relays of the table so I had to come up
with some way of moving around so all
right well nice you know I want to be
I'll see it also have it all fold up so
if I put the you know get a nice big
plastic set of plastic seats couple
hinges I can put the lodging in at the
bottom that's the biggest heaviest bit
that's nice and that you know ballast
put the control section on the side
they'll give their registers skid down
the other side it's quite neat and yeah
take me to get in the back splat fun
perfect so that's kind of how this thing
came about the whole thing is not used
to you're using
this on Google Drive so yeah good so
essentially this meter runs on Harvard
architecture which is the idea of it
runs off the paper tape rather than on
the computer memory itself so as a
separate store for program and data the
computer has five registers one working
register and four down the side as the
general work a general use storage
registers and then I came up with a way
of doing a really basic memory type
using capacitors and diodes so I've got
16 bit 12 bytes of capacitor diagram and
yeah the whole thing in the end use 160
relays has a full eight Hertz clock
clock rate and a full 16 bytes of memory
if you couldn't include the registers so
in a blistering speeds and not quite
running crisis yeah but the yeah
amazingly after I've waddle together and
spent forever debugging this I'm a meme
forever it's still my beautiful rack
nested wiring I didn't learn anything on
that front at this point still trying to
use as little wiring as possible there's
probably several thousand solder joints
in there all badly done by 1600 of me
and none of its insulated all of it
lands on 12 volts fortunately for
everyone's sake drawers consumed about 5
watts 5 amps of power when it's apt to
fill full chap and can do basic addition
entirely but the whole point of the
project was you know I just came found
found an idea of you know I realized I
could build computers out of relays I
was like ok what's the logical extreme
of doing this with what I've got
and yeah so what we end up was with Tim
it was Tim 8 by the way the name Kim I
just had to pick a name and Tim was a
knight good name so there's it was I I
pretend it was an acronym for a while as
like no no it's just I just picked a
name
very much but yeah and that we've said
Tim eight is the kind of combination of
the two years that that will that was
that project and I took it around
various places doing talks it turns out
when you have some whole computer made
out relays in a really nice clear box
that opens out on the table with all the
different chunks it's actually really
good way of teaching with computer
hardware because if one of the problems
is these days at least in my opinion is
that everyone learns software these days
only said one here probably learnt
software you know how to write programs
and you know how to do - and all the
rest of it but how does the computer
work you know you give out kids for a
surprise the last bit and like there's
this magic black box if you put code in
it's you know it does these magic things
so how does it work
don't it has millions of transistors do
crazy things
okay you have a picture of it now no on
a picture of it where is this thing you
know you can open up think there's the
register so right this big you can see
them there's the ALU logic unit it does
number things there's the control
section there's the program on a punch
tape that's reading through it
here's all these flashing LEDs you can
see the program stepping through eight
Hertz of them bang and it's done so I
mean this was although this was a
learning learning tool for myself it's
actually been quite a good educational
tool having taken them out of your
schools and you know just showing this
is what how computers work and yeah it's
been not the most reliable piece of KISS
you can imagine but and in a minute I'm
hoping to demonstrate it and it's wet
see when it survived the trip from the
car to my tenth amendment temp to here
but yeah covered that I'm just going
back on the pic on the program I made a
program called the basic language of Tim
or BLT she my sandwich again my name is
scheme said entirely arbitrary you can
see here on the right the instruction
set that I wrote for it so you've got
basic you've got eight different logic
processes you've got addition and then a
load of simpler ones you've got all the
addresses of the bottom left for the
registers
to load from Luthi when a punch tape is
interesting instead of like a normal
program we can just jump this is the
kind of more traditional hearing machine
style of when it sees a loop command has
to rewind the tape until it sees start
loop command and then runs it forwards
again if statements are similar so you
have if it sees an if statement it just
stops it keeps running the tape itself
executing executing commands until it
gets to an end if and then start
executing commands again unless that
statement isn't true in which case it
will just run as usual so there's a lot
of interesting working around on the
punch tape there but I think it's
technically turing-complete
steering complete is quite a difficult
definition of all the different things
that compute has to be able to do but I
think with conditional branching a key a
bit if statements and looping it can
kind of do nested loops obviously being
able to loop within a loop is difficult
I did kind of implement map yeah a lot
of things in this computer kind of work
but yeah the basic I mean I did actually
write a program in the end that could do
full simultaneous equations that first
so solve simultaneous equation with
using matrix algebra which was about ten
meters long I never printed I wrote I
wrote for the sake of myself writing
programs I wrote a assembly language and
the simulators I could run or the lead
first before printing it out because
debugging on paper tape isn't like this
so I wrote some ridiculous program
servicing probably the most complicated
program inside of managed to actually
run is the Fibonacci sequence which is a
lot simpler but recently I added
basically I Tim had been sat under my
bed bed for the last five years having
really done anything with it but we
think i holed out blew the dust off it
and picked up this basically there's
this ferry terminal problem of somewhere
buried deep deep within the wine one of
the relays had died and it was one of
the important logic unit vietnamese and
i found which one it was many years ago
but just never managed to work out how
to get it out
so we're 70 years I'd go do this no
that's way too much that's it so this is
another this I'm gonna do plug in turn
on relay stuff working against it right
run with it it's fine
so on the so I got a good all working
again mostly it's to the point he could
run programs at least and eyesight right
the one thing always really knowing
about this is you'd run a program and
you'd have nothing to show for it except
the lights at the fund you always really
want to printer I tried designing way in
printer and all most of that and it
didn't really work as you can imagine so
so but these days right
I know a bit more about electronics and
stuff having now done my degree in
electronics and they going away and you
know spending many more years doing
electronics after this so you know I
kind of know a bet bedroom protocol
isn't don't that printer parallel ports
about the simplest possible program
protocol you can use so it's like a
parallel port on it and wire baton and
it can now print with the tape with the
tape reader so I plugged it into the
same tape read it does its with this the
text is very small because the default
text him that is done pretty tiny font
but technically I could plug this into
any printer and it'll print out so you
can use it like a teletype terminal it's
great in theory if you know your ascii
codes and goodbye switches but keyboards
necks in the list
but basically this they still allowed me
to write the program later you know
every well everyone always does when
they first do it now gonna do hello
world on real a computer which was very
satisfying so yeah we'll give it a try i
can't promise anything but unfortunately
tape reader is got a little bit worn out
so it's it's a bit sluggish on actually
programs the program the clock speed is
set by the the motor and the grip on the
roll at him the tape reader so it's not
it's not the most reliable set up but
we'll see if it works so the power
switch in the front we've got the five
registers front here which that working
register at bottom in the four main
registers the nice big rotary switch on
the sides to select in which you might
to you got all the switch at the bottom
that
give you the option of manually writing
data to the registers and yeah currently
we've got the hello world program ready
to go so I'll boot it up and see if it
will go LEDs on the function start
lighting up if it works then we feed it
fine so that hopefully printed out hello
world well it printed out hello well
twice but that's close enough
[Applause]
it kind of survived the night in the
tent but I'll just open it up to see you
guys can have a better look inside if
anyone wants to ask any questions while
I'm doing that then go ahead I've ran
out of slides so that's sir me done for
hey so I've got a question so how many
hours and all do you reckon it take as
you put into this I have no idea
basically it was a two-year project
pretty non-stop but main main Basco that
was designing the or doing all the
little circuit diagrams in paint I say
little by several had almost tens of
thousands of pixels across but the the
actual wiring for this particular bottle
didn't take too long I mean each module
took me I mean I remember I recently
Facebook memories sent me a link to one
of the pictures of this then just spent
three days wiring this up solid so I'm
guessing it took me about three days to
do the main logic unit god knows how
long it took to actually debug that and
get it working
same with you that there basically it's
very modular so he knew it was made
separately and it would that's that
cycle and then every each module have
made each modules debug then they all
had to kind of be wired together yeah so
I mean I can't really hold this up but
if after the talk you guys want to come
have a look I can pair it up and on the
desk and show you how working and talk
through some of the bit bits
the great thing about relays you can
just plug LEDs on any of it and it's
lights up and it's really pretty and
also helps for debugging you can
remember what all the LEDs do which 90%
of the time I can't better ever give us
a run while item no not really
I'm told paper
I'll have a fiddle see if I can get it
to work that yeah it was kind of oneself
to come up have look it's play the
random question have you ever set him up
on a table on a train just to see what
people's reactions with Beijing I did I
did consider taking into my GCSE final
GCSE exam will have had Tim six I
focused out I think I was told that I
couldn't because the noise would be
distracting but the general idea was to
get it to a point where I could run
programs on it with it doesn't really
transport very well although it is 12
volts and I have considered making it
battery-powered but it's not really a PC
answer but I've always wanted to try and
get it to you know I've always joked
about the fact it could run Windows if
it had enough memory and time but now
I've got a terrible Ivan you can almost
write an operating system for it but I'm
not quite sure how how much you can
actually do with it and how awfully slow
at me the interesting pitted run with
that Alondra to good fortune it's not
very much light in here so try and get
sim try and gets in there data in the
relay
[Applause]
you