all right hi so I'm very happy to
introduce Andrew Godwin telling us all
about lidar and taurine mapping thank
you hello good evening everybody I am
Andrew my day job is to do boring things
with Python and the web but my hobbies
are far more interesting and varied and
take too much time this what we here so
this is a talk about modeling terrain in
particular making small different models
of different parts of the world one of
my first projects was this
I apologize by the way this is like a
weird low-res thing with the screen but
imagine it's much prettier but these are
small metal milled national parks of the
US so I moved to America around four
years ago and one of my goals was I want
to go and see every one of the national
parks there are 59 of them and I wanted
to do a thing to commemorate them I
started here I then got a bit more
ambitious I got a 3d printer and then of
course bought a second one because you
can't only just have one of them and I
ended up printing these giant city maps
now these the one you see here is San
Francisco is one of London two is a
picture later on but they're about a
meter long and about 30 or 40
centimeters high and they're made up of
these individual tiles I bought one here
come and see me afterwards various props
I have here and then finally something
else I've made recently is inspired by
you know a very famous particular album
cover taking sort of different terrains
and doing laser-cut versions of them and
again you have one of those here because
it see it in person officered if you
like but this talk is about how to go
about this kind of stuff like what is
that worth it are coming from how do you
get the data how do you process it and
turn it into these real artifacts here
so let's start with the data do data is
an interesting thing there's a lots of
different kinds it's a big industry all
in itself the thing that we really want
here is elevation data that
is how tall the terrain is it is
generally called a digital elevation
model none of these terms are accurate
or precise it's kind of a weird
disagreement in industry about them but
generally you have what's called a
digital surface model which includes
buildings and things like that or you
have a terrain model which is just has
it removes buildings and trees and just
has a surface of the earth people who do
research on things like flood plains or
on the terrain model peep through things
on urban environments of them on the
surface model you want to have those
buildings there when you have an
elevation model it often in your head
looks like this it's a sort of lovely
set of information and data but this is
actually just a rendering this has
what's called hill shading it lets you
see the individual valleys and shading
actual raw elevation data looks a bit
more like this this is the raw data for
the Big Island of Hawaii which is the
source for that thing I just showed you
here it's not very presentable in its
exact form but it is basically just a
load of data there's a XY grid each
individual point has an elevation but of
course this is all well and good and
it's not very nice like that we'll get
to the nice bits later but how do you
get this well with this wonderful 2000s
era image we can see that the Space
Shuttle in February of 2000 I believe it
was did what's called the shuttle radar
topography mission and what that was is
it had two radar antennas one on the
shuttle itself from one a 60 meter cable
next the shuttle you see here in the
picture and they used radar to map the
surface of the earth it flew round the
earth projecting radar pulses down and
using radar reflections to try and get
that elevation data now this was very
successful and it gave us a great
overview of the earth elevation and
there were some issues it was early
technology but issues of radar in
general radar is pretty low resolution
it's great for large-scale long-distance
stuff but it's not very good for fine
detail so it's fantastic for your a
space shuttle and want to see the earth
it's not so great for I'm a soldier in
carmell to see what's in front of me it
also needs quite large
antennas you see that's 60 meter
separation on the space shuttle it's not
really practical at low level so we have
lidar
so lidar is like radar but with light
it's a very inventive acronym basically
you send a laser beam of your target you
receive it back again and you measure
how low on the radar beam took to go to
your target and then you put that light
that laser on the thing that spins
really fast and you have a thing that
can scan the world around it at fast
pace this here is a robot you see it on
suffering cars often there on bottom of
planes and in general what you use lidar
for is more close in mapping mapping of
city scale or individual terrain scale
so for example this here is an excerpt
from a aerial lidar survey of the San
Francisco Bay Area they took a plane you
stick a big lidar pod in the bottom of
it and the plane flies in strips over
the place you want to map and the lidar
device literally scans the ground below
as you go it gets all this detail
information and with that you can build
up a really accurate model down to often
50 centimeter accuracy of the place
below you in the raw data here you
actually see the individual crossings
and individual parts of streets and the
data and this is the low resolution
version you can of course also do it not
just from the air here at the site
itself there was a wonderful lidar scan
done of the campsite before everyone
arrived a few weeks ago and so this is
from a van which has lidar sensors on it
like few cameras and it's really
versatile technology you can map things
at different scales you can literally
just map one or two walls or the
interior of a room as well and the nice
things about lidar is it's very high
resolution and you can get down to
centimeter or sometimes of the new stuff
even millimeter level accuracy the
devices are very compact a standard
lidar scanners around this big all the
laser infantry stuff is much smaller
than radar is in general it only works
over short distances
the problem with light in general is it
attenuates over long distances very
quickly but generally you're doing it
only from a maximum of a few kilometers
away even if you're flying up and it's
probably not that far
so in general
for most things apart from orbital
missions it works pretty well and one of
the nice things about lidar in general
is that even though it's very expensive
to do a lot of free data's available
from different governmental departments
in particular our very own environmental
agency in other parts of the UK
government have free de jure available
the Environment Agency have a sulli
mapped most of the floodplains and
coastal areas in the UK with free loader
and I believe there's an ongoing project
to map a lot of the rest of the country
in lidar for free as well and over in
the US the US Geological Survey of
Mountain most of America in a sort of
low resolution and again a lot of flood
plains in coastal areas in high
resolution
lidar is often used for floodplain and
modeling and analysis that's where you
see it often more near cities and rivers
and things so we have this data we have
it basically where it comes from but
what we do with it well the problem with
lidar is is not a nice simple elevation
model like I showed you earlier what you
get back from lidar is a thing called a
point cloud now a point cloud is
literally a load of points individually
in space with no links to each other you
might get what color they are you might
get what sort of intensity the laser
bounced off of them but there's no link
if you zoom in you just go through this
swarm of points there's no solidity to
them at all you can't work out with the
surfaces and so we have to take this
point cloud and turn it in something we
can actually use we feed this to a 3d
printer or milling machine it's not
going to do anything it's just literally
a point these are dimensionless points
in space they have no material being and
so that's one of the problems but the
other problem is it's also not pure data
lidar when you get it back there's a
couple of things extra when the laser
hits something it might hit more than
one thing you get what's called multiple
returns and so you may in fact get in
any given point a series of diminishing
points behind each other if you're
flying over something you in fact may
get several different features below you
in the same vertical space if you're
trying to make an elevation map you
might get well there's a top of a
building but also we went through the
glass to the floor below it and got a
weak return
that or we can see through trees and
things like that too and general it's
just quite noisy the data tends to be
marred by reflections water and steel is
especially bad also if you go anywhere
near like a power plant and hot when my
favorite examples recently is a looking
at a bit of Didcot and did cuts pretty
well mapped apart from over the power
plant there's a sort of giant mess as it
sort of starts going near all the giant
steam emissions this quick example here
this is the sea office in San Francisco
again they're just random spikes in the
middle of the sea I can reassure you
there are no random spikes in the
Pacific Ocean I've checked myself but
the lidar occasionally bounces away even
things as a spike there so you have to
sort of get rid of that stuff and in
general we have to do more than that we
have to take our point cloud
we forgot to finish we have to take the
point cloud and go well there's
individual data here too much higher
accuracy than we need I'm not printing a
tree in this kind of size I'm putting a
much sort of zoomed out model and so
we're to take all those points and
reduce the resolution often what I'll do
is if I'm doing a service model I'll say
okay for each small like 10 take me to
grid find the highest point and just
give me that and that way you can thin
it out to a nice grid you don't have to
take those points and turn them into an
elevation model often this is easy as
looking in that grid square taking the
highest point is writing into a file
these two first steps can be done with a
variety of pieces of software
unfortunately none of them are entirely
free I use what's with last tools which
is free for small amounts of data and
evaluation use but if you're due to
commercial your to pay a licensing fee
if you're lucky and your department is
good and this includes the UK government
they were good at this they were to ship
you ready-made DMS from the lidar data
so you can skip the first two steps you
can also miss smoother results this is
done with in my case and a special code
that'll sort of tries to average out the
different stuff but you have different
techniques here you can try clipping you
can try reducing stuff and one problem I
had was when I got data back from a
lidar scan of London
it was when Crossrail was being dug
initially about 2014 or so and the data
was like oh there's loads of points are
like minus 40 meters below sea level and
of course it had seen the giant pit they
put the TBMs in and so I had to rather
than print a model they had this thing
with a big hole me have to tell it it
smooth it and bring it up to sea level
like nothing should be below sea level
will ignore the giant hole and ground
for now so that's kind of the easy part
taking the data getting the data there's
one of them places do this and it's not
easy I'm being a little bit overzealous
here but we have GIS tools we have ways
to do this tutorials online if you want
to find elevation data for a part of the
world you're at least gonna have a rough
resolution of data you might get
mountain level rather than city level
but then we come to fabrication now one
of the things I was maybe a little bit
too shall we say overzealous about
initially was I would be really easy to
make these how hard can it be well let's
go through the three basic techniques
I've been using here 3d printing which
is what makes the city models things
like these tiles here laser cutting
which is what makes those sort of
wave-like shapes like this one here and
then milling which is what makes the
small metallic shapes as well so stop
with 3d printing 3d printing is
thankfully these days pretty cheap very
really like quite accessible for other
people and quite easy to get stuff into
the basic requirement is to have a 3d
model that's kind of it once you've got
a good 3d model the slicer will take
care of the rest and give you a good
tool path and it'll print to do most of
the work for you so the basic thing here
is to take that data and turn it into 3d
model this has achieved in my case
through a wonderful Python script it is
open source links at the end if you're
interested but this takes the data it
makes it into 15 by 15 centimeter months
as STL files now this data is quite
detailed it tends to be on the order of
25 to 50 megabytes per
some 3d printers do not like this and
will just sit there and complain about
10 minutes and then fail so there's
options for making it less and less
detailed so it sort of fits in the
printer but in my case I took these big
tiles I put them on one of my 3d
printers at home this is a Cetus mark 3
and that's it to print so 3d printers
thankfully are unattended they're fully
automated now the problem is this is a
very detailed model it's got a lot of
fine detail or my tiny buildings sort of
like print a little bit lift the
printhead travel over print a little bit
again and keep doing that this means the
tile of this size which is about this
big is between 4 and 12 hours of
continuous printing you would sort of
put it on and then just go to bed wake
up in the morning and hope you don't
find a big spaghetti mess of plastic in
the morning which unfortunately has
happened sometimes and then the problem
is you're printing tiles you have to
assemble those tiles into a bigger hole
now ideally that looks like this but
this is after hours and hours of
meticulous work sanding the size the
tiles down making sure they're perfectly
square aligning them and trying to glue
them perfectly and in the end it works
out pretty well
if you look very closely you can see the
seams between the different tiles my 3d
printers not exactly making perfectly
straight edges but it generally works
quite well and again here's the London
one this is a bit more like East End a Z
you can sort of zoom in with your head
if you like and sing the theme tune if
you look closely here maybe put on this
projector there you can see visible seam
lines this one these tiles aren't as
good in this case my printer was not
behaving perfectly right and so I have
practically a second part of these in
Sam and dandy perfectly square and so
it's a relatively easy method what I
like is it's mostly unattended you run
the script it makes a file you press
print and then you just go and do
something else for 12 hours there is a
lot of manual work involved that sort of
lining up portion and making sure it's
all correct and the glueing stage is a
bit tense cause like once the glues on
you've got 20 seconds or so of work time
for it sets and if you get it wrong I'm
gonna peel it off and have it looks all
right again so it's a good start it's
not sickly durable the ones you've seen
here printed using PLA if you know 3d
printing or nurse a cheap but not
relatively durable plastic I want to
move up to ApS and other things too
there's a variety of plastic in 3d print
with but in general 3d printer stuff is
a little bit brittle and it's a little
bit hard to deal with so let's move on
to some is much more durable which is
milling so if you're not familiar
milling is sort of the opposite of 3d
printing 3d printing is an additive you
start with nothing and then the ant's
plastic to build the model up milling
needs to get different it's subtractive
you start with a big block of metal in
my case aluminium because
aluminium is cheap and easy to work with
and then you have a mill which
progressively carves out the shape with
multiple passes in a similar way you
build up layers in 3d printer you carve
out layers with a mill smaller and
smaller and smaller to build out a shape
here you can see is how about halfway
down a copy of Mount Shasta in
California now there's a couple of
problems with milling first and foremost
is you've got a certain shape of milling
bit often it's circular
you can have a flat end or round end
this one here is a round ended one but
if you do small detail you did a small
bit in fact need to be very very small
but the smaller it is the slower it goes
and so you want to do a big rough pass
with your big nice big milling bit first
and then it sort of a medium part of the
half sized one and then a final part of
the small size one and in between these
you've got a half of the machine come up
and let you take the bit out and put the
new one in and know the depth properly
and it is a lot of manual work whereas
pretty 3d printing is unattended
milling is not it's kind of unattended
you can kind of sit there while it does
each pass has about an hour or so per
pass but between those who get up change
the tool out and do all that kind of
stuff there are machines that have
automated tool changing I would probably
give some sort of limb to have access to
one but they're very expensive
and so the one in my local makerspace
in Oakland in California does not have
any of that it's very much a you get to
put new bits in and do it all manually
kind of machine but the nice thing is
the final result looks really good you
get these sort of very small detailed
models almost intricate in their design
of various different national parks and
things like the mountain and the terrain
come out really well these are the six
I've made so far given how long they are
to make it requires me to have an entire
free evening just go and sit next to the
Machine and just listen to a podcast
while it was away and hope it doesn't
break anything I have broken about ten
milling bits at least making these six
of them because as you go smaller and
some more they break really easily so
they'll be carving out a valley and
cookbook and just break off the other
problem is milling is it's not quite as
simple to just feed a model into the
machine you have to take the 3d model
feed it into a CNC program I use fusion
for an Autodesk and then sit there and
manually tweak the toolpath and tell it
the strategies to use you say oh and
won't you do this kind of flat pass
first and then a part of this milling
bit and there's a good 30 minutes or so
each one of these of me sitting down and
planning out how the machine's gonna
work most of the routing is done for you
but the strategy the high-level idea is
yours
and you sit there and go well can I
shave half an hour off the time my chain
was changing the strategy a little bit
so it's a lot more involved in general
which is why they're going a little bit
slower they are a bit faster than 3d
printing ones because there were a lot
of smaller obviously if you were gonna
mill but want me to thing it would take
almost forever I imagine them on the
machines I have access to and is
attended work
you can't leave a CNC mill alone they're
giant spinning wheels of death they're
kind of dangerous to get in here so you
want to make sure they're attended not
gonna sort of like round themselves
straight into the side of the piece and
just spray out a minimum everywhere the
small features also a hotter mill and I
have an example in my bag and come and
see it later if you want and it's very
it shows very well like there's a little
bit between two mounds in
that you just couldn't get to there
wasn't a bit small enough to meal that
part out so you lose a bit of features
in those deep valleys which is a problem
for anything with mountains in it and
finally CNC Mills are one of the most
expensive things are going to refer to
in this presentation the entry-level
model is like ten thousand pounds and
also you have to have some light
industrial space to put it in and also
you have to have like some air
extraction in that space and also you
then need all the tools well I would
love to have one I do not have the money
all the space to do so and so thankfully
makerspaces
kind of saw this problem but even then a
lot of makerspaces don't have the budget
or the expertise to run a CNC mill as
well it's kind of rare by itself so
that's often kind of the big blocker to
doing this as a project I really hope in
the next few years we get a more of a
revolution in desktop or smaller CNC
Mills it's a few of them out now but we
could make a lot bigger steps and having
smaller more accessible milling through
this kind of stuff but finally
everyone's favorite laser cutting I
think pretty much every makerspace from
here to Sydney has a laser cutter
they're incredibly popular and
incredibly easy to use I love the things
that's one of the reasons I then took to
the laser cutter for this third project
because it's something that I can
literally just plan out an SVG file send
it to the laser it's about 15 minutes a
couple the pieces outlined a little bit
of gluing this here is an example of one
of those sort of profiles that's being
cut by the laser now I have a piece of
software that simply takes the terrain
data you want you slice lines out of it
in two dimensions and then for each of
those lines you take the sample of
Heights and turn them in to the side on
view at a solid object that you that end
you up with about 30 or 40 of those
individual pieces obviously I would cut
a giant piece of plastic this is an
illustration of one of them and you get
this B piece of plastic you pop all the
pieces out you glue them on to a nice
little ridged bed a mental stuff like
this this is my first attempt this is
the wonderful Scotland it's not great
I used clear acrylic I didn't realize
that because it's clear you can't see it
it's kind of an obvious thing it looks
lovely when you shine a light from the
back of it unfortunate very hard to
photograph and then the problem is
Scotland is almost too big when you're
zoomed out that far the height of the
mountains is not that high relative to
the heights that the size of the
landmass and so I tried to exaggerate
the height and like say I'll make the
mountains way higher but it doesn't
quite look right I'm still working this
I want a nice Scotland on the wall but a
second bit of work what is easy is
Hawaii because it's giant and surrounded
by sea so various islands of Hawaii you
can do this too pretty easily because
they are very very high like 10 to 12
thousand feet each you can drive from
sea level to 10,000 feet an hour it's
ridiculous and also they're quite small
they're only about 10-15 miles on each
side and so you get that nice ratio of
height to depth
I also think things like the South
Island of New Zealand could be good for
this there's a few other options as well
there are a few problems with this
though the sort of presentation of this
has a few floors first of all you can't
see it if you're looking straight at it
because it has to be a view from the
side which actually means you want to do
them side on so you could see them as
you walk around the room if you do them
vertically then people of a certain
height will never see the artwork if
you're short at all it's great but if
you're like you know exactly an average
height but why is there just a random
grid on the wall isn't make no sense
other problems is it I tried it with
things that were sort of cut out
portions of landscapes but it kind of
needs things that surrounded by flat
edges and islands obviously perfect for
this but also if you've got sort of a
big mount in the middle of a nice flat
area and there's a few of those around
the world that would work pretty well
and of course it's limited detail this
is much more of an artistic
interpretation piece most other ones
it's very much going to show you the
rough outline of how it looks it's not
really gonna show you fine detail and
the script takes a lot of liberties
exaggerating Peaks in
fact it multiplies everything to a power
of two to really push up the mountains
and bring down the valley so you see
those details much more clearly that's
kind of the secret of all of these
everything I've showed you the London
model all the city models everything has
the height exaggerated because if you
just look at a normal scale model you're
like oh that's really flat boring you
have to have that exaggeration to make
it seem interesting to have it see how
you see it when you look out the window
of an airplane for example so that's a
brief rundown the stuff there's a few
things next I want to work on these
projects all kind of in progress along
with my other like 3,000 hobbies they'll
get like time shared but one of the key
things is I want to do more milling
there are 53 national parks remaining I
do not have 53 spare evenings in the
near future and so ain't I booked a way
to do a less human intensive version of
that whether it's doing them quicker or
whether it's somehow finding a milling
machine with an automatic tool changer
and like bargaining with someone for
that or sending away for even I'm not
sure for laser cutting I want to work on
the future highlighting and I said is
getting Scotland work and we great its
case of working at how do you make a
nice defined coastline but still bring
the mountains out to be really obvious I
want to see the great Glen in perfect
detail or still seeing the shape of the
landmass and that could be really hard
to do when the edge is gonna be quite
flat compared to the mountains around it
with point clouds and lidar one of the
big things we'll do there is 3d directly
from the point cloud what I've shown you
here is taking the point cloud making
into a 2d height map and they're making
that into a model but that what that
means is you lose undercuts you lose
like buildings that have things
underneath them and you know in London
like the Gherkin would render as just
the top half and straight sides and so
you need to do it more for that there's
some commercial solutions but I'm a
cheapskate and so trying to find a way
to make a script that actually parses
point clouds directly to surfaces is my
next interest and then maybe I can get a
lidar scanner when I said the CNC mill
was the second most
thing lighter scanners are the most
expensive thing the entry models are
like 20,000 pounds I do not have that
anywhere they're a handheld one but it's
one of the things like I'm hoping like
as we get them and like they used like
as a crucial component self-driving cars
they come down in price of it
if you're curious at more of this some
of the code to make 3d models is up on
my github there's a few blog articles
with us on the process of this as well
and there is a couple of videos of me
making the process and going through the
big city models on my youtube channel as
well about 20 minutes of me
mostly faffing around gluing things
badly please don't hate me for my bad
gluing and that's basically it
thank you very much
yes we get we can do questions we have
the giant throwing box of questioning
there's a hand up over here we sewed oh
I just I guess I'll just duck in the box
but yes to hold it very close until
gladly that's awesome thank you very
much for the talk it was really good
actually
I had a question about you are actually
more of an idea I really like the idea
of laser cutting the air at the edges
and then stacking them that's really
cool
yeah and I also understand you've got a
problem for kind of looking directly at
it you wouldn't be able to see right so
what about maybe building your model and
then putting it into a vacuum former hmm
so this way it would actually feel you
know put a very thin sheet of plastic
between all of them all of your layers
basically and cannot fill it so this way
you'd have like a completely filled
model with with with shapes so wherever
you look at it you'll still get a light
refracting from it and it would really
pop I think yeah that's a good idea
actually another one on the same thing
is I've also try casting those shapes in
William and like Trickett and negative
of the basic that's not way of doing
that - okay yeah like there's a lot of
interpretations of that like this is
only a few weeks old the late sounds
like it's the most recent things the
least developed I'd say that's a good
idea I think cuz I think you could
potentially just stick it in and just
press it down and I might work yeah it's
the wonder of vacuform use pull the
leaves yeah
maybe another thing is expending for do
you think I haven't got any of that
around its kind of really wanna do I'll
see you though that's right you need to
do a lot of cutting yeah oh yeah thank
you yeah a mope over that dresser over
there Oh see much it still work yes yeah
have you seen the Polish map of Scotland
the what sorry okay so no is the answer
but yes so about an hour south of
Edinburgh near people's there is the
what claims to be the world's largest
terrain relief mapped who called the
Polish map of Scotland or map of
Scotland and it's made of concrete and
it's 10x vertically like exaggerated
basically but it's um probably as big as
this tent if not bigger it's next to a
like a country home but it's really cool
that's amazing
okay that's going on my on my list of
things go see thank you very much over
here one more yep one more question okay
it was just about your milling yes
whether you've considered milling
perhaps wax or much softer materials
which you could potentially then lost
wax casting like that yeah in terms of
increasing the speed I was looking at
the tree milling machining wax casting
that and then casting into a resin the
problem is I quite like having aluminium
as the result and I don't really have
the ability to you know Forge or cast
metals and so it definitely would be a
way of increasing speed making like nice
resin versions I'm not sure I can get
the same like aluminium like machine
effective is it specifically aluminium
or you just wanting a harder metal
I mean the softer metal faster is right
bronze or aluminium is is quicker like
you can you can mill iron I guess
potentially yeah yeah is it like I
haven't done the milling for a couple of
months now I lost I lost access to the
machine and while I can just go back to
a different machine so I need to start
an army machine basically thank you what
was one more question in the back oh no
come on that's got but go long right
there we go okay yeah away from people
even better hey
and the scan that you did of this side
yes that looked like it was done
optically rather than by da as in was
that a camera because it's not my scan
yes somebody else a scan I've blanked
the names Everly yes I I've done some
work using open drone map and it looked
very similar to that and one of the
advantages of that you could just take
video or photo images and it stitches
them right and I wondered if that was
done the same way that that scan was
done using a professional lidar van with
a with a laser rangefinder I believe and
you can do what's called photogrammetry
which is people talking about we're like
you take lots of pictures and then you
use the just differences in the pictures
to work out the shape of the terrain and
that's much cheaper because if you need
a camera basically it's also much less
accurate and doing the stitching into 3d
models takes forever I have some
photogrammetry of Crater Lake in
California Oregon and it took like three
hours to render the model out of it so
it's possible but it's difficult indeed
I did a scan of our local heck space and
that was a 12-hour render right exactly
so like in terms of in terms of like
throughput and accuracy like lidar is
the thing like and also it's being
improved a lot too but then it also
maybe put camera trees as well thank you
thank you I don't show them the question
okay yeah yes scat this the person to
the scows right here he's amazing please
ask him questions all right are you go
question okay oh sure effort so actually
would could you make your own lidar with
like an old laser printer or some other
mechanism the laser is not the hard part
is the receiving of the laser the hard
part shining lasers very easy accurately
measuring the time of flight much harder
and there is there is decent entry level
like single laser stuff it's the case of
like taking that mountain on an accurate
gimbal and mapping and stuff like that
basically Andy I'm putting a get like a
the most basic laser rangefinder I can
try and I tried to I sort of cheap happy
version of it I think is my next project
all right thank you very much thank you
very much any people
you