and now can we have a round of applause
for Terrence Edwards and his talk the
connected house of horrors good
afternoon
AMF thank you so much for for coming
here my name is Terrence Eaton I need to
tell you three things about this talk so
the first thing is that this does
contain some mention of sex and death if
that's not for you that's all right
please go to one of the other talks at
that's absolutely fine for everyone else
I assume you have parental permission to
be here the second thing is this is a
personal talk it doesn't reflect the
views of my employers past present or
future and the third thing to say is
this is all absolutely true everything
that I'm going to tell you today is true
I've not exaggerated it for comic effect
this a lot of this comes from my life
and citations are available on request
so I've been building smart home things
for I guess about 10 years now and you
know from automated plug sockets to
really quite complex interplays with
different things within my house and let
me tell you it is an absolute nightmare
it is one of the worst things that I
have ever done and I encourage you not
to go into the field of smart homes it
will ruin your life and I'm gonna start
talking you through some of the kit that
I've got and why it is so terrible so
the first thing which I think most of us
here will have given me a cheer if
you've got a smart TV
course give me a cheer if you read the
end-user License Agreement which came
with your TV liar
no wonder no one does I'm sorry no
wonder no this is this is interesting
Smart TVs offer us something really
quite cool so if you've got iPlayer or
YouTube or 4od whatever it is you're
making a trade off you are getting the
convenience of watching whatever you
want whenever you want but the privacy
trade-off is someone now actually knows
what it is you watch when you watch it
which bits you rewind and watch again
and again which bits you fast-forward
through now maybe that's an okay
trade-off you know you get hopefully
better quality TV and in exchange you
give away your demographic data because
what you're watching says a lot about
you but things start getting slightly
dicey and the reason I know that so few
people read the end-user license
agreements of their TVs is a few years
ago Samsung released a Smart TV which
had a microphone in it and you can bark
at your TV you could say volume up turn
to channel 7 but whatever it is but
buried deep in the end-user License
Agreement was this wonderful sentence
please be aware that if your spoken
words include personal or other
sensitive information that information
will be among the data captured and
transmitted to a third party through
your voice and through your use of voice
recognition anything you say in front of
your TV can and will be used against you
and this is not sort of a theoretical
concern Samsung I think put out a press
release saying people should just try to
avoid having sensitive conversations in
front of their TV any cameraman do not
argue with your spouse in front of the
TV otherwise you will start seeing
adverts for divorce lawyers I mean as
that's basically what they say and we we
sort of we just blindly put these things
in our homes and with microphones and
all sorts of things and and they listen
to us but oh my goodness they do so much
more and it is quite dreadful there is a
company called Vizio who didn't just
look at you know what I Claire stuff you
were were looking at they analyzed the
video feed of everything that you put
through your TV so from the HDMI they
could tell what D
you are watching by sampling the video
feed and could then sell that to
advertisers and they will find a 2.2
million dollars for this sort of gross
privacy violation because you know you
think I'm getting it a DVD or a blu-ray
putting it in no one's going to know
well turns out they do and again you can
extract an awful lot of data about
someone about their their tastes their
habits their sexuality their age all
sorts of things from what videos I watch
and then this is just being sent back to
advertisers and and who knows where I
think that's that's a really weird
privacy trade-off though I mean we joke
you know in in Soviet Russia you don't
watch TV TV watches you it's it's now a
reality and your Smart TV is probably
doing that the these aren't a toy that I
have but I love these these are cloud
pets they're just $39.99 plus $6.99
shipping and handling and they're
magical so that you're a high-powered
business executive and you don't can't
be bothered to see your kid so you give
them a cloud pet and while you're out on
the road at a Hilton Hotel or wherever
you you speak into the cloud pet app and
you say oh I love you very much or
whatever it is people say to their kids
and the kid hugs the toy and your voice
comes out of the toy oh my god that's so
cute it's real cool but the people who
design cloud pets just I mean the only
way I can put it is they they just
didn't know that security was a thing
and it turns out that if you can yeah
you could go onto an unsecured website
that they had and just look at all the
recordings that people had left for
their kids that's not creepy at all is
there or all the recordings kids had
left for their parents or you could
inject your own recordings into someone
else's cloud Pet it's just it's just
awful and you know this company sort
said I'll live that security fears are
overblown blah blah blah and oh my
goodness I don't think these are on sale
anymore which is probably a good thing
but lots of people are training their
kids to be complicit in their own
privacy violations and I think that's a
a bad lesson to teach kids I don't know
so I used to drive a BMW but I'm much
better now this is the
oh it's versus this was the electric BMW
because I'm a cool eco hippie so this is
the BMW i3 this is this is not a car
this is a computer that you put your
body inside this has a permanent 3G
connection that BMW used to have an API
for their cars so you could do cool
things like a unlock them and sound the
horn from their from their from their
app that they they sort of locked that
down but what the hackers do when we're
told that we're not allowed to do
something hack the mainframe so I
decompiled the app but now BMW engineers
obviously didn't feel that security was
was a thing so it didn't do any
certificate pinning or any checking like
that so I was able to extract the
certificate from the app and now I could
control my car from my Raspberry Pi
that's probably secure that's probably
fine now the other thing so I said you
know you're putting your body in a
computer let me refine that because it
gets worse you're putting your body in
an unpatched Linux box now now I know
what you're thinking how do I know that
it is an unpacked Linux Linux box well
in the infotainment system if you press
the right buttons it will say parts of
this system are licensed under the GPL
so I wrote an email to BMW and said yo
my car's like it's got GPL and stuff can
I have your source codes and they went
hard no one's ever asked for us so that
here is a DVD with the source code to
our car on it which I have uploaded to
github so you can take a look at that
and it's mmm it's not good it's really
not good I mean you know I love Linux
someone my best friend's run Linux but
I'm not sure I want to put my body in an
unpatched Linux machine and it gets
worse if you want to update your car's
firmware that the 3G connection isn't
strong enough or fast enough or whatever
don't worry
BMW will just mail you out a USB stick
to just plug into your car to update it
so we're there now teaching people that
hey if you get a random USB stick in the
mail it's fine to just plug into your
car nothing could possibly it must be
official it's
the word BMW stenciled on it it gets
worse it just gets worse and worse so
having lots of IOT stuff in my house is
quite expensive so I thought I need some
security cameras so it so I got these
these are sort of cheap Chinese security
cameras and they're you know they're
basically fine they they display an
image and I can see it on my phone but
the the company that I bought them
through who sort of managed a platform
for viewing them when went bust so I
can't I paid good money for these and I
can't they didn't go bus they they
stopped offering the services and so I
couldn't use them anymore which which
was really unfortunate and so I ended up
with these sort of lumps of plastic
which I can't do so I'm going to teach
you now how to hack almost any security
camera now this is really technical so
if you want to take notes that's
absolutely fine so what you are going to
need is a paper clip
you're gonna unbend the paper clip by
exactly 90 degrees and just shove it in
that reset hole in the back just hold it
down for 30 seconds and boom the these
cameras unlock so once I did that they
were unlocked from the manufacturer and
we're gonna do a little quiz so the
default username for all of these
cameras was administrator can anyone
guess what the default password was
shout it out
password ah it was one two three Oscar
and that that of course was a trick
question
there was no passwords
[Music]
so I've reset the cameras and I can then
do a firmware dump and I can see that
these are running an outdated version of
Linux and I write to the company and say
hey there's Linux in my cameras can I
have your source and they went no well
that's alright because I downloaded it
and someone else I suck it online
someone else decompile there and they
went oh I found the default telnet
password in here so now I have root over
my cameras which is really handy because
the only way to configure them is using
IE 7 which is I'm not joking it just
gets worse and worse and you know you
can reset more or less any security
camera so this the one on the left there
that's an external security camera and
that has a pin on it so if you see
someone's security camera there is a
good chance there is a little hole which
just says reset you know I mean hmm it's
not good is it and it gets worse it just
gets worse and worse so I'm Matthew
Garrett gave a brilliant talk about
Wi-Fi light bulbs the other day I'm
going to talk about Wi-Fi light switches
which are infinitely worse so the thing
about light switches is so I've got one
of these complicated things in my
kitchen where it's like a bank of four
bulbs and bank of four and I can't
afford to replace all eight bulbs with
with like lifx I mean I can because I
found some bugs in the lifx firmware and
they just e-mailed me a bunch for free
but assuming I had a light switch is
actually really good that this is a LAN
bond one they sell this solve this on
Amazon it's sort of interesting you wire
it in you connect it to your Wi-Fi and I
thought well I wonder I wonder how it
works how does this Wi-Fi how does this
Wi-Fi and light switch work so you know
again there's there's no real security
on it there's no certificate pinning so
I stuck up a little proxy and found out
what it does and so once you've
installed this onto your network it
makes a permanent connection to an IP
address in China as that's probably fine
who among us doesn't have a yeah and I
thought well what's what's his server
running so you know I did a sort of net
stat on it and the the server that my
lights which connects two runs Microsoft
Windows Vista
I'm sure it's secure I'm sure it is
secure and the the way that the app
works again I sort of decompiled the app
there's no security all it does is the
app sends the serial number of your
light switch to this server in China and
the server and China coexist and the
serial number is only like seven digits
long so you could just enumerate through
all of them and just turn on and off
random people's light switches it's a
no-no often I mean you shouldn't do that
that's that's bad and naughty but you
could and that's terrifying and it just
gets it just gets worse and worse so
there was an Android app the that comes
with these light switches and for some
reason it wasn't allowed on the Google
Play Store so I had to download it from
a sort of non ssl site in China and
these are the permissions that my light
switch app asked me for that's just as
too many so what why does my light
switch need to make premium rate phone
calls I mean it so some of them location
so if I move out of a geofence area
can't turn lights on and off record
audio modify the contents of my story
it's a light switch it doesn't need to
do these things and yeah this was just
these were sold for I think twenty or
thirty quid on Amazon and I think this
is part of the problem is that a lot of
the IOT stuff with a lot of the home
automation stuff we buy is cheap and
there's no business model in supporting
it once you you've bought it you know
you've paid the thirty quid and that's
it they don't really care about you
anymore and I'd like to say it's because
it's cheap but you know with that the
BMW i3 is an expensive car and BMW are
not doing regular firmware updates for
it although maybe that's a good thing do
I want to be driving around in something
which has only just been tested I don't
know but it gets worse so this is the
nest smoke alarm is without a doubt one
of the worst smart home things that I've
got so the first thing is I am it just
eats batteries I sort of put in a bunch
of AAA batteries and he started
complaining but I had given it the wrong
brand of batteries and I've never met
something which was so fuss it needed to
be energized a lithium something oh but
again lots of these smart home things
are designed for single people living
solitary lives so when I started this
you know I had an account on my phone
and I could see what my smoke alarm was
doing but there was no way to give any
of my other family members an account on
my smoke alarm so that they could know
when the house is burning down which
they might want to know the only way I
could do it was by giving them the same
username and password and there's a
whole thing and I do kind of think that
lots of these IOT things are designed by
sort of bros in Silicon Valley who you
know just live by themselves because no
one likes them and and so you know it is
you know and like with light switch apps
is quite often you know you there is one
app and you know no one else in the
house can have it there's also some
really dodgy stuff with this home
automation stuff where it starts to get
used for domestic abuse as well so you
know you can say well I'm not going to
tell you what the password to the lights
is I control the lights in the house and
you don't and that can get very abusive
and I find that very weird and strange
but the the thing about the nest was a
reason why I hated it I was on holiday
and I thought I'm just a little paranoid
I'm gonna check and see whether my house
is burnt down I don't know what I'm
gonna do you know I'm a hundred miles
away what am I gonna do my house had
burned down so I opened up the app and
this is what I saw to continue using
your nest you must agree to the Terms of
Service read the website privacy policy
the cookie policy and the privacy
statement I agree and you know I have
bought this stuff this is this is my
product I have paid money for it is
install in my house and I'm now being
told you cannot use this unless you read
for legal documents and agree to them
well what if I don't agree to them this
this thing that I've bought is no longer
under my control and I find that a bit
troubling and strange that you know we
we're now trusting companies who may go
bust they may change their privacy
policy I mean I'll be quite honest I
couldn't be bothered to read for
different privacy policies I just
clicked I agree I have no idea of what
I've agreed to maybe this now means that
this can come in and wallpaper my house
I don't know it would be lovely if they
did but I don't think they will
and it just troubles me and it gets
worse and worse so just give me a cheer
if you've got an elector or similar
small speaker thing you fools fools so
um we let's just stick a listening
device in our in our living rooms why
are we can order nachos quicker we're
now entering this really weird phase of
human existence where you know society
hasn't caught hasn't quite caught up
with the 20th century and some of us are
living in the 21st century with gadgets
so when those of you who've got a smart
speaker like this when you have friends
assuming you have friends when you have
friends who come over to your house do
you say oh by the way there's something
which might always be listening to you
should you should should you assume that
they understand what it is should do you
need a privacy policy when someone comes
around for for biscuits maybe should
just click here I agree on the doorbell
to come in
I'm gonna build an IOT doorbell which
does that by pressing it yeah million
dollar idea
so things like the echo I one of the
reasons I find them a bit troubling
there's many reasons what so one is we
are teaching kids that they don't need
to say please and thank you to this
disembodied robotic female voice and and
this robot woman will always do what you
say you don't need safe these and thank
you but you know there are devices we've
bought them they're in our houses but
they're not under our control so I
present you a very interesting case
which happened last year in the States
echo search warrant raises concerns so
there's a very sad story a guy had some
friends round and one of them died was
found the next morning facedown drowned
in the hot tub and the police assumed
that this was murder or foul play and as
well as searching the house and you know
doing all the normal stuff that police
do they went to Amazon and said we have
a we've got a search warrant for this
guy's Alexa we want every single thing
that he said we want to hear what it was
what happened any background noise is
like that is that okay
I don't know if that's okay I I don't
know whether I don't know if that's
legal I but I don't know whether it's
socially acceptable I don't know how I
feel about something that's in my house
and if I make a casual joke about
something is now recorded and maybe the
police can get to it now Amazon to their
credit turned around and went no no
we're not giving you we will fight this
in court we want to protect our
customers privacy which is nice and it
looked like it might go courts and you
know I object overruled
and the guy who was whose echo this was
who was accused when actually no I'd
quite like the police to have it because
I believe that my echo will exonerate me
and how do I feel about having something
listening in my home which may prove
that I am not guilty of a crime and now
eventually the the case was dropped the
police I think realized that the guy had
drunk too much and then drowned but it
starts
it took it sort of rubs me up the wrong
way that we have listening devices which
may or may not be used against us and
actually it gets worse they didn't
necessarily need the search warrant for
the echo because in a statement another
smart device is a smart device his water
heater points to an exorbitant amount of
water being used in the early morning
hours what investigators believe was an
attempt to cover up a crime so you know
if you can take a look at your if you've
got a smart meter a smart water meter
any of these smart devices which are
constantly recording every single minute
by minute what's going on in your home
which of those points to you being
guilty of something a-any gets worse it
just gets worse and worse so I talked
about computers that we put our bodies
inside what about the computers we put
inside our bodies does anyone know what
this is a an x-ray of pacemaker
excellent well done so this is a science
II term it keeps your heart going
basically and it's a little computer and
that's cool we've got little computers
inside us now but here's the problem
with these things is that they are
usually built quite cheaply and the
companies which build them don't pay
much attention to security and what we
find is the lots of these pacemakers if
you go online you'll be able to find out
what the default password is for them
and it is not a long password and if
you've got a laptop and an antenna
you know shoved into your USB port you
can start reading off pacemaker data
from someone and he gets worse you can
write data to the pacemaker as well so
you know usually what happens if the
heart goes into I'm not a medical doctor
or any sort of doctor but you know once
the heart goes a bit funny the pacemaker
can give it a little zap of electricity
yeah and you're still alive you could if
you know the default password and you
are close enough reprogram someone's
pacemaker so it doesn't provide that
jolt of electricity or that it provides
too much or something else and it's
really weird these devices which are
inside us are not under our control that
almost what not almost anyone certainly
anyone in this room would be able to go
up and literally reprogram
your heart and it gets worse this is
another case this guy said I woke up and
someone had set fire to my house so I
quickly packed my bags jump through the
window ah it was awful and police and
fire when we think you did it and we're
gonna subpoena your pacemaker data to
find out whether you did it or not
whether your heart activity was
consistent with the story that you told
us now again I don't necessarily want to
get into whether this is is legal in
this jurisdiction or legal here because
I really don't know but it worried there
is a computer inside your body which is
not only not under your control will
betray you if asked it will give up your
secrets and that worries me you know
because we are seeing more and more
people whether it's cochlear implants or
neural implants or heart things or you
know all sorts of you know crazy cool
amazing that we're rebuilding humanity
but there's a default password and any
hacker on the Internet can slurp you
know what your heart was doing last
night it worries me it really worries me
and it just gets worse it gets worse and
worse so this is where we get to the the
sort of juicy topic of sex now we're
going to be talking about teledildonics
telly from the Greek word meaning
distance dildo niché's
from the Greek word meaning and
offensive slogan painted on the back of
the campervan
it was the last one they had I'm so
sorry so I and I am NOT I am NOT here to
kink shame anyone I am here to security
shame some people so this is the we-vibe
this is a vibrator and it connects to
your smartphone via bluetooth so far so
good so you can control it from your
phone and you can also set up an account
with someone else and they can control
your vibrator from their phone while
they're in the comfort of their own bus
or train C or wherever they happen to be
to Troy which is fine that's good but
and this this uses bluetooth and that
that's not true if
to be secure and what that means is if
you know what the default pairing key is
of this vibrator you can just pick up
your phone
scan find them connect and activate it
you can commit serious sexual assault
from your phone via bluetooth that's not
funny
but this is a real problem the people
might be wearing these and thinking that
only my trusted partner or myself can
use these but in actual fact anyone with
a Bluetooth phone or a Bluetooth laptop
can do it now the other problem with
this is that we talked again so give me
a cheer if you've read the privacy
policy on your vibrator lawyer
no one does if people had read the
privacy policy on this vibrator they
would have realized that the the company
which manufactures this takes diagnostic
information and so every time it's used
they get a record of where you were when
you used it how long you used it for the
intensity of the vibrations when you
stopped using it oh and your internal
body temperature did anyone tick the box
that says yes I can send to my internal
body temperature being sent
I don't think sighing there's been
lawsuits and all sorts over this and
it's it's worrying any scary and it gets
and it gets worse
it gets so much worse so this is a
another internet-connected sex toy and I
know what some of you are thinking mine
doesn't look like that well well yours
doesn't have a camera on the end whereas
this one does
nokay no no listen what people want to
do in the privacy of their own internet
connection is their business but sure
are you ready for your close-up now you
you cannot stream HD video over
Bluetooth so they've helpfully put a
Wi-Fi logo on there now Wi-Fi as we know
has a fantastic range you know a couple
of hundred meters if you're lucky in
with good and antennas this does and 10
attenuate somewhat if it is surrounded
by a body but you know you can you can
listen in on this Wi-Fi signal and again
the company just didn't think of setting
a strong passwords on this so if you
find the the MAC address broadcasting
while you're in a hotel or in EMF or
anyone else you can take control of this
you can see what someone is doing with
this you can commit sexual voyeurism
again there's an offense in this country
with a Wi-Fi connection because people
don't understand what it is that they're
buying they don't understand that when
you buy Internet connected things you
are sacrificing a part of your privacy
and unless you are absolutely on top of
all of these things and read every
single privacy policy every time they're
updated you could open yourself up to a
huge world of pain or embarrassment or
blackmail or or anything and it gets
worse it just gets worse and worse every
time we buy something with an internet
connection it sort of eats away at our
privacy a little and no no one no normal
user is reading privacy policies no
normal user is changing their default
settings no normal Hughes is changing
their passwords on their on their sex
toys it just doesn't happen it just gets
worse and worse everything is terrible
everything is absolutely terrible and I
have no idea as a community how we fix
it thank you very much Cheers
I questions yeah I think yeah if we use
the blue box if you don't get your
question answered I will be drowning my
sorrows in the bar all afternoon so do
you come find me I think there's a
question there and then there hello
yes so sextoy sextoys aside we're
quickly coming to a time when no matter
how much money you can spend or are
willing to spend you cannot buy a
consumer product be the TV a smart meter
a boiler heater whatever that is not
horribly laughably insecure do you see
this changing in the near future that
basically there will be a line of
consumer products for people like us who
care about this so for people like us we
can build our own so I mean III
jailbroke those smart cameras so that I
had complete control of them they
weren't going to a server but most
people just can't be bothered to do that
there might be a case for a privacy
focus one but it would I think it would
either be very expensive or you know in
the case of Amazon echo they realize
that I think they realize that if they
breach their customers privacy too much
people will abandon them and I think
with laws like GDP are that's going to
make things stronger but the problem is
as I said is that when we go to Amazon
or Alibaba we tend to sort by lowest
price first nor highest privacy first so
the problem is us as much as it is the
the manufacturer so I don't know I don't
see it improving anytime soon I'm sorry
can you hear it
in a couple of weeks is very possible I
am going to become a developer of
precisely this kind of kit in a startup
organization of about ten people where
it's painfully obvious that I am the
only one who has the vaguest concept of
security any thoughts on how to educate
the highly intelligent highly motivated
people who have no concept of security
and the rest of the organization yeah I
mean you should and you know kudos for
telling the map I think one of the
things that you can do especially with
founders is show them the finds which
people have been given so as I said
Visio Visio in in the state's 2.2
million think cloud pets had a big
out-of-court settlement remember but
showing people the money is good and I
think telling people the stories of
privacy and I remember talking to a
developer years ago saying but when
people get in you out don't they just
automatically flick through all the
settings and see what they like and I
had to say no normal people don't do
that what I would recommend is doing
user testing so if you've got an app for
example go down to a coffee shop get
real users and you know buy them a
coffee say hey can you use this app tell
me what you think and see how many of
them read the privacy policy or do
things and I think showing people that
there is monetary problem as a society
problem and that their users don't
really understand or care I think that's
a good way but I'm not sure that it's
been successful yet but yeah do you come
and chat with me afterwards anymore for
anymore hi Terrance are you running a
bug bounty on your house am i running a
bug bounty on your house a bug bounty on
my house yes yes I am and you get some
delicious home-cooked cookies which
unfortunately have been cooked by me and
will not be very tasty so yeah but it is
very interesting so trying to I've got
virgin media at home and they've got a
you know they're smart hub and there is
no meaningful firewall on that I think
there's question right in the back there
so it is really hard as a home user to
secure your home without buying more and
more stuff I think there's a question
there and then if we've got time for
more yeah and if not you can buy me a
drink
this is working is it all good I was
wondering what you think about this
perhaps being a consumer rights issue
that our law hasn't really caught up
with I'm thinking back to even what we
see with mobile apps where something's
gone terribly wrong with the software
model but we've got yeah where users are
forced to accept upgrades as you say to
continue to get functionality and
functionality is taken away and things
like you think about my sonís speakers
on a monthly basis forced to accept new
software they changed them yeah so is
not possible to install an old version
yeah and a good example is the nest
smoke alarm so the original nest that
I've got it touted a feature that if if
the alarm was going off and it was a
false alarm you could stand under it and
wave and it would switch off and what
they discovered was their firmware was
unable to tell the difference between a
person waving under their smoke alarm
and black billowing smoke I mean they're
pretty easy to confuse I can and so they
disabled that functionality now I'm kind
of glad they did it but that's something
they've turned off which I paid for at
the moment I don't think there is a
consumer rights movement for that and I
don't know how we fix that I think
someone on the back had a question hello
hello are you as worried about the
recording capabilities of mobile phones
as you are about Alexa and if not why
not
so you can usually tell when your phone
is recording and when it's transmitting
it's it's harder with an Alexa the mode
of a smart speaker is that it's always
on you don't have to do that with your
phone I don't use Google assistant on my
phone or Syria or anything like that but
yes it is entirely possible that those
things could be recording and sort of
doing stuff just what we're getting the
next question up and I would love to
take a selfie with you all because
you're all wonderful so if you could
just give a a big EMF wave just like
that concern no it's too late still like
by attending this talk you give up all
rights
sorry sorry the the yeah the gdpr does
not cover my photos oh yeah as I am
curious what devices you've ended up
deciding you're okay with having in your
own house
oh all of these because it's a trade off
dude do I really think that nest are
going to sell my how often I burn toast
to it to an advertiser they might but I
run out block so so what do I care with
these cameras
I have routed them jailbroken them I'm
confident that I am in control of them I
no longer have the i3 and when you car
coming doesn't have a permanent 3G
connection but it still runs Linux so
it's a trader from we all make these
trade-offs you know it's it's like with
as I was saying with iPlayer I'm happy
to give up a bit of privacy if they make
more good episodes of Doctor Who because
they've seen me rewinding you know the
good ones and watching them again and
again the you know your trust model your
failure model might be different and I
wouldn't blame anyone who just when I'm
having no part of this because you know
it can be quite scary one more yeah is
there necessarily a trade-off between
usability and privacy or security yes
because you some people is there a
trade-off between privacy and usability
because you are going to have to ask
users questions are you okay with this
being stored outside of the EU are you
okay with us doing face recognition from
your smart doorbell and every time you
ask a question that reduces usability
you shouldn't make users think too much
about this but if you give them too much
privacy maybe the utility of what they
have isn't good enough so I I think
there is a real tension here we want to
buy some I mean the nest is great in the
sense that you just you know stick it up
until all that's it there's no real
configuration necessary but you know
that doesn't do much it just sends you
an alert in your house is on fire but if
you're doing smart doorbells and you
want to you know record people spaces
and send them to seven people and talk
about you know all right I think that
the more interesting a smart home device
you have the more usable it is then it's
going to necessarily be a privacy
problem and trying to get people to
understand
and the privacy trade-offs they're
making for themselves their families for
their friends coming around for the post
earring on the doorbell that that's
something that we haven't worked out how
to educate people on thank you so much
for coming to my talk and I shall see
you all in the bar kiss
[Applause]