all right hello thanks for coming I'm
going to talk about the secret powers of
podcasting so Who am I I'm temperate
laughs I'm living in Germany in Berlin
and I do podcasting a lot it actually
all started on the radio around
I forgot 20 years ago or so I liked
radio I like talking into microphones
but I always had a problem with the
distribution part of it the way it's
framed by time constraints and intermix
with weird how you are supposed to talk
to the audience depending on the radio
station so I liked it but I didn't love
it
then podcasting came along and I saw wow
that's something for me and I started my
own project called meta in Germany meter
level because I found out that if you
are in a good discussion that's where
you want to come to you know if you are
on top of everything you reach the meter
stage and that's where I wanted to be I
also started a small open source
software project called hot lava which
is providing some tools to the general
public
I'm going to talk about this later on so
what is this about this talk I have
accumulated some experience doing
podcasts I do a lot of podcasts I have
10 shows or so not all of them are very
active around 6 are more or less on a
regular basis and I have a larger
audience I can talk to and that's why I
found out how this works or at least
what I think how this works and why this
should matter to you so I'm going to
talk about why podcast meta at all I'm
going to talk
why podcasts are actually useful for a
lot of things maybe how podcast can help
you in whatever you are doing and
therefore why you would probably want to
start a podcast and if you want to do a
podcast how to do your own podcast but
maybe the main question you have in your
mind is what are these podcasts anyway
so we start with the small poll who
thinks she knows what a podcast is raise
your hand if you think you know what a
podcast is I would say like something
like 80% so there's work to be done who
actually listens to podcasts doesn't
need to be on a regular basis I would
say the exact same 80% who actually does
the podcast on his own that's one or two
I'm not going to express this in
percentage who has been thinking about
doing a podcast that's like five times
as much you're my audience and who has
no time for podcast and doesn't care or
doesn't care one it's fine we can move
on so let me clear up some confusing
confusing terminology first
so there's podcasting and there's
podcast what's difference when I talk
about podcasting I refer to the
technology I refer to how this thing
works and podcasting is basically a
distribution technology that's the idea
it's like how is this stuff actually
passed along on the internet and this
technology basis is the cool thing about
podcasts that's what make my head click
when I first encountered it because it's
just very suited to both the internet
and how people should all want to
consume
content on the internet so it all comes
down to three letters called RSS RSS was
a very super simple format that was
capable of transforming blogs into media
and then podcasts into real media
because there was a way how to subscribe
to it so it's all about the subscription
it's all the way how you attach to your
sauce and that you can't really lose
track of what's coming without you
having to spend much time or energy to
follow up on what's happening if there's
something happening you will know if
there's nothing happening you don't have
to care and you shouldn't so that's a
good thing
and there is this download thing you
know the thing you always look for on a
YouTube page and it sucks that there
isn't one and you know why there isn't
one because they want you to stay on the
page they want to be you know you in in
this Mia Wonderland powered by ads
powered by your attention and podcasts
don't care podcast do it the other way
around it's all about the convenience
and the convenience is the download
because as you find out if you are at
one of these camps at least when you are
setting them up that's probably no
internet when you need it but the
podcast is always there when there is no
internet and that's good for no apparent
reason here's the list of five people
who are very have been very helpful to
this whole podcasting thing to work
there's dave winer the guy who came up
with all those RSS ideas which still
work great and also like his style and
his general setting is very cool to
follow as Christopher Lydon who was sort
of the first one using this technology
or actually delivering content that was
using this technology
and also starting the idea of doing
interviews on the Internet
there's been Hamersley from the UK who
dropped the term podcast which was just
fine and then there's this weird
Adam Curry who encouraged developers to
actually create a podcast client so
thanks to all those white dudes but
there's one more it's you it's the
audience it's the people who do it
podcasting really has become a thing on
its own and it's powered by the people
and it's powered not only by a view but
it's really powered by a lot and most
people are contributing to podcasting by
listening to podcasts so what about
listening to podcasts first of all I
think you should do it it's a very very
healthy thing to do podcasts can help
you and best is do it while you are
doing other things it's really helpful
it's both helpful for listening and it's
both helpful for doing the things
because your mind is nourished all the
information while you do tasks that are
basically boring driving a car running
around through the woods doing your
chores housework all these things tend
to be totally boring actually become
super exciting when you're also
listening to a podcast while doing it
and as an extra hint get out get out
into the fields get out into the woods
if you're outside and you're listening
to podcasts it becomes even more super
amazing you know you're on holiday you
walk the streets of a city you've never
been to the podcast you are listening to
right now at that very moment you will
probably remember all the topics
attached to all those strengths and
things you saw for years to come
it's really amazing how these things
match up and another recommendation is
use the pot I know many people think the
pot is the iPod but I really more refer
to its original meaning it's this small
thing you have in your hand it's where
everything is where you store your stuff
that you need
so today the pot is of course the
smartphone has helped podcasting a lot
and the good thing is that there are so
many dedicated apps that are delivering
podcasts probably the way you wanted to
there are many many many clients
available and you can just choose any
try them all find out what suits your
needs if you're more in a oh I need to
listen to them one after the other and I
can't get enough of it or if you want to
have something that makes it easier to
pick easier to select even parts of a
podcast so that you can really find a
mode in which podcasting come to your
life in a way that suits your life along
with clients comes directories and also
platforms and that's something I think
you should be aware of
depending on your opinion here in the
beginning there was iTunes or how it's
called these days
Apple podcasts there are some general
misunderstanding of what a podcast
actually is it is basically a directory
it's a directory of feeds so those URLs
that actually point to the RSS content
and that's it that's all of course they
attach all the extra data ratings and
other statistics to it more and more but
as a podcaster Apple podcasts are still
very friendly to podcasters because
everything that is displayed apart from
comments of course is more or less
provided by you you are in control and
being in control I think is one of the
more in
and really nice things about podcasting
in general I think there is no need for
platforms of course there are a lot of
platforms coming up Google is starting a
podcast site which sounds like the same
as Apple is doing but it's not really
because then they want to host your
stuff deliver your stuff there might be
good technical reasons for that but
everything that's being taken away from
you you should think about this twice
even more this applies to things like
Spotify other platforms basically
they're all inviting you to a ward
garden and once they're all there they
want to define the rules and that's a
problem and I will expand on this later
on there are other open-source
directories that also serve you as a
resource to find stuff like the food
project which originated in Germany
there are others fit is quite nice so I
can recommend that yeah I think that's
something you should be a wealth so why
do podcasts matter to people what makes
it so attractive first of all you find
out if you're interested in a thing
there's a good chance there's at least
one podcast about this thing and it
doesn't matter how far from other
people's reality this thing is your very
special interest niche is probably
already covered if it's not that's your
podcast niche that's where you have to
go for because nobody is already talking
about it and you think it's interesting
there's a good chance
other people will find this interesting
too and that's some kind of people you
want to talk to so these are very
vertical target groups how you would you
know call this in marketing speak but it
makes sense because everybody is totally
going crazy about mass MA
kids large numbers and so on but in the
end it doesn't really matter so much how
many people you actually reach it's like
how good is this contact you are making
to these people and even more important
who is that you're actually reaching if
you reach 10 super important people of a
certain niche that's much more than
talking to 1000 people who don't care
and that's why podcasts are really
really good
so podcasts are also a very independent
medium that's complicated to support I
think along with blogs podcasts have
been able to retain this independence
first of all because they are not
supported by platform so much if you
talk about video your video is usually
not mattering much if it's not on one of
the big platforms or the big platform
because people don't find it people are
not used to discover video on any other
way than by searching a platform maybe
they use search engine sometimes that's
also a possibility but most people just
turn to YouTube and look for it and if
it's not there it doesn't exist that's
not yet what's happened to podcast and I
hope this stays this way even more
important it's in my opinion the most
personal medium that is what do I mean
by that it's it's very personal in two
ways it's very personal in the way it is
consumed you plug your earphones in you
walk around the streets you're totally
on your own and voice is up talking to
you you know it's a very intimate
relationship it's it's nobody is
watching you while doing it and even if
somebody is watching you I don't know
what you're listening to
doesn't matter this frees your mind it's
something different than looking on a
screen also it's very personal in the
way it is delivered podcasts usually
tend to have a totally different tone
when talking to their audience then the
way you find people speaking in videos
on TV or in radio so even radio is
different and if I would give this talk
in a radio voice you will notice and you
will hate it so it's the voice that
matters and I think many people are
overlooking the power of the voice in
podcasting why is the voice so important
first of all it's our primary
communicate communication system if you
meet somebody you not stop writing notes
on paper and passing them around you
talk to them and if you finally meet
somebody and can actually listen to
somebody that forms your opinion much
more than anything else you might have
read it's very important to calibrate
how you think about other people and
that way it's both capable of building
trust and the opposite of course too
because then you know like I don't
really like this guy because you know
something is wrong because you can
transport so many things in your voice
and you can't really hide behind your
voice so the voice is very important for
credibility it's very important for
emotion and of course the irony and
wherever has written something on the
Internet
published it and there was irony in it
guess what happens people misunderstand
you either because they want to or they
just don't get it and it might be your
fault might be therefore the problem is
writing and
means extra encoding and decoding and
the voice is basically encoding decoding
free of course there is encoding and
decoding but that's more or less done in
real-time
everything else is work for your mind so
that's why the voice is so important and
that's why podcasting is important as a
medium on the internet because it takes
this situation of the radio of being the
primary delivery of voice and gives it
back to the people another thing that's
happening is that there is far less
prejudice involved when you are
listening to people
the images are gone you don't say like
oh I don't like this guy looks you know
this look ism this is what you think of
people just by looking at them without
really having interacted with them
that's absent in the voice world because
the first time you notice somebody
there's already communication involved
voice is communication and you your
opinions are are delivered on what you
communicate with what you what gets
communicated to you so that's helpful
especially for some communication I'm
not saying the voice is something that's
totally free of prejudice of course if
you have a weird voice or something that
is considered to be a weird voice it
will still be a problem to get past
these prejudices but it helps a lot
believe me so having sent all these
things you probably think like it sounds
nice maybe I would start my own podcast
so how do you start a podcast first of
all that's easy to say you just have to
do it don't overthink it
just grab a microphone and start doing
things and publish them always as well
because doing a podcast recording it and
storing it on podcast one not mp3
doesn't really help it needs to get out
but of course if you really want to have
some kind of format that is at least a
bit successful in the terms of what I
told you before that you want to reach a
certain audience you need to think about
what to do what to actually do so I
think it comes on to two things first of
all think about what do you want to
convey what do you want to actually put
out what is your original content
what's your original interest what
matters to you that's much more
important of what you think of what
others expect just find the source of
information where you can actually talk
about what you really have the feeling
that you need to clarify need to explain
want to discuss think it matters maybe
it's something you don't understand and
you want to learn by talking about
doesn't matter but these are the most
important decisions in the first step
think about what what matters to
yourself and then you can go to the next
step and think about who is it for who
do I want to talk to who is it that
might be interested in what I have to
say and it doesn't really matter again
how many people these are it's just like
who is it who do I want to talk to if I
have three free wishes who are the kind
of people I want to be sitting in front
of me so that I can talk to them that's
the audience you're looking for and you
find this audience by talking to them
without knowing them because if you
start talking to them they will find you
the audience is coming to you just by
radiating the right stuff so when you
think about who to talk about
you have to think about community in
general and when you are when you want
to grow your podcast when you want to
grow the audience always grow naturally
and I call this the ring theory because
I think it sounds cool and actually I
got rings involved start with your core
always talk to the core community the
people that you think you know maybe
even the people you already know like
all your very close friends or people
who are involved what you want to talk
about and then continue doing it and
then by time you will find out that you
are you know you'll find out what it is
you're really interested in which might
deviate a bit from what you originally
started with you find out what works you
find out where you get feedback you work
with the feedback and then what happens
people who are listening to you start
talking to their friends and those
friends are going to be invited hey you
really should listen to this podcast
because it's interesting or will change
your life or whatever that's how it
grows and then you will have this outer
ring of friends of friends of friends
that are actually you know also
interested but didn't know that you
exist or didn't even know that this
topic could be that interesting and once
you have reached this state of growth
then you might be able to reach a public
that didn't even think about that this
could be interesting at all or you know
probably even have heard about podcast
but now find podcast interesting because
that's what you talked about so grow
from within to the outside
and always remember numbers are relative
and don't really matter it's about the
quality of your audience that matters
and it's also very important that you
find your own comfort zone be
comfortable in what you do don't think
that you need to talk about something
because somebody told you so or you
think it could increase your audience
you know whenever you try to appease
unknown people you will probably fail so
do this over and over again
and once you have started your podcast
make it 10 10 podcasts and you call 10
shows and you could call it a podcast
it's my experience usually coming to 10
can be very very complicated once you
are adding a digit things get a lot
easier you know what you talk want to
talk about you know what you don't want
to talk about you know how you want to
talk about it and so on and so on and so
on of course some people might be able
to find it sooner some people need
longer but I would say 10 is a good
thing so then at a certain point you
need to think about who is doing this
podcast and how are you doing it and
that's not that easy to answer you might
have no friends interested in your topic
and then you start with monologues you
grab your microphone and you just talk
to the invisible guy somewhere out there
hello
I know you're there here's what I
thought about and this is a random
collection of my thoughts some people
are really talented in this but I think
most are not if you are not the kind of
person who could just send on front of a
stage and out of nothing you know
talk endlessly about whatever monologues
are probably not your thing so don't
push it if it doesn't come naturally
it's probably not for you
much better dialogues I think this is
sort of where the majority of podcasts
work dialogue means two people could be
more the style is important that you
discuss which is other one person
presents information the other person
asks about us did I understand this
right what do you mean by this you
really think this is so important
I've never heard of it the other person
and this can change throughout the
podcast of course who is playing which
role is some of the stand-in for the
audience at least a temporary stand-in
for the audience filling this need for
somebody listening to it's like I know I
know I want to I want to ask a question
stop stop stop this permanent wish of
podcast listeners to somehow jump into
the studio and ask a question it's a
good chance that once you are doing your
show in a dialogue that you already have
this dynamic and that's very pleasing to
listeners who somehow think like oh yeah
well that's exactly the question I
wanted to ask and then they feel very
warm and welcome in your dialogue for
some things you might open this up to a
larger group I'm not sure there's a real
limit on how many people people can
enjoy on by listening to them I would
say five maybe but really depends on the
people in the group I've seen groups who
are really structured never talk into
each other somehow know that it is
very complicated to remember names and
somehow you know do this
Oh Tom what would you say about this you
know Cara have you thought this through
if you are helping the audience by
inserting cues or you just have the
blessing of totally different voices
that are easy to recall that might work
but always think about people listening
to it and if everybody is just talking
about each other all the time at the
same time this can become a train wreck
pretty soon how much time is left 20
minutes yes so another question is
publishing cycles how much do you
actually need to talk and also the
question of how long the podcast is
actually haven't prepared a slide for
this but talking about this it really
depends
some people think short podcasts are
good because people don't have the
attention span to follow a long podcast
I can tell you from my experience the
only requests I ever had was oh my god
you could have talked to another hour
about this that wasn't detailed enough
podcasts are for details podcasts are to
get into stuff really really really down
to the core and that's what why people
are listening to it so don't think so
much about the length you can stop them
you can rewind them you can listen to
them again and if you don't like it you
can skip at chapter marks you can use
all these tools don't think about the
lengths that doesn't mean you have to
repeat the same stuff over and over
again and just talk about the same thing
all the time
that's not helpful but the the length
itself is not so important but might be
more important is the the cycles what
can you do you can do a daily podcast oh
my god this is a lot of work I want you
don't do it don't do it
unless you are really into the
podcasting stuff you have your setup
ready your life can accommodate an hour
every day or more to support this this
is probably only for professional
podcasters but it's also only for
content that really changes on a daily
basis and needs commenting on a daily
basis because otherwise you just run out
of topics and will repeat yourself much
more helpful and probably a good start
for anything that is related to news
ongoing events things that change
regularly is the weekly period because
in a week we think about things in week
terms we think about like what happened
last week Oh
in a week things can change and so on
people remember weekdays and know when
your podcast is supposed to come out so
a lot of very helpful things in terms of
work it's still a lot of work weekly
podcasts are a lot of work I always
wanted to have the what fortnightly on
my slides so now is the time every two
weeks actually works pretty good for a
lot of things that's something I could
recommend if you are really looking for
something that really has the regular
podcast stamp on it but you are still
working towards the capability of doing
on a regular basis every two weeks is
good for both producers and consumers of
content works well you always have a
free week where there is nothing which
is a relief and same goes for people
listening to it actually people who
somehow are still in the process of come
to know you understand what this is
about
they can drop out for a week they could
even drop out for two weeks but it's
always possible to follow up on what you
are delivering again the
periodic question is much more
interesting than the length of the
podcast you can have like double lengths
but only two weeks and it works better
than half of it every week three weeks
also fine very good for stuff that is
somehow eternal content you know
interviews about topics that you can
listen to in five years from now and
they are still valid you know like how
the railway works or what the history of
the Romans were that's not going to
change so soon and you can increase this
to monthly and I think that's the end
don't do a podcast that is you know
taking longer than a month to come out
on a regular basis but you can also do a
podcast whenever you feel like so
irregular podcasting is also fine once
people are interested in it and in the
end doesn't really matter so if you
prepare your podcast there probably two
rules you could follow first rule is do
not prepare over-prepared podcasts are
sometimes very problematic because you
tend to know everything in advance and
then you are coming up with questions
just to somehow you know make this
specific answer you're looking for to
come out that's super boring super
boring for everybody don't do it another
way to approach is prepare a lot but
this more applies to self where you are
somehow translating information that has
come out if you are reading the news for
your audience following a new cycle
making your own opinion really trying to
understand what happened then it's
really very important to really prepare
because once you start talking and you
don't really know what was happening
before that's where it really becomes
problematic for everybody so in general
there's this Golden Rule of some so you
have to find your
yeah also important especially because
as I said before podcasts are such a
personal thing do interact with your
audience if the audience is willing to
interact with you feed from feedback
everything you get is valuable things
that were good things that were bad what
you could also do because this is really
the the thing that that will keep up
your motivation in the long run you
might be motivated to do things without
you know you don't care who's listening
to it because you just wanted to say it
but at a certain point the motivation is
going to change and then you really have
to find a way to interact so except the
commenting culture as it is it's usually
much better in the podcast world it's
not like in blogs because people
actually have to listen to what you say
because they before they can comment if
they comment without listening to you
you will and everybody else will
immediately notice that this was
happening so you don't care so I would
say the troll quota in podcast Commons
is miniscule compared to the written web
it's fascinating
I'm not saying there are no trolls they
are but right now the situation is much
better I got lots of feedback from
podcasts who were on like problematic
issues gender equality feminism and so
on if you do a blog on feminism oh boy
you know you hate the Internet if you do
a podcast on it it's different it's
really really different the commenting
culture is much better after a while you
might to consider to do it life that
doesn't make sense for all the podcasts
but if you are sending a podcast live
and you're capable of doing this then
you will attract people into a live chat
for instance
and you get feedback in real-time that's
more work so only do it once everything
else is set but it can be helpful to
really find out who are your core
contributors and with only the people
themselves that you find that you can
ask for favors or get into a dialogue
with after on it's helpful and every now
and then if your podcast has been kind
of popular do it on stage also very
satisfying thing to do
I've done it many times now and I can't
stop doing it so at the end some hints
on what technology you need and you're
always hear like oh my god audio that's
so complicated and so expensive and you
can do so many things wrong that's true
here is a guide to fast success first of
all you need a microphone and I can only
recommend headsets loud speakers
headphones and microphone in combination
it's just the best why first of all very
compact you don't need a stand you know
there's no table where the microphone
erupts where you start tapping on it and
these things you always have this
constant distance to the microphone
which is especially good if you talk to
people who have no experiences with
microphones and don't know that makes a
huge difference how far away you are
from your microphone so the good
handsets are expensive buy them anyway
because if you buy cheap you pay you
know you buy three times this is the
model I'm using you don't have to do it
it's the biodynamic dt2 97 there are
other options but the good stuff is
always in the same financial ballpark
alright then you need a mixer because
you want to you know
listen to what you say and in case you
wondered why you need to have a
headphone well first of all think about
intros jingles audio you want to play
back to everybody in the situation and
comment on so headphones are Apfel
anyway but also you can have very
relaxed positions you can like sit
meters or yards away from each other how
you say and you can still talk in a calm
voice also it's a much more intimate
experience for everybody
people just come down so headphones are
fine but you need a mixer to mix all
this together to create the signals
recorders this has been a nightmare
until recently because how to wire
everything happened in the recording and
the cabling and so on there's so many
things you can do wrong but there is
help zoom has finally delivered a device
that everybody wants it's the L 12 life
track it's a mixer it's a recorder it's
very good for life setups too and it's a
mostly digital and you can still use it
as an audio interface at the same time
so you get mixing recording and delivery
to a computer that you might need in one
box and that's it that's what you need
for a professional produce podcast these
days there are other options available
and if you want to like walk around and
be more mobile you will probably need
other looked for other options but yeah
actually there is a step 3 because
there's added value to record your stuff
on the computer while you do it
you can still use this recorder you know
there's an SD card you put the files on
your computer everything is fine but for
more capable environment recording to a
professional audio software has its
values and there is an interesting
solution of course from Germany it's
built on the American digital audio
workstation Reaper which is super fast
super cheap and very ugly to use incomes
would kasha which is a system that
somehow skins the system its
functionality
removes all the crap you don't need as a
podcaster so turns a digital audio
workstation meant for creating music
into an audio workstation meant for
creating podcasts you can do life
chapter marks it renders your stuff
perfectly automatically adjusts loudness
levels and so on it's an amazing box of
stuff it comes for free so you bust just
by Reaper for few bucks and you add
ultra and you're set if you want to do
publishing of course I have to now
recommend our own project there other
solutions but not so many and not so
good first of all the pot love team has
produced the pot love publisher actually
a plugin for WordPress so for many
people this is already an environment
they might already use that's readily
available and widespread and many people
know how to deal with its
insufficiencies so with potluck
publisher you get an integrated solution
or you can just pour your podcast in
produces the feet and everything has
detailed analytics other things it's
very nice we have also added the
subscribe button which makes subscribing
to podcasts easier for people so
whenever you put up this button people
can just press a button select the
podcast client they want to use and then
if you select it you can automatically
open
the podcast app or you can copy the URL
whatever you want and of course you can
customize this button to look like you
want certain styles is multilingual and
so on so that works fine it's in
widespread use already best of all
there's a web player that comes with it
so not only do you publish your podcast
to podcast clients and your feet know
you can publish it on the web it's a
full-blown player that works really nice
and has a lot of very sophisticated
features including coming soon
transcripts that are actually moving
while you're listening to it and it's
super awesome and the future so that
more or less concludes what I have to
convey to you was my personal podcast
for you and if you have some questions
I'm happy to take them with microphone
[Applause]
do it oh yeah there's a microphone it's
being handed around hello do you have
any advice for recording podcasts on
location at conferences events EMF etc
recording but like like here ya get a
caravan that's helpful because then you
have seats on the table that's how I do
it is that what the kind of us can can
you take the microphone again sorry I
work for a publisher and we do a lot of
conferences and events and what we're
trying to do is speak to people after
they've presented a paper and then grab
them for 15 minutes before they then go
off and do their own thing the problem
that we've got is quite often there's
background noise there's portability of
equipment there's mixing after the event
that you think oh my god I wish we'd
managed to isolate that and so on so any
advice really well also I think the
background noise is usually not a big
problem once you work with headphones
so that's especially where headphones
will come in and doing that so I'm going
to do that you already do that I know we
haven't been songs to implement that
yeah so some people like these clip-on
microphones and think especially if
there's a camera think that headphones
look ugly I don't think so and you know
if that's your problem you won't be able
to produce something if you have a
headset I think your said I've done this
it works well the main problem is the
organizational part how do you get these
people in time so you need a true real
planning and logistics to have everybody
show up at the right time and then you
know know to talk to and so on that's
like there many aspects we can talk
after the talk over there
hello I was just wondering you were
talking about audience like community on
the web and responding to comments and
so on
how many platforms on the web would you
want to use to stay in touch with your
audience I mean you were saying
WordPress when you just stick it to
stick with WordPress or would it be good
to have a I mean I don't particularly
want to do a blog
I don't yeah so I think it's a matter of
personal taste I try to get everybody to
comment on my own blog for various
reasons because that's like where you
can find all the show notes and you know
the transcripts and everything so people
are actually at the right place where
there is the the primary information of
course I get also a lot of feedback on
Twitter
I like Twitter because I think the
follow follow our model works really
well for podcasters and I personally
hate Facebook so I don't use it thank
you thanks my talk so it does
monetization work okay with this model
because you don't let's pick up it sorry
um because you don't have adverts really
in in podcast so much money in this
slide because I don't think it should be
the most important thing hmm again you
know I do agree but but I think that's
one reason why people might go to like
Spotify or something you know yeah so
it's a cultural thing in America and as
far as I know also partly in the UK
people think that ads are the primary
way to go I don't think so I don't like
ads because they get in in the way they
are somehow interfering with my message
in my voice and that's something I don't
want you know so it's a personal
preference of mine
it is also possible to do it without
especially because you have this very or
you are capable of establishing a very
strong relationship with your community
and when you have a very specific topic
you are talking about that people find
valuable they will be more than willing
to support you financially on a direct
way you could choose to go to one of
those funding platforms they have their
problems as well I think they take still
a bit too much of the money but there
might be helpful
reaching out it's something I don't use
as well these days
you can find your model but I think it's
always worth thinking about not doing
what that's in the first place and only
if you don't see any other solution and
maybe yeah so y'all just worry about
like you know just how how people make
money so it's really about building the
community too so so so so for people
doing it professionally they they build
a very strong community to that then
supports them directly I'm not sure I
got the question what's I'm it's it it's
not really a question it's just
something you you know sort of like
saying instead of going on video so that
you can share out your your-your-your
more building a strong community alright
so how much time we're running out of
time so maybe last question thanks here
just a very quick question there is it
it strikes me that podcasts are
primarily a you know a reflective medium
they're great for talking about issues
and sharing information around
communities but what about intervening
in issues so I'm interested in setting
up a podcast that maybe is able to
intervene in is faster moving is there
are all the podcasts in in that kind of
sphere
I'm not sure I got your question right
well how can a podcast intervene if so
if you've got a fast-moving political
situation there's lots going on now I
mean yeah I think the podcasts are the
place for debate because they take their
time and they can provide the necessary
context to understand it I'm listening
to the Romaniacs podcast because that's
the only place where I think people are
actually talking about the right things
when it comes to Braxton there's no
other source I found where people are
not totally out of their mind and same
goes for for many other things so that's
where I think you don't really have to
you know be in the same speed with the
news flow it's actually worse of taking
a break resting on a few issues and you
know build more understanding and
provide more insight into you know why
is this happening has this happened
before what can happen in the future I
think it's this context and it's also
the opinion people are actually looking
for they don't necessarily have to agree
with everything you say but they just
like happen to find people who actually
have an opinion you know that's not just
formed by media bias and other things
and that's where podcasts are really
helpful all right so if you have more
questions I'm happy to take them outside
thanks for listening
[Applause]
[Music]
you