[Music]
hey everyone
happy saturday morning thanks for waking
up early
all right so today we're going to talk
about cyber security in the
aviation industry and if you're
expecting this to be a presentation on
hacking airplanes i am sorry to
disappoint you
well we'll cover a little bit of
background information but it's really
going to be more on the uh
overall posture of the cybersecurity
ecosystem
in the aviation industry
so of course i have my disclaimer
because i like what i do
and i want to keep presenting at
conferences like b-sides so none of this
is endorsed by or sponsored by any
producer
uh employers that i have because i still
like working for them and it's an
overall
reflection of my experiences in the
aviation cyber security industry
most importantly everything that i found
you can find on the open internet
nothing
is a proprietary and i'm a huge advocate
of showing your references
so i will give all of that at the end of
this presentation
the little qr code is i would love your
feedback it's for a quick survey i have
if this was what you expected or if
there's any topics that
i didn't cover that you'd like to hear
in future presentations so one of
the times i gave this presentation
someone wanted more
information on the uh
sort of like the the certification
process
so i was able to uh try to dig out some
more information to answer more
questions
all right so just a little bit about me
um so you know i'm not full of uh
fud and i'm not making all of this up
but about
12 years ago i began as a software
developer
by degree that wasn't a huge fan of
coding all the time it doesn't spark joy
but i love interacting with people so
when i'm not doing cyber security i'm
a curler by trade so that would be
awesome to keep doing again once the
pandemic is done
i was super fortunate that when i
started my career out of college i was
able to work on a bunch of
transportation related programs so i
worked on a
air commander control system i worked on
a gps system used by aircraft and
eventually found my way to uh
avionics where i got to work on an
in-flight entertainment system which was
really cool
so i focused on the uh the crew terminal
and its functionality specifically for
the ife system
and i got very lucky again that i was at
the right place at the right
time where i found the cyber security
product uh
director and was able to make a
connection
and since i got into security i just
never looked back so i've been
geeking out for about six years doing
that
all right um
scope so to cover that before i start
talking about anything in specifics i
want to just frame
the scope of the discussion so we're
going to talk about some regulatory
aspects
the players and components in the
aviation ecosystem
and then i end with some use cases and
experiences i had which is
great so the um
not specific hacking i'm not talking
about hacking on planes because
please don't do that but more of
here's potential use cases that may lead
to vulnerabilities
so for anybody who works in the industry
this is an overview
probably no more than i do or what i'm
going to present so if you have
questions
stick them in discord i'm gonna hope to
to look at things when i can but i know
our moderator is gonna
do an excellent job of pinging me as
well
cyber security regulation
so regulation varies depending on the
location that you're in
and for a supplier manufacturer it's
important because they have to comply
with several
different government agencies
specifically for this presentation i'm
going to focus on
the current u.s regulation but it's very
similar to the eu
and other regulatory authorities so
specifically
for aviation cyber security there are
three key documents
and here come all the fun acronyms and
numbers uh
d o stands for document or document
order and when you get the hard copy
printouts they are these like
big thick books that uh
if you have insomnia they're great for
like bedside reading
and we're going to start with do uh 326
a so airworthiness security process
specification
so why do we need this process when
safety assessments were
initially developed they focused on a
failure
of onboard systems and not failure
caused by a
malicious intent so this process fills
the gaps by defining
security scope for the certification
process for new development
of systems or modification of existing
systems
so in addition to the scope it lists a
long
list of additional requirements
including having a security risk
assessments
and other effective requirements
the next one is do356a
it explains the methods to show
compliance to the profit
processes reference in do326a so for
example
if you're developing a security
architecture what should be your
corresponding measures for that
if there's any assurance guidance for
verification activities like threat
assessments
or what systems should you have logging
enabled so that they're properly
monitoring
your environment so you can be aided in
incident response
lastly there's do-355 so
once the plane is flying how do you
ensure
the cyber security of that aircraft once
it's been handed over to the air
operator
so this uh regulation and document was
really important when i worked at
american airlines this is the one that
the
security team specifically looked at so
it highlights what you should have in
regards to incident response
what personnel roles you need from an
aircraft
information security specialist which is
relatively new
type of role
all right
so cyber security regulation so who
needs to follow
these three documents specifically it's
for
aircraft with special conditions and
what causes an aircraft
to have a special condition
so this is directly from
an faa document that says this airplane
will have a novel or unusual design
feature when compared to the state of
technology envisioned
in the airworthiness standards for
transport category airplanes
these new connectivity capabilities
may result in security vulnerabilities
to the airplane's critical systems for
these design features
the application the applicable
airworthiness regulations
do not contain adequate or appropriate
safety standards for protection and
security
of airplane systems and data networks
against unauthorized access
these special conditions contain the
additional safety standards that the
administrators consider necessary to
establish a level of safety equivalent
to that established by existing
standards
uh very long-winded but in a nutshell
back in the day when these planes were
created
we didn't have these networks and
systems on the planes therefore
this special conditions is going to
cover those gaps
so what types of aircraft have these
special conditions
examples would be like the 787 737 max
a350
anything that has um the newer types of
networking
systems on board so
what do we do for these aircraft we have
something
called an ansp which is an aircraft
network security program
and this ansp is an agreement between
the
air operator and the manufacturers on
how they plan to
secure the aircraft and that's signed
off by your regulatory body which would
be
the faa in the u.s so the ansp
captures um guidance
and so that like if there's any system
modifications or updates they're not
going to negatively err
impact the continuing airworthiness due
to cyber security vulnerabilities
and most often the ansp
is leveraging existing cyber security
frameworks like the nist
cyber security framework and it uses
common standards as well
so the main takeaway from these
documentation
is that its emphasis is on safety of
flight
and framing that in the aspect of cyber
security
so how do we do that by using a defense
in-depth
security approach
all right so who needs to follow these
regulations
there are a lot of players in the
aviation ecosystem
and there's several lists but the one i
like
the most is a compilation from the 2018
us national strategy for aviation
security
and they highlight uh that there are six
a's or six players in the game
and the first one is aircraft so of
course the plane itself
and prior to covid there were over 24
commercial flights daily over the u.s
and the category includes government and
private aircraft in that
figure the next player are the airlines
so what's highlighted in the airline
section is that there are airlines of
multiple sizes covering functional scope
of operations and maintenance
so you want to consider that there are
several different uh enterprise networks
of an airline that span more than just
the aircraft so you may have a separate
passenger system
or a ground system but
that all flowing information my favorite
sentence in regards to the airlines
is how an airline is managed has impact
on its safety and the security of the
aviation ecosystem
every player on the slide has an equal
impact to the ecosystem
none of them is more important than the
others
uh the next one is air lift and when i
first read about this i was like huh
what is that but airless are just the
cargo version
of airlines and even though they don't
have passengers they have
the same stringency of regulation so
just because it's cargo doesn't mean
it's any easier
and more importantly they have an
amazing great economic impact
uh the air international air transport
association
said that the uh world trade by value
of these cargo airlifts is about six
trillion dollars that is being
transported so any impact to them is
huge to the economy
next are airports there's over 44 000
airports globally
and about 19 000 in the us so when you
think of airports you might think of
like the big hubs that you see or maybe
some small regional ones
but they also include package and
package delivery hubs and logistical
airports and logistical airports are
really cool
because uh if you have ever seen them
they're where like aircraft scenes are
filmed for movies or where aircraft our
airlines store aircraft
when they're not being used right now in
addition to the physical
uh airport location itself the entity
that runs the airport is also included
in this category
and that could vary some are privately
owned some are owned by
a city or public authorities so that's
included as well
next is aviation management so that is
your national
or international regulatory body and
they manage the
operation administration of the aviation
ecosystem so of course the faa in the
u.s
eos and europe and there are several
individual
civil uh aviation authorities in other
countries
so that's for the us that would be where
air traffic control would reside
lastly our actors and this group is
categorized as people or entities that
operate maintain
uh or utilize the
aspects of the aviation ecosystem so
this includes
i see it as a very wide catch-all bucket
which i'm not a huge fan of but it
includes
the original equipment manufacturers
also known as oem's
suppliers so like in-flight
entertainment companies or internet
connectivity providers
and contractors so your cleaning crews
your food service suppliers
they also include
[Music]
threat actors in this group which i
don't
i don't think it's fair or insider
threats
because they can exist inside of their
specifically can exist anywhere
inside either of these six groups listed
all right
so now we know how the players fit into
the operational aspects of the aviation
ecosystem
excuse me so now i know who the players
are we know the regulatory background
now i'm going to talk about how the
players fit
into the operational aspects of the
ecosystem i'm not a pilot
so when i was trying to frame the scope
of how i was going to talk about this i
took it as a passenger because most
people can relate to
flying so i'm going to talk about in
regards to what happens before a flight
during a flight or after a flight
so what a passenger sees barely
scratches the surface
and uh this graphic that i'm showing
right now is courtesy of nasa
and it captures the major components but
just remember that they're framing it
from a government perspective so if
you're like there's something missing uh
that's the reason why
all right so before the flight
before you buy your ticket there's
several activities in place so that you
can reserve your seat
or ship your cargo on an airlift carrier
if we go back to our certification the
aircraft needs to be certified
uh safe to fly by your civil aviation
authority
and you need to have approved staff
to do that so you have your approved
pilots
that know they they do their check
around the aircraft
even when you walk before you walk into
the airport you have your
tsa your transportation security in the
u.s customs and border patrol staff
you have your airport ground crews your
airline gate crews additional flight
crew
that have all been embedded beforehand
then you go to planning
so what staff is needed you need a staff
certified certified to fly that specific
aircraft
how many flights are needed overall what
type of aircraft do you need
for example you're not going to want a
regional jet for a long-haul
international flight
and then you jump into reservations so
what passenger and cargo options are
available to
to offer to the public do you need next
day delivery
do you need full uh internet
connectivity on those long haul flights
and what locations are you gonna offer
that at
next you have what happens in the
ecosystem during your flight
so as your amazon prime package spends
so many hours
on the aircraft or you're sitting in
your seat
there's even more going on behind the
scenes you have your
avionics system that's active on the
aircraft
you have your cabin functionality which
either is
available to the passenger or to the
clerk to the crew
so a good example i like to give from a
a crew standpoint
is that weather is very important so you
want to make sure weather information
uh is being accurately
transmitted to the aircraft so that the
flight crew can make accurate decisions
on the best course of travel and then
you have your air traffic management
that's providing
navigation information
lastly you have after your flight so
once you land there's still
a lot going on once you're on the ground
so your plane gets checked again
by the pilot uh they may need to call
the ground crew or the ground crew does
their own checks to
say that there needs to be maintenance
you want to make sure your bags get
routed
to either the baggage claim if you're
done with your journey or to
the next flight that you're going on and
then there's information
regarding the flights themselves so are
you
going to run to the other end of the
airport because your next flight is in
the other terminal
and then there's even uh continued comms
with
ground systems so if you put everything
i said together
that is the operational aspects of the
aviation ecosystem
awesome now we have to secure all of
this
what is aviation cyber security
so it's every single system related to
the functions that i previously
referenced
so now i'm going to speak about the
experiences i've had
in the industry so i was on a
aviation cyber security team when i
worked for american airlines and then
panasonic avionics so their point of
view is from a third-party supplier
here is another nifty graphic that i
really like it's from
the american institute of aeronautics
and astronautics
and in 2013 they developed a white paper
entitled a framework for
aviation cyber security and they had a
section that references
that aviation and the evolution of
information
uh and communications technology
and what it highlighted was that once
the plane was a closed system
and then due to
events in industry it expanded based off
of demand
and i'll give more specifics on that
later in my presentation
and if you're thinking oh i want to read
this paper don't worry
i have everything referenced at the end
of my presentation with links
so that you can find it later if you
want to read up on that
more importantly i have this
presentation
in pdf format on my website so you can
go to
olivia stella.com if you want to get a
copy of that
all right
so now that you're thinking about
securing all this data
you have to do it for each part of the
system and it's a lot
and you can't do it by yourself no
matter how big of a company you are
and more importantly you're dependent on
others in the ecosystem
and you're under the watchful eye of
your government jurisdiction
so i'm going to start with the focus
from the airplane
because that was my initial point of
entry into the ecosystem
so the ecosystem employee experience
versus the passenger experience
is a little bit different so when you
think of onboard systems
there's the native ones like the
avionics
then there's your third-party systems
like your passenger internet
connectivity in the internet
uh the entertainment systems so
how do we uh talk to the rest of the
world via these systems well
ground communication is different than
connectivity in flight so if you think
about your
your wi-fi and your cellular versus your
satcom
you're just and then you have to support
all the infrastructure for these
communication systems
then you have your external environment
the systems
that support that so if you're thinking
from
an airport perspective you'd have your
ticket kiosks your baggage claim systems
and any on-site
maintenance systems if you go another
level removed you can think of all the
uh
iot internet of things devices and
systems
that your third-party companies are
using so for instance the catering crew
needs to know how many meals
for this specific flight your cleaning
crew
if you're doing a wide body aircraft
you're probably going to need
maybe two to three times as many people
as an air body aircraft
and they could be all sharing the same
infrastructure depending on how it's
set up within the airport
so how do you secure all the data for
each parts of those systems
those were the slides the past slides i
referenced was the world i was living in
when i was working at the airline
and it's a really interesting
problem when you think about it how to
keep everything secure
so uh before i jump into more specific
aspects of aviation cyber security
i want to spend a little time focusing
on
the aircraft when i gave this
presentation at a pass conference
people were like where's my plane
information i
wanna have the plan please don't do that
but i will give you a little bit of
background of how
the data domains on the aircraft are
split up
and what exactly exists
so this graphic is courtesy of connected
aviation today
and they list the domains uh in
criticality to safety of flight so
remember we're referencing safety of
flight again
so remember safety of flight and data
security
so the first domain is the aircraft
control domain this is the
most critical to safety operation of the
aircraft
including the flight control
applications and core cabin functions
next is the airline information services
domain or the aisd
more acronyms and
one of the best descriptions that i
found for that was from
iko's 2014 uh description saying that
it provides services and
interconnectivity to the other domains
while creating a another security permit
permit
it's too early for a saturday
also the isd can be categorized into two
subdomains so there's an
administrative subdomain and there's a
passenger
support sub-domain so the passengers
support one
of course supports uh pastor systems
and then the administrative sub-domain
includes
airline administrative information to
the flight deck
and the cabin the third one
is the one that you would be most
familiar with when you are flying
yourself so that would be the passenger
information
and entertainment services domain or
pi's d as
a lot of people call it and it's the
most
dynamic in regards to functionality
because we need to keep up
with the devices that you're bringing on
the plane so like how
apple just announced their new their new
cell phones if they had any new
functionality
you may need to have a ife system that
could interact with it
i doubt there's new functionality
but this includes any live
connectivity it could also include like
if you have one
if you're in happened to be in business
class and you have a fancy seat it could
be the seat actuators
um or the passenger message messaging
systems
all right so this is one of the reasons
why i really love
the aviation industry in regards to
cyber security
so we understand the rules that came
from all these awesome
regulatory books and i gave a highlight
of the ecosystem
and its data domains so how do we treat
this
unique ecosystem is it really i.t
information technology or is it more of
ot
operational technology when i think of
an ot
environment i see electrical grids water
treatment plants nuclear power plants
facilities that if there were a failure
there would be a negative impact to the
safety of human life
and if you happen to be an ot
professional sweet i am not an expert
hit me up on discord afterwards if
there's any other details you have
because i'd be really interested in
finding that out
so does that mean the aircraft is
industrial control system
uh not exactly but it's not your
traditional it system either due to the
safety of flight aspect
more of our environment
became open in regards to detecting
connectivity and
the more that these two areas uh
converge it just blurs in the middle so
from the avionic aspects of the aircraft
um
systems in the aircraft control domain
could be comparable to ot scada like
software if something goes wrong
there would be a high risk to loss of
life
similar to like a nuclear plant disaster
but if you think about the
passenger devices and the the pi's
domain
that's your i.t aspect with the latest
and greatest tech and software
that's um potentially more vulnerable
than your ot software so living
in that fuzzy gray area where it ot
collide is is really unique
and you don't see too much like that
and i like to phrase it as uh we're an
industrial control system
in a commercial environment with ot like
regulations and it needs from passengers
and the business so sometimes it's clear
as mud but it really keeps your uh
your day job very interesting
and if you're like most people that
originated from
the it world ics could be relatively new
to you
and if you want to learn about it
there's some cool free web-based
trainings brought to you by
dhs and it's up to you
if you want to give them your
information because i think you have to
give like an email address and your
your first and last name but you give
your info and you get the
a lot of cool information from these
classes
all right this is my favorite part of
the presentation that i lovingly like to
call
aviation unicorns so i wanted to provide
a few unique use cases that i have seen
and or experienced when i was in
industry that sets uh
aviation apart from typical i.t and ot
environments
software patching and upgrades back when
i worked at panasonic this is something
i personally experienced so
it was very important to have
a good communication path with your
customers
for example if we needed to get
either a patch out or a software upgrade
and it
didn't matter if it was security related
the teams were always
we'd go into major crunch if we had to
to make sure the software was properly
tested
and bundled in the appropriate way that
it could be handed to the customer in
less than a day
if we needed to yay for processes
because we were able to
recreate all of our stringent guidelines
and make sure that the software was in
the right state when it was released
so we'd hand over the soft software to
the customer
and the customer owns the system so we
have no control
over when it would get updated
because we don't own the aircraft and
every airline is different
so how did we overcome that uniqueness
in our industry you need to have great
communication
and there's so many segments in the
supply chain
being able to know who you need to
involve is very important
so if you compare that to it
and you think of your cell phone again
software updates get pushed
and eventually your phone's gonna get
locked
if you don't upgrade we all see that we
all say yeah we agree
to whatever updates they're gonna do you
don't want that to happen on your
aircraft
especially in an ot environment what's
nice is that operators
have the luxury to make updates based
off of recommendations of the
manufacturer
and they have compensating controls in
place too
to say you know what if we're not going
to do this update
we have controls xyz in place until we
can do this update
so if if it was that closed environment
that has no internet connectivity
it might be okay to wait to do that type
of an update but more importantly the
system owner
has that option so how do we
combat against that in this unique
situation
i'm going to refer to defense in depth
again
so for instance the hardware
only allows certain software packages to
be loaded to it it's it's looking for
that
the software is signed and uh roots of
trust exist
more importantly the uh aircraft
is an embedded system it's not an open
operating system that's caught off the
shelf
the hardware is more robust as well in
that if
you see that it's running lennox or what
a lennox or some
type of common operating system it
really is not it's severely stripped
down
and for example the software can only be
loaded
via an official manual push to
the aircraft subcomponent so there's a
lot of different
items in place to make sure that there's
additional checks
all right the ever expanding attack
surface
since uh iot
technology has been incorporated
it's drastically changed our attack
surface because the
aircraft was designed to be a closed
system initially but due to its long
life span
new technology continues to be added we
want that new functionality
uh when we fly and the moment we added
satcom
and internet connectivity everything
exploded
as we've seen through hacking claims
and the first time i learned
about how interesting iot was i was
actually at a conference
and the speaker was talking about a
wi-fi
water kettle and i am an avid tea
drinker as i've been holding my mug the
whole time
and the wi-fi kettle and similar devices
are just an unsecure
entry vector into your home network and
luckily when you compare that back to
the
aircraft it's an embed system with
defense in depth and there are
several safeguards so when you think of
iot it's not really comparing it
apples to apples so for example
uh experience i had the usb ports on the
aircraft
though you may see a lot of them several
of them have been
they've had wires clipped in it so that
it's power only
the data's physically been turned off
via that wire clipping
so the main point i want to make for
this one is just that
iot is something that the industry
really cares about
it's on their radar and they know that
they're going to have to increase their
scope to accommodate that and
back when i i worked at american
the scope of our team was aviation cyber
security and
internet of things technology so they
were looking at that
uh software patching and upgrades
so when i talked about this topic it was
interesting i got called out in person
on stage
because someone cut me off early so
the great thing about virtual
conferences is that i get to talk about
it first
and that doesn't happen but it's an
awesome segue
into a potential future state of what's
being discussed which are
over-the-air updates so depending on the
software
that you're trying to update and load it
could take minutes to hours
to load an update and in
in the industry when a plane isn't
flying because it's either out of
service or you're doing updates or
maintenance
uh that's bad because you're not flying
you're not transporting passengers
so the thought process was if a car can
do an over-the-air update why not a
plane
well there are multiple reasons
first there are initial talks that if
this were to happen it would be
in the pi's d space so the passenger
domain space
you definitely do not want to do this on
an avionics or
a critical system in the aircraft
control domain
while in flight because there are
specific items listed that you need to
have
testing and verification that the
software was loaded correctly
it's signed off on it's it's not taken
lightly at all
that you would want to do that over the
air
but if you compare that to your flight
entertainment system if it doesn't
update properly
the system could be shut down the
unfortunate that the passengers don't
get to use the system
uh whether it be purchasing items or
whatnot
but depending on the airline's risk
tolerance that may or may not be okay
so it's it's up to uh the business case
of of that airline in that specific
instance
so for instance how much revenue are you
willing to lose
more robust system that's backwards
compatible and that can fail over
gracefully
if the update happens to not work so all
of those things
are items to think about but
once it becomes successful in one
aircraft a proof of concept
there i i see that it's probably going
to creep
into the other domains but luckily
we have the stringent safety standards
and anything that happens in the
aviation industry does not happen
overnight it is
very very slow and there's a lot of
steps in between to make sure that items
are properly vetted
and all of the players i mentioned in
the aviation ecosystem
get to speak on whether or not they
they agree with that because we all work
together with our suppliers
our oems so it's
something to be aware of and to
to i'm i try to keep an open mind
but i wouldn't be afraid of
jumping on a plane right now and having
those types of updates be a concern
all right so how do you deal with all
these awesome aviation unicorns
that uh spin out spit out
vulnerabilities and threats as opposed
to awesome pretty
rainbows and it's it's something simple
that people may not think about but it's
just having
constant communication with common goals
so
one of the one of the reasons i loved
working in that industry and it was one
of the hardest things
to step back was that every security
team
regardless of what organization you're
in has the same goal
we care about the the safety the privacy
and the security of our passengers
and their data when they're traveling
with us so back
i was talking on a daily basis with my
competitors
with my manufacturers and suppliers to
make sure that
we were all in the loop when it came to
current and future threats and what we
could do
to improve processes best practices
anything
in our space and i i thought it was
unique
to be an environment where you're
working with your competitors and it's
a non-compute type of atmosphere so if
you're lucky enough to be in that type
of environment too
it's it's really cool and
it makes perfect sense but when you
think about it at the end of the day an
attack or threat to one
player in the ecosystem is an impact to
everybody
so how is that done it's through
information sharing
and there are great organizations that
already exist
that allow this to happen so the
aviation isac
is one of my favorites it's the
information sharing and analysis center
and then there's also iota like who i
referenced earlier
so through those organizations and
individual companies
the industry is just growing to to
better engage
the research community and this is one i
really like to harp on
with my counterparts in when i was back
in the industry
because more importantly we need to do
better there
has been signs of progress so there's a
lot more aviation companies that are
offering
bug bounty programs and vulnerability
disclosure programs um
for those who attended defcon i
i took a break from hacker summer camp
this uh this past summer
but we're seeing more engagement so when
the
aviation village now aerospace village
came up
that was a great step forward um
but the flip side too from the industry
standpoint is
testing on an aircraft is is a common
concern and
we know that testing on aircraft
shouldn't happen because it's not
safe but doing nothing is also not
acceptable
so how can we be curious while being
safe
and supporting both sides
back to you to goodall regulation and i
think it is specifically
uh 355. you need to prove that systems
are secure
and testing is one way of validation so
all the parties need to work together
and i'm looking forward to
coming back to the aerospace village as
a
potential somewhat neutral third party
uh and and come with my uh research hat
on to see how we can continue to
improve uh the way that we're testing
these systems
uh the other item i like to support a
lot
is that i have a constant issue of
a lack of trained cyber security
professionals and it's in general it
doesn't matter what industry that you're
in
but to make it even more complex is that
you you need a certain specialty to
understand how all this works together
uh in the aviation ecosystem and that in
itself is a unicorn of a person
and in order to to build that up we need
to train the next set of professionals
you just can't say
i i hate the job descriptions where it's
like it's kind of
entry level but we want this experience
but how do you get this experience
there's not a class you can take right
now
for for aviation cyber security that's
um in theory open to the public
so word where do you start off if you're
new
my recommendation if you're really new
is
everything that i mentioned in this
presentation
go back read those articles do your
initial homework
because one thing i've noticed uh back
when i supported
a bug bounty program is that if we had a
researcher
that provided information that said you
know what i found this vulnerability
i know it may not be um applicable
because of so and so standard or we know
you have these safety things in there
but we want to make you aware of this as
it sort of
it makes you look knowledgeable that you
did your homework at first
is one one bit of advice
and with that i'm going to just
prove is in the pudding of all said
references
and once again this is on my website as
well
so don't massively screenshot right now
but i really want to thank everyone for
for attending this presentation on a
saturday morning i know it could be
nice to sleep in and whatnot but i hope
it gave you
a little bit of insight into the world
of aviation cyber security and that it
sparked your interest
i i want to leave you with the feeling
that the aviation industry
really cares about the cyber security
mission and
they want to continue to uh work with
the research community so
keep pinging us please don't have
complaints
and uh more importantly let's keep the
conversation going so uh
the top one's my twitter handle if
you're on discord uh
that's my number for discord uh
i'm not gonna lie i'm i'm on discord
infrequently so ping me on twitter most
of all
or through my website and if you have a
minute or two i'd really appreciate it
if you could give some feedback
via my survey
you