[Music]
wonderful
thank you very much for joining this
talk and good morning
and thank you to josh to all the
volunteers and to everybody that's
making this possible today
i wish that i was there with you in
seattle but i'm located in spain
so i guess this is the the win of the
situation is that we get to meet over
over the internet
and have a conversation and so before we
start to talk about
trust in security culture who am i
and why am i talking to you about this
hi
i'm annie i work as a security culture
manager at outsido
a company that provides authentication
and authorization services for
developers
i also am the chapter lead of wasek
madrid women of security
which is a non-profit that aims to
connect women that work in the cyber
security field and
share trainings networking opportunities
and so on
and you can find me in twitter if you
like to continue the conversation
any questions i will also be in the
discord channel and so as a security
culture manager i work
with people security full time and i'm
really passionate about it
and throughout this time i've done a lot
of research
on different topics like behavioral
economics
influence negotiation
how can we change people's mindset
and so what i'm presenting to you today
is
is like putting all of that research
into
a 50 minute presentation mixing
everything up
and finding the core of the topic
essentially so that's what we'll discuss
today
and before we get started i would like
to ask you
what do you see when you look at this
picture with your infosec
lens i know it's just people essentially
but depending on on your perspective
maybe you see a group of people that
might be insider friends to the company
or just like warner boggles for instance
he might see idiots that just click
keep on clicking on the link over and
over and over again
or maybe you might see conflictive
engineers
that just keep on coding the same
vulnerabilities over and over again
or maybe that don't fix them fast enough
now maybe that's what comes to mind
when you look at this picture bugs
vulnerabilities
human ever just waiting to happen
now let me tell you what i see and
especially after doing
all of this research what i see when i
look at this picture
is opportunity maybe the most
important and the most undertapped
opportunity we have
because is it a ridiculous idea to say
that if we get all of that people to
think
and behave securely then we can make the
internet a safer place
in a scalable way i don't think that's
that's a crazy idea i think it's
i think it's something that we can
achieve if we
if we actually put ourselves into doing
it
now why do we need to essentially take
this opportunity in
and take advantage of this gold mine
that people represent
well if i was with you in seattle in
person
i would ask you to raise your hand if
you think that the cyber security
industry and everything if the internet
is is a safe place if we if everything
is fine
i think it's not so we have bridges all
over the place
security incidents happening all the
time i think we
have a problem that we must fix
and the people side of things is
something that we haven't really
touched too much maybe we have some very
boring and long trainings
but i think that people represent the
goldmine
of opportunity that can really make an
impact
and that could help make the internet
safer it just becomes
a question of how we have an opportunity
we know why we must
take it how do we do it
and so what i'm proposing today then
again it's my perspective
it's a set of ideas that have come from
from a lot of research but it's what
it's it's just a perspective and i love
to share with you
so i would like to explain this with
with an example imagine we have company
full
and we have company bar and company foo
everything is
full so so here the security team
is feared people are afraid of us
we are the naysayers or the police
we just say no all the time they might
be
afraid we might they might feel that we
blame them all the time
they don't care or want to hear anything
about security at all
and whenever we try to do anything or to
maybe put out a process policy
something it feels like fighting an
uphill battle
everything is just very very difficult
and if we have a security incident or an
issue in company foo
then we are not resilient it's
it cost a lot of money to fix
and it's a very dangerous situation
so essentially we don't want to be in
company food
but i would dare to say that there are
many company foods out there
maybe this is how you feel it's a toxic
or
a difficult work environment to be in
and we have company power
company bar is opposite completely
opposite
here we have collaboration and the
security team is seen
we people are not afraid of us they they
engage with us they care about security
and have a secure mindset
they grow and learn about security they
consider
it's it's an important part of their
professional selves
and of their personal lives as well they
want to
learn and engage with us and here
instead of
things being an uphill battle it feels
like going downhill
instead everything is much easier much
simpler
there's less friction and and overall
issues and so maybe in company bar
we will have a security incident there
will be security vulnerabilities for
sure
i'm not saying that this can be
completely eliminated
however in company bar i bet that we
will be more resilient
that we will fix him faster and and
everything will feel better
overall and i would dare to say that
everybody should want to work at company
bar
where security is valued people care
about it
we engage and people engage with us it's
a
it's a much better environment to be in
and if you put these two companies side
by side and if you start to think
at the core of the issue what
differentiates them we can
put that into a single word and that's
trust
because ultimately without trust there
is absolutely no room whatsoever
for collaboration or engagement
and learning there's no room
for for essentially anything that have
anything to happen
in this context people will not
engage with us the right way they won't
care about security
trust is the one thing that changes
company 2
to become company bar now trust
i think it's a it might be a difficult
word for us
a difficult concept because we're used
to think about
zero trust and trust but make sure
that you always verify or every social
engineering attack happens
because people trust too easily
and we may even consider that it's a
fluffy topic
hearts and and rainbows
however trust at the core
it's a skill and it's and it's
actionable
it's measurable and it leads to economic
growth so if you get good at inspiring
trust and being a trustworthy person
then it this ultimately leads to better
results
and there are studies that show that
companies
or organizations that are high trust
environments
get things done three times faster
and a lot cheaper because when there's
trust
between two teams and which into orgs
that everything just happens faster
and everything is just cheaper
financially
and time-wise so we want to get good
at generating trust and
trust at the core if we study it it
starts with each of us
individually with the trust that we have
in ourselves
and then after that it goes to our
relationships
the trust we have with every single one
of our teammates
and everyone else in the in the company
then that goes into the org
and then that leads to market trust and
so
and trust in the society but the one we
care about the most
for this topic and for this area is
relationship trust
and then organizational trust so that's
what we'll talk about today
and let's define it before we go into
the security side of it
let's understand class a little bit
better because then again
it's not a fluffy topic and
and we might we might think that it it
just has to do with kindness and honesty
and integrity
however when it comes to work settings
trust
is a measure of two things character
and competence so on the character side
you have
integrity and you have intent and on the
competent side you have
capabilities and results but let's
explain those two things
more so character the roots
of trust is your integrity and this is
your honesty
your congress is what you say and what
you think
align with what you do the courage you
have to speak up
for what you believe in the right way
and the humility you have to
accept that you made a mistake to learn
from others to accept
other people's ideas then after
integrity you have intent
and this is having a good purpose and
a good motive for doing things having
the right agenda
not not a hidden agenda not not seeking
self um win but seeking to have
a win-win for everybody involved and
generally caring for others and
ultimately we have
our behaviors so our purpose
translates to our motive which goes into
our agenda and then this leads to
what we actually do and we have to think
and do and providing the best for others
and after we have character
you must also have competence because
maybe
you will trust somebody with high
character and trustworthy character
to watch over your pet perhaps but when
it comes to
work we must also showcase capabilities
and results
and on the capability sides we have our
talent whatever comes to us
naturally we also have our attitudes our
growth mindset for example
the skills we have and the fact that
we're always learning drawing
sharing all the knowledge we accumulate
and the style we have and ultimately at
the peak
of the tree of trust we have our results
this is the performance we have
our past our present and an anticipated
performance
and methods that we use to achieve those
results
meaning not stepping on everybody's in
anybody's toes
seeking to have win-win and when it
comes to results it's not just tangible
outcomes but also
learning is a good result supporting
someone else's goals is also a good
result
it's not just a metric so to speak
so we have those two things so and now
we understand that if somebody
has integrity has good intent is a
capable person that also has results
then that is the most trustworthy person
like that you can be
and that leads to our relationships as
well
and this not only this is good for you
overall
in your personal life in your
professional life
these skills will just make you better
and
social skills or soft skills
they don't go outdated so this is just
overall good for you
but it's also good for the security of
the organization
in the domain of culture security
culture
so culture is essentially what people do
when no one is watching
is the behaviors the
values the way that people just
act on a company level so first we have
the company culture
and this is the overall organizational
culture
this is the values of the company the
way
even the way that people dress is part
of the company culture
but within that culture there is always
a security culture
and this is a way that people think
behave
and the way that people react to
security
and this is people in engineering
marketing sales
everybody security is something that
touches
on everyone's everyone's role
essentially
so this if you become if you're a
trustworthy person
and and the security team is a
trustworthy organization
this leads to to a better overall
security culture
and ultimately culture drives behavior
not policies not processes
but the culture of the company is what
actually drives the way
that people act in the organization and
if we want to take that opportunity we
have discussed before
where we want developers to code
securely
we want people not to click on facial
links or report issues
we want people to think and have a
security mindset
it all comes down to culture
because that's what leads or that drives
behaviors
so i really like this explanation about
the different types of security cultures
that a company might have
and and any any company won't have
just a single type of one of these but a
mix
of everything and if we have a tight
control
and an internal focus company we have a
process culture
this is the company that just seeks to
enforce
policies everything is very rigid here
there's
barely no room for innovation or
creativity
here we have everything standardized
everything is a policy and there's not a
lot of room
for collaboration even now we have
tight control but if we focus externally
then we have the compliance culture or
the checklist culture
here we just want to pass audits
essentially
and then again we also have everything
documented and there are many standards
but there's also very little room for
collaboration as well
and and it might feel very
rigid as well if we go
to lose control but we focus externally
we have the autonomy culture
and here the directive is to get results
just one result i call this the shipit
culture
and i think that a lot of a lot of
startups might
might initially have an autonomy culture
when they are
growing and expanding and here people
have a lot of freedom
to essentially innovate and and
decisions are not made in a hierarchical
way but
it's pushed out to everybody and this
can be
a little bit of a chaos in a way when it
comes to security
and then we have when it go to internal
focus and i lose control
we have our trust culture so that's what
we now know what trust
is there is there is this this
we can't have a security culture of
trust and here we focus
on empowering people and on growing
human relations
in a trust culture people are
knowledgeable
they are committed they are accountable
and they they're engaged
they consider that security is part of
their job and part of what they do
and so in this culture this is the the
most
easiest way that we have to scale as an
organization
and to really make all the company more
secure
and ultimately make the internet safer
now the question is how do we generate
a security culture of trust in our
organization
it becomes a question of how again so
this is my my proposal and and what i
what i've come up with after mixing
all of this research i've done that
considers different topics
so in order to have trust i believe that
wimbas have
two pillars on one side the security
organization
in the company is a trustworthy
so we are people-centric we consider
that people represent this
opportunity that we want to take and we
put a lot of effort
into building that layer
in our program we seek to have change
through influence rather than enforcing
something
enforcing a policy or
mandating people to change their mindset
we influence them instead
we seek mutual benefit so we don't just
consider security
but we want everybody to win and
everybody to achieve their goals
and so that's on one side and on the
other side we have our company
allies everybody in the company
becomes a security ally and they are
knowledgeable
so they know about security between
their
within their needs and their
domain they are committed they're
engaged with us
and they feel responsible for security
i believe this is what we we can
consider having that security mindset
that we wish we had a little bit more of
so we have these two pillars
how do we build them so we want to have
a security
culture of trust then each party must
make
trust deposits so i'd like to say it
this way
essentially imagine that you have this
trust account in your organization
and every time you behave in a
trustworthy manner or you
influence someone or maybe a developer
considers security or
somebody reports a fission link we make
trust deposits
essentially now if you're a leader in
the organization
and you have a a bigger sphere of
influence
then you can make larger deposits but
that doesn't mean that individual
contributors
and or anybody essentially can help this
to happen
then again trust starts with each of us
so we want to make as many deposits as
we can
and as as as constantly as possible
and here are some ideas how we can do
that
on our side and if you want to change
the world we can start with ourselves
so first is the concept of win-win
mindset
so here we consider
essentially the security teams considers
the goals
of everybody else in the company so for
instance we want to help
sales sell more in a secure way we want
engineers to be able to ship
more ship better ship faster
securely we want marketing to be able to
do their job
and in a secure way so that means that
we consider other people's in other
works
goals and priorities as well
we don't just consider security and we
think that everything must be secure
without considering the needs
the constraints the risks
of everyone else in the work as well
we seek everybody to win win
essentially this acknowledges the fact
that
between any company we're all part of
the same team
maybe we play defense and everybody and
someone else plays a goalie
but we all want we all have the same
goal
we should all seek to win together as
much as possible
so shifting our mindset for just
considering security and security at all
costs
to a win-win mindset then after that
we must i believe have strong customer
service
principles so whenever somebody
in any company whenever somebody has
a question or like how do i
enable mfa how do i report a phishing
email
how do i get a threat model or a risk
assessment or report a vulnerability
having a good customer service is key
for the engagement that we need and so
these principles
are are absolutely key for to have a
good service
first is approachability how is it
how is it decision to contact the
security team
do we have an email or a ticketing
system
a channeling slack can people send me a
direct message maybe
with that scale what's the easiest way i
can
i can do to help people reach out to me
what's our turnout voice do we sound
or do we sound like we want to help them
or are we we don't we we hide
from the requests for instance and
what's our reputation
so for instance if we are a security
team and we don't
we don't participate in company-wide
activities
or people don't see us in the office
in the slack channels we have no
disability
and the reputation that we have is is
negative
like the naysayers or the police and
this
makes us less approachable for instance
somebody
might feel concerned or afraid to reach
out to us
but we can improve that after we are
approachable then we must show
interest in the in the query and in the
customer so we create a safe space for
the user
this means that no matter the question
that's being asked
no matter anything at all we show
empathy and we show that we care
and then after that we actively listen
so
this is listening or reading
the query to understand not to reply
but just to understand the situation the
problem
what's happening not interrupting
the the person when they're talking and
paying attention to what the user
doesn't say
so sometimes they sure might not express
themselves the right way and they and we
might see something
that they're not saying and then
interviewing so asking questions to
clarify
but not in an accusatory manner and here
this
this is a lesson that i had to learn and
i sort of learned the hard way
i used to ask why do people a lot
because i believe in
that that we must always do things
for a reason so why do we have to do
this
and not that for instance however that
why in general it makes people
feel accused so we can shift
something like why did you do this to
what caused this to happen how did this
happen
shifting what from why to what or how
can really make a difference and i
i invite you to try it out maybe with a
friend
your family of anybody
try not using why use it what or how
instead
and the conversation will likely be more
fluid
and and feel better on both sides
then answering so we always thank people
for reaching out to us
some people it might be hard then again
we might
feel a little bit intimidating maybe
that person
used to have had a bad experience before
so we make them feel good we thank them
we praise them for contacting the
security team
and this then again this is another tip
that i
strongly encourage you to try remove
no problem and you're welcome and change
that
for any time habit of help
and things like that things that show
that you are genuinely happy
for helping the person instead of making
it look like you did them a favor
or that they were actually bothering you
no
make it look that you are happy to help
so this
i i invite you to try it out as well and
then follow it up
so we have our our slas
we keep them and if we set when we're
going to do something by
extant we do it or we manage
that expectation so we have customer
service
and principles and we have an excellent
customer service
then we have communication which is the
key
theme overall first we communicate
with touch and with empathy not with
blame
or not without caring we genuinely care
for the person
and we can communicate as tactfully as
we can
we keep our commitments so then again
we said we're going to do something we
do it
we set up a reminder anything we need
but we do it when we said we were going
to do or we manage
the expectation we created explaining
why i think this is absolutely key
to gain adoption because
people might not understand why they
need to follow
a control process a policy so explain
why does it exist what problem is it
solving
why should they do it then they will
have
a far better understanding of the
situation
and they will adopt it faster and they
will care
more about it clarifying expectations
so if we expect developers to follow
the secure coding guidelines then we get
an agreement
from their leadership that this is
what's going to happen
so we clarify expectations on both sides
if they want us to do something we
clarify that as well
accountability is also key so this means
that we keep
people accountable for the expectations
and the commitments
that were generated that were approved
so so this is something that that we
must do as well
and we keep ourselves accountable and my
personal favorite is no fear
knows uncertainty and no doubt i
feel that historically
security has always been something that
has been sold
to prevent something really bad from
happening
and for some people this can be very
scary and
for instance in trainings we can remove
all of that fear
all of that doubt and change that for
commitment for why in a
in a in a careful way not to make
anybody scared but just to understand
the situation
so no fear no thought essentially
and this is this directs the way
that we communicate within ourselves
and with everyone else in the company as
well
and this vulnerability so this is not
related to technical vulnerabilities
this is personal vulnerability for
instance
a lot of people especially non-technical
people
might feel that the security team is
absolutely
perfect and we don't make any mistakes
we never fall
for a scam or for everything we code
is secure 100 of the time
we might have that reputation of
maybe a little bit of perfection if we
want to call it that way
so if we allow ourselves to say hi
i made a mistake now or when i was
starting for instance
this can be key to help people up and up
with us
so the other day we had an event in the
company i work at
and i told the company that i had almost
had a security incident
back in the quarantine and i told this
story
with a bunch of memes people laughed
about it
and then after i finished that talk a
lot of people came to me and said hi
i made a mistake hi i almost got scammed
in the mall the other day
what should i do my
wife gave my credit card details to a
scammer
what should i do and so a lot of people
allow themselves to feel vulnerable with
me
because i took that initial step
and that made me look and everyone else
in the team as well
made us look more approachable and we
need to create that sense that that safe
space
because sometimes falling for a phishing
scam
coding or vulnerability or any any
security situation that might happen
can be just essentially a very stressful
experience
so then again if we allow ourselves to
be vulnerable
we help people feel a lot safer as well
and ultimately all of this
comes down to relationships empathy
and caring for everybody in their
organization
caring for everybody to have not only
a safe experience online for their
personal lives
but also that their actions lead
to a more safer space for our companies
as well
so that's on theirs on our side what
about
their side how do we help them
become the allies we need to have this
culture of trust
and the core of the matter is changing
the behavior
now you will have in your company you
likely already have allies
that care about security that know about
it are committed and engaged but maybe a
lot of people
doesn't have that yet so we must help
them change their behavior
and here i want to bring up
what the fbi does and especially in the
hostage
negotiation team there's a great book
about it
so back in the 90s the fbi was
going through a very difficult time
they were essentially losing all
negotiations and this led to a lot of
loss of lives and so the director
back in 1994 the fbi director assembled
a special team
whose only job was to figure out
what's what's wrong with the way that we
negotiate
and how can we negotiate in a way that
actually
changes the behavior of the criminal on
site
and helped us save lives and this was a
special
unit that had people that dealt with
crisis management incident response
behavioral sciences psychology
anything that was needed to fix this
problem
so this team went and did a lot of
research
a lot of experimentation a lot of
learning
they contacted harvard they contacted
the best minds they could
and one of the things i found was the
research
that was done back in the 80s few years
before
by daniel kahneman that said
that essentially people are irrational
beings
so back then in the 80s
the the economic sciences thought that
people do things
because it's the right thing to do
because it's cheaper because it's
rationally better but in reality what
was found
is that we do things because of how they
feel
so we feel before we think
and feeling is a way of thinking
and the way ganimat explains it is that
we have system one
which is the emotional irrational beast
side of our minds and we have system two
which is the logical rational
side of our minds and whenever something
happens
question uh uh and a stimulus in the
environment
we first process this through system 1
and then
that response informs our system 2
response
so this means that if we want to change
the behavior of anybody a criminal
a terrorist a person
then we first must appeal to emotion
rather than to rational thinking
and this is the mistake that the fbi was
making before
because they used to see negotiation as
a problem-solving thing
fully rational and that's why it didn't
work
a hostage situation was extremely
emotional and especially everything else
is as well
and so after they they found this
research they came up with
what is today called the fbi
stairway model for behavior change
and so whenever there's a hostage
negotiation
no matter the type no matter how
dangerous
an expert negotiator from the fb guy
goes
and essentially establishes trust with
the criminal
and first the first thing that they do
is that they actively listen to them
they want to understand why they're
doing
what they're doing without asking them
why just using
what and how questions they want to make
the criminal feel heard first then they
employ what they call
tactical empathy which is like empathy
on steroids
they mirror what the other person is
feeling
they label it they manage to understand
the criminal as much as possible they
build rapport
they become not friends but they have
the established relationship
after they have all of this that
influence the behavior
of the criminal to get them to see
things as they see it and this
ultimately leads to behavior change
the reason why i'm bringing this up in
this talk is because
this showcases that establishing trust
being able to be perceived as a
trustworthy person
an organization can ultimately lead to
behavior change
and if this works with hostage
and and crisis this way with terrorists
and with criminals
then we can use this to get anybody
to adopt our secure coding guidelines
to enable mfa to care about security we
can change
that perception and those behaviors by
establishing
and liberating trust
with people so it's a skill then again
it's actionable it's measurable
and it works in the field
and in general and it goes back to
listening
to empathy building reporters and
relationships influencing instead of
mandating change
and then ultimately using those
techniques to change the behavior
so let's say that we manage to change
the behavior
of the person they now accept
security they care about it it's part of
them so so now we want to make it
part of their identity so this means
that they
believe in security in a way so we talk
in their language
that means that whenever we explain the
topic
we we don't use this complicated jargon
we have
we don't talk to sales and marketing the
same way we talk with engineering
we help them understand our message we
explain
how does it benefit them in their
professional lives
in their personal lives because
ultimately
people do things for their reasons
that's just the way it is
and we use intrinsic motivation so
purpose
mastery and autonomy as much as we can
and after this this it becomes part of
their identity
now what happens when we change the
person behavior
it's part of the identity they care as
much as they can care about security
what happens if their leadership does
not value this
so executives directors leaders
must also be allies so they might have
competing priorities say that security
is not prioritized
from a project management perspective
and then they
literally can do can do anything
what are the price behaviors so is there
a focus on shipping
or is it a focus on shipping securely is
security consider a quality
metric in the organization and
what support do they have do they have
the time they need
to learn security the learning resources
the learning opportunities the support
they need overall
because security is not simple i would
dare say
and and we need to give people the space
to adopt it to learn about it
to interact with it
and if they're leaders managers
program managers executive directors
if they don't value security then we
must start at the top
with that behavior change to help
individual contributors
behave securely as well and now
say that we change behavior people
care about security it's part of their
identities
we adopt we adapt our messages
to their language something that they
can understand
and this is actually valued by the
leadership in the company now we enhance
their capabilities
so this means training on a constant
basis not just
one hour annual training that
we would dislike ourselves no this is
a fun engaging training that happens
multiple times a year we can have
mentorship
as well grab people from the security
team and do one-on-ones
or do one of many's lunch and learns
uh ask me anything's gonna be very
useful maybe we can grab leaders from
the security organization
to talk with people and what do they
think
we provide all the resources they need
blogs books video trainings
conferences even video youtube talks
anything that might be needed and we
have focus groups
maybe we have a team of people that's
working on
completing x certification
we have our security champions with a
special
learning path security ambassadors with
another learning path
we we do our best to
help everyone in the company grow
in their security journey throughout the
year
on a permanent basis and so
we have all of this but at the same time
i want to make a not a warning
but but also add this as well
so we want to extend trust we see that
trust
is the one thing that changes company
fool
to become company bar it's a way that we
can leverage people and take the
opportunity they represent
to make the internet safer but at the
same time we have to extend trust
in a smart way with judgment this
doesn't mean
that we extend trust blindly that we
just
trust everybody and trust that everybody
will define
and have no controls no
we must always have judgment as well so
this is like adding another layer in our
security program
we still have our detection and response
our logging our serious trust mechanisms
our processes policies
we still have all of this what i mean
by all of these stocks and all of these
behaviors is that
we have a high propensity to trust
that means that we don't go around
without
extending trust anybody or distrusting
every single person we see
thinking that they're just human error
waiting to happen
that's what i mean by this we can change
our perspective we have
on people to help them
become the best they can be and to turn
them
into another layer in our
security program with judgment
in a smart way so with this
we we have these two pillars to wrap
things up
we on one side the security organization
is trustworthy it's people-centric
we influence people we seek mutual
benefit
so we want win-win mindset
on another side we have everyone else in
the company
who are allies to the security program
they are knowledgeable because we've
trained them with
everything they need they are committed
because we change their behaviors we
change their perspective
and security is part of their identity
they're engaged
because we're not scary we're not
we're not intimidating we're fun we are
engaging we are seen we participate
we are part of the company and they are
responsible
because they care about security and
they also have
all the support they need from their
management chain
and with these two things and
all the things we can add on top of this
i believe that we can have
a security culture of trust that
actually drives behavior
and makes the internet safer and so
hopefully
if they have if this happens then maybe
next time
you see this picture maybe you might not
see
inside their threads and phishing people
that click confusion links
or engineers that are conflicting
and that code insecurely that don't fix
anything
you see trouble overall hopefully
if this happens that's not what you see
you see an opportunity
that was taken and you see
people that you trust that also trust
you back
and with this a security culture of
trust
that i strongly believe has the
potential
and the capability to make the internet
safer
in a scalable in a humane way and with
that
thank you very much
you