[Music]
welcome everyone welcome to the north
pole
it is cold up here so i've got some hot
chocolate to help keep me warm and i
hope that you are comfy and cozy
wherever you are
my name is barry allen kennel and i've
placed a little bit of info here by way
of introduction for you about myself but
it is extremely busy up here this time
of year so we're going to keep moving
so my goal for your this brief time that
i have with you today um is not to
answer all your questions i would love
to do that but i simply don't have the
cycles it's so busy here right now
so what i'd like to do is the opposite
i'd like to leave you with tons of
questions
hopefully this will wet your appetite
and fill you with curiosity
and you will want to it'll give you
point you in the right direction but you
will want to use the resources that we
give you here um and delve in on your
own tongue
i'd be remiss if i did not thank santa
and his amazing elves over at counter
hack and the sands institute for hosting
this epic ctf event a ton of hard work
goes into putting an event like this
together and it's a real joy to be a
part of
since it is christmas time here at the
north pole this talk will be my gift to
you we're going to talk about a lot of
free and open source tools and projects
here today but do me a favor i'm going
to challenge you
not to be a grinch
do not pull an ebonies or scrooge and
just take take take
there's a lot of ways that you can give
back in this community and you know it's
been a tough couple of years i mean i i
have neighbors who are you know work on
broadway and they have not worked in
more than a year and a half and they're
finally now
going back
um so i get it it's been tough um if you
can't give financially to some of these
authors maybe you can just send them
thank you and email like i really liked
that application that you built and it
was really helpful and here's why
or if you're a coder and you can pitch
in great
but try to give back tis the season
and it goes a long way up here i will
say with when it comes to uh doling out
the naughty and the nice lists just
saying
uh brief disclaimer about me um i do
work for bank of new york melon however
i am not representing bank of new york
melbourne with this talk any examples or
scenarios used in this presentation hold
absolutely no affiliation with the bank
of new york
so let's talk about what we're going to
talk about real quick
virtualization software right the
hypervisor that we're going to stick
with today is virtualbox it's free open
source very easy to use and it's come a
long way over the years um vmware i like
i like it a lot um and you know even
their paid version is you know fairly
affordable right um they offer a free
version now here's the reason why we're
not going to use it today you know we're
going to be blowing up samples you know
ransomware malware um and we need to be
able to revert back to a clean state
and unless the free version of vmware
the vmware player unless there's a
registry hack that i'm not aware of you
just can't do that and so you know so
that's why we're not going to cover it
here uh but it's a great product
as far as the cloud goes
personally i've built malware labs in
aws in google cloud
and i've heard that digitalocean is
fantastic and it's only about five bucks
a month something like that and the
machines are really fast
um but we won't cover that today um just
keep in mind um with aws you know and
gcp like those are the ones that i've
used um i know that you know there's
the cloud is someone else's computer
right so there are you know strict rules
around running malware and you just need
to stay within those confines and um you
can you can get away with it for free
if you stay within their free
requirements and free limits um great
tools great tools by the way
so we're going to talk about where to
find virtual analysis boxes
how to configure them
where to find malware analysis tools
where to find malware samples and if the
demo gods prevail we will do a live demo
let's talk about vms first we need the
software to run the vm so virtualbox you
can grab it here comes in a lot of
different flavors um the one thing i
will i will point you to when it comes
to virtualbox there's they have what's
called the the extension pack and the
guest additions um and those might throw
you a little bit at first if you don't
know much about them so this third link
here on the bottom of the screen takes
you to a forum and it's moderated by the
folks at virtualbox
some of the authors and this one
particular link explains the differences
you know between those two in like one
paragraph and it's succinct and it's
really really uh it was really helpful
for me so check it out
as far as machines to run
i like this one a lot this is a
microsoft free eval version it's a
windows 10 edge machine it's good for 90
days
and it's fast i like this one a lot
as far as a different flavor this one is
a windows 10 dev machine
i mean it's still windows 10.
i always say different
not really different flavor one of the
differences that you this machine gives
you that this one doesn't so this one
runs a little faster but it's a smaller
hard drive this one out of the box is
125 gigs and you can go on the back and
you know you can you can adjust the
sizes um
but you know i like out of the box right
there that you know i have all that
space if i want it they're good for 90
days now
when we talk about extending the life of
the machines snapshotting is a little
different it's my understanding that
snapshotting does not extend the license
right but this does this is called
rearming and reverting back
so
you know you can do this twice i think
for every vm so you can see here on
my on the the um example i give you at
the top of the screen i had 12 days left
on my 90 day vm right good for 90 days
well i did a re you know rearm um and
boom i'm back to 90 days so keep that in
mind
more machines from microsoft all the
server products are all trial eval
versions for free
um and those give you they're good for
180 days you know so uh let's talk about
remnants so revnex is uh you know when i
think of reverse engineering and i open
up the dictionary and i look at you know
i look up reverse engineering i see
lenny zelser's picture in my dictionary
my book um so lenny zeltzer
is the author of the sans reverse
engineering malware class
i've taken his course twice in its
fantastic class and he gives away a lot
of the resources for free so this is his
machine that he uses in the class to
analyze malware it comes pre-loaded with
tons of tools that you can look at
malware with
that's the one we're going to use um
this one is very good as well this is uh
it used to be fire i think when they did
their recent reorg i think mandy had got
the tools side of the house i think is
one of the things um that happened um
but it's still you know still being
supported
it's a fantastic distro
i think it's
it definitely needs at least 60 gigs
so you know make sure you have plenty of
free space but i've used it in the past
and it is very very uh
very good it it's also you know comes
pre-packed with like
tons of tools to look at malware
so i didn't want to not talk about cali
so cali is not you know probably like
when i think of a machine that comes
pre-loaded with malware analysis tools i
mean i probably wouldn't think of cali
per se
but it's got tons of tools that are
great for looking at malware so it's
also a possibility
so that's it for you know building that
that building our machines that that
just scratched the surface i know but
we've got to move on i have very little
time here so
uh these are some more resources that
are more in depth that i'm going to
leave with you so you can check those
out
let's talk about configuring these vms
so when we're running ransomware you
know back in the day when ransomware was
just coming on the scene you know
ransomware has a list of file types
right that it's going to encrypt and
then it's going to go after and back in
the day i didn't really care about pcap
files so you know i could i could hose
my entire box but i still had my
analysis pcap you know i could go back
and look at everything well you know the
authors kind of i think um
you know you know became wise to those
types of things and so they you know
they build in anti-forensics now
uh so
you know we just need to think about
anti-anti-forensics right um so a little
bit of of that
is what we're going to do here today
we're going to pipe the traffic out of
our victim machine our windows machine
is going to be the victim machine and
that's where we're going to detonate our
samples
and we're going to pipe that traffic out
to remix so the way we're going to do
that is we're going to run ifconfig on
remnix and file away that ip that it
gives us right
then on the windows machine you run
ipconfig and whatever ip it gives you
just hard code that in and make it
static right then for the default
gateway you're going to put in the ip
that you had for your remnix machine and
for the dns server as well and what that
does it allows the two to communicate to
each other
and
you know the remnx box can reach the
internet but the windows host cannot and
that's kind of what you want
so
the first thing i like to do on my remix
machine is
i fire up wireshark and then i fire up
fake dns and that's going to log the
traffic queries right from the victim
machine which is the windows machine
um in over on the windows side of things
i fire up burp
um in you know process hacker or
frockmon or you know a host of you know
many other tools that you can run um
just a few of my favorites you know but
there's many other
others that you can that you can run
so quick things before we detonate host
only will keep you out of trouble
make sure the host that's running the
virtual software software is non-prod so
if something does escape uh you know it
doesn't rock your world
take snapshots that's why you know one
of the reasons why we use vms right so
that we can revert back to a clean state
turn off the av under the ends shut the
windows updates down set your vm
firewalls off i know this is not it
sounds counterintuitive right but just
remember this is not this is not a
talk on how to harden your endpoints
so uh we're doing something very
specific here so this is why we want
these uh these settings the way we we do
if you're kind of new to malware
analysis just one thing to file away is
you know when you download malware from
places like virustotal
it's going to be zipped up and the
password is usually infected nine times
out of ten it's going to be infected um
the one last thing the usernames and the
passwords for all of the vms that i
mentioned should be right there on the
downloads page you just kind of have to
look around for them but they're there
where to find tools
again rem next the document
documentation page for remnux is
fantastic so all of these are little fly
out menus that you see on the screen
here and if you click on them it'll take
you to a little description about like
tons of tools and where to find them
um and the bitly link on the screen is a
paper that i wrote about dynamic
analysis static analysis incident
response and um there's some helpful
nuggets in there for you as well
so just a little bit about the
nomenclature you know i'm not i'm not a
reverse engineering snob by any means um
but you will run across people who uh
you know they're you know sometimes a
little uptight about the you know the
nomenclature that's used so this is my
way of sort of
you know putting everything together um
and you know
a little bit of reverse engineering you
know is is in some of what we're doing
here right
also static versus dynamic malware
analysis this is a great uh
a great resource um to talk to to learn
about the differences between those two
as well where to find malware very
simple just go to my
uh i run a little uh website with all
things dfir it's dfirlinks.blogspot.com
click on you know
the uh the beaker that you see there the
malware analysis um and you know you'll
be up to your eyeballs and malware but
uh but be careful and i am not
responsible for any malware that you
pull down just saying all right speaking
of malware let's run some huh all right
so we've got our victim machine ready to
get hosed
uh we've got over here
i did set off and i see some updates are
running i really i did shut them off but
you know
uh so
fake dns is running right shut that off
i kick that off
um the machines can talk to one another
you can see here
the configuration that we have
right
we've got burp running we've got
the virus protection is turned off
as well as the firewall and then the
windows updates have been paused
so
we're going to download the uh
we're going to run the black matter
ransomware
this is a
fairly new sample so it's still pretty
fresh i just pulled it down a couple
days ago
what's the password that we're going to
use right
all right we're going to call this
[Music]
and
should have process
hacker up and running
all right yeah it's running here
so that'll you know
give us an eyeball of what's happening
when we detonate the malware so let's
kick off our pcap
and let's roll
ready to get hosed here we go
now it's probably going to reach out
to some shady.org
right
you should see it over here um
not wj32 so it's in right now it's it's
deleting the volume shadow copies it's
encrypting those and uh we're not
encrypting them it's deleting them
um
it's not reaching out
to those there it is there it is those
dot orgs there we go
those are the shady ones
that it talks to
uh so
it's gonna hose everything in fact it
already has right
so you can see
here we go here's our
ransom note
all your
files are belong to us
right black matter
and
it's
hosed everything this was a file it's
now encrypted
you can see over here even my txt files
are encrypted
um did it get wire shark yes it did oh
no it didn't get
i wonder if the airshark was still not
let's see i'm curious
no no it got it it got it it got the uh
the deal out i think that
is a attached well we are out of time
but
you can see um how valuable you know
this kind of a resource is i hope that
you see that
and i hope that you'll have lots more
fun running more malware on your own
you