[Music]
hello and welcome to cringlecon 4. my
name's tom liston i'm a senior technical
engineer and breaker of things at
counter hack and today i'm going to do a
presentation on rfc
3514 compliant pen testing
you may have heard somebody say
something like
this before sometimes
there are good reasons to do bad things
as pen testers
that's kind of our motto
we're good folks
but we do bad things
uh
actually if i'm out and being introduced
to a bunch of new people and i'm in one
of those moods uh sometimes i will
introduce myself to people and say that
i'm a professional thief or i'll say i
break into networks for a living or i
steal data for a living
because i do
but those of us who do these things
on on a regular basis
know that there are some rules that we
have to follow in fact we probably have
more rules
that we follow personally than most
people do
even if you're doing bad things you
still need to follow some rules
interestingly
back on april 1st of 2003 a gentleman uh
an amazing gentleman by the name of
stephen m bellovin released uh rfc
3514 via the network
working group of the ietf
now rfc 3514 put forth a pretty radical
proposal
for the use of
what was previously unused the high bit
of the ip flags field now that has
always been called the reserved bit
because uh they didn't have any use for
it it was the only bit in the ip
header that wasn't used
but mr velvin
came up with this utterly ingenious idea
uh in this rfc
uh and his idea was to provide a
solution for the growing problem
of malicious traffic on the internet and
this was back you know at the beginning
of of 2003
his
proposal was
that this bit should be set
in order to
show whether a packet had evil intent or
not so if you set the bit to zero the
packet has no evil intent at all you
should just assume that the packet is
harmless you should not take any
defensive measures against it uh because
this is telling you that
there is no evil intent here if however
the bid is set to one the packet has
evil intent and you should uh secure
yourself try to defend yourself against
this packet um
so
with this proposal he also came up with
a name for that it was only fitting that
once was this this this register this
bit that was once named the reserve bit
now became known as the evil bit
now
suddenly security was easy this was a
boon for the makers of firewalls why
would you need to do deep packet
inspection why would you need a next
generation firewall
it's simple it's so simple now all you
have to do is look at this one bit and
decide whether or not you're going to
drop the packet if it's if it's one
meaning that the packet is evil drop it
interestingly gartner declared the ids
dead in june of 2003 two months after
the release of rfc 3514. is that a
coincidence i don't think so because why
would you need an ids anymore security
was now easy
but maybe that isn't how it all worked
out
what happened well rfc 3514 was a
wonderful incredibly innovative idea but
it did not deliver
on its early promises
why not well i'll tell you why not it's
because the bad guys failed to comply
and why did the bad guys fail to comply
well i don't think there's any question
it's because we in the security
community have been setting a horrible
example
my question to you is this if you are a
pen tester if you are a security
professional and you do any kind of
security testing
are you
rfc 3514 compliant
how do we expect others to follow the
rules when we don't
the second the security community really
needs to step up in this instance and
set a good example
well i'm here today
to help you do just that
i've created a fun little piece of
python code called evil bit dot pie and
well i think it's fun you may not think
it's fun but i think it's fun and
interesting
it uses iptable's net filter queue
capabilities
and then it also uses some of scabies
packet crafting and editing magic
to make your linux box proudly proclaim
its evil intent when you're doing pen
testing you can now boldly be
rfc 3514 compliant
the way it works is this
net filter queue allows you to tag
packets
uh with a with a an identifier that can
then
be pulled those packets can then be
pulled out of the packet stream prior to
being sent
and uh you can do many things with that
by using scapy what we're doing is we're
pulling these packets in
we are altering the ip flags field to
turn on the evil bit we're then updating
the checksum the ip checksum for that
packet
and then
tossing the packet back into the queue
and allowing it to be sent
all on done on the fly all done uh
without any interaction with any other
piece of software on your system your
system doesn't even need to know that
this is happening all of your normal
uh pen testing tools work just fine
all of your network connections will
work just fine all that will happen is
that every ip packet that goes out will
have the evil bit set
i've got a a github a github repo for
this uh it's down there at the bottom of
the screen it'll continue to be on the
bottom of the screen for the next slide
or two here
i would strongly suggest that if you do
pen testing and you want to be rfc 3514
compliant
go take a look at the code because it'll
really help you out in that regard
but then i'm sure there are some of you
out there who are just thinking well i'm
an anti-social buffoon who doesn't care
i don't want to set a good example by
being rfc 3514 compliant while pen
testing
well
hey
if that's what you want to do
that's fine i suppose but i'm just going
to have to say it shame on you shame on
you for not wanting to set a good
example
this is why you are why we cannot have
nice things on the internet
but even if
you are a horrible horrible human being
who doesn't want to set a good example
far be it from me to deny you a learning
opportunity so
the github repo is still there perhaps
you might find this little example to be
an opportunity uh where you could
uh take a look
at uh
the code that i'm providing to you be
impressed by my incredibly amazing
programming prowess i i know it it's a
little intimidating but that's okay um
you might want to take a look and see
a little about how you could use
iptable's net filter cue combined with
scapy to alter packets on the ply on the
fly
from
you know the warm wonderful comfortable
embrace of python
you may find that this has some other
potential possibilities
i may or may not have used
this kind of technique to do some
editing of packets uh that i needed to
change within a pcap file at one point
in time or another
learning this kind of stuff learning how
you can use scapy
edit packets while still
fixing things like ip checksums or tcp
checksums or udp checksums
really really interesting stuff stuff
that has a lot of imp implications a lot
of uses uh in other types of activities
so take a look look at the github repo
or as my friend josh wright says github
repo repo um and uh
i hope you have a really really
wonderful rest of your day i hope you
enjoy the rest of your trip here to the
north pole
and that you enjoy the rest of
kringlecon 4.