we're still broadcasting
all right
right folks so we are at the
well almost the end
of
our work here is done
uh beer con three
um we've got leonard
and i think nikos is kicking around
somewhere too soon
wonderful
so
yeah let's show your face
there he is
so we truly are here international
really leonard is in the netherlands
nikos is in switzerland and we're in
southeast london
but our speakers were from everywhere
right everywhere everywhere so we're
gonna do some thanks
and then we'll say a few other words and
then we're gonna sign off and then we're
gonna do some music
um first of all i wanna thank the
sponsors and they have been mentioned
and they are magnificent and some of
them are here
so first up
first
yeah
half of them are here
yeah so first up quorum
so if you can see the two people in shot
they'll raise their hand if they work
with quorum
worked or work
oh sorry never mind oh [ __ ] off
all right we'll carry on it's cyber uk
hacking proof uh digital overdose just
wave nikos that's your yeah
rock and roll octopi ms that's your
creation yeah
sounds a bit nepotistic this whole thing
doesn't it anyway nevermind havelock
studio that's your
[Music]
um robert walters our recruitment
partner
pentest partners who are a super cool
group and pen test people as well who
not to be confused
um
for giving us some money allowing us to
put this thing on um
this magnificent fleet of engineering
which we'll come on to in a few seconds
so
mentors
and they're the people that have made it
easier and in some cases very easy for
the people to
deliver their testimonies and their
presentations today and some of these
people
uh are here beautiful people
beautiful dave and sam behind me here
but we also had claire tills zoe rose um
and james ball
behind the scenes but
more often than not freely available for
our speakers to get in touch with
share their presentations get some
coaching get some support and the
speakers supported each other as well
which was super cool and typically like
we did last year the bay farms kept out
of the whole mentoring scheme so it was
not to interfere with it really
because we're not mental
right
a roll call okay of the speakers yeah
and
my able assistant sean wright sec
ios expert
oh yeah so let's do this
it's a long list and we had absolutely
no no-shows right that's right there is
an exception but there's an absolutely
legitimate reason for it
so let's go nikos will yura poncho gabe
nolly drew josh and down
ayosh yevgenya
um shruti who is the exception because
truthy was unfortunately unable to join
for personal reasons but we wish shruti
very well and we will reach out with our
best
dan
vicky ben
kelly stew
nice one stu
gavin tebow and of course the music
presented last night by dj miss jackalo
which was absolutely fantastic cheers
cheers to miss jackalope
onto today
troy liam sebastian nick pankaj sonia
ben
dave mac
man
leonard
david
c
uh parker
matt chris anne pete rock and roll
what oh i miss somebody dorian i beg
your pardon um jonathan
uh shah and sam and sam again
so that was fantastic so that is all the
thanks done
in terms of the crew and the cast
um thanks to the people have tuned in
yeah because we did it for you
we did it to enlighten people stretch
people's imagination and i think you'll
agree that there was a really why i
mentioned it earlier really wide variety
of talk topics that we've covered over
the two days
some very technical some not technical
some about people because it's all about
people yeah that's what we do you know
we talk about people processing
technology in technology as an industry
but it's nothing without the people
people build things
people operate processes but in
businesses people take orders
they do billing the provision systems
that's what it's all about people and
communities been mentioned a lot of
concepts across the two days
and that's really really important daily
and deeply important to the bear farmers
and the people that work with us
and that's why they're here because
we've all
dedicated our time and effort and the
speakers have dedicated their time and
effort and the crew
but the people that have listened in and
watched in over the two days of the con
conference no comic con so this concert
yeah it's a festival yeah it's a
festival um i've made it what it is
so
a lot of engineering and a lot of effort
we took a risk doing this we could we
could have all just sat home and did it
via zoom
and used heavenly biscuit our magic
computer to make it all work for us but
we haven't seen each other in a long
time long time very long two years
probably we've never met scott
hi um it's a big bear farmer by proxy in
many ways
but
we give a [ __ ] and that's why we put
this stuff together and the people that
work with us care as much as we do and
the people that come and talk at our
conventions they care as much as we do
so that's kind of a wrap
um have i forgotten anything
the road is yeah
yeah okay you missed your point now yeah
jared so not only has jared been our
engineering rock
but he's also been the guy and that this
feels really pathetic but he's been the
guy that's brought his teeth
and and bears and and broke some egg
cups and he shattered some egg cups that
hexa beam donated that apparently don't
like pachin
as the evidence
i think the moral of that story is don't
pour drain cleaner into an egg cup
all right we're going to sign off now in
terms of the conference but we're going
to give you 10 minutes
um but feel free and please do come back
because we've got some dj live dj's in
the house and one of them you'll know
very well
so we've got dj nav coming up in about
10 minutes time once we've cleared up a
few things and done a sound check and
then after nav we've got dan sampeyo who
you'll also know is dan khan who's a
really cool member of our community and
also delivered a talk for us yesterday
sorry just speak
you didn't finish off with
the rest of the roadies well i mentioned
them all in other dispatches did you all
right well we'll be abundantly clear
let's do it again the road crew
the honorable mention to the road crew
is jared who got an explicit mention
dave mac has been mentioned more
and of course leonard and nicos who were
tuning in from their respective
countries and homes so we thank you we
hope you enjoyed it the next steps in
terms of the materials we will we had we
know we had some
seems like a distant memory now but we
did have some
issues yesterday morning um
but we will review
an edit the recordings if we think we
might need to maybe redo them and we're
willing to do that because we will
always promise that you get an artifact
a speaker gets a thing at the end of
this as well as the kudos and feeling
good
about the event they get something that
they can say i did that that was my
thing so if we do need to reach out and
maybe do a podcast equivalent of your
talk slot then that's exactly what we'll
do and we'll do it soon so you'll get a
recording for all the material that
we're able to publish that'll go out as
soon as we get it done and last time we
did it within two days no guarantees but
we'll get it to you as quickly as we can
and that's it
and that's it so we hope you've had a
good time and continue to have a good
time into the evening
thank you we love you willow beer
farmers
one last thing before we go like to
thank jer because he's been awesome
uh
and dave dave mack because you know he's
been listed in everything
like to thank myself
and honestly guys this has been amazing
this is beacon 3.
this
has been
absolutely fantastic the number of
people that
again you had you had rookies again this
year
and you have done an absolutely amazing
job
mike
always you're my favorite beer farmer
that's current uh sean you're my least
favorite beer farmer
ian you're my scariest beer farmer
and scott you're my [ __ ] pure farmer
that almost sounds like a boy band
excellent
thanks very much guys these have been
awesome everyone's had an amazing time
the feedback has been awesome and yeah i
mean yeah everyone has had a great time
apart from the egg cups the egg cups
[Music]
didn't make it but uh yeah
thanks very much for having us guys and
these have been awesome absolutely peace
all right
see you in 10 minutes
if only there was an engineer turn this
crap off