we'll welcome gavin
along um sorry we're overrunning a
little bit but you've got exactly the
amount of time that you've requested in
your talk we promise you
um you're ready to go so
with godspeed
okay carry answer i hope and we're going
to show up
it's a zoom team whatever you want to
call it call so the first thing has to
be can you hear me i'm assuming you can
unless i hold it otherwise
my name is gavin chester um i'm hoping
that you can all see the screen and the
magic is working um and this talks about
micro red team testing
kind of how many pen tests we're going
to do a week
so let's click the right screen
so who am i my name's gavin chester i
spent about 30 years to 32 in big pharma
uh eight years making drugs sorry
penicillins nothing interesting uh 10
years lab support so that was basically
the machine had broke somebody has to
fix it new machines turned up got to
make it got to make it work
eight years as a data loss prevention
analyst so dealing with the people that
just don't think what they're doing and
accidentally let their company secrets
out
two and a half years as a red team
analyst which sounds really cool but
kind of the first year of that was we
were starting out and setting up so it
was just things like a very boring
authority to operate and it got to be a
bit interesting
and last couple years i've been an
information security officer
so i'm dealing with interfacing between
the technical side of the stuff and the
business side of stuff and hopefully
getting to see eye to eye
so microwave teaming um
this is not a lot of original work um
it's a lot of what i found out about
where we're going to go in the future
kind of a few bits of tricks and ideas
something that maybe you'll get an idea
that you want to go forward with
almost all of the code on here and
examples is from either red canary's
atomic red team and the github
repositories there
alternatively it'll be using soa's
vector tool um which again available on
github freely usable installing
i'm aware that in places this is going
to look like an eye test please try not
to read the screen try not to read too
much into it
so
what's micro red teaming um well this
isn't about doing a full-on red team
test there's just no point in doing that
it's not about pissing off the blue team
with false positives well it's fought
really no no it isn't
um
it's not about repeatedly pointing out
the same issues to the blue team uh just
talking a few moments ago in in the
pre room saying you know we've all got
these issues that we know are never
going to get fixed it's there's no money
to do it it's it's an old system that we
can't change it's a system that we can't
upgrade anything like that so the whole
point of this is to
find these issues but if we found them
again and again and again there's no
point beating that dead horse
um
but what it is about is just trying to
speed up our analysis of risk exposure
so we can
look at what we've got out there when we
get a new actor a new threat um we see
well
could they get in you know we've got all
this protection in place but does it
protect the way that they're using and
the way that their vector comes in
try and give you an idea of where you're
going
so
if i just explain a bit more um a
typical red team engagement a pen test
it kind of looks uh a system and network
and invariably
you've got to get something so
maybe they want you to get credit card
data to say well we've put this flag
file on your credit card server can you
get to it uh alternatively a pen test
might be can you break this app
they're all really good they can take
days and weeks and they do find up good
findings but invariably you're going to
find that one big issue you've found the
root of how you get to that file that
doesn't mean you've actually found all
the vulnerabilities
if you're lucky you patch those
vulnerabilities and you've kind of
sort of stopped a bottleneck so you've
stopped everything but that doesn't mean
you really are sure that you've got all
those
so
what
if we've got the ability to test
everything all the time
and this is kind of it's an impossible
dream but it's kind of where we went to
so this idea came from uh my manager at
the time and he saw it from somebody i
gave a talk at arcticcon
minnesota
i believe
it was somebody from target but
arcticcon don't release their videos so
i couldn't go back and check it and and
if you happen to be listening to this
i'm sorry i'm not name checking you but
i couldn't find who it was
but basically can we red team the entire
infrastructure on this semi-continuous
and kind of regular basis and
that just seems like an impossible task
so where do we start
we start with a pretty simple core
concept we just take the red team down
put it into really small chunks and we
test them so
if you look at any of the minor
techniques you can see can you get it to
work can you actually detect it in the
sock does the sock notice do the sock
care
two different questions
we're going to do this at least once a
week random times random days sometimes
i'll do it in my id sometimes it'll be a
friend i've got somewhere else in the
business sometimes it's going to be my
machine if it's something that
potentially is going to trigger an alert
higher up and somebody's going to get
worried it would be a computer that's
obviously mine or i'd i'd give you the
name of micro red team test if it was
something we really wanted to be sort of
different and out there i'd get a friend
to run it on on a lab computer something
that maybe a bad guy has got in usb
dropped in a car park that sort of thing
if we tracked every time that we do
these tests um we know when we started
the test we know when we finished the
test
and we can find out when blue actually
got back to to to tell us hey was this
you guys testing or was it not so we're
gonna then sort purple team red and blue
together not really a proper purple team
we just had a meeting together at the
end try and see if there's anything that
we can look see fixed and improve
so
that sounds really obvious he says
changing his slides over but you are
going to be attacking your own
enterprise so you've got to have all the
relevant approvals from your c-suite
you can start without that that's
probably going to be a little bit career
suicide
next thing is despite what i said way at
the top of the slides
this isn't about red and blue attacking
each other in a lot of senses you've got
to work in partnership you've got to
trust what you're doing i mean the one
thing that you don't want to do is
start doing something right in the
middle of an attack happening so you've
got to find a way that you can talk to
each other
but you can still do the tests in secret
so as i say you don't want to be
launching a test when the sock is
already overloaded you know if they've
got a real incident you coming along
with a little
red test is not going to make them your
friends
there is an argument that says that
could be what the bad people are doing
they launched attack over here
and diversionary tactics go and play
something else somewhere and that's
where they're going
but we're not trying to be a complete
red team we're trying not to be a
complete simulation so let's try and do
it when they're not absolutely screaming
and pulling their hair out
we don't want the stock to filter out
anything because it is a known user id
or a known device id from people on the
red team so if it's my laptop that i'm
using and i had my laptop and a test
laptop
if they recognize it as mine we just
don't want them to go but gavin will not
play with it because sometimes it might
not be
and similarly we don't want the red t
the the stock to look at it and go
that's a really pointless little test
that's just a micro red team again
you've got no guarantee it really is
chances are it is might not be
so
where do we start with this um the good
thing is is you're not at zero
there's lots of attack tools out there
they're kind of
they've got this new category breach
attack simulation tools um
there's an awful lot of them out there
we went with red canaries atomic red
there is end games automation khalida
from mitre and uber
have a tool called meta
they're all really good but the reason
why we started using the atomic red bit
is it's really basic it's nothing more
than a set of scripts on github
so the beauty of that is
you have to spend a bit of time working
on it but then you can just pick up that
script take it to a machine go and run
it go and run it anywhere if you've got
the ability to copy things to usb write
them in there you can copy on usb go to
where you're going install that script
run it in command run it in powershell
whatever you happen to be needing for it
the only downside to that is that there
isn't any embedded reporting in um
atomic red and that's why we started
using vector so we have to do a test
log where we're doing kind of report it
ourselves
i'm sure that
everyone is familiar with
the mitral attack framework this is
where it gets to be an eye test and no
i'm not expecting you to read any of
that but we all know that there's this
long framework but we can start off with
a few bits and pieces that we know
there's no point working on
first couple of steps on the left-hand
side the reconnaissance and the initial
access there's a lot of benefit if you
can stop somebody in that phase
if you've got somebody who's searching
for your whales your users on social
media if you can stop them brilliant but
you know what we probably can't
if there's an awful lot of active
scanning on your perimeter well chances
are you've been scanned welcome to the
internet that's business as usual
we already do fishing simulations on our
users
if we're going to do fishing simulations
as part of this red team we're going to
probably cause problems we're either
going to pollute the work that they're
doing so they're going to think well
that was better or worse than what we've
been doing
what we're going to do with it are we
going to
break some of these things are we going
to send it to the wrong place and we
could potentially do stuff that is all
publicly facing so it's a drive-by
it's just about practical um
but in real terms it's not practical for
this to attest and it's even dangerous
you know we want to do this in a very
tight controlled manner so we know when
we've done it what we've done it with
who we've done it with when the
detection is if you've done something
that's a public drive-by
you know even if it's a private drive by
sort of in your internal sites you don't
know when that test is going to happen
you've got no idea what's going to do it
could be one person picks up five people
i haven't got a clue so we tended to
stay away from the reconnaissance and
the initial access thing
so basically we're going to assume that
us as the bad guy has got in i'm going
to kind of concentrate on the next whole
bundle of the miter chain
so i'm going to move on to a couple of
examples
so the first one is
going to be privilege escalation um
the way that it works is pretty simple
go to my
um sorry the red the red canary atomic
red database they've got a wiki page
about it and you'll get this chooser
test and they're all sorted by their t
number but you can also have them you
see just down at the bottom we've got
all tests we've got windows mac
um and unix
we tend to use microsoft stuff because
that's what we've got most of the time i
had a laptop that i dual booted to
either linux or windows depending what i
wanted
we didn't have many macs in our
environment at the time so
we didn't purposely choose not to use
max
but we knew that it was a much lower sac
surface and while we can use it now and
again let's concentrate on the
the low hanging fruit the stuff we
really can get
but just remember you are almost
certainly going to have these oddballs
in your environment so you're going to
have to all right
hello hello
okay uh
the zoom just comes
just shut
my end or yours
okay
we're just looking at it coming back uh
it's cartwheeling
yep we'll all zoom there folks so we're
just getting zoomed back and hopefully
gavin back yeah
and hopefully he's not just speaking
into the void i don't think so it looks
like he stopped now
oh no now
so carry on thank you
you've just put me off my throw
my flow thank you anyway
um so you're always going to have those
oddballs there's always going to be
somebody that's got something or other
um i just i worked in a lab environment
we always had a few weird and wonderful
bits that would only run on unix
you've probably got a graphics
department that you know for all sorts
of weird reasons they won't use pcs and
insist that macs are the only thing
you've got so you're going to have those
in your environment don't forget to test
for them they might be there so looking
at a couple of examples as i said start
with privileged escalation
so the tests are actually pretty simple
uh you can see we've got 107.8 here just
setting up some local accounts
all the different t-tests have got
different number of subtests this
particular one has got one um the red
red canary atomic red gives you the
instructions and you'll note that it
needs to be admin so i've just got a
screenshot there i'm pretty sure you can
all read what we're doing we're going to
add a user we're going to set the user's
password we're then going to push that
user into the local administrators group
and nicely even gives you the cleanup
commands
so
i think most of us would probably be
really surprised if we could actually
detect that i don't think there's many
companies that would probably detect a
local account being set up on a local
machine adding somebody into a domain
putting a domain user into a domain
group yeah we've probably got some
detections for that it may work they may
not but would we ever do it on the local
machine
not sure
if you do have that logging that goes
into a sim um
what what are your rules how would you
surface up that one single event when
you've got thousands tens of thousands
hundreds of thousands of endpoints
and would that actually even be a
priority
you know a local user suddenly being
created on a machine
no not sure
another example persistence um so this
is one five four seven uh this has got
seven different tests so you can see
we're adding a couple of things to
registry keys trying to get stuff into
the startup folder the user startup
folder so we've got a suspicious uh in
this case it says uh visual basic
javascript or a batch file but it could
be anything just any file you want
we're adding it to the startup or we're
adding it to the room once when the user
logs in or when the machine starts up it
goes off and does something if we were
bad guys with an implant maybe we're
getting that implant start up every time
i know that this is not really really
complex in terms of
operational stealth and things like that
it's not meant to be it's meant to be a
test
um one thing to remember is that the the
known malware as i'm calling it the the
in this case it's the hash command to
execute the part
isn't necessarily going to be malware it
could be a batch file that's going to
keep re-adding your users it could be an
implant you know if you've
really got done it well and you've got
your cobalt strike and you've encrypted
it and you've got your private keys and
nobody's leaked bugs keys and things
like that
maybe you're going to get a file that
will not be picked up by a signal based
iv maybe it will maybe not different avs
work different ways but ultimately
you've got to remember that that file
isn't malicious in itself the
maliciousness is the adding the
persistence
he says turning these files over
so
kind of like the first one are we ever
going to see
that that's been done i mean if you
think about it this is what software
does all the time
it's the software comes along sets
itself up puts its drivers in
puts its little tray icon in does it set
up to start automatically when the user
logs in all of this is standard this is
normal industry practice we're not doing
anything strange
so would we ever see it
software you know we rely on the
antivirus to check that the file's not
malicious
but we kind of not missing the
non-malicious files that could be
delicious
and again
i don't think socks are ever going to
detect this in the noise
and yeah i know what you're probably
thinking i'm being really bad on the
sock so we're looking for a local alert
on a machine that's potentially in
amongst thousands so let's try something
a bit noisier
so my third example
um is uh c2x filtration using dns
um there's four parts to this test
sending a large volume of dns queries
beaconing out on a regular interval
pushing out a very long domain query and
a simulated c2 i'm not going to give you
all the commands i think we've got the
idea by now
but we've all got this wonderful
next-gen hardware that can see all and
do all and it's going to surface these
it's going to tell us and within minutes
it's going to maybe even block it
well we'll see
something to note on this one is because
it's dns it needs a digital well i use
the digital ocean up the digital ocean
droplet but we're needing an external
destination of some description um the
reason why i went with digitalocean is
the kind of cheap five dollars for a
small droplet i could spin it up have it
running
delete it and wipe it you know
probably cost less than a dollar a week
if if that to use it's five dollars a
month i could put them anywhere that
digitalocean had got a data center i
tended to use singapore and bangalore
because we don't have a lot of comfort
company infrastructure there it's not
trying to hide it completely this should
kind of trigger some alerts why is our
dns going to singapore
just trying to make it stand out a
little bit more
as i said droppers would cheat
so it's going to be probably apparent
from these names but they all use dns so
the first one sends out a lot of dns
queries to a specific ip in a short time
frame
not normal dns behavior um second one is
does the same thing but instead of it
being a lot in a short time frame it's
just sending them out on a regular pulse
test three shoves the dns up to as long
as it can be which i think is 254
characters
um and again unusual it would be really
unfair for me to use a test that sent
that one query out i don't think there's
anything that's next next next next gen
that's ever going to catch anything that
simple because if it's never seen it
before it can't make a judgment and if
it never happens again well it doesn't
know about it so to be fair to the blue
team i put this in the loop so there was
quite a few of these calls being doing
and the fourth test uses um dns cat to
try and simulate um c2 activity between
them
so as i said surely all this wonderful
next-gen kit caught it
yeah no
and if you think about it we kind of got
a lot of the systems that we use you
know i've got examples there av and
cloud work on virtual cloud instances
and they've got these long names the
very things that we almost looking to
try and pick up so i've got an example
there that's
an amazon reference so each c2 is your
size and then
uh yes okay i picked random numbers
that's not really an ip address which is
what the next digit should be
location and details about it
and at this point you're probably
thinking what am i talking about so just
to bring this home this is actually very
real world
so you've got a query there with the 70
fov
all the rest of it um was actually the
the query issued by the sunburst malware
to tell the c2 server that it implanted
itself on the cisco machine so the 70fov
was saying this is cisco.com um
in whatever way they've encoded it and
you've got the rest of the strings
but that query looks awfully lot like an
amazon address and and i i do not doubt
that that is extremely deliberate on the
part of the bad guys so
so we've got all our tests we take each
test we've got yesters nose detections
things like that log them into vector
and we can try and visualize this
so we can try and understand what the
technique the actor uses
how they're going to look at on our
defenses and kind of repeat it see if
you're going so i've got a few
screenshots just showing you that um so
apt
uh so with the apt groups you can see
we're bringing them all in here
uh these are all
the reference screens that come from
sra i'm not giving you any company data
away
you see we can drill down and look in
any particular one we've got apt-33s so
there's the things that they were known
to use
we can also build a custom campaign so
if we had intelligence that apt-33 were
thinking of attacking us we could bring
one of these custom campaigns in look at
it and then we can maybe look at it
either run the campaign ourselves so we
can go let's not micro red team this but
we'll just run through all of these and
see where we go
alternatively we can kind of look at
that look back at our heat map and try
and work out if we're going to be
attackable or not
so as i said we get a heat map so
should be kind of obvious red is bad
green is um is good
you can see just looking there
uh in in the example data that we've got
we've got a boot or logon autostart
execution which is kind of green which
probably means you've got good detection
about it so my tests earlier should have
been picked up then you've got some
things that are yellow and orange where
there's minimal coverage
um
you can also see that um when you drill
down into the tests if you do them often
enough
you've got an idea of where you've got
better um there's two examples there
one's the green outlines one's the red
you see how um the first time the lmn
nr test was done
went through went through the second
time
third time it was blocked
interesting there's no alert triggered
so probably that's something being done
by the scenes rather than sock being
said hey we need to go and look at it
and you can see the other one for
yourself
i'm gonna move on okay
so in theory every one of these tests
could have been caught you know if you'd
loved enough if you'd have if you'd then
look through those logs hard enough
you would have found them absolutely
without a doubt but you know
the sock analysts rely on automated
tools
we're not trying to burn the sock
analysts out well you know you can't do
that but the question is is
do we actually know where these things
are working so
in my examples they're all a look well
most of them are a local alert that the
dns one would have been on your maybe
your firewalls or your proxy logs
they would have been alerted would have
alerted locally they would written into
the log did that log get to the sock did
it even get into the sim and that's
where we started looking at this
so we'd look at our purple team debrief
the sock would look at what we've done
we'd talk about it sometimes they caught
us sometimes they didn't it was usually
about 50 50. um and if there was
anything where they went that what where
we should have picked that up why did we
not pick that up the beauty of this is
we knew exactly where and when we'd done
it we knew the machine name the time all
that sort of thing go back into the
audit trails go back into the sim go
into the sock alerts and you can try and
work out where that alerts somewhere got
triaged out
so
how did this all work out for us in
practice ah yeah this is where it goes
wrong
so we ran these tests for about nine
months um as i said one or two a week
random times random dates um so it
wasn't always monday morning and they
could be spread through the week it
usually when i've got an extra half an
hour i could just slot one in
so we were just trying to build up this
nice heat map what we've got where we've
got where there were holes
and at that point my employee decided
that we didn't need an internal red team
anymore so we were all made redundant
and i moved sideways into my current
role
so yes this nine month project never
really made any impact in in the grand
scheme of things
but the key takeaways so
micro red teaming is a mouthful so it
needs a better name uh defense
engineering i know it's been mentioned
in other places it does
sum up what we're trying to do we spent
all this money on
next-gen hardware next-gen
xyz it doesn't matter what it is but i'm
sure it's next-gen we spend all the time
getting those systems up running and
installed
and then do we actually go back and
check that we're getting the alerts that
we think we're getting
so
i said we'd try not to burn the analysts
out so we tuned things out but do we
tune too far and too much
do we ever re-baseline our tools as
often as we could so
if you think back to my um
the solarwinds thing they wrote that so
that the dns string looked very much
like an amazon string
you know if you've said well if it looks
this long and it's got so many bits
you've got some clever regex that makes
it look for
usc let's go sorry usc us west it's
entirely possible you've actually just
managed to triage out the alert that you
were looking to detect
and finally do we have that right
coverage um some systems are forever
stuck in learning mode we we do use
carbon black um i'm aware of a couple of
systems that every time they move them
off at learning mode something breaks
they put them back in learning mode so
the cost of that agent and they're not
cheap
is actually wasted it's not doing
anything we're not getting any alerts
sent back for it i'm sure we can do
things better
so what started off as a way to test our
defenses kind of just changed as we went
along um it didn't work out for us my
current company but it could work out in
yours um my ex red team manager
is doing this same thing in his new role
and he's always found bits where
they've got to it and gone hey we should
have gotten alert from that why didn't
we and it's warranted further
investigation into working out why or
when or why something didn't happen
um so
as i said the real key takeaway the one
thing if you do it
other than somebody's time and effort
there isn't any major cost to trying
this process out all the software's free
yes you've got somebody's time you need
to spin up a couple of dns's if you get
a little more complicated going down the
line you'll probably need some domain
names
it's peanuts it really is you know
with all the time that we did all these
tests we probably never spent more than
100 pounds on them so what have you got
to lose if you want to try this out and
what visibility might you actually gain
into how your systems might be at risk
and that's it i just have a couple of
thank yous um firstly to all the people
in red canary and sra who made the
they've got the tools out there that
gave them away made life a lot easier
the people that actually contributed to
all those red team tests i don't think i
could have sit and written the scripts
myself in fact i know i couldn't but
because somebody's done it it's easy to
pick them up go and use them pick them
off the shelf
and thankfully to whoever gave that
talker
all that years ago um that put the idea
in my manager's head and
got me to go and run with it
last couple of things
uh chris b chris m my two red team
colleagues we had a lot of fun in two
and a half years i think one of them may
be listening in i'm not sure if he is
hello
um
it did took me a huge amount in that
short time we were active it was really
interesting and also to our blue team
and again i think there's might be one
of our ex blue team listening in hello
um they took it entirely in the right
way they didn't see it as red team just
being trouble red team looking to
just create a problem find a problem and
keep saying you've not fixed it you've
not fixed it it was definitely a
learning experience for us both to go
back understand what could work
understand what couldn't work and
ultimately how we could defend the
company better
and that's it if i haven't talked too
much and hit the time limit i'm kind of
happy to take questions uh there is my
twitter handle there it's gjc but there
are two underscores because somebody
else had stole it but i don't know
whether i'm at time
you you
run perfectly to time but we are running
over time no problem
but that's absolutely fine
so gavin thank you very much indeed
another great thought great feedback um
thanks for joining us cheers hey bye
brilliant thanks kevin