right thank you
so
welcome everybody to my talk about
reverse engineering minecraft rng to get
world records
starting off
first who am i uh i'm yuri runendike a
19 year old i've been a little bit of
away with corona but 19 year old um
scholar student studying computer
science and engineering at studio dels
my pronouns are he him
and i'm currently the owner of the
biggest minecraft co-op speedrunning
um
server in the world on discord
um we currently hold
between 40 and 70
world records
um
yeah that's it about me but before i get
started for some terminology and
starting info because
i assume some people in the audience
know exactly what half of those words
mean
so um
what is speed running
speed running is the art of trying to
finish a game as fast as possible
within speed running there are some
other terms like pb which is a personal
best
and wr world record which is the first
time anyone has ever beaten so far
then what is minecraft
a lot of us have probably grown up with
it but for people who don't know
minecraft is a
sandbox
um
yeah building mining crafting game
so it's kind of like an mmrpg where you
just go around you you can mine stuff
you can craft stuff like the name
implies but there's also combats there's
um
mobs loots dungeons everything
within minecraft there's a few things
that you can do for speedrunning
so there's uh the categories relevant to
us today are
uh any percent which is just beating the
game
which i will get back to in a bit and
minor chunk which is where you take a 16
by 16 area and mind the entire thing out
um within these categories is also
subcategories namely random see glitch
list where you create a random world you
have no idea what you're doing and you
just go in
and set the english list where you get a
world that you've already chosen
beforehand and you you know exactly
where everything is that you just go in
and do everything as fast as possible
there's also for the any percent
category it's also filter t glitchless
which is where you get a world that you
have never seen before
but it is guaranteed to have the
features like the villages and the
portals and stuff in the right place
i talked about beating the game but what
exactly does that entail so there is
three dimensions within minecraft uh as
of right now
you have the overworld which is where
you spawn
and where you yeah when you start out
run around
then eventually you will make a nether
portal which will bring you to the
nether which is the second dimension
here
um and then last but not least you go
back to the overworld and then when you
find the stronghold you can go to the
end and within the end third dimension
here you can beat the ender dragon and
then when you kill the underdragon you
go into the portal
you've beaten the game
to get there there are a few steps you
need to go you can't just run to the
portal jump in and be done with it
so
to actually get to the portal and enter
it you need blade rods
so
which you can get from blazes within the
nether which are the top creatures and
the ender pearls which you get from
endermen which are the bottom creature
together you can combine those and they
make an eye vendor which will point
towards the stronghold and when you get
to the stronghold you can go to the end
and beat the game
this is a very crucial part
about
yeah about speedrunning
how do you find a stronghold so the
issue with finding a throttle is that
when you throw a pearl it will point you
towards the stronghold but
that's just a straight line and still
it's really hard to find it
so
the trick that i'm going to be talking
about today or one of the tricks
is this
there are fossils in the nether
and by looking at the position of the
fossil
you can actually find the location of
the stronghold without throwing or well
by well drastically reducing the amount
of pearl throw
when you actually get to the end uh you
can use a little trick where better blow
up if you sleep in them
and by clicking on the bed on the exact
the right timing
you can kill the underdragon just by
sleeping in a bed
while it is above you
um this is known as for bedding or five
bedding if you're worth it or
shakespearing like me um but yeah this
is just a little easter egg that just
turned into one of the most important
mechanics within minecraft speed running
um there's also some version differences
when it comes to speed running
namely pre 1.9 so before version 1.9
um
you had to actually kill enderman for
the ender pearls
between 1.9 and 1.15 villages uh
villagers got added and actually made
decent for trading so there instead of
killing under enderman for the pearls
you actually
um traded with villagers and then 116
plus which is the version that um
i'm talking about now or that
is most relevant to speedrunners today
is you actually go to a bastion uh
within another and you trade you partner
with the piglets there to get pearls
and i think the last bit of terminology
about minor chunk
uh where as i said you take a 16 by 16
area and you just completely mine it out
this is footage from one of our world
records
and you can just see a bunch of us just
happily mining away with our group
um
yeah and as you can see on the left
that's a 60 second area or a chunk and
that's the
yeah you start with a full one and you
just go
and it's empty
um all right now to go into my journey
as a speedrunner
so it started out when um i wasn't
university and i had a little bit of a
disagreement about how they thought
things
so within university discord i said hey
everybody at everyone
i'm going to give a
mini workshop on assembly
we have to do an assembly assignment for
this end of this week so
we'll we'll see how it goes um i'm gonna
be in the discord y'all can join if you
want i don't i don't mind
um
and that went on i did that for about
four hours and then halfway through i
got a message saying hey uh
we're at 150 people and we cannot fit
any more in the discord
so then my brother had to live stream my
discord to twitch to get everyone in
there and from that i had a little bit
of a following on yeah within the
university class of computer science
engineering cohort 20 uh 2020 2021
so
um yeah
one fateful evening after we were done
with some of our exams
um
we actually thought you know what we
have a bunch of people in here let's
just do a micro speed run
um within the speed running categories
there's like you can do it solo you can
do it with suit people three to four
five to nine or ten plus
and since 1.16 just released
and we did it with more than 10 people
or exactly 10
we were the very first person the very
first group to actually get or to
actually complete this category
and therefore we got a world record
um
that's done with my introduction to
speedrunning and we were like whoa
this is free
we can get a lot of these
so i made a separate discord
um
i invited a bunch of other speedrunners
and
uh well that grew out to be still the
discord that i used today for
uh for my co-speed runs
um and then about a few months later
once we were you know uh we were a
little bit burnt out on all the normal
80 percent speed running
we started thinking about minor chunk
and we started doing minor junk runs and
our minor chunk runs were
decent
but then
we started to get into minor chunk ssg
or chatseed glitchless
it's time to get technical
first off i want to give a big shout out
to these two people
on the left here we have neil i put a
little crown on his profile picture
because he's a king
this guy together with captain woodsex
set up the minecraft seat finding
libraries that we and most other
minecraft finders use today
and it has been amazing
and also this is henry on the right side
who actually has a um who actually
helped me and the other people with it
within this project figure out how
ravines work within minecraft
all right
so minecraft randomness minecraft when
you create a world you can enter a seed
you can enter letters as well but that
just turns it into numbers and it just
basically always makes it a 64-bit
number
that 64-bit number consists out of two
parts the structure seed which is the
left for the right most 48 bits and the
biom chip which is the left mode 16 bits
worlds with the same structure sheet
will have the exact same
structures
so villages
portal location ravine everything else
like that will always be the same
if a seed has the same structure sheet
we call those seeds sister seeds
then also the biome seeds and those
those bits get used for
generation of biomes terrain
mountains everything like that
so say you have a seat which has very
good uh location of the structure but
you know there's a giant hill in the
middle of everything
you can use you can just
make the biome sheet something different
while keeping the structure sheet the
same and you can get something else
all right
as i mentioned earlier neil made this
amazing library called feature utils
and feature utils
is amazing
before this existed we had to launch a
minecraft world hope it was a good seed
and try to see if we could find
something decent and that would take
hours
oh it would take
we have we would have like
tens hundreds of people trying to reset
to find a good seed for
any percent or minor junk or anything
really
but now with with the feature utils
you can just say okay
create
a world for 161 with this seed and tell
me
uh tell me the location of the four
villages in these regions and then we
just print it out to the console it
would simulate the random calls and it
would give the output
and then suddenly instead of this taking
i don't know a minute
it takes less than
say what
10 milliseconds to figure out the
location of four villages in any seat
it's changed everything we were suddenly
able to automate
and program
everything that we needed for
seed fighting well
not everything i'll get to that later
these are reveals
ravines
are
extremely useful for minor chunk runners
because as you can see
that is a lot of blocks that are not
there
it's a big gap in the world
but if you're doing minor chunk and if
this ravine goes through the middle of a
chunk
then suddenly you can cut away well
thousand two thousand three thousand
blocks just straight up out of your
chunk
that drastically reduces
the amount of time you need to mine
so they're a gold mine and we started
digging
is the code that then resent me about uh
reviews
so you could pass a random object it
would do some stuff with the
um with the position of the chunk
and it would say hey
is there
a
um
is there a veneer yes or no
this was huge this means for any chunk
in the world for any world
we can tell if they're a ravine or not
by just programming by just coding by
doing some yava it's it's
amazing
not only that
this code also contain the x y and z
offset so within the chunk so within the
16 by 16 area you also saw the exact
dial
or the exact block where it would uh
yeah it would generate
but also the yaw pitch
and more importantly
width
we could use
a we could find
the widths of the ravines that spawned
the direction they spawned in and
whether or not they spawn
this was amazing
so we started coding
we had um
we did a bunch of stuff just in pure
java with just our own code and neil's
code and then reach code
and we made a program that multithreaded
went through all the seeds
and tries to look okay can i find one
ravine that is decently wide another
ravine that is decently wide
do they intersect somewhere and
you know close enough that it's actually
useful
and if so
can we get some nice structure sheets
that are not from like world seeds so
that it is actually close to spawn
so here we combine all our knowledge so
far you know the structure sheets where
you would get the ravines the world
seeds where the spawn location change
and it would give us a bunch of seeds
together with the location where they
intersected
but this was still a lot of seats we had
thousands if not tens of thousands of
seats
to manually check and see how many
blocks are here is this a good spawn is
this decent you know it was a lot of
work
then we went on to part two you see
checker
so what uh what gullah and utroth two
people within our group actually did
is they made a um
they made a script that would straight
up call minecraft code in java
it would create a world
and it would
as you can see here it would call check
world and we'll check what would do it
would take the world and it would see
okay how many blocks are in here
and
yeah
that's it it would go through every
chunk through every 16 by 16 area around
uh
around the ravine
and it would see okay what's the best 16
by 16 area
that we can find
and it will be an output for example for
sheet 380 blah blah blah
we have a chunk that only has four
thousand blocks
within with x x coordinated thirty five
and that coordinates minus fifty
this is amazing
we found this with it
so there's a 16 by 16 area here
that is intersected
by five different ravines at least from
what we could tell
all going towards the same point in the
middle here
just got rid of a lot of blocks
and just to illustrate how many blocks
got rid of uh it got rid of
this is it side by side to a normal
minecraft chunks approximately 16 000
block
compared to our chunk
and eighty 3687 blocks
this was an enormous improvement for
minor chunk across the board
set seed run or well set seats uh solo
sets c go up sets the quads set c five
to nine sets c ten plus shattered within
a week
it ends up giving us this record
four minutes and thirteen seconds
that is how long it took
to mine out an entire chunk in minecraft
that is less than a third of the time
that i've been talking so far
this shattered everything but you can
ask yourself
how
how do we figure this all out
so as i said before neil is a king a god
an absolute shad within the world of
minecraft or at least within minecraft
speedrunning
within the old server we found uh he
made this which i i used the second one
the decompiler mc but these are all ways
that you can actually look at
minecraft code
and you can use mappings different
mappings and you can just see what it
says and how it works decompile it have
a look at how have a look at it
side note it is an absolute mess
trying to understand this stuff is
very tricky and sometimes you'll just
spend like
like three four five six out hours up to
days
looking at a piece of code trying to
figure out what is it doing and how
they're doing it just because you want
to make sure a chest spawns instead of
being overwritten by air for example
but now that we can read minecraft code
we can see this
this is the code for ravines that um
that then we found in um
in minecraft code it's actually called
canyons instead of ravines
and this is the official version of it
at the top you can see the
israelite on the next float is less than
0.02
um
which basically is you know does the
ravine spawn here and if it does then it
calls it guar function and then it will
give you the x y and z coordinates which
are d d2 and d3 it'll give you the yaw
and which and pitch which are f2 and f3
and it will give the length which is n7
so
it is definitely not legible
but if you do a bit of research try to
figure out what what
what goes where and what the variable
names actually mean
you can figure out what a thought is
so
back to the knee trick
stronghold
strongholds are procedurally generated
in rings
there are nine rings in total i think
and
um these rings generate around zero zero
um
and for example in the first ring there
will be three strongholds within twelve
hundred and twenty eight hundred blocks
from spawn
second ring is between four thousand and
six thousand there's six uh six drones
etcetera etcetera etcetera
we don't care
when you're speed running you want to be
as fast as possible and having to travel
all the way to a second ring stronghold
no way nobody does that we only care
about this first ring
uh which is good because limit
situations for us and it also makes the
programming a lot easier so there's a
few types that you can do to actually
find the stronghold
so as i said when you throw an ender
pearl it gives you an arrow straight
towards where the um where the throne
will be
so here is an example of how you would
travel to it
so you would draw a pearl travel
approximately that way you know go off
throw another one see how far they are
apart see what the angle distance is
um and just go all the way until it's
really close then go 90 degrees off your
path and throw another one and you can
triangulate it using the two yeah to
skew
point and then you found the throttle it
takes a long time
this is a lot of walking
so what people have figured out
is um an important note here
within the nether that second dimension
i'm talking about
every single block you travel actually
equates to eight blocks in the overworld
so
when you
um when you go into the nether when you
travel 100 blocks or 200 blocks
that in the overall actually 800 or 1600
blocks that cuts your time by eight
you know logically
so what people started doing is they
went into the into the nether tried to
find their uh their fortress and bastion
to get the blade rods and pearls
and then instead of traveling all the
way back
going out and then traveling all the way
to the to the fortress or to the um to
the stronghold
what they would do is they would go to
approximately a place that would bring
you to the ring place the portal
and pray
hope that you get close to the
strongholds
in some documented cases
people just randomly placed their portal
and got put right smack dab in the
center of the stronghold
like a few rooms away from the portal
room
um this was the meta for a while it
actually still is the meta because any
other method takes a little bit longer
but it's also
really inconsistent like if you have a
good blind you can be in the portal if
you're blocked away but if you have a
bad blind you can be up to 1300 blocks
away and that's
still really really bad if you have to
go out walk all the distance you know
your runs dead
so what people started doing is doing
estimated travel where they would leave
the portal throw a single pearl see okay
it's in this direction then go back to
the nether travel a few blocks a few
other blocks or whatever and then make
another portal and hope they're closer
uh then there's another one which is
calculated travel which is where you
would take
two pearls and uh you would very
carefully note down the coordinates and
the
angle of the intersection and hope you
know
see if it see if it works
um and then put it into a calculator and
because you have two lines they will
eventually meet somewhere and you can
actually calculate where the throttle
will be
but then
one fateful day
match you did and i quote
hacking invent of a threat
divine travel
people were calling this this because it
simply looked divine
made by the gods there's no way this
could make sense but somehow it does
to explain what this is i need to get
into the different kinds of random
minecraft users
so minecraft random object and chunk
rand
uses
a set seed like just any other random
object you can say okay this is the seed
and then all the random numbers that
come from it will always be the same
if you say
set seed one next number will be five if
you do it somewhere else in the other
side of the world set seed one next
number will still be five
they also have a thing called set garber
sheet which you can use to
get a specific random number for every
chunk so it will be different per world
seed per chunk
but it will always be the same for that
chunk for that world
then there's also set terrain seed
population seed decorated seed feature
seed there's a bunch of other stuff but
we will not be going into that now
we just have to look at that garbage
sheet
set garbage sheet takes the world seed
um
puts that on a random object this is
within a random object
creates two next longs
multiplies those by the chunk a and
chunk z
and then xors those two numbers with the
world seed and then set that as the c
that's like the actual seed that gets
used for the random thing
it sounds really complex
but what match you figured out
is that if you put the chunk x and chunk
z at exactly zero so if you're within
the chunk zero zero
then the actual final calculation this
one for seed
will be zero times something
xor zero times something x extra world
seed or
just world seed
so what a set garbage sheet call at
chunk zero zero does
is exactly the same as just setting the
seed to the world seed that is the most
important thing to take away from here
and if you look at the codes for
fossils which are those things i showed
before
um
it calls the shed garber seed with the
structure sheet and then the chunk x
trunk g and then it does a random call
again at chunk zero zero that will just
be the same as saying seed world seed
for the ravines it does the exact same
thing there's a plus one here but that's
that's semantics you can ignore that
that also has the same effect as just
setting it to the world seat
and as you can see
it goes for the strongholds the
generation of the strongholds and like
the placement for those three
strongholds within the ring
is shedding the seed to the world seed
and then it calls the next double which
gives you the random number between zero
and one
and multiplies that by
um by two pi to get an
angle within the in radian within the
circle
so by looking at the x coordinate
of a four though at chunk zero zero
you can directly map that
to the angle
of the stronghold within the first ring
and also the second and the third
stronghold because they're always
equally spaced apart so you can add
a circle divided by three and it will be
like you know one here one ear one here
so they will be equally spaced apart
same works for ravines however that is a
little less consistent but it's also
something that i found out
at 0 0 if a ravine spawns we know that
the angle will be less than 0.02
this is amazing this gives us a way to
look where the stronghold is without
throwing any pearls whatsoever
and people started making charge for it
so
um
yeah if you find a fossil with x
coordinate zero then your first divine
location is in another two five one
fifty
and people started using this
many of these charts started popping up
and by god did it work
because a few weeks later
this run was had by brent
dilba nine minutes and 38 seconds
by using the vine travel
you can see here uh he pauses game looks
at the um
looks at the fossil and the fossil is at
let's see
expedition eight within chunk zero zero
which you can see here but it's a little
bit illegible but it's expedition eight
so he went to the chart looked up for
expedition eight and made a portal
somewhere close to the coordinates
and he spawned
right in the middle of the stronghold
no enderpearl's throne no triangulation
no calculated travel straight up divine
travel
sprayed went in there and
shattered
the world record
second place our first place before the
run was 11 minutes and 7 seconds in game
time
this guy didn't cut off
a minute
not a minute 15 seconds he got off
one and a half minutes
from the time he shattered the 11 minute
barrier he shattered the 10 minute 30
barrier he shattered the 10 minute
barrier he shattered 9 45 and went
straight for the 936
that's my talk i want to give a quick
shout out to neil and captain wootax for
making the um
making the libraries k4y4 for adding me
to the threats and routing discord where
most of this was discussed matthew
boland for actually inventing divine
travel and being one of the smartest
people within minecraft street finding
community
leila close the witch for helping me
with um
with a bunch of stuff and also just
being generally all around amazing
within the community this is denver for
helping me with the
um
with the
ravine code calling neutral for making
the seed checker and my brother yellow
for helping me out with all of these
projects
thank you