good luck parker and we'll let we'll
leave
the bummer of this is that the the
speaker card for me has me with short
hair and i've since run out my hair a
significant amount so
uh i was hoping to like full surprise on
you all but just just just take look at
that picture think about i've had really
long hair and it looks better than
scott's
[Music]
i love it
you're getting a round of applause from
the i don't know if you could hear the
popcorn in the back of the room
yeah so i will introduce you now and i'm
going to be very mean
um
but yeah so ladies and gentlemen someone
who spoke at beer con 2 and played a
musical outro as well absolutely
um parker seaman burnout is not required
parker take it away my friend
well thank you all for having me as
mentioned my name is parker seaman and
i'm going to do a little talk here on uh
burnout
um but first
to to
do this right i'll talk about myself for
a little while um so who am i um i am my
name is parker seaman as mentioned i am
a
senior in um grad school studying cyber
defense and also working as a devsecops
engineer
always really enjoyed
learning about security and also being
able to share what i've learned with
others
what i found is the most interesting
part of
the cyber security world for me is the
intersection between people and
computers
and how all those relate to each other
um it's because of that i think that the
talk about burnout and mental health is
is worth talking about as with these
computers really don't do anything
unless they have a person behind them
um
so that's who i am and here is
why should you listen to me um well to
be quite honest i don't have a lot to
compel you here i am just standard
regular guy
with my main qualification here being
that i have experienced burnout as i
imagine other people have
um
which is why i want to present this talk
as a set of ideas but not as a
definitive solution
uh the problem of burnout cannot be
easily encompassed fully in the uh in
the time that this talk takes up but
however what i can do is bring some
attention to the issue and i hope that
doing so we can
encourage further conversation and
um potentially improvements to
um
the the problem of burnout
so now that i've explained myself a
little bit let's get into this what is
burnout uh burnout is a series of racing
games developed by criterion games the
first two games are published by claim
entertainment well later installments
and this is a funny joke uh what burnout
actually is is um well if you go by the
the who's classification her definition
is burnout is a syndrome
uh conceptual sorry conceptualized as a
result of chronic workspace stress that
has not been successfully managed
and the ways that this manifests itself
is you have people who are in a
in a in a career a position that they
have sought after um
work to the point where they no longer
find it
rewarding or engaging and can lead to
the point of people wanting to
leave that career entirely
uh just because they
can't be in that kind of environment
anymore
so
i mean why
you could it could be considered like
why why should this
matter if let's say there's a i hear in
the news frequently about how there is a
shortage of security engineers and more
people are going into that field to fill
the gaps well
part of the reason it first of all i
think the first reason it should matter
um
is
if you're if you're a hiring manager or
if you're looking it from just a purely
a utilitarian point of view
that
it stress people are less productive uh
plain and simple so if you have all
these people who are experiencing
burnout trying to perform their jobs
they're just not going to do it as good
what i think is a
stronger factor for why we
should be addressing burnout is
just taking care of people you spend a
significant portion of your life in at
your job doing doing work
and i just don't think it's right that
people should be having to experience
all that time
with
feelings of stress and anxiety and
depression and all these terrible things
that burnout can lead
people to have
so
if we if we have this issue
why are if this is an issue like how do
why is it happening in
uh the first place
and to try to answer this question i
asked around to a number of different
people friends i have and other people
of working in cyber security industry to
try to get an idea of
why
we have this
and i had gone into this with the
thought that it could be pinned down to
just a couple of reasons that if i got a
list of them then we could better
address it
what i found is that the reasons people
feel burned out are as
complex and
varied as individuals are
themselves
that said i do believe that there is an
overarching issue that plagues people
here that there is not enough support
and to give an example uh in a previous
stop of mine
uh there was many times where i did feel
overwhelmed with the workload i had um
both whether it was just regular
workplace tasks or activities or when
there was a crunch time with
uh certain events going on that would
stress out me and other co-workers but i
never felt burnt out and i think i can
contribute a significant portion of that
of my manager at the time
was very good at making time for all of
the people of her team
um would have one like
15 to 30 minute one-on-ones with every
member of the team every week so people
could be able to talk about not just
what's going on at work but
individual things that are going on in
everybody's life that if they that might
be affecting the work flow
and
it wasn't always something that i needed
but it was something that
led me feel better to know that i was
being supported
and that's from my perspective on this
issue and
talking to other people it seems like a
lot of problems people have
would be
not necessarily always fixed but at
least assisted with better support from
those around them um and i want to
expand that out from just a leadership
point but from
just a
community as a whole
which um i want to have that play into
the next point of
if those are the kinds of things that
can potentially help fix this issue of
burnout
uh what can we as individuals do to help
better
um address this issue
um
and like i've mentioned with bad slide
time and communication is key um but
going back to what can we do to try to
fix this
i
have to go back to i'm just some guy and
i can't fix this myself
um
if i could i would say there should be
better standards for how we treat people
how we engage with our
workforces and all that kind of stuff
but
i
don't have that kind of power all i can
do is encourage us to continue to make
this
um
known make sure we communicate it and
work together to create a understanding
that this is a thing that does happen
that
people coming into this career who
experience this and have had not had it
before can know that
it's okay and it is important to take
care of yourself
um
because you
you matter that's that's the main part
about that
um
i
i think that
it's just a continued discussion
understanding and cooperation is the
best way forward we have
to address this mental health issue we
have in our career and through that we
can
work towards better standards and
um
treatment of
uh of everyone around us
i
finished my talk last year um with it
with a little musical number and that
was that was fun but the tone of this
talk i feel like is different from that
one and i am apologizing to them i
apologize but it doesn't feel right to
do it this time so i will end with just
um a simple notion of
um just be good to each other
thank you
and that's
probably the best advice ever it's
pretty pretty damn good advice isn't it
it's the classic don't be a dick and i
think we've all we've all
been a dick from time to time and i
think you learn from it you'd like to
thank you anyway yeah yeah you know
i'll go ahead and find a slide where i
link before i'll get get your final
slightly get your final side up let's
we never got to see your face parker so
the very least you can do is share your
contact information and let people know
how to find you and see your face
this is great everything's going good
increase window swap file
defrag your hard drive
take take it
well what you can do is just take a
screenshot and then share it on the
discord channel yeah you can always do
that i can also yeah the slides are not
making it to the full slide
this is so good nothing
you couldn't hear look you could yeah
so for anybody watching or you're
watching you can read but if you're not
watching and you're listening and you
can't read at strong fanny underscore
yeah okay and the blog is
blog.strongthank.cc
strong
t-h-a-n-y a-n-y and um i all know that
the blog is down right now because my
reverse proxy is broken and
grad school is keeping me very busy and
while i'd like to have my blog up i paid
enough money for the for the classes so
i should probably do that first
um
yeah no we totally get we totally also
i'll be starting a podcast soon with a
friend and hoping to talk about uh cyber
security the uh ethics of security and
also just whatever happens to fall out
of our mouth
that is also not up yet but you can find
it probably sometime next month at tel
net.show that's t-e-l-l-n-e-t dot
s-h-o-w
yeah we're definitely going to check
that stuff out just coming back to your
the point in your talk the the feedback
on the on the on the chat has been
awesome
yeah but reference your yeah i didn't
want to finish with the musical number
because it just didn't feel appropriate
absolutely right that's that's fine but
for those of you who didn't tune into
beer con 2 last year um you missed out
on some amazing sax playing at the end
you did you can find
yourself at the beer farmer's youtube
channel or the twitch yes you can you
don't you don't have to miss out no
you've got to if you go to youtube.com
forward slash
look at the bc2 beercon 2 playlist look
for strong fanny or just watch them all
or watch them all yeah if you really
want to see the sax
there is but if sax is your thing yeah
dig out strong funny and pakistan
you can see its face and then imagine
the long hair yeah just basically
photoshop my hair out
paste it on
your hands
all my hair is nice
i'll i'll post some selfies there i'll
dox myself that's fantastic nice you
want some selfies to get your selfies
into the discord on the discord so
that's bare con dot tv forward slash
discord but we expect that i've not even
looked at discord since we started the
con i'm guessing there's quite a lot of
quite a lot of chatter in there at the
moment yeah fantastic
all right parker have a great weekend
thanks ever so much um never mind the
technical blips we got the material we
heard your voice you did a great job
thank you very much yeah yeah we love
you man have a good one cheers