oh vicky hi vicky hi everyone
good afternoon okay
okay wherever you are
so um we our next speaker is vicky lynn
um so she's gonna give us a talk about
how i landed a job as a pen tester in 10
months it's kind of like giving nick
cage gone in 60 seconds a run for his
money
um so vicky over to you over to you
hi everyone
thank you for being here
i'm very excited to give this talk
because this topic is so personal to me
and i hope by sharing my experience in
becoming a pen tester this can be
beneficial to you somehow
so
if you don't have any prior cyber
security experience and want to pivot to
pen testing
this talk is really for
you i started with knowing some basic
linux command
and a 2008 network plus certificate from
comptia
i didn't have any prior work experience
in cyber security
and so i decided
to get a reputable certificate
and get
concrete accomplishments as my trophy to
open the doors for me
i chose oscp because
it's a very hands-on certificate
and i want to learn the skills the way
it will be i will be using in the future
and oscp is pretty much
me trying to hack my way through
and five machines get enough points and
pass the exam
so typically people recommend
knowing linux networking
know how to recode and basic scripting
before start hacking
so even though i didn't know
all of them
i decided
to just start hacking and dive right in
there
i use two platforms
try hack me and hack the box
these platforms have
lab machines that
this that's designed for people to
practice hacking
and they're really great because they
are gamified
it's interesting
to hack there and the more i play
the higher the ranking
the more points i get and these are the
things i plan to put on my cv
on average
i practice four to six hours every day
while six days
a week
about three months into
my plan
i met my mentor maria through women in
cyber security
she is
already a cyber security professional
and through talking with her i learned a
lot on how
it is like working in the
in the field
she knew some people were organizing
cyber security conference and encouraged
me to do a lightning talk
around three months i really didn't know
much
but
i remember an exercise i did
using just a simple script to extract
password from firefox
and it was very interesting for me
so i decided to turn it into a talk
i submitted
and abstract to the organizers
then i got busy in preparing for my
upcoming oscp exam
before the exam
i've studied
around seven months
i've gone through all the all the course
materials and exercises
and rooted about 15 machines
on the exam day i prepared a whole table
of food and drinks to get me through the
next 24 hours
the exam is 24 hours
the very first machine i tackled is a
buffer overflow machine
this is a technique i've practiced many
times
so my plan was to knock it out of the
way as soon as possible and then move on
but i couldn't
two hours into the exam i was still
struggling on that freaking machine
so after nine hours i finally solved the
machine and it turns out to be the only
machine i've solved
i felt the exam
on the other hand i got some good news
that my talk was accepted
so i prepared the best i could and did
the talk it was a wonderful experience
around a month
at
oscp was taking way too long
than i expected
so i decided to take whatever i have
and
just start applying for jobs
probably because of my taiwanese route
i always want to get the most bang out
of my book
my inner guru told me to not cheap out
this time and i'm glad i listened
i've asked
three cyber security professionals to
give me feedback
on my cv
and they really helped me
present my accomplishment the best i
could
on cv
and i also paid for premium membership
on linkedin and zing just so that
i can
compare my profile to other candidates
and i can also know which companies
or head hunters have been checking out
my profile
and also just to show that i'm serious
about finding a job
i have a spreadsheet that keeps track of
the companies with the pentester rules
that i have applied
and the day that i get their first
response the day of this
of the first interview second interview
etc
and every day i will apply for pentester
rose
and i will
add more companies as i apply
and cross our companies as i get a
rejection
about 1 out of 10 applications i sent
now i would get a response back
i also network with
headhunters
what's really nice about working with
headhunters is
they are typically knowledgeable about
the current job market
and they are open to talk about
salary expectations and the realistic
expectations from the companies
and through which it really helped me
position myself in the market
one day i got an email
hi vicky
your cv looks very interesting and we
would like to have an interview with you
i went to the interview and the rest was
history
i'm three months into my new pen testing
role
and it is really the job i have been
looking
for i get to hack all day
i get to share my passion with people
and i get to do it anywhere i want
some of you might be wondering hey so
you got a job
without having a certificate
no i i have a network plus certificate
from 2008
even though it probably didn't help much
because it was so old
not having oscp
definitely cut out some of my chances
through a headhunter i know that some of
his clients
wouldn't even consider
candidates who don't have oscp or the
equivalent certificates
i will probably get more chances
if i i'm certified
but now looking back
i would like to say in confidence that
don't let not having certificates stop
you from applying for jobs
if you have done enough studying and
have something to show
and
so
to to summarize a little bit
how to
land a job as a pen tester
first
have a plan
whether it's more or less than 10 months
have something that work with your
schedule
if you can spend two hours a day
to study
then do that and do that consistently
once you've decided on your plan
stick to it from the beginning to the
end
second
collect trophies to open the door for
you
we've talked about certificates
you can also use things like
the number of boxes you've rooted the
global ranking or
the hacker pro hacker
status that you have on these online
practicing platforms
if you play ctfs
it's the same thing you can also talk
about it on your cv
i've had an interviewer who go into
detail about the ctfs i've played and
the challenges i've solved
i have a talk under my belt
you don't have to know the organizers to
do a talk
there are so many cyber security
conferences happening
globally every month
and many of them will be happy to give
new speakers a chance
now look at beacon
and let me tell you a secret
you don't have to do the best talk of
the world
to put it on your cv
so definitely find something that fits
you
you can if you know how to code that's
brilliant
do a coding project that has to do with
pen testing
even if you don't have any ideas now as
you study
ideas will come up and when it does you
know what to do
you can also write a technical blog
a senior pen tester
rana khalil
publishes
write ups
as she
hacked
as she was preparing for her oscp
and
i asked her how has this helped her in
her career
and she wrote back to me
it definitely helped in many ways in my
career
first it got me noticed
i've received many messages from
recruiters informing me that someone
technical on their team read my
write-ups
and asked them to reach out to me for a
position
that opened up on their team
in one scenario i've even had someone
wave the technical interview because
i've already showcased
that i know what i'm talking about
through my write-ups
second it advanced my knowledge in the
subject matter
since i had to explain to the general
audience through video or blog
i had to really properly understand it
to do that i spent countless hours
reading and researching about every
single thing
that i include in my content
so it really solidified my knowledge
and lastly you can also do a fun hacking
project
and this is an area where you can really
show your creativity and passion
just through a quick google i found
something called arduino tv annoyer
pretty much
you make your own tv remote control and
you can go around and turn on people's
tv and off
and to annoy them
so keep it light and fun a little bit
mischievous is totally okay and
definitely stay within the legal
boundary
so third
get a mentor or a coach as early as
possible
do you know why world class athletes
have coaches
it's not because the athletes are not
great
it's because a good coach
can take a great athlete even further
even this is a service that you have to
pay now
trust me it will pay for yourself
once you once you lend the job you
wanted
so that concludes my journey and my tips
i would like to give a big thank you
for
my mentor maria and everyone who has
helped me
in becoming a pen tester
without them it is really
not possible
and i would like to give a big thank you
for the beer farmers at beer cotton
and i hope to see you again
you're very welcome
um
first of all congratulations
it's a fantastic story a journey
and
you achieved your objective you got to
where you wanted to be through having a
passion for the subject
and perseverance
so well done and i think you'll you'll
go on and flourish even further so
that's a wonderful story
yeah
yeah listen vicky thanks for coming on
beercon3 thanks for being part of it and
thanks for sharing your story thank you
thank you amazing i wish you all the
best
youtube thank you