of C&C this is not the evolution of
cookies-and-cream because I mean
honestly where do you go from here it's
the ice cream of the future but we have
it today this is not the evolution of
coheed and cambria although they've got
a number of albums that progress through
the years in interesting ways I know
we're talking about command and control
today although I don't know what it has
to do with nuclear missiles but this was
the best picture I could find like I
said my name is John askew not the
trance DJ from the UK although I am
somewhat of a fan I'm just a guy from
right here in Kentucky than doing
penetration testing and red teaming
stuff for going on 12 years now I still
consider myself a beginner the more I
learned the more I realize I don't know
hardly anything so I'm always trying to
learn more I also enjoy writing software
and that's part of why I'm here today
some stuff does played around with and a
quick disclaimer these are my statements
not positions or views of any clients or
employers so I'm really honored to be
speaking here today in front of you all
this is a really big room I'd like to
give you a quick overview of what we're
gonna be talking about for the next 40
45 minutes I'm going to break it into
three different parts first we're gonna
do a brief history of command and
control and it's not really a
chronological history it's more I'll be
kind of cherry-picking some different
commanding control methods and talking
about how capabilities change and evolve
between them from the past through
what's what do we use today most
commonly and then looking towards the
future what what things are we going to
be seeing from command control going
forward second with that you know
forward-thinking view how can we
increase red team capabilities I'm going
to talk a little bit about capabilities
and and maturity and hierarchy of needs
and what what are the ways that we can
advance these capabilities
these into the future and then lastly
from a blue team perspective I'm not
very much of a blue team er but I want
to talk about how we mature our
detection response in kind with these
new potential capabilities how do we
detect those and respond to them and I
think there are a few interesting things
from from some research that'll
potentially be useful to that effect so
to start off with let's go over just a
brief definition of command and control
what we're talking about today the mitre
attack framework gives a really good
working definition here it's a tactic
which in I'm sure you've heard about
mitre attack framework this weekend from
multiple other talks but you've got a
hierarchy of tactics techniques and
procedures or processes and this is a
tactic so a high-level thing that
represents how adversaries communicate
with systems under their control within
a target Network so basically when an
attacker gains access to a host or
system how do they retain control of
that host remotely over a given time
period
there's other related components you
know how do you get that payload on the
system to use stagers how do you persist
your control how do you make sure that
that that malware continues to run and
then post exploit modules all the fun
stuff that you can do while you have
access we're not really going to talk
much about those I'm going to try to
focus just on the communication channel
aspect because that's more than enough
to cover an hour's time a few other
concepts I want to cover before we dive
in capability is something I'm going to
repeat at least say basically the
ability to perform or achieve certain
actions or outcomes in offensive
security we can use this to describe the
extent of what advert adversarial threat
actor can achieve during an attack and
specific to command and control I think
we'll be talking about capabilities
along several different axes or or acts
aspects like reliability security
concealability on the flip side you've
got this idea of constraints so
attackers and defenders both operate
under a number of constraints which are
limits that are placed on those
capabilities these can be general that
that apply to you know your your blue
team as a whole or your red team as a
whole how many how much time resources
personnel do you have to be able to do
research and be able to develop things
more specifically we've got situational
constraints like a tack surface you know
in a particular environment that you're
attacking what does the attack surface
look like what are the the firewall
rules and endpoint controls and all
these other things are going to
influence your decision on what command
and control method to use and what will
will work in those situations and also
situational awareness being aware of
that environment of what's going on and
knowing you know what the what is being
looked for those kind of things are also
going to affect how you decide to do
command control and so you got
capabilities and constraints that are
kind of playing against each other so
let's jump into a brief history of
command and control and this is going to
be more like a narrative than an actual
history but once upon a time there's a
buffer overflow and Bob's Network server
I guess it was the 90s and it was cool
to not you know check your bounds in
memory so we got a vulnerability Alice
finds this vulnerability she wants to
exploit it but she didn't want to commit
to a specific payload up front she liked
the ability to kind of retain control
and decide what she wants to do over
over a period of time maybe send some
commands receiver response and then
decide you know from there make make
some new decisions on what to do so
Alice made a bind shell so I guess the
bind shell is probably the one of the
simplest types of commanding control you
can you can think of right you got
malicious software that opens up a port
on your target system and then your
attacker can connect directly to it and
get a shell you can you can send
commands you get responses back and life
is good you can make that target do your
so that's great now we have something we
didn't have before we've increased our
reliability we've also increased our
agility we got some flexibility to send
a command receive a response and then
based on what that response is we can we
can make other decisions the different
commands to send maybe we've decreased
security a little bit by opening a port
on a target network that someone else
can connect to but we'll ignore that for
the time being but there's some problems
with the bind shell - it's definitely
not the end all of command and control
right there's situations that this is
just not going to work for us
in particular you know you've got
firewall rules anybody that's ever done
an external penetration test or red
teaming exercise where you're trying to
gain a foothold on an internal network
you're probably gonna do some kind of
fishing you're probably going to try to
to exploit endpoints which are inside of
a corporate network inside of a
perimeter firewall and those firewalls
have ingress rules and in that and all
this other stuff that prevents you from
going from the internet directly and
into their network so mine shell is no
go for something like fishing right
that's okay because now we have the
reverse shell which is a reverse
connection might I read that right okay
that's that's the joke they realize that
yep so reverse shell is almost the exact
same thing as a vine shell accept the
connection starts in Reverse instead of
opening up that port the target is going
to connect back to the attacker and then
at that point the connections
established you can shuffle those bytes
back and forth send commands get
responses life is good you can make it a
target do your bidding so we've
increased our capabilities right yay
weak egress filtering because this is
gonna work in a lot more scenarios
because he dress filtering and in
corporate environments is generally a
lot weaker than ingress filtering
there's usually some way out of
environment or at least it's a lot
easier to get out than it is to get in
so we've increased our reliability it's
working in a lot more situations that
are useful to us and you know we've
we've maybe slightly increased security
and scalability
things as well but mainly we've got that
increased reliability which is cool so
reverse shell is great we can all go
home right now now this this is there's
still some constraints here because
they're egress filtering does exist so
you might have to pick the right port to
go out maybe they blocked all ports from
the particular host you want to
compromise so it can't just get out at
all and this is not a particularly
stealthy method right it's just a raw
you know probably TCP connection between
two IP addresses that's just shuffling
bytes back and forth that have commands
and command responses in them maybe
you've got some encryption but it's it's
not something that's necessarily going
to blend in well with what under a high
amount of scrutiny so oh and there's one
other thing
potential attribution so you've got this
payload that's connecting back to an IP
address on the Internet
whenever that gets detected you know
that IP address is going to be
associated with this this campaign and
so if you can start associating that
with other things and it's more
information for an investigation to to
use so what's what's the next thing
after reverse shells well let's just
yeah IRC channels
everybody loves IRC channels right so
this was actually something that was
really popular for botnets in the early
2000s there may still be some that use
piracy I don't know for those of you
don't know what IRA see is it's Internet
Relay Chat
it's what slack was like ten years ago
so if you know what slack is it's it's
like that but with but I got a terminal
like with the dark background yeah
so people started using IRC channels to
send their command control messages and
this is nice for a number of reasons but
the way it works is your targets join an
IRC server the connect to an IRC server
they join a channel and they listen for
commands and your attacker connects that
same Channel
types of commands out and those get
broadcast to all of your your targets
which then can execute the commands so
it's it's a little bit more
sophisticated than a reverse shell for a
number of reasons so first of all we
have moved from a raw network layer up
to a protocol layer and we're using the
IRC protocol not just raw TCP so there's
there's some you know increased
reliability with that because protocols
are more likely to be allowed if they're
in use in your target environment then a
protocol may be more likely to be
allowed to connect out to the Internet
we've also increased our concealment and
scalability because if presuming that
there's other IRC traffic on your
network then this can potentially blend
in right so this is great we've got an
IRC shell alright I receive commanding
control method but there are some
problems as well namely in twenty twenty
eighteen let's see here it is right 2018
I don't think many people are actually
using IRC does anyone using IRC a few
but is is anybody's work using IRC for
business purposes not a lot so this is
likely to stand out in a lot of places
that we would want to use it potentially
likely to be blocked and detected not
only for the fact that it's unusual but
also for the fact that for a decade or
more
we had lots of botanist using this so
you got a lot of a lot of scrutiny but I
like this idea of towing through
protocols right so are there other
protocols that we can tunnel through
sure we can we can do just about
anything right
you get ICMP
which you can tell through but it's it's
kind of slow and in Cluj II you can you
can send stuff through SMTP but he most
kind of complicated I don't really want
to get into that can of worms we can
just use raw UDP there we go the the the
you know everybody's favorite UDP joke I
tell you but you might not get it and I
wouldn't care if you did but there is
one or actually two the one protocol in
particular that turns out to work really
well and that's DNS so and we're here in
the modern age now this is this is stuff
that that everybody's using DNS
tunneling works well for command and
control for a number of reasons
the two biggest I can think of is one
it's very ubiquitous you know you can't
have the internet without DNS you have
to be able to resolve names to IP
addresses to get anywhere so every so
DNS is is necessary and it's gonna be on
every network it's also got its own
built-in routing right DNS is recursive
so you you make a query you don't have
to query your your attacker server you
can query your local DNS server and then
it will rehearse - another one - another
one - another one and it'll eventually
get back to your malicious DNS server
through the magic of DNS it's built
right into the protocol which is great
so we've got high reliability because
those two reasons that I just stated and
also concealment because DNS is
everywhere right so great we can all go
home no because actually turned out if
you're looking for DNS if you're doing
DNS inspection it's it's fairly
detectable and there's ways to hide it
but you know it's it in most cases it
tends to be obvious when when you're
using DNS for command and control unless
you're being very very careful about it
so so in fact it does serve a use for
well I'm gonna let's let's move on to
one other protocol and wrap things up on
the history HTTP as is the other will
probably the most popular method for
command and control not least of which
because it's the most common protocol on
the Internet
and its use in commanding control tends
to be mostly building a custom HTTP
server and a client and then doing some
type of polling or beaconing out to that
server so you build your HTTP request
payload and you encode your commands
into URLs or headers or parameters you
send it and you do the same thing in the
HTTP response you encode those
commanding control commands within that
protocol that HTTP protocol and you can
even get very you can get a lot of
flexibility with this there's a thing
that's commonly referred to as malleable
c2 profiles where you can tweak all
those parameters right you can you can
say I want to make the URL look a
certain way and I want to make the
headers look a certain way and I want to
make the post parameters look a certain
way and and make it behave like this in
such a manner to to simulate particular
websites or things like that so we've
got a high reliability and
concealability just for the fact that
HTTP is used everywhere and you get a
lot of flexibility with with malleable
profiles you've also got this this idea
of resilience where we've gone from a
stateful
like a synchronous connection like a TCP
connection or something like that to
something that's stateless you've got a
request and response and then you can
you know wait five seconds in your other
requests respond so you can wait an hour
you can wait a day or whatever but
there's no you don't have to have a
constant connection you've also got
other infrastructure like
proxying that that helps make it more
resilient to the failure so these are
all good things to have in a command and
control protocol and help us out a lot
there's still some constraints in
particular if you're setting up an HTTP
command and control server you never put
it on some IP or domain or at some URL
and once it's discovered that that thing
is gonna allow you to tie it back to
other things so there's that but then I
want to talk about this other concept
that many of you may be familiar with
domain fronting which is not a command
control method per se but it can be used
effectively with HTTP to mask your your
actual destination and avoid blocking
because when you do this and I don't I
don't really have time to go into the
technical details of how this works but
connections go to an actual cloud load
balancer or something like that so it
looks like it's actually going to Amazon
or Google or somewhere and then on the
back end it gets routed to your actual
malicious command control server and
it's used to be possible with Google and
Amazon Cloud Front but both of them
earlier this year supposedly fixed that
issue it may still be possible to do
with Microsoft's Network and there's
lists on on github of potential domain
fronting domains that you can you can
test out so this is still a legitimate
way to mask your command control traffic
but definitely took a hit by Google and
Amazon eliminating it so you could get
really really close to looking like
actual legitimate traffic with HTTP and
domain fronting and some of these
profiling things but there's nothing
quite as good as the real thing right so
the last thing I want to talk about is
apps and third-party services so we
seen a lot of more recently a lot of
commanding control traffic utilizing
specific applications or third-party
services we've seen one-off tools and
POCs have been created for specific
services we've seen some tools add
external commanding control plug-in
capabilities where you can try to write
a plug-in to use a specific method or
service and add it in and there's
definitely been used by real world
threats so this is something where by by
going from looking like you know Google
cloud platform traffic to being actual
Google cloud platform traffic increases
our concealment and also increases our
reliability some constraints their
situational awareness so if you're gonna
use something like this you need to be
aware of what your target is using and
we'll talk about that more in a minute
and there's some probably some other
constraints with it as well but this is
kind of where I want to focus a little
bit on the future of command control how
we'll be using more of these third-party
channels so I'd say it's likely that all
these methods will continue to work in
some cases particularly opportunistic
attacks and in fact you know it's a bind
shell or reverse shell is gonna work for
you in a particular situation then you
might as well use that instead of doing
something more advanced given your
situation and your constraints you're
operating under hopefully we're gonna
see mature organizations continue to
improve their capabilities for detecting
and preventing a lot of these methods
and there's tooling out there that
exists up to a certain level I believe
but on the Red Team side if we want to
be able to succeed against these mature
organizations we're gonna need to blend
more and more into that legitimate
traffic as much as possible and that's
going to include those third-party
channels so the next thing I want to
talk about is how we take this and we
start to increase those capabilities
so some of you may be familiar with
Maslow's hierarchy of needs the idea of
a person being having a number of needs
and they have to be met in a certain
order
like the foundational ones before you
move up the pyramid so there's no point
in worrying about a scene if you can't
eat today right and then there's also
this which has nothing at all to do I
think with with the hierarchy of needs
but I like Parks and Rec but I think I
think it'd be useful to talk about
command and control from a Red Team
perspective and a hierarchy of needs so
you've got these different capabilities
for different different aspects of
capabilities that I've been talking
about like reliability and security and
I think you know those at the bottom
reliability and security are probably
the the the most foundational of these
you gotta have something that works that
accomplishes your goal and then and then
well here let me just jump into one at a
time we need something that's reliable
right we need something that that can
deliver our messages our command control
messages we need something that works
not just in the lab but but on the field
and we need at the same time something
that's going to be secure because if if
we're introducing vulnerabilities into a
client's network as part of a a
penetration test or a Red Team
engagement then that's a that's a huge
problem right we don't want to make them
less secure I make them more secure so
security is important and so thinking
about the needs for for a command
control framework we gotta think about
encryption and authentication so in
particular TLS is is not enough today
not every single organization out there
is doing man-in-the-middle inspection of
Tianna TLS but enough are that it should
just be assumed and we should make this
this security built-in and as simple and
foot gun-free as possible we don't want
to shoot ourselves in the foot
oh I don't know what a foot gun would
actually look like okay so we also need
moving up that pyramid from from yeah
reliability and security next thing I
had in here was concealment we want to
be able to avoid detection for at least
some minimum period of time against some
level of detection capabilities right
it's kinda it's got to work long enough
for us to get the job done if they
figure it out you know two weeks later
or six months later it may not be as big
of a deal but we need it to at least
conceal ourselves long enough to achieve
our goal beyond that we want resilience
we want something that's going to
operate and continue to operate in the
face of unexpected outages so I'm sure
no one's ever had a shell just disappear
for no reason in the middle of
engagement right if we can build
redundancy and then then that can help
us out there and then on top of that is
agility we want to be able to adapt we
want to have flexibility to adapt to new
and unexpected needs because you know
unexpected things happen in pretty much
every engagement and not only be able to
adapt but be able to adapt quickly so if
we can build a build tools and
frameworks that allow us to do that
easily then we're gonna be that much
better off and then you got features at
the top which are like icing on the cake
I guess like remember the old food
pyramid you had like sugar at the very
top that's what that is
so yeah resilience I'm gonna repeat
myself here sorry slides got a little
bit out of order
expect messages to be lost and still
operate expect some network traffic to
be blocked or modified and still operate
and try to learn from other software
engineering disciplines like there's
third a lot of stuff out there on
message of passing and on consensus and
things like that we don't have to get
too advanced but but there's some things
we can click pick up there and apply to
our tools
yeah agility and in particular it'd be
nice if we can plug in new transport
mechanisms during engagements so we
realize that a target is using a
particular service and we can adapt that
service to our needs in the middle of
them gate would that be nice ok so I
started writing some some code I I
called this thing hyper wave for
whatever reason it's a it's a framework
for decentralized messaging over the
Internet
basically message passing that can be
used as part of a command control
framework and the the code will be
posted there on bitbucket
hopefully later today or tomorrow I've
tried to thinking about these needs I
tried to think about how you would build
something that would meet a lot of these
needs and this is in no way a completed
concept but some things that I tried to
to lead with were using some functional
programming principles where you build
larger things from from small pieces
kind of like Legos open a big Lego thing
because it gives you a lot of
flexibility you can rearrange those
those like I wanted to do something
that's decentralized and have
first-class routing built in because and
move a little bit away from a
client-server model because you could
still model a client server with a
decentralized network so it gives you
more more of that flexibility and I
wanted to have pluggable transports so
that you could you can change things out
use use different types of channels
within the same framework
again for that for that flexibility and
adaptability so I'll just go over a few
things about the architecture at a high
level there's a concept of an address
which is a unique identifier kind of
like an IP address currently it's
represented as a you UID for value but
every every peer in the network has a
unique address you can't have a message
passing framework without messages right
so this is this atomic element of
communication from one peer to another
and the message is basically a
combination of a header and a body the
header is that metadata that the
framework uses and then the body is
whatever the implementation decides to
use so you you you can make that
whatever you want then there's this
concept of an envelope which is the
encrypted message plus the minimum
amount of metadata that you need to
handle and deliver that message within
the framework right now that metadata
includes a destination address which
allows you to relay and deliver
ultimately the messages and some type of
identifier for each individual message
that allows you to to track those and
then a transport which is the mechanism
for asynchronously sending and receiving
those envelopes so these are generally
speaking services that can be used
abused for ad hoc message queuing and
this is kind of where that that 99 ish
number comes in from the very beginning
of the talk the title now don't get too
excited because not all these things are
necessarily available right now for for
use but the general concept is you take
a lot of these different services and
plug them in interchangeably and still
get your your messages delivered and
you'll take an envelope and be able to
embed it inside a base64 text body or a
JPEG file or an mp3 or other different
types of
of formats that these different services
can natively utilize and going down this
route I found there's a few few
interesting benefits to to looking at
things in this way so one example here
is transitivity so say you've got you
build this this hypoid network you've
got three peers none of them can connect
directly to each other let's just say
Pier 1 is our commanding control server
and Pier 2 is like a workstation on a
target network that can get out to the
internet and can in fact reach Dropbox
so you can use this framework to send
messages through Dropbox to appear
number two so now they can communicate
and then Pier 3 is actually blocked
completely from the internet
but they both have both peer-to-peer
three have access to a CIFS file share
so we can use that to to relay messages
between 2 and 3 and then by transitivity
which is just I guess I pretend it's way
of saying routing you can send messages
between peer 1 and P 3 and I'm actually
gonna gonna show a demo of this specific
example in a second example number two
is redundancy so another thing we kind
of get for free by approaching things
from this way is you can have redundancy
so we got pier 1 and P 2 and they can
both connect to s3 bucket of some sort
and they can both connect to Google
Drive so we can have them use both
methods to relay messages back and forth
and then if one goes down then you can
have failover through the other one
which is something that would be useful
in an engagement right to have you
always want to have multiple ways so
you're not you're not out of luck if one
goes down
so I'm gonna try to do a live demo but I
have no internet access so I did make a
video and unfortunately it seems like
the live demo is not as commonly used to
be I kind of missed that but here's a
here's the thing I recorded this morning
when I didn't have internet access so
and to preface this so there's the
framework and then I wrote a little
implementation of an implant and a like
a server so that I could I could
actually do something with it so this in
this situation I've got two implants
running on Windows machines they can
both reach a file share like in that
first example and then I've got one
running here on my Mac that can can hit
Dropbox so they just play this so what
we're gonna see is I'm starting it up
what's going on this is getting cut off
I'm sorry you try a different way drag
it over it's almost as bad as well I've
been on there - all right is that big
enough you'll see that drag it there we
go that better yeah sorry about that all
right
so running the console here we've got a
console and we've got two peers that
that are our consoles aware of their
both those big UUID blobs we're gonna
send a shell command to that guy and
it's actually going to route through the
other guy first so we're gonna go to
Dropbox and then the other peer is gonna
pick it up from Dropbox and relay it
through SMB files here and then the
reverse is gonna happen to send the
response and I'll drag it I'll try to
drag it up biscuit lower so we got back
real exciting right so let's do
something a little bit more interesting
we'll do a directory listing list C
colon backslash and there's about 18
second round trip because we're polling
Dropbox every nine seconds well I guess
the max would be 18 seconds depending on
how the windows whine so in a second
we'll see we get back a directory
listing there we go so it worked that's
good
[Applause]
okay and that was not a live dama that
was a video but I appreciate the
applause anyway I mean I had a hard
enough time getting the video to work so
it can't even imagine what it would have
been like otherwise cool and I wanted to
talk a little bit about operational
concerns things you got to think about
if you has a red team or gonna use these
different third-party channels in
particular each each channel is going to
have its own concerns but there's also
credential handling concerns that are
more general with each service that
you're gonna use you know it's like
Dropbox for instance I wrote an implant
that used a connection to Dropbox so
obviously I had to embed some type of
credentials in that implant and then
once that implant gets reverse
engineered those credentials get
discovered you want to make sure that
whatever credentials you give it are as
as sandboxing as limited as possible so
that that you limit what can happen once
once that burning occurs yeah and then I
really need to get back into the this
last part make sure I've enough time so
talking about a little bit about
increasing reading capabilities how do
we mature our detection and response in
kind we definitely want to start
anything at a fundamental level
adversarial threats and that kind of
alluded to earlier
we'll use the minimum capabilities
necessary to achieve their goal right if
all you needs a reverse shell then why
do some kind of fans of Dropbox stuff if
if the reverse shell will work so it's
important that we on the defensive side
address less mature methods first make
sure that that we've got those
fundamental things and like I said I'm
not an expert on the blue side but
there's a lot of things that
that are more fundamental at the network
and protocol ever layer that we need to
look at and think about reducing our
attack surface that pictures so that I
have to get out okay but what would I
really want to talk about in the next 10
minutes or so is this application layer
and so as I as I've looked at tunneling
commanding control traffic through a
bunch of different types of services
there's some commonalities that that you
see so if we're trying to detect that
abuse of applications it's it's kind of
dependent upon the specific application
that you're looking at as to how you
would detect abuse because each each
service is very different and we're
talking now about something above the
network layer and above the protocol
layer we're more like an application
layer so some of these can be very
challenging to display you can to be
very challenging to discriminate between
legitimate and malicious usage and the
tools that exist today that I'm aware of
the the commonly deployed tools don't
have that granularity to look within the
application to make determinations about
whether this is a good use of drop box
or bad use the drop box it may just be a
loud drop box or bought it so how can we
do a little bit better than that and I
want to go through ten ways to detect
abuse of using these services for
commanding control these are general
principles that should be kind of
adapted to your specific needs
they're a mixture of specific artifacts
you can look for in requests and more
general application behaviors and most
of these will require that TLS
inspection to look within your HTTP
traffic but that's something we kind of
assumed
and these are not like a top 10 or even
the best 10 or anything like that it's
just 10 10 things that I've did that
have come up as I've been looking at
doing this the first ones probably the
easiest unused services so when somebody
says we don't use that here that's
probably a red flag right so you got our
organization's say you use everything
AWS you're all about AWS all-in and you
see something going to Google cloud
platform one day that's an easy way to
throw a red flag right maybe even you
know beep block all traffic to Google
cloud if you're not using it in the
enterprise but at least you should
should be able to detect it that's an
easy way to raise a red flag I didn't
really talk at all about endpoint type
controls today but this this one is just
too good to pass up
looking at correlation between processes
and traffic you can see stuff like you
know else a study XE should never be
connecting to weird serve third-party
services right that's that's a given and
that might seem a little silly and
hopefully a a sophisticated attacker
would not be doing something like that
but the point is the attackers make
mistakes and so you need to be ready for
when those mistakes happen and be able
to catch that that one thing and then
start that investigation unique domain
activity so a lot of these services like
s3 for instance have unique domain names
associated with accounts or associated
with with particular buckets for
instance so if you know that your
environment uses these 10 s3 buckets for
4 prod and for your dev environment then
you can easily whitelist those and alert
on others that you see through you know
DMS queries or through HTTP traffic
unique URL paths URL parameters so
similarly something like Amazon's SQS
simple query service so those cue names
show up in the URLs if you know what
specific cues that you use then you can
whitelist those and you can alert on
ones that aren't on that whitelist and
these are just examples like sqs but
there's a lot of other services that
have unique things in the urls there's a
lot of other services that have unique
domain names like slack every every
slack workspace has its own unique
subdomain of us like com and share files
is the same thing so these are these are
broad principles depending upon what's
services we looking at headers are
another good place to look
user agent agent mismatches is a great
place to look for differences so certain
applications use particular user agent
headers and you know attackers may can
know that as well but it's a good place
to look for for potential abuse and
their application specific headers that
you can look for as well the presence or
absence of which may indicate a
legitimate application versus something
that's trying to pose as legitimate
application authentication is a good
place to look these these API keys these
OAuth tokens like when when I'm using
Dropbox earlier I've got a static API
key that I use for all the implants
which is going to look a little bit
different than actual use of Dropbox
where clients who all have unique API
keys so if you see in the same API key
coming from ten different workstations
then that's something that should arouse
suspicion and sometimes even over time
like you've got those keys rotating so
if you see a static key
one hour two hour five hours that hasn't
been rotated then that can be a good
place to to look as well to raise a red
flag behaviors which api's are being
used how they're being used a lot of
these services offer multiple api's they
can do some of the same things so the
the ones that you decide to use in your
application versus somebody else's can
all you to differentiate and the order
in which they're used timing so many
things go back to to a time factor that
the transporter I was using earlier was
polling Dropbox every nine seconds it's
kind of an odd number intentionally
other applications that use Dropbox will
call it different intervals or they
won't pull it all they'll use some kind
of push mechanism so it's a good way to
discriminate between things and then
like I said earlier the the ordering can
be unique as well payload patterns so I
am using base 64 texts or just raw
random looking bytes and I'm using
filenames that look like UUID values so
that's not the pattern that you can look
for that may be very different from the
way that other applications use the same
service and you know in more complicated
formats like JPEG or mp3 you should look
into metadata fields because that's
that's where I'm stuffing a lot of these
these messages within those those fields
and ten general behavior so just one
example here this is kind of catch-all
but so you got
okay
you got you got WebEx meeting scheduled
for 2:00 p.m. on Fridays right you get
this WebEx chat room or conference room
but then you look at the network and
someone's sending web at WebEx chats to
this room all throughout the week so
that might be something that that should
arouse suspicion because you understand
how the application is used in a broad
sense and this is a deviation from it so
with with Dropbox in particular we go
back through the list of 10 things or so
and you know most of those things I just
mentioned are ways that we can build
detections but wait there's more
so I was thinking about how to how to
make this a little bit easier how we
take take this these concepts and apply
them to the real world for detection I'm
not an expert on detection but I think
unit testing may be a way to start
looking at some of these things so what
I also done is started working on a
little tool that uses these transports
to spoof commanding control connections
to various services and then spit out a
report that says here's the times stamps
when these things occurred and here's
the ten things that you should be able
to pull out of your plot of your logs so
that's that's a work in progress
hopefully that'll be posted in the next
week or two you'll see looks like I got
about one minute left so I got time for
maybe one question
yeah sure so the question was have I run
across any organizations that forced me
to use more sophisticated techniques
like this and the answer is yes sort of
it's actually started I started down
this path maybe two years ago when I was
doing a test for an organization and I
could not get any of my HTTP connections
for different command control tools to
get out of their network for for various
reasons and I banged my head against the
wall for a couple days and well it
frustrate me the most was the fact that
I was just able to log in to share file
and upload and download any kind of
files throughout this time so I started
trying to figure out how I could use
that to to bypass I don't know if it was
if they forced me because their controls
were so great or that I was just