we good to go
should we go okay hi everyone welcome
thanks for coming by
no yet okay before I start just want to
give a quick shout out to Derby con for
giving us the opportunity to present
today you guys are doing a great job
right about it
so I am Nick de Lasky I'm a management
consultant with Spirent Security Labs
with security labs I'm a pen tester red
teamer focusing mainly on network type
attacks
I do also help out with a little bit of
embedded wireless and IOT type projects
I'm also a physics enthusiast so I
apologize in advance if any math or
science jokes come out in today's
presentation I am I'm thought about it
feel free to butcher my name goes by the
handle 0x sabe I work at Mandan fire I
and just like everyone else these days
I'm also a red teamer because it's
trending on Twitter also I want to be
the birth engineer and for all the
recruiters in the house I'm also a
security researcher trainer and speaker
right uh this is what the agenda for the
talk looks like we'll start with an
introduction to connected medical
devices we'll talk a little bit about
the architecture and workflow of these
devices we'll talk about talk about what
are the good aspects of it and what is
bad or could be bad
and then we'll touch upon the surf the
threat surface from a penetration
testers perspective associated with
these medical devices we'll talk about
some of the real-world attacks that has
happened against medical devices and
after we have wasted most of the time
then we'll jump into the case studies
where we will talk about the validity of
all abilities that we discovered in a
couple of medical devices in a typical
InfoSec style presentation we won't be
providing any solution to any of the
problems we'll talk about but there will
be some generic closing remarks so just
a couple of notes about some of the
medical devices we're going to be
talking about today they are still
deployed somewhat you know we are going
to be talking about a device that has
been improved upon over the last several
years with increasing focus on metal
medical device security however there
are likely still these devices out there
in the ecosystem and therefore you know
we will have some heavily redacted
screenshots you know some details like
port numbers and things will be changed
so please expect that so when we're
talking about healthcare devices you
know we're talking about a wide variety
of different things you know there are
you know your classical connected
healthcare devices things that you would
find in a hospital or doctor's office
more clinical medical devices then you
have things that you know might be you
know more aimed toward the consumer
market you know things that help you
improve your lifestyle fitbit's health
trackers some apps on certain wearables
that kind of thing so all of these
devices are collecting and processing
different data about you essentially
it's all data that can in certain
contexts be construed as medical data
this data is
proliferating sometimes in ways that we
wouldn't quite expect and it's important
to take a look at these devices how
they're handling your data what
protocols these data this data is being
transmitted over and what is done with
that data after its collected and
processed right we try to classify for
medical devices into five different
categories and the first one you'd be
most familiar with it are the the
consumable consumer variables so your
fitness trackers would be part of it
then there are patient monitoring
devices which are like insulin firms ECG
heartbeat monitors and so on and then IV
D or in vitro medical devices are are
your HIV detection systems and then all
the devices that I've talked about so
far they are external to the patient's
body but then there are embedded devices
which are implanted in patients body so
like most common example would be your
pacemaker and then finally there are
these huge bulky stationary medical
equipments that you usually see at the
hospitals like medical dispensing system
MRI machines CT scanner and x-ray
machines this is what a typical data
loop for an IOT device looks peyote
medical device looks like so the device
is always in a constant monitoring mode
using the sensor in case of an event it
triggers an action and then finally the
data is aggregated and analyzed so if
you take a quick example of an insulin
pump it uses a sensor to constantly
monitor blood sugar level of a patient
and if blood sugar level drops it
injects right amount of insulin into
patient's body using a catheter which is
usually placed under patient's skin and
then once that action is data are taken
the data is then gathered and analyzed
and I think that aggregation and
analysis part of the data is going to be
the most important to watch out from
connected medical device perspective
in terms of architecture the device
itself on the further left side has a
lot of subsystems so first of all they
can talk on tons of protocols the Wi-Fi
lo-fi irda Ethernet ZigBee z-wave then a
typical connected medical device would
have a sensor and actuator to say for
example to monitor your heartbeat or
insulin level and then most of these
medical devices are actually heavily
monitored and maintained by the device
manufacturers themselves so there's some
sort of remote access which also could
be interesting from security perspective
it would have a display of location
tracker especially if the device is
something that tracks your steps then
there's device association module which
would be responsible for authenticating
and authorizing a device onto a network
storage it will gather data from the
patient and then would have some sort of
small storage event architecture is
another important module because it
based on the data it gathers it analyzes
the data and then creates a trigger and
then there is command and control which
is our hackers paradise then middleware
you can think of middleware as like a
web server for your medical devices so
it it handles most of the code for
authentication authorization come on and
control but I think the most important
part would be the database part because
this is now taking all the data from
different medical devices and then
processing that data and then it outputs
the consumable data set which can be
just fed into through api's into the
third layer which is like management
interfaces like this kind of data can be
used by the patient themselves to
monitor their health by the doctors to
monitor a patient's health and I can
take preventive measures by by device
manufacturers they can use the data to
better the device for future use and so
on
so why would we want to connect our
medical devices I think there's a lot of
people out there that would have a lot
of good reasons for for why we're doing
this why we're doing what we're doing
some that is even encouraged mandated by
legislation in various countries having
to do with electronic health records the
efficient sharing of medical data the
availability of medical data in an
emergency making sure that medical data
is portable to various providers and not
in proprietary formats so when you're
talking about connected medical devices
there's a lot of stuff that makes sense
it enables remote health monitoring so
you have to spend you can spend less
time in the hospital if a doctor can
read your implantable device for signs
of heart problems from home you know you
receive better quality care if you have
more accurate and instrumentation if you
have instrumentation that is you know
say maybe remotely calibrated or the
data is able to be sent to you know an
expert in the field at a moment's notice
as opposed to you know an overworked a
general practitioner who has to deal
with all different types of patient
complain at once you can get some faster
response time again from that
instantaneous communication also
telehealth telemedicine is becoming
increasingly popular where you can
actually get in some instances a full
consultation or examination remotely
I've heard instances of hospitals
implementing what we're affectionately
called robot doctors where you have
essentially an iPad connected up to a
remote controlled car more or less than
these drive around the the ward and the
doctor comes in say hi I'm your doctor
I'll see you now
some people are a little bit put off by
the concept but when that doctor is
actually one of the preeminent experts
in the country or in the world on that
particular malady
people would rather have that expertise
than be put off by by the fact there's
that remote connectivity there in
addition you know you're able to get
early warning of things that might be a
trending problem so for example with
insulin monitors if your your blood
sugars are trending downward you can
send an alert not just to yourself but
if for example your sugar is already at
a low level or if your reaction to low
blood sugar means that you're not able
to see that alert you know if there's
that ability to maybe get that
information to another safety contact
that also has the potential to benefit
the patient in the long term as well all
right and then obviously there are some
nightmare that are connected to the
growing number of medical devices so
first of all I think in my opinion the
biggest challenge would be for hospitals
and medical institutions to accommodate
large and growing number of medical
devices so there I think there are
already quite a large number of
connected medical devices per bed in in
modern hospitals in the US and if you
factor in other devices like portable
medical devices which patients might
start bringing then that will also cause
a lot of chaos so hospitals first of all
must make sure that they have in it
enough bandwidth to support all those
devices and then their wireless
infrastructure it doesn't choke because
of the growing number of devices there's
also the issue of network segregation so
how do you distinguish legit device from
malicious or rogue medical device so and
also we will talk about some of the
malware in the next few slides about how
they can compromise medical devices and
use them to use them to pivot and then
launch further attacks on the hospital
system so frosting we would want as that
one compromised medical device affecting
the other medical devices or other
systems on the hospital network so
that's also going to be important and
also going to be a huge challenge to
segregate these medical devices we
already talked about how different how
leg
medical devices support different kind
of communication protocols so especially
devices by different manufacturers it
could be a challenge to get them to talk
to each other I think attend occasion
other ization also going to be an issue
because you need to figure out how to
authenticate these device and also most
importantly how to authorize these
devices to different segments of the
network in water systems and subsystems
they can access patching a lot of
devices are which are now connected
never meant to be connected to the
network and so they are typically what
do you call legacy medical devices they
never had any connectivity subsystems
built into them and then we will talk
about in the next slide how they're
connected to medical to the network so
there's that issue as well right I so
like I just mentioned that there are
some devices which were never meant to
be connected to the network but here we
are because they thought we're
connecting everything to the network so
why not devices as well and so how these
medical devices are connected to the
hospital network are using serial to
Internet converters and that's just a
terrible idea
so these devices that connect to the
fetal communication cord they've never
had any security built built into them
in fact Department of Homeland Security
last year alerted against one of the
most commonly used fetal - Ethernet
adapters which is in port developed by a
company called MRSA I hope no one is
here from that company but apparently
like there were three critical voluma
T's one was that would allow an attacker
to extract sensitive information
remotely without authentic without
authentication the other one would allow
in the tracker to upgrade or downgrade
firmware again remotely without
authentication and as if that was not
enough there's also a buffer overflow
and quality that you can exploit to get
remote code execution on these devices I
don't know if you guys remember like the
unscheduled power outage in Ukraine that
happened in 2015 so as per DHS that also
happened because someone corrupted a
bunch of these these adapters are
remotely
so when we're talking about any kind of
IOT device I like to think about it
still in the same terms as I would a
network pen test or an enterprise
network pen test layers one and two may
be different but ultimately we're still
just connecting together a bunch of
network nodes now in any kind of a pen
test you know the open source recon is
going to be a key can make your job a
lot easier
it also gives you a much more realistic
picture of you know is this particular
vulnerability exposed are there any
other compensating controls that are out
there so one of the things that you can
do with IOT devices you can take a look
at the device itself you can take a look
at the interfaces that are on it
you might be able to download data
sheets you might be able to get
regulatory data that's been filed about
these devices that's great that's one
kind of open source reconnaissance you
can do on it another piece of
information though that will really give
you a lot more insight about the actual
risk profile is to learn about the life
cycle of these devices how are they
deployed how are they maintained how are
they retired as we've seen in the news
in the last couple of days supply chain
attacks are real or are they depending
on who you ask
so if you have a device that you know is
vulnerable to a physical attack and it's
kept under lock and key and it's also
tagged with an active our ID or RFID
tracking unit you know that's a device
that you know has some of the risk
mitigated in there it might open up some
additional attacks namely being able to
tie that active RFID beacon to a
particular patient so you're always
making a trade off personally as I
mentioned before I like physics I think
that risk is an awful lot like the
physics concept of entropy which is
entropy is always increasing in the
universe I think as long as as we are
adding more devices to the network as
long
we are expanding the amount of data
that's being shared from place to place
risk is also constantly increasing and
we as security professionals we're just
trying to minimize that increase until
we actually kind of reach an equilibrium
there so talk about some of the horror
stories actually there are times the
forest stories associated with
compromised medical devices that
connected medical devices but I
specifically wanted to talk about magic
and magic tale magic also known as
medical device hijack is a malware that
came out in 2015
lived through most of 2016 where jak 2
is actually a more sophisticated newer
version that came out in 2017 and so
magic exploited older operating systems
like Windows NT 2000 2003 XP all those
and like one of the interesting thing
about magic was that it went undetected
for the most part and the reason why it
happened was because it exploited
Willamette is like MS zero eight zero
six seven which are like old one
limiting so all the modern operating
systems have already protection against
MS zero eight seven so the modern
operating system would just drop the
packet it won't even reach the end point
and the medical devices which are
running the older operating system they
didn't have any endpoint installed on
them so it it went undetected for the
most part and so it compromised a tons
of medical devices on hospital network
and then use those compromised devices
to pivot and launch further attack on
the hospital network it was also known
to to use Citadel and Cu small word for
horizontal privilege escalation so yeah
yeah it cost a lot of damage at that
point of time
so the first device that we're going to
be talking about is an older model of
connected IV pump now what I'm gonna
talk about today are mostly you know
architectural and design decisions that
were made when this pump was being
engineered and manufactured I don't
think that the modern focus and the
modern capabilities of the Red Team or
attackers were being considered when
this device was was designed so as I've
mentioned before successive iterations
of IV pumps have gotten progressively
more and more secure and that's in part
to the efforts of the FDA to really put
a focus on the need for medical device
security it's also I'd like to give a
shout out to organizations like I am the
cavalry who put on the bio hacking
village or involved with the bio hacking
village at DEFCON really spreading the
awareness of medical device security and
helping to increase accessibility of
these devices to researchers who just
want to make things better for everybody
so I think that there's been a lot of
improvement going on here and we're
going to talk about some of the things
that we find in these legacy devices
that really need to be engineered out of
current and future solutions so as I
mentioned the device is an IV infusion
pump meant for injecting nutrients and
medication to active patients within a
clinical setting mostly it is used for
controlling the dosage of medication
that's being administered and it has a
master drug list on it and that drug
list sets limits so that it reduces
medication errors they can be changed
depending on the floor of the hospital
the care area of the hospital because
you know sometimes you might want the
emergency department to be able to
issue a certain dosage of a medication
that would be maybe inappropriate for
maybe a less acute setting such as you
know a normal medical surgical floor
they used to be completely standalone
devices that you can program at the
bedside while those devices are still
out there they're standalone devices are
still out there I think that more and
more settings and more and more
providers are moving toward these
connected devices because they integrate
well with EHR systems and and other
hospital systems again you know these
are random images that was not this bump
that we were looking at so at a high
level you have the infusion pump at the
patient's bedside connects to a wireless
access point in some infusion pumps it
might use proprietary access point that
uses is M band communications that are
dedicated to medical devices in some
instances it might use the same Wi-Fi
frequencies that are available to
everybody else and then through that
access point it'll connect to a gateway
possibly to some cloud services back at
the manufacturer for updates or other
telemetry data and then most often they
also have some sort of a server
component on-premises so that way all of
these devices can report back and be
managed centrally in the case of a mass
update of all the devices that are that
are out there in the field with a new
master drug list or other clinical type
settings so with this particular device
we took a look at the different
interfaces that were available to us so
there was a toe to toe to 11 BGA using
standard frequency ranges so that
equipment to assess the security of that
part of it was readily available it had
some proprietary power connectors on it
generally in order to charge a
battery-powered device you might need
voltage and you might also
some sort of data for smart charging
capabilities or some kind of data
transfer regarding how much power is
left so we did take a look at that but
didn't find anything particularly
interesting there it also had an IR D a
port normal lctd LCD display keypad and
what we found was that there was a
maintenance mode accessible through the
keypad UI with a guessable password so
that provided us with some read-only
access to the device the actual
interface in that maintenance mode did
have an option to upgrade and downgrade
the software we looked high and low to
see if we could find copies of the
software and see if we could extract
anything from the binary
luckily access to that data is pretty
well controlled we weren't able to find
anything on that so we could tamper
directly with the device so the next
path that we took was taking a look at
the different network interfaces so
since the interface was only readable on
the UI we took a look at a feature of
the device which allowed us to change
the network settings via the IRDA port
so I had took I've taken a couple
different ideas under consideration
first was alright well we could go out
and buy an IR di interface over USB over
USB you know seems like the reasonable
course of action but that was going to
take a little while to get to us because
it's not really a common component
anymore so that was out I had had some
IRD I'm sorry some are LEDs and IR
sensors in my parts bin so I considered
alright do I try and cobble something
together with an Arduino and Raspberry
Pi and I thought to myself well that's
gonna take just as long and probably be
four times as frustrating so all of a
sudden they had an aha moment you know
this device was engineered
quite a while ago so I looked at other
technology that was available quite a
while ago and ultimately what I settled
on was handspring Visor cost me about 10
bucks at a local pawn shop so I am one
of those people that will hoard
electronics from days of yore and say
I'll use that later and much to my
wife's dismay this did actually prove
that point for me in this case so once
we were able to change the wireless
settings we now have the device on our
network so what I'd like to note here is
that the does overall design of the pump
handled wireless communication fairly
well it's we tried to perform an evil
twin attack against the pump is
completely unsuccessful because it
appeared to be checking the server side
certificate on the WPA enterprise
network just the way it should have been
likewise we tried setting up a rogue
access point that didn't have any
encryption it didn't fall for that
either
finally we couldn't just extract the
credentials or the the network data
using IRDA so when it when the update
function basically just sent a copy of
the configuration template to the Palm
visor and it had some rudimentary
authentication mechanisms that we were
able to get past because we had physical
access to the device so after we took a
look at the template we found that it
didn't share any pre-shared keys in that
template it didn't share any usernames
or passwords so somebody had clearly
thought of the security basics here and
they just maybe didn't go quite far
enough in the engineering of this device
so what we did was we substituted our
own information
just hooked it up to our own wireless
network in a clinical setting you know
this would be raising all kinds of red
flags the device wouldn't be reporting
back so this is more emblematic of what
happens with IOT devices that are maybe
accessible controlling where those IOT
devices are can be key because what if
one of them gets compromised are you
able to recover your security if there
are key secrets or key trusts that are
placed in that device so that's really
what this illustrates here more than you
know any kind of a James Bond like or
Mission Impossible like scenario with
this particular pump so once we had the
device on our network we were able to
learn a little bit more about the
protocols that it used notably we see
telnet FTP which obviously are plaintext
protocols anything having to do with
medical data medical devices
you know plaintext should be in big red
letters a bad thing and any sort of
design documentation whether it's for
management or whether it's actually
transferring patient data obviously with
telnet and FTP it also sends
authentication credentials in the clear
so again if this were a real-world
scenario if for example we were able to
get access to the wireless network that
these devices were on by some other
means say via VLAN hopping or through
compromising another network node
there's a pretty good potential we'd be
able to man in the middle sniff test
traffic and get those credentials as it
is we just had the device in our lab so
we didn't have any valid clients
reaching out with valid credentials so
we had to brute force in the time that
we had we weren't able to brute force
either telnet FTP or SSH maybe we just
need better word lists so in addition to
taking a look at the pump from a server
side we also took a look at its natural
interactions with the network and we saw
that it was attempting to resolve a
certain hostname so being that we
controlled the network
say okay well we're that hostname what
we found when we set up a netcat
listener based on that traffic was that
it was using plaintext protocol that
looks like some some ugly XML followed
by a short trailer it contained a lot of
descriptive information about the pump
but not really anything that we would
see as sensitive medical data we tried
to respond back with the same sorts of
data and we're getting we were having
some some varied results there mostly we
were just getting back what looked to be
some kind of a formatted error message
that's until we took a look at the
trailer the trailer that they have at
the end of that data turned out to be a
simple X mode 'm checksum so clearly
they were concerned about the integrity
of the data in transit not so much the
confidentiality and the integrity check
is good but he needs to go a little bit
further given that it was just an X
modem checksum we could now craft
packets that looked as though they were
valid you know and integrity checked
packets from the perspective of the pump
what would be better in this sort of a
situation would be something more like a
signature as opposed to just a simple
checksum now once we were able to send
some some checks as some properly
checked traffic back to the pump it
started giving us a lot more information
there were actually two different
services there was one outbound from the
pump and then there was another service
going back from the simulated pump
server back to the pump itself and then
that service used the same basic data
format with a couple of differences
once we had learned a little bit more
about how that communication occurred we
were able to create a custom Python
library to interact with the pump in
both directions and we did some fuzzing
if there was a message type filled in
some of that data that we were able to
enumerate we went from 0 all the way up
to 250 for most of the message types
didn't do anything but a quick summary
of what we learned is here type 2
appears to confirm that you know yes I
am trying to associate to this pump
server and then type 8 is also a related
message and that's when the pump seems
to seems to to really say okay yes I'm
part of this network I'm gonna start
giving you more information now type 7
and 31 we're not really sure what they
do they caused maybe a seven or eight
second delay before responding back with
sort of a generic message to us same
thing with message types 208 and 238
message type 20 turned out to be a
little bit more interesting that when we
sent message type 20 the pump responded
back with information about its own
wireless card as well as the wireless
environment around it so neighboring BS
SIDS MAC addresses and signal strengths
so somebody who is able to access this
pump and and send it a message type 20
might be able to find out where this
pump is physically located through
similar open source reconnaissance
methods so here's some of the types of
data that we were able to get out of the
pump once we successfully associated it
to our Python library as you can see up
there and as the the pump status whether
it's on AC power or a battery it also
has the drug and the dosage it even has
information about the caregiver that is
either programming or administering the
the pump and it's it's medicine so
clearly there's some protected data
there that's
potentially at risk if there were an
attacker that were able to get a
position on this network now I mentioned
the master drug list before that is
something that would be pushed down from
the pump server to the pump itself we
had some indications that with some of
the communication we were able to fuzz
were highly confident that we would have
been able to update the master drug list
we didn't have that pump server software
in our lab to view this traffic and so
we could modify it and work off of it so
again that that's kind of a limitation
of this particular lab setup but to be
sure I think that with the other
architectural decisions and design
features of this pump I'm fairly
confident we could have we could have
updated that master drug list and again
that would have some some definitely
patient safety patient care impacts yeah
like one of the things he can do and you
can override master bedless as that one
of the safety features of infusion pump
is the doctors can set a limit to the
higher dosage so for example they can
set a limit to morphine to be hundred
milligrams and once that is that even if
patient wanted to more inject more
protein morphine they can't but if we
can overwrite the massive drug list you
can actually cause harm to the patient
all right so the second device that we
looked at was a digital pen so the pen
is used by doctors and medical
practitioners to electronically write
prescriptions on a special paper and
then that gets electronically
transferred to the pharmacy so the
benefit is that you save time so by the
time you reach pharmacy your medication
is already ready for pickup it didn't
look like much of a device to be honest
like when you started looking at at
first we thought oh the most we can get
out of it is maybe like a few
prescriptions and that's pretty much it
clearly not the case these devices are
manufactured by many manufacturers we
only looked at one device from
manufacturer and this is definitely not
that device for sure in terms of
workflow the the device itself sticks on
the privateness panel network connects
either internet or Wi-Fi and then it the
prescription is sent to a cloud server
and on the server side that the web
portal so the patients and doctors and
admins can log in and see the
prescription an app server and a
database so we initially notice that it
comes with a Windows 10 operating system
okay at least it's not XP it came with
two different accounts one was a nurse
slash physician accounts of which is
typically the account your medical
practitioner would use to write the
prescription and in the other one was
the administrator which is typically
used by device manufacturers to update
troubleshoot the device I think I was
the only person other person who used
that account then there was USB it had
violet and Ethernet capabilities HDMI
VGA a standard DisplayPort it came with
a full fully updated Windows Defender
there was also a docking station so you
can dock the pen on to charge the pen
and software layer which basically
comprises comprised of two applications
by the manufacturer
alright so because it had HDMI we could
connect a monitor to it because it had
USB we could connect keyboard and mouse
to it and so we noticed that when you
put up the pen it automatically logs
into the nurse account which is a
lockdown board but it was still
something so you had access to Windows
10 operating system you know in a in a
very lockdown mode then we they had
there were a couple of applications that
were provided by the manufacturers and
then there were a couple of services
they were running by the manufacturer
this pen is a liquid when doctors used
to pen if it's connected to the Internet
at that point of time it will transmit
all the data in real time to the
pharmacy if not that the pen used to
store data in an encrypted manner on on
the disk and then transmitted over when
it connects back to the Internet the
data transmission itself happen
using ssl so yes 256 and we looked into
it but there wasn't much in there there
was also a remote access component which
involve using team beaver to remote in
again used by manufacturer which I think
could also be very interesting factor to
look at I feel like from from a pen
testers perspective we already had
access to the operating system but it
was low privileged and locked down so
initial thought was to just just update
access to local administrator so
basically I could change the screen
saver because I didn't like that one
we started looking at different services
and because it was in lockdown mode we
could restart stop stop services we
tried some of the exploits were out
there against Windows 10 that also did
not work but then we found this service
which actually by the manufacturer
although we couldn't start stop the
service we could replace the binary of
the service on the disk so nothing
really rocket science here so we created
a payload which would create a local
admin user replaced it with the original
binary for that particular application
since we couldn't restart the service we
just rebooted the pen so as it came back
up it created a local admin account on
on the system so at this point of time I
could indeed change the wallpaper we
also installed some other tools like
white shark and then also Windows System
internal utilities so we started looking
at Wireshark and there wasn't much in
there because the traffic was mostly
encrypted I'm not that technical all
that stuff but after that I fired up we
fired a proc Mon specifically to look at
what are the different events that
happened what are we write operations
registry operations and so on and if
you've ever used proc man you would see
that it captures tons of events and
surely like you can set a filter to
capture from single application but
still ends up a lot of events there so
cycle through them for a long time and
then we realized that the application
reads a file with extension dot E&C it
will be an encrypted file we located the
file on file system open it in notepad
and it was all garbage so yeah
definitely encrypted remember I
mentioned I am a born abit of birth
engineer so I put in all e debugger in
there just wanted to reverse engineer
the applications so started doing some
dynamic and and static binary reverse
engineer on it and so like after several
hours figured out that the portion on
the left side is actually the logic that
would decrypt that file so what
application basically was doing was it
was reading this file in memory
decrypting it and then reading some of
the parameters from it took another
little while to reverse-engineer the
logic for decryption and what we ended
up doing was just writing a Python
scripts that would locate the file on
disk it decrypted copy the contents and
paste it on another file we didn't
really have to do it because if you look
at the bottom area there that's already
decrypted data so like when it equips it
it will show up there I just want it to
be a bit more fancy than that I guess so
we reopen the file if you can see I have
it has a database string in there so for
my sequel database so it's got host name
IP address it's called database name as
well user name you will see its roots
which is the highest privilege user
there's also plaintext password so we're
like okay it said it has to be written
data it's there they're not probably
using it but then we had to do in n maps
and and there it was
database itself was exposed over the
internet and like even at this point of
time we are thinking this is like one of
those osep CTF style things where they
want you to think that that's the one
ability but it's not really there but we
connected to the database and there it
was so at this point of time because we
were connected to the backend database
and not just through the portal we could
access the patient health record from
all the institutions where this pan
these pens were installed and not just
our test man so it essentially millions
of records were in there so if you can
see you can see
like I've redacted Mosul data because
real-world patient data but there's
patient code in their patient first name
last name date of birth gender of the
patient and then we found chance of data
like this is another table where you can
see the user name email ID password so
on in plain text and then there's
something called a roll code and which
basically says if this account belongs
to an address later a manufacturer a
patient so we pulled out some of the
credentials in there logged on to the
portal itself here again you can see the
resident name the unit home address room
number HC and his healthcare number I
suppose and then finally we were also
able to pull out prescriptions that were
written by the doctors for different
patients they like tons of them there is
no point collecting all that information
yeah so we thought that was pretty cool
but not the prescription part so these
are some of the vil images that we found
in in these two devices it's hard to get
your hands on medical devices so we work
on them as in when we get the chance in
terms of closing remarks I said like as
I mentioned before going to be very very
genetic I think Nick did mention some of
the good points during his coverage but
I know there's a lot of fresh in
bringing these all these medical devices
not just medical devices or the IOT
devices out to the market but there
isn't any security built into them
they're just trying to bolt on the
security or someone finds issues and
it's more like security by obscurity
because not a lot of people looking at
these devices so they get by in the
market again they're going if there's
going to be tons of medical devices on
the network so from medical institutions
perspective they have to make sure that
they come up with a model to trust the
devices and also blacklist the untrusted
device Nick mentioned that FDA is like
they've started to pay a lot of
attention to medical devices but we
still need to go beyond beyond
regulations on that I'm selec I don't
know for whatever reason
as per FDA regulation once a device a
testing and deployed at a health
institution you're not supposed to
change anything on those devices because
of how they might react to the setting
so which basically leave these devices
strictly at the mercy of the
manufacturer so the IT technicians at
the hospital don't have any insight into
the device is kind of a black box for
them we can learn from past mistakes I
think any of the issues that we talked
about today aren't exactly three today
if they have already happened with your
web applications your other hardware
mobile applications and all so we are
not learning anything new here we just
have to be just just learn from the past
mistake and use those while building the
new devices and that's it thank you
[Applause]