okay arrest okay cool so Wow
big crowd awesome so my talk is called
app' a palak ellipse now and it's a talk
about different bypasses for AppLocker
but a not only bypasses but also
mitigations so hopefully it will enjoy
this tart I've been excited to to talk
about this for a long time now so yeah
really confirmed to this so briefly
about myself I am my name is boomer and
I work with IT since early 99 I took my
first Microsoft certification when I was
16 years old
that was pretty early in the game the
last six years are been focusing on
security both pentesting but also
hardening environments Windows
environments so previously I worked as a
Microsoft consultant I did I'd done a
lot of training I speak a lot and as a
result of that I'm also and Microsoft
MVP within cloud and data center
management and I've been up for three
years I'm a huge fan of memes and gifts
so I really love presentation that
includes that and as of this Monday I
started working at trusted SEC so Chris
said it okay so I'm from Norway right
and you're probably thinking oh you live
way up north
you ride polar bears and kill seals and
other stuff no it's not that
as you can see on the map here we are
approximately around here somewhere
maybe a little lower I'll leave up there
so that's a great length to swim for
sure so I don't know if you notice this
but some maps there are different things
like for instance in Italy they have
this shoe you seen this before yeah and
I heard someone told me that Texas
looked like a finger it's there correct
yeah
so there are different maps that come
here you can use your imagination to
like see things we have one in
Scandinavia as well but we don't brag
about it okay because the Italians okay
so if you're if you're from Russia this
is not meant as an insult that's
important to me okay this is just a joke
so and when you first see this you
cannot unsee it this is just one of
those things that kind of hit you in the
face and you can't forget them okay
ready
okay can you see it I'll help you so I
didn't finish the drawing because I
think something needs to be like left
for the imagination yeah funny
it's a pervert why am i talking about
AppLocker
first of all it's because I have
implemented that product at several
customers and I'm also like try to
bypass it a lot of times in several
environments and to me it's like a
product that often gets misunderstood on
what it is and what is it's not so I
want to like get it out there how it is
and show you how easy it is to get
started and all that stuff so that's one
of my motivations behind this and as I
said I have I've heard that it's not
that common in the States to have a
blocker enabled a bigger companies so
anyone here use this app Locker wow
that's a huge bunch ma'am cool okay so
one thing I see is that this product is
often overlooked and many customers have
like Enterprise licenses and have have
it free they can use it it's just a
matter of enabling and configuring it
correctly so people tend to forget this
product and this this torque is for both
sides so I have some
stuff for the red side and hopefully
some cool stuff for the blue side I hope
you appreciate that right so what I will
cover I'll give you an overview of app
Locker how you configure it like from a
default perspective and just go over
some basics like how to configure a rule
and all that stuff and then I will show
you some different bypass techniques
that are important to be abwehr up
that's the up all of the lips part and I
will be dropping on you I'm doing
quotation mark near because I haven't
seen it before a constrained language
mode bypass so when you enable app
Locker
it will change PowerShell from a full
language PowerShell in Turkish train
mode language PowerShell so then I have
a working bypass for for ants and I will
also be releasing a PowerShell module
it's not 100% done but it's good enough
to like release it here
I feel so yeah good enough for you guys
I'm just kidding nobody works so but I
haven't like polished it hundred percent
then alright so app Locker it's one of
Microsoft's
whitelisting solutions basically it's a
product you use to tell what is allowed
to run on the endpoint and not and
instead of like telling it everything it
should block you're telling it what it's
supposed to be allowed to run that's
white listing and it's if you worked
with Microsoft products from back like
XP and 2003 servers you maybe remember
something called software restriction
policies these are app Locker it's the
version to build act so this is like the
next generation software restriction
policy the big difference between
software restriction policy one and two
is that version one you didn't need like
a special kind of license but in app
Locker the version two you need to have
an enterprise or an education school in
your windows there's a star there and
that's because there is an exception to
that
and if you use model management you can
actually enable AppLocker through with
pro additional windows as well but you
have to configure it differently so you
have to like take xml files and embed
them in the Intune portal and all that
stuff but I haven't seen anyone done it
yet but I know it's possible and our
blocker is a part of the defense in
depth strategy to Microsoft so it's just
another Oh their product to like harden
stuff as much much as they can and you
can allow and you can deny execution of
stuff you can base it on the publisher
that's the certificate if you have a
binary that's sign you can tell it to
either allow it or deny it based on that
certificate and that's pretty awesome
it's hard to fake or you can base it on
the hash of the file or just a path
where it's located in the disk ok
what is it what is it what AppLocker is
not it's not a security boundary and
there have been many reports to
Microsoft where where we have
highlighted like problems with a blocker
but they always tell this is not a
security boundary it was designed for
compliance that's what they're telling
us but it's but still it's a great
product that I really feel is new needs
to be deployed more and it's if you see
here this is the latest blog for
Microsoft the criteria of getting like a
CDE or service it clearly stated here
that AppLocker is not going to be
serviced so this is something they don't
like really care about but if you find a
serious enough bug there will probably
fix it anyways but yeah it's a different
story
and it's not a true vitally whitelisting
solution to my opinion because I try to
take a pucker and only allow what I want
a boon of the machine I
like kind of log what happened during
logon and I whitelisted all the
different things that ran and did up
like 10 times and then I turn on the
policy to enforce it and it crashed so
that doesn't work and that's how a white
testing solution should work right so
there's something in the operating
system I haven't figured it out I've
reached out to Microsoft about it but I
didn't get any help so to me it's not a
true vitalistic solution what's my
opinion list another important thing
it's not meant to protect admins because
if you're an admin app Locker is easily
to bypass for real it is I have a blog
post about it
so if you're interested in why you can
read about it there okay so let's go
over some basics let's let's configure
AppLocker policy from the start up let
me show you how easy it is right let's
see I think I need to do like duplicate
alright so everyone can see this cool so
so this is the domain controller in my
lab domain maybe it's kind of hard to
see in the back I'm sorry I don't have
submit or anything so I will tell you
what I do so I have a predefined
organizational structure inside Active
Directory for computers and I've created
a dummy organizational unit called demo
oh you derbycon so we're gonna start
here by just creating a group policy
that is as easy as just right clicking
create a GPO I'll link it here there we
go just gonna call it like app Locker
policy oh if I can type what's hard and
then you just right-click the policy go
into edit and then you browse yourself
down into policies sorry Windows
settings security settings and under the
application
twelve settings and this is where you
live when you configure AppLocker
so here you have different sections you
have executable rules you have Windows
installer rules you have script girls
and you have packaged app rules so what
you normally do is that when I start up
policy I just right click every section
and I used to create the default rules
it's a good starting point because what
it does is that it says that an
administrator is allowed to run
everything on a box right that makes
sense and we have a rule that allows
everything under the windows folder to
run and everything under the Program
Files folder to run and the idea behind
this is that a normal user is not
allowed to place files within the
Windows folder or the Program Files
folder so you as an admin allow sit by
installing software right that make
sense so the default rules are pretty
good so just go through them and there's
one thing missing
that I see all the time and I've seen a
lot of claimed bypasses about app Locker
and they haven't like configured
something called dll's there's a section
for dll's as well an app Locker is a
waste of time if you don't enable that
so you need to go to you right click on
app Locker go into properties go into
the advanced advanced tab here on the
top but then you need to enable that
enable the dnl rule collection click
apply click OK and then you've got the
dll rules here as well do the same for
them and they state here that it affects
performance
it does not for real ok maybe back when
we had like Windows XP and stuff it
could affect a little but today no it
doesn't affect the performance and even
if it did I would still turn it on all
right and after you configure all the
rules you need
and force them you can either do it by
starting off by just doing an audit what
will happen then is that every time a
binary runs on a client it will log it
to the event log so you can like take it
out and see what would have been blocked
if the rules were applied and first so I
just enforce everything like this
already now we have a pretty good decent
protection on the endpoints for malware
just like that we're done all right
there's one thing one more thing by the
way we need a service to run that's the
application identity service this needs
also needs to be turned on it's not on
by default so you have to go in and
configure it define it hook it on to
automatic and boom now the application
identity service will start to run on
the clients and it will apply or enforce
the AppLocker rules and we're good to go
that's that's how long it took to apply
of applica policy a default AppLocker
policy and then you have to deal with
only exceptions of course but that's a
little story right and when we have
enforce this policy we can move over to
a client run GP update and then you can
test it up by just trying to run a
binary outside outside the Program Files
folder or Windows folder and it will say
say that it is blocked by group policy
or you will get a little bit like this
if you double click it that's how easy
it is there's this was the default setup
that's the one I prefer I've tried a lot
of different setups so you have you can
for instance only allow different
publishers so everything's signed by
Microsoft by Google by Apple and all the
other companies the problem with that
approach is that sooner or later you'll
figure out that a lot of binaries even
from Microsoft isn't signed
especially dll's so you will end up in a
situation where you need to make a lot
of exceptions
to that baseball where you allow only
signed binaries so I don't like that
approach so I always end up using the
default rules because I think that's
better
you also have the Kaos approach that's
what I call it you can use a Parker to
automatically generate rules for you and
it will scan Program Files and windows
folder whatever you choose and it will
calculate the hash or everything and it
will also create one rule for each file
and it will create a rule for almost
each publisher and you end up with our
huge amount of rules like a couple
hundreds so you lose control I don't
like that approach I don't recommend it
at all and there's a new new boy in town
called Aaron Locker a guy Packers are
called Aaron ragosa's has created a lot
of great scripts to automate the entire
process I have played a little with it
and it's it's freaking good so if you're
starting out with app Locker I need to
maintain it over time I would start by
looking into Aaron Locker
let's our tip for me it's it's really
good ok so I did a lot of work to get
that background moving
repel that it's like an earthquake it's
the apocalypse you know okay so the
default rules so we have the default
path rules that was the one we created
right so the problem with that is there
are exceptions where a user is allowed
to place binaries within the Windows
folder so the default AC else on Windows
isn't that good so you need to harden
even more and as you can see in the
bottom here these are you can download
something called access check from
sysinternals and you can run these
commands here to pipe up every folder
you have write access to as a normal
user and if you need to do it forever
for users everyone authenticated user
interactive to get all the a sales
that's an important step there's a link
there if you're too lazy to write this
out and also third party I've seen a lot
of cases where you install a software in
Program Files and the ACLs are all
screwed up they forget to harden it so
the user can inject files there that's
not a good thing yeah so do access check
basically just run it see what you're
allowed to do and you will discover
something mind-blowing so what are you
looking for when you're looking for
exceptions to the default ACLs or the
weaknesses well you're looking for
places where you can create files write
data or create folders or append data
list folder read data that's important
things you look for and also the execute
file permission that's our that's a good
one okay so let's go over an example
here in this example the I'm sorry the
the user is part of the users group and
the users group has access to the folder
under the dummy folder called only files
where he is allowed to only create files
and write data that's the only
permission he has right okay so it's not
allowed to execute anything he's only
allowed to write data but there are two
different approaches you can do to use
this to bypass a blocker okay you ready
so the just to prove my point Harris
under under the C tools folder on this
computer you can clearly see that it
AppLocker blocks execution right
even though authenticated user has the
ACLs or read and execute so you can
clearly see that it's a blocker that is
blocking me
not the ACLs okay and we know that we
can create files on into that folder so
normally you just try to copy the file
into the Program Files folder and try to
execute it and as you can see I have a
different error message it's not
AppLocker blocking me now it's DAC else
okay so a procore approved it but the
ACLs blocked me there are two ways for
getting around this so the one I think
it's the coolest one is to use something
called hard links so instead of copying
a file you can use either FS you tail or
m'kay link to create the hard link where
you create like a fake file called
something else whatever linked order
runs and then you link it to the
original file and when you then try to
execute the hard link file that blocker
will say okay you're trying to execute
from Program Files we're good to go
and then the air it will redirect
execution to the folder I have execution
rights on so it will pop up magically
that's pretty cool so another way of
doing this and this example I'm using
folders but it could be files as well so
in this example I have the create folder
right and the permission to read them as
well so what you can do you can create a
folder um under that folder so we create
a new folder called create great folders
right
and if I check the ACLS
afterwards I don't have any rights on
that folder so I'm not allowed to do
anything with it
right wrong because if I run I cattles
and grant everyone permission I'm
allowed to actually add rights but it's
not strange it's not it this is by the
sign you may be going like this that was
to be reaction I was hoping for okay so
what is this evil sorcery it's basically
the thing that in Windows that you have
something called an owner so every time
our user creates something you become
the owner of that object and if you look
it up on TechNet it clearly states under
the how permissions work an owner of an
object always has the ability to read
and change permissions on the object aha
so I as an owner can actually change
everything on that object so that's
pretty cool
so I just as I did I changed the ACLs so
now I can just copy the file in and
execute it you see the bypass so that's
something to think of so you might be
going like this when you start to look
at the ACLs on the windows because you
will find out there's plenty of folders
where a user actually has rights I have
mapped out most of them and describe the
different techniques you can use so
there's a link there at the bottom
I love Deadpool by the way he's cool
and to my big surprise that's not the
only place to start even more if you
have deployed configuration manager
anybody hair users configuration manager
so cool there's even more folders under
there you need to protect so it's pretty
easy to bypass if you like look for the
right things so yeah SCCM something to
think about fan when it comes to third
party here's an example of a bypass I
found Reese
not that recently like a half year ago
or something around TeamViewer they
screwed up the rights so they have
actually read and write access to some
large files under the TeamViewer folder
and you can either just pipe an exit
file into that file or you can I used
ultimate data streams because I think
that's cool
so I had a B gene for hair as an example
into the stream of that file and then we
can execute it directly so I tweet it
out and they fixed it so that's cool all
right
let me quickly show you see I can show
you a bypass let's take look you can use
the older data stream okay let me just
fire up my good old friend
come on prompt so I'm logged in as a
normal user here so under the I think
it's the temp folder I prepare it yeah I
have older on sexy right hopefully I'm
not allowed to run it it's blocked cool
so a cool thing you can do with all the
data streams is that you can actually
take take the file and then you can pipe
it to for instance see Windows tracing
or Excel and now I place the file on the
Steven of tracing but you cannot see it
it's in swim on that folder so it's
pretty good hidden so if I go into
Explorer let's see here
there's no okay so here's our has a
little leftovers from my playtime but
there's nothing to see here basically it
it doesn't state there's a exit file
connected to the folder so the only way
to see it is to do it dear are and
there's probably multiple things into
that folder right now because I have
used its computer a lot so let's just
look Oh Tracy so here you can see
the different streams that's NTFS as a
feature NTFS so this you can actually
execute you're saying for instance
Viereck its tracing order Lexi and boom
we're running order runs from a folder
that Piazza and the problem is when you
create blocking rules because you want
to block like tracing the tracing Foley
you want to block that from execution
right but the problem is you have to
think of the open data streams as well
and this is something people tend to
forget so I will show you so what I
prefer to do is to instead of having
bung Group Policy where I shove in all
the whitelisting rules and all the
blocking rules and all that stuff I like
to create different group policies so I
create one on the top that are the
whitelisting rules mostly the default
rules with some tweaks and then I create
different blocking rules for the
different things that way I have full
control over each thing so if all that
was a HC path that was blocked okay let
me look and then I go straightly in here
and I'll find it easy so that that's a
good practice at least in my opinion and
so here's an example of blocking rules
and you cannot see it here but because I
have not included the ultimate data
stream blocking rules yet so this will
not block the demo I just showed this
will still allow me to use ultimate data
stream to execute so what you need to do
is to block all potato strips as well
so a normal rule will look like this on
the right side and on the left side you
can see I've added a colon and a star so
you need to do that in order to block
alternate data streams for executing so
that's an important step so there's a
great block by
geha stinger
about about this problem that I
recommend that you read okay
when it comes to third party what I
normally recommend is that you contact
the developer or their company in this
case where I had the team here I can
contact them over Twitter and I said all
you have to do their TeamViewer is to
block execution on that file and we're
good to go so they did that they added a
specific deny execution on that pile so
even though you have write access you
cannot use it to execute anything so
that's a proposed fix okay so that was
the default path rules so now you see
the problems with that and what you need
to harden and what you can use to bypass
it let's skip over to script rules so
what you can do with script rules is
that if you have our environment that
has upgraded from Windows 10 earlier
built to newer builds you will probably
have PowerShell version 2 meaning that
you can start PowerShell attack version
2 and this will bypass an important
function called constraint language mode
which locks down PowerShell so if you've
run PowerShell version 2 it will
actually run in full language mode
meaning that you can add things into
memory and do all sorts of nasty stuff
so an another cool thing when you do
this as an attacker is it doesn't get
logged because PowerShell version 2
didn't have logging so so you need to
you need to remove that stuff if you
want to be safe
fortunately the newest version of
Windows 10 when you install it you know
18:03 it doesn't include version 2 it's
off by default now so that that's a good
thing but if you have an environment
that has been upgraded over time you can
still see it so yeah so the proposed fix
is of course to remove it so the coolest
way is to use PowerShell to remove
version 2 a PowerShell of course that's
the first fix from a friend mat so yeah
there's plenty of ways to remove it the
important thing is just
remember to remove it there was a blog
post like just a couple of weeks ago
where someone a brilliant guy called
Adam Chester found a bypass for
Castilian language mode he did a lot of
stuff I mean wow it's a really really
good blog post so it bypasses he managed
to bypass cuz to end language mode in
the environment he was in and I talked
to him before he published it and one
thing that maybe it didn't get people
saw was that if you enable DLL rules
this will actually be blocked so even
though it's a bypass if you correct if
we configure it correctly this would
have been blocked because you want the y
ll rules enabled and that's why so what
it could do it could actually load up a
DLL using PowerShell it from constrained
language mode we found out it's pretty
it's a pretty clever clever move still
and it's a great white up so it was just
that I need to highlight that if you
configure it correctly it will not work
but I have something else so I started
to look at preparing for this session
like early this summer I was looking at
well every time I start PowerShell when
I have a blocker enabled if there's an
error saying that the PSM one file and
the ps1 file under the temp folder was
prevented from running and I got curious
what is this so here you can see I'm in
a constrained language mode and what I
found out is that this is the way app
Locker figures out if it's in
constrained language mode or not so what
you can do is redirect the temp area to
a place where script execution is
allowed so when you then start
PowerShell it will be in full language
mode
and that's freaking awesome so I have a
blog post that I will I have prepared
I haven't published it yet I will
publish it later today where I have
details about this I did contact
Microsoft about it
that didn't wanna fix it because its
design so here's this air Stupak strip I
wrote there's a better one in the module
I will be leasing today but just to show
you what I what I've done so the first
thing is just to create two variables
setting the existing temp variables and
then I of course tells it where where
where is the allowed place to execute
scripts and with the default drills see
Windows temp is allowed because
everything on the windows is allowed to
run as squares so then I set the new my
current user temporary balls to these
bypassed paths then I use something
called invoked in vmi method to start
another powershell session because if
you start powershell by just typing
powershell it doesn't read the temp
variable for some reason and i tried a
lot of different things but this works
so you start you just via my method it
really right
we reads the temporals and you're good
to go and now i just set it back so when
you do that you will have a full
language powershell running so let me
show you you don't believe me
see just copy this so here we are let's
start PowerShell
so here I am in constrained language
move right so I'll just paste the script
then boom have a full language
aha thank you suppose a quick demo
coolpix a girl yeah so that was the part
of the scripting words now I'm moving
over to the MSI apx rules so as you
probably have figured out I'm covering
each section so the problem with the MSI
default rules is that it allows
everything that is designed everything
that is digitally signed Wow
same goes for app X and that's a problem
because getting a code signing cert it's
like 80 bucks and it's not that hard to
get it and you can use something like
MSF venom or whatever to create an MSI
file and then we can just sign it
using a sign tool and then you just
execute the payload and it it runs so
that's that's an easy bypass for cadets
cool so that that needs to be tweaked in
order to harden it so the mitigation has
to this is the best I've come up with is
to instead of allow everything to run
just allow at least only Microsoft's MSI
files to run you can start there at
least that's better than everything and
also if you if you use SSE em I would
probably use something called managed
installer that's something you can
enable in app Locker so everything that
comes from SCCM will automatically be
whitelisted
that's also something you can do that's
way beyond the top this they start but
yeah that's also possible and the same
goes for a pacts rules changed changed
it to allow on the DS to to run things
from Microsoft they have different
certificates I think there's a total of
three basic actually but I've only
listed to here but instead of allowing
everything to run narrow it down to what
you really want to run cool yes and then
you have you have something called known
bypasses even though you configure
everything correctly there's still a lot
of binaries that you can use to execute
code to bypass the protection of app
Locker so there's a lot of known
discoveries made by other great people
like Sub T and Matt graver and all those
guys where you can use install util I
must build MSHDA reg reg Assam Vegas we
see and VST o files I have a list I have
up actually our github repo called the
ultimate app Locker bypass list and I
try to update it as much as I can with
new known techniques so I recommend that
you check that out when you start to
harden your app Locker environment or if
you're looking for a bypass depends on
which side you're on
if we go beyond the default rules I've
seen places where they allow everything
from Microsoft to run
that's it helps but it doesn't help
especially when it comes to binaries
like XE files because there's a lot of
as you saw even though you block these
known bypasses and allow things for
Microsoft to run you still run into
problems here there's even more to block
because if you allow everything from
Microsoft that means I can download
things from Microsoft page other tools
and run them so for instance in this
example here I'm oh I missed up the
slide ok so
when you allow everything from Microsoft
to run for instance you can download BG
info or you can download compilers and
such and run code that way
so there's known techniques to bypass
AppLocker
if you allow everything from Microsoft
to run so that there's a huge amount of
binaries and that's what I'm trying to
map out in my AppLocker bypass lists so
check it out
another typical Mis configuration I see
a lot and I tweet it out like not that
long ago that I I think exceptions are
evil and Aaron Ragosa started to defend
it and that's fine they had a good point
but still I I find them evil so in app
Locker you can either create a deny rule
directly like you create a new rule and
say I'm not allowing this to run or you
can go inside our rule and there's a tab
called exceptions where you can add
exceptions so for instance allowing
everything under C winners to run except
for folder a b c and d right so when you
do that you can have assumed that you
block execution from that place right so
a thing i see like for instance here
you're okay this is a typical set where
you didn't I I calculate it will block
it right but when you do when you use an
exception there's a problem because here
is I'm inside the windows folder I'm
adding an exception for I cackles the
problem here is that he has also allowed
everything from Microsoft to run so the
problem here is that even though I'm
thinking okay what should happen here in
my head i cackles shouldn't be allowed
to run but that's not case it will
actually be allowed to run since we have
this rule here so that's totally
confusing and i and i see this a lot so
i prefer to keep my hip use strict deny
rules and don't use exceptions i think
that's easier to maintain their point
Aaron had was that if you have admins it
makes it makes it hard for you to kind
of segregate what you allow for an admin
to run and a user to run
so that that's a good point but in my
opinion when I harden clients I will not
allow any admin to log in there at all
they shouldn't like log on ever if you
want to do something on a client you
push it to a system SCCM or Altiris or
something else that's my opinion
yeah sorry I cattles why have i showing
you this
okay i was i was supposed to okay don't
mind i went ahead and told you
everything before i had the slides ready
so my bad yeah so if you open if you as
I said if you allow everything from
Microsoft you open the door for other
binaries to run such as PG info then you
can use that to execute code you also
have other binaries such as c DB and
there's a long list so just go into the
github repo and you will you will see
them all there's a long list and you can
also with the lower best project where
you can see different binaries that can
do other stuff that's a good resource as
well
okay so hardening rules if you go into
that github repo I have pre created all
the routes you need to like totally lock
it down so I have a default rules
improved that's instead of using the
default rules you can actually download
that XML and you can right-click inside
where you configure AppLocker and import
that rule set and there's instructions
on that github repo and the improved
thing is that it doesn't allow
everything from Microsoft to run smsc
files prints allows everyone to run
signed MSE files it only allows from
Microsoft's Princeton's so I have pre
created up for you and I also created
all these blocked rules so this includes
blocking every known binary the dust
evil stuff that I know of and it also
includes ultimate data streams as well
so
feel free to use them I haven't tested
them a lot so it could break things so
you need to like test them in an
environment before you put it into
production that's a place by right now
never it's all good yeah that's correct
that's correct okay so back to Aaron
Locker I started looking into our locker
because I was curious what this was so
it makes it a lot easier for us as IT
admins to maintain a bigger rule set
because it can scan the computer and add
things that are missing in a more
intelligent way than the default or
create rules based on scanning from the
Apocrypha the only problem as of today
is that it's missing rules for alternate
data streams so I reached out to Aaron
about this last week no early this week
I can't remember anyways he has said
that he has he has almost ready to
release his next version of Aaron Locker
where this is a part of the of the
release
amongst other things so he has fixed it
and I had prepared this slide to just
show you the problem and this is an
important rule from Aaron Locker where
he has used exceptions for for instance
tracing but he has forgot the ultimate
data streams so here you can just take
in evil EXCI file pipe it to tracing as
I showed you early in the demo and you
can use either bit admin or there
there's a lot of ways to execute all the
data streams I have a complete list at
the bottom if you're interested in
ultimate data streams so that's a pretty
good resource there so how am I on time
so my recommendation I prefer the
default rules that's number one always
enable dll's
even though it states there's a
performance degrade isn't true
okay this is my recommendation not
everyone agrees it depends on your
environment
I don't like exceptions because I find
them confusing I would rather prefer
deny rules that's my opinion I'll be
sure to create deny rules for paths that
users can first write to and also add
80s for the same paths create publisher
deny rules for bad by a bad binaries
such as msbuild
PowerShell why would I used to need to
run PowerShell I don't see the point
so create deny rules to block stuff and
of course as I said remove all the rules
that allow every signer I every signed
file to run that's a bad idea and last
but not least enable central monitoring
it's it's pretty easy actually to enable
event forwarding in Windows so you can
take all the events you get from every
workstation and put them into one
central place so you can see what has
run what has blocked and what not so
that's something I recommend if you
don't have like a cm solution or you can
run a Splunk agent on the host or
something
so yeah that's something I would
recommend it yeah so during my prep for
this talk I started earlier this year to
create something that made it easier for
me to discover this burn abilities
because that's important yeah I don't
wanna use a lot of time so I released it
4:00 a.m. tonight or something and the
sweet thing about this is that it runs
in constrained language mode so you
don't have to have like a full
powershell language mode in order to run
the module so that's like a big thing
when you when you like test on AppLocker
and i started out by doing like a lot of
thing like ad type and all that stuff
and it get gets blocked because of
Christian language mode of course so I
had to rewrite a couple times and some
of the code is not beautiful but it
works
and that's mostly because of constraint
language mode you have to be like really
figure out ways to get around it for
instance if you want to like check AC
else you would have thought that that
should be easy so you can just get a CL
in PowerShell
and you can get the AC else that's right
but if you want to set them you cannot
do it in Christian language mode because
you have to have the ability to use the
ad type who would have figured so i
scratch my head a long time I reached
out to callers and he reached out to Lee
homes the only way he said it was
possible was to to sign it so that's a
workaround but I don't want to do this
this project the first so yeah there are
some problems along the way so it
automates a lot of the hunting for the
vulnerabilities I think it's good for
both red and blue and please note it's
not feature complete yet it's still
under progress but but at least have
something to show for so that be quick
demo it for you
I still have some minutes left for pool
so on this host this sister could snap
you just let me close down some stuff
here so I have under my temp folder I
have all the functions so have I have
separated each function into a file
because I think that's easier to
maintain so first I just run PowerShell
in an unrestricted mode so that I can
run scripts and then I go into my temp
folder Parral and then I use import
module like this and now all the command
that's are in my in the memory so I can
for instance if I want to list up the
rules there are built-in commanders for
this but I don't like them I think
they're too
complex so I like UDC so if I do
something like this
yet how rules I can choose what sort of
rules I want I want all rules do I want
only pass rules path rules publisher
rules yeah so I want all done rule
actions maybe I want all or maybe I just
want the allow rules or the deny rules
so in this case just everything you can
also specify sits if you want to search
for a specific set default it uses like
everyone you can also export it to an
XML and you can take it offline and use
the same command that's against XML file
to figure it out
to instruct okay cool yeah so a lot of
fun stuff so if I run this I can view
the rules as yes and I can like go into
each one of them for instance like this
and I can use rule lists and I get all
the rules so it's pretty nice and I get
the path the original path because
there's a problem when you use a proctor
when you have a % program files there's
actually two paths
it's Program Files and Program Files x86
so I have to like split them out and
stuff so yeah that's pretty awesome yeah
I don't have time to show you everything
but let me show you the constraint
language mode bypass so this will
actually get all the script rules it
will figure out a path it can use to
redirect the temp and it doesn't change
the temporary ball it'll actually just
manipulates how the VMA vmi method is
invoked so this is pretty cool so just
run it BAM it figures out finds a
suitable location it picks a random path
out of the different paths it finds and
then it's just launched it change the
temporary bills and lost PowerShell and
there's also another cool thing once
here bypass spawn you can specify a
binary and it will figure out our place
it can place the binary and
secured it and I'm also working on an
edition where you can use 80s as a
parameter at the at the end so I can I
think I have time to show it real quick
I'm sorry
so yeah something went wrong okay sorry
I'll fix that
but yeah damn it I'm all out of time if
you want to see more please please just
come grab me and I'll show you more
sure thanks
[Applause]