so this is putting the bits back
together doing forensic investigations
in Amazon Web Services ec2 if you are
here hoping for something else I'm
really sorry to disappoint you there's
also going to be no in-flight service
today so further disappointment a little
bit about me my name is Brandon Sherman
I am a senior cloud security engineer at
Twilio we are a noted clothing
manufacturer and also occasional we
dabble in technology we're a cloud
communications company we make it
possible for text messages voice video
fax all these different means of
communicating to be accessible to you
through api's I'm also a Krav Maga
instructor in sort of my hobby my mentor
wants to describe security as being like
being in a boxing ring and fighting
rounds until you get knocked out and I
was perfect because that's pretty much
my hobby I generally have a cloudy
outlook on life and technology and all
that which is only somewhat affected by
the fact I've spent about four and a
half five years now working with Amazon
and AWS I'm a certified cloud solutions
architect professional grade which means
that I get 20% more LinkedIn spam and I
have definitely drunk the cloud kool-aid
so what we're going to talk about we're
going to start out with why we're gonna
go and talk about the sort of some
background on AWS ec2 and EBS quick show
of hands who here uses Amazon Web
Services cool anyone just sort of cloud
services in general anyone just wanted
to raise your hand because you wanted to
awesome we're going to go through the
sort of research methodology and my
findings and then we're going to talk
about protecting your forensic data
keeping control of that chain of custody
so one of our values that Twilio is to
start with why and personally this is
one of my favorite values because it
always makes you think what sort of a
the driving purpose behind this and one
of the big reasons why is
well happens proof of this exists
all over it's good to know we're gonna
need some of these techniques eventually
so other reasons why compromises happen
we're at a security conference we're
talking about how to protect data of and
from things going wrong this is actually
a great side because I've given us and
one of my co-workers like every time you
leave that to do in there and I told him
it's great because it's always relevant
last time it was Newegg last week it was
Facebook who knows it'll be next week
the other reason why is that prevention
is ideal but detection is a must this is
a very difficult sort of field to be and
there's a very good chance at one point
we're not going to get something right
and that's why it's important to know
not just that we've stopped an attack
but when an attack does happen we know
the full breadth of that attack how can
we know how bad something was if we
can't detect it so a forensic
investigation is investigating an event
that happened in the past
and we're going to use scientific
techniques to do so we're going to start
out we're going to say what we're going
to do we're going to work our way
through it we're going to show our work
and that way we can come to a conclusion
at the end this is not the sort of thing
that we want to be doing after an event
we want this capability to know how to
do something reliably and repeatedly
before something bad happens and
personally I just find what's more
what's hidden a lot more interesting
than what's visible so has an attacker
deleted log files have they caused log
files to roll over are did they use some
malware dropper that erased itself
what's what's going on sort of behind
the scenes that someone's trying to hide
from me versus what someone's willing to
let me see so we're going to start out
and talk about the cloud
and for the purposes of this talk we're
just going to say that Amazon Web
Services is the cloud Google cloud as
your other clouds out there they exist I
don't work with them as frequently as I
do at AWS some of these techniques may
be transferable so one of you can give
this talk next year on a different cloud
service this is also not supposed to be
an introductory course to AWS saw a lot
of hands go up this is also not meant to
be an advanced course in AWS I want to
give you just what you need to know to
understand the rest of the techniques
Amazon Web Services is comprised of a
lot of these services that's what the
console looks like at least recently I
didn't check it today we're gonna be
focusing on four of us if you missed out
where ec2 elastic cloud compute EBS
elastic block storage I am which is
identity and access management and s3
the simple storage service there in
those spots on the console so ec2 stands
for elastic cloud compute unit of
computation it's essentially a virtual
machine on demand you can even now rent
by the minute they're metal instances
from Amazon which is another interesting
concept but they all have different
capabilities in terms of CPU RAM
networking GPUs etc it's very very
simple you click a button and you get a
server if you have an API you hit that
API endpoint you get another server if
you have a script with a loop you hit
the API a lot and you get a lot of
servers by default all of these servers
are going to be scattered through the
data center they have shared tendency
but if your security needs require then
you can use dedicated tenancy and that
way you know that your neighbor is on
the hypervisor are at least other
instances owned by you a starting point
the sort of golden boot image for an ec2
image is an ami it's an Amazon machine
this is the initial host operating
system any configuration any soft earth
sort of the initial bootstrapping it's
possible to create one of these machine
images from a running instance and this
is going to include any configuration
files and software on that instance
makes it very easy if you need to
duplicate a server to just create an
image from it and launch a new server
but this is going to come back a little
bit later in the talk some instances
have what's called instant storage some
of them don't this is sure shocking the
instant storage though is is interesting
from a forensic standpoint and from a
security standpoint because it's
ephemeral it's directly connected it's
very fast but it's also designed to
basically go away once your instance
stops running this is in contrast to an
EBS volume elastic block storage this is
where you request a volume you say I
want a 15 gigabyte volume and I want it
attached to this host kind of sort of
think of it like Network attacked
storage but it shows up locally and
there's different backing mechanisms
behind EBS so these days if you want
block storage you get five different
options and they all have a backing
between spinning disks solid-state disk
different throughputs difference in
maximum sizes different prices naturally
charged in cents per gigabyte per month
which is fun for your accounting teams
but this is this is sort of when you
want a persistent disk that won't go
away once your instance does you use a
PS volume but the cool thing is that
they all have the same annualized
failure rate between point 1 and point 2
percent doesn't matter how big doesn't
matter what backing material is none of
that matters it just fails about an
order of a magnitude less than a
commodity off-the-shelf hard drive
so how does Amazon guarantee this
failure rate across multiple drives or
rather how do they guarantee this
failure rate in a single Drive that is
made up of something mysterious on the
backend it's about like twenty times
more durable than a hard drive you could
go out and buy and stick in your laptop
or a server in your rack so is this
magic well probably something a little
bit more sinister than that so to recap
elastic block storage is disk storage
that's actually network-attached storage
that has different capabilities that
depending on which type of instance you
are attaching it to will show up either
on the side of us or the nvme pci bus
it had can be dynamically sized upwards
but it's statically allocated they fail
one xx as often as a regular
off-the-shelf drive and you can take a
snapshot of them with an API call the
contents of that snapshot is kind of
what we really get into in this talk
because with all of this magic going on
or this this dark black magic that's
happening in the background is the
snapshot something that we can use to
make a forensic investigation possible
we're also going to talk about a little
bit of knowledge for Identity and Access
Management this is pretty fine-grained
permission controls who can do what when
where why but for example taking
snapshots is a permission that can be
granted or also restricted deleting
snapshots likewise is a permission that
can be granted or restricted and this
really comes into the chain of custody
that's going to be necessary to follow a
to ensure that these snapshots are kept
safe s3 so right you can take a snapshot
of that volume it gets stored in s3 the
snapshots don't have to be done when
that EBS volume is offline and detached
you can take a snapshot from a running
instance Amazon warns you that you might
see data inconsistencies I've
personally never seen one really go
wrong but it's it is possible you're
taking a snapshot of a running moving
desk with data flying on it these
snapshots are stored in s3 and they're
immutable they're the a.m. eyes are
special EBS snapshots so an ami is just
an EVs snapshot that's been blessed so
that way you can use it as a boot volume
and you can launch your volume from
these a.m. eyes but you can launch on
either to start with EBS or a ephemeral
storage and it kind of matters just sort
of for performance and what you want to
get out of your your virtual hardware
but the snapshots
they're also versioned they're not sort
of version 1 version 2 version 3 but
each time you take a snapshot of a disc
you get a new snapshot ID you're only
charged and the only parts of the
snapshot that are taken and kept are the
parts that are different from the
earlier snapshot so your v1 snapshot ID
is gonna be the full disk then v2 v3 v4
v5 as long as you keep taking snapshots
will get different IDs but may only be a
few bytes different if you need to
delete a middle snapshot you might be
waiting a while because you've got to
compute the diffs on both sides but this
also means that we can take a snapshot
of a volume multiple times maybe you
don't want to terminate an instance
right away you suspect that it's
compromised you want to do an
investigation but you don't want to take
it offline so you don't tip your hand in
this way you can keep seeing what's on
the disk without necessarily taking it
offline taking a snapshot and then doing
an inspection of it all right story time
so we have four different players people
and they are all going to play a game of
Clue clue is a trademark of Milton
Bradley EBS is a trademark of Amazon and
we're gonna pretend that the clue board
is a hard drive rather a EBS volume
and each square here is a a block that
data has been written to a player has
been has been moved through so clue if
you don't know it's a classic whodunit
you're trying to figure out by moving
around the board and picking up clues
who did what
so did miss white erase the log files in
the library was it Colonel Mustard in
the kitchen who was forcing log files to
roll over and hide his tracks well let's
take a snapshot and investigate if only
we could see past turns that had been
deleted that were on the board hmm so if
we take a snapshot of an EB som one of
these API calls his that snapshot going
to contain in use blocks or does it also
contain the deleted blocks by Omega it's
a ext4 file system I delete a file it's
very easy to understand that from a sort
of hypervisor level maybe those files
just aren't included in a snapshot does
it matter what that original volume pipe
is Amazon originally had just the
standard EBS storage but now there's
four new ones doesn't matter what that
is and doesn't matter what the instance
type is because these disks can show up
on either the nvme or SATA thus
depending on which generation instance
they're attached to is that going to
affect our ability to either recover
data or sorry is that going to affect
our ability to delete data secure from
these drives and make it impossible to
find or affect our ability to do the
recovery so here's the steps that I
followed start out by launching a bunch
of ec2 instances take an EVs volume of
each type attach it to each type of
instance write some known seed files
that I pulled off of my hard drive right
up to the EBS volumes then delete those
files use the API to trigger a snapshot
once I have those snapshots rehydrate
them onto a brand-new clean EVS volume
and then go looking for files and
because this is all through API is I was
able to write some very quick
dirty scripts that basically said let's
you want to start burning some cash so
this is the what it looks like to burn
virtual money in a virtual console a
whole bunch of instances coming online
I used the aw system service manager
which is just a way basically for me to
run some commands across all the
machines without having to write an ssh
script or use any other kind of tooling
basically just grab these files right up
to disk flushed out the file buffers
wait makes they're really truly flushed
delete those files and then again sync
the the file buffers so that goes it
runs and then i targeted twenty
instances and I got tells me it all
around successfully and then since I'm
not made of money go ahead and terminate
and shut all these instances down so if
we're gonna go back to our clue board
game analogy in the sort of the magic
clew console we triggered a snapshot of
the board in its final state and we've
done this against for whatever the ec2
instance right the magic controller of
that clear board we took a snapshot of
that we're going to go ahead and see
what happened to that board game what
happened in that volume to do the
digging i used software called
photo rack photorec is freely available
it's really really awesome software it's
used to it looks at the raw blocks of a
disk and compares that data to known
file signatures is anyone ever used
photorec before yeah
vacation photos or something like that
on a card wipe by accident maybe yeah
I've never done that
never so what it does is it doesn't
understand file systems it just knows
when I look at a block on disk does this
match an own signature of a file type is
does this look like an image does this
look like a PDF what can I do from and
then go from there
so my forensics script was to take each
of these snapshots that I had in the
console rehydrate those to a brand new
EBS volume attached that EBS volume to a
forensics investigation instance and
then run photo rack and start looking
for deleted files and so this is just an
example of the script running so it goes
and it grabs it makes a new file system
on a new volume you don't have to know
what any of this means it just looks
really impressive to have text scrolling
around but the upshot of all that text
scrolling around is we can get some
results and these results are a little
weird
yet heaps of files showing up in the
directory would hold photo rack to write
files to and when you take a quick
glance you see various kinds of files
that we'd expect my seed files you know
m4a JPEG PDF bunch of text files but we
don't just find the seed files we find a
lot more than those on the disk and it's
a it's very very noisy and the reason of
this is EBS volume eyes are snapshots
if you use an EBS volume as the root
volume to launch your instance it's
going to be a hydrator it's gonna be
coming out from that ami and that ami
has as the snapshot all kinds of deleted
files in it this is potentially
overwhelming there are a lot of files at
an operating system writes and uses in
it's sort of day-to-day operations that
are sort of normal and expected I can't
tell you how many different languages of
man pages show up in the results when
you go looking at an AMI so this was
sort of like if the clue OS game analogy
we're using here if the operating system
of like the rules of the game was sort
of running on the same board as the
players were moving around in which the
analogy breaks down a little bit but the
point being there's a lot of stuff that
we're going to get back and
Clou board it would be like if we got
the instructions showing up on our
results in 50 different languages along
with what we actually wanted to find the
whodunit part of the mystery and that's
just cuz it very simple a.m. eyes are
snapshots a.m. eyes contain deleted
files if you use photorec on a volume
that was the start up volume so it was
born from that ami you're going to find
a whole lot of those deleted files you
will also very likely get the actuals
you'll get like your results won't get
in Latin to a second but all the games
set up so it's like an in clue we
started Colonel Mustard in one corner
and this white in another corner we
would see that setup action has as being
as happening so when you go looking at
photorec results this is what you get a
few file names but mostly just a whole
lot of I found this type of file and I
gave it a file name based off of where I
found it it is a lot of data so how do I
know given all of these different files
that I've recovered which ones are my
actual seed files and which ones are
this sort of noise from the Nami so we
play match the hash start out by just
comparing the files and even if you're
not using an image sorry if you're not
doing using a snapshot of a volume that
was an ami or using a secondary volume
you're still going to get more files
returned so it's this is because photo
guesses where new files end in war files
and a new files start it's not always
super clear it's a software that just
looking at a stream of bytes in
gibberish what is a new file what's an
old file this is especially true with
text files and operating systems
especially stuff like Linux is made up
a lot of text files as an example is
there some of the text files that I used
I just kind of looked at a bunch of them
and just something like a the readme
from version 1.0 four of Windows some
forensic capture textbook that was free
and turned out to not be very useful but
more interesting and this is a better
demonstration to my point this is
originally the same text file it's the
just a list of flights in one day in the
United States the sort of from airport
in the to airport tax files don't have
really start or ends they're just bits
written to disk photorec doesn't know
that this was originally one big text
file that was a seated it just sees okay
here's a text file and it goes and at
some point it stops so I think maybe I
should stop - and then I picked up a
trail of more text files and go on from
there so this is originally one file
that's now been split across into many
many dozens of files so if you just
start namely hashing the files that you
find in your recovery directory and the
your seat files you're gonna find that
most of the time you swing and you miss
you get a whole lot of files back this
obviously these two files are never
going to have the same hash as the
original file so there might be a little
a little bit dispiriting you think that
well I can't find I can't like do any
analysis on this if I don't know that
I'm getting the data back but if instead
we compare the first few hundred bytes
or so then we can get a better sense of
how many of these original files are
actually recovered and I use like three
hundred bytes that seem to be a kind of
a good mix for between false positives
and and true positives and so really all
it meant was I computed the hash of all
of these things and then started to
check and see and again this is just the
instances and the volume types that were
originally attached to them and then
looking through and doing the some of
the legwork to see how many files were
recovered
so up to this point right we've written
files to disk we've noticed that a.m.
eyes are snapshots themselves and so
they contain deleted files we've been
able to recover these files we get a
bunch of that noise from the ami
snapshots we also get a bunch of our
actual original source files back but
the original source of volume type has
an impact on what kind of volume are
what kind of results we can recover the
standard gp2 and io one volume types
were sort of the best recovery the sc1
and st-1 were not so good and this is
just sorry if it's a little bit small
but for the SC one an ST one was forty
seven percent and twenty percent
respectively and these numbers if you go
out and you do this at home they will
vary because of that magic amazon's
doing in the back end of somehow being
consistent when I asked for a block back
but distributing that block amongst
multiple other systems of redundancy and
who really knows I I don't know I don't
know how EVs works someone here works
for Amazon and wants to pull me aside
and tell me then awesome look to it love
to know more about the sort of man
behind the curtain but anyway so these
two these two types of EBS volumes
designed for large data consistent
throughput it's not saying that they
were bad and in any means it's just that
compared to the other volumes where it's
89 percent recovery plus was very very
good when it comes to recovering data
these other volume pipe just kind of
stand out in comparison but the weird
artifacts don't stop there when I was
recovering from the sc1 and st-1 drive
types
there were times that I got truly
massive files back no other file I know
their volume pipe
have that issue with it was just with
these two large bulk storage ones and
this is just a capture that so
originally written seed files to disks I
did their recovery and then I looked at
sort of just to see how much disk space
I had gotten I was using to know if I
could use the same just for other
recoveries and I found that there 272
gigs used on my forensic recovery drive
and part of that is because when you go
looking at the different files that were
recovered if you don't speak exact bits
is some of these PDFs we're taking a
hundred and sixty one gigs the pedia are
the video files the m4p files 180
megabytes exactly what we expected
perfect match but these other PDS 21
gigs 24 gigs and this was the 24s are
sort of almost outliers I consistently
was getting these massive files and I
actually had to increase my target
volume size because I was simply just
getting so many of these massive
artifacts back a PDFs are generally not
that big if you know of like an actual
legit PDF that big in the wild let me
know because it sounds like you've got
some really great war stories but this
was truly interesting and so as to why
well I got some bad news for you I don't
know this is something that has to do
with how EBS works I'm sure in the back
end I don't know why it's only those two
types I can sort of guess the recovery
issue where the end of file marker for
that PDF was sort of found across some
it was multiple discs in the back end
that was sort of being concatenated
together maybe and that maybe explains
why it was only these two volumes but it
doesn't explain why only those two
volumes and other EBS volumes of
different types so again this is this is
who knows if you're curious this was the
PDF it was like a hundred and sixty K
our kilobytes really just this small I
don't remember even where I got it was
some sort of diagram pattern thing
almost looks like Conway's Game of Life
if he squint a little bit but this was
this file was should never be that large
and it was consistent - so now that we
know we can get data back and we'll all
kind of loop back around to some
findings at the end here but let's talk
about protecting this data all right
that PDF right we really want to make
sure that we can go through and know
that it's safe so snapshots can be
shared to other AWS accounts this is a
really great property of them because if
there's an attacker in your account and
they've already breached one of your ec2
instances they may be able to delete
those snapshots if you have a over
provisioned permissions on that ec2
instance and you do a snapshot of it you
do the recovery in the it you're kind of
waiting and the attacker is still in
your account they've exfiltrated an API
key they can watch you take that
forensic snapshot and then once your
snapshot is completed they can delete
your snapshot the best way to keep the
snapshot safe is to move them into a
separate account so once once you hold
the ball don't drop it
I hear so I'm a millennial so I hear I'm
supposed to really like avocado toast in
JSON if you don't like JSON I've got
some sort of bad news for you
identity and access management in AWS is
almost entirely solely JSON everywhere
permissions matter dealing with them in
a JSON format is something that is a
skill that I've acquired I have acquired
and I'm really sorry for everyone else
that has the ability to just parse these
documents by eye because it's you know
it's there's a lot of room for
complexity in these that being said so
this is not a basics of securing your aw
account talk happy to do that at another
time but this is just what sort of
things you need to be aware of when you
take one of these snapshots and you need
to keep it safe so if we know that we
have this forensic evidence we want to
keep it safe we want to know it hasn't
been tampered with we can't leave them
somewhere that they can be tampered with
and some of you in the back that are
nodding off might be going well yeah uh
but where can they be tampered with
where is right it's no longer the case
that you send an investigator out and
they go and they pick up a server and
they image the hard drive of it and they
put it in a briefcase and lock that
briefcase to their wrist and they fly on
a private jet back to your orbiting
headquarters and do the analysis there
at least allegedly I've been working in
the cloud for so long I forget what it's
like to have physical Hardware if there
aren't space stations you do your
friends arc recovery on then maybe I
need to get in touch with you so we want
to use come on there we go
so we're gonna use I am to make sure
that we secure the access to these
snapshots and it's really who what where
when and how so you could potentially
grant Colonel Mustard the ability to use
AWS lamda only in the lobby you could
say these these API calls require MFA
they can only be done from a certain IP
range you're only allowed to operate on
select resources this is an example AWS
policy this is the administrator policy
it says you can perform any action on
any resource it's very helpful if you
are struggling with your permission then
you're not sure what you're doing wrong
why you're getting permission denied or
something this will solve your problems
every time there's some people here are
like I did I'm not wrong though it will
solve your problem it's going to create
a whole lot of new ones though
this is the policy I attached to my ec2
instances to allow them to actually grab
the seed files this buckets not public
so there's also no PII in it unlike some
other like every other day there's a new
one of those but again like it's a this
is a much more restricted policy so if
you see the star star I that's you want
to look into that before it becomes an
issue especially because this policy
will only let me get things out of a
bucket this policy will let me modify
the files in that bucket then delete
snapshots when they're taken and then
own the whole account and lock the user
the legitimate owners that account out
which is another fun talk that some can
be gone through but the critically even
if you have that star star policy
because it's just easier than solving
your permissions issues and the
complexity of JSON those permissions
only work within a singular AWS account
an Amazon an account is basically like
in erecting blast walls around something
if something goes boom in an account it
can't touch other accounts there are
configuration mistakes that you can make
but you've got to try really hard to
make those happen and even still those
API keys aren't going to magically have
the power into other accounts so when
you get noticed that there's an instance
behaving strangely and you're doing an
investigation into it do you know what's
on that instance does that instance have
um
does that incidents have a policy that
is star star does it have a policy that
lets you permission escalate to star
star are there even not even necessarily
permissions granted to it but someone
couldn't figure out how to do that or
they wanted to work in another account
and so they put their API keys on that
instance static credentials are those on
that instance and yes you can do a
forensic recovery and find API keys
people have hard-coded into that
instance so
what happens in that well strictly
speaking the planet is like a blast
radius right this is I think many people
would consider it to be bad situation so
if we think of sort of this detonation
as happening what's going to contain it
well the fact that at some point there
is no more planet left to go boom
however other planets are going to be
perfectly unharmed and not suffer any
ill consequences although they might
laugh a little bit at the loss of the
whole planet the analogy that I'm trying
to make here which is sort of getting
away from you in the whole spectacle and
Michael Bay show is another Amazon
account can be very easily set up and by
default cannot be touched by anyone else
in that other account so don't take
chances you take that snapshot and as
soon as it's completed initiate a copy
to another account get it out of the
danger zone
there's a just I felt like I couldn't go
through this talk without touching on
AWS cloud trail
it's a cataloguing of API calls almost
all of them there are some caveats to
that I feel like I've been saying that a
lot was this you can do this but then
there's a caveat to it which is a but it
is it is almost all the important things
it is all the important things rather in
an account enable it write those log
files to a separate account this does
you two favors one it can help you
figure out if someone is on the ec2
instance and is trying to list snapshots
continuously trying to see if they can
delete any of them but also this gives
you proof this gives you a proof of your
custody over a snapshot and let you say
oh yeah I know that this user forensic
investigator a logged into this account
and they perform these actions trigger
snapshot name snapshot copy snapshot to
other account and then once in the other
account forensic investigator be logged
in and they attach that snapshot to a
new host
and they performed an analysis of it
there so this helps dramatically with
your chain of custody you don't need to
have a log that's viewed and notarized
by four different people saying who has
done what to an image you can just let
the cloud take care of that for you so
here's sort of a little graphics let's
say this is our Amazon account we have
one server in it and there's an EBS
volume attached to that server and we
suspect that it's compromised or it's
acting a little strange and we want to
look into it deeper
so trigger the snapshot snapshot winds
up in s3 and after some period of time
it will complete but if we leave it
there and we're gonna try and do a
forensics all in the same place then
what can happen is someone else shows up
with API keys and what they can do with
those API keys is burn the snapshot and
then burn the rest of it out potentially
depends on what permission those keys
have but again it's easier to grant
admin permissions and sort them out
later than it is to scope your
permissions appropriately so the benefit
here if you have a separate account you
can still do the same thing create that
snapshot gets pushed into s3 but then it
gets copied into the other account not
just viewable but actually copied into
that other account now yes something bad
can happen alright someone can still
show up and they can burn out the whole
the original account but you still have
that snapshot over in the other account
and their API keys if they were to try
and access that other account are going
to be just flat out rejected so you may
also be sad
your attacker will may also be sad
you've lost an account but you have a
way to trace back and see what actually
happened how did they get in
and what did they try and hide from you
on the way in there alright so some
takeaways what does your threat model
look like if you truly need high-quality
forensics and you need to be able to say
without the shadow of any doubt that yes
an action that happened on this instance
I am able to read that data back if you
need that capability don't use the S c1
s t1 or thermal storage your the quality
of your forensics isn't going to be top
of the top of the class if you don't
need that capability then just be aware
of it understand the limitations
involved when it comes to to doing a
forensic recovery know that if you have
to do an analysis on an SE 1 or s t1
drive that it may require a massive
volume on the other end to collect and
see all those artifacts the ephemeral
storage is well it's ephemeral you can't
snapshot it as soon as the ec2 instance
gets terminated it goes away so you
won't be able to see that data at all
consider only allowing rights to
non-root EBS volumes that ami with all
of its artifacts can be very very bad
for your signal-to-noise ratio it is
possible that if you have a very long
running instance or you have a many
large history of am eyes or just a lot
of data on it that there'll be too much
noise for you to be able to find the
deleted files especially if you're not
lucky enough to start out with known
hashes of your seed files if you're
looking for Apache logs and Jeanette's
logs whatever software you're using and
you're looking to see where those one
are then you you may not be able to find
them or you may take you a very long
time to find those log files if they
were successfully recovered also use
multiple accounts this is something that
I say a lot kind of big proponent of it
they are free to create and using
multiple accounts means that you
can separate out and reduce your risk
you put up more blast walls so that way
if something bad does happen you don't
lose everything especially because a
breach of a server which because I'm
sure all of us can think of that one
developer that just doesn't have time to
figure out their policies and uses an
administrative policy or maybe there's a
something wrong in your policy that
allows for privilege escalation or
someone put API keys on an incidence
whatever it is that if you have done
that that breach of that server could be
a loss of all of your stuff the cloud
gives and the cloud takes away
it will give you as many servers as you
want with an API key as long as your
credit card still will allow the
transaction but at the same time it also
allows you to take away all of those
servers with an API key that account
lets you limit the blast radius it keeps
your forensics importa Lee importantly
out of that blast radius finally also
enable cloud trail it's great for
looking and seeing what API calls have
happened it's great for seeing what API
calls are being denied but make sure
that those cloud trail logs are being
written to another account because if
you're leaving it in the same account as
you're potentially compromised
infrastructure then you might have a big
problem as well when it comes to that be
careful what you write to an AMI
a really common pattern is for an
organization to create an ami for use
internally it's very easy to do then you
have to customize for exactly what you
need but if that ami is being has API
keys static he's written to it as part
of the building process it's potentially
up there and visible if you write
sensitive data to ami then either
someone in your account may see it or if
that ami is shared publicly then others
may potentially be able to see that data
as well so yeah thank you very much I've
got a few questions or a few minutes for
questions
but sort of quickly we're hiring if
you're
interested you know someone who's
interested you like working for a very
stylish clothing manufacturer that also
makes lots of t-shirts and also on the
side dabbles and cloud communications
and connecting the world
come join us we also have a bug bounty
program please come hack us follow the
rules on bugcrowd
but we would love to have more people
taking a poke and seeing what's possible
finally if you want my contact
information go ahead and text der beek
on to this phone number and you'll get
my email address so with that thanks any
questions yeah so the question was do
you have different master accounts as
well or only sort of multiple sub
accounts underneath the one master and
for a little bit of context for people
that may not know Amazon allows you to
link multiple AWS accounts to a single
master payer account that is basically
like your friend that says oh yeah I got
the tab the account can also create
other accounts in in this case the limit
of an API key is the sort of the account
it's in if your master account has
computation running in it and is
potentially accessible by an attacker
then I would say you'd want different
master accounts if your master account
is very locked down then it would be
fine to just to use different sub
accounts because the API key in account
sub account a isn't going to work for
sub accounts B through Z anyone else yes
[Music]
yeah no I did not I was just looking
sort of the the the first chunk of the
the files I did pull some of those files
down locally just to make sure that I
wasn't missing anything - but I yeah I
was only looking at those sort of the
beginning ok ok yes interesting ok I
think part of the so part of the other
reason why I did just sort of the first
few hundred bytes was to see because I
get multiple text files back that were
originally one large file but had been
split across into multiples and so I was
looking to see sort of how many of those
early files I got but yeah doing sort of
the locality hash thing would be
interesting to see sort of the extent of
corruption and some of the files that
maybe didn't get picked up by this so
for you to your homework for next year
any other questions yeah so the way that
the snapshot copy permissions work is
you can from account a say to that you
will share a snapshot to account be in
account B then you initiate a copy of
that snapshot the one that's been shared
to you in account a and that copy is
going to reside in account B because
that's where your API keys are home so
it's a account B has the ability to copy
account a has the ability to share when
account B does that copy you get a new
version of that snapshot but it's wholly
contained in your separate account
yes so questions if you're if you're
baking an ami is it possible to I guess
zero out some of those the changes so
this was another interesting quirk of
EBS if you read from dev zero and write
and fill the whole disk with zeros and
then you delete those large zero filled
files your it like it this affects
recovery minimally it's sort of like
there's optimization happening that's
going oh you're writing a whole bunch of
zeros yeah yeah totally
totally i I I need to look more into
that because I haven't tested that
across some of the different file types
and doing like sort of multiple
generations of changes which I think
would be very interesting it's probably
better if you wanted to do that to get
like truly random gibberish and write to
the files it's just reading from dev
random wit on a source like an instant
source with very low entropy I can take
I stopped that for a couple of days
because it had barely filled up the
drive and I just didn't have time for
that so possible maybe any other
questions alright I think we're out of
time so thank you all very much
you