all right hello everyone can you hear me
all right we good for the okay thank you
so much for coming to my talk decision
analysis applications in threat analysis
frameworks I realized that is a lot of
words I really appreciate everyone
coming out today
this research actually came out of work
that I did as part of my master's
program for my thesis this past year
just a little bit about me to start the
kind of informs where I went with this
research so my bachelor's degree was
actually in psychology and political
science which then getting into
cybersecurity was kind of a big leap
from that I actually came very very
close to going for my PhD in cognitive
science when I say very very close I
mean I had filled out the applications
that was sitting there ready to hit
submit and realize that I was already
tired of the research that I had talked
about doing for five years so did not
end up doing that I went to Carnegie
Mellon University and just graduated
this year with my master's in public
policy with a concentration in
cybersecurity management so it's sort of
more of a non technical security degree
and even still having not gone for my
PhD in cognitive science I still love
that field I love the concept of
decision-making the human factors in
life and the concept that people are
generally predictable so that's kind of
where I went with this research real
quick here's just some things I'm going
to talk about I'm going to go into the
background of the work that's out there
that informed me in this research my
methodology and how I went about doing
the work the framework that I created as
an example and some of the kind of
future directions that I hope this
research can eventually take and if
there's time which they're almost
certainly will be I will take questions
so one of the things that's kind of a
hot-button issue right now is the human
factor of security the fact that
security is a little bit too much about
bits and bytes and we need to start
considering the people in the process
we're getting a
better considering the human factor but
really when we think about the human
factor of security the thing we think
about is the internet grandma the human
is the vulnerability the adversary on
the other hand is still the hacker in
the hoodie with no face and adversaries
are also human and that's a perspective
that we need to consider a little bit
more I believe as humans adversaries
have consistencies especially when
you're looking at established
adversaries like advanced persistent
threats a PT's that have a very
established MO so when you're
considering these human factors we
really want to look at decisions
hackers are making decisions when
they're attacking you and there's some
game theory applications about
cybersecurity they're very very mathy
very in the weeds and so I kind of took
some of that research and decided to
develop that is something that's a
little bit more manageable for like a
management standpoint one of the things
one of the concepts in game theory is
the prisoner's dilemma which if you're
not familiar with it it's if you have
two prisoners that are caught and
accused of a crime you put them in
separate rooms and you tell them if they
confess they'll get a lesson sentence
but if neither of them confesses that
they can't prove that they did the crime
so each prisoner is sitting in a
separate room trying to guess what the
other person is going to do and
basically what that means is you're
trying to guess what the other person
does and you often settle for a
suboptimal outcome to protect yourself
against a really bad outcome so I had to
go about choosing an approach for this
research and my dream in doing this was
to get aggregated pentest data because
pen testers kind of simulate adversaries
and for me that would have been a great
opportunity to kind of look at emulated
adversary behavior and aggregate that
data
unfortunately no one will let me have
company pen test data that wasn't going
to happen so I said okay never mind that
won't work what if I can get just one
anonymized group to sign off on letting
me use their pen test data my advisor
was very confident that we would be able
to get one group to let me do this
No did not happen did not happen so as
I'm a quarter of the way into the
semester and realizing that I don't have
a lot of time and I need to make a
decision I said okay we're gonna take a
more theoretical approach and that was
how I decided to model this using
advanced persistent threats because that
was what was available to me so to kind
of develop this framework and make a
model I chose two fairly well-known apts
apt 10 and Turla group apt 10 I chose
because it's a very well-known group it
has a very established MO it's taken
credit for a lot of big deal attacks and
also I knew because of all of the
tactics they use it was going to be
super overwhelming so I kind of took
that as a challenge for myself and then
Turla group I chose because they're very
simple they only go about attacks a
couple of different ways and I figured
that was going to be a more manageable
tree to kind of present so I wanted to
incorporate elements of existing
frameworks rather than reinventing the
wheel so I started with the cyber kill
chain from Lockheed Martin which
probably most people are familiar with
and then I also at the urging of my
advisor looked into the mitre attack
framework which ended up being kind of
the groundwork for what I did so here's
the cyber kill chain for anyone who's
not familiar it's a seven step process
it's very linear and it's pretty much
tailored solely toward advanced
persistent threats so basically what
happens with the kill chain is the
concept that an adversary goes through
each of these seven steps it's a very
linear process and the intent is that if
an attack has stopped at any step of
this chain the attack is considered
failed the minor attack framework goes
into much more specific kind of granular
detail about the various steps of the
attack process
um it was kind of my launch point
because it's still kind of linear in
nature but it goes very much into the
specific tactics that an adversary uses
so my process in developing this
framework and the process that I believe
an organization could use to apply this
is to start by identifying the top
threats so for a company to do this they
would want to look at adversaries that
are common to their industry to their
company size whether they're a smaller
large organization even their geographic
location there are various reports put
out by different organizations every
year they kind of allow for this so then
I looked into the attack methods of
those threat actors so for me that was
my two chosen apts and I got a lot of
reference from mitre and from rapid7
about these adversaries and certainly
that kind of work exists for various
groups so then I actually built the
decision for you which I will show you
in a minute
so basically starting with the primary
methods of attack from a group which I
found was often and spearfishing and
then going into how they progress
through an attack process and then kind
of going from there into what if that
doesn't work what if a step in that
process fails and my vision for this is
that an organization could synthesize
this with their own weaknesses as
identified in a risk assessment or a
vulnerability assessment all right so
I'm gonna go ahead and show you my first
tree so this is the one I made for
Trello group this one's pretty
manageable I take for granted that when
I present I can walk and touch the
screen so bear with me here
so going from left to right I hope you
can read that but basically starting
with trail is initial point of entry is
pretty much always spearfishing so we
look at what happens if they're
successful that's what's on the top and
then they move on to process discovery
malware execution etc that
a stage of successor successes is
generally what would be considered the
kill chain so basically the goal is to
foil one of those things in the middle
and that is obviously the first goal
because those are the things that we
know could be the biggest threat however
what I want to focus on is the failure
steps that are not true failures so if
there is in fact a failure there are
still alternate methods that the group
can use so we look into brute-force
attacks lateral movement things that the
attacker could use should their initial
attack fail so the things that I really
realized were the most critical places
for an organization to look at is those
nodes that go one way red and one way
green so those are really the things to
look at is oh that is my do or die point
I don't want to reach that point so how
can I roll that back a step or two and
look into how I can kind of head that
off towards the beginning or conversely
what are the red steps where the
alternate isn't a green that would be a
great place to say hey we can terminate
this attack before it ever reaches a
point where we're going to break so I'm
going to show you my second tree this
one is for apt 10 I am NOT going to walk
through this one because this one is
much more complicated this is actually
the simplified version because this is
assuming they start with spearfishing
which is largely but not entirely the
case so this can get very complicated
very fast is the point I'm trying to
make with this so it's definitely
important to kind of prioritize this and
maybe if this is a person's job is to
build something like this and then boil
it back down to those critical reds and
greens or just reds and to take that
back to management so some of my
limitations in this process and some
future directions I hope this could go
the first thing is this is obviously
very theoretical a lot of kind of game
theory research has some pretty serious
math foundations to it with probability
and such that's something I would love
to see in the future
I'm not a probability person that is not
my thing but that's something that I
would love to see kind of partnered with
someone with those math foundations in
the future also obviously I'm working
with static data about a well-known
group that's not as effective as live
organization a specific info and it
didn't allow me to do all the things
that I initially wanted when I was
hoping to get that pen test data I hope
to work with someone in the future about
that unfortunately well not
unfortunately but I am employed by a
corporation at this point so I'm limited
in my ability to work with other
organizations on this but certainly if
that was something anyone was ever
interested in I'd love to talk to him
about it so just to kind of wrap this up
hopefully this framework can be applied
by companies someday in the future to
help prioritize their mitigation so we
know where our vulnerabilities and what
the biggest risks are how can we overlay
that with the threat landscape that is
most critical to our industry to our
size our location and kind of
prioritized as mitigations it can also
allow for personalization of the
corporate policy find where you're
likely to be targeted fit your risk with
your specific threats and also kind of
calling back to this I used this for a
PT's because that was what I had access
to it's not just for that you could very
easily build a tree for the disgruntled
employee the script kitty
those would obviously be much more
complicated because you're looking at a
way bigger method of attack but that's
certainly something that could be done
and could be boil down something
manageable to hand back to a management
setting all right so at this point I'm
going to open it up to questions there's
my contact information follow me on
Twitter I talked about you know issues
in cybersecurity women in tech or fun
things like how on the plane here I
spilled coffee on my only pair of jeans
so yeah if we have any questions at this
point I love here yep
it says not but I just have to be
careful it's industry dependent but I'm
I can talk to people on a one-on-one
basis about that I appreciate that thank
you I'd love to talk to you more about
it so I was very limonade limited to
trying to pick an adversary as opposed
to trying to emulate what a company
would do so I had to kind of just guess
at how someone would work if they knew
apt 10 was their biggest threat as
opposed to taking a company for whom apt
10 is a concern and fitting their risk
profile in with the work that I did that
make sense
that would definitely be something that
would be interesting to look at I think
the same process could definitely apply
I think that's also something that maybe
has been done a little bit with fault
trees and such anyone else all right
thank you so much
[Applause]