i exploitation I'm Michael Gough I'm the
co-founder of logon D and how many
people here heard of the windows logging
cheat sheets oh yeah that's awesome
alright so this whole thing started from
that project which was based off of an
attack from the winning ta group in
gaming and it started with one one cheat
sheet there's now nine if you're unaware
we've released two new cheat sheets the
windows attack logging cheat sheet and
the windows logon D at a clogging cheat
sheet which adds system on and login D
to the attack matrix I'm a blue team
defender ninja incident responder hello
my name is Michael I'm a logger holic
okay you are awake that see the clapping
work
I am the co-creator along with Brian
Boettcher we are up at the booth we are
sponsors of Derby con so thank your
sponsors okay you guys are awake I like
this this is gonna go good I'm also the
co-host of breaking down incident
response podcast if you're not familiar
with breaking down security Brian and I
buying Boettcher and I started the
incident response to try to give you
guys a real I can take this back to work
and do kind of stuff of what we really
see and then I got this yesterday I'm
rather flattered with this I did not
attend Splunk comp this year I get asked
all the time but I got this tweet where
it turns out I don't know if you're
aware that Splunk cough has a boss of
the NOC and it turns out the winner of
the challenge named their team hacker
hurricane my Twitter handle so I guess
one of the reasons you should listen to
this talk or follow what I preach and
tell people is because even these guys
they won the boss of the sock contest so
I assume they're using the food that I I
spread with the cheat sheets and whatnot
but that's really cool I've never had a
team named after me so I'm happy about
that one so WMI sudden say whammy ok so
it's either one whimmy doesn't work when
you say wmic so women so now it's W make
or WI from my perspective but you will
hear the word whimmy that's probably
what they mean
so what do we care about this one
because no one wants to be on Brian
Krebs lists so that's one reason why you
should care about WMI now the other is
the attack might our attack framework or
a collection of they don't really want
to call it a framework anymore the
collection of tactics and techniques
from the hacker can
and they've app these out WMI is
specifically referenced in two of them
and mentioned in 27 other techniques
that means they're using WMI to query
the system or get information or do
something and that doesn't include where
WMI is using PowerShell where they've
referenced PowerShell so WMI is pretty
littered through the attack mitre
framework and so I recommend that this
is a good way to map it if you want to
see this mapping come up to the booth
and you will show it's all color-coded
and whatnot and again they use this for
a lot of purposes
WMI is built-in much like PowerShell but
Windows doesn't lock it very well like
like really badly so there's a lot of
opportunity here for pen testers and
hackers to utilize WMI which has
incredible power for the system queried
system information right you know who's
logged in who's doing this what's
running on the box etc remotely execute
payloads a really bad thing
remotely persists so it even has a
capability of persistence so we need to
understand what can be done with WMI so
we can stop the matte gray burs and the
Dave Kennedy's and the bent ends of the
world and detect them in regards to
their tests and/or the hackers bad foo
now much like we see them incur when you
sort from and Ian doing talks and WMI
and now with endgame and again it's one
reason we created this attack matrix is
because of what WMI and we added a lot
of updates to login D with the latest
version where we are probably the only
tool that queries the WMI namespace not
just the root subscription but all of
the WMI namespace thanks max graver for
that one and is blackhat 2018 talk we
went back and filled that hole so what
is w mine well it's the windows
management interface think of it as SNMP
on steroids right SNMP just sends an
informational work out to a system to
collect and tell you hey the routers
down or hey the CPUs hot but this thing
can actually interact with the system
WMI unlike SNMP you can query all kinds
of information about the system you can
even write scripts or applications that
can actually do administrative tax tasks
or actions that's stored in the WMI
database and so it's also part of the
operating system right living off the
lands a big thing here this is a
reference slide this comes from Matt and
other talks where basically all the
components you got wmic the command-line
utility there was a recent write-up
about wwic being used from a dot link
file
go out and fetch a payload from the
internet and again that would bypass
whitelisting because WIC is a trusted
Microsoft binary you got vbscript you
can use jscript WBM test is a testing
utility you can utilize that and
potentially misuse that you got C++ and
comm on demand compiling can happen
you've got win windows remote management
when are in stuff you've got the windows
remote system stuff you got the W query
language the whole query system that WI
uses you got some dll's you got comm and
again you got wrm with PowerShell
remoting in there so boom use large
PowerShell and I can start removing
around your environment W my as a
service is running which means side
loading can occur the same objects which
is the databases where all this stuff is
stored can be used for persistence and
and a way to store your food PowerShell
scripts and/or binaries and of course
there's a repo and you can use ma files
to install this so anybody concerned yet
so where does it live the first thing we
need to understand is where these pieces
and parts exist in the system one of the
big ones is wbem
I highly recommend you monitor this
directory this is where we NT I dropped
some malicious DLL 'he's taking
advantage of W my loading on a server
pretty much every five minutes
thus loading the bad dll which would
then load the good deals and the box was
infected no typical auto runs a side
load scenario you also have to look in
wbm slash repository that's where the W
my databases live and the three
utilities W my 80 a PW my ap SRV and
specifically W my PRBS e which you're
going to see used a lot in espresso
watch the execution of this one that's
really important this is where a lot of
the food that the pen testers and bad
guys will use to query your box and do
malicious stuff and of course the
databases index PTR at objects data they
are databases but there's a lot of stuff
in clear-text so you could just string
out these databases or use a tool
whatever scripts a Python whatever you
can find that will actually query
through the database and report to you
what's in there like it to a like a log
MD or anything else some utilities do
exist wmic in system 32 so you're gonna
watch the execution of that so there's
lots of components here that WMI has
tool failures well laptop and a
dishwasher isn't one of them and I got
this on Twitter I just thought this is
awesome
he's clearly a tool
and so I just had to include this
because yeah that's he is and as the
Brits and Aussie say he's clearly pissed
anyway the tool failure number one is
window sysinternals auto runs again
based on Matt graters talk at blackhat
he found that he can modify other
components within other namespaces not
just root subscription
unfortunately the auto runs module
assistant journals only looks at the
items in the root subscription so there
is a gap here I'm so be careful there
and definitely watch Matt and Lee's talk
black hat sis Mons another one similar
scenario it unfortunately only looks at
the root subscription nobody's really
done a lot of research and so that's
kind of where we all stop I even admit
we did that login D initially because
that's what everybody else does until of
course Matt graver talks and we always
have more work to do when he talks and
again sis Mon does not CW my calls at
all there's nothing in system on to do
this it doesn't see remote windows
remote management doesn't see that
doesn't see any authentication and
doesn't see PowerShell so there's some
things that system on just does not see
that you'll have to use built-in windows
logs to do and again do you have a tool
I want to see her say I want to see some
hands here do you have a tool that
searches the WMI database that searches
for W my persistence that searches for W
my execution that searches for W my
authentication are you catching my drift
I don't see a lot of hands so it's a gap
seriously as a gap this is more of a hit
and miss some eighty yards will do
pieces and parts based on what execute
sab wmic goes the internet it's probably
gonna flag and from that perspective but
there's a lot of gaps here what they do
and do not look at and so it's the
perfect opportunity to hunt in your
environment for these kinds of things
that we're going to talk about that so
how do we get pwned by WMI well of
course arnold's you know W my scares me
again I don't if you detect it well it
there's definitely a challenge here I'm
gonna talk about what those challenges
are and how you can get better at this
area and I highly recommend you do get
better in this area or Tyler's gonna
take advantage of you and as Mauer
analysis class right
it can be very low noise if it's done
well that's the other really important
point here which I'm going to point out
to you in regards to how certain things
occur and then what WMI does it's kind
of scary honestly I think the general
analysts are typical analysts will blow
this by WMI naturally occurs a lot in
systems so it it is a fairly noisy by
default and you have to look for these
odd nuances to catch what's going on
and of course pen testers read tumors
love this stuff because of the ability
to query a system you know any pen
tester whether it's callers piraeus
event an or Dave or Matt will use WMI to
find out what the heck's running in the
box what processes are running which
will tell me what EDR is in a box or
what security tools are unbox and if you
want to execute something against the
box all you need is creds figure you're
a lot better than cactus card you hear
that cactus con guys see the thing
nobody they know what do you participate
these guys are fun
I like this and WMI has tons of
capabilities and a lack of tools to hunt
for it so that's the that's the thing so
WMI pwnage again so many ways you can
install a malicious smoth so my
discussions would have occur I said so
moths exist in the WBM directory I can
just watch for them to be placed there
and executed no no they can be executed
anywhere on the box damn it Microsoft
site loaded malicious DLL when you drop
it in wpm which I saw with the winning
TI group hard thing to detect because on
a server that behavior looks totally
normal there's nothing weird
other than the DLL is in the wrong place
and Windows doesn't log PLO loads sis
Mon does so you don't have system on
everywhere which most of us probably
don't how many people here running
system on in some capacity that's
actually more than I thought
but yeah again not a lot here so system
on does give you DLL this is probably
the number one reason to use system on
its the DLL loading paja loads ID seven
and again you can remotely execute WMI
and launch malicious code an exe a
script whitelist bypass of course exe so
you can launch any other stuff that
Casey Smith talks about you can remotely
install a task and a service you
remotely launch PowerShell code yay
parish all has all the power net at its
disposal you can add coda persistence
into W my database there's lots of
options here you can kill a running
process a que your security tools
and just ask Carlos about what he does
with W my commences his attack and etc
etc etc I mean the power is almost
endless mas gonna be installed anywhere
so just saying I'm gonna go look for dot
my files for something malicious I think
Devon or Matt gave me a malicious calc
MA file that I used for testing a couple
years ago
and ya can place it anywhere and launch
mom comp space this my file and boom you
get you know basically where it executed
from and that's it W my AP ad AP AP SRV
and specifically P R vs e start and stop
on systems especially servers more so in
Windows 10 more so insistence that has
specific hardware like raid controllers
specialized NICs storage etc you'll see
those start and stop like in the gaming
environment hit tons of that it's
constantly starting stopping starting
and stopping so you really couldn't pull
out any malicious intent there at all
from just that normal behavior and then
boom once WMI starts then poof you're
infected if they side load a bad DLL and
when NT ID group use this in the gaming
as I pointed out so you can read up more
about that in reports that have been
issued about Quinn and Ti so some pwnage
tools if you want to play and do some
research win a women LM weenie implant
power sploit in PowerShell X Empire I
tested the first two again I tried to
stay away from PowerShell from doing the
testing that we were doing here and so
this is a typical sweet if you want to
do your own research
so here's W my implants menu as you can
see it's pretty extensive there's file
operations you can cat you can copy you
can delete you can download you can do a
listing and LS which is pretty funny
because it's Windows LS anyway a search
upload files so you have total ability
to do and look and read and everything
else you can do lateral movement here
with command execution you can do
disabled wws you can you can disable win
RM so you break the ability of people
who have win RM to do let's say Konza
you can break that so now I can't use
konso to go investigate as an example I
can modify the registry so I can turn on
or off the PowerShell logging registry
entries potentially until your GPO kicks
back in and over writes them because
hopefully you're doing it in GPO and
enforcing them you can do service
modifications creates deletes modify I
mean a lot of power here
process operations you can kill a
process
you can also start a process so kill
security tool a and start malicious
payload B and of course you new process
listings you don't know it kill until
you can list processes right and of
course all kinds of things about users
and basic info about the system very
very powerful capability here with this
w my implant tool so let's talk about
some more pwnage so w my attacks often
use PowerShell once in my greater said
use of PowerShell and pen testing is
dead because if you do the logging
that's in for example the windows
logging PowerShell logging cheat sheet
you're gonna do a pretty good job of
seeing what's going on with PowerShell
especially if you upload it to a sim so
from that perspective he's looking at
other ways to exploit the system whether
it's compiled C or whatnot or this
discussion that he had a power at
blackhat where he talked about using
already existing scripts and other
namespaces so common winner M are also
used a lot in the attacks in W mine so
you have to pay attention to that and
Khan doesn't have built-in logging it's
only available on some systems that you
install it on there's nothing on my
desktop for example to monitor calm
execution so how do we detect this how
do we detect this bad food has spent ten
minutes telling you about well all os's
are not created equal if you don't need
another reason to tell your organization
to upgrade to Windows 10
Devin and I were talking about this at
sans third and Orleans here a few weeks
back and we both agreed that Windows 10
has added a lot of capability in regards
to detection or at least the ability to
collect information from system to
detect and so if you're using Windows 7
or 2012 some of the items I'm going to
talk about are not going to be available
to you so upgrade upgrade upgrade and
also partial five for obvious reasons
better flogging
so there's your there's your one point
this is what I want and what everybody
wants a typical execution of malware to
look like or any kind of malicious
activity in this case this is an Emmitt
at word file that goes ahead and
launches command dot exe another command
box powershell and then launches the
binaries and then writes the final
destination SLS key this is a pretty
typical process treat it's eight deep
okay that's the point I'm trying to make
here there are a sequence of events that
occur and it's eight deep so keep in
mind this is what I wish all malicious
activity look for cuz that's real easy
to spot
so let's talk about logging first thing
you need to do to catch w my is to
enable process command line logging if
you look at the windows logging cheat
sheets and you compare them to the CIS
benchmarks or USG seabees are obvious
Ozzie's cyber standards they do not
recommend turning on process
command-line you might catch a password
in the logs yeah ok I can deal with that
I can stop that collection I can
specifically exclude that collection
there's lots of ways to mitigate that
problem so please turn this on if you
want to really catch the bad food of
course you can then see Moff installs so
now instead of just seeing Mothe comp
dot exe from a process execution I can
seamoth comp dot exe space malicious
Dartmouth execute so now I can see moths
actually being used the name of them
which then I could potentially look for
if it's not on disk that means somebody
executed them and deleted them that to
me so suspicious or the next example
you'll see in a second
and of course sis Mon has the event ID 1
which is similar scenario to process 46
88 with process command line o in
Windows 10 you do see the parent name in
Windows 7 you see the pit so there's no
Association of what that parent names
name was if you're looking at Windows
seven logs but at Windows 10 you
actually get the parent name very
similar to what's this mom gives you so
another reason to upgrade to Windows 10
process command line tells all this is
why it's important so here's an example
of a pwnage using WMI that's executing
PowerShell doing an OP so no profile so
the stuff and the chichi for older
versions of PowerShell say yeah don't
read the profile so whatever's command
line logging is being turned on there
ignore it or whatever else that's doing
non-interactive don't show it to the
user and hidden definitely don't let
anybody see the box and it's doing a
call to W my class so this would be a
great indication that yeah somebody's
doing something they're not supposed to
and you would catch this with a 40 68 46
88 process command line so there's a
great example of the power of this
particular item
be mine by itself when you execute it as
a query tool or even exploitation tool
it is not very noisy because each time
it executes it executes individually not
in the series of a parent/child scenario
that I showed you initially so for
example here's service host and this is
what it normally looks like this is
nothing here at this point is malicious
looking and here it is launching on the
left so service host is is and will be
the parent at all cases and so now that
we know that we can say okay let's focus
at W my ap SRV and see what it is it's
doing there okay
typical normal but bad foo again these
are all single liners right nesting
going on here W my activity logs there
is a log it's called a Windows it's in
microsoft windows so that subfolder of
the event logs W my activity operational
this is a log you want to pay attention
to Windows 7 or Windows 10 or later or
Server for sure the event ID you want to
focus on is 58 61 this is where anything
news created now those fails with auto
runs and system on yeah
any namespace alteration edition will be
in this log so that is something that
Windows 10 does that the other two tool
failures do not so Windows logging is
better than the other sis internal tools
that I just spoke of but there are other
event IDs so you can play with those but
this 58 61 is the one you really want to
pay attention to and this is the only
one that create again that catches
something that was added to a namespace
all of them so it addresses Matt graders
talk as well as what we're doing a login
be but not how you don't know how that
thing got created process command
execution or other things that I'm gonna
show you will collect this and again use
that command line because that is how it
got there whether it was a moth comp
whether it was a script where there was
PowerShell all that you'll definitely
need that log enable if you do have the
Windows Microsoft Windows attributed
comm collect it look at it and look to
see what comm objects are being called
you won't see to some workstations I've
yet to find one on a workstation I do
these see this on some servers it's not
in my personal domain controller so
there's something you have to add and
install that I just generally don't do
but definitely watch out for this
because comm objects are a big part of W
my so W my let's look at what it does
when it queries the system
authentication yeh Windows 10 and 2016
server to the rescue for the win
big time I was real surprised that I
stumbled across this it turns out there
is a unique authentication that occurs
when W my talks to a box in Windows 10
and 2016 server so here's an example
there are debug logs and trace logs so
if you got a tool that can do that great
you'll get the calls of actually what
WMI is executing but it's not practical
for us to go turn on debug in trace log
hey IT you want to turn on trace and
debug for me everywhere yeah I think big
answers gonna be no so it's not very
practical for us to rely on that you're
going to look at an EDR tool that might
do that or another another solution but
again all you need is creds so you need
a user account right the bad guys will
have gotten a cred through a myriad of
ways right maybe cat scan they can do
Kerberos sting write responder on then
on the wire keystroke logging or a fish
where the user just gives up the creds
somehow away from a manner the bad guys
will get the creds the pen testers will
get the grits they win almost all the
time if not all the time right so of
course it has to be a valid user ok so
once they do that unless of course it's
you know WMI the clue is what is
launched so what is WMI actually doing
you saw service host launching WMI doing
typical system management stuff but does
WMI then do something else and that's
what we're going to look at and Windows
10 definitely shows you some some cool
stuff so here's an example of the
authentication I was talking about the
unique thing here is there is actually
an impersonation and identification
I'm looking at this from a lateral
movement perspective workstation to
workstation so VJs box bad box over
vijay talking to kevin's box you will
see this show up and the local logs this
will not be a potential domain
authentication unless they crack that
and are using it but they're gonna use
probably a local credit they somehow
harvest a local administrator or your
users or admins how many people want to
raise their hands and say they're users
some of their users so admins and you
see this dual off you will not see this
in Windows 7 so suddenly there's a
oddity and authentication that occurs
when WMI is clearing the box now this is
a real surprise to me because 4624 is
just off but the fact that there's two
of these is keen and all something you
can definitely focus on
source and destination firewall logs I
love the windows firewall logs it's not
just bad IP one talked to bad IP 2 or
good IP 2 to try to compromise it it is
that this application from dot one
talked to this box on dot 2 and also the
port's that it talked on so you get some
more information that the context
inbound port 137 I know a lot of us
don't turn on the Windows Firewall in
the corporate world that's ok it will
still log you do not have to enforce to
get the logging very cool feature with
Windows in that aspect and so you can
tell what exactly is happening Service
host is making a connection to the box
ok again ask yourself why should
workstation 1 being talked to work
station 2 let's look at a typical
ransomware the podcasts were coming out
with here after we get back will be
about a breach that was shared with me
where it was a ransom or attack and they
got in through RDP on the Internet
yeah well you know that's the way that
goes and they laterally moved across the
environment 250 machines and affected it
this is where you'll see that lateral
movement not in their domain logs for
the most part other than possibly a lot
of logins but the fact that you can see
what ports and what's not going on here
is quite valuable so think about in your
lateral movement workstation one should
it be talking to workstation 2 3 4 5 6
150 the parent-child relationship is key
right server sauce where you talked
about is calling WMI so that in itself
isn't and most of us will filter this
out and I'll tell you I have because
this generally has no value ok but what
if I want to push a payload private any
key to the Box I queried it like I just
showed you
so again lateral movement so here's an
network login 5 3 2 again ntlm to play
target and a 10 target and hackers the
guy just connecting to it so in that we
know that that's happened then again net
used looks like this this is what a
typical net used looks like so you could
actually look for again workstation 1
talking to workstation - a lot / 4 4 5
is not normal behavior your users don't
map drives together not unleashed to the
IR guys are the IT people that behavior
is pretty deterministic so I've got to
connect to the share I want to push my
payload there if I'm gonna do it the
old-fashioned way which a lot of bad
guys do or I'll use W my
and of course I want to execute this
payload so here's services making the
connection again nothing too fishy here
right other than the fact that
workstation one's talking to workstation
two but lo and behold what do we see the
new advantage is what did Maurer dot exe
I renamed putty Maurer dot exe but what
is the parent and again in Windows 10
and system on you'll see this W my PR B
SC so now you have W my calling an odd
binary ding-ding-ding-ding-ding we saw
possibly and off we saw a network
connection may not have thought that was
malicious but W my calling a payload
focus on this guy right here this is
your winner winner chicken dinner
alert for sure and you can see it down
here and again there's no parent child
here see how flat it is so it's gonna be
buried amongst all those other
executions unless you specifically say I
want to look for this kind of attack you
can go hunt for this kind of attack by
looking through the logs or your sim or
whatnot and so again down here you can
see W my peer V talking to the malware
or launching them our of parent so
parent child here is really key Windows
7 gives you the pit so in Windows 7 on
the Left you're not gonna see W my prpsc
you're gonna see the pit okay or you'll
see process command line in the standard
46 88 saying hey W might launch this
thing that's all you're gonna see so
this is big to be able to see this is a
cool thing to focus on and here I show
just launching notepad so I was just
playing to see what else I could do well
there again W WMI PR vs e is launching
notepad yeah this is not good you see
this behavior you should be freaking out
this should be a very high return rate
alert for your environment because this
does not happen very often unless it's a
management utility that you vetted and
said yep that's just an HP whatever
adele whatever you know etc or storage
array whatever and Intel whatever but
when you start seeing odd binaries and
more importantly where that binary
resides the directory is definitely the
key thing here about where that thing is
I'm just launching notepad so it's in
system 32 the bad payload will probably
be in a user subdirectory like see users
app data roaming whatever wherever they
dropped it right they'll use % temp and
they'll just drop the malware there they
know where it is launched it at % temp
and bam it goes and finds it in the path
and again comms happened here so you can
see the 137 135 traffic so you know as
again yep somebody did connect to this
machine and did that thing so now I have
more data so what I showed you initially
was kind of the backup data this guy is
the big one look at look at the WMI
launching a payload and now look at the
other data to reinforce which direction
and where it came from because
unfortunately the top one doesn't tell
you where you got a little looking
Network coms or the authentication to
tell you where and who W my service
starting yeah this kind of sucks so one
of the things I noticed in the course
that win and TI attack is there were
some boxes that did not have WMI there
were dumb servers there was no W my
there's nothing special about them and
so seeing W might start with 70/40 which
is a built-in Microsoft utilities so
you'll see a 70/40 event for this it
doesn't raise any flags if all of a
sudden on workstations it starts up a
hundred 50 times yeah you might want to
pay attention to that
it'll be already running on servers but
not a lot of workstations won't have it
so of all the sudden you get the spike
and a bunch of W my service is starting
you might want to pay attention to the
1740s and unfortunately if you have
security tools the stoppage of a service
third-party service will not trigger a
stop on 70/40 event only the microsoft
supported stuff so your your EDR
solution and or some other solution like
net a queue or something else will have
to be the thing to tell you that hey
something stopped or you eat our
solution console will say hey 150 of
these as you'll hear in the podcast
that's coming out this week 150 of these
workstations EDR just stopped oh oh well
something's wrong here right so you have
to pay attention to that but again there
is some noise here and you will have to
understand its context of what's going
on so use W - start at a store service
now we're back to typical logging yeah
unfortunately Microsoft does not enable
the task scheduler log by default so you
have to go enable it as part of GPO it's
sad there are other logs in the security
log which I mention a second but really
this is the key log because they're
simple messages they're low noise and
you can literally look for creates and
starts and that's it you can filter out
and throw out all the rest
yeah they deleted it - you'll find that
in your investigation you don't really
need to log that now but the 106 and 100
and the 110 s are really what you're
after and again scheduler operational
log is not started by default in Windows
please go turn it on please please
please please please I big
creating a service is noisy when you do
create a service I don't care who made
it you get a 70 45 event this is the one
thing that windows by default does well
it is on on every machine forever for
all versions of Windows that I can
remember so you should always look at
new service creations in all
workstations and servers by far period
in a story
the POS software the hill the credit
card used this when nti seriously used
this so this was a major alert that got
us alerted to that cheat sheet that I
initially created this was the big one
this was a really a powerful one because
they installed everything as a service
and they used driver files because they
don't log anything so all of a sudden we
had 150 services starting called Splunk
driver like wait a minute I know Splunk
it doesn't that no no no and boom we
found it unfortunately when they stopped
our big fake service and found a cave
and infected it and restarted it we
never saw any of that and so when big
fix will start up it would actually read
a payload out of the registry drop it to
disk execute and then delete it we never
saw the hundred and fifty workstations
and servers stopping and starting
redoing that that would have stuck out
because Microsoft doesn't log third
party starts and stops and services but
there's help so in the more advanced
Windows cheat sheet the windows advance
login cheat sheet shout out to David
longnecker who helped out with this we
published some of these more advanced
settings one of which is the forty six
ninety eight ninety nine 4747 of twos
which are security log task scheduler
log events but you have to turn on some
specific logging additional logging
which can get quite noisy again original
windows login cheat sheets try to be as
little noise as possible to greatest
value but a lot of us want some more
advanced details and that's where we put
it in that one and again no third party
with 70 40s so what you have to do is
modify the tackles that's in the
advanced logging cheat sheet and enable
a couple other audit items and then you
will actually see the starting and
stopping of third-party services so now
you can monitor the EDR covering black
in game whatever if they don't have it
built in or the big fixes or whatever
you'll have the ability to do this if
you want to turn this on it and hunt for
this item it's pretty powerful to be
able to see that activity system on is
an option but again if you haven't
listened to Mac ravers talk blackhat
same one for he talks about how you can
modify it I know Carlos Perez's talked
about this and blogged about how
bypass system on just changed the
settings in a registry you can modify
the config and reload it so it Bork's it
and won't load lots of ways you can get
around system on so I would not
recommend being it your being a major
logging device I would say use built-in
windows logs first and supplement it
with the things that sis Mon does really
well and please watch Matt at least talk
for more on this subject but again you
want event IDs 19 20 and 21 in system on
that will tell you the new root
subscription items that were added and
so that's something to watch for if
you're using sis month how many people
here are familiar with wls the
government project Jason McCord
this is sis Mon on steroids this is an
actual syslog service developed by the
government the new people that can't use
third party stuff and this is a serious
badass logging agent it sees more stuff
than you could ever imagine anything
else seeing it doesn't look at the logs
it writes its own syslog data right
directly to your to your syslog server
Splunk whatever and it collects just an
amazing amount of data all the configs
are stored in a registry I on a personal
copy of it it's incredibly volumous so
licensing is a concern here but if you
really want to see stuff there needs to
be some work on WMI but it does see the
user calls so you can see what dummy my
object call was made and that's that's
what he's logging so some of the trace
log data here I'm so another option for
you guys we really are concerned about
the apt scenarios of that wls what can
really help so look at PowerShell you
can't have double you might have that
PowerShell in most cases and again don't
forget you have to enable the logging
you gotta turn on Windows does not turn
this logging on by default so please
follow the cheat sheets and get that
enabled and there's a lot to this so
watch my show me con gracefully recorded
by Adrian so he posting that has the
ability for all of you now to see the
PowerShell sister talk about this so I
highly recommend you go watch this video
because I share all the interesting
powershell food that you should collect
and again detect and hunt for powershell
oddball powershell there are two logs
the windows powershell old v2 logs
though still works in 3 4 & 5 & 6
and also specifically the new v4 or five
and six logs windows powershell
operational this is where the 4100
series comes into play
the powershell logs are 200 to 800 so
definitely monitor these logs for
powershell activity heading in process
command line right I mentioned this
before you'll see the 46 88 but then
when powers shall execute you're gonna
see PowerShell executing a lot of
duplicate log entries 200 400 600 500
500 ones 800 etc but these you want to
watch for these as well depending on
your version of PowerShell and of course
if there's any base64 involved or any
odd scripting or off you station the
4104 will actually decode a lot of that
for you so that's the cool part you'll
see this big base64 blob show up which
is probably always bad like 99.9% you
could then go looking at 4104 and you're
gonna see it decode it very cool so it
does that for you so very powerful
feature of PowerShell 5 6 etc here's
whom you know so whom he owes a solution
I recommend if you want a free solution
to work at home in your lab and your
testing who mios free for 2 terabytes of
data for seven days and I'm always
looking for something I can recommend to
people that's again completely cloud
they have an on-prem solution I'm not
here to promote whom you know they're
sponsored a podcast but I need something
I can do in lab and at home all my
stuff's monitored
so here's PowerShell running right so I
now know that powers will execute it I
now can create reports and alerts of the
other objects of what executed
so here's PowerShell seeing me execute W
my implant alright so here's an example
how at home I can do this research and I
can monitor all my stuff make sure you
know your kids your wife don't get
malware well they'll get malware you
just at least detect it but very
powerful in regards that aspect and then
you can take what you've learned to work
and convert that to your sim of choice
and flavor and of course this was a
base64 blob so it gets translated into
41 of cores how do I hunt for power show
well I love logon D but I'm biased I'm
co-developer of it but here's an example
of the kinds of stuff you should hunt
for in PowerShell though Splunk logging
cheat sheet has an example of this kind
of logic that's on our archaeology so
again suspicious artifact so they're
using the buzz word - Ian C 4 encoded so
I know there's something decoded and
also we're bypassed so they're trying to
bypass something I have seen legitimate
software do this but it's rare
so that in itself isn't a warning but
then the very next thing is there's a
138 ticks and 264 pluses anybody see
Daniel Bohannon's obfuscation talks yeah
well you just caught it right there this
blunt query and the cheat sheets will
have an example this as well and it's a
large block size so I know there's a
big-ass block and it's got lots of
special characters or potential off you
station so log MD we have a settings
file you can configure to make this
really stick out the last item is the
fact that power shell is phoning home to
somewhere and so it's making an HTTP web
client request these three combinations
together should say hey somebody's
infected or the box is trying to be
infected by something for somebody and
again this can be initiated by a
PowerShell wipe our shells with trusted
binary it can phone out and your white
listings gonna be fine with it
ADR should be freaking out right now too
if it doesn't don't buy the EDR or buy a
different one or something or complain
but yeah so some tools to talk about
login D we query all the namespaces so
if you want to come take a look at our
booth while we're up there and I'm here
to push that I want this to be generic
for anything you use and do this
literally is something you can do with
with a myriad of tools scripts
PowerShell Python whatever you want to
do if you do anything interesting let me
know and maybe we can help promote that
in regards to an option for people to
scan or if you hear something and again
we do also have a - W my options so we
can just scan or hunt for W my my
perspective of hunting is a little
different a lot of times you hear talks
if you listen to my sans third talk
which still publish in three six months
some random time they probably tweeted
out I say start with excluding what you
know you don't have before you make a
theory or hypothesis meaning when you
watch my sans talk there are four items
on there that I've seen a 95% of all
malware I've ever seen so if you can
hunt for that and eliminate I know I
don't have W my going on that's bad I
know I don't have large registry keys I
know I don't have any no bites I know
I'm watching my see users directory
structure for executions I'm looking at
my auto runs that I know I don't have
any funky autoruns you just eliminated
like 99% of all infections right there
because they all have to do one or more
of those pieces so go after what you
know you don't have eliminate that then
build your hypotheses to go hunting
but definitely hunt for WMI because this
stuff is stealthy it's quiet and it's
easy to in effect infect a system with
house it has lots of power just need
user right because all you need is creds
still better than cactus going and again
you can use system kernels Auto runs but
again you're gonna be limited to root
subscription so if Mac graver as a
contractor you've signed up for pen test
yeah he's gonna screw you here W my
Explorer will show you all the W my
stuff but it's way too complicated but
you can query every damn thing in the W
mine but it's huge
I'm over talking list this long
namespaces and subscriptions and whatnot
it's it's there's a lot of stuff in
there and a server it will be even more
complicated with all the hardware from
storage and whatnot wbm test is a
diagnostic tool that's built in the box
so you can actually play with some
commands and whatnot there and you got w
w make as well so again i'm gonna give
you the commands i'm you know yeah
please try logging d but here's the
commands to actually query the command
line to see what's in these various
namespaces so you just have to change
the name so the appropriate consumers
and whatnot and you can actually get a
dump of what's out there and again be
sure to watch Matt stalk here so you can
understand what he's talking about and
understand all the things you might have
to change with these queries so yes you
can make a big-ass script and you kinda
are replicating what we're doing with
log gonna be and again use allow them to
you to do this it's a lot faster and
easier dummy M I see so here's an
example of where wmic would be used and
I mentioned earlier that there was a dot
link malware that came out if you're not
blocking dot link at the email gateway
it really should and then it just uses
wmic to use one of the parameters that
go out and fetch the stuff from the
internet to bring down and infect the
machine this is just a query so it's
those things I just showed you how being
executed and again this isn't malicious
it's just an example of what presses
command-line gives you all the details
not if you don't use process
command-line just do process execution
you get double you make dot exe and
that's it right you get what's on the
right but you won't see what's on the
left what you need is what's on the Left
context is king here you really under
need to understand the context so mother
W my tools again if you want to get a
copy of the payload here's an example of
how to harvest it so you can see what's
in there if you come across a big base64
blob or a big PowerShell blob you got
some homework to do alright so you might
want to get a copy of it and decode it
and do that sort of stuff here's an
example right here
a decoded payload and W mice namespace
that I got from somebody's report so
yeah it's actually down at the bottom
crypto mining Mauer using WMI so there
you go
hiding base64 in the WMI database this
is not good so all you have to do is all
I have to do is see that go oh okay you
guys might have to do more research but
I can tell you right there oh you should
never see that in the W mind database
and again the 4104 when PowerShell
executes this will decode that for you
if indeed it it actually ran in the box
and you can I give you a link to go to
decoder if you harvest it so hunting for
W my pwnage autoruns so first thing
logging to eat free as well as pro will
let you dump all the auto runs the pro
version has a bunch of master digests
exclusions of all known good hashes and
a whitelist to get rid of all the
parameter items that you trust so you
can very easily hunt your entire
environment with just looking at the
auto runs that do all the WMI querying
again watch out for those other
namespaces so you could start with
sysinternals or whomever and then go
through it and say okay I know I don't
have any of that it can see now I only
have to worry about what mats talk
talked about and again look for anything
new anything weird any base 64 any blobs
any powershell
look at all the scripts that are already
there anybody's seen Kern VBS Tye VBS
and there W mine I put what if I added
the payload to the end of that script I
haven't changed a W my database but I
now have persistence because when that
script kicks off its added my bad food
to it so now you got a hash all the
scripts you see in your W my database
and do a compare against them to see if
they've been modified okay so that's
another tip for those existing and Devon
ker confirmed that he sees a lot of this
in the field so watch out for those
already existing entries that are
modified from the script watch for the
46 88 you can actually in sim or log
management go search for 46 88 so you
see any occurrence of the thing WMI and
my sands talk I talk about the three C's
completeness coverage and configuration
so completeness is do I have this turned
on everywhere configuration is did I
turn on all the logging Michael said
right and a coverage is is actually the
agent collecting running and doing the
right things and ending up where I want
it to end up like a sim so you have to
take that into account and because again
if you don't you missed that one box
that's infected because they turned off
your sim agent your spunk Universal
order or
when log beat or an X log then your
coverage is bad you're missing something
it's all configured correctly but it's
not sending upstream so you got to look
for that condition as a part of this and
watch for those 46 88 education
executions they are key in regards to
catching some of this activity check
your power show logs for base64 base64
is not used that often I've seen some
and some sequel server more for or doing
some settings into the registry but this
is not a normal behavior and even though
it's available it's not normal behavior
for the most part
check your auth logs for 4624 for these
odd WMI logins again exclude that you do
not have them and then you know yet well
I don't have those double logins like
you talked about in my wind 10 boxes
okay I can check that off I don't have
that right you're constantly trying to
eliminate things because you're not
really looking for it
you can say oh I've been hunting for
months well you didn't find anything no
but I know for sure I don't have this I
don't have this I don't have this I
don't have this and here's reports of
where all that got used that's a better
answer then yeah you're right I didn't
find anything and I've been doing this
for 3 months what am I paying you for
well because I don't know I know I don't
have this and right so it's a totally
different argument on how I look at it
look for those W my logins and check the
W my activity logs right not a lot of
noise here not a lot of W my being added
to a system it's definitely powerful for
you so some recommendations hunt
please hunt eliminate what you know you
don't have and that's a great place to
start and then build your hypotheses
based on that for what everybody else
talks about I would agree after that map
your capabilities to attack start doing
this you want to see an example come
upstairs will show you or cheat sheets
and how that that works the idea there
is you're not trying to see how good you
are you're trying to see if you as your
organization as you're trying to
understand how good you are at this area
or bad or non-existent you're just
trying to say can I see this item no I
need a tool for this hey boss I have to
budget an item I found a tool and I need
this much money so I can cover these
boxes that are in red on the attack
matrix I'm gonna do part of them and so
you can use that to your advantage to
help you kind of justify some budget
these are real techniques used by
hackers of all these apts we never see
apt I by the way commodity uses them too
so argument goes both place for that um
please look at the logging cheat sheets
as well there's too
Maur Archaeology calm slash cheek -
sheets recommendations process man login
46 88 if I say it enough times you guys
were member it pay attention to parent
child executions very important here WMI
PR v SEO exe the parents of another
binary that's not a true known mount
management software piece of utility
yeah you are gonna have some
investigation to do monitor these dual
authentications that I talked about
right where WMI is the launcher of that
because the process that called the
authentication is in there else ass
whatever but if you see W my doing it
you might want to investigate those as
well monitor the windows firewall
connections or whatever however you get
that firewall information on the hosts
to look for lateral movement right the
pentesters get on one box either through
a fish or whatever and then they're
gonna go east-west and that's how you're
gonna get nailed in big-time right the
win nti group got into somebody who
clicked on a word doc and then once I
get on that box I jump to another one
they got the creds and they went east
west from patient one patient zero they
never did anything other than initially
effect so you definitely have to start
looking for lateral movement because WMI
gives them the power of query and remote
executions very quietly so east-west
lateral movement is a big component here
monitor the windows remote so win RM if
you're not using it how many people here
are using winner m is it heavily used to
air enough hand so if you do use it
watch it and figure out what's normal
and Splunk you can say oh yeah that's
that's this konso stuff not that this is
yep not that and get it down to zero and
then when somebody bad like Menten gets
on your box home on a win RM or title
gets in a box i'm gonna win RM boom
you'll catch them all right that's the
idea behind filtering out the known good
and again windows remote management /
operational logs it's a long one please
upgrade to powershell v my talk from
show me con would be a good place to
start you understand why
monitor powershell executions generally
there is now more and more PowerShell if
you have bamboo puppet chef whatever a
lot of power shell being used their
management utilities are using more and
more of it Dropbox uses it to update so
you will have some normal stuff but you
can take strings out of those blocks
script blocks and say yeah not that yeah
not that yeah not that to get
the noise so that you can quiet down the
results and eliminate that you do not
have any base64 if you do then make sure
you know what the heck is executing and
why and then ask the vendor why are you
using base64 to get by av I mean there
may be a reason size of script blocks
big a script blocks not necessarily good
thing so the size of script lock is a
clue but not uncommon so this is a noisy
item but it is combined with the other
items definitely helps tell you
something's bad and obvious keishon
characters count them okay once you
start counting the normal ones you're
gonna see what I mean here the pattern
is 20 25 30 and most of my boxes on my
labs are set at 20 so I get over 20 and
occasionally I get a bunch of dollar
signs but when there's some off you
station going on it's in the hundreds
hundred thirty-five hundred thirty-eight
like I showed you in one of the examples
and again suspicious words which easily
can be broken unfortunately with
obfuscation
but after they're decoded a lot of times
these words will then show up in one of
the other event IDs right there's a 200
400 a 500 501 a 600 and 800 a 4100 of
4104 4103 don't do 4105 m41 6 please
turn that off the bad guys will rotate
your logs you'll never see anybody
there's nine of n IDs so that's a lot of
data here so one of those will probably
catch these buzz words and yes they are
case-sensitive so please upper case
lower this look for that especially in
your your Sims hunt for W my persistence
eliminate that you don't have it be
confident that you don't have it hunt
for large payloads in the registry
registry payloads get involved here if I
want to hide my binary and not take all
this file as now or but okay let's get
over the file a some our stuff but don't
take their binary that they initially
executed on the disk and then deleted so
it's not running right now put it in the
registry makes a big entry and you know
we're talking 250 300 K so if I go
looking for anything over 20 K you're
gonna see about a dozen keys and you'll
see another dozen keys under the GUID's
h key user scenario because there's two
entries right HT current user H key
users go ahead and eliminate that you
don't have any large keys this is where
Cove tur and when NT I played they
dumped all their scripts and all that
was in the registry nothing on disk so
if I did a full file hash compare I saw
nothing until I rebooted and did stuff
and saw it
up and got audit entries but I know
where they hit it neither WMI or the
registry keys because w mine can call
registry to then load said an hour
because they don't want the W my
database to be do clogged with their bad
poop because you might be looking after
the start you can also enable file and
directory auditing on WBN to look for
new entries 4663 file out of sitting
logging cheat sheet will help you out
here and in the registry you can watch
the wbm key that actually will show you
all the new namespace subscription
thingies going on that have been added
to the system and you can catch those
with a 46:57
if you turn on auditing and you select
this key and you say everyone new
created don't do reads that'll just
that's like four to one and noise so
just don't do that but that will be a
way you can also detect these additions
monitor WM i may consider a monitoring
solution so you can actually run a
partial script to look for any additions
to w my database
there's several projects out there i
thought i'd mention that because it's
kinda interesting this is a report w my
versus w mine for him i think man yet
wrote it
yes kind shin concept right use W my to
catch W mine but yeah so it's an option
to you if you want to do that if you're
in that boat that that might be valuable
to you it is an option and it can write
an event ID and then boom you can
trigger on that so a conclusion W my is
dangerous it is not very noisy as you
saw that malware eight deep is not like
the amount the WMI queries that I saw
all one-liners okay you'll occasionally
get to depending what the guy did and
after I played with his research I
realize if I do this each one at a time
I'm only gonna have one liners the guys
bad he'll nest this stuff together and
you might get some parent some
parent-child relationship maybe two or
three deeded max but for the most part
if they're good they will make them
one-liner so you won't see it and again
it uses built-in right living off the
land built in stuffed upon you and or
expand so please enable the logging I
discussed here definitely watch for this
and go hunt and eliminate you do not
have it some additional reading put some
resources in here this will be posted on
Maori archaeology under the presentation
information and if you have any
questions I'm here please I have some of
these pop-ups anybody gets quite good
question I will give you one and then
please come chat with us and ask us
questions in a booth
about some of the stuff and continue the
discussion because that's what we're
here for to share and be part of the
community so there you go
and with that I am done questions we
have time for some questions I think or
not