the guy in the back has closed the door
I think that means I'm supposed to start
cool hello everyone hello I for those of
you who read the pamphlet you know why
you're here if you just happen to wander
in this room we're talking about a
forensics thing that I just wrote so
it's my first time doing a conference so
I might as well do the who is this guy
introductions I'm Hayden I look like
that I also look like this either one
works for reference I like to computer
newer computers too I specifically like
to security the computer sort of fun I
also like to write a lot of golang it's
the last language we're ever gonna need
it's perfect this is not true but it's
fun I enjoy writing it when I'm not
computering at work I like to be outside
and away from computers because they
actually suck and Norden making society
terrible and stuff but that's fine
they're cool too so anyway I like to go
camping and outside have a cat looks
like that it's a fun fact about me it's
not an actual picture of my cat I don't
want to Doc's my cat but you get the
idea I'm employed by coinbase we do
Bitcoin things and the theory of things
and other digital currency things if you
haven't heard of us coin base is a lot
of fun blue wristband okay and today
we're talking about a forensics tool so
this is a forensics acquisition thing
for live real-time response I do
detection response at coinbase currently
ok so let's keep going so before we get
too much into what's going on here let's
talk about what this is for what you'd
actually like the situation if you want
to use a tool like dexter real-time
remote forensics acquisition is the name
of the game so for example you want to
collect a memory snapshot off of a
specific host in production that's doing
know things or maybe you want to collect
docker artifacts from all the hosts that
are running this one service maybe
there's like a malware thing going on
like there's a malware breakout and you
need to collect all of the files from
employee machines that happen to have
downloaded this file something like that
other stuff too is you can really
you know use your imagination from here
hopefully get the idea okay so before I
talk too much about the tool there's a
topic that I want to make sure we all
can visit and address and take some time
out of our day for and that's the
environment okay as I said I like to go
outside a lot so when we're talking
about the environment of coinbase we're
running ec2 and on this ec2 environment
we have a Gentoo based minimal ami it's
basically just enough to run docker so
docker big fans of docker
also we're mostly an OSX drop OS X is
pretty cool I don't actually developing
it more on that later but that Mac's are
nice also those windows somewhere I had
in the corner I don't want to talk about
it I don't want to think about it we
don't have a lot of this I actually
probably do really want to think about
that because that's kind of a job to
watch out for that but yeah so we're
running lots of different stuff and
there's lots of different environments
where we're going to want to put dexter
so that we can use this one single tool
to do collection off of our whole
environment should we need to do instant
response cool so let's talk about goals
now goals look like this I'm sorry I'm
only gonna do this bit twice I apologize
this is terrible
so what are the goals of Dexter well
first of all has to be secure I try to
make everything secure that we do at
coinbase that's pretty important for
what we do so we want Dexter to be
secure in various different scenarios
also extensible I want to make sure that
when I give a comms talk about it
everyone's whipping out their laptop and
making pull requests because they're so
excited about how easy it is to use yeah
get some ideas okay so extensibility is
important as well
okay so concepts what are the the things
that went into this this idea here
basically it has to do with tasks and
facts so task is something that you're
going to do for the forensics operation
that could be collect these files or
really anything you have this go daemon
that you can write any code in and then
tasks are just functions and go most of
them are collecting forensics artifacts
that's the purpose of the tool right and
facts are scoping mechanisms for if all
of these things about a host are true
then you should run these tasks and
together this forms what we call an
investigation so Dexter is the mechanism
by which we issue investigations into
the entire environment and then the
hosts check hey are these facts true
about myself if they are
okay I'll run the tasks and then that
generates report for the investigators
all feeling good about that so far
cool great okay so this is the general
architecture in one slide oh we've got a
host okay it's a host it could be any of
those operating systems or whatever it's
got a dexter daemon running on it sets a
process that's the go binary alright and
it's running a simple loop it's pulling
us three for these investigations it's
running the tasks that are defined in
them if it's in scope and then it's
uploading the reports which are the
outputs of these investigations
investigators are using the same exact
binary actually there's running in the
CLI mode and using that CLI they're able
to issue these signed investigations and
get encrypted reports back created cool
okay so this is all backed by s3 because
all the other pub/sub queuing services
that we had on the amazon just work
harder to use and figure out and stuff
and there's like a lot of complicated
stuff around something pops a queue and
then it doesn't go elsewhere so that's
three s3 is great we can also look back
in history really easy and see
everything that's gone through s3 so
gives us a good audibility and everyone
knows s3 so right everyone knows us they
cool okay okay so there's three problems
in making this secure I'm gonna have to
deal with one who can run the task so
who in the company is actually able to
issue these investigations obviously
everyone who has write access to s3 or
so that's part of it but we need to be
more secure than just that and then who
can read the reports that are generated
so you want to make sure that if we're
dumping this stuff onto s3 and then has
to be somehow accidentally gets opened
in a way that's outside of my control
these reports aren't just open to the
world right and then also privacy
concerns it's like let's say one of the
facts is investigate the laptop that has
the Hayden user on it you know what the
whole company or all the tech savvy
people to be looking at the
investigations going wonder what he did
right so we have to uh solve for privacy
in some way okay so obviously this is a
bad situation right if you the tasks are
really sensitive the facts is everything
and there's no signature no validation
you know a terrorist with a tor client
installed could issue an investigation
and steal all our data image courtesy
NSA thank you so obviously it's like
this is where we're gonna start this is
this bad place to start so we could do
something simple like out a signature
okay
and I know what you're thinking that
that clip
Bart looks really familiar so yes III
had that Commission that's a clipart of
myself that I paid for as you can tell
you see the resemblance it's fairly
obvious now this would be the kind of
the go to I you put a signature on
something can validate who issued it but
it Quinn base we're really concerned
about consensus as a security mechanism
it's something that's super important to
not only the infrastructure and security
team but just all the admin tools we
have across all the teams so what that
means is we don't want a single point of
failure where one internal threat or one
compromised laptop can be responsible
for a bad thing happening so we build
various consensus mechanisms into all
sorts of stuff
so what we're looking for here is some
sort of approval system now tasks can be
you know varied in the terms of
sensitivity right you can have a task
it's just report all the hosts so we
know who's actually listening out there
and Dexter or we can have task spec
collect the memory snapshot and the
memory snapshot should be from the hosts
that are signing the hot wallet keys
like that would be insanely bad right or
sanely sensitive so what we have here is
a variable sense of a consensus so tasks
are able to specify I need this many
approvers and then investigations
consensus requirement is just the
highest level across all the tasks so if
you have three tasks on there two of
them require one consensus one of them
requires three the whole in biz but
investigations gonna require free make
sounds cool okay now who can read was a
results it's important so we have
reports generated on the hosts by the
daemon he's only like the CAC deck model
the key encryption key data encryption
key no okay cool this will be fun then
so what we're gonna do here is we have
investigators are identified by public
keys right because they use their
private keys to approve the
investigations and we're going to
encrypt the reports back to them so
first thing whose our recipients that's
a part of an investigation we need to
know who's actually authorized to read
them in this example here Alice and Bob
because that's every example okay so
let's generate a encrypted report back
to Alice so first we generate a random
data encryption key so this is just a
random AES key for Alice's report and we
encrypt the report and we get Alice's
encrypted report okay but Alice needs to
be able to read the encrypted report
course so we take Alice's public key and
we encrypt the data encryption key to
give us the key encryption key that's
the CAC part of the CAC Dec and then we
get Alice's decryption payload so
together these make up Alice's report
and we do this because we can't take an
arbitrarily large report and encrypt it
to an RSA public key without a lot of
issues so this is the mechanism by which
now we're going to get these reports
back to the investigators an end-to-end
encrypted way this happens on the daemon
to do the collection right and then it's
not able to be read until we get to the
host where that's Alice's and we can do
this for each investigator who's who's
allowed to read it right so different
data encryption key for Bob so there's
some separation there cool so okay let's
talk about privacy we had this problem
right where if we were doing user
exists' username and some tech savvy
people realize they can get the keys for
Amazon out of decks or on their laptop
and they can start looking at all the
reports that are going around org-wide
they can start looking at usernames so
what are we gonna do about that that's
not good we're going to hash that where
the salt is the investigation ID so it's
a randomly generated for each
investigation and then what we can do
something pretty simple like for each
user on my machine
I'll hash the user and if it equals the
hash that's being requested that's great
so in order to get around this now you'd
have to brute force after the
investigation has published a list for
each user and that might actually not be
too hard which is an issue so there's
some concerns around this I think this
is the appropriate topical meme for this
topic I'm 25 now so I feel like I'm kind
of past my prime especially when it
comes to meme development but I tried so
this this is the idea right that's the
good one
okay this is not perfect because let's
say the set that you're looking for is
say twenty people you can brute-force
that relatively fast and if if you use a
hash algorithm that's slow enough that
you can't spend it's gonna be pretty
hard for the hosts to actually do the
verification all right so this is an
interesting problem here oh I'm trying
to do is raise the bar right make it a
little bit harder but there's definitely
room for improvement on this Laurie's an
argon too so we can adjust the
requirements for the hash difficulty
with the different variables and stuff
okay so let's go through an
investigation exam
what we're looking at here I generated
with Dexter it's pretty simple it's put
up to s3 is a JSON structure so we get
our random generated ID we get a list of
tasks so these are they're not sending
arbitrary tasks right you can't just
send code and have the host run it
because that would be remote code
execution as a service so instead we
give task names and those are built into
the binary right now these all have
arguments as well which in this case is
planar
the scope that contains our facts so the
platform is is a fact the argument is
Linux and the hosts are gonna check is
my platform Linux for the user exists
one that's a private one so we got the
hash like I was just talking about cool
Dexter also has the ability to kill any
docker containers that aren't Dexter and
shut down the hosts after it's done so
we have two boolean values in there for
that the issuer is the investigator of
course you did the issuing comes with a
signature I took out the enormous base64
data cuz you don't need to see that
approvers then will be more sets of
these keys these signatures right for
the other investigators currently known
as a prove this and then the recipients
are the investigators who are authorized
to then you know get the encrypted
report so pretty straightforward pretty
minimal in terms of what's in here try
to make it not super complicated that's
a good idea
when other investigators approve this
but they're not what they're gonna do is
not going to change this file on s3
they're actually going to upload a new
file that's the same exact thing except
it also tax on their approver signature
for the rest of the data
and in this way we can see a history of
okay who actually issued it you know
obviously it's their sign it in their
name but we can see when they posted it
you know what that file was and then
when other investigators came and
approved it so cool that's what that
looks like okay so what can you do with
Dexter right now well there's two main
things I wrote and that's it so there's
a lot of work to do but currently
there's one task to dump the entire OS
query database on a local system and
include that as JSON so that's pretty
nifty I'm not trying to reinvent the
wheel here and make a bunch of forensic
stuff that's new or like you know that's
like not new it's just a real
implementation at some other tool so as
much as I can it's good too I think it's
good to rely on other things so like it
takes some it's like an OSX collector
script out there that's pretty good that
should just get wrapped into dextra
trying to reinvent that and go even
though I'd really like bright and go
it's you know good to use other tools
and so for docker this was a little
custom but I wrote a task that will give
you a different look at all the changes
to the docker file system between when
the container was started from the image
so every added file you'll get ok here's
the other file remove files it'll
actually start up the old image extract
the original file include that in the
report and for files have changed you
get both and a diff so that's that's
pretty cool okay I think we're on to Oh
no examples not demos ok examples so
this effect this is the platform is fact
it's like what we saw in that example
right platform is Linux ok so this is
this is the entirety of the code you
need to add that to Dexter - tests which
are a good idea so you have this fact
struct right you got the name good bye
you've got the description minimum
required arguments right so if you know
you don't have enough arguments the
command-line will fail and then the
actual function function here just
compares the runtime go OS value to the
argument that was provided and if any of
the arguments that were provided are you
know correct if any of the platforms are
the platform you're running on then true
so extensible right we want to make it
so you can just add one file to the repo
another file for the test please and
then yeah there you go
that's that's a new fact ready to be
used by dexstar rebuild it and it'll
show up in all the right menus ok tasks
same structure same general idea or I
accept the collect OS query thing is
really long so I don't have enough
screen to do all that but you can see
it's just a function that you plug in to
the struct that you pass during init and
yeah one file pretty good ok so now yeah
now it's demo time
cool so we're gonna go over in this
direction uh-huh
this is not when this is this not
Windows XP this is Linux but you know I
like this is the pinnacle of user
experience and so I want to be able to
develop in in an environment that feels
comfortable and it feels empowering for
my workflows that I really feel like I
know my way around so
all right we're in Windows XP cool just
kidding like whatever you in right now I
think uh yes this is sabay own just like
a binary district junto to make my life
hard and it's pretty cool
alright so let's let's make this
fullscreen so that we don't have to look
at XP anymore for the people who that
bothers alright so I'm gonna do down
here so I'm gonna start the Dexter Damon
Dexter
Damon boom okay cool that started in up
here I I can do various things so I got
some Auto completion stuff I can run I
can interact with investigations I can
interact with investigators reports
start the daemon already did that docks
generates the docks bash will generate
bash completion so let's uh let's do it
let's do a new investigation huh Dexter
investigation create cool ASCII art
everyone loves ASCII art right makes us
feel like we're using Metasploit or
something ok so first thing we got to do
is we got to select a task so we got
some autocomplete here I can drop down
little menu scroll through tasks let's
add the OS query collect one that's a
good one let's add the docker file
system diff cool hey it handles air is
really well let's add docker file system
diff again oh we can't do that because
we already added it cool ok let's tell
les yeah that's nice looks like our M
docker file system diff cool we removed
it let's add docker file system dip
again whoo
alright eros very good so that's it so
we got two tasks now that feels that
feels good because that's all the tasks
I have but if we want to do help we
could look at other things right we
could look at like hey how do I do this
like someone's playing cool beats over
there no all right let's keep going
so we're done with tasks so we just hand
enter a new line now we're onto facts
alright so same kind of thing right I
can scroll through facts about a lot
more of those if it's running a docker
image or like a substring of the docker
image is running so you like let's say
you're in an environment where I don't
know all your engine
hearing repositories start with
engineering and you want to do that
right that type of stuff you can do the
platform is one they talked about let's
do that platform is oh but I need
arguments right because I have minimum
arguments cool yeah I tried to make it
easy to use okay so the platform is
Linux I've got that one and let's do my
laptop so user exists' hey cool
that's redacted now we're storing the
hash so it knows okay I can't you know I
can't display that which it's kind of a
problem because I'm the one who's making
it but more on that later okay cool so
these are these are pretty good there's
other things we could add what else do I
have in here that's some stuff for
doctorate project name so Dexter will
let you define a project name for your
daemon and that's either a file it opens
up or an environment variable that it
considers a project name for your host
so that you could scope things in your
production environment like we do at
coinbase okay yeah if it's running
docker image is platform as we've seen
all that before cool okay so I think
we're all done cool
terminate the containers nope terminate
the host nope and then Hickam so I want
to do this thing where right where looks
like a command line loop or you can drop
in all these things that drop out of
them and preview your stuff but derbycon
came up really fast when you're trying
to open-source something like wow you
really don't realize how much time you
don't have until you're three weeks away
from the conference so whoops this is
the command line we got today all right
so what else we got here which
investigators can read it Allison Bob
all right I could do things like disable
access for Alice or we enable it but I
only have two and the other person's
gonna have to approve it so we're gonna
do both all right so we're done with
that now we have a local encrypted
private key RSA we're gonna have to
decrypt that we're gonna like do a Pam
decryption on that to sign it so that's
how we use the password to authorize
signing the investigation and it's
uploaded cool so I should be able to do
almost type darker because I do that all
the time
Dexter investigation list okay cool so
we can see it now in this pretty little
table we have an investigation ID we've
got the issuer Bob the task we're going
to run the scope and then the consensus
requirements so each of
requires one approval so our consensus
level is one no one's approved it yet so
we don't have any one of them reviewed
by field Neto alright so now what I'm
gonna do is I'm going to switch over to
the other user let's see I'm Bob right
now so now I'm Alice all I did there was
I just renamed the home slash dot Dexter
and then put the other one in because
your entire identity is just what's in
your dot Dexter home folder so nothing
fancy really going on there ok so now
now I am Alice and I want to improve
this investigation so I'm going to do
Dexter
investigation approve and ok so you know
when you use git and you don't want to
type out the whole thing so you type out
the first part of the thing and then get
figures it out because it's like enough
to make it not ambiguous I've got the
same thing here so I can just do F and
it'll know ok well there's only one
investigation and it starts with F so
there it is ok get a little preview here
it's just a different view tables are
fun
this one goes this way not this way so I
can type my password as Alice spoiler
alert the same password if it's password
and now I have a approved investigation
so let's check that out Dexter the
investigation list cool consensus one of
one approved by Alice ok and now the
daemon you see there's a log line there
very cool it picked up the investigation
it is now reaches consensus requirements
it does the tasks it ran them hold on
we've got the reports encrypted and
uploaded whoo all right so now let's
let's take a look at these reports so
Dexter report list hi ok so now we see
that there is a one host reported
recipients Alice and Bob we got the
scopes tasks all the same information
cool so what we can do now is download
it from s3 and decrypt it by decrypting
our local RSA key and then decrypting
the data encryption key then decrypting
the data lots of stuff going on there
all right Dexter report retrieve F
password cool okay so that was fast
because this is actually a local demo
and I'm not going to s3 I'm going to my
temp directory and no hard-coded that in
for this okay cool
so we've downloaded it we've decrypted
it and what we've done is we've created
a new directory called Dexter report -
the ID and inside there we have every
host that's reported so if your scope
contains like 20 hosts we're all gonna
upload separately but when you download
the report you're gonna get it as one
report that has all the hosts that were
uploaded at that time so that's nice
okay so bayonne dot local is my host
name apparently so let's go there oh I
need to I need to enter that directory
some of the audience that isn't always
doing okay let's go into sip and on
local cool and what I see is each task
has its own directory automatically
great yeah cool it's very easy to write
these tasks and have it work this way
you don't have to do anything fancy you
have this artifact writer thing where
you can give it bytes of data and
readers and and file names and stuff and
Dexter will figure out where to put it
in the file system so that's it's just
super easy for you guys - all right
features don't forget it okay let's
check out the docker file system diff
what we have in there we've got a
container okay cool what's in there we
have added so what's going on here is in
the in the docker report basically to
give it like a CH root so in adit that's
like the root directory of all the files
that were at it and there's gonna if I
modified anything there'd be a modified
directory and that would be like a
tribute into you know all the files are
modified and then removed same thing
manifest gives us a ton of information
about the container spoiler alert I just
started a new bunch of container and
then got a shell on it and then made
stuff so oh okay well that's empty at
the moment cool oops so let's go into
that a bit dark possum at it what do I
have dot root right so slash root on the
actual container dot SSH cool that's a
directory what I have here
authorized keys so someone added a
backdoor key sneaky
yeah okay so we found that looks good
where am i oh boy okay cool so let's
check out the OS query thing I'm there
right now I had to change my ps1
variable for the demo because it's
ridiculously long and it's got like you
know the name that my name the host name
my whole directory and then like a bunch
of get information and so when I try to
zoom up it's like three lines and
strapping it's just a whole mess so I
can't tell what directory I'm in I'm
sorry okay so let's go into OS query
collect and what do we have here is all
the tables that OS query happen to be
running on this host we just kind of
like a little a select statement for all
the tables that were available and for
each of those took the results put it in
a JSON thing so I don't know let's look
at what sounds interesting
listen let's see what magic okay sure I
don't
a lot of these are empty because there's
actually nothing in them
yeah sorry but like I think that's the
house has stuff for example yeah okay
cool JSON mean everyone likes JSON I
like Jace phone what else we got
I don't know okay that's that's cool
yeah okay so the route and wheel groups
can see dough huh Portage juice okay
cool
look at that this thing's in there okay
that's neat
yep okay so let's let's get out of here
let's get out of here okay cool
there's some other functionality in here
right so like now if I do
Dexter investigation list I still see
that investigation eventually you're
gonna have a lot of investigations in s3
so you can do like Anna Dexter
investigation prune there it goes it's
gone okay you know Dexter report prune
same thing
work in progress on making these
features a little better for various
reasons okay so that was demo time
cool it actually works I'm pretty happy
about the manifest thank you oh thank
you okay
we'll keep going cool so the future what
is going on here one we have to make
everything better
this is merely the humble beginnings of
hopefully an open-source project that
actually is good someday but things are
a little rough and just yeah it very
recently open sourced so first of all
actually write tests that's really good
advice there's one package in here
that's tested again Derby con came up
really fast so there's a couple things
in here that should be tested that
aren't I'm looking forward to everyone's
pull requests where they you know test
my code I'm just kidding I'll do that
but yeah desperately needs some cleanup
and tests and stuff investigators are
currently embedded in the binary I do
this thing where I use this tool that
takes the investigators directory and
then it creates this virtual in memory
filesystem by embedding everything so
you can interact with it like it is a
file system mostly just cuz I thought
that was pretty cool but also makes the
binaries pretty portable once you build
them because everything that's baked in
they don't you know you can make like a
docker image for Dexter that doesn't
have any file system is just like from
scratch that's pretty neat it's actually
not really a great idea in hindsight
because it makes it really annoying to
revoke things so if you need to revoke
an investigator who is compromised you
actually issue an investigation that all
the Dexter Damon's run that wipes that
key from the Damon's internal memory
file system so that it can't encrypt
reports back to it just like way worse
than just deleting a file from s3 so yep
that's that's happening versioning that
config files I made my config file a
JSON file because I would be like why
would I ever need to change the config
structure ever again in the future it's
done it's a terrible idea I should
probably go something flexible like
Hamill in version it's a future upgrades
of Dexter can use old config files
understand them you know report things
that are missing stuff like that like a
real open source project argument
validator this is a cool idea
so the idea here is that I got a minimum
number of arguments so the command-line
doesn't let you make nonsense however
there are times when the arguments
should be even more specific than that
and in those situations it makes sense
to just write a function that validates
are these valid arguments then you can
run that function on the Damon's as much
as you can on the command line interface
so that investigators don't make
nonsense investigations so yeah there's
the whole private arc thing right we did
this thing with the hashing for the
private arguments which is kind of okay
except if Alice makes an investigation
that has like userexists
Hayden and then Bob tries to look at
that Bob's not going to be able to you
know brute force it in theory and figure
out which who's actually under
investigation so Bob's just gonna have
to trust that Alice says no I'm totally
looking at that person's computer or not
that person's computer right so that's
not great for the actual
consensus-driven trust model so what
probably the the obvious solution here
is you just take the arguments and you
encrypt them back to each investigator
so they can when they pull down the
investigation decrypt the args and
actually see what the scope truly is and
then yeah you should also have the hash
right put the Damon's because the
Damon's aren't going to have keys like
that but that is the as the obvious next
step they're not JSON structure is
getting more complicated and I like it
okay
knowing when all the hosts have reported
is important so we're getting to like
the bottom of the slide there's a lot of
things apparently that I want to change
so we're using the whole slide knowing
when hosts have reported is important
right so if there's say 100 hosts in
your environment that are going to be
the scope of your investigation you're
just gonna kind of have to know via
another channel that there are a hundred
hosts that are gonna be in the scope of
your investigation because there's no
mechanism for dexter to you know say how
completes the reporting is so some some
mechanism for that would be cool but i'm
not i don't have a ton of good ideas
here so come tell me about your ideas
afterwards
lastly archiving not pruning so pruning
is the mechanism by which you can just
delete the old investigations and
reports but I think for audit ability
and legal compliance type of things it
would be good to have a archiving bucket
so you can clean up the CLI output when
we're looking at stuff but cleaning that
up doesn't involve destroying the
information maybe these files should be
moved to another buckets towards a
history of everything Dexter's ever
in the organization forever but you know
keeps the command line clear so that's
something that I want to set up but
haven't had time for yep cool memory
snapshotting is a great thing to do I
that I haven't done and this is gonna be
a little difficult because when your
snapshot in all memory I have to encrypt
the report still writing I'm using AES
GCM right now which doesn't like to do
streaming stuff and it's hard and
everything sucks so I'm gonna have to
probably switch modes in H macit and
stuff and so there's some work to be
done architectural e on to Dexter before
I'm doing memory snapshotting I also be
cool to have some kernel modules that I
can load for each platform when it's
asked to do a memory snapshots that's
not just there all the time and have
Dexter responsible for that that would
be neat okay in last automation so
automation this like there's a vision
here okay there's a vision of the future
and that vision involves detection
tooling that is able to figure out oh
hey look that's the name of execution
we've never seen before from that
service or Oh some you know mechanism
detecting the applications behavior is
throw in an alert that's weird maybe
there's like a zero-day ruby available
and being used or something or you know
like hi signal things like oh hey we got
a phishing email we also got you know a
new file load out of a weird directory
within five minutes from this host so
you know there's some detection platform
that's watching the whole organization
and when that has an uh-oh moment it
should be kicking off automatic Dexter
investigations so that as a instant
response person I get an alert hey this
this happened and it's not good but also
here is a ec2 instance that in like 30
seconds is gonna have all the data from
all the relevant hosts is preloaded with
all the tools you need to get started to
highlight what's interesting stuff like
that so I think that there's a cool
future here in you know just reducing
the amount of things that I have to do
for my job and Incident Response and
being able to have a response
environment that's got all my evidence
it's got all my tools ready to go and I
think this is kind of the underlying
machinery that's going to help us get
there eventually so that's cool
all right so that's Dexter it's open
source already I didn't want to be that
guy who was gonna open source it and did
the talk but like said I'll publish it
in a couple days
it's ready oh phone's cool hi everyone
hi yeah so it's up right now it's been
up for a couple days check it out
it works mostly Hayden at coinbase comm
that's my email at coinbase calm blue
wisp and if you want to talk let's chat
HK Parker comm is my personal website
that's hosted out of my living room
there's this whole ridiculous set up or
my router VPNs to a VPS for a static IP
and they're like reverse traffic back in
my living room so I'm kind of concerned
if everyone goes on that right now it's
gonna go down I'm actually kind of
curious so like just let's try that it
should stay up like it there's no reason
why it should go down but a probably it
probably will so that's cool we have a
surprising amount of time for questions
and stuff so we can do that in here if
you want because I have the room that's
cool okay let's go front to back up here
what's up yes great question
no one no one yeah that that's a good
thought right so that what can we do
about that we could have you know people
at the in a company we trust more to be
around long term we could have say I
don't know like someone who's who would
never normally read it like a VP of
Engineering or something but yeah yeah a
sharted private key for example that's
stored in in cold storage would be yeah
we have the mechanism to do that of
course so that'd be good that's a great
thought so no no that's that's awesome
that's actually I mean I'm here to get
feedback from the community and get cool
ideas it's like a break glass shorted
keys perfect yeah
two investigations for now you could
make it more complicated right so you
could have some sort of and/or thing and
then eventually you just reinvent
JavaScript so we can go down that route
that'd be cool I don't have enough
experience doing that stuff so let's
bring my JavaScript yeah let me go wrong
right yeah it'll be the backbone of the
web for like 20 years
yeah so currently separate
investigations I consider that fine for
now but there isn't one right now but
good idea what how do you mean Oh
you--oh was it hard to see oh whoops
okay I probably should have made
everything bold I thought it was doing a
good job is assuming it who could see
what was going on there most of the room
okay yeah what oh the the colors yeah
well I gotta have like a hacker kind of
feel you know yeah so depending on where
you live I might be able to recommend an
optometrist but we'll chat all right
it's up thank you does that look like an
RFC looked around a little bit
specifically I was looking for does
anything already do that and didn't
encryption and consensus stuff and I
didn't see anything that had those two
requirements and since those are pretty
heavy requirements in our team we rolled
our own but I'm not like I said I'm not
trying to reinvent the wheel I would
love to just take all the good forensics
tools that are you're supposed to run on
the hosts and just wrap them up with
this mechanism for getting results this
is mostly just the acquisition part of
the arrangement and then where we need
to write our own custom tooling because
you know I'll go to some cool talk
that's like this is the newest cool
forensics thing for OSX that no one's
done yet yeah I'll write a custom you
know task for that but as much as we can
yeah I'd love to use whatever is out
there
oh yeah I see what you're saying because
they don't have date stamps yeah that so
that that's one of the minor features I
wanted to put on the things I need to
make it better thing that didn't make it
other ones would include like putting
the consensus requirements directly in
this truck so you don't have to edit the
consensus config file like there's a
bunch of small things like that yeah you
definitely want a date stamp in that
JSON file for sure right and you need to
be able to see that and then you can do
things like you know Dexter Dexter to
generate audit report history whatever
and it'll give you like a tree for each
investigation what time what everything
happened a like this yeah definitely
PRS I'm accepting PRS otherwise I'll get
to that someday yeah that's a good tool
yeah yeah so I really want to build
Dexter report analyze which would be the
command that knows for each task what's
the function that extracts the
interesting information and parses it
and stuff like that I'd imagine for a
lot of tools that is already gonna be
stuff to analyze it but like I said in
the automation section of the idea here
I want to as quickly as I can get the
interesting information out so totally
in scope of the like future vision of
this project is that once these reports
are pulled down you can get information
about okay what's interesting in here
you know how does this differ from what
we'd expect you know parse it and give
me summaries you know give me brief
summaries of the various parts of the
system and you know from there I can
decide what's interesting stuff like
that for sure yeah sure
which Keys the reports I could but I
want this to run everywhere right so I
want that use the same thing on OS X and
on Windows and other things so I so like
our OS X fleet would have access to kms
to excuse if it's easier or more secure
we worth doin haven't looked into it to
be honest but just tell me why it's
better in more detail
not for this yes okay
yeah I briefly looked into it a little
bit but I don't like so it does have
like a encrypted reporting option for
like individual people and stuff like
that and crypto consensus all that what
nice okay sweet
well that sounds cool I'll look into
that
thank you yeah yeah good question so for
the ec2 environment we basically deploy
compose configs with our system we so we
I think there's been other public talks
about how this works but we spin up new
aSG's and then deploy these configs for
for docker across them so there's a
little helper in there by which I can
say every part of all these deploys
should also have this container on it
and then Dexter's containerized and then
in order to get access to stuff I need
on the host I've all you min the docker
socket so I could do docker stuff I
volume in an OS query socket things like
that so that's currently the idea now
eventually I could bake it into the ami
once it's a little more stable that
would be cool for the OSX fleet so
we're not quite there yet so I don't
really have a good answer but there's
options around like Central Management
so performance no I should probably
benchmark it go hazard go great language
has good stuff for benchmarking so that
want to be too hard to do but I have not
done it
yeah sorry which closers you see others
oh no we don't use ECS I don't know a
ton about what sort of like interface
you have to it so I just completely not
explored that at all yeah yeah that's a
good question oh it for weed so we use
ec2 is an isolation mechanism as opposed
to any sort of managed container
solution because they don't trust
containers is a security isolation
mechanism just to be super paranoid so
you'd have to get a container breakout
and you'd also have to get Amazon
hypervisor breakout which is a pretty
small group of thread actors so for that
reason we're just not looking at those
things at the moment but you know maybe
someday containers would be really
secure yes so the way it's configured
you can either put it in the config file
that's embedded into dexter or it can be
overridden with an environment variable
so it's it's global yeah
and currently we're only doing this in
places where we have the ability to
distribute Amazon keys easily and you
know ephemerally and stuff like that
when this goes out on the OSX fleet
we're gonna have to talk about what that
looks like if there's some sort of like
a network Akal that you can do that I'm
imagining probably different s3 buckets
for different scopes of the network just
comin kind of coming up with that right
now I don't know we'll see
yeah
definitely that was suggested to me
before like just just before Darby
cloned I thought that's a great idea
but it's not written but yeah I think a
good task would be just report your
hostname and then that way you could say
you know noscope report your hostname
and i can get an idea manually there but
a heartbeat would also make sense too
that would also do a good job of letting
me know what's in scope how many things
I can expect a little heavy on the
traffic side right depending on how
that's set up so not sure what that
would look like also shout out and thank
you to the entire rest of the clan base
security team for all of the great ideas
you can give me along the way of
development
alright other questions No
cool well thank you everyone for being
here and letting me talk about this
thing and for the