well good afternoon my name is Chris and
I'm happy to talk to you about burping
better they're they're really kind of
two concurrent themes in this talk one
is about really about finding struts and
kind of the best way to do that in an
environment whether it's in your own
environment or in a client's environment
in a pen test but then there's also kind
of a bit of a John strand theme here of
building things and giving them away so
you pay attention I'm sure you'll pick
that up so just a bit about myself so
you have some idea who I am the last
name is pronounced LG like a letter L
and the letter G I am a nerd at counter
hack challenges proud to be there were
those guys I do want to mention Sage
data security too and my previous
employer because I did most this work on
their time I do appreciate that from
them I got some certs I'm also in the
Army National Guard
if you speak army at all there's some
letters and I feel really so important
all right so so this this all kind of
came from what I like to call false
negative anxiety now a penetration test
is not about finding every single thing
in a client's environment if you're
hiring a pen tester and they tell you
that they're going to find every single
thing they're lying to you run away at
the same time if there's something
really obvious that you miss you're kind
of letting your client down so for
example had I been the pen tester and I
don't know they had a pen test but had I
been a pen tester a month before Equifax
got hacked I would feel really bad
having not found the RCD in their
website and and not to pick on Equifax
but it's it's a case that I think
everybody's familiar with when it comes
to us to stress vulnerabilities by the
way as this goes on this is this is a
moderately technical talk and and really
more looking at the strut side of things
in the burp extension building side of
things there was a talk last year in
stables by Samson was the last name he
talked specifically about how to belt
extensions so if you're looking for that
piece of it that could be the piece
you're missing I encourage you to go
back and look at that
so things that things that I don't want
to miss is a pen tester I don't want to
miss Cisco Cisco right if that's there
and someone still got that
I'm gonna really feel like a jerk having
missed that if somebody's got a password
that's really terrible but not in my
dictionary I mean that's that's kind of
hard to deal with but I might miss that
I don't have an easy way to find all
those terrible passwords a really dumb
URL with things hidden in it again maybe
it's in my my fuzzing dictionary maybe I
found it with der Buster and and then
I'm gonna feel like a jerk if I didn't
if it's something obvious like this that
I just wasn't able to find logic bugs
like like shopping cart quantities
that's that's really what humans are for
when it comes to web app pentesting
right tools like Nets Parker can find a
lot of the automated finds but it's
really the purpose of having humans is
to is to think about things there and be
creative and and think that oh that txt
file that's being served up that's
actually a log file of admin log ons I
saw that recently scanners will
typically pick up on that the last two
are also kind of in that same category
when you've got an XML external entity
in a in a website where you're able to
basically inject in a call out to
another site to pull in additional
entities that's that's not hard to check
for but it's something that we don't
always think to do in every case maybe
if there's that if there's a piece of a
web app that involves submitting XML you
might you might think of that or maybe
it involves submitting JSON you think
well maybe they can Swiss switch it to
XML and try it I want to do that I want
to do that automatically every time same
thing for struts there are ways to find
struts vulnerabilities and oh my aching
struts this is just a partial list these
by the way on the left-hand side those
are the CBE numbers along with the
Apache internal s2 struts two numbers
with them those are all RCE and as you
can tell by the years they come out fast
and furious and they're they just they
seem to keep coming as far as finding
them there there are plenty of methods
of discovering them I didn't invent any
of these Python scripts in the red box
there because we're gonna come back to
Python scripts is a good way to exploit
things in fact if you look and I
actually built this before I started
built this piece of it before I started
working for the fur counter hack if you
like the 2017 holiday hack challenge you
actually needed to use a stressful nura
bility to get into a web server to pivot
into the internal environment
and there was actually a coincidentally
there was a sans pentest blog post about
doing that very thing right before the
holiday hat came out and by the way if
you do try this plug in and we'll get
there and you want to scan dev North
North Pole Christmas town calm it will
pop with the vulnerability for struts
this second newest one 1905 another way
sometimes you can find struts with the
ball and scanners but that's kind of
hard because they could be URL specific
so unless you're feeding your nessus
Qualis next close with a full list of
urls you're probably going to miss that
that one page that has the vulnerability
in it NSE scripts similar there are some
powerful NSE scripts and I love and map
scripts but they've got to have that URL
s because they're not typically going to
do this to the kind of spidering you
need to find these things active scan
plus plus has anybody used active scan
plus plus awesome so if you're using
Bert Pro already it's a free extension
you can get we're gonna talk a lot about
it here in a bit and it looks for cool
things including the epiphytes version
of struts the 5638 so here's here is a
Python script this is something actually
coded by Chris Davis Chris Davis thank
you very much Chris Davis code this cool
thing it's up on github and then in
longshore what it does in the top box
you I set up my home script for the
holiday hack last year where I could
just get a shell on a box by feeding a
command in this is what I want the box
to do please execute this command and
then the script very helpfully hands
this big OGN el blob of java code that
you don't really need to understand
other than that it's the the stress
engine is interpreting this and then
taking the command which was very
cleverly disguised with base64 and some
tea also you can get special characters
through so long and short paths on
script awesome I aim it at a specific
website give it a specific command it
executes the command for me that's
awesome
now if I have a whole list of URLs and I
want to script something to use this
script a bunch of times for each of
those URLs you could in theory use that
to scan for this specific struts
vulnerability but I'm lazy and I'm
forgetful and I want it to happen
automatically for me every time I in
your shell oh my god I have configure
all right so active scan plus plus built
by one of the one of the smartest Weber
testers I've ever heard of James kettle
if you've ever heard of L vinyl wax if
you want to feel really dumb go look up
a talk like cracking the lens the man is
absolutely brilliant when it comes to
web at pen testing and he wrote this
cool extension and gave it away thank
you James kettle where it'll look for a
bunch of funky side things including
5638 that is the that again the Equifax
struts bug it does require Bert Pro I'm
sorry it's 3:50 a year also joy on is it
is a Java Python interpreter that lets
you use Python code in in verb and also
Bert collaborator welcome back to
burping a letter collaborator in just a
second so here's an example of what
happens so you're you're on a page
you're you you've spidered all your urls
you're been told it to active scan
whatever pages you've found so active
scan plus plus would already go ahead
and give some funky commands so here in
red box you see a content type and then
like weird code stuff as web app pen
testers typically we think of injecting
funky values in in what kind of areas of
a request form feels absolutely where
else and cookie yeah absolutely values
may be in the URL may be in the host
header field right with with some of
these Java struts you kind of things
it'll be in like content type or it'll
be in the name of the cookie or maybe
even in the name of a header it'll show
up in weird places where people haven't
thought to sanitize input so kind of
cool so what this one does is it throws
in a please add a header called X AK and
here's some math and then when it comes
back from the server with a response
with a new header called X AK and the
math completed for you you know that
it's vulnerable to 56:38 so cool that's
a cool easy check all right switching
gears which is second Bert collaborator
so normally when you're testing the
packets are going back and forth between
you and the server and that's awesome
your your client server as does client I
should push it the class over anyway now
sometimes it's useful to have a third
party in here and that's where Brooke
collaborator pops in this is a this is a
service it's available to anybody using
Burke Pro you can also set up your own
collaborator server for no additional
cost so that when you send something to
the client
is going to cause an external
interaction it'll go up to the
collaborator whether that's pulling an
HTTP request SMTP smtps or DNS this will
serve as a DNS server as a webserver all
those things just to receive those
interactions so that then you can pull
the verb collaborator automatically in
the background and find out what what
you've caused that webserver to do
useful for things like blind command
injection all right so so active scan
plus plus it does all these things I
wanted to do more but I don't want a
code in Java I'm sorry it's their Java
coders in the room god bless you thank
you I don't want to but I can use Python
right cuz there's this there's this
GenCon thing and that's that's great I'm
much more comfortable with Python not
like Java are comfortable but but a
little bit comfortable also alright and
this is a co-worker saying just an
extension of my to type I don't know the
first thing about building a burp
extension this is in my first year as a
professional pen tester like I have no
idea but they're already things out
there that are similar like active scan
plus plus that where you can just pilfer
code because everybody pilfers code
right we all google and take other
chunks of code some of us are honest
about everybody okay and then and then
it comes you know how do I make it go
well there are a these cool existing
Python scripts so at this point at this
point you get everything you need right
you can use a language I'm comfortable
with there's also JRuby if you want to
code and remove your burp I guess there
are similar tensions that can pilfer and
their scripts I can use to ripoff so at
that point is just a matter of coding it
so that's what I did I stole Chris
Davis's code thank you Chris Davis and I
just put these big ogl blobs that again
not essentially understand every piece
of it but you're putting it in the
extension into the code that's already
not started there thank you James kettle
all right no this is this is about
command injection and in a lot of cases
blind command injection you may get
reflection and that's great but if you
don't you want something where you're
going to be able to detect detect that
because if your client if it's if it's
buried somehow you want to make sure
that you're you're detecting whether or
not something's happening right so I
wanted to work in a blind context which
means Durer LS Who am I echo they're
they're just out I wanted to be
cross-platform and yes I know there's W
get in PowerShell and that's great but
you're probably not operating in a
PowerShell
texts I wanted to be widely available
and this lookup is great but if you're
in like a a bear docker instance that
just has Apache in it Thank You Daniel
pendolino you may or may not have
nslookup there right that's that's an
additional package that's not
necessarily there I do like it though
because Windows is gonna use it in most
Linux most likes distros will use it I
also want to go over firewalls so clunky
ports are kind of out I also don't want
it to run forever because again this is
in a client-server and if I'm testing a
bunch I don't want to leave you know a
thousand running ping processes so what
I ended up with and this is going to
look a little strange to probably
everybody is this is this command on
Linux well what will this do it'll pain
once even though it's out of order it
will in every environment I tested it
will ping once but before it can ping
what does it need to do it needs to look
up the host right so even if nslookup is
in there it's going to resolve that name
on Windows you know what this will do it
will not launch calc I wish it did it'll
it'll actually fail when it gets to the
- c1 because in Windows this is what n1
and but before it fails it will resolve
that name so this is a cheap cross
cross-platform way to get the name
resolution and maybe it will ping out
that's great I don't care what I'm
looking for in verb collaborator is did
that name resolve so that's what I'm
using in this extension for to check for
command execution so then it comes as a
matter of hey I got it it's up it's
working and then you know new pen tester
anxiety how am I gonna go to James
Kendall and be like hey I made your
thing better right I'm just some some
new guy and then I don't know who who's
ever fish is but with an avatar like
that it can be a little intimidating
right I've never seen such a sharply
dressed stormtrooper so you kind of have
to get over right and that's what I did
and this is paraphrase it a little bit
but basically you know I go to github
and make my changes and hey I'd like you
to merge this into the main thing and I
made it and then James Kettle replies
this is the real James Kelly's he's
talking back to me he says oh yeah but
he does something kind of funky here did
you really mean to oh right yeah no
that's that's not quite right
just based on we can do that later about
what was kind of off about it but fixed
it and went back to him and he bumped
the version and made a couple style
changes and now it's in the product so
if you've been using active scan plus
plus since like May or so you've got
these these changes there thank you
thank you my mom loves me too so look at
me now number two contributor for this
plugin thank you very much
[Music]
and then homestar runner wants to know
so what all right you made this thing
what is it actually gotten um
interesting they actually actually found
a zero-day in Jam Pro it's it's a like
an iOS device management thing for
enterprises where it wasn't the struts
piece of it but it was but with
developing those struts little checks
doing an xxe check was actually kind of
trivial because I had all the pieces I
need especially the the collaborator
interaction so I found on a on a client
system that if I just just define the
the DTD that it would actually resolve
the name and then here it and it'll put
make the HTTP request as well so here's
my server listening for on a specific
board getting that callback so that was
cool this is basically an SSR app so
neat another use of it I thought was
kind of cool is if I give it an internal
IP address and port and it's valid it'll
come back in less than a second if it's
not valid the watch means it took some
time took about a second then I know
that that's a bad word so I can use this
to port scan inside their environment
that's kind of cool too I was a little
disappointed when I went to report it to
him because it took a while to kind of
like communicate well so that everybody
understood what I was talking about and
then once like once they got you know it
fully what I was explaining they said oh
we're already working on that which okay
so to answer your first question what
about the the new new struts right the
one that just came out this summer one
one seven seven six that one we actually
got a actually we his though you know
James kettle and I hang out
that's oh we got a request from
decidedly gray asking for that and I
looked into it and it wasn't much
different from the other vulnerabilities
the only catch with this one is it's
specifically for malformed redirects so
if you are when you're actively scanning
your your target if you're not actively
scanning the 302s the redirects you're
going to miss this specific struts
vulnerability because it's in it's in
badly handled redirects so so be aware
of that but that is now in as well that
took just a couple of weeks from from
the release of the vols that was that
was fun
I speak quickly so there's there's time
for questions I believe what questions
that people have about coding giving
things away and in struts yeah yeah yes
so so it worked the question was what
was the thing that that that he wanted
me to change in it and it was actually
in and kind of how I used the the API
because some things are really easy and
automatic in in burp and in the way in
the way it handles that the different
methods and objects some things aren't I
didn't realize that there was an easy
way to have to have my my test insertion
happen with every insertion point so I
was having it happen with each request
so it would actually go to and this was
the 2017 holiday hack addition of struts
vulnerability I was having it like cycle
through the head alert headers manually
to inject the payload and the different
headers when there's actually already a
different function and do that
automatically so it's just a matter of
simplifying that by the way if you look
at the code there's there's no easy way
when you're coding an extension to
switch and get requests to a post so if
you're scanning a get request and you
want it maybe switch it to a post so you
can post a neck sexy trial into the into
the web web application there's there's
no functions just swap it over so it so
in the code you'll actually see me
looking for a capital G like for a get
and then deleting three characters and
then inserting POS T and burp thankfully
takes care of like content length but
yes it was it was just just really that
made it a lot slicker mr fire
you know the one I was working with was
Python 2 to 7 I don't know does anybody
know if there's a Python 3 JSON great
question yeah
I'm sorry if you see that one more Sam
yeah what resources are useful for
building a plug-in Furber so I wish I'd
noticed actually the Derby con talk from
last year that would have been helpful
to look at but there's there's a decent
amount of documentation up from ports
wigger about about all the different
methods and objects so that was helpful
and also just just looking at other
people's code looking at the the
existing active scan applause applause
and some of the just weirdo things that
looks for for me was really helpful so
if you're looking to code your own
someone someone may have already done it
or what you're trying to do but I would
almost guarantee someone has done
something similar so just look around
and see what you can see what you steal
other questions yeah does it run
passively as well as actively it does
not know these texts are specifically
active checks yeah looking for remote
code execution thank you fails well
thanks so much for coming appreciate you
[Applause]