hi I'm John for the people in the back
can you can you hear me pretty well with
the with this one good alright awesome
what's it what do you this is a
self-portrait in my mind that's how I
look so before we begin I want to do a
quick overview of how SSL works so I
drew this in that word diagram on the
left you have a client system on the
right you have a server and in the
middle you have your network monitoring
solution so traditionally one would
think that with that network monitoring
solution all we would see is a source IP
a desk IP and in the middle a you know
it's encrypted so that's that's all you
get
but there's actually a lot more that we
can we can see with the SSL session
that's unencrypted so first in the
beginning the client sends a sent server
response an ACK clan responds ACK after
immediately after the TCP three-way
handshake the client will send a SSL
hello hello packet saying hi I'd like
the talk and SSL and if the server's
listening on SSL will respond with its
hello packet followed by x.509 subject
and an issuer which is also sitting
clear text now the x.509 certain details
can be used for for as artifacts for
detection so this is where x.509
certificate details live in pyramid of
pain you know the things at the top are
harder for threat actors to change and
even harder to detect and the things at
the bottom are easy to change and very
easy to detect right so it's in the
middle so I want to I want to tell you
guys a little story about a my
experience trying to build detection for
four certificates and my tool of choice
for like playing around with and
building these detection mechanisms has
been Metasploit because Metasploit
randomly generates its TLS certs and a
lot of tools use them like like the you
know the trusted SEC tool so so for you
know originally this is
what the Metasploit randomly-generated
SSL cert looked like the years ago it
was completely randomly generated the
code that they were using to generate it
hard-coded country code to us and then
it randomly created some mixed text for
the LNO field and the certificate and
another example clearly randomly
generated so how could we detect that I
wanted to build some regex for that
mixed case alpha and I came up with a
really complicated string but then I
realized that I could just do this and
that's because the L field and a
certificate is supposed to be the
location the city name because they
hard-coded country code to us that has
to be a u.s. city name what US city name
has a lowercase character followed by
two or more uppercase characters it's
the only one I could think of was
Washington DC but you add that to a
white list and so detection was really
easy I gave a talk about this at Nova
hackers a couple years ago and
immediately following that talk this guy
HDM made a change to how Metasploit was
randomly generating it certs he wanted
to change it so that it would look a lot
like the snake-oil certificate from
Ubuntu 14.04 so I was like all right HD
so called them let's do this so so this
is his code and it's as it's beautiful
code and this what the certificate
looked like you know subject an issuer
very simple and small just see n equals
and then some lowercase characters and
then the certificate Allah Q algorithm
was sha-256 but remember he wanted to
emulate the snake-oil as a fifth kid
have Ubuntu and so most of the items
were the same however the snake-oil sir
did certificate algorithms and sha-1 or
as the Metasploit cert did sha-256 you
know that's what he gets for trying to
be secure I guess and then the the CN
for the snake-oil cert was hostname dr
main uppercase characters and the
Metasploit sir was just two to ten
characters
lowercase alpha so detection actually
turned out to be really easy there and
that worked for a little bit however it
was changed again our Whitcroft last
october made a change to how is
generating certs and this is what it
looked like and you
detect it with this red text ring
however it was shortly changed again 20
days later and then they introduced some
code some bug that caused it to do C
equals newline C equals us and so that
was actually really easy to detect but
of course it changed again and you could
use this for edge X maybe but at this
point I was like so how how can we get
to the point where where we can move up
one level on the Pyramid of pain go from
artifacts the tools and it turns out
that you could do this by looking at
that client that SSL client hello packet
and if this sounds familiar to some of
you it's because it is using that method
of looking at the client hello packet is
not new so I've been discovered back in
2009 that that he could detect the
Googlebot and fingerprint Googlebot
based on the force ciphers that it used
in his client hello at the time but the
person who did the most research on this
was libreluch then released fingerprint
TLS at Derby Con 2015 and this got a lot
of people excited myself included so we
wanted to deploy fingerprint Els so bad
in our network however we just couldn't
it was a it was a standalone tool and
deploying new standalone tools in our
environment is kind of difficult so so
luckily at the end of his talk he said
you know like here's my research go make
a better Fork my repo build something
new you know take it from there and so
so you know we we basically did we
sought out to create a new
fingerprinting method that could work
and so we set our requirements it needed
to work on our existing tools the tools
that are already deployed in our
environment
it needs a fingerprint needed to be
unique to a client application just like
they are in TLS you need to be easy to
create easy to share and easy to consume
by any tool basically we just wanted it
to be really simple and and so let's go
over how it works so this is a TLS
client hello packet I got two examples
here
left one of the right to different
clients they look the same however if
you if you look here the one on the Left
supports 13 Cyprus sweets the one on the
right 19 the one on the left has an
extension length of 124 the one on the
right 141 so it looks similar but
they're actually very different so
Microsoft edge browser for example 19
Cyprus weeds extension length 107 dry
Rex malware banking Trojan 21 cipher
Suites fewer extensions though
and then trick Bach malware 12 cipher
suites and even fewer extensions
Microsoft edge browser orders its
ciphers from most secure to least secure
right that makes sense but the trick pot
now where it just kind of throws them
all in there and random order so it's ID
so we can fingerprint TLS clients based
on the TLS version the cipher Suites and
the order in which they appear the
extensions in the order in which they
appear in them for added complexity let
the curves and elliptic curve point
formats so this is how it works this is
our method for it anyways we take the
version followed by the ciphers and the
order on which they appeared then the
extensions and the order in which they
appear and they lip the curves in the
order in which they appear in the
elliptic curve point formats and so if
there's if there's no more like there's
only one elliptic curve point format in
this example then there's just no des
limiters afterwards we md5 hash that and
that's our fingerprint and then if
there's if there's no extensions or a
lip the curve for whatever reason then
the comma delimiter persists and the
reason why we md5 hash it is because
there could be up to 300 supported
ciphers so the the fingerprint could be
huge and our rule of thumb is that if we
can't tweet a fingerprint then it's too
long so the md5 hash into a nice
predictable 32 character fingerprint so
some examples Google Chrome Microsoft
edge tor client dry Dex malware these
are the fingerprints trick bots now
where it works really well and if you're
wondering does this work on TLS point
1.3 the answer is yes here's two
different clients talking over TLS one
three and you can see that the cipher
suites are different
and the order in which they put their
extensions is completely different so
fingerprinting still works and TLS one
three and and again this is the client
hello packet comes before the server
hello packet so even if the server's not
listening let's say it's a command and
control server and it's just not
configured yet but the client reached
out to it
we've already fingerprinted it so it
doesn't matter if the server responds or
the SSL session completes or anything
like that we've already got the
fingerprint we already know it's running
so yeah Java 3 is up there on the tools
level of a pyramid of pages cool remove
moving up and it's open source there's
the github you want the python version
you can pip install PI Java 3 if you're
running bro
you can just simply run bro package
install Java 3 and it was created by
John hotels
Geoff Atkinson and Josh Atkins and again
I want to make this perfectly clear the
concept came from lis brother Stan and
his talk here at Derby con 3 years ago
if it wasn't for him doing that talk
this tool would not have existed
everything's based on his research so I
want to give life full credit to him so
what are some things that you might want
to do with this well the first thing we
wanted to do was start mapping Java
threes the client applications so we
posted some lists on ER get up there so
so this is one of the lists that we
created and and trizol NSM they created
a module that would take Lee brothers
Tunes fingerprints and convert them into
ja3 so that list is also available we
linked to it in our github page but
here's an example and this is really
awesome because this is this laptop
right here based on my usage over some
period of time and this is exactly
correct this is what's running on my
laptop I'm basically just using Google
Chrome and then you have some Apple
WebKit networking which would indicate
that this is a Mac and it is and then
there's a blank one there ignore that
that's an internal tool but this works
and then so what about a large example
network so something with like 50,000
host Center or something like that it
still works it works really well so we
can see that in this example Network
that Google Chrome is the most prolific
application using TLS and that's
accurate and then way down there at a
2.8 percent we still have some true
believers using Firefox so you know
that's good what if we dive into a
specific domain like my PC master-race
brethren right so we can see that most
connections to steam powered comm are
using steam over OSX and and I guess
some people are connecting over Chrome
and Firefox maybe as a steam sale that
day so yeah it's interesting
so you might want to drop some malware
into sandboxes try to pull out the JA
three fingerprint for that malware but
it's important to baseline your sandbox
before you do that because there are
operating system api's that programs can
communicate through and including
malware so this guy Barford created just
this basic application that would create
a bunch of connections through all of
those operating system api's so you
could drop that into your sandbox base
line any java 3 that you see that's not
one of these you could probably assume
is the malware so file exfil detection
over TLS this concept was created by Bob
rats dead at reservoir labs
basically the concept of file exfil
detection normal outbound traffic looks
like this a file transfer outbound looks
like this right so pretty obvious and so
his detection mechanism was just
threshold bytes over time and then log
at the end after it drops off pretty
simple and so we you know we use this
and we have logs that output kind of
similar to this so you know here's a
exfil to Dropbox makes sense and if you
add in ja3 you could say that the client
application was Dropbox okay maybe
that's fine
but what if the client application was
PowerShell huh maybe that's someone
worth looking into another example
hunting on weird subjects so these
subjects look like DJs and they are
right so if we pivot on them grab the
Jah three that's connecting to that then
we can see a list of all of the domains
that it's connecting to so that just
makes it really easy before what DGA is
people would like try to get the
algorithm and have it run through the
algorithm and build a database of all
different potential domains and with
this you can just grab the Jah three and
just watch that and it's kind of awesome
evil Gen X is a man-in-the-middle proxy
so it's supposed to steal your you know
your cookies or your passwords and
whatnot and it's written and go and so
there's the the Jah three for that now
however this is the job three for go so
so if you were trying to detect on this
then what you would be detecting is the
go the go client however if you wanted
to detect connections to a server that
you controlled where you could see the
user agent and everything like that so
let's think that you have a server that
you know some critical server and you
wanted to be able to detect any time
sowing was having those credentials
stolen right what you could do is you
could look for the Jah three of the go
client but then also compare that to the
user agent and if the user agent is
chrome and the Java three is go client
then you can kind of assume that there's
a go proxy on between potentially and
malicious go proxy in between so you can
still do detection there another example
puppy rat this one's a you know it's a
open source pin testing tool it was you
know like with most open source pen
testing tools it will eventually get
used for evil so you know Iranians use
popular rat to hit Middle Eastern
organizations at least according to
secure works and then secure works
release um IOC s which included them
and why not and you know those IOC s are
not always the most valuable because
they're usually burned by the time
they're they're published however the
fact that they were using puppy rat is
good for us because then we can look to
see if we can build detection for that
and it turns out that detection is
really easy
so they hard-code the order in which the
ciphers are are picked for the client
hello so this is what it looks like and
there's a jaw three and it's yes so the
detection is actually pretty simple for
a puppy rat turns out and there's
actually I think there's an a bug in
their code where you can see the cipher
suite in the middle is unknown I think
that's like a semicolon or something so
it just makes it super anomalous very
easy to detect and move on to some
targeted malware so this is malware that
was specifically targeted for our
environment you know by some pin testers
and it turned out it was really easy to
detect using Java three because it only
had a single cipher very anomalous very
easy to find just by hunting for some
weird things I should mention that our
bro script if you uncomment some lines
you can have it log the entire
fingerprint string along with the jaw 3
so you can do some hunting based on
looking for something like only one
certificate so back to my display round
for let's go back at it
I ran Metasploit on on a Windows VM just
to get some more details that's what it
looked like a mole lock by the way if
you don't know what Moloch is it's this
awesome full packet capture open source
tool find out more mole och anyways this
is what it looked like in mohawk Mohawk
has ja3 built into it the latest version
so we could see that the jaw 3 wasn't
changing every time we were running
interpreter on Windows 10 and and this
was the jaw 3 for direct to an IP and
the bottom ones the jaw 3 if it was
going to like a domain name and so
looking for that in an example
environment find out that that happens
quite often that jaw 3 pops up quite a
bit and that's because it's actually
like a Windows DLL API so it's
windows API that it's communicating
through so detection just based on that
doesn't really work very well
enter Jah through yes this is where we
deviate from Lee brothers since research
starting to look at fingerprinting the
server side of the hello packet so this
was my hypothesis in building this
because evenly brother Stan and his talk
was like don't bother fingerprinting the
server side there's nothing there's
nothing of value there it changes too
often but I I did it anyways just to see
because I had an idea that clients will
or servers will respond to different
clients differently but they'll respond
to the same client the same and let me
tell you what I mean by that so in this
example you know client sends hello
packets to a server always service like
hello a let's talk a now different
client going to the same server sends a
hello packet all B's so that's same
server so it's a little bit let's talk
to eat right so did you know different
client responding differently however it
will keep responding the same to that B
client so here's the method that we use
for generating that ja3 yes we just look
at the TLS version that the server is
using the cipher suite that I picked and
then the list of extensions it's
actually just really simple so again
this is what it looks like
we md5 hash that and and that's how we
get the Java 3s now I have an example
here so I connected to the same server
multiple times over with different
clients ja3 on the Left jaw 3s on right
so first client connected to it four
times over server responds the exact
same way to that client four times over
different client server responds the
exact same way four times over right so
it works so what can we tell from that
some examples trick bot malware there's
a job area in Java three yes the trick
bot command and control servers respond
always the same - the trick bot client
never changes same with I Sai D the tour
client again the tour servers respond
exactly the same to the tour client and
it's been open sourced it's on the same
github if you do a bro package install
Java 3 you also get
three us building so back to Metasploit
round five let's do this this is the jaw
3's for Metasploit running on Kali
this is how meterpreter responds running
on Kali and and if we look at that in
our example environment there are some
hits so this by itself is not a good
indicator however if we combine it with
the jaw three the client right which is
that windows API that it's communicating
through and the way that Kali responds
to it no hits and an environment of you
know tens of thousands of systems sort
of no false positives if that's it
that's the detection mechanism and so
they can change the state all they want
they can change how they build this kit
this will still work another example
cobalt starts beacon it tends to use the
the same API that Metasploit is using
but the server responds slightly
differently however the same and and
this is interesting the way that it
responds it uses renegotiation Mpho and
extended master secret as extensions but
extended master secret they're both
basically empty so the I don't know why
the extensions are there
however they are and its anomalous so
detection Naz is also super easy and
then that's it
yeah it's just simple low false positive
detection you can do the joffrey of
direct to an IP and then the joffrey
where it's going to a domain because of
those will produce two different
fingerprints and then and the jaw three
s equals the in this instance the Kali
server this latest version Kelly let's
dive into Empire over Python so this
this example is game with pen testers
and and so they were using the Python
version of Empire so the jaw three there
is the jaw three for Python you know if
I look for that in our environment and I
forgot to take a screenshot of it but I
swear this what it look like in spunk
there was a lot right because it's
Python and there's a lot of Python you
know happening in a dev environment
however we look at the job 3 yes it
turned out that their server was
responding in a very unique way to this
uh this you know Python Empire hour so
if I search for Java 3 equals Python and
Java 3 s equals their c2 the way that
their c2 was responding then all I saw
was just the connections from the
infected hosts and that was it that was
the that was the detection mechanism so
it worked out really well of course we
had other detection mechanism on the
hosts and whatnot but for the network
detection this worked out really well so
they actually they they actually after
this after detection you know iterating
through normal you know kind of pen test
style stuff they changed their
certificate they went out and bought a
brand new certificate they had it signed
they bought a new domain you know redid
the whole thing got another shell on
network boom detection and they're like
oh let's let's move so they moved to a
completely new infrastructure you know a
new cloud hosting provider they bought
more servers they you know they move
their their image over and everything
like that bought a new domain new
certificate and then as soon as they got
their first shell boom detection
instantaneous they're demoralized
because you know what like who thinks
like in order to evade detection I have
to change my server image no one really
thinks about that but that's what would
have been needed in order to evade this
or or just not use TLS because then it
doesn't work so that takes me to hash so
fingerprinting tls/ssl uh that's not the
only thing that we can fingerprint
that's an encrypted channel it turns out
that we can also fingerprint SSH so this
idea and concept was created by Ben
Rearden on our team and what he came up
with was that we could use these fields
and the
saij key negotiation to fingerprint ssh
clients and servers so we use the Tex
algorithm the encrypted algorithms the
Mac out of the rooms and the compression
algorithms and just to give an example
I've got two different clients up here
but between the two clients one will
have Z lib none and the other one will
have none zlil so just the way that
they're ordering very simple things can
be very unique so the way that the
method for fingerprinting ssh clients
and servers that we came up with that
tends to just be simple and work is we
take the key exchange we use semi colon
delimiter that encryption message off
compression and then we take all that we
md5 hash it to a nice easy shareable 32
character fingerprint and and the reason
why we md5 hash again we were looking at
doing sha 256 but it just didn't make
sense because we're not worried about
hash collisions when all we have is just
a string of text and also it's
unnecessarily long so we can we can
tweet these fingerprints a lot easier I
guess another reason why we don't want
to just output the entire field because
this is what it would look like normally
so just nice and easy 32 character
fingerprint
hashes been open source that's the link
for it and there's a nice blog post on
the Salesforce engineering site and
again the the whole idea was basically
created by Ben Reardon and Adel myself
and Jeff we just kind of helped out and
and building it so there's going to be a
lot of cool research coming out of
coming from this from both Ben and Adel
so I recommend you guys follow them on
Twitter to see what's coming on next
something to note here though is this is
really powerful for honey pots because
you can correlate threat actors as
they're scanning the internet changing
you know they could say like I'm OpenSSH
version seven point six but are they
really I mean you would be able to tell
and they could change like now I'm a
Cisco SSH client and whatever and keep
changing and you would be able to tell
just by the finger
because the fingerprint won't change
same thing can be done on the other side
so this can also be used for for
fingerprinting honey pots so if you had
a honey pie and you said you know I'm a
Cisco switch or something like that but
the fingerprint shows that you're just
running OpenSSH then probably a honey
pot so it's a double-edged sword just be
aware of that but yeah it's it's awesome
so keep an eye on those those Twitter
accounts so in conclusion I want to say
ja3 is not a silver bullet apple
application collisions can happen what I
mean by that is that multiple
applications can end up having the same
jaw 3 for whatever reason they were just
built the same way the same process or
whatever and applications can connect
through OSAP eyes so you know just be
aware of that and there can be up to 5
jaw threes for the same application so
if you remember earlier in the talk
there was a lot of different chrome jaw
threes and that's because there will be
one for if it's direct to an IP one if
it's going to a domain another one if
it's a renegotiation and so on so
however now we're just tends to have one
so that's that's nice it's always
valuable as a pivot point for analysis
so there's no reason not to run it
there's no reason not to look at it if
you're beginning an investigation it's
just it's always valuable Java 3 is the
Silver Bullet sometimes each environment
is different but like in that other
example with the malware that was
developed and targeted specifically for
us it was it's like shooting fish in a
barrel so and then combined with Jah 3s
allows for fingerprinting of the entire
TLS communication which is can be like
super valuable for detection especially
for you know specific threat actors that
you might be worried about or seeing
your environment and this style of
fingerprinting can work across other
encrypted channels Ben Riordan came up
with the method for for fingerprinting
SSH and I'm sure that if there's another
encrypted channel that you're thinking
about you can probably apply the same
eye
to that so please take this use it build
off of it build off of our research make
it better
three years ago you know three three
years ago Lee brother Stan stood up here
at Derby con and and he was like you
know talking about fingerprint Els and
all the research that just got was so
excited and and at the end of his talk
he was like just you know going and and
build upon this you know make it better
and I want to I want to say the same
here like if you're seeing this and you
got more ideas on how to make it better
please do it you know for car repo
create something new and so you might be
thinking this is awesome
I I like it can can I have it and
actually if you're running some of these
you might actually already have it so
Mohawk had already supports Java three
extra hop just implemented a dark trace
is running at gray noise Cercado it will
be in the latest version and a lot of
other companies are running it as well
so there's an engine X module and and so
on so there's actually a quite a quite a
bit of support out there already I want
to take this opportunity to to give a
shout out to some people who have helped
me out mentored me technically so just
want to say thank you to these guys if
it wasn't for them I probably wouldn't
be up here because I wouldn't know what
I'm talking about
so thanks thanks and and again my name
is John all taos I do threat detection
you can contact me at my email address
or the Twitter link and again the codes
all been open sources on github so yeah
there are there any questions I can
answer yes yeah yeah yeah oh so the
question is the question is why were
there so many different hashes for
Google Chrome in that example for this
laptop and that's because like I said
there could be multiple Geoffrey's for
different things so like if chrome is
renegotiation reading ago she a ting to
an existing connection will have
different extensions and whatnot so I'll
create a new Joffrey and then if it's
communicating direct to an IP or to a
domain that'll create two different
Geoffrey's so so there can be quite a
bit for especially browsers but for
other applications there could be only
one like malware tends to just have one
tour just has one for example yeah yes
so yeah so the question is why is there
so much variance why is each application
kind of unique and the answer is because
it depends on you know what libraries
you have installed on your build system
at the time that you're building even
the the operating system in the version
of the operating system matters and how
the TLS client hello is formulated so
you know the way that that you build an
application right now like on your
laptop will be very different from the
way like Google's building their master
chrome you know client on their server
somewhere using different libraries
different operating systems and then
that's how that's why it's all unique
yes so so let me answer the first part
so the the question was how do we build
our library and and we basically use the
complicated a method and Splunk of
combining fields so so we get it from
the host logs and then the network logs
combine them together and we build out
like a list that way what was your
second yeah you know oh absolutely
so so the question was what if what if I
create a whole bunch of signatures for
malware like how would I share that and
whatnot so we didn't create a blacklist
because we're worried that you know what
may work in our environment may not work
in other environments there may be false
positives but you know if you if you
want to create a blacklist and share it
out please do you can you can add to our
repo or you can create your own repo let
me know I'll out a link and our repo to
link to your repo and then everyone will
see and you do it yeah any other
questions yes
yes yeah so that so the comment is is
that there could be a lot more variance
based on what admins are doing in your
environment whether they're changing
what cipher Suites could be in your
operating system and and absolutely
that's why I say and and why we don't
really want to build a blacklist is
because what may work in our environment
may not work in yours because doing so
they could create some collisions with
like a blacklist so it's all of this
really environment specific but it also
can work unbelievably well yes yes yeah
so the comment is is this no matter what
this will give you the outliers in any
kind of environment and absolutely one
of the things that that the pen testing
team after we detected them when we
talked with them about everything and
there they told us how the more lives
they were they they one of the first
things that they thought of and this is
a common thing what other people are
thinking is that well I'll just build
into my application some randomness so
will randomize my cipher Suites every
time it connects and and whatnot
however like that would actually make
them even easier to detect because of my
example where I showed this laptop
there's there was something like 18
Geoffrey's 4 for my laptop over a period
of time and so if they're randomizing
every time it connects well then they're
gonna have like a hundred or 200 and
that that client you know that that
machine would stick out like a sore
thumb and be even easier to detect
exactly however well so what then it
depends on how the server responds
because so the comment was is that well
if you go through the OS API that's true
yeah yeah yeah so the comment was if you
just go through the OS API then then
I'll make detection a lot harder however
you know in the example that we had they
were using Python so the jaw 3 was
Python but because of the unique way
that their server was responding to it
it was very anomalous so but then if
they use a standard server maybe that
would get around that and maybe that's
the the one way I don't know yes why do
you what do you mean yeah so yeah so I
can't I kind of mentioned that with that
but that other proxy was that the jaw 3
will be of the proxy but the it depends
on how the proxy is configured if it
would pass the the the user agent
through and everything else would be the
same besides the TLS communication says
yeah exactly it still can be useful or
it could not I mean it depends it
depends but yeah any other questions
yes so the question was how long did it
take us to to compare Jah 3 and Jah 3s
and find anomalies and the answer is not
long at all at least not in Splunk it
was very quick and easy to just you know
find something weird click on the JA 3
and I'd see a whole bunch of results for
that job
and then I click on the JA 3s of the
thing that could be malicious and then I
just see just that traffic and like that
process takes like 45 seconds so like
the analysis is fast yes in the back
the question is kind of fingerprint ssh
into a VPN oh I see what you're saying
so if you ssh into some like VPN or some
jump host and then ssh from that into
something else can i fingerprint the
original one the answer is no the I'd
only be fingerprinting just the the
client that is making the connection
from where I can see it so anyone else
yes so the question is have I done any
fingerprinting of common VPNs and I
haven't really spent much time on it do
a lot more fingerprinting with with the
well maybe this is was your question
with the what VPNs like tor like ways of
hiding your traffic yeah we do we do
research that and we have a list for
those to find any of that traffic
originating from within our network so
yeah and then is piece could probably do
the same but please don't anyone else
all right thank you
[Applause]