we have to know everyone okay I've come
to Taiwan and then you before the
station I have to say apologize to
everyone because my Latin language is
Chinese so my English is pretty basic
please don't lie about it okay this is
my first time to be Debra Kong and I'm
happy so many people it fits in my topic
I'm happy to hear and to share our
research result to you okay let me
introduce me my first okay I come from
Taiwan okay and walking around what
security and my Chinese name is little
Tauron okay I know it is very hard to
pronounce so you can just call me Daniel
okay you know Japanese Chinese the
different languages are really hard to
pronounce okay I have 10 years
experience security testing about what
application presentation penetration
testing IOT and scalar okay Oscar t we
have the ISO set 2002 device skirting
test laboratory so our laboratory will
do the testing for customers like IOT
the SCADA device and automotive okay so
now I in charge of the list skirt in
testing laboratory okay
our team since 2012 we start to oil tea
in a bit embarrasses and testing and we
found I was security at 2014 okay our
since 2012 our team already tests more
than 200 devices okay I think it should
be 300 by end of this year a device into
the SS point wireless router IOT gateway
everything about our ot and automotive
and embedded device so in the beginning
we provide a testing service to help our
customer to find a vulnerability so we
use the scanning tool to tell them you
have signed with some normal Bertie but
sometimes they will not satisfy with
this kind of service they say hey I want
you find a song I don't wanna be noticed
bye-bye another one so we try to find a
way to do this kind of service so we
choose the fast testing technique
technique so now the fast testing is one
of common and effective tech a testing
technique to find among the bility okay
so the simply speaking the 14 tests we
just send us something wrong or
something bad to tool a target maybe the
application or sound a groceries okay so
we send a mail phone data or some very
big value or very long string and
monitor latakia the Monica response from
the target okay so if Larry is known it
ladies no response from the target okay
congregation maybe we find a song I'm
not gonna build because the talkie can
now handle our mail phone pic and we can
create that application make fish by
some reason so far you may know the
synopsis the differences and the based
on the famous commercial father in
testing software okay both of land
support most common protocol regular
HTTP I said how SSH and DNS of course or
company have lower on father to do this
kind of protocol filing test okay so if
you want to build your fault
protocol filing test tool is pretty hard
it's a simple easy thing for some
protocol like HTTP FTP RTSP okay at
least kind of protocol are present in
text so you can just use the sniffer to
down pull up a key and you can use the
text editor to ideal accountant to do
the file in test okay for some protocol
Lila SSL tos and SSH
so this is a little a little bit harder
to do a father because this protocol are
not long test protocol okay so you have
to do some work to realize the RFC
inspect to know how the protocol and is
a proto structure okay but
for this test or loan test protocol they
are running under tcp/ip so you don't
need to handle how they how they change
they how they transfer to to the target
you just call a socket and send the data
Tula to a doctor to Latakia okay this is
a easy way to do the fuzzing but for
some protocol Lyla radio frequency the
Bluetooth VB the wave or a low cellular
network it is very hard to do a
testing because you have to do a lot of
work on how they work how they transfer
the data to Tula target sometimes you
may need a spatial and customized
software and how where to do the fast
testing for least ten of radio frequency
or cellular network okay well VB y5 z FM
bluetooth layout of already sounds
research already released lea falling to
long internet just google a keyword it
can you can find many github project and
you can download and compile and use
sub-layer how we're done go to do the to
do the testing but for the cellular
network it is the most hardest to build
the testing your a testing environment
because the CB the reduce and Wi-Fi is
very cheap to build testing the
environment but if you like to build a
testing failure environment like 2g 3g
or 4g you have to spend a lot money to
buy some equipment to simulate love LTE
signal okay so in one day our customers
to tourists okay they made a cell phone
a new cell phone in taiwan they say they
want to do the test formula LTE
side thus almost Kirti could help plan
to Dilys okay we say mmm it's pretty
hard but i we think we can do that so we
create this project and today we're
sharing our taste of research result
so for filing test in the most important
you
to feel the testing environment without
the environment you can do nothing you
cannot know lies look protocol you you
want to do the fast so in the beginning
we will try to to tell us how we build a
testing environment and how we find how
we how we analyze the product anguish to
the passing and sound cellphone okay
this is a LTE network architecture there
are three major part in LTE network the
first one is the user equipment we call
Yui so such as your cell phone your pair
or something can insert the SIM card I
belong to the Yui okay
another two is in Opie and EPC well the
critically important component in I also
network ok the inner be just like the
PlayStation in LTE network so your cell
phone will connect to in OB and in LP
will communicate with the EPC is PC is
the corner in LTE irresponsible manager
mobile and Hilty and roll at data or
network okay so if you want to build LTE
network you have to build in or be an
EPC in your testing environment okay
maybe someone know we can buy Lagasse
and w5 hungry to do testing environment
that you can spy it's a very very
expensive device you have to spend 150
grand to buy this device our security we
are a startup company we don't have so
much money to buy these kind of device
and the most important this kind of
device are designed for compatibility
testing purpose they just used to check
your device can connect to LTE or not so
we cannot stand some a male phone or do
a filing on this machine we can modify
the content so it's trying to do
let's simulator ourself so you can find
some resource and tutorial on internet
it is not the titik it's not difficult
to find so for in LP you just to buy one
the hard way we call the SPR USRP b10
okay
this is a str software-defined radio
tool
okay we open air interface of where you
the open air interface can control a
USRP b210 list SDR to control to
transmit and receive the LTS thing you
know okay to build a PC server it is the
most simple in this part you just
download a download and deploy a virtual
machine image and make a little
configuration the EPC server will be B
okay okay once you're in OB and it is
ready so you can you can take your LTE
phone before let you have to prepare the
planks in car because the each in OB has
the differences with your current
telecom carrier so you have to write the
information into the blanks in car and
use the listing card into your cell
phone your cell phone we are coming to
e2b okay so you can check to the work
environment is working or not
okay beside for the research purpose so
we still need to sound so for it to
monitor your device what kind of data it
receives so we use the q xt n the co
count did lag lies - oh so you can
connect to your cell phone to check what
kind of data received by your cell phone
okay so these screenshots so sorry about
the Chinese so the level image is from
the cell phone you just research
available Network and you find these a
to a 2-0 a 93 the lease is that 18 n is
assimilated by our inner peace
so you just choose choose this one and
you can find the LT status in your in no
the P okay if your let's connect if your
cell phone can assess the Internet it
means your LT environment is ready okay
so we can move to the next step to
analyze slow the LTE network and I'll
find a way to do the following testing
okay so you can find the latest load
testing environment would be okay we put
a NOP and EPC analyst send the single
server and we use use SP STR device to
transmit LTE signal to device okay you
know and we will also monitor the signal
by lock you XDM okay this is our filing
tested architecture so you have to take
a more loop to open air interface
architecture so in this picture you can
find EMP application and Mme application
all these are two application our most
important part in operating the face so
you can check how the open interior
interface to implement all different
layer like RSC in an ear in not be
piracy will perform the function like
the broadcast the connection management
and the nuts in mm II you will perform
the radio signaling between the device
and the EPC okay so you can find out all
the different layer implement or PI or
open air interface but we can do all the
test all of us testing on different
layer but look you xdn only monitor some
channels so we only do a testing in this
channel like the b tch tch tch in in in
LP and en n es n in EPC okay if you do
the fighting our other channels let q
scientists now support email we may
cannot find a quarter of Mesa area of
data
the cell phone fresh so in this research
we only do fast testing for this channel
but in this channel there are many
different requests ok because the LT is
a quite complicated the protocol you
must follow ltu workflow to final
request request to be query floss not
every request could be used to do a fall
testing if you set up mail from data in
a long time or or run request the cell
phone will discard a packet so according
our request only least 10 research the
only least 10 requests could be tested
by while testing and you can to follow
the the open source to find which file
and which function will handle the PCC
HTTP or CCHD message and try to do the
some little change to 2 to n some
function to read the data from our
father our Father will general write
love patent and we change we use we
rewrite like function function to read a
patent from our file and send a mail
phone data to mail form data to to a
cell phone okay
this is our testing target this time LG
Google next flight okay you can find the
process is the coconut dragon a hungry
okay this is our real environment so we
stole in not be in this let hops earth
host OS and running EPC is a virtual
machine it's a small simple but the most
point most important is the least
vibrant is walk okay we can find that
this is the device Google Nexus Phi and
this is the
USRP SDR radio - oh okay once we start
testing you will read the file from our
it's on file and try to generate two
transmitted later to to the mobile phone
and you can check the data on by QX t n
so this is the sister look from QX TN
you can check the data a bit like
message attack time pickle ends in lo
Pido
okay data we receive okay to receive so
we can know which data really cause look
the device crash okay so let me see our
filing results so we connect our device
to our environment correctly kou-kun s
Phi to our environment okay so we
explode in our testing we finally is the
last message called authentication
request and the star with zero seven
five four it means the authentication
reject okay
once the device received this kind of
request that the cellphone will come it
will not connect to and there were any
more you can only see the emergency call
on your cell phone even you switch on
and switch off to err primal ISTE or not
walk in a reconnect to network you have
to reboot your cell phone and you will
reconnect to a network ok app because
the environment is is complicated so we
use a video to show a demo station
beginning we change the device to
airplane mode then you can find ok we
connect we switch of airplane mode and
you will connect to it already coming to
our operative our not be our base
station then we switch our airplane mode
again to
okay the next one we will start to do
the fast testing we will do a little
configuration and and try to send on my
own phone data by our EndNote be okay
you already start you know being key
okay so now we will switch off the
airplane mode again okay you can see
with switch off and you will try to
connect to the our pay station so you
find the loss healthy status is your
emergency convey so this in Chinese life
is emergency to only so so even you
switch switch on and switch off again
sto show emergency co only okay so so we
already use the mail phone data also
authentication request tau is the old
seven five four two two to make the
device can connect to their work anymore
if you want to make a no more the simple
only way is to reboot the device let me
get it faster
maybe not fast enough
okay the boots and swish of the FMO okay
then you can connect to the network in
so we also explain our testing research
different cell phone glycol asanas PRC
or Isis length of critics and in
seriously I'm going to okay we find
another one then for Sony Xperia z3 plus
let use the coconut around 810 we also
have the same ability on it for issues
them going to they have used another
process you have to a sense situation
here okay so this device are use metric
track down a hungry and this device also
may be affected by this vulnerability
they oh use metric and a 10 but we have
to say this device may horrible we can
now 100% guarantee because we just we
just stop a company we cannot buy each
cell phone to do a testing and verify
this for ability so okay we also we
finally availability LS December and we
refer to a Kong and we have a some
discussion the response Franco can only
say or later release the vulnerability
may exist on some other Kokomo dance but
let's believe they already be fixed in
the new in your newer version your newer
products but let release update to the
OEM the sodium will not update up but
then and the problem may still exist in
the song device today okay okay they
also give us a little coal knowledge
ease the according to a 3gpp technical
specification
like say once the skewer exchange of nos
message has been established they have
to pass the integration if the message
not failed to in creation check youi
love device USL firm have to discolor
listen message but in our researcher
will find for County not compliant with
a specific occasion and UE steel process
this kind of message LED fail to
integration check ok ok I hope you
everybody liked my presentation and I
have to say project again because my
English is pretty best I afraid I cannot
understand and answer your question
immediately so if you have any question
and suggestion so you can come come to
me after the association or you can
reach me by email linking and Twitter
ok thank you for your attention again
thank everybody
[Applause]