starting
I guess they're just all right so the
title of this talk I can be Apple and so
can you if you're using hacker cracker
it so I can be company X because
anything that to censor your popping out
in the title I just so anyway yeah
welcome to derbycon welcome to noon high
noon track to thank you for coming a
little bit about my background that was
a breeze back last century I got out in
this 72 cost how station in Hawaii and
I've worked in sickened and the reason
I'm in InfoSec today because I got
worked in training put behind a desk per
year they told me to become a security
officer basically there's no such thing
as 6 purity so I was like ok well then
you'll see that as Michael so after the
breeds at which of University of Florida
I worked for PwC and the Booz Allen
libido security group and now I'm with
octo who hears furtive octa raise your
hands helping years ago there would be
no hands betrayed it now longer startup
and I'm on the internal offensive team
thanks for offending people now we throw
our bug reports so I work on the vendor
side of the house so anything that comes
in that needs to be looked at hiding
bugs do that also structure I look at
everything from routers to huevos so I'm
a full stack pen tester
yeah so I also write code for fun that's
my github I wrote back to her factory
and I percent in the first one four
years ago or at least the current
version and forty years ago here at
Derby con and I introduced the proxy to
exact repeat two weeks after that
presentation I found this thing called
ending two which was four years ago now
that was downloading infecting binaries
over tour during download or HTTP so
that's enough about me
this is the outline I'm kind of doing
something different I'm going in Reverse
and then show a demo and then we're
going to talk about how I found this bug
but I also have an update
I added because some news came out two
days ago that I don't agree with in the
Mac security space I'm going to talk
about that so what is cosine T cosine T
is a security construct that allows for
the consumer and user to fair fight move
aside encoded in question and to verify
the encoding question and modify you
need fighter in cosign name either at
the lowest level when third-party
developer tools can have disastrous side
effects especially if you're in the
defense side of the house or doing isn't
a response okay both Windows and Mac OS
support the concept co-signing cosign
for portable code there were issues in
Windows co-signing in the past however
we're focusing just on the Mac side of
house today so to talk about impact code
signing we're not talking about one of
Ben's
fineries per se while they are it's a
valid way to get code execution a lot of
the focuses on windows I challenge you
to find Goldmans
in Chrome OS or they might exist but I
don't think so but Mac OS does have a
particularly particularly interesting
well then which is Python it's signed
it's protected by sip and you say you
can't remem this you have these petals
or a driver but anyway what we want to
do is persist between reboots and full
user that what we're running the same
ballot and that's where it goes I mean
by peasants come in as far as impact
code-signing really impact zero trust
networks if you Michael at zero trust
networks are your hand young port so
zero trust networks is the concept of
you no longer have physical boundaries
on your honor there are no longer a
physical network like a moat for example
and you can have the device anywhere in
the world and we can make sure that is
secured and that we trust it just
because your device is trusted and you
have a token or something that says we
trust you now part of that is if you
bypass then the whole entire security
model for service networks broken so you
gotta have a code side enforcement you
also have to have modern which is a very
important part so we're gonna do a demo
this is going to show Google Santa which
is a white listing tool in full lockdown
mode and only Apple or native code can
run an apple sonic over where native
code from the from the App Store and
this is going to show the concept after
a phishing attack or social engineering
or some kind of post exploitation where
the user or not the attacker can drop
something to distance between removes
and this is gonna show that
you hide in plain sight so for those of
you in the back I hope you can't see
this today my room
alright on the on the Left we have the
user victim we have a root shell and a
regular shells on top and then on the
right we have the attacker come on so
we're going to do here is show you their
really calculator app this is not the
exploit it's just a show
it just works too soon so so yeah this
is just a show that native app pioneers
are running and I'm going to show next I
should be showing this is Santa for
control I'm just going to show what the
statuses and this and lock down those
only Apple sign go we can't run so I'm
going to try to execute in pattern Epcot
and of course as long as it should be
because it's not signed at all now I'm
going to show where LS this is a
maliciously patched LS the backdoor in
it
and it's in user local bed this is kind
of neat because this is showing what the
default do here but this is homework
demo room so if you do the default
install if you haven't really been
privileged escalation bug just someone
gets underwear station if you do
anything I'm gonna show you that and so
I just dropped in Melissa malicious LS
and use a little bit okay and so if I
use LS I get code execution and contacts
the attack on the right okay so now I'm
going to show the path of the routes and
you see that usually local business
first
that's default okay so if you have any
route scripts that run through soon
whatever those and you don't set the
path specifically the environment
variables or in the beginning the script
then whatever isn't usually use of local
bed is going to execute just keep that
line so now we're going to execute LS
and now I have it Rochelle okay
I don't not pop it into California sorry
so next we're going to turn off Santa or
put it in monitor mode and I'm going to
bring up I'm gonna use Patrick whirls
what's your sign - Linda show that the
check to see if this is signed by Apple
see who's I'm by and it says signed by
Amber and then I'm going to use cosine
tool which comes with the operating
system which shows code signing
contributes let me show you calm down a
little s that is that dinner fire that
this is signed by Apple and then I'm
going to check to see if it's it's valid
and it says it's Beth that's demo so how
does this work well this is released
June 12th alright and it's made a pretty
big splash but the details are so this
takes advantage of the fats commercial
binary formats what needs to happen is
the first file in the universal file or
fat file I'm gonna explain that a second
must be signed by Apple it must be
either PI 386 64-bit or even PowerPC the
malicious binary or not at this point
everything is in the oxide and also how
386 code with your target need to say a
little bit operating system you'll see
why in a second and the CPU type and the
fat header at the top of binary
must be set to an invalid type for the
first for the first file or YZ the anon
native chipset and I'll explain this so
it exists in
difference between how the maca litter
though psycho versus how improperly he
was consigned a the eyes check psycho is
wooden via the mouth horn universally
that binary okay so this is you that pop
on that all right you have two
architectures in each slice is the same
program compiled for different target
cpu so five 386 is for item 86 and
that's 64 I system
threesome and there's no signing on the
fat file itself so you can modify this
all just not the Mafia binaries and the
owner ability exists the difference
between how the Mako's order of load
sign code versus how incredibly is
consigned API so check the sign code so
let's create a Frankenstein binary and
how i did this i if i compiled that cap
1986 and i'm ad hoc signed it and I use
the lipo command which is a real command
to create fat bottles like TV not tools
use light flow to add to create fat or
you can use like though too thin it's
not something so anyway so we have a
universal fly over that bug you'll see
that Python is first and Hancock signed
yourself sign that cat is next next and
I'm over yeah so anyway so I'm showing
the cosine here he's the code signing
here so you'll see that net cotton isn't
he ad hoc sign and the team identify
there's not set so this is important
because you could use this
I'm just showing outside miners but you
could have used this on applications not
by Apple if you can set a team and I
team identified and that is a challenge
there's holes into it right now I would
have to write one so yeah so we're just
going to jackpot the liners so if I take
a copy the necktie Frankenstein - Tim
Python and execute Python I get my phone
but I want in cap or net capped execute
so how do I do this did not mess up
because I'm here well what I do is I
need to set the CPU type there in the
box to an invalid type or non-native
type I said to CPU to the data type or
the my computer will just skip over the
assignment popular binary and execute
the malicious code that's how simple it
is so you take here you see that Python
is now executing impact I give the
listen verbosity on port 8080 and he is
you'll see that shows that it is con
Dada Dada Python and that it is so let's
talk about it was affected and everyone
that I was able to test that every third
party developer that was able to test
they use that use cosine he gave me ice
and their chipset or in their future
sell everything I was able to touch some
some people I couldn't get a sample code
before this came out so I'm sure that
there were solid phases so I reached
record where I provided for samples for
the vendors to verify their bug and also
to fix it and each of these should
return non-valid basically the first one
is as it says it's a bash binary it's
not signed and has a malformed header
the next is a PPC binary it's the
malicious code bad luck sign and there's
no mount form header I found I found the
PPC binary in a install disk for OS X
leopard
I had to hang around I just pulled it
off there and then made the submission
potentially malicious binary and then uh
so back catalogue is just a box on
binary with a malformed header that
means invalid CPU type and then I
created a terminal app it's full
application bundle it is ad-hoc sign and
if there is a not more pattern terminals
kind of iffy when you go across
different OSX architecture earlier
versions so little
is there a little flocker upgraded to X
fence which also had you're still
vulnerable to this so objective-c every
memory so the see Patrick portals tools
all his tools that did cosign each
expert affected I only signed one CD
because so the first tool was what's
your sign sorry so what's your sign and
then next tool was uh I think tests for
the green lock means that it was on map
so a pupil Santa say that says the quite
the student and it's also OSX collector
decided information so most ice
collector only only return errors on
[Music]
invalid signatures so I had to patch it
up just to show that zeros municipality
carbon black advice from carbon black
but they came back as you can sign by
Apple Firestone invite your virus whole
I hear they're they're decent but yeah
this yeah and then it was very vague
about this thing
yes yeah Little Snitch so a little
snippet best response they could come
back and say hey this is different than
what's on
this might be maliciously modified no
like a memory or something but if you go
and check you know genique more detail
showed that bottom right
signed by Apple and then you follow your
other tools are saying hey it's fine bro
and then you probably just let it go so
well so this gatekeeper wasn't affected
if you used an application on dole but
also so let me just talk about
gatekeeper and this is where I'm going
to talk about some research so at least
two days ago that I don't agree with
gatekeepers a security feature that
enforces cosign and verifies the
downloaded application poor live in a
run right one time and that's off of
Wikipedia says true so this is how a
police gatekeeper it's very awesome this
is how I see it does not computer savvy
to go and download an application bundle
off of a shady website you know that's
not so yeah it does help people but it's
really not so patrick moore will talk
about this in his hey peepers exposed
talk back in i don't know was like
twenty sixty or some point that i can go
over the details here so what does all
that doesn't protect on the bypass
gatekeeper so an application bubbles and
DG's downloaded or the browser and also
happen to change these at any time they
can they can do whatever they want
Sarah us
so if you use their little Banco
binaries that's my homeroom execute for
you download it you there's no gate
keeper check at all so that's why that's
that's what I use mostly if I get access
to a machine I just run amok oh so if
you have protect against nip bundles
that you download it over the browser
unless you sevens in so if you 7-zip if
but little via the browser will check
for that uses curl or double you get
underneath those and also refuse it you
know if you're fishing misty sticks and
using a half bumble there's been check
that I wouldn't use can somebody get
that board please take it yeah I
wouldn't use a half mumbles in general
if you're contesting just so this is
where I'm gonna make a detour and I got
nothing against the researcher that had
this part will come out but it ended up
in Wired and if you're gonna publish
something in Wired better bring it
so this came out two days ago it was a
talk that happened at virus the bulletin
and I don't really agree with concepts
I'm gonna tell you why and here we go
so there are three main points maca less
for Mac OS does not check code
signatures after first run Cottle
infection is new application should be
self checks to ensure no modification
those are the three main points where
each month
so with checking Co signatures after
first run and my response is so what and
this is only for application bundles
right see my prior slides and no they're
less does this right there's no security
checks on windows on a default installer
so this is kind of a non-issue and if
you do Co sign your checks it has to be
a binary load time where there's being
blase about it
and that it's really not severity
control so you're gonna have a race
condition and if you do it if you do it
it binder a little time and call this we
call it this thing called whitelist and
it's been around for a long time and you
can actually put your Mac and iOS move
right now with this command and only
Apple sign coke and rum from the App
Store
it's very capable if you do that I've
done it it's like oh my god so if you do
that and the reason that this was a
suggestion is because it needs to they
need for a B and there are at a virus
bullets in the conference and for a
virus anniversary so this is yeah anyway
file infection is new so thought that
she goes back to the games
I heard mamako for Mongo in 2006 ROYGBIV
which I'm sure is his real name age hero
method which is no longer usable because
of changes so 2006 2012 the section
reverser FG introduced a library
infection method and then myself
introduced a pretext infection method
and has been in the back row factory
since 2014 so it's definitely not and so
the next point was an application to
self checks to ensure no modification
just show his who thinks that's a really
good idea who think that who think
that's a bad idea
show hands okay those of you that are on
the fence or have done hands it's
generally not a good idea and you're
going to have race conditions unless
it's coming from the kernel
listen in the kernel that boo you're
going to race conditions and if I can
modify the fire age modify the checks
so this is part of a particle as a
result of this research you read himself
at a co-signature verification of my
wife Mac products so you're not before
me check every time they launch my
response and so I get back to my hotel
room at like 1:30 morning I'm like well
how long will it take me to bypass this
and take ten minutes just to show you
this and put this to rest all right so
on the right same times I've got the
attacker already on the left got the
attack on the dragging of the victim
we got the recent version of ice trial
and so so what I'm gonna do here is I'm
going to pop in this thing called
settings test into the sudden sentence
demon and I is the back door factory
patched version of itself it is not
signed and back row fact that runs
removes the code signature okay then I'm
going to kill the demon and then go to
settings and then you'll see that I get
a shell
and then you'll see that there's a self
check okay so now I'm going to confident
we're going back kill the process and
then I'm going to run back over factory
delicious anyway so I'm gonna execute
vector vector here and I'm so what I'm
matching here is they're real time
protection process I'm cashing the
process that ensures that it doesn't get
patched so I'm going to head over to the
workstation I'm just going to run a real
script that just does what I just showed
you just doesn't quickly and then you
see I got a red shell right eye and
you'll see that I didn't get any warning
this time because I read so I'm
researcher so I decide to contact that
about this bug and on February 2nd I
sent the initial sample that was not
self signed to Apple and I knew I would
get this response they said I need to do
this trick checking so then I provided
them a sample that bypassed their
recommendation and then they gave you
another recommendation and didn't solve
the issue and I told them how I would
address the issue and then they said
that all third-party developers have to
do this on their own and then we'll
update the documentation so it's not a
wonderful now I haven't found any real
security baton boundaries in their code
say yes they're vulnerable though if you
look at the system information at see
that this is my terminal at POC and it
says that it's signed by Apple now I
hope they're not making security
decisions from these information now but
so yeah so developer reactions were very
good this is one reaction
[Music]
I contacted served the Carnegie Mellon
and the blog post because we don't know
who's using this code sine cosine in the
API is eternally I'm sure people are
writing their own stop especially the
government and we had the public
disclosure and so this is their
documentation common API at the top
before and after
so this paragraph specifically I'm just
going to call out a sentence or two be
aware that the slices of the universal
binary don't have to be signed by the
same signer or the test pass one slice
might be at my side for example yes yeah
that's it so how do we that was all
basically all that was updated there was
another API that was updated but they do
the same thing one returns with errors
and one doesn't
so how do we do this correctly well
there's different ways you're a non
developer or if you're working from the
command line you use cosign you have to
specifically call in there Apple on the
app or the PID you can check in memory
or if you're doing Apple generic means
anything that is from a developer a
developer
from a developer coach has rooted or you
can use lipo that fun little tool again
to send them out the fat file barely
exists then pull out the 64-bit part
like out of login for example and then
you can check to make sure that they're
actually the same program because you
can make some mash different programs
together so free adulterers it's really
simple you just call this separate
partnered with stranding and then you
pass in your app or a deploy Ankur
Kotwal generic that you call this but
all of them and then you have to depend
on what you want to see like boysenberry
they have to break out you slice in the
fat file to ensure that they're by the
same signer and by increasing the
complexity there that doesn't so
penetration tester you're testing a
product either either internally as part
of a product about don't development
cycle or if you're testing against
anything to this code signing we have
some samples there ought to security
labs on github and you just download the
samples and test against the actual
product and all those samples should
come back has invalid so how do I find
us well I've been doing cocoa signing
stuff for a while I just from the nature
of writing the UM
so this was an interesting bug just
outside of resources and I kept talking
2016 about hiding the investigator and I
found a kind of a weird bug if I added
padding to these are the padding between
each motto is straight yours if you had
anything in there
could sign the air l you says something
happened sorry
so this maybe want to look at the
universal file from that a little bit
more teacher I knew that there were more
gloves you know in that area so fast
forward with urgency about almost two
years later I decided to look at this
again
and I for instance I put it back door in
Pearl and then I uploaded the virustotal
and I got it was in fat pile and I got
that it was signed by Apple I was like
holy crap so I knew I was kind of going
on the right track here
so I come around February 13th you know
I'm really really in a hurry what
actually happens that kid and I just
right after that so so one thing I
wanted to see if I can create a mouth to
chipsets
the same time and I was like can I use
and I really the you'll see that you
know as the area says they have the same
architectures generally if you have that
kind of error if something's trying to
hamstring
doing something to protect you you want
to look at you want to do that thing I'm
going to do that so I manually did it I
created a fat file that would do this
and then the loader the mock-up loader
fail okay then the next question was is
like how can I make this an execute
anyway I wanted to execute inter makes a
match and that's when I found that if I
changed the CPU types I can get code
execution and I have to be able to
create a malformed fat biology I was
quickly able to make a fat file bypass
and third-party developer code signing
checks by using their novel signed code
first
and everything else you see from the
earlier parts this talk so in conclusion
I encourage people to take a look at
code signing especially anywhere you see
buy any product it's a corset recon
construct based in math and it's
extremely complex I believe that more
third-party developers will make state
mistakes again especially since the
documentation is not very good so any
questions yes actually said oh yeah
right and journalists are too so value
from here okay we went back and forth on
Twitter
[Applause]
oh she's just so in your example that
you have to code segments for different
particle CPU architecture to each other
or yeah so I don't know if there's
eleven and if somebody wants to strip
that it would be fun that would be
really fun put like 300 ship set
architecture together palette types and
see what the loader does they need a
code execution on you 256 who knows the
other questions yes so if if your this
is Douglas 4-0 trust networks doesn't
like you're gonna have zero trust
networks you can't you need device trust
that means you have to have a high
percent accuracy that nothing there's no
malware on that device that can get like
session cookies up of the browser so you
need to have you need to have at least
some kind of code signing on that device
right it's 70 cents yeah and then you
also got that monitoring so I mean
include look at
and like what's the most secure devices
out there right now it's your Chrome OS
and iOS right because a horse goes
talking all the time unless you put it
like unless you put the Chrome OS in
developer mode but then if you look at
the monitoring on iOS and chrome iOS
devices it's not very good so it's kind
of a dick opposed any questions yes iOS
right now does it cuz I'm right now
that's I didn't just do hardware I mean
I think I think I mean I'm not an iOS
expert for this hardware is pretty no
there's a she's everything