check check check check check check okay
sorry for the sorry so sorry for the
delay ten minutes off my time but I'll
I'll just speed up in in the floral
thing so this is a invoke Empire dog
merging a bloodhound and Empire merging
bloodhound and Empire for enhanced Red
Team work anyway Lu
my name is a Sat processor born in
France living in Holland working in
Germany security consultant for er NW a
small family size company that does a
very big stuff okay my my part in this I
do mostly PowerShell automation and I
try to build tools or a little tooling
to assist customers and other stuff
alike so electronic music Photoshop and
there's a few in my deck Lego Tetris
that's for the kid in me the geek world
food first time there becomes speaker so
I'm very much stressed to be standing
here right now arlenian and yeah forever
noob also with the microphone with
everything like I said I'm French I
didn't have any Kiwi ones just a quick
word I know this is derbycon but we're
all into security one big family so I'm
just quickly reminding that troopers is
a the CFP CFT is open and where they see
are having a double active directory
track so if you have anything to submit
send it in come to Germany and
yeah better like this okay so last year
was a fantastic keynote by Matt Graber
where he told us to follow our shiny
objects so this year I decided to come
and show you mine these are my tools and
Allah I'll be presenting them today so
on the agenda so tools and demo it's
gonna be only tools and demo first tool
I'll be presenting is empire strike
which is a set of command leads to work
with the Empire then I'll be presenting
cypher talk a set of compiled command
leads to be working with them bloodhound
and finally Empire dog which kind of
automates on top of both of these these
modules why do I choose PowerShell
simply because it's a cross-platform
work with objects you can use the
pipeline I just love it so there's gonna
be a lot of PowerShell in here my hope
is like I know people are moving away
from the PowerShell tradecraft on the on
the system that being is being attacked
I still believe PowerShell to build your
own toolings on the side of the attacker
is a fantastic framework so this is my
my language of choice when I build tools
so let's get started empire an empire
strike so what is empire Empire is a
powershell and python post exploitation
framework and just to put it in a
context i guess you guys are all red
teamers or security people but just what
is supposed to exploitation basically
anything that happens after the exploit
and here you will see situational
awareness lateral movement privilege
escalation persistence data collection
and exfiltration so i mentioned this
because all the modules that you will
find an empire also sorted by these
categories so this is a handy way to
find your your your modules
features from empires so powershell
without power shell in memory execution
multiple communication profiles secure
communication cryptography and
everything more than 280 modules mostly
built
the community and I'll just mention one
that has been fully incorporated inside
is the obfuscation by Daniel Bohannon
and one day I would like actually is to
map all the all the modules to dat TN ck
framework so that you could like work
with all the all this at the same time
credits so always give credits to the
real real creators I just build my tool
on top but yeah harm joy has been a big
big inspiration for me and behind here
the shelf father or Geoffrey Snover is
also yeah the guy who laid the
foundation for pouch ah that's what it
looks like and I'm not gonna go too much
into Empire itself and I'll present now
Empire Strikes OH Empire strike is a set
of command leads to interact with one or
more Empire server via REST API so one
or more makes it actually quite flexible
and also you could be more users working
on the same server at the same time so
it becomes a team server basically these
are the commandlets you will find in in
this module so all of them start with
the invoke Empire as a lazy way it will
use the the verb in PowerShell but you
can remove all this and just use these
commands as alias so it's very quick at
the at the command line features who
will have full control via REST API
multiple session easy syntax and aliases
tab completion intelligence and of
course by planning good object output
and extensive help pages once I get to
fully write them basically they're not
fully there yet yeah this is something
also I submitted this talk and I thought
I would have more time to develop
everything I've had a busy summer so I'm
still struggling to follow captain Jesus
and harm Joy's development but I'm I'm
catching up so let's start with the
sorry the demo I'll show you some code
first so you know what's happening so
here can you all read I'm just defining
some some variables and then we're gonna
start the action so I make the in the
demo the computer will talk just to make
it a bit more interactive and here you
start to see the the Empire strike
commands in there just to show how how
easy would be for you to write your own
your own automations with all this so
what we're gonna do basically is connect
to the server create the listener copy a
staged route to the clipboard then I'm
gonna infect the target machine with
this listener as a way to simulate
phishing or any other type of foothold
once this is done we're gonna wait for
the agent when an agent come in we're
going to start a loop where the the
automation will check if this agent is
elevated and if not we'll Auto elevate
the agent and install persistence and
hand somewhere on the target machine so
the code is not that that complex if you
were to if you were to read it you see
so we say something we use a module here
we set an option for the listener we set
the option here we launch the strike and
we wait for the action so basically
these little five lines of code are all
you need to to automate it and if you
have like once you saw the demo maybe
you can go back to the code and you will
understand a bit more what it does
so I'm gonna comment so this is my
target machine this is my empire server
and you see for now no agent no listener
I'm just loading the module and then I'm
gonna run it as a script of course if
you were at the command line you could
do it I'm logging in the server and you
see on both screens so we're waiting for
the initial agent I'm gonna simulate
this in on the target machine by simply
pasting my stager and you're gonna see
immediately on the server on the side
that first agent comes in this was a
little attempting to elevate the agent
you see another agent calling in on the
server and you saw the screen flickering
on the target
I don't dare to touch anything because
so the persistence has been set up now
we're setting up handsome wear which is
just a wallpaper to simulate the effect
but could be any any other type and they
are they are they are quite handsomer
so now I'm stimulating a reboot just to
show that persistence was installed on
the target system and you should see a
new agent coming in on the server side
as we rebooted the machine right there
so here from from a server that had
nothing that no listener no agent we in
one hit of f5 we've set up the listener
get a stager in fact the target elevate
the initial agent installed persistence
and handsome we're without without the
hand so it's all automatable
and this is again just an example of
what you can do with it but all the
modules are accessible all the options
are set at all so it's a nice a nice way
I think
to control the the Empire server from
outside the next step for me on this
upgraded to Empire 3.0 which is already
in the planning I believe from zoar your
and all these guys make it PS core
compatible so that you can also use it
on your Linux or any box you're working
on basically write more command late and
eventually at some point write an
automation playbook so you will already
have recipes for basic repetitive action
you you do on the server do we have any
questions so far so the code will be up
during
the weekend I'm still updating a few
stuff last-minute I think like we all do
when we come to conference we like to
add features and break everything but
the code is on the way
now bloodhound and cipher dogs ohm
Empire is a real offensive framework for
yeah offensive operation bloodhound is
just here for situational awareness so
once you have your foot hole you can run
the in gesture collect all the data from
your active directory bring it back into
the server and use this as a base for
your your your operations basically the
background for bloodhound so it came
from I think well this quote from John
John Lambert Microsoft threat Intel
summarizes the the philosophy behind it
so defenders thinking list attacker
thinking graph and as long as this is
true
attackers win something like this I
think this was a foundation of blog post
that kind of like paved the way to to
bloodhound and yeah maybe a few beers
and they decided to go for it so what is
it it's a relationship graphing tool for
Active Directory objects now once you
said that you don't understand it much
more but what does it look like so here
you have a screenshot and let me make it
bigger you see all your objects or
groups users computers but also GPOs
and oh use and their relationship and
all this creates an attack path for for
the the right team credits so again harm
joy but this time he teamed up with
Waldo and Captain Jesus the bottom one
is a attackers thinking autographs
itself anyone
now what is cypher dog so cypher dog is
again a set of powershell commandlets
it's time to interact with the
bloodhound and we're going to be sending
cypher queries to the REST API so cypher
being the neo4j language that we use
under under the powershell commandlets
these are the commandlets you have
available in this module so I this time
used real verbs because I got a remark
from Jeffrey's Nova that I wasn't
following the best practices so they're
all change and it does make more sense
you know what you get you know what you
set so it's a bit more it says a bit
more than just invoke basically features
for this tool so we're controlled by our
REST API data database manipulation
commandlets and this is something that
Waldo touched a bit upon but making
hypotheses on your on your graph
changing a bit the relationship seeing
if you get less path so this is possible
with these commandlets and again easy
syntax tab-completion by plying objects
and help pages demo so this time I have
here my bloodhound so I have a sample
database inside that is completely
corrupted so it looks it looks very
strange Barry was for me to be able to
work on this so I hope this this will
work for you guys so if you simply say
bloodhound you will have out all your
commands and a little bit of explanation
then you can start looking at users for
example and he will spit out all the
users if you like it more in a table
format powershell lets you do this and
we're here dealing with the objects of
course so you could start manipulating
this object dot dot referencing the
properties and everything so that's your
list of users you can of course get a
single user if you like
and all the other types of note in the
exact exact same way so all your
computers your groups your GPOs your all
use they're all here with their with
their attributes basically now if you
were to search for a node you can you
always have to specify what type you're
searching for so node search and then
user computer group I took out all the
ticks so you can just simply write it
like plain English almost and here so
I'm returning a user that has server in
the name I can return a computer that
has server in the name more
interestingly you can get all the users
and return for example has s pn equals
true so it's pin users on the side of
computers you can filter by property
also so here for computer with
unconstrained delegation so it's a way
for you to quickly browse who your
objects in the database and grab them by
by property and in bulk basically
everything is pipeable so once you get
these objects i can pipe them to another
command to start something else edges
represent the relationship in the
database so here I'm asking for users
member of the group domain admin I get
the list of all the objects but I could
also simply measure them see that I have
13 of them and my favorite option in
this in this module is the dash cipher
so all the commands have a dash cipher
if you do this it show you it shows you
the cipher that it uses that it's going
to send it to the API at the same time
it puts it in your clipboard so if you
go back to bloodhound and you simply
paste it in in the query box you will
have the the graph of what you're
looking at so here of course I'm asking
for users so there there's no
relationship but you can use this -
cipher switch on all all your commands
and I'll show a bit more later here I
was asking for all the users member of
the group and I specify the group you
can of course do
the opposite and you are asking actually
a different question to the database so
here I'm asking for the groups where
this specific user HW at the main local
is a member of so the syntax is user HW
member of group and you get the group
C's member up this is awesome this has
been added by captain Jesus in the
latest release of bloodhound so all the
edges if you I'll show you here so any
any edge if you right-click on it has a
help well any not the one I chose here
there's one missing do you see that one
doesn't and here you you start to get a
bit of info on how you would you would
start to attack this edge or how you
would start to move along this edge with
the abuse in for the upset consideration
and the reference everything all of this
I have added also to the command line so
an operator could add the command lines
okay I have here member of how can I
attack this and you get the exact same
info that you would get on in the UI of
course you can query path and here it's
a very short path but from this user to
this group I can query the same paths
and specify I don't want no ACL and here
you see that this is actually giving me
a longer path very often the ACL path
shorten the the attack path so here by
asking without this here I get them oops
let me format this as a table so you see
it better so this is what a path would
look like at the command line and the ID
would be in a third module in the empire
dog module to have semi-automated way of
following this attack path by asking you
which module you would want to run for
each edge basically that's not develop
yet I can ask for a path I can show you
this one actually in the UI if you want
so it's a bit of like moving back and
forth but as soon as you say cypher you
can go back in the in the tab paste it
in and you get the equivalent of what we
saw in the command line we have the
equivalent here I do this so you see my
path here you can of course ask a path
to hear from this user to any group of
course he returns more paths if I ask
for it in the command line it will look
way nicer twink so this is where the the
bloodhound graph can sometimes become a
bit overwhelming and this is why having
it accessible in a command line to break
it down sometimes makes it easier to
read basically but this this graph here
is the equivalent of asking this query
here sorry oops
which is actually just a path from the
user to a group from h/w domain to any
without a cm yeah and I can do the
opposite and you're gonna see that it
looks like the opposite in a graph so
this time all the passed that add up to
the that finish on on the group that I
was targeting so from any to that group
or from that group to any queries have a
warpath have a direction so you need to
you need to respect that I am following
the idea of or the idea or the the the
supposition that member of has no cost
when you're attacking a path so I kind
of wanted to calculate the cost of an
attack path not only by counting the
amount of hops you would have to make to
get there because for me a hop of member
of has a cost of zero so this command
line here passed cheap is a is a
shortcut to not
not counting member of as one in the
cost and then he takes the cheapest and
what I do to get this is actually I
asked for the cheapest path and then I
expand the maximum distance and I asked
him for the cheapest even in a longer
one so as to be sure that you you do get
the cheapest path of all the
possibilities
sometimes a longer path could actually
be cheaper because it has more member of
in it so you can in this way you can
quickly quickly see which one would be
the easiest to follow another cool
feature cross-domain member will give
you all the members that member of a
group on one side and have access on the
other side so here I have two two
domains and you see that domain from
domain.com to BSC local account up
domain has a member of account operators
you can also extract metrics from the
database so here I'm asking for the top
top five admins in this in this network
and you see that my top and minutes FK
at domain and I could also ask what the
opposite so see all the other computers
that are admin administered by this dis
user so it's a very quick way to
navigate members of a group I can ask
them like this not very interesting this
here
Waldo IO is the the Waldo index oops and
while it does actually for a given group
it will calculate the amount of inbound
users so how many users have a path to
that group and what percentage is this
of the total amount of user of your
active directory and then outbound
computers so all these users can access
that group and from that group I can
access all these computers and you see
here that actually 65%
of my users can access a hundred percent
of the the computers I added here the
amount of hop the amount of computers
touched on the way and the cost of those
paths this is a quick way you can like
pass it all your groups and pipe it to
Waldo IO so you would have a report of
all the groups and their input/output in
your whole in your whole Active
Directory ok database manipulation so
I'm gonna go very quickly over this but
here I can create a user and properties
in one go I'll create Bob and Alice then
we can have a look at Bob in Alice and
they've just been created we can search
who has property of color blue for
example did that work nobody read Alice
yeah now I can update just a property
and see that now Alice is in blue so
another nice feature added in in the
framework is that if you take a user for
example you can add notes to this user
directly in the UI not if you're on a
dark theme you won't see it but it still
is it still is here the dark theme that
ash has white white letters in it so
what you can do in that case is simply
for example here add a note to the user
Alice and simply by adding the notes
which on your note user Alice query you
will get the notes back out of this user
the idea here is that you could
eventually execute commands and pipe the
output directly to the the node node
nodes if you wanted to for example to
keep track of your your activity so I
created those two notes I'm gonna create
an edge between them I'm gonna use the
owned edge this is just to show you the
the cipher that is behind it and now if
we check
which use our own user Bob you will see
that Alice comes out basically and you
could also request of course a path a
pass from Alice to Bob Alice owns Butler
so there's only one edge here another
interesting one so when you have a user
or group you can with a right click on
it you can mark as a high value and you
see the little diamond icon appears on
on this user you can do the same thing
from the command line and you could hear
do it at scale by passing it a full list
of user for example I'm just gonna mark
Alice as a high value and if I go back
in my UI
and I ask for Alice you see that oops
not sure I'm not getting the icon but
I'm getting the the little diamond I'm
just not getting the the user icon
anymore and then of course I'm gonna
delete those users I don't want to put
up my database and they're gone so it
tells me the Alice and Bob are not in
the valid list of users so that's that's
the IDB behind cipher dog I think
bloodhound is a fantastic platform for
like gathering all your your information
during the engagement and for me having
a command line tool to do this at scale
allows for very quick like if you have
to mark 10 users eyes high value in the
UI there's an amount of clicks that can
be skipped so that's the idea behind
behind all these all these commands I'm
really late so I'm gonna speed up sorry
cipher log so what's next keep up with
captain Jesus the guy's a really the
coding machine so yeah I spend my
weekends trying to understand what he do
and adapt also make it PS car compatible
I would like to make it Milty
servers so that you could have database
in different places and query them from
your from your command line without
having to switch the database in in the
bloodhound UI now last last bit so
empire dog which is simply like mixing
empire strike and cypher dog together a
set of powershell commandlets for empire
strike and cypher dog automation for now
I have only these but I'm writing more
at the moment dog map is a automated way
to map your Empire infrastructure in
bloodhound dog bark is a way to return
nodes and dog bite is a way to set the
target by specifying the bloodhound note
you set the target in Empire basically
features yeah that's what I just said so
to map Empire assets or to select a
agent by a no-name pipe agent output to
bloodhound note automate owned or high
value at scale and then later write more
offensive recipes a quick demo to finish
I'm not going to show you the source
code because I don't have time so I'm
just gonna do it like this and this is
where I'm gonna map and manipulate the
Empire so here I have only one target in
bloodhound and I ask for Empire map
showing me all my Empire I have nothing
here I have one server no agent no
listener I'm gonna create all this like
last time so simply log into it yeah you
show that there's no no listener for now
no agent for now then I'm gonna create a
listener I'm going to use HTTP create
with the default name at HTTP and you
see my listener as I started on the
server you can also see the little bits
of code coming in on the server side
I'm creating an age to become just to
have two listeners and now if I list you
see all my listeners and their name so
again it's just object you could tap
into any property and I'm gonna now dog
map so dog map will take all this data
from my Empire server and come and
import it into bloodhound so now if I
ask again for Empire strike you see my
infrastructure is starting to to be laid
out on on the graph here I can dark bark
dog bark session and it gives you the
session you have in your bloodhound or
map it gives you the listeners you have
I still have no agents so I'm gonna use
a multi launcher for the listener HTTP
I'm gonna generate a stager to my
clipboard I'm gonna go in fact the
target I suppose yep so this is the same
same setup than last time now you see
the the agent checked in so if I do
agent least I have my agent available
with all the properties I can execute a
command against this agent and this is
just to show that we return full objects
even though Empire would return strings
you can trick it to return a JSON string
and open it on the server side on your
side now napping it and you should see
my agent being added to the to the map
and the target he's running on that's my
agent now I'm gonna connect seconds to a
second server and that's this one here
we're already a listener and an agent
and agent to gain some time once this is
logged in I'm gonna map it into
bloodhound again
so he's basically querying Empire
getting all the objects and pushing
pushing them into bloodhound if I map
again you see that I now have my second
server or session with another listener
here now we're going back to a session
one I generate a stager from for that
listener I just created I have it in my
clipboard I go back to session 0 which
is the one you had an agent running on
on top and I execute my stager against
the agent that I have running on a
target now you see here on the server he
receives my command and on the other
side you will see a listener or an agent
checking in so I basically passed my
listener from one agent to another via
myself and if I map this again you will
see now that this there's a new agent
that's been created on the HTTP one
session this time so that's a simple
demo of what you can do with it but the
idea would be that you can fully
integrate them to one another basically
what next or more commandlets automation
playbook and documentation if I get time
where to get more info so on the
bloodhounds rack Jesus answers quicker
than Google so just do it the invite is
on the bottom if you're not there yeah
it's really a really a cool place with
more than 2,000 people chatting about
Red Team stuff so it's a cool place this
is where you will find the code again
probably by the end of the weekend it
will be uploaded or on there so the the
three modules
and I was about it for today
[Applause]
and just yeah