all right hey derbycon how's everybody
doing this morning all right well I want
to welcome you to Rai Satori OMG
or re IOT botnets oh my a little bit
about me I work on the threat Intel team
at netskope
right focus on IOT Linux and mobile
malware I'm recovering pentester I've
done everything from network on testing
to IOT software hardware and back-end
service testing today's agenda we're
gonna look at how mariah has been used
as a framework for IOT bot net authors
will take a look at three specific IOT
variances look at how each of them have
used Rai as a framework the base to
build upon and then also additional
Flair that they've added to make it
their own
next we'll look at tricks and techniques
you can use when analyzing IOT based
malware we'll talk about some best
practices around defending against IOT
bots and finally we'll open it up to any
questions you all may have then
obviously 2016 the internet was hit with
some high profile high-impact DDoS
attacks these DDoS attacks were
associated with Mariah Mariah targeted
IOT devices and some of you may be
asking what's Niall T device well I can
think of an IOT device as any system or
any hardware that's running an embedded
operating system that can send and
receive data on the network common IOT
devices that you'll see out there are IP
based cameras cable DSL modems and DVR
systems Mirai supported several
architectures such as arm MIPS x86 and
PowerPC the reason for this is because a
lot of these IOT devices have these
different chipsets not all of them are
based on arm not all of them have MIPS
or PowerPC NAM they're across the board
when Mirai came out it's a tag vector
was to use default
pencils and scan for telnet so what it
do its standing internet look for any
devices that would have telnet available
and then use a set list of default
credentials these default credentials
Community Network set from the factory
time when the user received the device
or even credentials that were hard coded
by support organizations such as you
know maybe your DSL modem your cable
modem may have a back door password on
there so they can get in to update any
firmware that type of stuff now we fast
forward to September of 2016
author of ride decides to hey I'm gonna
open source or release my code pretty
much talks about also kind of made fun
of people that were doing analysis on
the bot itself once you open sourced it
or released it are leaked it however you
want to look at it we started seeing
several variants come out based on my
here's the following graph of just a
year date of ingestion of different
types of variances that were based on
right you see several peaks and valleys
here when a new variant comes out that
adds additional functionality or as
additional attack vectors or implements
some sort of new IOT vulnerability has
been released examples are like a cheap
on exploit or the realtek sdk exploits
now that we have a kind
a background of moriah let's take a look
at three specific variances and how they
leverage Mariah has a framework and then
built upon it to add their own Flair the
first one take a look at it Satori
Satori Satori emerged in late 2017 since
then there have been several variances
of Satori analyzing Satori you can see
it heavily used Mirai as a framework
several functions map between the two
and we'll take a look at some of that
the original version used a default
credential scanner just like Mariah but
other variances of Satori then started
to implement other exploit techniques
such as remote codecs remote command
execution vulnerabilities and some other
ones which we'll dive a little bit
deeper into one cool thing about Satori
was it's the first bot to support the
arch architecture no other box so far
has come out and support that
architecture now I take a look at some
of the co-chair Annette Satori uses from
Mariah
this first example here figuration table
in there it stores information about
like where the CNC domain is or where
the CNC port is and these values are
stored if you look at the strings
they're stored obvi skated and we'll
look at that obviously a ssin technique
here in the minutes on the right hand
side view we see Satori's the pseudo
Satori's configuration file we see the
same type of function where we're adding
our table index we add our obviously
value and then the size and the length
of that value I talked about Halle
Satori and right obvi skates their
information we can see that they both
leverage the same function the original
Mariah's
table
it was used when the source was leased
that key is with you those strings but
use different keys so you weren't seeing
the same dead beef they may have used
different incantations of that but same
function very easy to figure out what
those encrypted or those ex-ored strings
were the reason for the XOR they've been
a couple of things one to bypass maybe
ids/ips types of situations or to make
it difficult for reversers or blue team
members just to be able to run strings
and figure out all I hear there's a
domain that it uses here's a port it
uses the later variances though satori
swapped out its XOR function for a bit
swap which you see the pseudocode here
so it swapped the bits and then it would
call this base64 encode or decode
function and it would encode or decode
the actual string itself and here's the
the base64 encode er or decoder and as
you can see I mean nothing special it's
nothing revolutionary just kind of
reusing basic techniques where I
originally used a telnet or you know
telnet scanner more or less then we'll
look for default credentials
satori did the same but then it kind of
upped its game by introducing IOT based
vulnerabilities such as the reach real
Tech SDK here's this assembly for a
variant that was leveraging this exploit
and here we can see the exploit and the
string being built for it if we take a
look at the payload itself we can see
what's actually going on of Satori and
run it on device similar Satori used the
Jeep on exploit same type of fashion
here's a mixed sample we can see the
string bean builds and if we look at the
payload we see the same type of and run
it last example here of vulnerability or
attack
that's a Tory added it's kind of one of
my favorites from late August timeframe
middle of August we saw a huge uptick in
scanning for work five five five five
and for those Android people out there
you know exactly what that port is
that's the ATD port so Satori would sit
there and scan the internet look for any
systems that had a DB open and then
would issue the following man to connect
to a DB and issue a request to download
a sample and run that sample so again
infect the device and add it to its
botnet so we can see here through the
evolution Satori the addition of new
techniques to gain access and building a
Pomeroy the next example I want to talk
about is omg omg was discovered in early
2018 another my base variant with cool
about Emmet oMG is the author's decided
to integrate proxy server for both HP
proxy and socks proxy into it and
similar to other variants it uses
default credentials if we simply run
strings on the binary we get a good
indication of maybe what proxy and me
run you can see here it's using three
proxy let's take a look at how oMG sets
up this proxy here's a function that was
inside oMG that actually gets the proxy
portion set up what it does it first
creates random ports for both the proxy
HTTP proxy and the socks proxy then it
goes through and tables and what this
does is it either enables or disables IP
tables on a device so that the botnet
author can connect to it and proxy
through it part of this function too
would also send information on what
ports those are - it's C and C so they
know which one to connect to and if we
look at the actually of IP tables
function we see how this is done how it
does that is it stores the IP tables
commands in a similar table figuration
file similar to Mirai
and it pulled that value out and then
substitutes it in in this
and then returns and called the command
to either enable or disable it based on
what's the c2s said and if we go look at
that configuration table we see the same
type of table setting where we have our
values here which are again obvious
gated and it uses that table to
reference where that information is and
pull it out and we can see the actual
ITP IP naval commander right here where
this one specific talks about dropping
the table so once it enable these ports
are disabled once enable the ports they
needed to set up the proxy we need to
get those ports listening on the system
and whatnot here's the function that
handle it we look at the function we can
see how it calls the proxy options use
these server options use along with the
cache server and so forth if we look at
the configuration file on github we can
see the exact same options here so we
can kind of get a good indication at the
author just quickly copy this over just
to get it up and running and get it out
there the last grant I want to look at
is called our re over re and wiki were
discovered in 2018 both were based on
Mariah or re is a funny store and we'll
get into it here in a minute our re
originally used the default credentials
similar to basic Mariah
then it was updated to include
additional command execution
vulnerabilities there's a version
variant called wiki that was discovered
and part of Wicked's main purpose in
life was to download copies over r-e so
it's a good indication that these two
families were tied together and wicked
targeted specific Netgear routers and
CCTV dvrs similar to Mirai owari used
the same
this setup versus just either
hard-coding both or just put them in a
configuration table who knows here's the
function that looks for the default
credentials we can see the ones that
were matched then it would move forth
from there so it used this until they
got some love on Twitter here's a post
that was put up pretty much making fun
of our poking at the fact that our are
used
you know old-school technique telnet in
response to this Twitter feed artists
Twitter post the authors introduced some
vulnerability the this CVE attack this
to gain access
as I said wicked was also associated
with our re here's a different exploits
that were used from wicked words and the
last one is kind of a funny thing the
vice know that it's been compromised so
we see the again storing the information
within the table uh now D skating it
right and out to the different portions
of the filesystem and then who will ask
we still see these attacks and they're
still going on they're not going away
they're not slowing down
we'll see seem variance using this
here's just an example of a point of
time in the beginning of August where
we're seeing traffic this is from our
honeypot
collecting data and people still use
telnet so now that we talked about all
these variances how do we analyze them
in a quick and efficient fashion from a
butenes perspective our goal is to
figure out what new functionality they
have what new exploits they have so we
can kick out our i/o sees as part of the
source that was released from Rai
there's a build script to make your life
easier in the build script there's a use
of strip and for those that are not
familiar with strip what it does is it
removes any type of symbols into binary
which makes it difficult to reverse and
when I say symbols it's stuff like
what's work is and stuff like that which
makes you have to go through and figure
out okay we're all these system calls
it's real a trace it so what you'll see
is you'll just see the basic assembly
you'll see a SVC 0 in the arm world and
then you'll see the variable that's
being passed to it to tell you what
system call is so you have to figure
that all by yourself but in some cases
Dafa gets lazy and just leaves full
symbols there so it's very easy to
figure out this blue team's perspective
or analyst perspective makes our life
really easy but what happens when you
don't have that you don't have these
symbols you get the script binary why
not use the source code the same way
that a botnet author does why not
leverage that to help us build
signatures to be able to quickly analyze
these variants to figure out what has
changed there's still tools I'm going to
talk about real quick here is the phoria
and rizal which allows us to quickly
analyze these samples and if authors are
here to wrote those thank you
the forea you can think up the phoria
has been DIF and there may get their
screenshots there you information about
what functions are there and kind of
like signatures are on those functions
then what you can do is apply it to your
stripped binary function Rizzo Rizzo's
another favorite tool mile of results
Rizal Bay builds like signatures and
that you can apply against stripped
binaries so a similar fashion you create
your arrival rate that's not earlier
build your version MRI for the
architecture you want to test rip or
analyze make sure you don't strip the
symbols then you use Rizzo to creates a
pattern file or a signature file here's
the stripped binary this is what we see
we see the functions over here there
aren't label just the default Ida
labeling we see the assembly nothing no
real good clues here you know a lot of
work to try to figure out some just the
basic functionality well once we apply
the original database and we start
seeing great information it's not a
hundred percent so you're not going to
get 100% one-to-one matches all the time
sometimes Rizzo or the foria messes up
and doesn't catch the right function so
a lot of times you just double check to
make sure but it does help reduce the
noise another example of you know using
red zone
phoria it's not just limited to Mirai
recently there's a new bot that came out
called Tori this bot was built off of
you Lipsy
so what we can do with the same type of
kind of ID in mine we can build a Rizal
file or a de Fora DIF database based off
a UMC and then apply that to the strip
version of Tori to help us identify
these common functions like memcache or
mem Alex so we don't have to sit there
and figure
oh well we see this type of pattern here
okay this has to be mem copy Satori and
D forea does a lot of heavy lifting for
us the fan against IOT BA saw what can
we do you know the help reduce the risk
of this from the manufacture side we can
start looking at doing code reviews make
sure to secure code reviews and security
assessments are being done against the
devices during development time not as
an afterthought or a bolt on that okay
we have the chipsets we have all this
stuff now let's do the security review
and we're kind of locked into using the
technology and the hardware from the
user side basic basic thing we can do is
change the password go away let's not
leave those default passwords admin
admin and let our devices be used as a
bot from an enterprise perspective if
we're using like DVRs or IP based
cameras let's do ingress egress
filtering you know simple things that we
can prevent anybody on the internet from
attacking there's no reason that anybody
on the internet should be able access my
DVR or my IP based camera and from users
perspective also we need to make sure
that we're applying or subscribing to
the manufacturers security updates and
once we get that message coming in we
need to apply those patches and make
sure that those devices are getting
passionate timely manner
so in summary IOT devices are not going
away nor our malware targeting them it
just because of the simple fact that how
many devices are out there it's a huge
footprint and it's a very juicy target
you know security around IOT is like
that of late 90s on PCs we see the same
type of issues that we saw back then we
see default credentials we see easy
command injection colder execution that
type of stuff you still see and from you
know a blue team perspective let's
leverage the source botnet authors are
doing it why can't
to help us reduce the time it takes to
analyze these things and pull off these
ilcs and lastly we should be thinking of
IOT devices the same as our PCs and our
servers they should be added to our
regular security testing you know any
type of network pen test or web app pen
test these device should be thrown in
there along with our regular patching
cycle I know most corporations have a
railer date where they're doing their
patches they're patching their Microsoft
systems are patching their applications
these IOT devices should be included
along with that packing cycle that's it
well thank you guys for coming I'll open
it up for any questions yes sir yeah
that's an interesting question I've
thought about is actually attacking um
not only that since you have the source
Mariah also have the CNC server
reviewing a CNC server see if there's
any volunteers there and attacking the
C&C server and taking it over and
shutting it down that way so there's a
lot of these bots I mean the authors are
not I would say the most
security-conscious coders so yeah
there's a lot of bugs in them that we
can leverage from a blue team
perspective to you know either use those
to shut them down or whatnot but that's
one of those things you need to probably
talk to your legal group no problem
anybody else any questions all right
I'll be here for the rest of the con
thank you guys
[Applause]