okay hello my name is Nick if all name
is Nick Stevens uh I'm gonna be talking
about a number of trust zone bugs in
Huawei phones also just normal Huawei
kernel bugs if you don't know what
Huawei is it's okay I'm gonna talk about
in just a second I also want to briefly
apologize for the the program just has
my bio as the description of this talk
I'm not gonna be talking about myself
I'm gonna be talking about actual
technical work so I'm sorry if anyone's
confused by that I don't know how that
happened
so the first little bit about me i play
on the shellfish etf team from familiar
with CTF it stands for capture the flag
it's like a hacking competition but more
focused on actual exploit development
and software vulnerability finding
unless so about like a pen testing I
also worked on the cyber brain challenge
which is another thing that's similar to
a CTF but it was run by DARPA which is
the defense advanced research programs
agency or something they ran a
competition to see who could write an
automated hacking tool tool I could find
bugs automatically and automatically
where exploits for the bugs it found so
it was sort of called the self-driving
car equivalent of hacking so it worked a
lot on that with shellfish as well and
then also we publish a number of
research papers on subjects like
automated bug finding and automating
exploitation and also I published in
papers on Android bugs and just trust
them bugs in general and the kind of
problems that trustzone
introduced and I'm in familiar with any
of these things like trust owned I'm
gonna be talking about them and
introducing them to you in general just
played a lot of CTF and now I currently
work for Rieti on CSI as a vulnerability
researcher you may have actually heard
of us before we used to go by that law
different names such as breaking on si
Gove's and recount COI and now it's si
si you can just call it Raytheon
and I do this kind of work for a living
them at present if you're interested
please let me know we're always hiring
so first of all the goal of this talk is
to demonstrate a way to completely
compromise the huawei p9 now the what
wall way is a Chinese phone manufacturer
they're not very popular in the States
so if you haven't heard of them don't
worry they actually have a very
difficult time entering the US market
because of natural national security
concerns they're all you can find them
in the news about once a year they often
get in trouble but besides leaking
phones what they also do is they'll make
network equipment and sell that to other
countries that the u.s. finds unsavory
now this is a pretty interesting target
because they don't actually see as much
public scrutiny so I decided to look for
bugs in it as an exercise so what we're
going to do is going to start from an
untrusted app on your phone and
completely compromise something called
the t twe which stands for the trusted
execution environment now this is
actually a special operating context on
your phone that meaningful don't know
about it's it's pretty different than
what most of my familiar with when it
comes to security architectures and it's
between link ring zero and ring one ring
three excuse me but because of the
number of sensitive operations that take
place on our smart phones are armed in
particular and mobile manufacturers that
general have introduced more security
mitigations to stop roots from being
able to completely steal all your
information so all your sensitive
fingerprint data is actually stored in
the T on an Android phone and Huawei
store has a fingerprint agents which
we'll get to in a minute and tell you
how that works and just for a background
an untrusted app and in this context is
an app you just install off your phone
from the Play Store I assume that it has
no special permissions you know
oftentimes you someone snappin for you
guys have seen it asking for like access
to logs or contacts so none of that has
been enabled and if you're no Android at
all you also know the untrusted app is
the name of the selinux context which in
half is installed for so it's a bit a
little bit in a sandbox so we're going
to be starting from that sandbox so
I had talked about the new security
maintenance this is kind of what it
looks like broken down into different
trust boundaries so on Android you have
your your four components all right
you have your normal user land where all
your apps with is exception level zero
and there's another tacos interaction
went over the armed exception levels
these are kind of like rings and then
you have exception level one which is
your kernel which Android is kind of
like a modified version of Linux there's
a few lines added in networking and
other things to enable certain Android
security paradigms but then there's sort
of this shadow world that the T
implements which has its own user land
and kernel land and its own usual and it
has trusted apps which have the secure
Stormin secure storage secure payment
has the biometric sensors like the
fingerprint implements things like DRM
things that we don't want our kernel to
have access to so hypothetically the
kernel should never have any insight
into the trusted apps even if you root
your phone everything in the blue box
should be out of bounds for the kernel
of course it can communicate with this
world but otherwise would be useless but
it doesn't have direct access to the
apps running it like it does for apps
like Chrome or the Play Store and then
finally to support all these
applications in the security l0 or the
trusted apps we need another kernel
which can do things like load apps map
and memory and support things like IPC
so here's how the expla is going to work
in general uses a road map we're going
to start executing code in use rule in
so that's the assumption is every day of
code execution on the phone that's kind
of a big assumption I know but just for
academic person purposes just please
accept it
people do have found bugs and things at
Google Chrome and Google Hangouts so
it's you can't imagine that if you want
to step further you do spaghetti
executing code in Chrome or hangouts or
a bug through one of those and then you
can begin at the stage of this talk so
from usual end we're going to find a bug
in the kernel and Huawei's kernel and
we're going to exploit that that will be
a traditional route that's just two bugs
that I use of an exploit to get root on
the phone and then once we get rid of
the phone
we're going to take advantage of the
privileges that that gets us to find a
bug and trusted app and then we're going
to get code execution and one of the
trusted applications from the trust more
in the trusted applications we're going
to then go one sit further in filing a
code execution in the actual kernel the
TOS and with the tos code execution
we're gonna be able to find this
fingerprint sensor app so it's another
application that I actually didn't have
access to and I'll talk a little bit
that later we're gonna find this
application and patch it to accept any
fingerprint so a little bit about more
about Huawei the team presentation is
actually entirely depends on your chips
and manufacturer so Qualcomm has their
own tea in Huawei also has their own tea
now Huawei phones very own which chips
that they actually use and this has
something to do with like I think
certain like baseband or cell phone
stuff they don't really know that much
about but people are so many factors
will sometimes have their own ship set
that they develop and sometimes they'll
swap them around so there are a number
wall in phones with Qualcomm but wall
way also has their own ships and
manufacturer called high silicon which I
think they acquired in 2010 this is is a
Chinese chip manufacturer that they now
own and they now make the kerydin chip
series which a lot of Huawei phones now
use but still not all so the bugs that
must discuss all affect the Korean chip
Series and they've actually all been
disclosed as well this is a disclaimer
and they do not affect all Android
phones by any means just huawei phones
so the huawei trusted architecture kinda
looks like this now the reason is is
there's a fundamental question to answer
is how does a normal app actually start
communicating with the trust own and get
anything meaningful out of it now the
first thing that we need to know is how
does the new world begin talking to it
how does the kernel talk to the trust
zone and there's a special privilege
instruction known as SMC I believe the
stands for secure monitor call that the
only the kernel can issue to actually
make a request and interrupt the trust
own kernel so to handle this
Huawei
and a number of other transit
manufacturers that have their own team
have a kernel driver which takes
requests from user land and will issue
this SMC instruction on their behalf now
it gets kind of complicated because the
curl driver often wants to have some
form of session management between
itself and the trust let's that talks to
so wall way an intent to be secured
actually has a number of these trustless
on the right implement their own form of
credential tracking so secure storage
can only be spoken to by my file
management application other
applications should not be allowed to
make requests to it mighty a fingerprint
trust it should only be spoken do by
fingerprint D the fingerprint daemon so
the kernel driver is going to be passing
credentials up to all these different
trust le'ts and then those trusses in
turn and me checking this credentials
make sure they're correct but until we
compromise the kernel bra can be able to
forge any of those credentials so once
we have chrome code execution and
control the kernel driver all of those
trust lets or many of them are going to
be off limits now for an app to log in
what it has to do is talk to a user land
program then it's TCD the T connection
daemon I believe is what it stands for I
don't actually know so it will actually
make open up a UNIX domain socket to
this this daemon and once it opens up
that socket the daemon is going to read
off the credentials from the socket this
is something you can do in UNIX you can
get I think the UID in the pit of your
connector or your client and then it
will use that to look up actually which
application itself is making the request
and then it will make my octal to the
kernel driver file descriptors that it
has open this is kind of complicated I'm
sorry and it will do the login ion tools
once it has logged in and there's no way
to log out once it has logged in the TCD
will take that logs in final descriptor
and send it back to the android app
through C message which is another thing
you can do interestingly in UNIX you can
or passing space systems the links in
particular you can send file descriptors
over an X domain socket yes being on a C
message so now our Android app has this
file descriptor to the trustzone driver
and it can make I off
like you normally went to a driver to
make requests and it can send parameters
up and so forth
and one more simple step and I've
already kind of talked about this the
trusses of course can talk to the
colonel but while we call is a trusted
core and it does that through normal
system calls like a normal user line app
is so this is sort of the entire map of
how things are communicating back and
forth in a huawei's system now we're in
Trump right into the bugs and these are
all very memory corruption and focused
so I'm going to assume a little bit of
knowledge based off like security
mitigations from memory corruption types
of bugs are things like a to law or
buffer overflows and out-of-bounds bugs
and what you can do with those I will
try to go over the best as a can though
so the first thing we do is sticking in
the trustzone domain is we're gonna
target the actual kernel driver itself
there are two vulnerabilities and the
kernel driver which will allow us to
actually get code execution in the
kernel
so I've kind of already went over the
responsibilities of the trust own driver
but something I need to mention quickly
is that and this is going to relate
directly to the vulnerabilities is that
the sanitization of parameters is
handled entirely by the kernel driver -
and this is where the books come up so
our driver needs to be able to handle
sanitizing complicated data structures
like memory buffers as well as integer
values introduces some complicated but
the buffers are once a sanitized as
those and see realises them it's going
to be sending this up to trustless that
it chooses and the trust lets will then
act on those and that's how the
communication will occur so a little bit
about how the normal world and the
trusted core agree on things like memory
buffers so the normal world is often
going to want to send up memory to the
to destination trust let's now there's a
fundamental problem here in that the
trusted core the gnomon willecombe don't
have a lot in common by nature of this
design so your normal call has no
insight into the trusted apps that are
running and that's the way it's supposed
to be for security reasons so what
happens is the small song-and-dance
where the trusted core has a virtual
address space but it's actually
one-to-one with the physical address
space so all
the virtual addresses that exist in the
trusted core are actually the exact same
the values of those addresses are the X
aim the physical address is values so
this becomes complicated because trusses
themselves don't actually all follow
this rule they're mapped into their own
virtual address space and one of the
reasons they do this is so trust more
security via a SLR which is address
based layout randomization it's a pretty
standard way of making an attackers life
more difficult so what has to happen is
the normal kernel now has to look up
physical addresses of any buffers that
it wants to pass in to the trust let's
and it has to send those up to the
trusted core and once it has a physical
address of trusted core can say oh I
understand physical addresses as well I
will take this physical address all
mapping into this destination trust lit
and now your destination trust lit can
access it because I know about the trust
let's page tables I can modify them as I
like so this introduces our first
problem where during the during the
process of actually creating this
physical address we have a pretty severe
out of bounds right so well not our
minds right but an out of bounds bug so
if I want to set up a memory reference
or a buffer I'm gonna be sending up a
virtual address up into the kernel now
it needs to immediately translate this
to a physical address
but for some reason why we also include
the option to specify an offset and
since memory reference and they never
check this offset so what I can do is I
can give it a kernel address and I can
give it an arbitrary offset of 32 bits
and now I can do an out-of-bounds and
access and specify a different physical
page which doesn't actually exist in my
address space and just for those who are
curious the kernel of course I don't
control so as you see it's iterating
over this linked list it's going to
ensure that I in my own user land
process register pages and say these are
usually on pages which I'm going to pass
the trust zone and when I pass up an
address it must exist in this list and
then it will use the correlating kernel
address which is aware of as one of the
operands to that addition so this allows
us to specify an arbitrary physical page
to pass up
and now once we colonel pass up the
physical page the trust doesn't know any
better it doesn't keep equality
theoretically Kuya doesn't actually keep
track of the normal world page tables so
this will create an issue where trestles
will begin operating on memory which
actually exists into the kernel or
belong to the kernel and not to usually
an app which is making the request which
is a pretty severe vulnerability so as
you can see we can pass any physical
address of any page map in and we'll use
this too right now this becomes more
complicated because I would also like a
leak before I do the write in the kernel
so I know precisely what I want to write
over now here's a slightly more
interesting bug in my opinion this is
sort of a design flaw wall way since I
didn't actually know this subsystem very
well so drivers can implement a number
of different system calls when they are
being operated on as a file descriptor
and such as open and close and they also
can implement on map now while they're
on an app and in fact this is how you
register pages that get added to the
link list as I showed you earlier
you say I want to and map this page that
I'll eventually want to send it to the
trust zone and what they do is you call
mmm they call a currently pad called get
free pages this is kind of
self-explanatory it's a number of four
physical pages they bind those physical
pages to the virtual address that the
Linux of system created for it and then
adds it to the linked list as we saw now
the big problem is they had no idea how
to actually clean up it's no operation
so how do you clean up a lot people
don't know how to actually clean up a
map page by a custom Linux kernel driver
so their solution was to implement in a
octal as you see here something the
aisle is implemented don't familiar with
a octal it's just a very it's a system
call where you can send custom commands
to a driver so you give it an integer
value and then the driver will say I
know how to handle this command idx and
it'll have special voucher for handling
it so now they have a case called shared
memory lease now there is a way to
actually do this safely but the problem
with implementing it as an ion tool is
that you're not actually talking to the
rest of the Linux subsystem which is
responsible for managing this virtual
page so what it does is
is the tea CNS your memory release will
actually free those physical pages but
because it actually never bothers to
talk to the rest of the Linux virtual
memory subsystem it never actually
cleans up the page table so what you
have in your Uslan process is a virtual
memory mapping which now exists are now
correlates to and points to a free
physical page so what happens when I
free a physical page in the kernel is it
gets added to a list of free pages and
this is very basic explanation of it it
as a free list of pages in the kernel
and then when another application or the
kernel itself wants to allocate more
memory the curl will say I had this list
of free pages you can just take this one
so what we can do is we can allocate
memory in our user land process we can
via the M map then we can issue the eye
octal to free it we still have that
virtual memory page lying around and
then we can create a bunch of requests
and ask the kernel to allocate more
memory for us you know for example
eye-opening files the kernel will have
to open so many files and eventually
we'll need a physical page of its own
and at that point it's when I take the
physical page which is still bound to
our virtual memory map inside of Uslan
process and the kernel will begin
essentially allocating kernel data
structures inside our user lim process
which is another giant issue and you
could use this for a lot more leveling
purposes I just use it for leaking but
this is a pretty interesting bug I think
it's the first physical page you set for
free I've ever seen
so that can cause some havoc and that's
pretty fun so as I say with some kernel
spring we can get to Colonel -
structures and get a leak and in
particular I'm gonna show you how I
exploited this so there's lots of ways
to do this with an arbitrary write this
is just the way I chose so I wanted to
overwrite a file operations boring table
so a little bit about files how files
are implemented in Linux and UNIX
systems in general I'm sure many people
are familiar with the file descriptor
it's sort of an opaque number which
represents a more complicated structure
in the kernel so when I open a file I
have the file descriptor and that
correlates to this Jolyon structure that
the kernel has in its own memory space
which has this file operations pointer
table which is you can think it's kind
of like a c++ v table it's
way to kind of do object-oriented like
things by essentially allowing you to
overload a lot of different operations
so the way a file descriptor in Linux
can do so many different things as we
know file descriptors can be a socket or
it can be a file of many different kinds
of formats is that uses this file
operations table to implement all sorts
of different methods I also contains
things you'd expect the file to maintain
or the Carleton maintain like an offset
and the permissions the file was opened
with so for example if we opened a file
on a normal system we're gonna have our
operations two pointer table like X T
for read by octal and L seek but we want
to do is overwrite that file operations
pointer table and point it at a rock
gadget pointer table which will do nasty
things for us so for those unfamiliar
blob stands for return oriented
programming it's a way of bypassing NX
which is a non non-executable memory so
just because we can't introduce
executable code into the kernel we can
reuse the code that is just in the
kernel to do things we would like like
for example I have two examples of Rob
gadgets here I have a write gadget which
will take whatever in x1 and write it 2
X 2 these are our 64 registers and then
return and I have a leap gadget which
will load from load the value that x1
represents has an address and populate
x0 with it and then return and x0 is the
return value in arm so if you have x0
returns that's the value that L seek for
example when you're turning so what I
can do once they set up this fake table
is I can say L seek to this address and
then the return value of else equal I
should be the value of that address and
not what has actually been L synced so
to redirect the al-hafiz table we just
need missing one piece we have this
arbitrary right but we need a component
in the trust zone which will actually do
the right so here I actually have a
screencap of IDA so as I said the t's
completely proprietary the chipset
manufacturers have no obligation to
open-source any of this so if you want
to start looking for bugs in your trust
zone you have to begin reversing it I
was lucky enough to afford a deacon
which not everyone has the privilege to
do but this is what it looks like it's
very nice so the first thing that I
found that did this is an interesting
global command that anyone can actually
talk to the requests in the trust zone
which is a command ID need load app now
this is kind of a weird function which
will tell you if you need to load an app
or not into the truss zone so I will
give it a UUID which Huawei uses as a
way to recognize individual trust lids
so each Russell has a new UID and their
trust trust zone kernel will tell me is
this UUID loaded if it's not it will say
yes you need to load this app I'm going
to write a 1 back into your buffer if
you don't need to load the app then I'm
gonna write a 0 back into your buffer so
what I can do is I can point this buffer
as I you know my control I could point
that any physical page I like I'm gonna
point that at my f off stable that I
want to overwrite I'm gonna begin
writing a 1 or a 0 there so I have
essentially an arbitrary write 1 or
write 0 actually becomes a right one
because these are uu IDs of values I
don't know about and I can't control the
value of what I want to write to so I
have an arbitrary right one now how do
you with the ability to write a 3
two-bit one anywhere in kernel memory
how do you exploit the state code
execution so I was really fortunate I
could trigger this as many times as I
like so what I did is I took this a
while operation spoil your table as you
can see at the top we have this kernel
pointer which is pointing to an existing
ext4 file operations table and I
overwrite it piece by piece with little
endian ones to shrink it into an address
that points into user land so I can
never write the very first four bytes
and make that into a 1 now the interest
is much smaller then I can overwrite the
next 3 bytes and I can make that into a
1 over writing the original one that I
placed and then I can sort of even it
out so this third transition actually
isn't legal I can't map that page it's
too low there's an min requirement which
stops and all the reference bugs for
being exploited so I need to write
another one to bring that up to a more
manageable address that I can actually
map into my new client process and at
this point we've actually now pointed an
existing ext file operation pointer
table into user land so now whenever I
want to make
or writes that write or read from that
file or LC con it it's going to be using
my file operations table and use rule
and memory to figure out where those
functions are implemented so I have code
execution in the kernel now so with the
rocket just I showed you I can now
overwrite my cred structure if you're
not familiar with Linux kernel
exploitation that's okay
I now have ultra me too right so what I
can do is just say my UID is now zero
essentially and that makes me route so
now with root we still have two more
stages to go so I hope you're not bored
so these are a little bit less painful
so the we need to now own a trust lit
and in this case we're going to be
owning something known as a secure
storage trust lit this is what's
responsible for transparently encrypting
files on disk so not all phones actually
offer this but Huawei has a special safe
feature that they offer where you can
centrally say I have these files you
need to put them in a special place and
the way is going to handle this is it's
going to pass the content of this file
to the secure storage file trust lit and
it's going to be encrypting them with a
key that your kernel has no idea about
so theoretically this means that even if
your phone is free to buy a malicious
actor all the finals you point you're
safe are absolutely safe because they
have no way of finding that key now
unfortunately the secure storage trust
was actually riddled with bugs so it
doesn't really matter
now there's one big type confusion here
and to talk about that I'm gonna have to
talk about look back and see the
sanitization so the way they actually
handle the sanitization of these
different parameter types isn't that
complicated
to have a union which means they
essentially have a data type that can be
one of two things and they have a Union
which can handle either values or memory
references now a memory reference has
the buffer in size and you might expect
and the Union just has two engineers and
you can pass up I imagine it's two just
because the buffer it's memory reference
it has two values but you can pass them
an A and a B now the unit weight should
actually distinguish between these kinds
of parameter types because it isn't
Union there's no me to type track this
and so when they're actually passing up
this payload to the trust lit they say
I'm gonna have four parameters which can
be either a value or MMF but just so you
can tell the difference between these
two I'm gonna have an integer which can
support type checking for four different
parameters so every single bite of that
unsigned int will represent the type of
each four of each of the four parameters
now unfortunately they never actually
checked per M types so I can create a
secure storage file and the secure
storage file is actually kind of like a
POSIX API I can say I want to open the
file and then it will hand me back an
opaque file descriptor or a final handle
which I can say I want to read or write
from so I can open up the secure storage
file keep in mind I have kernel Co
solutions so I can now log into this
trust lit and begin interacting with
this API and then I can assume I can
tell it that when I want to read from it
I'm going to give you a an integer as
your buffer argument and since it never
actually checks those params integer
will now be used as the buffer and this
essentially prevents them from being
able to type check and make sure that
the buffer address is actually pointing
to a valid region so what this causes is
essentially me to read or write to any
place in the trust itself now the way
this so to give you an analogy of this
is to be similar to if you had a Lynx
kernel or any kernel that never actually
checked the user land pointers that you
passed in so when I say I want to read
from the to this address
what it's going to do is when you say
the buffer that you want to read into
must exist in user land it cannot exist
in kernel land it's going to check that
against some boundary between your user
land and your kernel now that track
never occurs so what we can do is we can
just read data back into the trust
itself and overwrite its function
pointers or we can write data out of the
trust and leek values from within side
of it
so how do we actually exploit this and
this is a different kind of file format
it's not it like a it's not your typical
form of a process in memory it's all
existing and we're operating context
so I was super versing I found this team
Alec which is hi self-explanatory now it
uses a table of function pointers to
implement different size classes of
requests so what I can do as long as I
can overwrite one of these pointers with
my read am i right I can actually get a
PC program counter control when I caused
a malloc request to be made now there's
one small problem and like I said I have
no idea how this is actually mapped out
through a lot of painful experimentation
I found that that there's this very
weird address space layout of a trust
lit so if you remember the memory
reference that I talked about earlier
they had this interesting thing where
they would have to remap buffers in my
user land process wanted to pass up into
the trust lit now it turns out that
these memory references that are
remapped in the trust was address space
for actually readwrite executable so
this violates the property of NX I
essentially have all these buffers which
I control which have both writable and
executable memory so what this means is
that I can point any of these T malloc
function pointers up into my memory
references and my fourth parameter to my
trusted call can be my shell code and
that makes expedition very simple so
then as soon as I get that email and
call and go can I do my reason my rights
I can get code execution immediately and
have that trusted code execution and
begin writing my final stage payload
which executes or exploits the kernel
now this one small problem starting with
the p9 trusted loading actually
implemented a Salar which is the address
space layout randomization that I
mentioned so I don't know where the t
malloc address space is going to
actually lie but they only gave a solar
a single byte of entropy which makes it
very easy to brute-force so additionally
as soon as a trusted crashes is there
meant to be very robust they'll
immediately be loaded back up and
they're actually putting the same exact
address whichever originally load it
into so I'm most there's 256 guesses I
need to make to hit that trust lit but
even then there's another problem and
that root has access to all these
log files which just revealed the ASL
are out right so I can completely defeat
the trust Allah enlarges with route
because they log any crashes and I made
two tasks storage so if I find a single
Molony reference in any of these apps I
can link their aslr which is finding in
all the reference is pretty easy to do
in these applications so now we have
trusted code execution I have used the
leak to actually overwrite those
function pointers in T malloc now all I
need to do is find a bug in the huawei
trusted core itself in the kernel so a
little bit about what the trust own
kernel does responsibilities it has
again it provides IPC so actually when
I'm making a request through the kernel
to talk to a trusted this is actually
hitting the trusted core first so it can
remap as an Emory references but then
also it will dispatch the call to the
destination trust light it supports the
memory address translation process which
I just mentioned and it also has all the
trusts in its address space so once we
have trusted core access we can
hopefully find our fingerprint trust
light and do things to it like make it
accept any fingerprint now there's one
big moaner ability here which anyone
with kernel exploitation experience or
kernel security auditing will probably
familiar with and that is there's
absolutely no pointer sanitization so
every single system called deny pass up
they'll never check those pointer values
to make sure that they exist within just
a trust list address space now this is
partly I think because of this weird
issue where they're actually mapping the
trusted core into the middle of memory
instead of at the very top like you do
you seen a normal kernel for example a
Linux kernel you have all of your user
land apps in the bottom of memory at
lower addresses and then you have your
kernel at higher addresses and it makes
it very easy to check between legitimate
pointers to legitimate user land
pointers and kernel pointers but because
they have this trusted core in a weird
location it's not as easy for them to
make this check and I don't know what
rationally trust are doing it but it
causes problems so this means that I
to actually exploit the trusted core i
mostly seem to reverse-engineer the
kernel and find a strange sequence of
system calls which will give me a
magical right what where which is the
holy grail means I can write any value I
want to any address I want in the kernel
and that alone should be enough to get
me a code execution so a little bit
about the trusted core environment what
kind of security mitigation is we're
dealing with
there is no a SLR or I guess in this
case should be KS or are but there are
in this kind of country so they just set
up at no point in position there are
some functions which strangely do have
hard-coded balance tracks so mem copy
and said the trusted core does check to
see if it exists within those boundaries
but almost everything else does not
there is something something called pxn
which stands for page executes never
this is an armed mitigation which says
that I can't execute code in userspace
so back in the old days I used to be
able to put a shellcode payload
dimensional in process I would write a
function pointer over in the kernel and
I would just say execute my kernel
exploit payload and user lands and it
would oblige but it will no longer do
that arm has protections against that
there's also no pan or so I can't access
user space just fine so this is for page
access Denver if you're familiar with
these you might be familiar with their
x86 equivalents which are SMAP and SMAP
which are like supervisor mode access
protection and supervisor supervisor
mode execution protection these are
essentially equivalents so with the axis
never what what which should occur is
that if I ever want to access an address
and userland I have to go through a gate
first and the kernel will say ok I'm
gonna briefly turn off this mitigation
and do whatever access is uni on this
usually in structure but then
immediately return and make sure that
any other accesses violate so there's no
gate we have to go through which makes
it quite a bit easier to do exploitation
now there's also no DEP which stands for
data execution prevention this is
similar to right X or X which is you
can't have writable and executable
memory that exists at the same time so
this means that our kernel heap is
executable which makes it a great place
to store shellcode
now interestingly for a kernel with only
about nine different processes it
actually has about
different system calls now I don't know
why it needs so many system calls but I
suspect this is something do with Huawei
just completely ripping off another
real-time operating system kernel that
they found online that has all this
functionality they don't need so some of
these are also behind permission checks
which will stop us from having as large
of an attack servers as we would like
now there are a number of primitives in
here that exist for a different system
calls and this is a bit more of a
pedantic slide if you found the rest of
the talk pedantic this is going to be
really bad so there's no magical like
right arg1 to our Gojira call which is
what we'd want we would love to find a
system call which just would take our
first argument and write to whatever
address whatever pointer is in our zero
with argument or vice versa now we don't
have that but we do have other room
parameters so we can allocate a 16 byte
string we control and we can write the
pointer of that to the allocation
anywhere in the kernel that's pretty
nice
we can allocate an arbitrary science
kernel heat buffer and return this
address this doesn't sound very juicy
but it's actually pretty weird if you
imagine a Linux kernel system coal that
would allocate a kernel heat buffer and
then return that kernel intrastate user
land that's essentially the equivalent
you have that'd be very strange we can
also write an uncontrolled dynamic value
from a linked list into the kernel I
know that sounds odd but this can be
used to essentially use this at will so
once we can fill that linked list we can
write values anywhere we want now we can
also copy the trustus process name to an
arbitrary address this is not as nice as
it sounds because we can't change the
name of our trusted processes there's no
nice system call to do that or at least
one that I could not find and then we
have another bug which well via an
overflow this isn't good point player
sanitization we can get a leak so we can
have leak values from the kernel
arbitrarily okay so this is my most been
anything slide I'm not going to really
go over all this if you're curious I
suggest you talk to me about about it
before but we essentially do is allocate
a kernel buffer to store shellcode in we
leak the address of our process name
pointer so he has a a giant table of
string pointers we should have all other
processes name in it you find where that
exists
as we have that we're going to point
this linked list to a small snippet of
16 bytes we control so we control some
the linked list we're gonna point that
to our stack and then we can essentially
do is we're gonna continue to unlink
this list and get it to arbitrary writes
for us and then once we're doing those
on links from our stack we're going to
write kernel shellcode into that
criminal buffer that we just allocated
and then we're gonna overwrite a
function pointer in the huawei trusted
core which there are plenty of and we're
going to make that function pointer get
executed and as soon as that happens
we're gonna be executing trusted
shellcode now that I know that sounds
really exciting that pretty much means
were done there's actually one
interesting problem left and that's I
actually had no idea where the
fingerprint logic actually was so if you
take your trusted execution environment
OS image off the phone you're gonna get
this blob with about seven different or
six different else in it some of these
are kind of self-explanatory like your
key master and your secure storage but
there's nothing in there which looks
like a fingerprint module for one this
should be pretty large they're probably
larger than 100k fingerprint logic or if
you're protecting this is kind of
complex logic which will require some
form of like image recognition or image
matching so where is it so where I had
to do was follow the userland
fingerprint the around and see what kind
of stuff it was mapping now the reason
this is is to support for Android to
support so many different
implementations the way an OEM like
Huawei has to hook into this is they
need to provide a library that gets
loaded into fingerprint D that has an
API that it uses so there was an
interesting library called FBC tax
shared I think it stands for fingerprint
something tack trusted agent something I
don't know what the C is in either case
but it has this really interesting Blom
in it where it takes this hard-coded
paths with a UUID dot SEC and then it
calls TKE open session on that so this
is going to cause us to have well this
causes a lot of questions right what
what is this if you want to file on it
it's certainly not an elf and just as
data so this is actually encrypted trust
lit now why wall wave
need to encrypt this trust lid begs a
lot of questions about where while we
got this fingerprint tracking logic I
don't know I've heard from some people
they think it might be stolen which
would seem very likely to me but I don't
know it's just a rumor
now what do we do with with this so if
the trusted core code exec we can dump
the cripton memory so although it's
encrypted we can get around that because
we're figure we're checking to work the
code must be decrypted somewhere in
memory right
so we have the code execution actually
working what we can do is crawl the
address space and find any arm
instructions so it can be blindly going
through an entire address space as a
trusted colonel looking for arm
instructions and once we find some we're
going to be looking for string
references for things like fingerprint
and fingerprint dean FBC
and this very naive approach actually
worked in my case I was able to find the
fingerprint checking logic just via this
once I found fingerprint the fingerprint
D strings it'll crawl up and find the
elf header and then very gracefully just
extract the entire elf interestingly
enough when I pulled it out decrypted it
had symbols in it so it was very easy to
reverse I think there was actually a
function called identify image and that
logic was essentially just returned to 0
or 1 based off whether that was the
correct fingerprint so I just whipped up
about 3 different arm instructions to
null out that logic and write a 0 for
correct I don't know why this was
inverse but they said 0 was correct and
then return and once that Patrick heard
we were done that actually actually
finished it now that's essentially the
end of the slides but I have a demo
where I unlock the phone with my nose so
here he goes a first of all a little bit
of imitation wants to I don't like the
volunteer things I'm not gonna ask
anyone to come up but so as an example I
have the locked phone I'm sorry if it's
hard to see I can use my index finger to
unlock it ok I cannot use this index
finger to unlock it I know this isn't
very convincing but it's working so I
can't I can't use my nose either
it won't work now just a second now I'm
going to run the user the untrusted app
I have installed here alright it's
running it's not 100% reliable
okay oh just one more time it just
crashed so I have to write again this is
this is actually a this is not a
production piece of software this is
just proof of concept so one moment
luckily I still have about eight minutes
left in my talk so there's plenty of
time to see me unlock this with my
fingerprint or my nose okay hopefully
the second time is a charm
all right it's running okay I'm true not
even one second okay it worked this time
okay so it shows through the shellfish
logo which means it worked now okay lock
screen I'm gonna hold up to my nose
thank you yeah I hope everyone enjoyed
it and of course if anyone has any
questions feel free to ask them here or
after the talk and one small pitch like
I said I work for Raytheon CSI so if
you're interested in this kind of work
if you're sitting in reverse engineering
that's a job or writing X loses a job
we're looking for bugs as a job come
talk to me I know it seems like a crazy
thing but people do pay you to do that
so if you're interested please let me
know and yeah you can work for us okay
thank you any questions yeah you can all
right so the question was one time in
the trusted core can I essentially play
with the base man firmware the memory
and these things like glowy fuses now I
haven't played around with the e fuses
but you can read and write from the
basement memory that's flown in since it
exists at a physical address I think
that could differ depending on I
something I actually don't know that
much about
but I have played around with it on on
this Huawei phone and I was actually
able to read a memory out of there I
think it's scissor belong modem and
right to it as well so it is something
is interesting research introspection
technique that you could use yet any
other questions ok thank you everyone
[Applause]
[Music]