oh good morning everybody thanks for
showing up in finding him on a Sunday
morning
catching some records from Canada and
you all are welcome there any time me
can you hear me okay
is this better yes okay thank you
is that better
yeah okay all right um so I I'm very
proud to be part of the Diana initiative
we do an annual conference now to
support diversity women in tech and you
all are welcome to that as well
finally the views expressed here are
mine mine alone and not those of my
employer okay so why patchy because it's
a common pain point that we all share
it's also a necessary evil and it
happens to be a highly contentious and
sometimes a divisive issue for which
they just don't seem to be any easy
answers let's look back at 2017 what a
year first we had eternal blue we had
one a cry and then we had Apache struts
not once not twice but three times
moving into 2018 and right out of the
gate we have specter and meltdown Oh
what joy when was that dumpster fire hot
enough for you now on a serious note
learned some very hard lessons from
wanna cry about untouched systems and
vulnerable institutions like hospitals
that could literally be the death of us
because we don't have a good process in
place especially when ransomware comes
to shut you down does anybody go to
shmoop router has anybody been this year
Bruce Potter gave a rather eloquent rat
about the patching process it's not that
easy
but it is easy to throw that phrase
around why wouldn't you do it it's a
best practice but the problem is the
blame game isn't going to help us fix it
does anybody know Wendy Nader she is
very wise and have seen good things to
say over the years about the realities
of the patching processing business
inner costs and the kinds of decisions
you have to make the kind of decisions
that factor in a lot of things we don't
see
can't know about don't necessarily
understand and that really is what this
talk is addressing that patching is
about the stuff we don't know and that's
where we get caught up
these areas we don't have a molarity
with areas of specialization think I see
a hospital equipment and main phrase but
also older legacy systems stuff that
lives on for 20 and 30 years in a server
closet because if you shut it down a lot
of people are gonna stop working and
then there is going to be held equipment
and there just isn't anything else you
can do how do you fix that
patching inevitably just gets ranked up
with all of the other stuff Enterprise
has to deal with and the decision makers
have to contently they constantly get
shuffled down to the bottom of the deck
so you know you get that it is a
fundamental professed security caucus
but we keep getting frustrated by the
fact that it isn't getting done or
getting done right well here's them the
pain points it's true isn't it it it is
a convoluted process if you've tried to
sit down and figure out the instructions
sometimes those instructions just make
neato sense it's messy you can't get
somebody to take ownership on it
especially when something goes wrong and
you have a lack of accountability
because nobody really wants to hit the
thing they're playing point it on them
for doing the right thing we talked
about misconfigurations and if you've
been looking back at the year we've had
a series of misconfigurations
on major databases starting up they got
on seriously because settings were
misconfigured that's that's a people
problem that's something that we can
actually take ownership on
does it sound familiar
it feels a lot more like ongoing crisis
management only nobody wants to have to
take on the added burden of doing
process review
does anybody who wanted to process
review put up your hands
I could hire you three words yes we have
issues so survey says service has
patching sucks this is the realities
putting on instigate he did this survey
of what it takes to actually put a
patching process in place the number of
people this should come as no surprise
to us we know that we're out land and
I've done so I would say for us anyway
three words prioritize optimize and
automate only that's easier said than
done the good old days remember the good
old days when it was just all about
hatch Tuesday got ready for patched in
soon we had some tests and set up
everybody knew it was coming
not anymore now we've got staggered
releases we've got out of fan bases
we've got three views and we've got
something called super sevens does
anybody have a particular favorite of
those that they hate we've done a lot of
out of them uses so from an enterprise
perspective which comes down on our
shoulders how do we manage the downtime
with the uptime and then who has had the
joy of trying to identify what the
stakeholders are so that we can inform
the stakeholders so that he can get the
sign-off from the stakeholders and
circle around back to get everybody is
a week has passed quite honestly before
you actually get to do what you need to
do so we're damned if we do because yes
stuff goes wrong inspector and meltdown
I've lived through that put it in your
hands how many people had to deal with
the dumpster fire up Spectre meltdown
this year I will have sympathy cookies
for you and then we heard happy
don't yes um these seem worse than the
disease but wanna cry was the case in
point for everybody it was a huge
wake-up call especially for people who
thought they were adequately protected
because they're not not pet Ches circled
around and people found out they weren't
that passion might have thought you'd
applied wasn't there so based on what we
are learning how do we help
organizations to do this better how do
we make it a less bitter pill to swallow
so yes good patches do go bad things
will go wrong what we need is not just a
patching process but a process that
addresses what do we do when shit
happens okay um there are those patches
that go terribly horribly wrong forget
bad day some some people have bad years
I'm not gonna name and shame any vendors
but somebody's had a really bad year so
far and they're adapted security
appliance had was a critical pen for the
CVE and then the patching really didn't
go right only had to reissue it and then
some stuff got falling further down the
line and this is a case in point that
the people who we rely on can become our
biggest liability I'm not going to say
that it's anybody's fault it's that we
need to be prepared for the fact that
the stuff we rely on that is integral to
how we run our businesses
won't always work as planned you can
prepare for that you didn't necessarily
know to prepare for this 20 and 30 years
in the making system wide
vulnerabilities are another issue but
now we know that these actually exists
in that there are going to be more of
them
why because quite simply we did not know
then what we do know now that's pretty
much the thing we can extrapolate
further to all of the other things
systems that we rely on what might
potentially go wrong because of simply
ignorance around what we were going to
be using it for 30 years in the future
it's just a realistic thing do we have
backups in place
how have we tested those backups do we
have an alternate to do the backups in
place you know you hear stories about
people he discover that the tapes the
backups the systems when they run them
failed
that was a awful surprise but not one
they had to happen it comes down to the
price we were willing to pay the speed
and performance rather like a buy now
pay later plan accept we're getting
served the bill now and there's a
constant refrain in business because two
words innovation disruption everybody
wants to be the first to the finish line
so we kind of leave security behind in
the dust in order to make it there so I
would say you need to question the
process when doing things right gets
left out of the process oh my god IOT
yes this is going to be oh is that the
root of all evil why do we have to make
things that connect to everything but we
do this is our way of our life we are
constantly building stuff so that it
connects
and anything we build we could find a
way to connect it you need to go back
and find a way to make something that
was actually never meant to connect to
our systems to the Wi-Fi to the great
world beyond you get plugged in because
everything else does so we also deal
with the problem around basic good
procedures you know we know the hell
that passwords are but on IOT devices
passwords are a new special kind of hell
they're hard-coded you can't update
firmer
who here has tried to update firmware on
an IOT device a router or was it easy
okay for you it was easy but what did
you have and I'll buy it
picky people okay okay
for most people for our neighbors next
door changing the default setting on
their table TV box is hard trying to
update the router firmware for the small
office Home Office device is impossible
we have so many people with so many of
those issues to contend with the
Nintendo switch something that you want
to play with something that you want to
use at trying to update the firmware to
address of our ability was a major issue
that's my casing point
so let's talk a little bit about
specialized systems that are very
vulnerable ICS gator does anybody work
in that realm so I have a friend Chris
this drug he spoke here actually
yesterday it's an ongoing issue and
he'll talk about systems whether there's
first of all there's a very little
network monitoring and they need to
increase that because they're connecting
more systems but these systems were
designed 30 years ago with the intention
that they would not be connected they
were going to do one thing and one thing
only but they've been expanded now and
people are connecting them sometimes
because they hate it's a good idea
sometimes because somebody just needs
the convenience of having a connection
but a thirty-year-old system that's
often left untouched because they don't
want it to break this hugely vulnerable
these are our electricity this is our
power grids our water systems nuclear
power plants traffic lights so yes
operational technology something most of
us don't have molarity with and we need
to understand why they don't patch and
find a way to make it possible to work
with them understand where their
vulnerabilities are so that we can make
these inherently any secure connections
better medical devices we've heard some
horror stories about pacemakers and
insulin pumps again it's the same issue
these are very specialized components
and the testing on them needs to be done
in conjunction with what the needs of
the medical practitioners require and
not what the interest this is where the
butting of heads occurs it's hard
choices based on realistic issues there
are some great people doing some
fantastic work here so a shout out to
I'm the cavalry and Josh Corman Jelena
Audie and thanks to everybody who is
trying to make headway and raise
awareness about this particular
set of issues there was some frightening
statistics that came out in the
aftermath of wanna cry about the
national health services in England and
the reality about how many of these
hospitals simply are not in a position
to apply patches or update the operating
systems there's an opportunity if we can
find it to work with them to make this
better
alright does anybody work with
mainframes well again specialized
systems the concept of wall guarding the
thought that nobody is ever going to get
in these the realities with the mark
nobody touches the mainframe there it's
very coy stirred and very secured and
for the most part they are very secure
hugely fast reliable machines that they
do have vulnerabilities you do schedule
down times because if you don't an
unscheduled downtime for mainframe think
of a couple of days of not being able
access your money from the bank made a
couple of friends of mine here who
actually ran an evil mainframe course
about how you can hack a mainframe
because yes Virginia you can hack the
mainframe and sometimes you should to
test all right so how can we do this
better
there are ways caching doesn't have to
be the only option in this configuration
this is a fetch so if we look at things
like network network set up putting
basic practices locking down ports that
don't need to be open setting up
stronger firewall rules friend of mine
in in Coldwater gave an excellent talk
yesterday about how you can attack
kubernetes and she raised the exact same
issues about firewall settings
ports left open miss configuration items
that attackers find utilized to their
advantage
so testing and bull baths having backup
plans in place and knowing what to do
and how to use them it comes as part of
your disaster recovery plan usually but
a lot of places just pay lip service to
that if you test it regularly if you
know what it is and how to use it you
aren't going to find out on the day of
that it didn't work let's talk a little
bit about visibility being able to see
from end to end understanding all of the
things you have in play where they are
what they do and their priority do you
know what your crown jewels are do you
know where they're running do you know
who to go to to get answers on them when
stuff goes down because I can tell you
from experience when you get hit with a
critical vulnerability management
suddenly screaming and your asset
management program is not up to date
these are my five W's so as far as
mitigation scale yes you can have
virtual patches Tonya Jung has spoke
without them she does SEC DevOps but
since virtual patches are a great
mitigator if you aren't able to get in
there and fix spiritual on occasion
virtual firewalls bottom line cyber
security is not a band-aid solution what
we need to do is be able to work with
our organizations understanding their
objectives helping them understand what
we do and how we can work with them to
make things more secure we can identify
the pain point you can make for them a
business case to give us the resources
the funding and the cooperation we need
to do this better
because we want to help management get
the message they mean what we are the
ones to write any prescription for
passion and it's time for a second team
thank you all very much are there any
questions okay thanks again