ready okay so hello I am supposin Castro
and today I am going to share with you
our research I have made a Windows
persistence I have never read already
hijacking maintaining access on Windows
machines it's my first time there become
here so I am quite excited to be here
thank you I hope you all enjoy this so
it's about me I am an info SEC nerd
I like this ploy development I am a
Windows security enthusiast not an
expert in fact my first goal was 25
years ago and I am a Microsoft paint
artist as you can see here I am the
current technical research lead at CSL
apps that it's a company that work
mainly providing ethical hacking
services to organization working on the
financial sector I have been working on
the field as a red teamer mainly been a
span and pastor and researcher for above
6 years
ok this will be their quick agenda of
the talk I'll first expose the attack
and how it looks like I will be expose
the windows security architecture
related to the login process and here in
the hijacking they are ID I will point
out where exactly are the security
issues that make this attack possible
and after that a live demonstration of
attacking against a Windows 10 machine I
have related this morning I hope you
will work and some funny conclusions so
let's meet up they already hit you can
attack so what is this this is a new
post exploitation vector which is
reliable on all windows always version
since NT I have tested it from XP to
Windows 10 and Windows Server 2003 to
2012 it creates in stealthy access on
the target all by using only OS
resources meaning that no noise reactor
files are needed to take advantage take
advantage of the security some integrity
issues that I have found that are
exploitable with this attack it is
converted reliable on domain joint
machines but not owning controllers yet
I am working on a similar attack that
can be reliable on domain controllers
ensured this attack modifies their idea
of an existing account
sets it up to another one Jose they are
ID meaning that all the other account
properties as you see it with the user
such as buzzer Hajj account estate you
sub cetera keep consistent before and
after the attack by hijacking the
already at the exact moment the
privileges will be spoofed and one cool
thing is that no matter what they hijack
the county statistics is active for now
the hijacker account will retrieve its
privileges Essam so remember that only
the relative identifier is modified so
an attacker could log on with an ax
specific set of revenge else he already
owns and get access as another user
depending on configuration it would be
possible for him to access remotely via
RDP bsx second so on and besides the
privileges is still in the system will
register any operation which has taken
place during the hijacker session as
done by this poofed account and of
course this technique is reboot
persistent so this is how it looks like
in this image we are running a CMD as
the guest built-in account we can see
but see in the output of the Who am I
command we are still members of the
guest local group but we have widen
permissions over the system32 folder
which is pretty cool why I think so
understand the magic behind this I will
briefly explain how the windows logon
process works the thing is that I am NOT
that really good at prayer but well I'm
terrible
well I think that the windows
architecture is pretty similar to the
security concepts of some buildings I
have been on so you introduce yourself
in front of the guy who is in charge
then he verifies you if you are
registered in their database and we you
are then he provides you an access card
which permits you to get into the sounds
you are allowed to so let's assume that
they this green guy will be the
representation of the ministry or
building account this red girl will will
be our main character that will
represent an unprivileged account for
example the guest account and the butler
will represent the windows security and
this awfully build in the Windows OS
imagined are in image
that inside of this building there is an
RFID a light control system which is
based on the access card the blue guide
provide us to keep it simple I have to
run three floors I know there are a lot
of more privileges but that it's really
hard to draw em all and depending on
configuration of the access card user
users shall enter inside instead some
specific floors so this is the windows
security architecture in a more
technical way related to the logon
process but as you can see we are
ignoring the models related to the ad
authentication that's because the our ID
hijacking is focused takes advantage of
the way that windows handles the local
users local login process so we are
going to be focused on the LSA as as the
MSB 100 DLL and the some server deal in
a nutshell the logon task is like this
I'm sure many of you have seen this
before so when a new is worth in the
case through window go on LS a SSB
verify it's Residential's and creates an
access token to identify see security
context against the to defend a security
context and after that after creating
the access token it will verify these
access token against the objects the
user is trying to access by using their
own access control lists ok here is the
structure of the SE identifier that is
that is the way that Windows has to
define other way that Windows had to
identify security principles so such the
users groups or computers the first part
in yellow we can see here that is it's
the one which differentiates off the
machine our own domain among others but
the last one the relative identifier can
be the same across all machines for
example in every Windows machine as you
may know the 500 relative identifier is
associated with the administrator
built-in account so keep in mind that
every user account local user account
built in or not had has its own already
so let's suppose that the administrator
wants to log on so he provides its
username and password to win log on to
do that Windows need to initialize some
test and connection between processes
right after window go on Co slogan UI to
grab the crane
by using credential providers and with
this information we level we create and
unique Logan s ID to identify this logon
attempt and now window retrieve the
handle for an authentication package
which has which are used to identify
sorry the authentication policies of a
logon attempt remember that we are
focusing on the MSB one DLL of unleased
an elephant ocation package so we Logan
sends the authenticate to the whole
intent occasion package the username
password combination we created logon
sed and then this critical step the MSB
one sends the user password combination
to the Sam server which retrieves the
related security information including
the security the user community identity
and now - submitter up there as we want
to checks the information retrieved if
it is occasionally generates another
identifier called Lu it for the current
session and sends back to other
information to the LSAs s including this
new identifier all these data will be
used by the security reference monitor
to define the security context of the
user so we'll see that in shirt now that
everything is ok the city subsystem
proceeds to create the access token for
the recently authenticated user so the
access token is used to define the
security context of a process this
subject is created by the security
reference monitor for every user session
it's important to know that every child
process in heretical attacking copy of
their creators 1 meaning that every
process within a user session will be
executed with the same access token so
continuing with the authorization task
LS a SS receives the logon information
from MSB 1o and checks up its sound
database to determine the users allowed
access this check is done by using the
security identifier of the user right
after LS a SS adds to the initial access
track and the related groups as Hades
and privileges which are associated with
this user and finally the primary access
token is created later will no one will
call usually needs and stuff to
initialize everything women are
concerned about it
then Alice a SS provides the access
token to the user session allowing him
to acess now he can get into the VIP
zone ok
yeah cool so now that we went through
the windows standard Logan process let's
take a look at the thing we're
interested in we're in the process or
something is playable so how is the user
identified by the system after being
successfully authenticated it is
identified but it's associated security
identifier which is unique within the
host how does this system associate and
username with his security identifier
with black magic of course this is one
of the things I have analyzed it and
burst at the back to find the security
issue so let me show how there's the
hell this work so do you remember this
part of the process here is the exact
moment when a new surname is translated
to his associated si D for the very
first time and then some important data
is obtained from the Sun so how is the
user name associated with the SAT and
what security information
it's retrieved some server now housed
now how to translate from username to
u.s. ID he goes into the Sam database on
this specific registry hive and then
selects the username each of these keys
contains a reg binary as you can notice
here and this registry by analysts have
an attribute called type this a3 which
contained an accessible version of the
relative identifier associated with this
user in this case is 3 e 9 which is
equal to 1000 1 now that the some server
node related our ID he looks at this
registry place and she's the one whose
name is the same our ID with some
significant zeros and then it grabs all
the information is tort ended into the
reference key and some server sent sends
back all T stayed at to the MSB one
process and this is the security data
that is returned back to the
authentication package after
understanding this process some
questions may rise so why does some
store only they already because every
user will have the same s ID initial
part but the our ID will always be
different for each of them the only
thing that buys from user to user is the
in the same system sorry is the already
what information is retrieved from the
some data obtained from the stamp of the
registry contains the password hash the
county status some additional account
restrictions and the pivotal one a copy
of the users already this is the core of
the our ID hijacking attack will see
that insured so let's simplify the
attack let's do the authentication
process with the red girl but now we
will omit some parts of the
authentication process and explained in
more detail and thus we table one so
guess it's just an example remember this
works also on standard user accounts so
omit in the beginning will logon has
done his job and sent a lot of
information to the authentication
package MSB one and now MSB one sends
the user has combination to the Sam
server now the some server query the Sam
database looking for the associated
guest key it determines that the guest
account has they are ID 501 or 105 for
next our decimal base so some server
queries again the Sam but now consulting
the zero zero zero zero zero one and
five key now the process retrieves the
security data related to the user
including this our ID copy I told you is
important after that some servers sent
this information back to the MSB one
authentication package and this guy does
his job so this could lead to two
possible the scenarios the first one is
that the hacker girl will not
authenticate because I never win to the
Machine by default the guest account is
disabled leading to an access denied
then is the second one so supported that
supposed that for some reason the guest
account is enabled she receives her
access token and then what she doesn't
get tick left but has access point to
the guest floor so how could we improve
this situation
it's a mystery for us right now to
understand why there's a copy of the our
ID inside a key with the same name but
what would happen if we modify it well I
have found that this our ID copy is the
value used by the LS a SS and security
reference monitor to create the primary
access to
so the privileges added to the access
token are obtained based on this already
so let's set this already copy with
another already already in this case the
500 which belongs to the built-in
administrator so now repeat all the
process MSB sends the user hash to some
server some server queries the same
database with the guest user name then
it retrieves the associated a'ready key
which is when a5 now it worries again
the same database with the obtained
array D and now it receives the security
data from some including the modify it
already copy this data is sent back to
the MSB authentication parish
now that the MSB one authentication
buckets check for security restrictions
of the user obtained from the sand I'm
security data so it compares the
restrictions with the data obtained from
the Sam the thing is that MSB one takes
the status of the guest account but that
seems that they are from the
administrator and allow in the access
even AB administrator account is
disabled as I have told you only the
only thing that we are modifying is
their ID not the other security
properties this applies also to the hash
so M is become first the cached version
of the enter password hash the hash
retrieved from the Sam and profit but
what will be the same now that
everything is ok the authentication
package retrieves the logon information
to the LSA SS and then LSA SS
communicates with the security reference
monitor to create the access token based
on this modified our ID copy so all the
security properties of the account
remain the same except the our ID which
is the critical one modifying their ID
at the exact place it's equal to
acquiring the privileges of its profit
account and doing everything one in this
case the guest account receives her
access token and she can do anything
inside the system all because the
administrator so these are the security
issues the first one is that that Sam
server does not check if the our ID
associated with the user is
assistant to this particular our ad copy
the second one is that the LS a SS does
not corroborate the relative identifier
with the username right before creating
the primary access token the third one
is that the LS a SS never looks for
already inconsistency
during the user session so the funny
part the demonstration so let me see
this will be our victim machine as you
can see I have updated early this
morning okay
and here the latest batches here are the
uses local users of the victim that
means Twitter one the guest one and a
standard user account called
unprivileged we can see that the
administrator account is not active we
can see that the administrator account
is active for demo purposes okay and
this is the standard account for
applying to use also this active and
okay
so let's look down and let's try to
interactively authenticate with the
guest account I have set the password
before we can see here that it is a
possible for us to interactively log on
as the guest account
[Music]
I have developed a Metasploit model
which is available on the latest
official version of Metasploit and you
can see it on you can find it on Windows
managed already hijack both windows
managed already hijacked this is the
model teaser some of the properties will
see that in shirt this the is the IP
address of the attacker machine and we
will try to do a PS xxxx against the big
team and by using the guest potentials
so if we try it it is not successful by
now we can try it also with the improve
already at account ok just won't work
and let's see the model so this requires
meterpreter session to modify the
specific registry binary that contains
they already copy so the gate system
will try to acquire the required
privileges to modify this particular
binary the guest account volume will
define if we are going to use as the
hijacker account if we are planning to
use the guest account as a hijacker one
sorry if we want to change the password
of a hijacker account we will set it in
the field password and in the filter ID
will set the relative identifier world
point you are planning to move to set to
and this session all might meet up at
our session so if we're an exploit we
can see here that we have modify it from
the guest account default or ID which is
501 to the 500 so if we try to
authenticate again with the guest
account interactively let's see ok by
now it's possible but let's see what's
happened if we try to do that with the
PS execration cool good show and by
default in packet version the basics
version of in packet will try to acquire
the most important privilege which with
our system account so that's wait here
but I think is that we are impersonating
the administrator built-in account we
can see here that it is disabled its
account is enabled we are authenticating
with the guests potentials but we are
generating or access token based it on
the administrator already so let's check
this can you see this okay cool
now we are the guest account but or a CD
or access token is generated with the
500 access token okay so if we run
something like who am i and we try to
write inside of a protected folder okay
will be possible for us to write on
protected folders by with my using the
guest potentials and no trigger and by
inaudible and triggering any alerts on
the victim you can see here that it is
also the user is disabled by default
okay but we are impersonating
administrator so in every never we lock
taking every lock that register any
operation that has taken place during
this decision will be registered as done
by the administrator but we are blogging
with the quest credentials this is also
I forget to do that they I mean I'm
running out of time but it is possible
to do this also with the standard user
accounts and some final conclusions so
by now as
you have seen this is the latest wind 10
version there is no existing packs patch
to protect window from this attack the
only way to the Phantom machine against
this is by detection I have tested this
with many antivirus but it is not
detected I mean then the only thing that
can be detected is the meterpreter
executable but this can be done also by
using only OS resources the thing is
that this is more complicated to detect
on big Windows domain since a simple
workstation can be used as an open door
to people inside the network I am NOT
currently aware about any malware that
uses this kind of persistence I mean as
you see this is a quite simple technique
and it's pretty easy to apply I hope you
will enjoy this technique as more and
more such I do and thank you for coming
that's it
[Applause]
you