[Music]
so today we're gonna talk about using
social engineering at work nothing we
did a sound check
[Music]
[Laughter]
probably help we did like a full audio
test earlier from the back okay all
right sure I will use the mic is this
better I'll take this thing up actually
that's a bad idea
okay actual a good morning okay okay so
today we're going to talk about using
positive influence of work to get stuff
done so this is a little bit geared
toward introverts at least at the
beginning but I get more into technical
ways to to work with people and engineer
choices and things like that later so
this was me for most of my adult life I
would take the stairs instead of the
elevator because I didn't want to make
small talk with people it was super
awkward I didn't know what say I just I
was terrified it was only like one
flight of stairs I was like the shortest
elevator ride anywhere so so if I've
been hacking myself for a couple years
I'm trying to get better at killing and
if I can do it I mean I was like
debilitatingly introverted like I would
try instead of go to parties so if I can
do this and be standing up here and like
talking to people and making small talk
and chatting up strangers then anybody
can do it so I have I was
overcompensating for a while with
certification
excited to have my degree yet and then I
just turned into kind of a joke so these
are my credentials since I've been
speaking publicly this is all the places
that I've traveled around the world to
speak I'm just amazed by this I would
have never thought that this would
happen to me like ten years ago or even
five years ago so you can hack yourself
and you can learn about it better with
humans if even if you are comfortable
making small talk and chatting with
people and things like that you can get
better at it and you can learn how to
get things via social engineering and
social engineering tactics but like
anything you do have to practice it
it is something but if it doesn't come
naturally just like learning a coding
language or anything else you do have to
practice it learn it get better at it
you're not going to be perfect on the
first day so a running theme of at least
the Wellness Village and some other
talks is impostor syndrome once you
realize that basically everybody has
some level of impostor syndrome not even
necessarily in this industry but
especially in this industry and
especially at work then you will start
to feel better about your own impostor
syndrome when you start to realize that
some that the people that are speaking
on stage have impostor syndrome just
like you we're just pretending it
doesn't exist
protecting that voice inside of our head
doesn't exist that's saying like why am
I here how did why did they pick me I
have no idea
so people are also super scary they have
their own egos and their wants and their
needs and they bring things to the table
that confuse us and are different from
what we are trying to do it seems like
we have nothing in common with the lady
who like makes her own dolls out of like
knitting or something like we we've been
nothing in common with these people but
we can learn how to connect with them
even though we seemingly have nothing in
common so a lot of us all have social
phobias social anxieties and small talk
feels kind of icky we don't like
networking it's kind of gross so we can
get over that many of us had it have
innate challenges dealing with other
humans being on the spectrum being
poorly socialized we the same thing that
makes us good at what we do is also a
little bit of a hindrance sometimes when
it comes to socializing so if we can if
we could fix that a little bit we can
get more things done we can get things
done easily at work we can build
relationships and and get anything we
want basically so one of the problems
with hacking yourself and learning
anything new is that uncertainty is
actually painful the same region in our
brain that tells us that we're feeling
pain is the region that's activated when
we feel uncertainty so it manifests the
same way as physical pain so a lot of
people are not good with it uncertainty
people like stability people don't like
change but it really sucks but and but
we realize that other people at work
don't like this either other people do
not like change as we may have seen
throughout your career so office
politics are also awful
they are the unwritten rules that
somebody gets something somebody doesn't
get something the crew that goes to
lunch together always seems to have all
the cool projects to work on the people
that have relationships and just make a
phone call can get something done a lot
quicker than somebody who sends an email
and I sells and things like that when we
don't engage in politics it makes us
less productive let's make some less
effective and we are more likely to quit
statistically so we should play the game
it's actually fun and rewarding
and we need to participate in some of
these politics if we want to be
effective so every group has politics
whether it's a bake sale or or a board
room every every group of more than two
or three people has politics because
people bring their own like we talked
about people bring their own egos and
wants and needs to the table their
aspirations and agendas and we're always
going to be compromising on something is
it going to be chocolate cupcake serving
only cupcakes so they're going to be
Cisco or juniper so bad politics are bad
politics are the politics that we we
don't like we don't like them because
it's nasty it's people being in it just
for themselves and we can tell that from
a mile away unfortunately a lot of
offices have politics that are closer to
this than good politics people are
sneaky people are trying to get things
under the radar people are trying to
just try to climb the ladder and they're
stepping on everybody on the way up so
good politics on the other hand we're
advancing our interests and we're also
serving a higher purpose we are trying
to make the business better
we are not neglecting other people's
feelings and needs and wants we're
giving recognition to people instead of
throwing them under the bus because we
want them to look bad so that we can
look good it's making sure everybody
involved in something looks good because
that makes us all look good weirdly
enough good politics may you may like be
bad-mouthing the people who play bad
politics so it's kind of kind of strange
that that works we can't be a successful
island especially in the industries that
we work in a lot of us want to sit in
our basements and and just do what we do
but that hurts our careers that hurts
our teams it doesn't help our or
as much just being a worker bee so we
have this increasingly collaborative
structure at work where teams are
getting things done and a Steve Jobs
said great things in business are never
done by one person they're done by a
team of people and that's absolutely
true any project is going to involve
more than one person
so influence can help you elicit changes
and get things done there are a couple
of different kinds of influence there's
indirect influence and there's direct
influence so direct influence is like
when you're a manager and you have
people under you and you have authority
indirect influence is when you can get
things done and influence people that
are not directly under your authority so
that's what we're going to be talking
about mostly today it's not manipulative
it's not a bad thing we're not using
social engineering to like take
advantage of people we're trying to do
better things for the organization so
influence requires sincerity it's the
main difference between good and bad
politics it's the thing that makes us
and trying to do networking that's the
thing that makes us feel icky is that we
don't feel sincere we feel like we're
putting on a smile we're putting on a
face we're putting on a mask and and it
it's exhausting frankly so if we want to
contribute to the greater good we need
to retain our sense of sincerity and
people will be able to smell us being
insincere from a mile away if oh I love
your earrings they're great that's
that's a lot different than somebody
who's being sincere so people will
actually respond to you better if they
don't sense a hidden agenda like within
bad politics authenticity and sincerity
go hand in hand we want to maintain this
as well
this is what this is how we we see
ourselves and how we present ourselves
to the world we don't want to be too
different from who we are because that's
also exhausting and it's not going to
help us at all
so we need to be able to sell our value
it's really hard to be able to write
like a bio of yourself or something then
and talk about all the cool things that
you've done because it feels weird that
goes back to the imposter syndrome it
feels like weird that we should be
talking in ourselves up and it makes job
interview is really hard and things like
that
you may think that I made this and it
should stand on its own merits but
that's not really how things work so we
have to extend our reach and our impact
and and we do that through other people
and it does get easier to talk about
yourself and I've learned this through
many job interviews that I've been going
through and through speaking and and
submitting CFPs and things like that
selling your value gets a lot easier
when you've done it many times because
you have like sort of an elevator pitch
or whatever you are more able to talk
about what you contribute and how you
help when you've done it before the
first few times can feel kind of
difficult and icky
so asking for help is also really
uncomfortable we want to be seen as
competent we want to be seen as
confident and capable and as high
potential employees so we don't want to
ask for help we want to be able to do it
ourselves it's part of the hacker
mentality like I can do it I can make
this work but asking for help is
required in a lot of projects and a lot
of different efforts at work so with SEO
at work we're trying to manipulate the
social and political system we need to
figure out where we fit into that
ecosystem we need to convince people
that they want to help us not just
convince people to help us
it will help us get the things done
quickly it'll help us negotiate and help
us build consensus on decisions and most
of all and this is the best part it will
help people prioritize your tasks and
your efforts over others because
ultimately there's a human who's
deciding what they're going to work on
today are they going to work on the
request from somebody they don't know or
are they going to work on the request
from the person that they know is their
friend or know is doing the right thing
for the company or whatever the myriad
of reasons is so when you start to enter
office politics when you start to
interact with people more it does take
courage it's it's trying something new
it's trying something difficult it's a
lot more embarrassing if you fail in
theory because it's not like your code
didn't compile its it could lead to an
awkward moment or something like that
but you will learn from that just like
any mistake that you make just like
anything you try to do it takes courage
to start so forget about your comfort
zone you need to anytime you learn
something like a new language you are
getting out of your comfort zone you're
trying something new our career
advancement requires networking getting
a job by just submitting a resume on a
website is not as effective as when you
give your resume to someone else and
they get it into the system challenging
situations are the situations that teach
us the most whenever we are tried and
our medalist tried we learn more we're
always changing so it shouldn't be too
hard and we came in just like any change
we can ease into it we don't have to
make a ton of changes at once and we
grow as people by doing things that we
wouldn't normally do so this is a good
thing people may hear your words but
they feel your attitude this is why
social engineering is so important and
this is why authenticity is important so
you need to decide if you really care
about your own idea if you have an idea
for a project if you have an idea you
want to implement something or make a
change if you don't care about it and
you can't convince others that it's
important then it's not going to happen
so you need to decide why it's important
to you why you value the decision and
why other people should believe in it as
well when we have zero political skills
that undermines people like us
intelligent honest hard-working people
so we need to be able to play politics
without losing ourselves we want to stay
authentic we want to stay sincere so
we're gonna do just like we would do
with any kind of tech and I hate to say
this but it is very much like an attack
so we're going to try to understand
what's going on at work we're going to
to implement so some different tactics
to try to make things happen
so recon and then infiltrate so we're
gonna start by mapping the humans we can
do this on paper we can do this in melty
go we can do it however we want so we're
gonna do some intelligence gathering
we're gonna look at who the stakeholders
are in the entire organization not just
relevant to your project but relevance
of things that you would normally try to
do so we're gonna look at who the
stakeholders are is it legal is it is it
the developers is operations we need to
figure out who the stakeholders are and
then within those stakeholder groups we
have to figure out who has influence and
it may not be the people with direct
influence it may not be the managers it
might be a senior person that everybody
looks to to make good decisions and that
we need to figure out how people are
associated who's friends with
what what are the groups what are the
cliques who talks to each other
regularly and we can do this by
observation we can talk to people and
try to figure out what's going on a lot
of people know the system better than
you would
so we recon the relationships between
PPO people we need to figure out how
decisions are going to be made are they
made in the meeting or are they made
after a discussion is in the meeting via
email or something like that do people
hate meetings is it better to just have
informal conversations it also
introverts do they not want to
communicate in a very personal way and
look for people who are well-connected
because they can help you so with formal
channels of communication we want to try
to figure out our meetings like just
talks or are you going to need to
present are you going to be more / - be
more prepared you need to have like
slide decks and things like that or is
it more impromptu you can also ask
colleagues who have recently or in the
past had success getting things done how
they did it and get some information
from that in terms of decisions
decisions get made in different ways so
sometimes they're made in the meeting
sometimes after sometimes the senior
people are agreeing to things rather
than management even without like
checking with management necessarily you
can look around if you're in person you
can look around and or even on the phone
try to figure out is everybody agreeing
or is it just a few people that are
agreeing or some people staying silent
you talk to them afterwards and try to
figure out did they agree and that's why
they were silent or were they silent
because they disagreed but they didn't
want to because it was in the popular
opinion so also in in-person meetings
people might physically look to someone
when a decision needs to be made
that person is an influencer if if
people turn their bodies or ask well
what do you think to somebody that
person is important that person is an
influencer so once we know who's in the
organization who the stakeholders are we
know who is making decisions who's in
formal we want to start to think about
how we're implementing the change that
we want to make so in any change there's
going to be kind of a winner and a loser
and there's people that are gonna have
to do more work there's going to be
people that have to contribute more
resources and there's people that are
going to have a better day so try to
figure out who's going to have more work
who's going to be on the kind of bearing
the brunt of the change because that's
going to be important later to try to
help them ease into the change so
there's going to be advocates there's
going to be blockers try to think ahead
of time about who those people are going
to be and again you can make a visual
map to help you with any of this once
you have that that's when we're going to
need to infiltrate we're going to have
to start building relationships and so
we want to secure allies before we need
them that's really important so one way
you can do this is to team up with
somebody who's really well networked
people that are well networked are not
necessarily really deeply technical they
they require people who are technical to
carry out their big-picture visions they
they tend to adopt introverts it's kind
of funny so if you can try to find
somebody that's really long networked
and hang out with them and look you can
actually learn from them but you can
also use their network when we talk
about body language this is something
that we need to work on as a community
it's true we have to admit this 80% of
what we understand in a conversation is
the body not the words so if your body
language doesn't convey confidence if
you're walking around and you're hunched
over and you're asking for something
you're like I really need help
or if you have your arms crossed and you
seem really defensive or you seem really
closed off to the world it's it's going
people are going to react to that
they're going to see that so we stand up
straight we keep our I mean they seem
like simple things but we project
confidence by standing correctly sitting
correctly and pitching our voice a
little bit lower because when we get
really excited sometimes our voices go
up like this and and we get really
nervous and things like that picks the
voice down a little bit when we talk
about mirroring other people you may
hear about this where people somebody
puts their their head on their hand like
this and then the person across from of
them might do something similar or maybe
the other hand when if somebody has
their hands crossed in front of them
somebody might put their arms in a
similar way so this happens naturally
when we have rapport when we don't have
rapport we can use this to build rapport
because people like people who are like
them people like people that are similar
to them including body language so they
can also change the way people are so if
you notice that somebody else is closed
off and they're they have their arms
crossed and they're sitting back in
their chair you can actually do the
opposite you can lean forward you can
open up you can have an open body
language versus closed body language so
if they are like a feelings person you
can talk about feelings if their thinker
they'll use words like I think if
they're a feeler person they'll be like
I feel like this is not gonna work
there's different personality types so
when we use words that appeal to those
personality types that's really helpful
timing is important so if there's
something going on at the business if
there's like a big merger or something
or they're big customers having like an
outage or something that may not be the
best time to try to make change people
will stick to what they know
tried-and-true things they're more
likely to say no because it
they don't want to think about the
implications right now they're too busy
so try to think about what is going on
in the business maybe in the world even
depending on what you do and try to find
an unstressed full time to suggest
change you can read the room this is a
little bit harder on the phone you can
try to see if people are bored if they
have their own strife if there's other
things going on is it the right time to
propose an idea our people really closed
off because if something else is being
discussed that may not be the best time
to propose something you can also notice
how people change if somebody walks in
the room and everybody suddenly sits up
straight that person may be important
they may be an influencer that might be
a better time to suggest changes well
you can also use a current strife so
let's say there is an outage let's the
other customers down that may be a good
time to suggest something that could
help with this in the future so you can
either by being aware of what's going on
you can either use it to your advantage
or you can step back and wait until it's
a better time so empathy is so important
in what we do I it does need to be
authentic when we empathize with people
it helps us solve problems when people
will people will notice that that we
understand them and care about them so a
couple ways that we can do that
something I do all the time is practice
gratitude I say thank you all the time I
will say thank you multiple times I'll
say it different ways over the course of
an email I will thank their boss I will
thank them I will thank them publicly I
will thank them later when I talk to
them like hey thanks for that thing he
did but last week when we say thank you
people appreciate it
people want to feel like they matter so
it
better to focus on their generosity and
their selflessness not on how you will
benefit like thanks that that really
helped me out is not quite as good as
like thank you you are always a great
resource for me to reach out to and I
appreciate it
kindness is another way to build empathy
we need to be conscious of how we are
with other people I mean there's always
going to be somebody that didn't Google
something and we're going to tell them
no we're not going to help you just
Google that but the way we say it can
change the way people perceive it so
respecting people being civil and more
than anything holding the other people
on your team accountable for kindness
isn't is critical because if people
perceive your team as being kind of mean
or rough or whatever then they are not
going to want to work with you because
you're on the team
so making sure that everybody is being
nice and and helpful as much as possible
and not being rude to people or just
saying flat-out no without giving
reasons or explaining things it's it
will help everybody when everybody is
being nicer so people want to be
effective it's a basic human motivation
we want to feel engaged we want to have
meaning in our lives the things that we
contribute make us who we are so when we
show people that they're effective not
just tell them that makes a big
difference so when we follow up if
somebody's helping us and at one step of
a larger process follow up and say that
that thing that you helped with last
week that helped us get this whole
project going you know you were a
critical piece of that thank you
and here's what happened and it went
well then the next time that you ask
them for help they will know that it's
for something good and that they're
contributing and that that will make
them feel good it's also good to not
tell them how to help because they may
have better ideas than you on how they
can help so if you tell them what you
need that's you're not going to tell
them how to do it sorry unless they
unless they have no idea what to do
you're not going to tell them how to
help you you're just going to ask for
the help so positive reinforcement is
good we look at like Pavlov's dog that
kind of thing
providing recognition and status and
achievements really important like I
said emailing their boss it's telling
them thank you for lending me the
resource of this person emphasizing that
people have positive impact telling
short not just telling what showing
people the results of what happens so
that they can see the good that they do
when we really give them the empathy
then we start acknowledging the things
that are going to happen because of
change so people are going to fear the
change they're gonna there's going to be
some uncertainty which is going to
manifest as a little bit of pain which
nobody likes so so don't tiptoe around
it address it say I know that this
change is going to be hard for you I
know that you're going to need to devote
some resources to it so when we as we
start the plan we're going to help you
get this going because we know that
you're short on resources already so
acknowledge that what's going on try to
try to make their understanding of how
it will happen a little bit smoother so
that they can absorb and accept the
change knowing that they'll have help
they're not just going to be like here's
something for you to do here's some more
work being a partner is really important
so when we share things that we like and
we talk to other people it's called quid
pro quo so this is part of a natural
conversation stuff
I'm talking to somebody and I say I have
two dogs somebody else might say that
I'm talking to you they might say oh I
have a dog too so by me sharing
something they also shared so this is a
good way to talk to people to learn
about them if we do find out something
like somebody has a dog we want to add
that to our little diagram we want to
say here's Susie and she has this kind
of dog and his name is whatever so that
we can ask them about it later it shows
that we're listening it shows that we
care and they will respond to that if
you make a mistake
say you're sorry it's hard I know some
people that cannot apologize it's just
they basically like physically cannot
apologize for things they're never wrong
so they will not say they're sorry
so by humbling yourself and suppressing
your ego you are going to show people
that you are honest you admitted that
you made a mistake you're sorry it's not
going to happen again things like that
it makes you vulnerable and that endears
people to you it makes people relate to
you if you are perfect and you never
make mistakes you're harder to relate to
so having shared experiences this is one
of the reasons that companies do those
like weird outings and stuff but you can
make that happen at work let's say that
there is an outage and everybody's
working on it and you order pizza that's
a lot better than everybody's in there
cubes working on it separately being
together in that moment and having those
shared experiences can help with bonding
so that later you can talk about hey
remember that time we stayed up all
night and fix the problem that was those
were the good old days or whatever so we
can only influence people we can't
change other people we can change
ourselves though
so with choice architecture this is a
little bit more advanced the goal is to
present all
things that you really want people to
choose so let's say that there's five or
ten or twenty choices for something you
want to present the first one you want
to create the illusion of choice but
you're really only presenting a few
options that are all good options or you
can talk about the first option the best
option first because people will focus
on the first thing that you talk about
so if you want to nudge people towards a
certain direction they'll present
everything all at once it they're
comparing things it's too difficult to
make a decision
give them one idea say here's one of the
yep get vendor on the phone first get
that demo first because that's then
everybody else will be compared to them
they will be the standard this is we we
need to start with individuals instead
of groups when they want to make change
you'll see this in a lot of like house
of cards or some of the other political
shows where people are trying to get
votes for something they'll call people
individually and get their support so
that when it does come to a vote when it
does come to a decision those people
it's just a formality for approving so
so when there's a commonly held opinion
and you have the majority of people that
are on board you've talked to them
you've talked to them about the pluses
and the minuses and how it's going to
work it's much better when you come into
a room and people are on the same page
if people start talking about something
that you don't like if they're started
talking about going down a path that you
don't think will work you can play
devil's advocate and make them start
thinking about the negatives of what
they are thinking of are we making the
right decision on this let's consider
the alternatives if we if we don't
something bad could happen so when
people make good decisions we want to
reward them we want to say bats and X
suggestion and that is a great idea do
let's do that and and making it so that
when they are making decisions and
making suggestions that help your cause
you're giving positive reinforcement for
that so humility much like saying you're
sorry is important we can't always be
the the people that are unapproachable
and always right and the best of
climbing we may be the best of what we
do but we don't have to act that way so
when we network networking sucks
it's true if it's not socializing though
networking is different from socializing
we're not hanging out with our friends
we're hanging out people who can do
something for us they might be able to
get us a job they might be able to help
us down the line I will have a
conversation with anybody that wants to
talk to me about a potential job or
something because even if it's not the
right fit because that way I have
somebody who knows me who may in the
future need somebody like me for a job
so when you try to socialize when you
try to network this is a good place to
try to you know you google like how to
make small talk and then you try it out
in like a networking setting a lot of
people are very awkward in networking
sessions and a lot of people are really
good at it too so if you can if you go
to a conference just go talk to the
vendors because they aren't really good
at talking to people so you can you can
actually listen to how like how they're
questioning you the way that they're
saying things could pro quo things like
that and and get some tips on how you
can be better - you're trying something
new when you do this don't think about
it like socializing it's going to be a
little bit uncomfortable because you're
going to feel an authentic and sincere
like
at least at first but when you get to
know somebody it no it's no longer
inauthentic it's no longer awkward so
questions make things a lot easier
asking a lot of questions is the key to
small talk
it helps us with pretty much everything
if I don't know what to say that
somebody I'll just ask them the question
hey what did you do this weekend or if
I'm at a con and I meet somebody like
hey what are you working on things like
that especially if it's an open-ended
question that's a lot better than
something where they just say no and
then there's talk words silence so if
you have something to add you talk about
similar experiences that creates a bond
as well so listening actively is
important when somebody says so I went
to the Bahamas last weekend you go oh
you went to the Bahamas last weekend
that's awesome
so you're repeating like they said to
show that you were listening
nodding mirroring body language things
like that we talked about open body
language as well helps not using your
phone as well
open-ended questions again here are some
examples are you originally from here
what are you - what are you doing the
weekends what are you looking forward to
on the three-day weekend things like
that so when we ask for help we want to
shift the idea to the benefits of
helping how good they're going to feel
when they help how how impactful they're
going to be so they should feel in
charge or in control of their decision
feel like they have a choice in whether
they're going to help you or not and and
by having a relationship before you need
something
it really Prime's them for helping you
so you if you go into it and you're
introducing yourself it's already too
late you should already have some sort
of rapport with people that you're going
to be asking for things throughout your
career so don't suggest that somebody is
instructing them to help so you can use
the authority principle of social
engineering like my boss really needs me
to get this done
that's not as effective as saying my
manager said that you were the best at
this and to involve you because they
knew that you would be a huge help so
may I ask you a favor makes people feel
trapped there's some different
questioning lines that you can go
through if you minimize your need that's
really really bad if you're like I hate
to ask you this or this is just a little
thing because then nobody's going to
want to help you being too vulnerable
can actually backfire too it can make
people not respect you so don't ask for
help when you when you don't really need
it it's like the Google at first and
it's also a fine line between being
completely helpless and asking for help
when we use the word together
it is impactful to our brains because we
are tribal originally so being part of
that tribe makes us succeed we want the
entire organization to succeed so citing
common goals common enemies creating a
strong sense of group is important when
we try to elicit change several smaller
meetings with individuals will help us
more than a couple of larger meetings
being positive one on one conversations
trying to get things rolling with with
influencers we always want to meet the
expectation that we say we're going to
do something we do it that builds trust
so we have to build these relationships
if we don't we're going to be less
effective people will resist change so
expect it and prepare to answer
questions and deal with complaints and
things like that when you think about
what the possible arguments are going to
be against your suggestion then you can
actually have responses ready when you
go into it you want to give people
with trains you want to let it kind of
trickle in you want it to like slowly
build change we're not saying like we're
gonna change everything about the
network tomorrow like that doesn't work
so we plant the seed of an idea and then
we use people into it we talked about
how some people will be winners and
losers we can try to we can try to build
like a prototype of something if people
don't think it will work so we can get a
mass support and we will be able to get
others to follow because that's how
social proof works if everybody says the
two plus two is four then the other
person's probably going to say the same
thing
be prepared to state your case be
prepared to deal with arguments show
respect and empathy when people are
disagreeing because they're they need to
understand that you are on their side
when you get nervous don't over explain
just state state the state your case
state the arguments of their argument
don't attack back try to stay positive
what is stopping you from saying yes is
a really powerful phrase card healers
use it all the time but you can use it
to figure out what what people are
thinking about how about what you're
suggesting so if there are arguments you
can address them then rather than let it
fester and you don't know about it some
people just won't care
so changing yourself is the only option
you can escalate up and over and use the
management chain I've also used FOMO to
try to get people on projects and things
like that if they feel like they're
gonna be left out of some big successful
project they will want to participate so
we need to be sincere and honest
building trust try not to lose it
cultivating relationships not being
afraid to take risks sometimes admitting
our mistakes
letting others win sometimes we don't
always have to be the winner valuing
people setting aside our egos asking for
advice and looking outward trying new
things interacting with people
attempting to do do things differently
than you normally do remote work does
make this a lot harder you what I
usually do is show up a few minutes
early for me like a phone call or phone
bridge and just make some small talk if
you run a team talk about some personal
stuff before the meeting starts or after
and if I'm like chatting with somebody I
will continue to talk to them after
they've helped me I'll be like so I
haven't talked in a while how are things
going over there it's just a simple
thing it's just a simple way to keep
conversations going you can reach out
just to touch base you don't always have
to ask for something in fact that's
probably better having a more fun
environment where you're like sharing
gifts and emojis and things like that
can also help so bringing it all
together we have to not acknowledge that
politics exists and that we have to
participate in them we can fake it till
we make it a lot of us are pretty good
at that we manage the network of
influencers that we've discovered and
can use to our advantage we build
influence before we need it not after or
not when and socializing and networking
all these things it sets us up for good
things in the future it's not just
necessarily with making change but also
in our careers and our lives
authenticity makes networking not
completely awful when we maintain who we
are and then we can craft outcomes with
things like choice architecture and
nudging so some books that have helped
me this is on my blog at architect
security org and I will tweet it out
after so that's my thing thank you
[Applause]