thing that I've been consulting with law
enforcement sheriffs counties fortune 50
s just did a consultation with the young
the company of the youngest two
billionaires ever because everybody
wants threat intelligence cuz it's cool
buzzwords so first thing if you get told
you need to stand up threat intelligence
you need to understand that threat
intelligence runs a full spectrum of a
company is a true enterprise program and
it should not live in your InfoSec
Department and I'll explain why how many
of you are paramilitary got a couple
hands in here alright so the military
and I'm going to use military as an
example but you can understand what what
you should be doing in the civilian
sector so in the military we have
something called an s-1 shop that's
equates to Human Resources in the
civilian world we have something called
an s2 shop that is your intelligence arm
right we have something called s3 which
equates to your operations we have that
something called s4 which is logistics
and then we have depending on what
they'll show and we'll have some five
shops they do super-secret squirrel
stuff then we have s6 which is your IT
department so no matter what the
organizational structure is you have a
head of that organization in the
civilian world to CEO okay that's the
EEO needs to make business decisions if
you want to have a threat intelligence
program that is successful you must be
value added to the CEO what the CEO
needs from you is to make a well
informed decision so somebody tell me
give me an example of what a threat to a
businesses where's the ham yeah
malicious insider loss of intellectual
property
loss of PCI loss of life we're getting
bigger think bigger now get out of your
ones and zeros what's a threat to a
business competition natural hazards
reputation how many of these are unique
to just your information security team
none this is the first indicator why
threat intelligence is not an
information security function okay now
what if your building were to explode
and I use this as an extreme example
here because the same people that stayed
in the corporate building that you were
in you had an abortion clinic on the
first floor and you were in the Bible
Belt would that be a threat to your
company a hundred percent
how many information security people are
monitoring threats to the abortion
company on the first floor when your
company is on the seventh none that is
why this is a threat intelligence
function and it does not belong to your
information security department okay how
many people could ever assume they fire
drill or a bomb scare to clear a
building would be used to access your
network remotely how many of your
information security departments have
thought about that potential kind of a
threat and actually have a plan in place
of what to do if they have to clear the
building immediately
not very many because what's your
information security team worried about
technical assets the network and the
hosts and nodes that reside on them
usually to some degree the data that
resides on them right but what are they
looking for they're looking for the
50-meter target they're looking for the
whack Amole threat they're looking for
the IOC the mal
well what's the see an IOC stand for so
what happened already somebody already
got popped right and that's the only way
you're learning your lesson if you want
to have truth or intelligence you have
to think about what could be the threat
before it comes so you can go out and
find indicators of attack not an
indicator of compromise all right I
didn't hear anybody I might have heard
somebody mentioned your company good
name did I hear somebody say good name
company good name your brand how many of
you actually go out and look to see or
have alerts use tools like domain tools
for brand monitoring and go out and look
for somebody that registers a domain
that has the sequence of characters that
match your company name anywhere in that
domain a few people do how many of you
actually share that information with
marketing and legal - that's more hands
than I usually get okay so I'll tell you
I worked for a company for a little
while still do stuff with them all the
time and I worked I helped with red hat
for a little while I went to Red Hat and
I said hey guys have you guys taken any
look at potential phishing for your
customers or people trying to get people
inside the company setting up sites for
blogs and chats that are not threatening
they're not attacking they're not
malicious they're not hitting they're
not trippin sensors on your network
they're not phishing your people but how
many of you look at anything that's been
said if it has your company name in the
name somewhere of that domain well why
would we care about somebody who's not
attacking those not phishing our
customers but is helping support our
good name right we're an open source
community
ever ever heard of oversharing okay how
many of you could read a job description
and tell me what technology a company
uses have you guys ever asked your
marketing and HR department if they have
the people that they're using when they
post job descriptions to capture the IP
addresses of people reading the job
descriptions but not applying wouldn't
that be some awesome threat intelligence
to give you a hint at who might be
recounting your technical capabilities
is this something that is unique to the
information security department is it
starting to make sense why threat
intelligence is not an information
security only function now if you are in
the information security team you are in
the impression you are two things one
you are a consumer of threat
intelligence but you are also a
contributor and a creator of threat data
so because you're an information
security and they're in threat
intelligence if you are in threat
intelligence do not put it get the big
head you are in a customer service role
you have people that need you and you
have products that you need to produce
for them but if you are an information
security you need to be sharing up as
well because guess what you might help
drive intelligence requirements your
threat intelligence team they may be a
bit badasses on the internet they may be
badasses at ascent and recon and red
teaming but guess what
we can't boil the ocean either if we
don't know where possible problems lie
and we don't know of some of the daily
battles that you're fighting great and
the fires that you're fighting we don't
know where to go look for information or
what to be searching for right we just
named a whole bunch of threats out here
I was a one-man show for threat
intelligence team for a multi-billion
dollar company do you think I have
enough time I have a husband I'd like to
sleep I'd like to eat
okay I can't I can't chase all the
boogeyman on the Internet
so far threat intelligence team that's
number one what you need if somebody
wants to hire you for threat
intelligence you say what are your your
intelligence requirements oh well we
want to know about anybody who's gonna
harm us
my five-year-olds a threat to you
let me let them loose in your data
center for five minutes I promise that
five-year-old is the person that
five-year-olds a persistent threat right
okay so they need to at least know what
their intelligence requirements are so
if you get asked to stand up at threat
intelligence team you need to know what
are my intelligence requirements what
question am i trying to answer okay well
next year we would like to buy property
we want to set up an office in Berlin we
want to open up a new global office
overseas okay let's go to a side
assessment let's see who's in the
building
let's see who's within certain ranges of
these things okay
let's see let's find out what type of
security the facility owners have let's
talk about badge readers right let's
talk about Wi-Fi let's talk about
building padding let's talk about low
frequency high frequency badge raters
let's talk about door access let's talk
about cameras let's talk about physical
footprint who did I just mention what
team is that and physical security
how often do physical security and
InfoSec team share right so is threat
intelligence InfoSec only or 5sec only
so now for all of you have been in a
corporate America everybody heard of a
role of called chief security officer or
sizzle who might need to be in charge of
your threat intelligence team maybe we
need to be higher up at that level
enterprise level as to who we're
reporting to because who does he attend
meetings with CSO marketing HR by sec
right
so for the things I could share with you
about threat intelligence is even though
we're all digital people rate we've got
to get our heads out of ones and zeros
and stop looking at the 50-meter target
threat intelligence is a strategic
investment if somebody tells you I want
to stand up a threat intelligence team
and we need to blog and we need to share
information to our customers and be
value-added you are in the wrong role
that is not threat intelligence how many
of you in here have children how many of
you guys have ever had your your kids
ever gotten sick okay
and god forbid don't raise your hand
maybe a child needed surgery okay if you
came to my office as a doctor and I
didn't have a white coat I didn't have
an x-ray film board I didn't have
alcohol swabs I didn't have a
thermometer or one little doohickeys
when I take your blood pressure and you
brought your kid in to me and I'm not
doing any immediate Diagnostics on you
and I talked to you and I'm like yeah
sure
superglued some stitches shut and put on
a few band-aids and a tourniquet I can
absolutely do surgery on your kid would
you let me do surgery on your child
right so if I am your customer and I'm
coming to you and you could want to
convince me that you can do that
intelligence for me and then I asked you
to show me how you do it
would you expect your customer to buy
thread intelligence services from you if
you can't even do it in-house yet so
there's your first pushback when
somebody tells you they want you to do
thread intelligence and give something
to your customer boss we don't even do
it in here how are we gonna do it for
somebody else right
I don't need my ass flapping in the wind
let's not make us a liability let's not
you know we need to think this out we
need to plan it now and I'm not here for
self-promotion I'm really
trying to jump in and fill the gap I
have a blog called ascent fail okay I
talk a lot about threat intelligence on
there and I have one that's the three
myths of threat intelligence that I just
put out feel free to use it and butcher
it okay but if you guys are hearing this
buzzword and you're an information
security I promise you sooner or later
you are going to be asked to start doing
threat intelligence you need to be the
guy in the room that says I'm not sure
this is our role or it needs to be
buried down at our level because what's
going to happen is you're gonna get
stuck looking at the immediate threats
the 50-meter targets in ones and zeros
anything that would appear on a network
plus or a CCNA exam that's all you're
gonna care about and you have 1/10 of
the pie okay you have a hand for a
question so I would tell you the best
way to use business speak that they
understand about threat intelligence is
what this gentleman said here risk
that's the word they understand okay
okay so in God forget forgive me for
using this but how many of you have CIS
ESPYs okay how many of you guys remember
the formula risk equals threat times
vulnerability okay then you start Kalki
calculating in likelihoods and
probabilities and those two words mean
different things the statistician x' but
so if you want to get in there and
they're doing risk calculations or
whatever start talking with them and say
hey what is your risk model what is your
risk formula okay if they understand
vulnerability management okay I think I
have a blog out there that might help
you where I say this is how you can
score a threat use this score with a CVE
score to get the holistic risk slash
threat score of this vulnerability
because you can take a low and if you if
your info set people you know you have
these five types of actors attacking you
regularly or you face these five types
of threats you can go in and evaluate
that threat actor so that you use the
same consistent repeatable process every
single time and you give them my score
of what type of threat they pose to you
and oh by the way you're never act truly
zero threat there's no such thing okay
but you take that and you say okay well
we have these vulnerabilities over here
right this is technical risk
so we are exposed because we are putting
intellectual property at risk we are
putting assets at risk we may be putting
physical people at risk right so you
talked to the legal department the legal
department hated me and loved me at the
same time right if when I did my job
I made work for other people okay
the patching team the product security
team they could they could not ignore
when I had documented that there was an
exploit out there for a technical risk
the physical security team could not
ignore once I put it in writing that
there was a ticket for a threat against
a badge reader the finance team couldn't
ignore me when I had said hey here's
this problem over here okay so you have
to find the other areas where they're
talking about risk so that you can start
to talk about threats exploiting them
whether it's a person somebody else in a
building that you own a neighbor in the
building that you so that's how you want
to get if you want to pivot look at
concepts governance risk and compliance
right look at how red teams are going to
do a penetration test and you do it in
Reverse if they have to do a physical
pen test on a building how do they get
in there is where you're looking at
threats for threat actors because the
red team is supposed to be the bad guy
this is an amazing example of that if
you know him Jason Street amazing he's
up there gonna get in right so look at
how they're doing things and the reports
they're putting out take that model and
go back and say how would somebody do
this to us that help any other question
yes sir
okay so I will tell you what happens
with insider threat people pay attention
to that in cycles about every five years
okay like seriously it's EDS and flows
go back and want just look at news posts
insider threat is something that's
always a threat you think you've got it
down right so if you want to talk about
the rest of that you need to start
talking to your HR team right say about
okay how are we doing job descriptions
how are we vetting people in key roles
right it's illegal
supposedly in some countries to do
background checks on people where you
actually goes to do stuff like that but
guess what the threat intelligence team
can do the threat intelligence team can
assess risk that critical hires pose to
the corporation so unless you have an
intelligence requirement that says they
are concerned about this person you are
at a strategics
enterprise level the threat intelligence
team unless asked by the HR team right
and this is where you start sharing
right when if say they have I don't know
maybe they're on a development team a
dev ops team right they need to be
having that conversation up to HR HR
comes over to the CISO and says hey we
have a potential insider threat or we
have some concern about this person
right but again this goes back to should
you be working on it maybe it depends
okay are you a startup company that has
200 people are you a multi-billion
dollar company that has 200,000 people
great if you're a startup company with
200 people and they are smart enough
they want to have a threat intelligence
team in a start-up amazing yay kudos I
don't think it's happening but yes you
may have time scope and availability
because if you're hunting something you
can't be
hunting and developing and analyzing a
and B and C and D and E so is inside
without a problem yes is it an InfoSec
problem only no is it an HR problem only
no could the threat intelligence team
augment our help yes would you normally
know because you're typically at a
strategic level does that make sense
that doesn't mean that you can't or you
won't right but if you guys have if you
think you have like a faction inside the
company that's gonna try to overthrow it
or still a bunch of stuff and walk out
okay that might be something more a
single individual it's gonna depend upon
what that individuals role is whether or
not the threat intelligence team would
be concerned about that does that make
sense well yes and no so when when in
talking with HR teams when they start to
understand that what they'll typically
do is they'll say okay thread it thread
until team you can ask for demographic
data without having individuals names
I'll give an example if I worked in the
Ukraine I might want demographic data
about who's pro-western or who's not
who's pro-russia and who's not right um
nationality city of origin and burst
regional loyalties right the HR can give
me information about these groups of
people right or you guys can proactively
go out figure out who's targeting your
thing and then see who in your company
is dumb enough to participate in these
gatherings and the
politically driven meetings and then you
could say hey here's here's a problem
yoosh at the threatened tall teen level
probably would not be getting names of
individual people's to be doing
investigations and you wouldn't - he's
right you have so as the threat
intelligence part of it is you have to
build relationships with the other
departments in your company because they
don't understand what you can do to help
them and when you're saying hey I'm here
to reduce our risk and help you with
these things I literally sent out emails
to managers and key roles and said hey
I'm the new threat Intel Bubba and I'm
here to help my job is to hunt threats
and help us avoid them right not respond
to them so is there anything you're
concerned about my five SEC team said
hey we're kind of concerned about any
attacks or weaknesses in this product
well guess what the product doesn't
didn't necessarily have a problem so I
asked him it's okay well tell me who the
company is who your sales rep is and all
this other stuff I looked into the cells
are up and found out some really sketchy
stuff that I don't think his employer
knew and I was like hey I might not deal
with that cells are up right so go down
sent it sent it over to the marketing
department hey I'm here I talked to them
what kind of business intelligence do
you guys use
what are you doing from a brand
monitoring this that in the other found
out what they were doing and I'm like
okay so what kinds of things if they
stumble across my desk while our mouths
filtering the on the internet would
you like me to toss over the fence to
you if I find them and they'll tell me
hey we'd like to know about these five
things if you find out anything about it
cool not a problem
so I started finding out what everybody
else might be interested in knowing that
they didn't have enough cycles to
process or dig into but they they it's
been on their board right brought that
back to my boss and I said well here's
that list of potential priority Intel
it's requirements now you tell me which
ones matter to the company and which
ones matter to the CEO which ones tie to
our mission vision and our quarterly or
annual goals for the year you tell me
which ones of these I need to work on
because when I said priority
intelligence requirement to my boss he
said Oh what okay I had another hand
over here and I got two minutes
all right well did anybody learn
anything today okay I am always
available for questions my DM stay open
I'm at GRC underscore ninja my blog is
OSINT dot fail
feel free to DM me if you guys have any
questions thanks for staying in sincere
thank you to TAS are stepping up last
minute doing this dry without slides so
that's another round of applause for
please