all right welcome to ubiquitous chills
I'm John borne flow I'm a penetration
tester security engineer that type of
thing I teach for sans and do
independent consulting on my company's
fundamental security
I love security it's just a fun right
and I think that's why we're all here
but I teach hacker techniques and
instant handling for sans I also teach
the pin test class ambition penetration
testing it's a little bit about like why
I chose this talk is one of those times
I didn't really feel like I chose the
talk I felt like the talk kind of chose
me right so I don't year and a half ago
something like that my boss kind of came
to me and said hey we're gonna go this
direction I need you to kind of do this
project right there's one of those
moments is like really cuz I think it's
time for me to leave all right
and so I lined up like a consulting gig
who's gonna have like a four month
contract somewhere put in my two-week
notice
all right one week into my two-week
notice I get word that the seaso that I
was gonna be working for got laid on
right going
and so like contract was gone - all
right so lesson number one of into
Pickens independent consulting have some
sort of like get paid contract like
project ends right doesn't happen so I
was in this situation where like I don't
have income I no longer have a job okay
and you took whatever work I could get
so yes option came up somebody's doing a
look
you know project they're taking a look
at somebody's Network and included
reviewing their ubiquity Wireless can
fit good big I'm a network guy that's
kind of where I cut my teeth in the IT
world like all right no problem I'll dig
into that so I dive into um ubiquity
right and put the tools it's kind of
cool right so it's a little bit look at
the company itself because who is it
were they doing what kind of products
they have where is it picnic in the
environment etc and really kind of a
cool story all right so the equipment
manufacturer self focus on like small
medium sized businesses real heavy focus
on
wireless ISPs okay I'll get to why in
just a minute the CEO like a billionaire
like five point nine billion dollar
networks something like that last I saw
owns the Grizzlies and like he just
turned 40 right
he was like killing it and I'm like I'm
speaking at Derby con so the company is
like approaching a billion dollars net
worth itself right I he bought the
Grizzlies when he was 35
hey it's crushing it okay so a little
bit like how it got started his name's
Robert Pera was working at Apple right
he was testing all the Wi-Fi gear at
Apple and looking to make sure like that
with all the regulations and everything
in terms would like electromagnetic
emissions and that kind of stuff and he
kind of noticed like these things are
way under power we could like crank the
power on these devices and like shoot
Wi-Fi shots like really long distances
so he took it to his boss he's all hard
charging okay we could do this this is
an opportunity and the boss is like
Pat's him on the head and says go away
with the Schnapper all right yeah pay
your dues here before you go do
something funny exciting like that so
its first year at the job like killed
himself did all the extra could and got
like a 2 out of 5 when his review like
yeah thanks try again next year right no
raise
okay and like his salary at that point
he's reported to be about $65,000 a year
on California right that's not much the
dudes smart right he went to work at
applicants i lysing Steve Jobs right and
then like just kind of all the hopes and
dreams kind of get crushed well he's
like okay well they don't want to do
this I'm gonna start going into it on my
own you know I work on nights and
weekends by hardware mess with chipsets
and all that good stuff he did that so
about like 2005 ish he's like ready to
go to market with with a chip but he
quickly figured eyes like he's got these
chips he can shoot these Wi-Fi shots
really long range right but the problem
was once everybody else kind of figured
out what he was doing he knew he'd be
screwed
alright cuz something else is just gonna
copy it and undercut him
with the scale and so what he started
doing is like saying okay how did Apple
succeed at this so he took and figured
out how he could package Alden together
to make all this stuff work really well
really easily and then deployed at a low
cost
so what he did was he started folks on
his wireless ISPs and packaged
everything together shooting long range
Wi-Fi shots he could get a house online
for 200 bucks whereas two antennas for
the competing ISPs you're looking at
between five and ten thousand dollars
and supporting the research they did at
that time so that was pretty good so he
had like this early market into wiles
ISPs used everywhere for like rural and
undeveloped areas okay so real popular
in lesser developed countries
real popular all the rural places around
the United States okay okay
cool well as I got thinking about is
like you know I think I've heard of
ubiquity before now seems like they've
been in the news recently alright so I
start doing a little bit of searching
like just see what's been out there
right first thing I came across oops
right so they got hit by like the the
money transfers schemes where they're
trying to steal money like to convince
people to move money around one way or
the other kind of an elaborate scheme
it's not the simple like oh this
person's just stupid they didn't
validate no they emailed using multiple
different email addresses right send 14
wire transfers over 17 days so it wasn't
like they just asked him hey can you
just transfer forty six point seven
million dollars alright oh I wasn't how
work they had a bunch of different
transfers over several different days
they're emailing multiple people within
the company and in the process there
they were telling them that the
information the transfers had to do with
in acquisition so they weren't allowed
to talk about all right and all the
emails were like from lawyers are
claiming to be lawyers etc which had
credence to that and keeping it quiet so
then like the natural process of
checking to make sure that somebody you
know did request a transfer or not
didn't happen because they've got this
reason to keep it quiet okay now they
did get most of it back but I think they
losing arounds like for $17 something
like that in the long run there's a lot
better than that 46 but like okay well
know what right oh and then the email
address right it wasn't from their
actual law firm right the email address
they're using was from consultant comm
sounds official right all right
ubiquitous worms so Ubiquiti Networks
targeted by a firmware worm alright so
this was a world just went around sprint
through all the farmers using like known
vulnerabilities default passwords and
that kind of stuff right
and it kind of turned into ubiquitous
bricks because then we had like brick
robot going about there's multiple
iterations of brick or block right
there's three or four of them and so
brick or bot was like pedis or permanent
denial service and connect up the device
it's hard a whole bunch of different
things that cameras other types and it's
not just ubiquity but ubiquity is a big
target with wood brick or bot so when in
and then it would just start copying
random stuff into all the places in
flash so like eventually just guilds
built the box and that's kind of mean
and nasty
okay so additional stuff that did here
different ways that got in their way at
the firm denial service had arbitrary
file uploads and dropped their
vulnerabilities with two major things
that I saw right then they had the
really big use this one was like the
kind of thing you just got slap your
head and then scratch it cuz like I put
a 20 year old vulnerability into a brand
new piece of equipment but it's like
yeah I kind of say when I teach like
like IOT stuff anymore I swear it's it's
wormholes too like the 80s and 90s yeah
that's really what it is cuz like you
just jump in there's like oh look okay
things that we thought we fixed 20 years
ago we're back again alright so what
well as I got to look at all this stuff
like oh you know that's all that stuff
right so once you issues bunch of simple
things not even hardly anybody you're
gonna build a brand new project starting
today you
go get a 20 year old version of PHP I
mean like so there's some serious
oversight missing and how they're going
about its business off the ground and
getting these products to market all
right
so you see that mini stuff you know
they've got some issues well we'll go
back to the that first project right I
get in there and once I start digging
into the the product itself I seen what
it can do I was really kind of impressed
a whole bunch of different like
enterprise features and he was cheap
right like so cheap like I'll demo this
stuff in just a second here but you get
into ubiquity anybody who's ubiquity
users everybody came to find out all you
have to do the demo right you're like
online I'll quickly go over that second
all right so this is a demo box
available out on ubiquity site all right
so you can just go through this is
actually set up I don't know if this is
the actual live equipment at the the
Grizzlies basketball arena or not but it
they've made it at least look like it is
okay but you dive in here you can see
throughput latency stuff you can kick
off speed tests all right so it'll run a
speed test on the internet connection
and give you an idea you know what your
bandwidth is looking like at the moment
all right nice suppose you ran land WLAN
stuff over here you can see all the
devices that you've got set up and when
it says devices it's talking about the
network here itself for clients it shows
you all the different clients the
channels are connected to you can see
throughput latency all sorts of data has
this calls it deep packet inspection
you've got to have the firewall or the
security gateways for that to show up
I don't really call it the packet
inspection I think it's more like oh it
went to this domain it must be Facebook
and social media right like it's it's
not extremely intelligent but it's at
least some idea what's going on there as
you go into other stuff there's
statistics here you can analyze you know
what
going on with the different channels the
devices you know are they using which
frequency are they using that kind of
stuff the map stuff is pretty cool you
can integrate Google Maps into this I
can put an API key for Google Maps and
then drop it in it'll also show you your
topology that's good that's really slow
it's really big this works better on a
smaller network but I'll switch the maps
you can see than that there we go so you
can see all the devices they've got
inside the basketball arena and and the
coverage roughly and you can click on
individual devices and take a look at
you know the information about that see
the details all right what's the our
frequency for that specific device I
mean this is all like just included in
the software and the hardware and you
can get into this software and hardware
for as cheap as like between 60 and 80
bucks all you need is to buy an Access
Point install the software which you
download for free from their site and
you're off and running right like 80
bucks or you can go by like a hundred
and fifty dollar Linksys router that
really didn't all that great or you can
buy something like this right well you
all have it okay so I mean really really
pretty impressive in terms of what it
can do
clients keeps track of all the different
clients you can take a look at
individual client coming here tell it to
use a fixed IP address and then assign
that IP address to it and it's going to
reserve it I mean real simple management
gives an easy way to keep an inventory
of your home network which is what I've
really loved about having it myself you
know
and then as you're digging into the
access points themselves you've got all
sorts of different options here all
right so you've got the the tools and
then we've got this debug terminal now
they've got this disabled on this site
here all right so we have to switch this
is actually my home site I'm going to
open up the debug terminal here
that's a shell all right now notice
we've got a see it we've got a pound
sign there which means Ruth right did I
authenticate to it
no I'll indicate it to my website right
so to get to the management site but
that's it okay it handles everything
else now it goes about doing that with
WebRTC all right and that's what it's an
area like I'm going to continue
researching after this because it
includes like using s done and all that
so you like it reaches out to a third
party to help exchange the negotiation
for the authentication back and forth
it's insane right
can't believe that that's set up
properly but either way at this point
I've got a root shell now okay it's a
root shell well what are we running
right so it is Linux and you've got just
about everything you want to do with
Linux okay now you're running busybox it
is a MIPS processor so you're limited a
little bit with what you can do however
like you've got all the makings of a
start into somebody's environment all
right
all right so roof shell now here's the
crazy piece right it has this wonderful
cloud management feature how many of you
use the cloud management feature not
very many good right like far less hands
okay so cloud management feature all you
all you have to have is the account out
at ubiquity site right so if you go out
to their site you can just click the
register button okay now so I create an
account right I'm John Gorham flow so
I'm gonna look for that try and get Jake
warm flow everywhere I go well like I
didn't bother disclosing it to evic wa t
it discloses itself right so as you type
it's doing like the JavaScript either I
don't know if it's on key press or
whatever but basically it's sending
every few seconds whatever's in these
boxes out to ubiquity and saying hey is
there a user with that name okay well
that's kind of bad right so then what do
you think most people do like if they've
got their if they're like the super
league wizard hacksaw or 73 alright and
that's what they use everywhere well
they've got super super bleep hacks or
wizards 73 is their user name what do
you think their email addresses at
gmail.com at yahoo.com at hotmail calm
not outlook calm right and so
so not only does it do that with the
username field it also does it on the
email address field so then I take the
user name and I just start appending
Yahoo Gmail whatever to it to take a
wild guess right and so get that where I
got the the start of this user name in a
minute
but I just found of what it was a
potential user name typed it in and then
just started guessing on the domains
started with Gmail is well we're all
owned by Google at this point right
thank you
it took me about three different users
like acquiring user names before I found
one had it synced up like this now and
that's just going with personal domains
if I can figure out this user ID and
then trace it back to the company that
they work at you think that they
probably have you know their company
email address set up for their company
access oh absolutely
all right all right so then we have the
the profile setting right so when you
set up your account out at ubiquity you
get a couple different things set up one
you get set up so you can go access the
cloud management features right and then
it also sets up a forum account for
their communities all right anybody
noticed something like sort of related
there yeah the name that shows up in the
community is your user name you can use
that to log in all right well that's
what makes it relatively easy right so
then I can go through I take all the
different users that identify in the
community out on the forums start
guessing Yahoo Gmail etc do the research
on them find out what company they work
at try their domain name and I've got
potential access to their system right
and then well okay so we've got like
these user IDs every like what's the
likelihood that somebody's actually be
able to exploit that right well we'll go
back to my friend that I found earlier
today and seven breaches
seven breach sites and one paste I mean
his username and at least password her
password hash has been identified in
something like pastebin or somewhere
similar yeah okay so now like I said it
only took me like three or four users
going through the forums to like take
the username guest user name validated
against the user registration guess that
it was a gmail account and then checking
have I been phone I can see he's already
been pop all right is it really all that
hard to go find these password dumps not
in those cases alright so how else can
we get the username well so the first
thing I did was you know you can go
through the forums right well so then I
start looking at the web app a little
bit more and I click on a few different
users profiles I noticed that there's
this nice little number up in the users
profile all right in the URL just a
number so you can start iterating
through on on those numbers and you're
just you're discovering more users right
so the the top example here is going
through and just iterating through those
numbers alright so we set off a loop
starting it you know eight hundred
thirteen thousand one hundred through
two hundred pick it off and then it just
does curl grabs that information back
gets crepes it out cuts it out dumps it
out this screen right now down below
here is another way to you just go
through and start crawling through the
form itself and take all usernames if
you discover on the form drop to the
file and take those and then guess it
either against the ubiquity API to see
if there's Gmail Yahoo whatever go that
way and then take that same kind of
approach with the have I been poned API
right you didn't know there's an API
it's absolutely free to use it have i
but vin poem you can easily make those
calls and check it for compromised
accounts now that all sounds like okay
so we've got some issues right here's
where it got really scary for me as i
started digging into my profile settings
alright the false security settings
session timeout yeah really like I
realized that's convenient especially
for the forum's right but if I can log
into their website and then go down and
connect in to my house or my place of
business place it is I did that during
that assessment I forgot to check
something one day my home at night I
like oh I'll just do it this way they
gave me all the password so I could
manage this stuff right and I was able
to check something remotely using a
shell I'm like who's like pivoting
through the Ubiquiti here to get other
parts of the network legitimately right
but still what I was doing all right now
cool thing they do offer to factor how
many people have to factor in abled on
their account hopefully those are all
the same hands that said they're using
the cloud access right with the cloud
connection to manage this stuff from the
internet okay so you set that stuff up
create token and stuff now the problem
is how many people like to use
two-factor well I mean people like the
security two-factor offers but don't
necessarily like using two-factor right
most people it rarely makes it easier
right it's very rare that to fact
there's an easy smooth awesome process
all right so then oK we've got all this
stuff we've got like remote access into
people's environments and then we've got
all these issues out on the internet how
much stuff is out there all right so I
started using showed in doing some
searches trying to figure out what's out
there
what what what how much is the world
actually using this stuff well probably
quite a bit since its new a billion
dollar company so the scary thing is I
started doing this jodean searches stuff
was coming back and finding all these
devices out there and I've got stuff
showing up on weird course and I've got
things like the second one here is port
1900 which is what the universal plug in
play alright so people's universal plug
and play is exposing ubiquity stuff to
the internet they don't even know
they're exposing it to the Internet
right it's a little bit scarier okay
because now I don't even have to have
access to the cloud stuff so access your
network if you put it out there you
don't even know the universal plug and
play is like broadcasting stuff out to
the Internet you're exposed and you
don't even know it's there
right then they got even scarier for me
the number of like MongoDB which all the
configuration stuff for the web app is
saved in MongoDB which like has a great
reputation for security right now but
worse like it at least son William so
software by default it puts it on the
local interface right so you got to hit
it via 17.00 about one some people
apparently thought it was a good idea to
put it on the internet directly right
that's brightening okay so I'm like okay
well how much is actually out there oh
right now that's not all management
servers a lot of that's equipment rights
Wireless adhere the longer-range Wi-Fi
shots and that kind of stuff it's a
mixture of all of that
okay now the unify though unifies
anything that has a unifying the name
that is there Wi-Fi lineup right and
that is more like Wi-Fi let me just even
through home and hope of use a lot okay
and then I was doing more research than
last week and still macrosse1 in the
name of the router had been changed
right the name of router was changed to
hack router help
SOS boom EDB three nine seven oh one
like they were at least kind enough to
tell them exactly how they did it right
I wish I could do pen test reports like
this right
my child would be a lot easier but so I
go through a check you're like what's
the count on those okay and it's not
just this vulnerability it's a whole
bunch of other ones so they change like
hack router help SOS and it tells you
like duplicate password and a few other
things that it like other ways that they
compromised the devices okay sometimes
you hate internet trolls and sometimes
you love them all right
and now we've got ubiquitous customers
so this is a conversation I saw happen
on Twitter right so this guy message
Troy hunt and I saw a photo hi Troy hunt
this guy is in the UK right and his ISP
set up their CP so the customer first
equipment sets out that stuff button but
set all the device name two names and
addresses of their customers okay
well he's like basically it's like
broadcasting stuff out so he plugged
into his own unit by switch and then his
home management server started sucking
in all those usernames and detecting all
the devices that his unified switch
could now see you layer - okay and so
then like he lets his his service
provider know and you're like threatened
to shut him off right really
GDP GDP are much you know I mean so I
messaged you miss I go okay give me the
full story like what was actually
happening here so this was his home set
up like it basically he set it up this
way because he's like he's running out
of power outlets I had to kind of in a
premium premium at his apartment so he
wanted to use the ADA 2.11 not home to
use the power of Ethernet features of
the switch to power their access point
all right so he fires that up plugs in
and that's when it starts sucking all
that data in okay so basically it's the
field name for the clients I saw a
little bit in the demo a few minutes ago
it has the names in the first lines of
the addresses so I asked him like okay
so what kind of names addresses
who's in there like any celebrities like
politicians anything like that not quite
that exciting but there are a lot of
business names right not-for-profits etc
that we're customers of this is P and
now and you know there is P had all the
private IP addresses for the management
stuff so it was all 10.5 dot whatever
okay so okay I love the victory here but
the problem here is we've got a lot of
people that made it so easy to set this
stuff up that anybody can do it whether
this should or not right so we've got a
lot of people like going into the wisp
business or the Wireless ISP business
that have either limited or no IT
experience right or they're some of
these nephew that was kind of good at IT
they did a bunch of small businesses and
that kind of thing you've got folks know
those things and can get these things
set up but may not necessarily have any
security mindset at all all right we've
already talked about all the different
vulnerabilities that the gears had and
how easy it is to get this stuff
misconfigured and expose yourself to
some pretty nasty stuff all right now
wait here okay now you're all here
because you all have the equipment all
right or you know me one of the two okay
but this is why you should care they're
starting to make this big push to get
into corporations they've got like the
Wireless ISP market cornered all right
you've got the best gear they've got
proprietary technology for those long
range shots way that you timing and all
that with the signals so they're not
losing customers there if anything I'm
just gonna pick up more so as they have
developed that lack buy stuff they're
getting the pushing into the enterprise
market so we're gonna start seeing this
stuff stuff pop up in smaller and medium
businesses even more I think you're
gonna start seeing it pop up and your
companies as well because this is the
kind of thing in the tech enthusiast
you're gonna have it on their network
now you're gonna try and bring it to
work this is awesome we need to have
this set up
that's how iPhone has made it into the
enterprise right not saying that was a
bad thing but it's how they did it they
got an invoice personal stuff a personal
phone it was just you know then the
executives took it in and said I have to
have this
so we've got ubiquitin hard into the
enterprises you're gonna start seeing
this either from a deployment standpoint
your environment and you have to know
how to configure it and harden it and
you can also see it coming if you're a
pen tester things you're gonna have to
understand unfortunately doesn't take
that much to understand it it's just
pretty simple all right real quick on
connecting the Mongo database so it's
kind of old the MongoDB version that
it's using is like Cupid 2015 alright so
you have to good download previous
versions I've got like the links out
there using the download the older
versions I had download you got 4.1 for
to actually get it to connect on my host
I've got the controller right now
running on a Windows box and so you
connect up there's all sorts of
information this is just an example okay
so you connect the database so using the
Mongo client you go use given the
database name which is a spy default and
so DB admin dot fine which is kind of
like selects card you know home table
gives you everything so this is the the
admin collection so we've got the
username of admin and then X shadow
which is hash of the admin password
I have readwrite access here so I can
either change it so I don't have to have
the password to get access to the web
app fine just get access to the host
that's running the controller software I
can connect to the Mongo database and
insert my own hash or whatever I want it
to be worse is you dig into other parts
of the database and these are things I'm
not including up here there's a lot of
stuff in it's clear text that you
wouldn't expect to be clear text all
right so if you have any type of radius
profile with secret keys oh yeah clear
text all the Wi-Fi passwords if you're
using pre-shared keys clear text you go
through and dig through it's amazing
what's in there it's just plain text and
easy to pull out you could also then
change it if you wanted to all the
configuration items for how all of
ubiquity gear and Mongo database
so at that point if I can get access to
the host without password or anything I
can either just change the password here
or insert my own hash to get access
create my own user whatever I want to do
or if I know Mongo won't up I could just
write out myself and make all the
changes directed okay no security now
beyond that let's say you're on a
network and you're looking for the
wireless stuff and this is like it just
kept I kept looking for that things like
I was gonna do this really wicked
awesome cool specialized hack I never
got there
like the more I went the more I found
stuff I'm like really okay it's like
this if you kill the controller software
on on the controller the devices
apparently get lonely and they start
pinging through the controller
all right non-stop and they're just
broadcasting out on port 10,001 and
spewing all their personal information
at the same time right so this is just a
TCP dump or we're looking for UDP port
10,001 Dublin dump out in the ascii form
so you see I've got it marked out here
so I've got two things on my network
right so the number one for both these
that's the the host name that I gave it
right so this is something that I can
control in terms what it is also going
to be descriptive within an actual
company then - you're looking at like
the model of the device that it is right
3 is the hardware so like the QC a 9 5 6
X that's Qualcomm chip set what that is
Paul comma 8 grows er E 120 down below
that's the ER as edge router that's
actually ubiquitous information about
the device the ebon pointing is specific
to the security gateways and then number
4 is probably my favorite here all right
next full revision level on the firmware
that is running so there's all sorts of
vulnerabilities in their firmware in the
management consoles in the software etc
throughout
all their different hardware if you
can't talk to the host right it's just
starts spewing that out to the to the
network as a whole just it makes it easy
to get the information to customize an
exploit etc okay and so if you're on a
network if you can just kill or
denial-of-service the controller they're
gonna start spewing this information out
all right so let's go back to the show
so on on the box you get onto that ap
all right we've got netcat TCP dump curl
ash which is a watered-down version of a
shell an SSH client and DNS mask all
right con that a lot of that stuff is
from busybox okay so the downside there
is like you don't necessarily have
anything that's all fantastic right so
they're like netcat for example it's
busybox netcat it's not like
full-featured netcat that's like you can
connect to another host on a port and
that's it right not all that fun ash
well it's just not - yes sage client
limited like it doesn't do some of the
newer ciphers and stuff like that so
it's again very very limited everything
else that's cool about Linux you can
still do now you've got to go back in
time a little bit if you're more
familiar it's like more modern versions
of bashing and I can do some of your
scripting language stuff in there you
got to go back a little further to do it
in in ash but it all still works okay
now the real cool thing though is DNS
mask there's what does DNS mask what can
I do with that
anything right so like with DNS master
kind of limited to your own creativity
there's other stuff on there too have to
add the voice so EB tables everything
with et tables it's like layer to IP
tables okay and so it even has features
like natty right like MAC address
matters seems little crazy but basically
if you do maca MAC address natty on an
AP what are you gonna be able to do it's
going to come in destined for one that
and
Mack can go out another one right so can
kind of reroute that stuff that's all
the makings for man-in-the-middle right
and not just man in the middle on the AP
because like I said it's miss you're
gonna be looming in terms of what you
can actually run on the device but you
can do man the little by doing the MAC
address forwarding you do that that Mac
nap
it's gonna be able to forward to another
post it may be the control on the
network and you man in the middle there
now if we want to upgrade this stuff
like how we get these things on the box
well you've got some other stuff that's
built in it makes it a little a little
bit easier okay
the home directory is when you log in is
in var at C persistent and we need easy
way to get the tools on the Box well I
don't like typing and so I wrote a nice
little script right I call it the Adobe
tools right so do a curl - she'll go out
to the bitly link right because
otherwise it's really long and pulls us
down from github which will then go out
and it'll download a bunch of different
nips binaries so they will just find by
googling around a little bit
alright so it downloads netcat lua a
full-featured version of the tcp dump
sinful adoption right because some quasi
can then do the denial service to kill
the controller all right and then start
watching to see who broadcasts out what
the and then I can actually get a full
featured version of bash - okay so
downloads all that stuff puts it in the
persistent directory and then from there
it will be there any time you need to
use it
all right so this is me ssh directly
into my my access point
no cheating i'm gonna copy and paste on
this alright that's so now i've got the
script downloads all the tools alright
so now I can do and it's full-featured
netcat at that one right now this works
for just about anything that you can get
in terms of MIPS binaries now there's
some other stuff out there that I could
get the MIPS binaries but it didn't work
for it didn't work on on the AP for
instance like better cap it doesn't work
on there there's actually an open ticket
out on github to compile that properly
so it'll work on this hardware because
it's not working at the moment so that
it can be used on things like Wi-Fi
pineapples etc and so something
hopefully hopefully will be compiled
soon I haven't a chance to try and do it
myself yet alright okay so we've got
neck cat so what right well yeah there
we go a few people have taken some 504
and 560 classes alright so this is a box
that I have out a digital ocean alright
so you can see it's public IP address on
the access point to create our back pipe
file first
set this up so I've got I'm digitalocean
sir if I'm going to do in cat which is
the that cat comes with in map right
we're gonna listen on 2 2 2 2 & 3 3 3
right and then on the access point we're
going to connect 2 3 2 3 3 on the
digitalocean box all right but we've
also got neck hat here which is going to
connect to a Windows box at my house on
4 4 4 5 okay
we can see that connections established
you need another session here
we're gonna pee a dress
thank you
she had that ready screen use exploit
and those 17 yes Zack
I don't keep that off of you in second
I'm good I guess like you're actually
gonna see a password
that's been a fantastic well he do it
work
I just forgot to add derbycon to local
admin group but you can see like we
connected up at that point going from my
cloud server through the netcat shell
and connecting back to that network
compromising the Windows machine in
there and now the time here so I'll go
quick through the rest of this alright
so other ideas and what else we can do
so things like better cap in map better
versions of SSH compile those with a
nips all right that'll work on the hosts
all right the other thing that the I've
been doing some research on is using the
DNS mask to do all sorts of stuff so it
has all sorts of things built in to the
APS so that you can use it for Wi-Fi
hotspots and that kind of stuff
firewalling paywalls and that kind of
stuff all those options built right into
the AP so it has the ability to launch a
web server etc and you can use DNS masts
to issue IP addresses issued DNS which
if I can show you DNS I control just
about everything right so kind of nasty
stuff alright then options to set up the
persistent through reboots ok if you
went to Darrow Highlands talk this
morning he talked all about how you can
who write the flash and that kind stuff
on IOT devices and in control and
basically persist you know past reboots
cetera alright so this is the cloud key
this is a piece of hardware they sell
its power over ethernet right and it's
about this big
right it's like three or four inches and
so this has like a quad-core processor
in it Snapdragon processor has a SD card
slot so you can put like and it comes
with an 8 gigabyte SD card they can put
in there alright so and it runs Debian
right Debian 8
at that point right that's one heck of a
Dropbox in my opinion all right you just
disable all the ubiquity stuff and you
can start installing your own tool so
things like the pen testers framework
works really well on there all right has
pipe on that point great for creating
that shell and into an environment
because our ethernet is really common
anymore because it's where all right we
have to have it for boat boy right
wireless access points etc in Court of
environments so that's pretty cool and
they just release this like I was
watching it's hoping to buy one before
Derby con but it was only available in
like the the advanced purchase thing
right the partner program or whatever
this is the next version of it and this
is the unify software also controls like
video cameras and stuff and so this
device acted has like a 1 terabyte hard
drive built into it alright I've not
finding the specs for the processor and
all that but I was at imagine it's gonna
be similar to the Snapdragon processor
and all that so forget in the sign so is
it for now
like I have a lot more research I plan
on doing any questions at this point
so I didn't report any of this to
ubiquity because what is it a report
right your users are misusing their
products you know like the the only
thing that I probably could have
reported out of what I've shown so far
is the username enumeration on the
website but it kind of discloses itself
so I didn't really see the point right
beyond that like it's not really
exploiting the gear itself it's
exploiting bad configurations that's it
wide open now like I said by default it
is listening on the local interface
what's that he asked if the Mongo
database is wide open by default and
yeah it's wide open by default no
authentication necessary is connected up
to it you can touch support you can make
configuration changes to the ubiquity
stuff right I just update the database
now actually the scarier thing so you
asked if there's Pete if I didn't
research the people that are packaging
up the unify sock where the the
management controller on raspberry pi's
right so though packets add up kind of
sell it and a lot of people just you
know buy a PI and install it themselves
in their home that way the scarier thing
for me is there's people running unify
as a service as a business and so they
set up unify controllers out at places
like digitalocean and Amazon and all
that and then charge people to host all
that out there yeah I'm getting the stop
sign so thank you all very much