hello everyone I'm Ryan O'Grady I'm a
research scientist with a small research
company called soar technology and we
focus on artificial intelligence and in
particular I focus on the inner
intersection of artificial intelligence
and cybersecurity so I'm just a it's up
front I get nervous and I get nervous I
talk really fast we talk really fast you
know so if I start talking too fast
just shout slow down okay otherwise
we'll be done in five minutes so this
talk is your training data is bad and
you should feel bad
and hopefully ways to make you not feel
quite so bad so how did this come about
well I had a pretty simple question can
i detect botnet command and control on
twitter using machine learning
classifier so I started digging into
that and going okay well you know
there's all these tools out there all I
needed some labeled bina data right well
that's easier said than done the
availability of of data is low labeled
beta is almost non-existent and recent
labeled beta forget it you just give up
and go home so then I started thinking
well I found this data set from 2011
that's that's good enough right and it
got me wondering trends change how
people use technology changes is that
data actually meaningful anymore so I I
asked myself the question how does data
age and more formally to what extent
does the recency of training data affect
the performance of machine learning
classifiers trained on that data in
other words can I use old data to draw
meaningful conclusions about new content
so what I was really interested in was
is a given tweet or set of tweets or
account really a bot well as I said I
don't have good data for that so I
thought okay if I want to answer this
question about the recency of data what
information do I have so I decided that
verified as a stand-in for trusted is a
reasonable place to start so I started
looking at you know can I determine if a
if a tweet comes from a verified account
no I know a lot of you're thinking
that's not the same as a bot I know but
we have to start somewhere so in order
to answer this question I needed to
collect data thank you that's sorry
that's already labeled data each tweet
includes whether it's from a verified
user or not so that makes my life easier
so I just need to go out and collect
around 1,500 tweets for each year the
verified program was initialized in 2010
so that's where I started was 2010
thanks to the kind people at Twitter and
the limitations they placed on the API
that meant I had to gather four million
tweets and I can get more into that
later if you're interested but basically
you can only get the 4,000 most recent
tweets and for a verified account that
might be a year it might be less so for
each year I trained a classifier with
data from that year and then tested it
against data from every other year so in
2010 I trained a classifier on that data
I then tested it against determining if
tweets are verified or not in 2010 2011
2012 and so on up to 2018 that gave me
the data that you see in the in the
upper left there which is kind of a
square year-by-year grid but that's not
how I think about the data how I want to
actually think about the data is what is
the offset between the training year and
the test year so you can see I shifted
all the data so that all of the plus 0
meaning 2010 training data and 2010 test
data 2011 training data to us loading
test data all lines up and all of the
conclusions I'm going to going to
discuss are based on that representation
of the data
you don't need to be able to read that
don't worry I'm just showing you how
that process works so how did I actually
measure the performance of these
classifiers well the first thing you're
gonna find if you start looking in
machine learning is accuracy accuracy is
a garbage metric I didn't use it for
four reasons I'll explain it's
especially bad for what are called
imbalance classes which for verified
that's exactly what it is 95% of
accounts are unverified so what does
that mean if I am a lazy machine
learning classifier and I just say yeah
sure it's it's unverified I'm gonna be
writing 95 percent of the time but I
didn't do anything so we needed to find
a better way to measure performance
that's why I settled on the Matthews
correlation coefficient it uses all the
elements of a confusion matrix I won't
get into that but the bottom line for us
is that if a lazy machine learned
classifier says yeah sure it's
unverified the correlation coefficient
is going to be zero meaning no
correlation it has to actually make
predictions about the least and most
popular class in this case unverified
and verified in order for it to actually
have any measurable impact on the
correlation coefficient
I put an asterisk here because it
doesn't matter there are some edge cases
where you just say it's equal to zero
and you just move on but by and large if
you're predicting zero for all the
classes this is going to be zero at the
end of the day each classifier was
trained using three distinct sets three
sets of features the first is tweak only
features those are features of the tweet
itself the content although I didn't
actually use semantic content I do I
make that clear when it was made how
quickly was made from the previous tweet
and so on the second set is user only
features these are features associated
with the user account and not the tweet
itself one was the account created how
many friends do they have and so forth
and then of course all features is both
the user features and the tweet only
feature sets combined
so now getting to the actual meat of
what I found the first finding is that
classifiers perform best at a plus zero
year offset this means that if you train
with beta from 2017 and test against
date from 2017 that has the peak
performance as you start moving away
from a zero offset either positive or
negative performance decreases now I
know you're not gasping in shock that's
not a terribly surprising conclusion but
it's it's it's an important conclusion
and one we want to be able to prove
there are some more interesting things
in there the performance of different
classifiers varies so any of the
ensemble classifiers tend to perform
best those are things like a random
random tree gradient descent anything
that combines multiple classifiers into
one I have a bucket approach SVC fared
the worst it's it's plus zero offset
performance was not bad but it quickly
approached zero as you moved away from
zero offset I should go when you look at
these numbers the 0.98 point nine one
and so forth
that's the matthews correlation
coefficient which can be interpreted as
Pearson's R that means that a value of
zero is no correlation a value of
negative one is perfect negative
correlation and a value of one is
perfect positive correlation so what
you're really looking for is a value of
approaching negative one or one so here
you can see side-by-side the performance
of the classifiers the mean performance
of the classifiers for the tweet only
versus the user only feature set you can
clearly see that performance is optimal
at plus zero offset and it does drop as
you go positive and negative you can
also see that the user only feature-set
performed significantly better than the
tweet only feature set
finding to feature importance changes
over time again not really shocking but
I just wanted to make it make it clear
that if you're using the same feature
set that you derived in 2010 as in 2018
your performance is going to degrade
using the tweak only features
performance didn't really degrade
because it wasn't good to begin with so
it went from bad to bad for the user
only features though we saw a
significant drop from 0.62 2.39
the biggest change was in the user
friend count so in 2010 you your user
friend cat was a strong indicator of
whether you're a verified account or not
in 2018 that's no longer the case
what this research doesn't do is try and
answer why why these features changing
the way they did but that would be good
good future research and here you can
see the plot of the user only features
on the top and the tweet only features
on the bottom there's a bit of an odd
drop in 2017 that I couldn't explain but
the trend does hold the third finding
adding more features doesn't necessarily
increase your performance if that's an
old hold it is being given the field but
it's a machine-learning axiom more
features is better I'm saying
right here that if you add more features
if you have the all features you have
the the tweet only features into the
user features your performance is
getting worse I can't tell you how many
of my colleagues I talked to trying to
figure out what features to include and
they'd like just just throw it all in
there
you know it's fine it won't hurt the
performance well yes it will so you
can't you can't just skip the feature
selection and feature extraction step of
creating machine learning classifier
that's an important step and if you if
you skip that part you're gonna hurt
your performance I should point out that
certain classifiers were less
susceptible to this again the ensemble
classifier
tend to fare better when you started
adding extraneous features in there
others like SVC I don't mean to pick on
SVC but it it totally trashed its
performance so here you can see again
the user only performance is on the left
and it performed pretty well plus zero
and you know it dropped off but even at
you know point six on the left or a
point only 0.5 to the right of the user
only features that's still a pretty
positive correlation points but once we
add in the all features added in the
tweet only features to the set it only
dropped up for performance across the
board so what's the bottom line here
what does it all mean
again I don't want to shock anyone but
training with contemporaneous data is
going to get you the best performance of
your classifiers
that means unfortunately if you decide
you want to go out and create your own
Twitter bot classifier you're gonna have
to figure out some way to get relevant
recent data you if you just go and find
some data set off the shelf that's been
sitting there for five years maybe you
can maybe you'll get some good data
making some good good results or maybe
it'll get no better than noise there
were some of these classifiers that you
know by three years out either positive
or negative we're performing no better
than if I trained on noise and the
conclusion you might draw if you're not
careful
is that your classifier or that approach
to classification is faulty
but in fact it's just bad data again
machine learning isn't magic garbage in
you get garbage out you have to be
careful with how you select your
training data you have to be careful
with how you decide which features to
include because including experience
features can hurt your performance and
don't skimp on natural feature selection
itself and feature extraction
that's one it's been a moment to talk
about you know what are some of the
future directions that I can see this
going and it appoints some of the
limitations of the research
itself so what I've done here is said
can I use data to determine if a tweet
is from a verified or unverified account
with the assumption that that has some
correlation to determining if it if a
tweet is from a botnet or non botnet
account that's an assumption that needs
to be explored does the same approach
hold true given good botnet data and
then the Twitter limitations as I talked
about is the performance is being
observed here in spite of those
limitations or is it some artifact of
those limitations itself so for example
I could only use verified accounts that
had tweets from 2010 up 2018 that right
there is a is a you know limitation and
self sucking criteria where a lot of you
know other accounts were left out
especially high volume accounts were
left out because they put out you know
4000 tweets in the last two years I
couldn't use it so what you really need
is access to the full data stream so you
can do proper random selection of the
accounts and get the full set of data
for any given account rather than the
the limited set you can get for the free
API unfortunately didn't I didn't have a
hundred thousand dollars lying around so
I had to make do and then finally what
would be the effects of including the
semantic content I left aside the tweet
content itself entirely usernames I
didn't consider those you know how does
that affect the performance of any
classifiers if you start looking at what
they're saying what is the sentiment you
deduce a incentive analysis semantic
content analysis any of those things to
try and get a better sense of what is
the actual content of the account rather
than just the characteristics of the
metadata so if you want the full paper
it's available in the sans reading room
or if you trust a shortened link there's
the Google link I did this research as
part of the sans master's program I'm
to be part of that so if you want
talking about that I'm happy to talk to
you more about that program too so I
didn't go too fast but I still have
plenty of time left so I'd be happy to
answer questions at this point
so just to ask myself question one of
things I'm often asked is why or why do
you see this performance why is there
this degradation in feature mutual
importance and I couldn't answer that as
part of the research but I have given
some thought as to you know what's going
on here why are features becoming less
meaningful over time and I suspect it
might have to do with the fact that as
the Twitter base grows as becomes more
diverse individual features are no
longer as meaningful you have you have
accounts from all over the world you
have accounts from all different ages so
I think that as their base is growing
it's essentially watering down the
significance of any given feature and
decreasing what you can derive from that
information yeah it did not there was
actually no content analysis whatsoever
so if you want to see the features so
the tweet only features is I basically
there are more or less boolean boolean
features some of them are numeric like
the how long it's been since this is the
account was created I didn't do any kind
of was there a link was it a retweet
actually I think no sorry is a retweet
is is one of the characteristics but he
didn't for example look at okay who were
they retweeting was it another non
verified account versus verified yes and
actually shortly after I faced this
research a couple of researchers out of
where announced they had discovered a
roughly 400,000 botnet account called
the Star Wars botnet which you know I
would love to get my hands on their data
but data sharing is its own quagmire
and if you want to look the features for
users only absolutely so I mean there's
you can do some attack analysis to try
and you know reconstruct the the actual
content and say you know determine you
can determine the language I actually
toyed with that you can determine is it
content from somewhere else you can do
sentiment analysis to try to determine
it as a positive or negative tweet
there's some more advanced techniques
I'm not all that familiar with to try
and like essentially determine if it's
if it makes sense like is it a and
Twitter that I realize that's a bit of a
sucker's game but but I haven't I
haven't explored any of the actual
sentiment analysis approaches I filtered
for English tweets I filtered based on
the language field specified by the
tweet itself there there is a field that
can specify what language of the tweet
is in a lot of them come through is
unknown I didn't use those I use only en
tweets
it was trial and error actually a lot of
this was was trial and error and part of
why I want to see here was how various
classifiers perform so as you can see
here I I did use seven different
classifiers or six six seven just to
compare their performance so the answer
to your question is I didn't decide I
just chose some based on what's popular
and what seemed to make sense for the
data there was there was a before any of
the rigorous science started there was a
fair amount of just exploring the data
looking at you know what are the mean
median mode for various fields you know
what are the outliers that kind of thing
and then I started homing in on like
what I actually wanted to extract his
features and what classifiers I wanted
to use I can tell you there were several
long afternoons spent waiting for you
know a teeming classifier to finish up
because I was using thirty features and
that was going to take it 200 years to
finish and I didn't realize that until
too late so yes did I determine if there
was changes in the negative versus
positive year after year oh I think I
think that's what you're saying
so no I didn't and actually I'm going to
point out you know another shortcoming
in my in my research which is user data
is is as of the time you retrieve the
tweet okay so when I can go when I go
and get a tweet from 2010 the user data
is from 2018 or whenever I capture it if
the user data has changed significantly
in that time of course that's going to
be reflected in the update whereas the
tweet
the data is as of 2010 so if I get a
tweet from an 8-year old account the
tweet looks like it did back then but
their friend count you know number of
retweets all that all that is going to
reflect current time and that's that's
just simply a limitation of the data
that's available that I without
capturing data across time like I
started eight years ago I don't have a
good way to counteract that in the
questions
[Applause]