the b-sides DC 2016 videos are brought
to you by clear jobs net and cybersex
jobs.com tools for your next career move
and antietam technologies focusing on
advanced cyber detection analysis and
mitigation hi everybody welcome thank
you very much for coming to my talk
appreciate it the next hour of your life
is going to be so entertaining and so
fun you are not going to believe you're
in DC about how to join the information
security community and for those of you
that didn't know it it's 2016 it is we
have amazing things in 2016 we've got
hoverboards well yeah they catch fire
and they have wheels but they are
hoverboards right right we have
self-driving cars which is pretty cool
we even have let's say that you're
making dinner okay and you and you have
a great that falls on the floor and it
breaks open we have robots that can
stitch grapes together because somewhere
in the world that's a need well I mean
these things are out there and it's an
amazing amazing world we live in and
it's kind of cool because I'm at work
I'm kind of a senior person okay I've
grown up through all of the old things
that have happened and and now there's
all these new things in this world and
constantly people come to me and they
say hey you know what your senior person
would you be my mentor would you teach
me how to get into the information
security community would you teach me
how they be where you are on that side
of the desk and ultimately the
conversation moves into how do i InfoSec
what do i do to do information security
things not just at work but in other
places and so I have to introduce to my
mentees the concept of information
security industry versus information
security community there is a difference
and for those of you that have been in
the industry for a while
you'll recognize it this is the
professional you know you're going to
work you're talking with customers
you're talking with clients you're
solving solutions versus the community
we
well is you people that go to
conferences sit down and pick locks do
other things they're distinct but
there's a lot of overlap and I wish I
made a Venn diagram that shows the
overlap some people like I used to do
stay in the information security and
like I used to do and stay in the
information security industry and don't
dip their toe into the community they
don't come over here and see all the
cool things that we're doing now that's
an absolutely fine thing to do because
some people need that they feel secure
just being in the community being in the
industry or likewise some people love
being in the community without
necessarily getting into the industry
section but nowadays we have an issue we
have at least in the DC area here we've
got more jobs in InfoSec then we have
people to fill them so we have this huge
demand for people to come and do the
work for either our customers or for our
companies and that's a great position to
be in as a in person already in InfoSec
I I love having that all these companies
want me to come work for them that's
really cool if you're somebody that
actually is looking to get into InfoSec
then this talk is for you this is a talk
to help you join your InfoSec industry
life and you're in for a life isn't
necessarily that strong for you right
now I'll give you some some tips some
points but if you are one of the people
that's trying to hire one of these
people trying to get them to come to
your company I would almost guess that
you've tried all the traditional ways of
hey we'll post something on our website
and we'll just wait for resumes to come
in in I'm kind of guessing that that's
not working as well in this market as it
might have been five 10 15 years ago and
that's because it's a buyers market as
far as jobs we've the people with the
skills can shop around and get new jobs
in a day in a week it's really easy so
one of the things that I find is that if
we have
people that want smart InfoSec community
people and we have people that want to
join the intersect community then this
is the prime place for each of those
different groups to meet and you have
vendors out here people that are looking
to hire people just like you and me and
it's a great place it's a great feeling
to be in when I find is that if you
marry the industry with the community
it's like taking chocolate and peanut
butter and putting them together - I'm
just type of hypothesizing I'm thinking
this might work putting chocolate and
peanut butter together it might be a
good thing and that's what we're doing
here because the community augments the
industry and the industry augments the
community we'll see how that works but
right now I want to show you my 14 tips
to enhance your community life or if
you're looking to hire people in the
community to get into their lifestyle
meet them where they are so that you can
hire them and ultimately retain them the
first thing is really that double-edged
sword that catch-22 it's like I'm gonna
tell you to get experienced well that's
great Micah the reason why I'm here is
that I don't have experience and I want
to break in the industry cool I get it
information security is a really really
wide wide field and it can get quite
deep as well what do you do what do you
start how do you start the way that I
like to tell people to start is you
start with general experiences right
let's say that you're a person that's
and that's an audio file you really like
like sound systems and your home
entertainment system is really like
smoking at home cool you have some
skills there your your home system might
have Wi-Fi on it it might do some things
interesting with sound you can parlay
that you can mix that up with some
computer things whether you're using a
Raspberry Pi to power that or something
else or what if you are playing with
raspberry pies or your heard of one and
you you want to play around with it in
information security
we do is we take those basic skills I'm
kissing that some of you might have
parents or relatives that you are the
primary helpdesk person right when they
click an email that they shouldn't have
yeah yeah I don't know why my screen has
this face on it but it says I need to
pay some bitcoins to get back in yeah
you are the primary people and that help
desk work that regular system
administrator work that's your
foundation what I think is that people
that have that foundation of normal
everyday InfoSec skills can pile on the
InfoSec to the top of it can can learn
the information security stuff that
leverages those foundational skills so
when when people says go out and learn
things go out and do things yeah you can
get a certification but play with your
computers try out other types of
architectures or devices mobile things
because that foundation is going to help
you be more effective when you get into
other types of the InfoSec industry and
for those of you in the InfoSec already
you understand that there's actually
once you get into InfoSec because that's
a lot of people's jobs everyone I want
to get into InfoSec and you get in there
and then people start talking about
reverse engineering and IDS's and policy
in and and you realize that there's this
other inverted pyramid on top and
InfoSec is really quite broad and that's
okay because there's time for you to
become a specialist there's time for you
to take and keep building upon your
information security knowledge to grow
and and ultimately give back now when I
started in this industry I started back
with ye oldie tiny stuff yeah
pong tardy yeah those were my basic
skills I started playing on an Apple 2e
and writing some interesting programs
for it and then I graduated up to NT 4 o
ne & T 4 o MC SES out there yeah right
yeah that's what I started doing playing
with Windows systems and and I got a job
doing system administrator work and it
was cool I was learning how these
systems
worked properly once I did that
sufficient I actually started playing
with Solaris as well my boss said hey
Michael you understand this Windows
system administration stuff cool how
about you come and do this UNIX stuff
because it's very very similar it's just
totally different sounds like okay I
guess I can and you know so what do you
do when you don't know what to do you
google it or back then you AOL it yeah
so so I asked geez thank you sir yes
from the past so so you know you go on
there and you and there's lots of people
that can help you out I found a nice
person that had posted you know if
you're a new person that that needs help
testing your your UNIX system as the
root user type in RM minus RF splash
front it was the best way that I learned
how to rebuild that server after it
started removing all the files on it but
yeah so there's things out there this is
my experience this is my foundation and
I'll bet each and every one of you has
some of that stuff and you know what if
there's things that you don't know if
you go out and learn and that's my tip
number two learn things take control
over your self learning and I say self
learning some of us we learn better by
by standing in it and by it by being in
a room where an instructor is leading us
absolutely cool some of you have the
self-discipline to do an on demand type
of a course or watch a youtube video and
learn stuff from it cool wherever you're
at there are resources out there that
can help you whether it's you guys have
heard of YouTube yeah it's a new site um
yeah YouTube you go on there and you
type how do I you get a lot of
interesting responses back there's some
of that as InfoSec stuff and you can do
anything from how do I attack this
system or leverage PowerShell in this or
some of the primal sex stuff do you guys
have videos out there yeah on YouTube
right Python learning in and other
things it's a valuable resource if
you're the type of person that can learn
stuff from videos I'm a type of person
where I need it spelled out for me too
so wiki's and blogs there are people
that will find anybody see the the
fruity armor APTA attack or the dine
dns attack just this past week there are
already blog post out there detailed
blog posts by Krebs and other people
that have outlined exactly how this
thing goes and how these things went on
then it breaks it down for us so learn
capture the flags are a wonderful time
to learn too because they're you're
doing hands-on stuff not just a reading
about something not just getting a video
about something but actually doing
hands-on this morning I did some of the
crip I mean I watched as my kids did
some of the Crypt kids CTF and it was
really cool just to get back into like
ciphers and all just to do something and
have a goal to achieve I mentioned that
the one of the ways that I like to learn
was doing instructor-led training and so
in back in the early 2000s I took a
class from the SANS Institute and it was
so empowering I went there I learned I
took that stuff back to my work and I
said hey let me show you how our systems
are insecure and I did it my boss's eyes
got open and and he said this is this is
great we need you to to be an InfoSec
person all the time I was like cool so I
kind of parlayed it into an InfoSec
career like yeah I'm an information
security professional now this is
awesome
I got cards with that on there I felt
really good and you know the best part
about information security professionals
is this well if you google it and you go
to Google Images you get this guy now
any of you InfoSec professionals out
there actually do this on a daily basis
it probably deals with cyber's or
something or I don't know Holograms
maybe we just haven't gotten there yet I
don't know um so yeah and you know being
in the industry cuz I was doing this all
all for work and and you know I went to
Stan's through work and I did all these
other things through work I got my cissp
because you know that taught me more
about the industry I was really happy
camper I was feeling good about myself I
was learning things and so my boss came
up to me said hey you know what you're
getting pretty good at this how about if
you go out to blackhat you know that
this big like info stack community on
InfoSec training out in Las Vegas it's
like you guys I mean to Vegas for a week
for free really yeah yeah I'll go oh and
I have to go to talk school so I went
there and that's me at Caesar's Palace
yeah um so I went there and and I
learned in these talks were wonderful I
actually found out in the talks this was
my first information security conference
and I've never been to one before and I
found out I had some skills I really did
and it made me feel good because I found
out that there were vendors out there
that will give you stuff all you have to
do is scan your badge they will give you
free stuff I've got so much stuff I had
to buy another suitcase to get it all
home well worth it though well worth it
I still get emails from that but um when
I was in in 2006 I was out there and my
boss said you know what Mike since
you're already out there we heard about
this other conference it's kind of
exactly like black hat it's DEFCON it's
just exactly exactly the same but
totally different so do you want to go
it's like peahats only 100 bucks I'll go
and so I went there and I met hackers
yeah yeah yeah hackers were scary people
at that time these are people with with
with ski masks on type in with gloves
that is uber have you ever tried to type
with gloves on this guy's got some
skills right yeah but the this was like
mixing information security professional
with this this weird class of people
that I'd never ever met of I just I
never met but I'd always heard about
them and so what I did was I went to Def
Con and I stayed as far back from all of
the things they have this cool cooler
contest were to see how fast you could
cool down beverages that's really cool
I'm not doing anything with them just
staying back did this wall where they
had intercepted all of people's clear
text communications all the Wi-Fi and
they'd taken out usernames and password
and they put this on the wall of sheep
it's like wow that's weak oh my god is
my Wi-Fi on so I observed from a
distance because I was not yet ready to
engage with the community with those
people and that's cool that's where I
was at at that time and I stayed in that
place for many many years until one day
a good buddy of mine actually PW crack
Bob Weiss here who runs besides DC he
kept hammering on me he's like hey you
know what you got to come to Virginia I
live in Maryland it's like you got to
come to Virginia with me there's a bunch
of people and Nova hackers of the king
he said don't come they're normal people
they just like information security it's
like all right so I went and that's my
tip number three join a group like I
said I joined Nova hackers but since
then I found there's unallocated space
up in Baltimore there's other groups out
there go to these groups
it says hackers in it or unallocated I
have no idea what that means it's like a
memory corruption thing but these are
places with people just like you and me
in fact a lot of the volunteers and a
lot of people in the audience probably
have been to one of these groups at one
point in their lives or maybe they're
regular members or maybe they run them
these groups are great because they meet
on a regular basis in communities like
yours and mine
and they talk about information security
they talk about the things that we're
interested in and they help raise your
awareness you can talk to the people
that just gave a talk in fact these are
groups that are a self-run so
participation is a must each person in
the organization stands up and gives a
15 minute talk about something if you
don't want to join these groups that's
cool
there's is essay chapters out there
there's even a wasp chapters the open
web application security project all
around the world don't like that there's
meetups do information security if you
go to meetups and you want to look for a
group InfoSec had very few hits on it
but there are these groups that are out
there all over the world that have
opportunities for you to connect with
other people just like you and you know
what it does when you're going to look
for that next job or when you need help
with that Python script where you want
to get into ham radio but you have no
idea what you're doing
these are the people that are going to
help you these are the people that are
going to connect you with the resources
or just teach you now I mentioned that
these groups are groups where the
members many times will present to to
the other members and what that creates
a big barrier for people in fact if you
go to the Nova hackers comm website
you'll see that you know there's a fight
night type of mentality where your first
time there you have to present it's not
that way actually and what people
generally tell me is that you know hey I
go to these things but you know what
everybody knows exactly what I know
everybody knows the things that that I
would present on so I really don't have
anything I can present on that's not the
case within the industry there's
something called impostor syndrome
impostor syndrome is where you feel
inadequate about your skills and
abilities because everybody else is
doing things that you aren't
that you are not doing and and they're
doing uber ly things that you're not and
so you feel like your skills your
connections what you're doing it can't
compete with that
I had a very bad case of impostor
syndrome when I came back from Derby con
one year about four years ago I came
back I saw people doing Oh days and and
PowerShell stuffing and really cool
things and I got back and I was like you
know what I'm not doing any of that
stuff what the heck what good am i doing
in in in the industry and I actually
started looking for jobs outside of
InfoSec I didn't find any that paid that
well or or anything so I stayed in the
industry but this is something that
that's very pervasive especially for
people just looking to break in but
here's the thing
Bill Nye puts it puts it very succinctly
that everyone you had you mean know
something that you don't it's just a
matter of whether that can come out you
might meet somebody that's really good
at like kernel rootkit development or
just understanding kernel stuff you
might need people that understand how to
program or how to programming languages
that have not even been invented yet or
you might need people that do what this
guy is doing because I don't even know
what part of infrastructure thing but it
looks awesome that gives with
miniaturisation keys it's just a
password right
I think that's under the keyboard yeah
it says password but yeah so you know
something that somebody else doesn't
know you just have to figure out what it
is I talked I did a similar talk to this
at besides charm earlier this year and I
brought up that one of our members in
Nova hackers one day gave a talk about
how to brew the best cup of coffee
well that's not related to InfoSec but
if you think about it what do we run on
caffeine right so this was very very
well well written well well-received
talk so you know stuff how do you know
when you're gonna get where you're going
you gotta set goals because as Yogi
Berra says if you don't set goals and
you don't know where you're going how do
you know when you're gonna get there
this is an important piece of our of our
lives you might not be a person that's
it's a year five year ten year plan
that's cool I'm not either but I can
tell you this you can set
short-term goals I'm going to achieve
this certification by this date I'm
going to learn Python and create my
first script on that date and hold
yourself accountable to those dates put
them in your your whatever you use to to
keep track of dates and times
make it a firm appointment with yourself
to to go ahead and and achieve that goal
and then when you achieve it set another
goal or set more goals because you know
what when you do this you'll be able to
track your progress you'll be able to
see that you have learned new things you
have developed over time which is a lot
of things that we don't look for when we
are trying to get through the
information security industry we're
always looking ahead we're looking at
the new skill we want to learn we're
looking at that new technique that new
opportunity you don't see the stuff that
you've already tackled you don't see the
stuff that you already know that junior
people are looking up and going holy cow
I have to learn what tcp/ip means I can
barely spell it ipv6 forget about it
but you know it it's core to you and
you've already moved on so um make sure
that you makes make time for yourself to
achieve your goals
next thing is open source projects open
source projects are really important I
feel because it's your chance to give
back to the community it's also another
place to engage with community these are
projects that people are making and
publishing the code online there's lots
of opportunities when I was a UNIX
system administrator I could write bash
scripts really well but I found as I got
older that bash wasn't a great
programming language and there were
these other things like Python and Ruby
and Perl
okay maybe not Perl but there's Python
and Ruby and sorry if you like Perl well
never me um so I decided to learn Python
and and I could participate it with a
project called recon and gene it was
really good because what I found is that
I could do all of the tutorials online I
could listen to all of the primal SEC
podcast and do all of their trainings
and stuff like that and that was great
but if I actually sat down at a keyboard
and tried to type out some Python try to
make a script I was ineffective I could
not do it and
to goal and so recon ng allowed me to
mix web application stuff which I under
already knew
along with Python and marrying that
chocolate and peanut butter together
allowed me to have a reason to Python
now one of the things I hear is that
from people as well I'm not a programmer
I don't know how to code things so I
can't participate in the open-source
community and I say that's wrong because
there are projects out there that if you
know how to use notepad or text pad or
sublime or whatever it is G edit you can
participate here's just three of them
that came up off the top of my head I
have a project on my will on my github
where I have published just extent
essentially a text document and that
text document is interview questions if
you're looking to interview text on
technical people so there's just
questions
there's no programming it's just
documents on the fuzz dB the fuzz
database all that is is lists of words
special words organized
maybe there's a list of user names a
list of passwords a list of files on a
certain server if you can type in file
names or user names you can contribute
and then there's a Justin or Dean's
OSINT framework this is just essentially
like bookmarks they're URLs that you
copy you pasted in there and they're
done it's pretty easy and anybody can do
it if they want to Mike is step number
six is attend and participate that's the
important part at conferences you've
already satisfied probably both of these
here this here today maybe yesterday
right how many of you did another
activity aside from just attending the
the talks how many of you pick locks or
how many of you did a wireless CTF or
the Crypt kids thing or or yeah you're
already doing this stuff and there are
lots of opportunities for you within
this DC Maryland Virginia area to attend
conferences these these conferences like
this the b-sides they're great for
meeting people in your community for
talking with people for making those
connections and for learning your new
skills besides DC this
weekend besides Nova is the first-ever
Northern Virginia conference the call
for papers is out there and they're
going to be doing some amazing things in
Reston Virginia
Herndon Virginia coming up in February
and besides charm in April all of them
great conferences for connecting with
people and I already mentioned that at
these conferences they'll have the open
organization of lock Pickers tool or
some other people there doing a lockpick
village if you've never picked the lock
as some of you probably haven't ever
done go in that room over there sit down
on the table pick up a turning tool and
a pick and start out with the basic one
lock
it's amazing that feeling I saw some
people today they were like oh I just
picked the lock like yeah didn't get
arrested here it's awesome right yeah
but try things participate when I was
over there or sitting at the table and
the people around they're like hey this
is just like you know where I'll have
our turning tools in our lock picks like
this is just like a clambake you know
where you're just sitting around
socializing and every now and then
somebody's like oh don't eat the locks
but yeah I mean it's a social time to be
together with other people and learn
from other people teach other people if
you're a lock picker sit down and show
somebody that doesn't have the skills or
doesn't have them yet there's also the
CTF over there that's going on um my
first CTF was at Derby con several years
ago and several of the guys that I did
it with are here in the audience
I had gone to Derby con you know with
that that telescope going hey that's
kind of neat they're doing like wireless
hacking in that room that's neat I could
probably do that
yeah but I'm not gonna put mine now my
computer on that network it's probably a
hostile network you know hackers um but
then the next year I was like no if I
format the hard drive putting you know
some some simple system in there if it
gets compromised I can just throw away
the hard drive or reformat it whatever I
could participate in this and so I did
that and we got a team together and we
did that we did the CTF and I said I'm
just gonna sit down it's 12 o'clock on
Friday I'm just gonna go and tell I'm
bored that's all we didn't stop until 12
o'clock on Sunday we hacked the whole
time and each day was neat because I
would call us
like hey I got this I have no idea what
it's like and Luke or Andrew would be
like oh I know how to do that can you
help me with this and we would share
information and we would learn from each
other it was a great experience
we took third place that year one of the
other things that you can do is talk to
the speakers like myself like Andrew
like other people that are talking we're
here to help you learn and understand
things and if you want to connect with
us where you don't talk right now to me
but talk later on to me but but talk to
us come up and talk to share your
experiences help us make our talks
better tell us how we connected with you
because this is an important part of the
dialogue of the information security
community again talking to people and
making connections next thing you can do
is make a blog now many people tell me
oh I've got nothing to post I I don't
know what I write about carnal ownage
Chris gates he's one of the founders of
Nova hackers great guy um he said you
know what I don't blog for other people
I blog because it's kind of a public way
of me keeping notes because you're
touching a lot of different systems or
you're doing a lot of different stuff
and invariably in eight months or 12
months or two years later you know Dan
Timmy I already do this once you can
just go back to your blog and pick it up
and you're blocking help other people as
well so what I did when I came back from
that CTF that I did at Derby con I made
a blog post and I heard one a person
commented on that and today I listen I'm
gonna go ahead and I'm gonna do a CTF as
well I thought that's great you know it
helps one other person and it helps me
to keep track of my my adventures
there's other blogs that are out there
that can be helpful if you want to
create your own blog do it or your own
podcast do it but there's some of that
out that are out there that are really
really good for instance Leslie Carr
heart hacks for pancakes is her Twitter
handle
she has an awesome blog and you know
what her blog she has seven chapters of
how to break into information security
what I'm talking about today lots of
people are talking about it she has an
amazing well organized and well written
blog that you can use
I put a little short URL at the bottom
it's not gonna rickroll you were
downloading malware or will it next
thing I want you to do is go and
volunteer give of your time
why you meet people how many of you have
volunteered at a conference before nice
thank you all I appreciate your service
there's opportunities to do it
besides DC they were still looking for
people up until you know a couple days
ago you want to volunteer at besides
Nova coming up in in February there's
opportunities available you can just go
in and check in people you can help
speakers you can run some some type of
some of the the events that are going on
there there's lots of opportunities to
pitch in go ahead and do it next thing I
asked for and take feedback anybody
heard of this that most people listen
with the intent most people do not
listen with the intent to understand but
the intent to reply how many times
you've been sitting there and maybe
you're talking to your spouse or your
kid and they're like blah and you're
thinking your head okay I'm going to go
ahead and I'm going to share this life
lesson with my child or or my why I'm
gonna tell her this you're not hearing
the other stuff that she's saying or
he's saying you're hearing what you want
to trigger your response without taking
in the entire conversation if we open
ourselves up to actually hear what other
people are saying it can be very
powerful
I'll give you an uncomfortable situation
when this happened I was presenting a
talk at besides Boston great conference
had a great time up there and my talk
was called running away from security
the talk was essentially about finding
people online and tracing them back to
their homes or they're on virtually
tracing not actually appearing at
somebody's house and that would be
awkward
hello I'm Micah I found you online so
but tracing them back and I had three
examples that I used in that talk guess
what they were all women they just work
I mean they that's okay I mean as far as
i concerned but a lady raised her hand
at the end of my talk she said um mr.
Hoffman what do you have against women
I'm anything against women I love women
my wife's a women I like it so she said
all three year examples were about women
why didn't you use one about man like
well I I just didn't but I thought about
I was like well why couldn't I so I took
her feedback which was not necessarily
used in the best manner I found out
later she had a feminist blog and she
was just using she was doing this to
everybody at the conference but that's
okay her point was that my examples were
biased so I went home and my daughter
and I sat down and we figured out a way
to take the three examples and find a
one with a man in it and you know what
my talk got better because that man that
we used for an example was actually a
better example than the woman that I was
using so I listened to what she was
saying and I actually learned a lot and
and my talk up better next thing as you
start to learn stuff share it even if
you don't think that you know a lot you
may surprise yourself and here's the
thing you could take the things that you
learned here at this conference whether
it is Andrews talk or somebody else's
talk or my talk back to your
organization whatever it is back to your
college back to your high school and say
I learned how hospitals are vulnerable
to things or I learned this really cool
thing about Python or PowerShell or
whatever
talk to me do it over lunch however if
you live in a state where you can have
lockpicks break out your lockpick set
and show them how to break locks it's
cool I went to Home Depot one day and
bought a hundred dollars worth of locks
just grabbing deadbolts off of the
shelves and and padlocks and I have my
arms full stuff and Home Depot employee
came over he's like can I help you sir
like no I got a lock-picking thing
tonight
I'm fine
so but yeah we just took him on we took
him back to the office we broke them up
and we just started picking them and
it's amazing if you're new to
lock-picking it's really easy to pick
some of the lower quality locks out
there and people were we're enjoying it
so share your information go to the
Career Day at your children's schools
don't don't just show up at the school
and leahey I'm gonna want to talk to you
about information security schools frown
upon adult males like just arriving
there at the doors unannounced come but
mentor kids mentor other people junior
people that may not know as much as you
there's a person in my organization
really smart guy really smart and and
he's in one area of information security
that I know very little about and one
day he came to me it's like hey I'd like
to mentor with you Mike cool all right
he said I know nothing about networking
like what do you mean you nothing about
networking he's like I don't know what
TCP I'd meet Pia means I don't know what
a port is or protocol it's like you're
like an expert over here in this how do
you not know about that but he didn't
because he specialized he didn't get
that foundation of knowledge he
specialized and that's absolutely cool
he's an awesome rockstar and I helped
him learn some things that I thought
were basic and that he already knew but
we shared knowledge we shared
information now if you so choose you can
go the professional route and start
sharing I decided to become a sans
instructor and teach people how to web
hack and share my knowledge that way and
it was great I love meeting students I
love talking with them and sharing
knowledge and you could do classes as
well Liam Randall over here he does his
broke classes that are just amazing and
other people as well you could teach at
besides conferences it's pretty cool
stuff one of the things I already
alluded to was track your progress now
tracking your progress could be just
putting a star on a calendar
it could be marking off that you achieve
certain goals it could be any one of a
number of things let me make it simple
for you though I have one of these
things hanging on the wall in my office
and you might not be able to see it this
is a runner plaque essentially you you
buy this thing from like running on the
or some other site is on Amazon and
there's just little hooks coming out on
it and it says at the top success is and
how far you got but the distance you've
traveled from where you started when
people come into my office junior people
they're like how do i how do I get into
InfoSec how do I do what you're doing I
can point to this because this has every
badge and when I go back to my office
this badge will go on there to every
badge for every conference I've ever
been to is on that wall every training
I've been to is on that wall and I can
say I've put in my time I've put in
effort I participated that's how you
start and you know what you could buy
one of these and you put today's badge
well the one that you're wearing I put
it right on there and then next year and
the year after and soon you'll be able
to see damn I've been to a lot of
conferences and maybe your badges start
changing colors because you start
becoming speakers or you start being
volunteers that tracks your progress too
next we're gonna talk about joining
Twitter now this is pretty sensitive to
people that some of the people in the
audience that may work in a sensitive
area in DC or Maryland or Virginia where
you're not necessarily allowed to have
social media accounts cool I get it
but I'll tell you this Twitter is a
wonderful place for you to connect with
people it's bi-directional I don't know
if some of you look old enough that you
might remember BBS's remember used to
dial-up yeah yeah there are people that
said let me take off let me put on my
old guy hat back when I was a kid we we
had mold UM's and we liked it no we used
to dial into system I'm sorry I was
slightly Bernie Sanders too sorry
um but we dialed into these places and
and and we would connect with other
people but there were some people that
wouldn't upload files they were they
were just lurkers they would just sit
there and watch or maybe they would
download files without participating on
Twitter
that's absolutely cool you create a
Twitter account you make it so nobody
can follow you but you follow other
people and you get to learn about stuff
if you don't know who to follow here are
three quick things that you can do
follow hashtag InfoSec follow besides DC
and follow me
and you find through what I retweet or
what I tweet other people that have
similar ideas to what you want other
things that you want to get into the
other neat thing is if you wanted to
contact me right now you probably don't
have my email address many of you do but
you might not have my email address but
you get on Twitter you can send me a
direct message it's like having my home
phone number and you can do that for
anybody that has a Twitter account that
allows that type of access you want to
talk to Adam Savage the mythbuster BAM
you can DM and Brian Krabs man you can
you can send them a tweet and put his
name in there or whatever but you can
communicate with people you're having a
problem running recon ng you send
something to Landmaster 53 Tim chums
will pick that up and go let me see if I
can help you or Rafi over here if you've
been over here to the Kobol strike booth
really responsive people Twitter is the
way to do it
the fruity armored apt attack the the
dirty cow stuff that's coming out the
dime DNS stuff all that stuff was on
Twitter way before it hit sent on
mainstream media so you get things
faster this way to my next int my next
tip is to surround yourself with people
smarter than you many of you are in
organizations where you are the only
InfoSec person so you can't do this
right but maybe you've joined Nova
hackers maybe you've done some of these
online classes maybe you're on Twitter
and you start surrounding yourself with
the Twitter universe with the the other
tweeps twitter peeps and you start using
those people as your organization
because you know what if you're a big
fish in a small pond you probably feel
pretty good about yourself that's great
yeah you guys know about this this nine
year old rugby player in Australia dude
is crushing it he's huge and very strong
and he's just like flinging kids it's
like what the Hulk did in the Marvel
Comics you know and all those moves like
just kids are flying in this you'll
notice that every other kid on the
opposing team has a helmet on but he
does not he's just like throwing kids
left and right but I'll tell you this
once those
kids get bigger or he gets promoted to
the next league where he's may be as
strong as other people he might not have
taken the time to learn the techniques
that he needs in order to move on to the
next level or the in order to continue
to succeed you can you look at him as
opposed to Rudy Daniel root ruining her
um this is the guy who the movie Rudy
was about Notre Dame player football
player he only made he was only playing
in Notre Dame for three plays in his
entire life
but he set a goal way on early on in his
high school life and and he said I want
to play for Notre Dame and he tried to
get into Notre Dame and he didn't his
grades weren't good enough so he joined
the Navy and then after he got out of
the Navy he went to a two-year college
and he learned there then he got into to
a Notre Dame but he didn't get on the
football team because he was too small
he's only five six and 160 pounds but he
kept trying and he kept doing things and
participating and the final game of it
the final putting the final play in
plays of the final game of his college
career coach put him in and the dude got
the final tackle that ended the game it
was a sack on the quarterback and he is
only one of two people that ever got
carried off the the field on people's
shoulders not like on a stretcher he was
the only psyche no I've watched the game
before we've seen a lot of people
carried out now he's only one of two
people if you believe Wikipedia that
were carried on I carried on the
shoulders of the team players off the
field because he tried and he kept
trying and that's important he's
surrounded himself with people that were
much smarter and bigger and badder than
himself
and then here's my last tip you got to
realize that not everybody out there's
like you this was a hard hard idea and
concept for me to understand you know I
go play some like well why didn't they
pick that up that's easy that's easy I
could pick this line I can pick this six
pinlock really simple I don't see why
it's taking you so long I had a hard
time understanding that not everybody
was like me until I heard a talk by
info' Jenner sitting right there in the
audience I'm gonna call
yeah brother um he gave a talk and it's
talking Nova hackers was about the
different types of people in info sack
and he needs to help me understand that
there are a lot of different people in
infos nation security or just in
information technology some people are
there because they're hobbyist itting
site it excites them to play with this
little tiny Raspberry Pi computer just
to make a light blink on and off some
people love doing that kind of stuff
cool
we need you there's some people that go
to work they put in a solid 9 to 5 they
do their job really really well but when
they get home they're playing with their
kids or they're helping out somebody
else or they're doing sports or
something else like that and they leave
InfoSec at the office and that's cool we
need you to in the industry there's some
people that are 24/7 people they immerse
themselves in the InfoSec lifestyle
they're in their off hours they go home
and they're coding up some open-source
project or you know these are the type
of people that when they walk by like a
porcelain point-of-sale system and they
see the USB points pointing towards the
customer they're like I could do this I
could exploit that system with one bad
USB but they don't because they're
ethical people as well no but these are
the people that we also need in fact the
information security community needs all
of those people because everybody
contributes whether you're finding the
next cool way to hook up on Apple TV or
whether you're inventing some new type
of attack or defense and we need you and
so our industry in our in person Marg
and if you do some of these things I'm
not saying that you have to make this
into a checklist my goal was to start
with number one then work my way through
14 you don't have to do that ladies and
gentlemen although that would be
impressive if you do come back here next
you're like I followed like this plan
here's my misadventures and you could
give a talk here next year but these are
the ways that you can participate in the
community and you've started today some
of you go pick a lock go talk to some of
the people here share your knowledge and
grow and that's my talk please don't
thank you very much there any questions
for me
anybody have any questions for me yes
sir you thought no that's you in the red
shirt yes sir yeah yeah where do you
where do you where tell me where to
start within that grand cake right so
the genre mentions you know so if
information security is this wide
information technology is this wide and
and where do I even start within that to
gain that foundational experience that's
a very valid question sir and I can tell
you that the best place for you to start
is somewhere that interests you if you
start out doing what I tell you to do oh
I'm going and do some web hacking or go
ahead and learn Python that might be my
way of doing it look in the blogs look
on Twitter look on other places come
talk to me or some of these other people
go to one of these groups and see what
interests you within there and then
start learning a little bit about that
and variably you'll have this kind of
spider and branching out thing where
you're like oh I learned some Python
that was kind of fun oh I can figure it
out I can make web calls well with that
web calls I'll bet I can scrape dado if
I can scrape data and now I can do and
that will lead you in other places the
foundational things learning networking
XCore learning how systems run that's
core also as well okay yeah thank you
for asking anybody else questions no all
right thank you very much again enjoy
your day