yeah I know it's a hell of a name but
will come to that later on
so welcome to ought to
of the two at school how has to convince
so far few guys
very good like that I only few when the
last night so I missile talks yesterday
whatever they were really nice
that's perfect so first thing for you
sorry so many mister
Peter honey coated some people might
know me by my nickname calling code
I'm the founder Ralph column the
you can follow me on twitter but rather
I'll I don't hold any certifications
so unlock one of these well I'll try to
keep you folks away anyhow
I know where the first talk after lunch
is usually a bit difficult
guys that the fall asleep solo tu some
exercises
to keep the blood flow running I am
because the stock will be slightly
technical I I find you guys to
raise your hands and ask questions to
stop me
as I go on to actually try it out
I suggest that you all ratio have right
now
all of you yet maybe all along let the
slow
good for the book flow so we all wake up
again
for growth alright so don't hesitate to
stop me I am
had an interesting talk this morning
with that and the guys are
right on the front row had an
interesting talk
and they asked me okay Peter where
you find all the time to to do this
think I'm
is an issue for all of us so
I will start the stock with time and if
you to work time
what is the first thing that pops into
your mind and I'll
let you guys just she also works at the
idea is to make it a bit instructive to
wake you
guys up or to keep you awake like SLE
yes s
anyone else yes alright
I wrote a couple of
he works down I think we all agree we
don't have enough time
flies by finest universal time is money
hey we got money stress it's hard to
manage that lines
so there's a lot of things that we can
associate with time I am and 30 FPS
unless you are very fortunate
unless you have like your dream job what
we usually do with our time
is not what we want to do we all have to
make a living
you have to earn some money but so
we have to spend most of our time going
to work and then the fun begins in the
evening
up we also need some time to sleep so
that's a little now we only have 24
hours at:
so up there's like a secret our
but you'll fight you'll find out when
you have a kid that you have to try to
squeeze
24 hours in a day so that is the reality
finding a balance it's painful
maybe a few words about Bay
we all know what pain sounds like anyone
yes and they have three
treat a number of times in our life will
end up with more P
more pain means mores
mores leads to a buffer overflow
and if that happens in your life this is
what happens
yeah
now I don't know if any if any of you
this is a bit familiar with them would
exploit development
what kind of overflow is this it's an
exception handler also
that says so what do we do
to try to squeeze in more time we try to
multitask
I have a background in the suspect
ministrations
system engineering I one of the things
that I always done
slight script certain tasks up we try to
automate sir
thanks so what we do in the morning
before we go to work or to school
we we start our cross or plus they were
at Amazon or at home and
me levitra we've built some scripts
to let it follows and to make sure that
things get locked properly
that's what we did and ensuring that the
during the day
when the first find something you get
like a a nice message so
via Twitter or you get an email so you
know that
something is waiting for you evening
bottom line
you also fight all the way to and then
by the time you get home
you are presented with an ice cream full
of
calculators so you have like your magic
script that too and all the crashes
into exploits right right yep
okay all the title says lights come see
me after the doc
I want to have your script because this
is
of course not through I wish
usually when you write that exploits
it requires minimal talk I'm annual
exploit development it takes time but
wait a minute
you're ready set that we don't have
enough time and we have to earn a living
we have to go to work during the day be
only have a few hours at night
and now we have to we have to write
exploits and its final task
if you have the luxury to be able to
write exploits during a bet that for a
professional assignments
you're still faced with that line so
even if you have the luxury to do it
your still run out of sight on top of
that
when you build exploits you're trying to
make it fast and reliable
and efficient so
it works if you are doing a pen test and
you have to
make the target machine crashed two
hundred times before it actually works
that is also prop so if we can build it
fast and reliable and efficient
be also create more time for the heart
exports so it's a win-win situation
frustration as normal
so how do you approach that's what is
the solution
and the solution is again automation we
try to use plugins
you gotta plugins that will make the
Export Development
easier and there's plenty of plugins
weekend spend the night diet they
figuring out which looking to use force
exploit
and find out why certain plugin doesn't
work
doesn't work the way you wanted to do so
I had the same problem
and even with all these plugins out
there
I still was frustrated a I still wanted
something that was a little bit more
intelligent too little
foster ideally one single plugin
have to be a plugin for immunity because
that just happens to be
the debugger of my choice have to be
reliable
because I don't have the time to figure
out why
a certain point it doesn't work so I
wrote something myself
well quick ball who
in the room raise your hand is actually
using that bucket
personal I'll see like three hands
don't want fell asleep again only three
people
it's not that statistics or so important
in fact if you look back to the states
statistics in general we see doubt about
eighty percent is based on fiction
anyway
including this one and pie charts
I mean the biggest part
of pie charts look like an ass anyway
sophisticates on up that port
so beve find addr
what any the first version was released
September 2009
so about year and a half ago
it's like a month so it's written in
Python nicely
a pluck pluck them nicely into immunity
to viral
as a little bit over the five thousand
lines of codes
and it was initially written to find
Atmos
hence the name beefy are my initials
find addr yeah I could have made it
longer
by name in be fine addresses
we don't have enough time to do that
and the ideas to run the the plugin
when debugger is attached application
ideally a crashed I'm
so you get the code context and
for the the three people that actually
you state you know that
due to the way unity works on the I am
lip
works when you kick it off justly to
you just need to have it let's run
because otherwise it will just crash
immunity debugger
basic usage you just call
the name of the plugin soaked buying if
he finds added
addr the commands and the parameters a
confines
more information about the fuckin on our
project
website
it has a lot of comments again I said I
just wanted single plugin
doesn't mean that I just want the single
month it of course it needs to be able
to do a lot of
a lot of things a.m. I will go through
some of these
comment in a bit so
enough chit chat seeing is believing
we'll have a look at a basic example
its safe 1.2 overwrites so that's
like the mother of all exploits
wat u feed a no plea long-promised
to a function rights on the stock it
overwrites
the safety pointer and when the function
returns
you own E that's that's the basic idea
and in general when that happens
ESP which is a sec order it points
at part of your failed of control state
so the goal is to both a pointer to jump
ESP
in yeah I P so it would jump to ESP
or two got bailed that is the general
so before that was PV fight addr we had
a couple of weeks
do that because E we could use the
but they're both in search control f
search for jump ESP you find one pointer
if you want another one you just
continue the search that is away and in
if you look at all of lot of information
on the Internet tutorials and books
this is actually a way that this at ties
to a a Faisal
you can also use a comment line to a
find jobs
assess the scan number of tools
available
that will actually also allow you to to
look for points
but you have to tell it what model to
query you have to say
rum the excusable against yellow
look for that information and it returns
a list points
and if it's supports Rex it might
actually provide some
results so that's an option
third option is to use a plugin that
will query one molecule
or all models say dot
and then you get a lot of results you
don't know which one to pick
course you can try you can pick up
pointer
and then you end up frustrated because
appointed work
have to try another phone is a problem
so we have officials
first the fall we either have to select
the modules we want to query
or we simply select them at all
if you use a command line tool we have
to say search this DLL
or if it's a plugin just where is all
the mod so
Yes No there's not a lot of fun too
you're just and up
with the big list pointers a half filled
with them
manually
why should we need the ability to select
models well
first the fall there's is a lock sense
Windows Vista also window so if
2008 2007 yes is a law
it's a I system that rebased thats
changes the base at his of modules it
basically randomize it
bit but the key is that
it makes your pointers be like so you
don't want to use pointers from those
models
you need to have an ability to exclude
them from your search
a second reason is rebates and that is
often overlooked
at hazel or again it only works on Vista
and up
be base has been there for ages
and what it does it also changes the
base address of the models
so in essence its has the same problem
as is are
it makes your point to some reliable so
you want to exclude those markets as
well
and we also know that if you want to
build a reliable exploits
we don't want to use pointers from an
operating system model
because that would limit the exploit
just that operating system
or even that patch version of store
service pack first
so we ideally we would like to exclude
this as well
so there are plenty of reasons why we
should have the ability
to exclude certain or two select so
molecules to query
on top of that we also need to look at
the point properties
if you are dealing with it string bass
overflow
you don't want to use pointed that has
an old bike because it's going to
stop the overflowing most likey
break inside exploits what if your
exploit inputs is on for tips or
arstan only ASCII actor sorrel out
I mean there's no way if use a command
line tool
and it's going to spit out five thousand
pointers that your
you know they're going to be successful
at going through that this
and find the point is that consist of
ski principle by Sony
it's a it's a lot of work
also important what it is a molecule is
packed
model that the crips or TN Colts itself
when it gets slow its if you query that
model but a comment line two
it's not going to produce anything
useful because is going to change in
time
assume that the model gets load and that
basically that alone
already rules out all of the command
line tools
unless you are in danger
and you really know what you doing but
if not you are just pushing your luck in
your quest
so if you summarize all of that think we
can
yep and of course all the plugins of
outdated
as soon as is a lyrical cock introduced
a lot of the all the plugins simpy were
not able to deal with that so
so if you put everything together
context
it's very important if you run your
scripts
each run within the correct context
needs to half
the correct date and the correct
pointers at runtime
ideally crashed I'm so you know which
models are loaded
which aren't that is important
and that is one of the reasons that I
wrote
the V E find attr so
it will automatically filled about all
the bat models
we don't care about is a lower we don't
care about the base
of course optional if you still want to
query a solar modules
UK well
it would also indicate if certain point
source
contain no lights and you can even him
out say I don't
and working with the string exploit
don't give me the point have no
it also shows with a point to consist of
asking boats
it's also interesting and it will also
ignore
operating system os if you tell it
every Kamal every time the plugin
searches for information
memory it fights the output to the lock
window
and to a text file so you can save it
for later or you can
just use crack there's a a link to
UNIX you feel for Windows so you can
easily
with a little script together and search
for the pointers
affects
he fights addr also look for parts
doesn't look for instructions
so that means that if the parts
that reference instruction
if those fights are part of a bigger
called or
big construction it will actually find
it's not
looking at just instructions so it
should use
a lot of results and in this example
issue looking for appointed to jump to a
register
its obviously going to look for the the
obvious once
jump to the register a call or register
push the register to the stock and
return to it
but it's also searching for or
combinations
so it should issue a lot of results and
all of that
just happens with won't come out so
yes let's put into practice
I don't know if anyone is familiar with
the tutorial some court and I'll be
the first tutorial it yeah describes an
exploit in the
easy RM to mp3 converter to you probably
everybody nose and uses on a daily basis
anyway I am the key in that exploit is
to find the jump
ESP and let's have a quick look
at the results if you just use a
comment line script free carry all the
molecules
we end up with two other than 35 points
Sri limit the search to the application
modules we end up with
94 pointers if we excludes
the ones that are going to be based we
have five
pointers BV find attr will just fine one
pointer
and it's the only one that works so
clear time time ditch you're ready 1
a lot of time
so when you have a good pointer
have to put it somewhere in your pilots
that's that to
and the most common technique is to use
a cycle batter
so what you do instead of
using a lot of aids in your payloads
and crash the application with A's we
use a long stream
with the cyclic pattern that cyclic
pattern is deals
to make sure that F 34 bytes in the
pattern
or unique so that means that crashed I'm
you can actually find the offset in that
long string
and know the exact four bytes where you
need to point
need to put your point to for example
jump ESP
these are just to tools that are part of
the Metasploit
framework so you can create a pattern
this case
a ten thousand bites I turn right fall
you copy the contents put it in your
exploits you crash
application and then when you look at E
yeah I P you see that it contains the FB
you look at the offset and you know that
yeah I you will be overwritten
after that offset
so that's the traditional way
but we can do better well
stock with we can do the same we can
also create
exact same pattern from within the
plugin
we can also get the offset from within
the plugin
so if you don't have a medal sport
coffee available at that time
you can still do exactly the same
once you have crash that district by
cyclic pattern
there's a lot more that we can do
weekend use it for more purposes that
just finding an offset
to ER AP
and I think it's really important to
mention
that before jumping into action
building the exploits it's important to
enumerate all your primitives
all your options not only look at the
offset
but where where is the payload stored in
memory
is just bought one time on stack can be
fine multiple copies may be difficult
he and especially if you look at
exploits that are for example based on
Muni code
building unical payload is a bit more
complex
but if first look at where our failed
and replaced maybe there is an ASCII
version
happy waiting for you to be used so
enumerating all your options is really
important before building
the exploits so
when you make when you trick at the
crash using a cyclic pattern
you can simply use the find MSP come out
and it will not only if you the offset
automatically
to the IP but it will actually search
for all the site
cyclic patterns and memory it will look
at all the registers
it look at the exception and watching it
will look at stack
see if points to your pattern so it will
too
it will do a lot of lot of things and
free tip of the day
and most buzzer state use he's to
trigger a buffer overflow
if you build your own first-ever police
make sure that its greats
cyclic batter it's going to save you a
lot of time
when you have crash you can run fine MSP
you have all your premise
right away so you don't have to make it
crash
a second part so
I already said fight MSP
it was fine all the copies it will check
if registered as
written it will also check is a
registered
points into a cyclic pattern exception
handler records
it will look on the stack and have also
indicated if the pattern
is a normal or unico the expo fortune
of off the bat
any questions so far no
right seconds very common
type of stack-based overflows is in
exception handler overrides
so if you offer ends up overwriting
an exception handler on the stack and
you find a way
trigger an access violation more than
that the virus
access violation where
the excitation stryker it will actually
told the exception handler
to handle the exception
pretty office now when the handler kicks
in
a pointer to the next hand structure
is ESP plus so a common exploit
technique
you just overwrite the exception handler
with the point is to
a pop pop rap com- pop-up rat
combination
which will bring you back to
the next structured exception handler
and execute so that will bring you back
to your
Williams
but we all know in the meantime that we
can't use any pointers from argues about
protect against this
Mikes of at the nice technique that
prevents you from using
all kinds of operate combinations
so we you're seeing similar issues
well and looking at building an exploit
for exception handle rights
ass with the once that you saw when we
needed to jump to register
like in South the same problem
they either won't be able to indicate
that
model is protected protections were at
it
but the plugins were not up update its
course they don't like games that will
actually indicate which model is
protected which one not on
you can already hear that there is some
money will work involved
you have to look for the models that are
not protected have to query them
individually we still have the hazel or
and the rebase
issue so those are models that we want
that we don't want to use
pointer criteria what if don't use no
ASCII unico so long most plugins
only look for pop opera but there are a
lot of
alternative routines you can use
look for at yes peepers a threat
you could also look for at yes people's
for
pop rats called the work look outside
of so molecules and that's exactly what
if he finds it York us has a a couple of
Kamal's that relates with exception and
that overwrites
that basically allow you to specify what
more does she want to query
and it'll just happens without a list
point to stop or
usable or we
and a cop other options if you want to
tweak the search so if you want to
exclude
no point to see if you don't want search
for a if you don't want to search
in OS models actually the minus so
this making sense anymore because even
on XP
all the US model source sese protect
that these days
and if you want to limits the search to
just one model
you can space fight so lots of options
but maybe we can make it the better
we have a a lot of techniques to search
for pointers
there's a lot of stuff that we can do
when looking for cyclic patterns
so maybe we can you throw all these
things together
I just three steps to victory
trigger crash for the cyclic pattern
we tell the plug and to suggest
something
and we so yes
let's look at the quick them
it's a recently discovered a.m.
fallibility endoscopic Asian
I think it's a bites 'em
so we'll have a quick look how to
suggest feature works
and how fast we can build an exploits
for
solvability I am
this video that other show is shop in
real time
so I didn't cut out any time frames
a try to guide you through sir just a
couple minutes so let's have a quick
look
so
first we launch I gess which is called
application
it's running shows on number of popups
system started and now we attach
immunity debugger
to the application
so it's the data server component
licence imports
12 for all while and we just
run the application inside
next recreates acyclic
I cheated a little bit I already figured
out that we need 5000 bytes
and i also prepared for that skeletal
that will be used to send
those 5,000 bites to
to the application so the open the
father contains the pattern
we copy the pattern and
we open the proof-of-concept scutum so
it has a little Heather
we just based in flash the five thousand
bites
within the buffer the buffer will be set
supports 1240
one
very easy very simple
and we run the Python script
bull access violation you rock
wrote beyond the end of the structuring
we see
cyclic pattern on the stack so all we
have to do now
is stellate to suggest something and if
you look up
what you can see oppose it so
first the fall it just looks for all the
instances
of the cyclic at so you can see the
first one
is one on the stack the other two are on
the heap might be an option
maybe we can just simply to return to
keep
why not and also looks at the registers
entities that
yes I points into the pattern at
position
752 so we already know the offset I we
know that
maybe we can do a chump yes I it also
looks
at exception and the chain edits shows
that we have overwritten the chain and
its shows that be
over have overwritten the X a
exception handler after 540
bytes and then it has done
a little search on the stack found a
bunch of pointers
it's important just enumerates your
primitives
make sure that you have you options
options you might need to
using that knowledge it's just going to
show that
on the stack exception handler
fy14 so using that knowledge
it can simply suggest and I'll exploit
it can tell you are you need two feet 5
and 10
Jan bites than half the next exception
handler
pointer some not show called that issue
field company much easier than this guy
it even shows you the commands to find
pointer to a pop opera
so as with let's use that information
and built the exploit so
remove John we need five other than 10
bytes
for reach the exception handler next
anyone familiar we recognize this
this is just a small jump okay
we need a pointer so will tell he finds
your
to get as a pointer again this is real
time
it will take a little while you're going
to exclude
no bites Noize molecules know the base
so it's just going to search for all the
combinations
field them and then at the end
will have a list pointers guys still
okay
there with me hands up
the flow yes thurgood almost there
if you do this demo real time and you
accidentally click
the fucker hang and echoes of them so
590 nighty pointers
that should be enough so let's open the
fall
it shows the list below the molecules
with all the properties
and we'll just take the first 10 so
because
youth and be pasted into our exploits
yeah I know
this is sup optimal way to
present the pointer but it works I was
just lazy
okay we also need some Chilcote so let's
create
a few lines show coats would use
Metasploit Sanath
F you know to do that everybody familiar
with that snook a month
on earth like two weeks ago it combines
the and as a pillow and as F goat to one
single moms
thats school so been a slow
she it'll take a few seconds to
generates psalm
calculator show called I'll
country liquid gel coat but an excuse
company
so because Chilcote and replace it
into our exploits okay
now remember this is an exception
handler overrun
we need to trigger an access violation
we can do that by
writing the arms the end of the spectrum
so we'll just
at more junk to the nth will build our
buffer
which consists of the Heather some junk
the exception had the records
shell both and the official John
so all the components put it in but for
and we'll send it
reports 12 for 10 it's close
if the thing yes
start I gess again check
throwing yep
started listening and
which simply run exploits book so
if
question so far
no I think here
alright let's move all this is basic
function I think this is basically what
other plugins
can do as well with some Kathy outs with
some
throwbacks you can do better but
characters
but characters are very important if you
are building
exploit and you want it to be reliable
if it if you for example want
to an end and two with Metasploit module
so you can use
all kinds of bailouts you really have to
figure out what the back
are and that is a heart process
its as a lot of work and
there are like three ways to approach
you could just
ignore it you could just say well you
know what will try
without figuring out what they are and
if the export works
fun its lottery you can also get
maybe certain file types
on the country
they can be very helpful to the time the
list characters it might make
very much sense if you for example take
I'm
your typical playlist file in that file
as a reference to another file so what r
the characters that or far-left or at
Follett
in a filing and if you also realize that
every turn
witches and bites your ails you got the
it will
break that string then you already know
that okay
these are my iPad characters so you can
sometimes you can just guess
at Cubs the few really want to make sure
you have to build
perfectly accurate list and
can be very time consuming so
what is the idea instead of putting
ace or cyclic pattern in your paleo
we fill it with an array with all the
bites all the fights between zero
an as we just throw
the play feel old at the application
hope it still crashes
and then we can actually compare
the original untouched array with your a
memory maybe some by so corrupt that
maybe the entire
paid out Scott's after certain by and
then you know that
okay that could be that character let's
take it out let's
regenerate the array again excluding
that bat
character hey just continue to do that
process
until the source array matches
the array and memory it still takes a
lot of time
up it pays off its
will help you to build a reliable
exploit
so BV fight attr has a an option for
that as well
you just write your array to a binary
file
you also put it in the payload and then
it crashed I'm
you basically say compare you provided
the file name
it will automatically search for all
against show them and it'll compared
with the original ones
and it will indicate which fights alter
a top position
so it should help you figuring out about
characters
unico
for a long time a lot of people thought
that unique ot
was not exploitable and it requires
a different approach its sometimes not
easy
to exploit unico so we strive to do our
best
puts out of tools into PV find your
that will help you building unico
exports unical by the way
you see 0.00% 41 0.00% 41 it's not just
about
and sorting nope I between every
character the payload is actually the
result
of course it's a function that will take
ASCII convert it into unique old and
most cases
its results in the payload that contains
not bites between yup but it's not
entirely true
we also have transforms we also have
certain bites
that if they are conflicted unico are
not
00 but they have another
and that is interesting make because
simply searching for pointers that our
and the Seattle Seattle
xx 00 xx former is not enough
ideally feel so would like to search for
transforms
be honest haven't seen a lot of scripts
that do that of course
other scripts search for the easy ones
other local strip search for
transforms and it does pay off
it does pay off let's look at
an example I am sign player
another very popular player all of you
from use it on a daily basis I
it'll exploits there was a
proof-of-concept posted on exploit pp
I'm about a year ago show the pier
exception handler overwrites and of two
weeks they were still
exploits wonder why she to a normal
search
it showed 0 unical points that were
simply
nada unical pointer to a operetta
to actually exploits that ability so
Iran a simple easy fight addr guess what
it found three transforms so that means
that I
three ways to exploit it I posted
exploit the same day
so it pays off
second example I am a while back
there was an exploit weekend organized
host
by offensive security where they ask
all the cum old contestants to
exploitable through
flow in Foxit Reader a
one of the guys of Courtland he just
mailed it in a few hours
using tools so
and of course it wouldn't be PV
following
addr if there was fine function
not that the other functions are not
looking for anything but
there is a fine on sure you can do
fine for straying or a binary or
whatever and
the fucker your phone touch with the
plugin is that it was
it will simply this locations and
it just presents the same information
basically what it does a couple of other
options
it can assemble moms it can calculate
offset between
to address is if you for example to know
are
need to jump back 400 bites were on come
back from this register to that address
you can quickly type an offset with the
Atmos register
and it will show the distance and it
will show you ok coats to jump to that
this
so it seeks infocomm
will show you what's more information
about the mattress
show you what model it belongs what
instruction is
also show information about the molecule
whether it's
is Laura's a sec sector and so on
you can list them all tools with all the
properties you can show the ones
not is are and so on
above a lot of options and features I'll
readily available for you
not impressed well
there's also rock I am
I published though the rock generator
with this just another come out in the
plugin I published it
June 2010 so that's about year ago
in conjunction with the toward that I
wrote
I am it will cap gadgets
it will cap the required information
to build the role exploits its low
I can't deny it it's very slow but it's
accurate
and at that point I figured that it
would be better to
use more results that need it stand to
pee
produce not enough results so
speed is not not rates it will actually
look and memory
built gadgets up to 8 instructions by
default
it's a parameter so you can change that
if you don't want your gadgets to and
with the rat
you can just specify call yea
EA X or call you saw you whatever
ending that you want to use it has all
the features of all the other compounds
so if you want point to sell ASCII
printable
have no bites she want felt about is a
law or
you based models that's all available so
the end result is good what you get in
your hands
is action useful one of the reasons why
slow is that it also of goats but
so just an example the first one as a
jump for the rat
the second on it's just subset of the
construction
and it produces seconds catch it
yes question I catch it
is am a series of instructions
that in the most common
set up and spit Rep so you in Iraq
exploit you chain
gadgets to each other so they will
actually
for example to a4 chip affect mark
the memory has executed yeah the key
concept of chocolate that
is that your they don't stack is no
longer XQ
preventing you to execute shop
by the way if you have time check the
time line on exploit you be
force the publication of the rock
might see that there's a link between
the two
nice to see that gets adopted
conclusion BV fight a Dr
it will buy a sign for sure accurate
information is important
it also automates certain tasks we'll
see
the demo of suggests sir certainly a
nice example
automation and November mess I don't
know if anyone knows from
when we're a mess he it didn't talk at
Black Hat
about visualization I I attended a talk
be good attention so I'll try to
visualize
without the plugin frustration
with the fuckin
fun
questions
okay
as go too far to walk the talk and
actually this is a scoop
for the nice guys increase in Athens
this is the first time that I'm going to
talk about this
and public what s wrong
know a couple things wrong BV fight addr
it was never designed to do what it does
today I started with a single moms
I added the second on at a certain point
I realized that thinks to integrate
started writing a lot of math
go them copying go to three times
ha there was no functional sign
and I figured if I was going to add more
features
trying to fix certain things with
probably only make it worse
so second everything works
it's reliable it's accurate but its very
slow
and I heard a lot of comments it still
fast
than doing it manually still faster than
doing it with all the plugins
but in the end it still slow and its
slow mainly because of the way the
plugin searchers
memory it uses the eye and lip search
search for example if you
should tell it to search jump yes people
enter it look
in time in the range for all the
pointers and it will then feel to them
so that's painfully slow it's hooked up
to a suboptimal
because after API second of all
no sorry 30 issue is that all the output
files
are written into the same full so if you
use the same
back for instance to build milt exports
multiple applications
you end up overwriting files when you
forgot that this is not a file from this
but from the previous
using a point that doesn't work and a
lot of frustrations
the last fall is also very important
I'm as Hawks 2 excludes so
molecules from the search let me give
you an example
um we all use of virtual machines
to build exploits if you for example use
VirtualBox
you install the cast additions it
at Los at the lol your process the same
thing elsewhere for example s implying
that when those
shell extensions in general it just
loads
official the other else in your
applications you don't want to its
models
even if they give you good pointer it's
only going to work on your
own system or on a system that has that
additional market slowed
so in PV fight attr
there was no way to actually exclude you
really have to manually
going to the next fall and exclude does
models crap was helpful feel
so boom not good
and that's why
we kicked off project go back we this
was actually
a court nineteen project and this is the
working title
for a project that would result full
rewrite
we started the design phase and back in
February
its
development still doing development
still tweaking it a little bit adding
more features
it will get a new name and
unfortunately have to announce that
EV fine addr is now fish
debt so anything we've seen so far
is that and maybe we should all take a
few moments
few moments of silence to mourn about
the loss
of our nice plugin but of course is good
news
doesn't your and that's the name
yeah don't ask me where
I got the name from maybe some of you
already know the name of my little
daughter
the the guys in the team they insist
that on using that name
although law I had some issues with it
because
he put the exclamation mark in from the
you know how they pronounce that
out today pronounced X exclamation mark
buying so gang mona I don't think so
I mean as a good that
on the other hand if anyone if any guy
ever wants to bang Mona it will be in it
Booker
and not and realized over Mike that body
so
I'm ok with that there was some
alternatives
we also thought about naming it bus or
your mother or cock or
so a Bangkok it's not
right so yet they lost to do with
right this time really think about what
does it need to
to make sure that there's a function
design
it still uses the same concept so
anything we've seen is not lost
up it was professional redesigned from
the ground up
again it was a team project nice to see
we'd all
really professional job reworked arts
didn't waste any time so
this was one of two the kickoff meeting
very important
these other guys actually participated
im
and the project
we are still right working on
documentation
some other stuff so that's the project
so what all the improvements
first of all I think it's easier to
pronounce
and also safe site because if you're
struggling to pronounce the name
Mona just
is Kamal no house separate help function
for the guys that have use pde5
80-yard in the past you know that if you
want to see help
you have to type fight at the ER without
any command
than you get like five ageless with all
amounts help
you have to scroll up find moms week
that will text
so just figured that every single Kamal
help function
we have config file we have some global
options
performance there's a pep direction
and we now focus all Ruby output
re so
let's take a look at the functions that
are available right now
a monster available right now so
you for example see that we've marched
all that be
p1 p2 a J say
just put it all into one single I'm also
we
basically we thought all of the commands
this is these are the commands a dollar
developed already
today there will be some more
if he wants to see what your options are
the parameters are for
amount just help with comment show you
okay kasich fall so we have two issues
first the fall there was the issue where
all the help files
sport into unity immunity program
what you can do now is you can set a
conflict parameter
and that its to set the working full to
something else can use the percentage p
to indicate the process name so if you
create
fault see locks you set the working
forty percent P
it will create subfolder for each
process
and it's alright all the output so
output is better ranged by the way you
can also use percentage
I and that will include process ID
excluding models again
we just put them in a conflict fall we
say okay
exclude molecules we just this all the
shell extensions
that are installed in our computer and
they will be ignored
research so another time saver
global options so for backwards
compatibility
we still shakers
with keep the minus and to filter out no
bites
minus 0 felt always models this at work
but we figure that we need more panel
out so we added
minus cm the M she is four criteria
hands for molecules there you can now
really specify
what type of criteria you want include
or exclude
by setting certain parameter true or
false
and most Kamal for example this one
most epic amounts already half 3d find
or the full set of multiple criteria
they will if you for example look for
exceptional Andrew flow
it will already set say sector false
isadore
to falsely based falls West false so the
points that you get by default
are most likely pointer work you want to
tweak behavior
you can overrule by setting multiple
criteria
so that's just one
you can also query a list of course the
query in
if you find a Dr you could specify one
volume knob you can just say okay I only
want use
or I only want to search that that
mall you you can use while course
nice
become more especially with
patrol point to speak on beta
in the past we need that one pointer and
we went
minority through the list find the point
that didn't have any at characters
patrol a big chunk of bail on
points so
we actually need more Krunal at on
selecting points as well
and this is what we did minus EP
criteria pointer and you can now specify
one or more of these criteria so if you
want
ASCII printable pointers and
you just specify mines TP ask print
that's what only show you those ask
points
so that's good one step in the right
direction
we also can this become not only
specified behavior on of pointers we can
also
feed it at this time at characters if
you already know
that for example 00:18:00 the
FF will be pat characters
we just specify to the search and it
will exclude pointers
at half character so it works just like
an encoder
but for points and you can use that
in conjunction with mine CP mine cm
you can combine anything in every search
compounds
that is so this should be noted thanks
safe
yes next improvement
performance what that we do with
performance
so I think you'll agree he find a Dr was
a time saver
but mona is designed to be a lot faster
and
I think the toukie is that be
stopped using I am live actually spend
think spent like 20 hours straight
figuring out what would be the best way
to do search
and we ended up with about 40 lines of
code
that performs a genetic search in memory
and it goes place Fox so will chill
we'll look at some demos
some statistics
a second thing is that they will filter
during the search of the searched so
instead of searching the entire memory
space
dang feeding that through the filter
it's actually going to show through the
search and it smart
it knows that if for example if you look
for
unical pointers it's not even going to
search molecules
that doesn't start for 20 because it
knows that it will never return
point so and if you are in a hurry and
if you only need one
5 and pointers you can just that it's
okay if me
who if I folks question
it will to exact it will 3 transforms
unico so
well the transform only happens at the
end not in the beginning
so that's that's the problem if the
module
doesn't start for 20 it's not going to
end up with you
so it's safe to exclude or to limit
searched smart
it's never going to unless you're
searching back
research the way
so oh and by the way it search from
combinations so if you compare or if you
look at
the combination sources for forces the
ones I SOC
for NP fight attr it looks for more
combinations
short fine so that's when when I get
we can also show that the axis left what
if be
only one point the staten to be
writeable
for example then you can just specify
minus X
W and its will search for Point like
for this dick this time fact fiction
I Iran three types of searches
against an application I just use the
high GS
they a server the one that we use it was
filled
fucker so three title searchers I
did a quick search for jump ESP search
for
operetta and I get the full though Rob
search
so
Mona was ten times faster but the jump
sp
about seventeen times faster with opera
and about ten times faster drop so
that's nice
we also improved interaction I
again I i wrote he fight attr as I moved
forward as
as I was learning stuff but there was no
reader interaction between
functions one function you some results
but there was no way I could use those
results
French so we tidy read redesign that
which leads to fostering better results
and since we like Metasploit
there is much more we can do so let's
take a look
at the second them I will show you can
you suggest
so we will do said basically will do
exactly the same
that's what we did earlier we will see
the cyclic pattern
we will run suggests so
again we start the application
real time it's running
so we create pattern first be attached
the poker to the application well 401
okay run first we create a pattern
more now on let's check it's just an
example of the working for the parameter
so which
it will show that I've put it to see
locks percentage p
will be easier to find the results
betrayed a pattern but I'm grateful PC
just made an alias
its growth into our folder thats open
open file see locks
name of the process and
copy departed bases again in our
proof-of-concept
it's the same file at the junk buffer
will send its
to ports 124 want
okay safe and run we should get
exactly the same X violation exactly
a clear the window and we have an
suggest
last night we have a lot of information
now the loudest ease people exploits
is six .7 seconds we now have
something diff so not only
doesn't exactly the same searchers of
it will also show the lengths you've
seen lang so it shows you
how many bites the cyclic pattern are
available
and using that information if provides
you with the Metasploit
skeleton that already includes the opera
pointer it includes the offset it shows
you
exploits function for Metasploit
and shows you how much bites you have
for your pillow
so I couldn't
think of a way to make it easier for you
guys this is purity when
and it took what 6.7 seconds so
yeah I didn't create the exploits mean
it would probably take longer to type it
that action generates I I was lazy
four-inch I briefly went over to find
function
he fight addr because it was not lot to
say about it
we changed the law fine is no really a
powerful tool
and what we did is
first of all you can now specify the
type of
information want to search for do you
want to search for straying
for binary information for instructions
so you can tell it what type to search
for
but it now also has a point if 2.2
search
and that is that it's really really nice
cuts
much havin buffer overflow
where you control location referenced by
dcx and this is the Colts
that fight you with colorful over yeah I
P
so if you look you see Xcode yeah I
missed here so this is the flow in
essence
in order to turn this to a jump to page:
what we need is a pointer to a pointer
to jump
dcx if you have to look for that
manually
good luck this is going to take a lot of
time
so
we can do this now with one simple
instruction I just limited
to one PLL even and all the other elf
takes with on the Italian takes like
three or four seconds if you do a search
in all the
the levels might take a few minutes
it won't take dates so I think that's it
that's it future
future
some other goodies pp
that well that function is going to
allow you to set a breakpoint
on reading or writing and thats
my command if you're working on sprays
to
make sure that the buck stops assume
something rights to 0 Caesar Caesars
see for example you can said breakpoint
rights to that
at this just stop doctor on
fall compare it's also a new feature
imagine you're working on exploits with
a colleague
he could beat the list pointers his
system
you have a different system know you
want to compare
yes output with your output and find the
matching
pointers and cons use file compare
and it will just show you all the
matching
finally we also it a
full repeal of the rock pretty rock
rates low it was actriz really slow
we gave more options so you have more
parameters that can tweak
you can
limit the distance look at the offset
ran
bill number of number of options I'd
more options that we had in the previous
version
you can now also to a separate spec
its search with the previous version
really have to run the entire property
to get on that list
if it's now you can just wrong
perspective search
specified minimum max distance
and thats really helpful because it
speeds up your from as well
reading from memory the slow so what we
did
you can also reach from farms if you
create a rock fall for
some common the allowed paths: just put
them on your hard drive
you can actually use them out and put to
create a property
so Coast fast
let's look at the generation process for
ROP
so it is a search in memory or false if
you specified false
it will create gadgets so it will
basically look for all the ending
you specified and then walks back for a
number of instructions and
each series catch writes that into
all txt
strong that information it extracts
three types of its great separate file
back befits it creates a file
suggestions
will look at it and the rock funk
rock funk is going to look for reliable
pointers to functions that can be helped
at Camp use to bypass that
for example social protect so it's going
to do that such
automatically very sorry
so that means that if you take
information from suggestions
and for your exploit is just waiting to
be built
is going to its only is a lot faster
but if just limit your information to
those two blocks it will allow you to
build your
exploit fast
so that got us thinking
wouldn't it be nice
if there was something like this
I can automatic rock build
so yes we we made it we build it
we can now fully automate rock export
so of you we should do it
with the knowledge and experience that
we haven't building rock exports we can
search in memory for specific actions it
will be fast
or we can duty classical property first
build all the files it will be slower
of we prefer quality because
what if you don't find that specific act
you end up
with a little bit of of information
nothing to work with so we prefer
let's build all the gadgets first with
bill your rock followed your suggestion
file and
everything together and see if we can
ultimi
property so going to do with them all
better Wireshark
was actually in book that was reported a
while back to wash or
it was fixed in version 1.4.5 I'm
if the Dec normal text
phones accident if the attacked packets
you cross-posted on the local network
and
you could basically taken an oath watch
so if you have a washout listening on
the network
this is what could happen so using this
single come home
this this what we can do missus fist are
fully patched
is Lauren able step enables all the
goodies
so let's look up I have to be honest
cheated I cuts out
bought of this video because it was
going to last for like
almost five minutes I could out on
so let Scott Weishaar
with attached Booker to it
actually what I will do I would use
and already existing export Metasploit
one that I added action exploit that I
wrote
and I'm just going to rip out indirect
peace
and see if we can use the piece that was
produced by
so let's
let's let mona work
so Sony going to create those molecules
looks for all the ending
and I was going to do stations that
takes a while
if this green changes that's why I
without apart okay
alright so five minutes and 20 seconds
if you do the same
fight addr it took two hours I think
there is already a
levitoff speed improvement here
let's look at what it use first falls
back but it's
so it will show you all the pits and in
fact
take a look at this one the first
Kamal is just changes the value of ESP
doesn't X or that doesn't do anything
that few pops
so it's not just looking for at ESP
with the rats but it actually looks at
Baker chain
and it combines values instructions
that don't break the if it's but allow
you to
go to sir like so you end up with more
if it's
that should work all the time so that's
a that's also a
a little improvement that we've
whips think I accidentally started the
game
so will again
finished process
seconds
stay away from it this time
so with its shows you the decimal
distance that you can jump
you can actually specified minimum and
maximum size
know exactly how far you want to jump it
will only show you
one step to that haitian suggestions
its categorizes certain gadgets
and its Asian like readable name so
if you want to move EDI to assert
registry can just search for it guy
arrow ya too much and it will show you
all the catch the computer
and then finally
it will create or attempts to create
when star in the movie sewer lines it
will fully
create a role bail
so we'll just copy go to
backtrack box has Metasploit install
and I'll just at the model that was
added
so this is
the chain that was present
in the molecule go to strip it out based
in
what mona created actually the one that
was in the mobile
I created my newly before I wrote
routine this routine what mona created
is like
7 the works shorter who it's even better
than what I did monthly
so we just close
editor safe to follow the other
and we kick off Metasploit
in the meantime will just close
everything
and will just
Wireshark on the network
just effort this yet face
just sits there in the meantime
it 30 that's the white shark exploits I
use the me to preach to figure out so
it's just going to do
the first be connection 2010 11
is my Linux box exploit
ok so
we
automatically created a full-blown Rob
exploits
yeah because launch calculator since
my wife happens like acculturated screen
so
got conclusions
BV fight a Dr is that long as Mona
still be some work you need to do to
clean up some coats
some small bugfixes need to build in
update mechanism
finish documentation expected to release
is in two weeks so in about two weeks if
you follow me on twitter
or if you just keep an eye on the corner
and I'll be your website
will do a big announcement about it and
it will be available for you guys to
play with it
so thanks guys for
having me thanks for listening Russian
guys wanna hang out with the
myself with other guys from the
quarantine just hop on IRC
spagnolo fine since
you save a lot of time now so right
thank you