for speaker for today's Michael can and
will be presenting
when I grow up I want to be a cyber
terrorist much
sleep
who are my wife should be published in
what the hell you doing here at nine
o'clock in the morning
you do realize it's nine o'clock you
could be in bed now
you stupid stupid people anyway
abundance camp
as you may have been able to get by the
action from the UK 'em
I'm a cofounder small also great things
for a living
and I am I like generally causing
trouble which is what this talks about
up quick weather warning before we start
firstly a there will be no odor in
stock if you expect me to drop
substantial amount I die I would leave
now
go back to back was that would be
sensible additionally
please don't be upset this talk we will
see how bout I look without caffeine and
sleep
upside by all means take photos but
please don't like that yes
a kachuck copper quotes well
from uk-based sent section actually
structure
occurs once again chill computer systems
and use them for their own purposes
new a bomb from rowing line
resist injustice michener walls talk
about
an shopper everyone should be worried
not just
Julia and finally quote from die hard
fall which is
I'm sure you all know is highly
represents to the real world
and not to see a much means a demented
Hollywood screenwriter
distrust it's a fun style anywhere
site what am I gonna be talking about
well I'm going to talk about cyber
terrorism
I'm going to refer to a cyber terrorism
I can
I'm gonna be talking about the claims
have been made about her
some reputations for those flames I'm
also going to talk about why the media
is retarded
cialis apologies to any journalists in
the room but
biology people suck also gonna be
talking about
a and I love you wall I'm going to talk
about there are
carcinogens solutions up to the problems
that were
wanting to know up to about ninety
slights to get
room in our so I will so quickly and if
you don't understand
please feel free to probe probe only
and/or alcohol
I don't make peace like their but
cyberterrorism
means many things to many people
basically concerns about
on computer bomb attack so disruptive
computer attacks stopped in the eighties
personally I think matthew broderick's
to blame it's all his fault
a concerns grew until 2000
when you know everybody got distracted
by the millennium no complaints gonna
fall from the sky
role gonna die a however really when
Manjula
the 9/11 on because you know obviously
Pete comply planes into buildings
obviously locators
a to turn the first was discussed very
late in 2010
in an article from the enough cult
cyberterrorism
fact or fiction as you may be able to
cast
I know which style up according to
Wikipedia
which as you all know is the fund's all
human wisdom in the world
I US company Toltec politics define
cyberterrorism
house the premeditated yousef district
elected
these for their organs computers on all
networks with the intentions
I'll tomahawk social ideological
religious political tool or objectives
all to intimidate any person for social
so objectives that's a mouthful
on upset there's also a degree in
history between incoming call
is the update politics title it it's
basically got nasty habit
making shital which will discuss later
so that may or may not be a top as well
Anna I'm sure you're a familiar with the
wonderful lucky will take clock
a which is caught those who don't know
walls the acts anti-terrorism saw about
george bush junior
and also bill clinton he's been
predicting
an electronic poll all but that will
destroy the West Amwell
years as we dole's his latest
opus Colts libel the next threat to
national security or what to do about
that
really on contentious title a a
basically he predicts the Chinese
capsules can destroy the entire US
infrastructure
in about 15 minutes planes will stop
flying
a gentle stopped working just refiners
will explode
on the US will go back to the dark ages
also a
search he's also recanted his position
on cyber terrorism electric pole
shoppers as a
all know are tied it be but is no I'm
as much to the US as a whole can't even
decide what conventional terrorism
EG people with balls so you've got
a different definition from the FBI a
different definition from the Department
site
on various definitions from the military
a person like you know are I'm Mike
define terrorism is
I'm impaired stomping around the world
cheap oil but you know
on over the FBI raided so
point as saw some objects if you believe
the hype in its entirely up to you if
you do all
I read about people gonna do very bad
things with computers
understandable fall now I will play
must the claims made about computer
mediated terrorism
are insanely exaggerated and all
bullshit
a the problem is
trumpeters have also encompasses the
word cyber
which if you use at and you're not being
ironic
make sure sounds like a pitcher to reach
alt
now I personally will define
cyberterrorism house
the use of technology assault II actual
a terrorist nature
simpler than tackle it its definition
now I know somewhat nebulous
don't think lots and lots of noise about
informational for
I look the Wikipedia article information
well but I like
and has botched up it cites the examples
and perspective in this article
deal primarily with the United tonight
do not represent a worldwide view
so if special only happens in the US
power
now well over claims that cyber
terrorism is fake sex
Paul something I'm calling the permit
annoyance
now Fox News under allegedly decline
backers
lovely in the bay did looks like a
terrorist
now I'm a blow to this group such
impartial souls
anyway my parents to pinpoint stuff but
listen which is basically defacement
go to crime which is taking your credit
card details goes up must be an offer to
taking on state secrets
up to terrorism which is blowing your
shit so to wall which is blowing
everything up
now actual computer mediated terrorism
according to a conventionally scene is
lost over
actions before all-out war war is a
fairly retarded thing today
now I wanted in this talk to trying
something
what risks are actually pose boy you
know the supposed
evil soaring terrorists a sign in to
Gmail access them from the UK
being from the UK I'm part of the
country that's the most surveilled
nation on earth a and
the UK has also introduced also for
legislation
aimed at addressing terrorism agents and
about child and generally being dicks
so I wanted to try to examine threats
sup
not tuna
site first time ago just very stripped
down version this talk to an
organization called the eyesight
I was told by a couple people it was a
dangerous tall
on it give people also the wrong ideas
built a I would hope that you all
sensible enough another one of two come
to your own conclusions
on I was also told that UK mediums calm
down below
about cyber terrorism other data not
talking about us
much I I did some analysis
a survey pro the UK government about
$650 million
pounds that was going to be spanked
addressing
computable threats and developing
offensive cyber war capabilities
there's also articles lights are on in
April
or and also eliminate pro patiently yeah
my favorite will is the private sector
has been asked to help fight cyber
terrorism
about the state-sponsored attacks by
submitting traffic data
GCHQ I'm not
to fight terrorists GCHQ can now read my
email
the car anyway but you're not
comfortable ship but yeah my thing is
looks like the meteor really homes down
now I don't like to the point but the
media does reporter
thats Wally weirdly terrorist terrorists
well I think the church is basically as
Roque PR companies
pill companies wanna shape opinion bar
yet have
getting press coverage that's what
terrorists do that's why the coach it's
ok because it makes huge
now I would argue the
the Richard clog pipes approached that's
a discussion about left
I doesn't make sense as much the a
if you're talking about planes falling
from the scholarly
a national CNIB destroyed in 15 minutes
Dutch really not defining Rex and is a
little bit hyperbolic certain
you know we make home the language down
a bit
I'm also quite who controls the past
controls future
controls the present controls the past
very relevant so good about it
but talking about perhaps I'm gonna talk
about little bit of history about
shipped from them that not yet so the
first reported active
over Saudi about Sarah a
of you see you could argue the inner I
world and the like
on were cyber terrorist I would say
that's bullshit I was
outside the Celtics you needed from the
habit but yep
anyway not yet you have an organization
last name in the world a one of them
the inch netbook actually such ski
also day but basically they were
approachable group
the to in for prints that aims
distributed I the mail today to
a trunk embassies around the world now
that plan was to disrupt communications
now even in ninety-eight when you know
action shaken mail servers didn't work
properly
800 emails would not kill a decent miles
up
a.m. females for a fortnight for the
Knoxville
decent miles up us that they are
frequently cited as the first saw the
terrorist
the not terrorists have to call some of
that
that's what makes them terrorists now
their actions caused no major outages
and
also a pretty crap also not terrorists
so my if you're a current the IPTV tears
spirals a better terrorists
Sat and in 99 you have pro-serbian
hackles
the also the night black on purses
tighter
nature servers again watch with an email
and allegedly a there was some data
exfiltration
chrysler's whether or not those
pro-serbian souls
knows on up front there are lots of
Parsis
British rap loans a more importantly
Bolens which are a little bit more worry
playground place a not no I
yes I am talking about like I I'll
a corn syrup all US military computers
were being targeted by Christian
capsules up in ie9
newsweek which is ever reliable source
of information on
not at all bias in any way shape of all
report that going the then US Deputy
Secretary of Defense
US was in the middle of a cycle in 1929
I wanna know who the fuck wall the
schools were not to clash
is it Russia one american air America
what Russian Hill
who knows the stalls never came out
on 2005 news shipped item running
a like the russians before the Chinese
law let's have a go at the US
putting up our the owning the US by hope
other team all US for
or bones than any other country bottom
for the Chinese
a interesting 2005
first used the term AP today we love AP
che
it's such a ridiculous phrase it means
no say
but you can sell anything using it
basically in and
fun a system track are absolutely
pathetic tripe
is by their evils DDD capsules with
millions okay and they're going to fuck
you ok
no bullshit a that said
2009 the Chinese were back 2005 wasn't
enough for them
the comeback in 2009 operation Aurora
according to McAfee we are as a result
all do
on lets people buy mcafee the world will
aunt
now Colby cynical if you will
after tax and problems all happened
roughly around the subsalt I'm are as
our site
sales pitch sales pitch don't know
this one's Gopala 2009 a European
of mobile infantry got bored during our
midst of
2009 your song had nothing but you know
the word or 830
so they decided to have a look at
Twitter shall we don't like churchill
show we look at switcher now
they wanted to see how terrorists groups
all I'll cut you don't like
group use the Internet and also use
mobile telephony
and cooled use social media
the question findings from the internet
a
a couple places but that's what it's all
fairly speculative
reading in the report by the talk about
pro terrorist interfaces for your phone
so
wallpaper they also discussed but
Baffert's by which mobile phones can be
used let that sucks
yes phones have GPS who knew
and they also talk about scary voice
over IP on
voice changes pretty standard stuff
they also examine helps but it could be
employed by terrorists
I quote this is a direct flight twitter
has become a social activism told
socialist
human rights groups communist budgetary
inch and a kiss
religious communities a fierce political
issues yes
activists and others to communicate with
each other and send messages to a
broader audience
my question is which one ear I have is
nice to see
miserable the but surgeons and people
interested in human rights
ok to the same a in in the same genre
a third Scianna also
I'm bakery on a case today basically
vegetarian
and basically interest in him much thus
I am a terrorist
also now basically
their search at the report is a social
media
can be used by terrorists organized it's
not or to conduct research
well yet coat but they could also use
carrier pigeons
Anna twice already have a number of
legal issues
like you know our fates the WikiLeaks
the ball
I'll United such made a request wickedly
gave it to the press embarrass the shit
up fat
us that have any other requests and
floated room to the right up
earn now if you're a terrorist
site or otherwise you probably patient
be aware of the risks of using Twitter
which is
Republic for doing anything over them
propaganda on it seems highly unlikely
in my head
anybody involved actively involved in
terrorism is gonna use Twitter
as anything although then in a the alt
pay all message you know it when it
comes to organization %uh probably gonna
use closed all rooms are still a
upset can switch to be used for open
source intelligence covering
yes it can you have to read for a shit
load of bullshit
to get to anything useful can it be used
to plan and schedule attack
it can but then so compounded messages
on blog page is a tractor
coded message on but the book page
but is social media threats
a yep if you post details the troop
movements or personal identifiable data
if you do that you worry child I like is
not
right if your personal crap Anna
is it being used by terrorists or as
anything other than the river rally
old toasted that said
US-trained of mobile infantry want
access to Twitter in 2000 I
yes they did the cable also welcomes
that
ap quick quick look forward to but not
prove it right now is in a terrorist
organization I know decide
bought this tight butts the coming home
in 10 was talking about earlier
now apparently according to conjecture
not for is gone you believe pundit axles
energy 20 wall now according to a report
issued by major speech said
yes there is a guy who works for the US
military called may just sayin
I'm not making this shit so a unit 121
got seventeen thousand hackers this was
picked up by dark ball cap
have whole rampant his phone
una but I i've done some research enough
grip
aka open Internet the basic have
telephone system
1920 mechanical switches all octal
digital ones which much thank thank
so yeah how the hell attack anything now
Anna that said it not 300 soup
on how home non-state groups
less well-funded of cream north korea's
his poll
how come cherish for to go
forget for any more interesting
depending on your view a
I wanted to look at one individual
attacked a good day I want to look at
what so ever
nations out there from 9 strobe light
while well-motivated
Finance Group could do they actually
knew what they were doing
is anything illegal discussed causes
as anything illegal pinned onto obtain
this information no
goes up so please don't like sup what
day it is I applaud don't like this
on the concept open source intelligence
covering
on which between you made by should be
reading in shell
alt stantly
nephews not line on a hook up because
paper doesn't
better nephews not like that don't like
it
sup welcomed what individual talk today
%uh what's up shit like repeating slight
net anyway Anna quick then
so this is just be ranching up so
I haven't written anything from an H&M
so my apologies
for I'm sure your pets there were the
PLO plays a major role in international
by there are lots and lots that there is
about
about church turning up the ATM network
in the UK on
writing capitalism Instagram's before we
became
greater love the payment process just
indicate
payment processor very big process for
the handle all transactions lots of
merchants
they didn't know what their stables had
to ask on it just
one who went light went off sick after
having a nervous breakdown
is replaced by a look-alike three months
later when subsequent sprite them
the have no talking ideals on that
network
and then manger peace
of clients Floyd software you know
the thing that her chin up into two
check by that money
alls could be broken by using double
stop
enough by now Two and a Half Men this is
a major payment processor that a don't
know what's on their network
beehive nobody in charge that workers
are people having nervous breakdowns
and see you can not carpool compounds
their infrastructure in about 10 minutes
it rubbish anyway action that was in the
UK
I managed to judgment banks and as a
shingle
link what linked it was get 38 banks
building societies together
get lot shawl independent ATM operators
to get unsettling
network let that workers put the whole
that's where I got
is incredibly paranoid and it's
basically a pupil
on hence easy to go after the HM itself
everyone I presume is for the US give us
if you're not
skin but you can buy the Holy Bible the
company baby
barriers messages message bolt-on if you
really creates a big nose in the books
he wrote in
on fake sugar on a mini card reader I
make your
budget for the summer holidays also
anyone
you should also go up the item for
hard-sell of people have
but the japanese Japanese jams I also
Rocky S rover and its leader decided to
take partners its
it Italian ATM networks which don't
really talk about a lot of people there
said if learn physical touch to do hot
actions of management notes most the
footprints
a time probably find all the people
petrolia gyms and distribution
in the UK I what prices Pope's
slopes newsagents strip clubs %uh
taxi ranks up some restaurant you
strikes on ATM's
now manuals and peaceful post-fight are
all
attrition as we speak on they have
really retarded master passwords
and I were talking about 123 456 what's
your password
all if want to free fall wicket
now certain fun manuals on either if you
can find information
line Angie usually pay about fourteen
fifteen books
that what Paul any 2007
the street guys here the street popular
in March she has not been beaten by the
police
whole on then convicted in the UK
terrorism
the crowing apart from setting up the
really quite retarded
al Qaeda in Northern Europe relief you
don't want to be surveilled
don't settle for the organization called
cult leader in Northern Europe
people might get a bit edgy about on
was inciting terrorism using reforms
they also used low-level
all rolled two forms jihad only
for those who don't know the story the
three stooges shall refer to them
used known publicly distributed Malla no
attack
don't and tequila Windows PCs
the night party which were then filtered
for games on
a want us also others but cccam from
this can use the cash to go out this is
genius to buy 10
GPS and other items that could could be
abused you honey types
from other I wasn't sponsoring shot
also now willie's performed for people
to use its
should punch technology told by
sophisticated surveillance
mmm no they'll call because a guy
on called misha activist civic
who the sweetest Austin service which is
a really unusual combination
Swedish bosnian terrorist think I it's a
bit like
do she prayed saw anyway a
the patient was arrested on how cities a
telephone number in his cell phone so
sweet shoppers were
landowners this other told the pressures
on hope
is fun check for fun and sending them to
Afghanistan
happen I'll is gonna come as she told al
Qaeda in Northern Europe
feature watch this guy
site quick Assad UK banks
our part nine other people who probably
work UK banks
or maybe free phones but you can thanks
all else that's
and not just because they won't give me
an increased over
basically what happens if you if it's
the merch you get ripped off
now officially sort of you'll see TDI
banks
on you think on such a requiring back
now so banks will be not some banks will
say yes
the hospital rolled on the CC's very
sorry let's work together about it
some however up usually the Americans
bunch because they fight takes
protection in at two so we can't
possibly tell you anything cuz a factor
customers block of mister merchant deal
with that
now that's sad
if part was both payment provider and
inquire about the luge
type of other side there are a number of
banks the patient will not play ball
merchants ripped off now
whitehall pa rin banks Supplier likes
this
while the bank's us they are evil
basically if the to many brought so much
the end called whole up have to prove
fraud happens
everybody wins not case Papa much call
toll
by 1 I'm in the back on
this basically means that the system a
fraud report UK broken
Anna a that's all a lot easier
to exploit then scanning all Trojans
approaching the stock exchange
and I am I won't tell you the affected
acquired by Miss army
Cape if you really wonderful from stop
terrorist just find a bank that doesn't
cooperate with merchants
and repulsion the bank's says the merger
few people up
site quite fun about her chin
a getting on flight times us from action
fairly large merchant doing boy a decent
rate in what they did
on their channel network was a bit flaky
but not major
they also decided that we're gonna have
a knack he also decided they weren't
actually going to detect any wireless
access point potential that'll
network which been I could sit in the
car park
crash that chills or actual church that
date
specialty cake ought to on yep
this is this is fairly standard Acision
hall today now if you want to do after
Stock Exchange
packing Stock Exchange licked a
you gonna have to exploit deficits
within we approach school like federal
financial information exchange
let's work in a stock exchange never
forget her
a as a cook paper those presented a
weirdly are recycled packing the trading
floor which is which
a little salt financial never heard of
because you've never heard of these
acronyms I with us a tank all
play much stock in trade or at fault our
internal
look at the history in a the Holcim
cement star
carbon trading thing that went down last
year I've never heard of carbon trading
before it went down after gym most you
carbon trading
for house election culture carbon trader
is also guys like sergei on
of who was employed by Goldman Sachs who
decided to sort of with that tried to
help her abductor
and internal right as opposed to
external threat Otaki going to cave in
Afghanistan
some guy with a suit size or I usual
percent if you're too lazy to have
cordial to poor
power notes purchased credit card
details national charter
for like you've been shut down there are
the ways and means
pasty I'm pastebin except for a a
lecture
Perry County itself basically what there
is no quick rap
awful that I A your credit card details
either the fixer about past him pasty
pics been rather and found 15,000
current credit card each of them
say without using any scrutton's
scrutton scripts
in a your request for happy visa
of those summer gonna be track obviously
so will almost certainly be flagged so
beloved being
K to be there will be nothing left some
will have been reported so however
may work if you've got in of people
Nov rituals then I'm this is more
a viable option for example
because the self at
don't we all aspire later on this year
but you know the
so she can pull off that I've tried and
for if you are actually called you keep
things simple you know you find a
reliable exploit
exploit the Ripper live like sparks
coming for target
and if critical teetered doctors held
and petted
you will drop for that now obviously PCI
DSS
from stop up obviously because we all
know
that you're a small merchant or a former
chin really bored
up their stuff now dot
moaning so all that way doing in poet as
early as
offers life 2007 installed to help
it's simple hutu anonymized data used it
in a while
wall I exploited busboy them I V Day
this to analyze and for some it's broad
enough X Factor
the third term shouldn't cause financial
chaos the other do it
you find a week merchant are lots of
them the final
your bank credit card data are attacks
are either by a physical attack on the
premises
or by finding reliable exploit which
deployed elsewhere
you then use on the card thanks that
belongs to Norm
helpful acquiring banks surgeon at a
time I report for all
you don't profit and compile tanks that
you once
flying the friendly skies this model of
the month
the money on a traffic control systems
are a lot of Paul
on traffic controllers launched the busy
moving planes around
that's what they care about that's their
job there
had about network security
up because that job he punched in stock
guy called writer Konkel
up frightened by like present some
awesome find
on something are your fam trip very
interesting the last
when people talk about terrorists making
plans fall from the sky
is one of the populace nightmare
scenarios
can only make plans for from the start
now Nikkei you gone out of fashion
organization called not
national air traffic control services
about self as a private-public
partnership in 2000
up as a result some people transport as
we all know private-public partnerships
work all time there's nothing that can
go wrong with them
people are pissed interest in profit
owner
and go home and operational centres but
they've also got
separate traffic control 15 UK adults
by a company called not Services Limited
outbreaks them
the Queen unheard loyal subjects in
government and foreign I'm Sun
a be a a own hopson
on the allied group which consists 7 UK
airlines
and the residual the lots and lots of
people involved in this
all with their own agendas sup
lipton also up by making very simple
query
like find out the information security
manager not
los voy a finalist not what time
managers infrastructure architect
the head safety security and program
management
security and only said up
their own names I'm because the way that
nuts were
in a the very simply email for
sonya spearfishing purposes the space
so without using multi there are any
social engineering all
what you can't do is built a really
detailed organizational chart
for the air traffic control system in
the UK if you were to do it now
if you were doing a targeted attack
state on his bill
nora is over Sony got it out make your
day
a doctor knots also use work pressure
publishing platform the weather
which is actually roller really skill
number please that
at all obviously the website will be
connected to anything else
obviously sup in adults technology stuff
but like to see huge
well last year details were published
but watch flycatcher
Islanders made by frequencerz and then
use a prospect in the plane's roll
elsewhere but currently arguing polished
a electric light air systems a run on
Mike
top what's and its use to track fight
now the for quenches system is used
Nigeria but obviously in the take-home
cope the bus cuz you know we have more
planes Nigeria
and %uh skies are busier on not so also
in 2009 sign docs
single European sky initiative his own
technology stack
if you have enough time to produce the
data about systems reviews from
technical specs are a
outside if church groups mission funding
prospect poll it also focus on talk
about tax
AG the way comes up made in China is all
that shit is made in China
and you know the chinese for are in
charge online there's nothing that
I'm if you want to listen to ICC you can
as an offensive to the lawless like a
few in a hey listening to
about possibly go you find the
transmission frequencies
their a one interesting thing
I am in the UK with also a quick system
which is how military aircraft
communique
iSuppli a pic is basically random radio
frequency hopping
which it makes a pain in the Ulster
moments are and also I mean for
the most you pick upon is American pilot
pitching that the hell
but like lightly sup
she is better than this something I call
upon paradox
on earlier this year guy called Ryan G
first
about all caps actual cameras Apple
point to the from whites
on you know Booker find your topic on
is highly unlikely it will ever be used
by terrorists just her style
and to your own place blockbuster at
probably not right idea from a security
standpoint
I would have polls una sir
wanna criticisms about the stall is the
Turners Falls
also will be turned computers physical
attacks
really halt in a blowing chill is
getting increasingly difficult
on her fun I can accept up-close look at
Apple's
contents winchell sends up on Angeles
such document published which documented
at Paul attacks between 2000-2007
the following the number of attacks
spots open subculture
also plans in the UK and US combined
that was 18 a truck so potential attacks
in Pakistan which is
a much smaller geographical area UK US
that was fifty all sup
attacks really hard for terrorists in
the
Foreign Legion of why
well corporations a this increased
security
business philosophy of terrorism which
is about gaining local sports
you know it's like they are right your
route profession applying pops up in
Belfast
the reason why the blue pops up in
belfast was to remind the people I'll
aft that they are right probably in a
okay if you with a French
same with you know both organizations
blowing about polls
in Pakistan an simple
you play where you have the most bang
for your book if you're looking to
recruit
check out a wrap or in a place you'll
try to recruit
suck quick but about himself into
you may or may not be inside other US
private computers
193 the action at this is also
as a private contractor for intelligence
agencies
intelligence agencies the private
contractors afternoon
an the to arrange publicly available
publications including The
terrorism reference for Apple's Mac
dropped
thanks friendly expensive a cost about
fifty books for a book like
happy on and if you buy one
you were going to put a watch list I can
say
site pickle congress coming to us now
includes descriptions communications
the slow to focus on diagram voice
networks etc speaking about
freaking out about VoIP no because for
all the stops is checked 25
those that you don't know the extent of
stock and international package which
day at work it was the first wall
I deployed in the seventies eighties on
it still use now
on actually fun at work for an upright
largely by national telco companies and
also couple private operators or talk
about later on
Sat your plane X 25 because it is no
longer
1983 it's a pain y'all
the next 18 passion in a dollop now a a
you also need some way to make the
template to
a playhouse no easy why Paul
well X 25 nope stock
thus it's very difficult to secure
doesn't play nice avoid yes
playhouse for only PS and pick up on
idea
for by Sprint network position info
numbers of understand the whole night
night night three
an nothing that's good if you from wall
tile
K associate expand part number:
impact group of the authentication
mechanism all
knowledge other be detected to the
complaint hospital idea
additionally what's the phone share
rooms on x 25
example Vodafone all-male
Osama operates fire 25 can
dole's actually area now accordance
conjecture
as a member of the carriers such as
orange 3 acceptor up
that deploy X 25 Sparta its partner
network but right
now you go offensively a deprecated
stack
grozny in environments where it may or
may not be secure
also another interesting thing
the Greek National Lottery works over X
which is interesting say no deprecated
protocol which comes
chill is in a controlling lottery
a fun she went
Anna yes he is International Telcom
Julian publishes details at that network
ID
notes basically hours 25 workstation in
fact that network ID code
on a network user dress which you know
most is 15 digits
a X 25 addresses our oversight
they have a change the archie you suck
at this is our ship docked at Russia
how to find the new you what I'll know
about football games again people
I am Bowl host of interns
all day stores that the UK well
you've got voted for who was talking
about policy of %uh semester
and day floating around on up you goal
%uh no more the Mora who thanks to the
responsible for the London Stock
Exchange
not not interested now I'm sure however
the last one a the shower all 'it's
dangerous
the organization called Rachael time
total rightful
if you don't know them became toless
Thomas if you don't know them
make bombs and baby killer shit that's
what they did
on be a the fairly interesting shit
still assigned sup
at Kohls terrorists will not spend that
time darling
room for 625 what would you do something
the
for me to imagine I'm gonna get caught
doing
mission also stated I'm not two thousand
olive
and closed countries like China and Iran
might be interesting insight abusing
that systems to do
worshipful set the smaller fun of it
disruption
build a shelf life John if you wanna
take down homes never
build a very big cell phone jammer put
it up on
park in the city centre of 40
cover the archer also sup
that also role in regards homes in a
on you can use a boy finances
a cell minutes or dial premium rate
numbers and find a
not is not be called don't show done a
graph
have a dial and there you go you've got
all funding a future happy camping trips
some local shit
under sign and
the suspect in some customers for much
better weapon
village but is incredibly can be
indicative deeper issues
if only was a terrorist not watched all
Jinnah easy so much
a and China who are believer TV company
up here
a personal trip Hellenic defence systems
to make bombs and shit
up for such cryptic this happens daily
paper
hospital site scripting goodies to make
hamburgers I believe
a precise picture the point is finding
that shit
not halt but it may be indicative of the
ship is going all
instant if you work for an 8-yard those
organizations I didn't tell you because
I don't speak Greek
alright I also understand that like
French is here or something anyway
agendas
I'll be quick apparently the fresh cycle
or is looming
at the UK government is developing cyber
weapons schools
you know obviously using Metasploit all
campuses too difficult and he spent 16
$50 million developing their own shit
apparently
rogue states and political terrorist
groups are coming to get you some role
going to Doc
why our task institutions and decreased
yes because the small computer which
of physical attacks at least in
non-western countries increase in
yes because in Western countries halt to
do
to attract make heck slim trash all
sales strategies
an app fun the system I yeah
on what can you do if Craig terapia
around basically some strange accident
defined
right well in the UK
the Prevention of Terrorism Act 2000 on
which makes it legal to detain
terrorists without trial
on you've got situation where the UK
such a critical issue control orders
suspects and those controls complacently
allow
I legal representatives to ok out
human rights law your cherished human
rights no longer apply for
you a we've got the chairs are not
2006 which allows for 14 days detention
without charge a legal counsel little
bit worried
on got perhaps terrorism bill a 2009
which plans to increase the interment to
42 day
the 42-day in a jail no access full all
now charges ball a very tempted packed
before to get we've also got such good
folks at the pollution Justice Act 2006
which
I quote a person is guilty of an offence
few supplies office to supply
any article believing but
it is likely to be used to commit also
assist in the commission of an offence
basically if you Roy sports and each
used your guilty of an offence
duck cue to misuse also
that's gonna help research UK's don't
really chinaman
now sign
we got really increasing surveillance
state UK
got a nap increasing array of walls
we've also apparently built terrorists
so also lawlz lots of violence
we still have to earth now
interest in russia you can no longer buy
a prepaid sim
help because they could be used by
terrorists this being debated in the US
and if that happens in the US it
developed by that Picard said
welcome to the UK and you have probably
two groups
this is this on for using above right
2007 fosler a got hoped-for
patch from zones propose
users wanting to access the internet
globally
could be required to use a biometric
scanner before continuing
okay you're not insane
Anna now these mechanisms
may indicate soul up the threat of
terrorism
the obviously thought to hold back
either be useful
officially enough you have to buy a much
clearer dance party to step up before
you can use it
us not gonna be used for any other
purposes Hollister
but personally almost editors
when it comes to light computer-related
attacked
on I'm also not avatar those immediate
ripples
while I am genuinely terrified of
ill-informed knee-jerk reactions to it
and my thing is if you actually give a
fuck about secured a
important there's define rips you can
only
dude up once you remove the political
and social engineer sociological
engineering
and all the agenda the guy with the day
now
I've got no problem with people arguing
about supposed to trucks which I
actually don't think
all real threats how many successful
terrorist attacks by terrorists burden
of State
spotlight do you know of no
0 zip house in happens but you know by
all means argue about
up but back to keep angst in reality
in a if there hasn't been an attack okay
what are the risks someone into will a
tired what you attack
a if you were to attack it will be an
effective attacking
you know don't just make shifts open
site you know the world's gonna end in
fifty
minutes cuz evil axle you know orange
have bullshit spurious and it doesn't
help
yeah I don't watch for close are the
enemy is fiyah
we think I Pittsfield another set by
Conde
he was assassinated by a terrorist the
me to get my own saw
questions comments abuse run them
suggestions
me anything doubt
we tried chill from
nothing
well Sox somebody all kid
and good arguing up
fine soldier that
Sun think it's the kind of thing is for
having me
thank you for getting real if you wanna
come suck me by the way
with death threats all mail bombs a slut
sup
thank you all and any questions at all
if you're too shy I'll be out there
drinking coffee in trying to looks
basically saying thank you