okay welcome everybody
levin my name is Kia risk
and upright alia reverse engineering
yes the main goal of my
presentation is to demonstrate the new
concept
regarding dealing with 21st techniques
particularly regarding so protections
I love for example it is
a common practice among the virus
software development companies to use
Parker's noted not bought an extra layer
of protection
against anti-piracy now
the most sophisticated by Curtis willa
integrate their cold
I'll virus kinds of underinvestment
greeks
most of them come other be completely
custom
or use directly some windows
API's eyeliner to give you an example
I'll case you
like for example to I numerator
processes in order to detect malicious
processes like a malicious to running
like a well known to Barca reversing
cool you would use
layer process 32 first persisted next
API's
in order to enumerate the purses sent
the pic the ex
if not to release currently running
along with your process
now the good thing is about
I'll one hikers use
this kind of three is that it in
the it really gives you a punk that's
because
this cold it's already the memory its
operating systems call
so sits this cold is there and what's to
be triggered
at the center point why not use it
for in that's a in our favor
because what really happened she's
as the execution of the Parker goes on
and the
porous layers get the crib in memory you
get closer to the original entry point
to the publication
so the figure is not along with his
execution
or so the varsity first picnics are
going to be trigger
so what we're going on but said the
point some what their first picture
going to be
more close to the end of execution of
the Parker
so this means that the either with half
I'll their original cost of the program
or if the impact in memory
I in other cases
went to a park itself implements
its own licenses them probably this
layer is the cryptic
I die and is going to be used directly
after
about the use the three getting office
and the rest greeks
so you're to close and Yukon
from from those techniques to a doc
either a pic the park itself its
licenses them
or theoretical I'll
gold of the program if the protection is
there
now this concept has
I as you gonna see has many advantages
well first the form
since most of the Packers shipments also
virus sick some sex now by using
called up it's nothing site the biker
the fuck it doesn't know what you're
doing
this is the first lines one of the most
important
and the the second the second one is
that
up you come like for example you don't
have to
completely Michael unpack the
application which means that you can
avoid a local folks the world like
reconstructing the
it's not important but a stable the
original lawyer fixing called splices
and other virus picnic start the pack is
used in order to make the reverse is
life
quite more difficult of course
you could use any Windows API used by
the program
if it's of course triggered letting the
correct timing
during the execution but this is another
thing
up today we're going to talk about the
specific
activist recused by your mobile a
which tries to cross lit by Garrett this
is a specific
to reversing 3 its AP packet a specific
University it the want or
fight dialect woke up any effect this is
the first technique was discovered by a
the guys behind on my pillow years ago
and is still used so this technique is
going to be used
I in any case by automobile
I so I use the issue in order to
find let's say emo replace the place
cervical
now the I our case
it's also or make what makes our case
more interesting
if that's the whole application has been
let's say you're up there around
with fax-no: Co we're gonna see in a
while
what's all this
so it on my pillow probably many people
ripping no
most of the people but deal with
southward
my sense of development its axle
inexcusable
occur it's true that the first very good
protection against
reverse engineering antisocial popular
among commercial
software developers sure some
3x that there might be a lil biker
diplomats
you can either have portable executable
code their elimination
it actually want to eliminate the whole
chapter just small part of it
I quote splicing it's a very interesting
technique it will actually
during the parking I'll the program
which gets executed it gets fucked in
memory
it's going to steal some my ass Pacific
Lance of cold
and substitute them with some toms
into high memory locations so if you
dont the process
I some cold is a let's say
a substitute it with dance some places
the so you want tough working working in
much
I come either choose to do specific port
redirection
sets two's to redirect specific pointers
the inside important but a stable are
either eliminate the whole
important stable the but block your it's
a very interesting feature
it was actually applied as compromiser
against about seeing because it's a very
good idea on your up like a
a publication and
you you see that you can't bypass some
tricks during their
execution the Parker electron and then I
thought
the process notebook local what really
does ease
but it forces the application I
lots a second process and Budget Inn
member who want to running
so burial program is going to run from
the second process
which is a tight process which is while
it's running
its key skit gets it is the up by the
parent process
so you can at that's the second process
by a
ordinary means of course is a way to
bypass this to
I'll the copy man it's a very
interesting
this it was out with us practically as
an extra feature along with the puck
locker
because the guy sold out was very easy
in the end to
bypassed but but locker so copy member
works
with Bates guards so when executioner
the tide
tries to execute the specific I'll
a specific like stocks on specific which
all others are aids
which has been marked only with for for
exemplary toxicity has
doesn't have execute Texas and excision
is going to be raised
with its the Pirates the box it and it's
going to
receive this event it's going to see
that help memory access violation
it's going to restore bach and their
Italian permissions
endorse the group that Bates I'll cover
some non-whites
along also is the company implemented
doesn't accept feature
along with putlocker on
mites a very interesting at the best
technique its
only used by Armadillo I'll armadillo
shell it does is
substitute some conditional toms with in
30 months which are like software
interrupts
so what the are in process bucks the
application
I knows by in a creek to table
what actions fake depending on where the
exception occurred
and normal it's going since it will
normally
Tom substitute on condition its amps the
parents house to check
like only that execution flights
and redirected the direct the suction
pointed to the time
depending on the fines execution blacks
some mother call +1 and reverse it fixes
just that the bug detection through the
column on
is the bugger present I
gonna have some serious he six-ounce
runtime:
and or so of course the
public or talk with the box thing API
with things of this form up trying to
cross the bike and as we said
this we only work with only
so what this lets channel cynical
is is mostly used for portability
its it will actually bach all cock
all the dependencies of predicted
independents together for specific
program
so you can avoid some issues like the
early to tell for example
when you want to I run your application
where the taping machine has a previous
versions
some pls so this is mostly used for
portability congress what you see you
later Center
sometimes neck at the booklet from work
itself up and this is very important
that the brutal as it gets a lot
dependently from the other software and
SaaS the host PC
everything is going to be lots in memory
runtime:
is not going to use the let's say that
the lengths of
the of the printing system to running on
it's going to launch
everything it needs a petition the
brittleness YouTube channel that picture
called uses
so has a muscular University UN that is
yes
if you're eat just interested Michael
impact on my pillow kung fu
online and find many tutorials about
but we're not sure for that day up dust
samples provided the antivirus
protection
well your ass is no at least not on
purpose
of course tenneco it implements a very
basic
the packet detection become if that
doesn't work mentions you
and the of course but the fact that
everything is going to run on conviction
records Britto machine
makes the whole process more interesting
because
nope not only every module that's going
to be loaded in memory
has every time a different too much
space
it is also the fact that natively
armadillos going to
allocate some extra memory and right
there
effort will be led point they are much
has been a from the previews
from the previous page we're going to
see this later on
so the hope other this is the first time
the committee look it's
are can't get simple with publication
utilization
there's a lot to learn regarding to see
inappropriate self-protection
because we will see a case where we're
going to use and reversing technique
I'll against the protection itself
so this is a short description of our
case
this is a real commercial software I
it's not
something I I made just to
play around it's quite expensive so
so fertilizer the fertilizer application
was slow to return for the
from work and the
their mobile protection has been applied
gonna fit Steelers
libraries before dipped actionable Peter
latest gets applied
so when we run the application Excel a
cold as Surratt said
is going to look memo reorganised same
organs it clean
than what they look like they let which
is used for the license management
electrons days remaining License
Verification enter
of course the tix as I said are going to
be launched by either
Britt on BBE lol but we're going to see
this later on
now here's some pics information about
the trick
are police so organise a modus arose
around that much for it said
there's no writing them temporarily like
that these help and the harvest
axis on for this think also
mister William Rothwell from a babys
company
I used his it's the F hardware firewall
when I was on there was talking with him
so because he wanted like a
proof of concept but the reason really
%uh know why o.o with the heart this
quite acceptable
close the application I was right
I soul work with a tent for example to
come from memory in with programmable a
popular
but this it's completely using this
every time
you're on the guest acceptable it's
going to blow the original in memory
as we saw rates have a myspace for more
goods programmable but then it was
different
memory every time irani
and as I said before there might be a
look below
we'll look at some extra memory runtime:
and right there some extra cold
was the last season's going to that's a
perform with sex and the Sorcerer's Mar
boxes the lead from the previous
versions
or Italy like years ago you could see
Remarks Bilal
probably created I am
into specific for their offer of windows
but
this is not the case anymore
so the fact that the payments based
changes every time
many stalkers the brutal others that
specific goal regarding
I'll the last six want to that's going
to be different
time
soap up well normally cue you could do
to thinks you can either call the loader
rollovers Ricky member that specific all
look modified
runtime: well normally for applications
will have different types of
a box it's a you would either
try to my early completely Michael Young
pocket which is
very funny say cannons owners have with
a
I you can either practical tool older
and do all the talking runtime:
I alright then you could line
the application itself normally lining
I am will either reinforce only execute
the ball
or some pillows particular use
but that depends on its case for example
from my personal experience
abused I like orifice techniques and
it's crazy when you see like with
protectors
I really kicking destroyed by program is
that they don't know how to use them
i've seen cases like where they have
used like a
very good bikers like us perfect like
the new versions
of prospect and they come
for example bach execute the ball with
us put their
and the half-blood like the trial
beer a limitation into a non McBeal
so like come on why did you
I did you pay for the biker if you think
Euclid meant the the license sick like
inside the popular enough but the letter
and exit from but is that with this girl
is called
the application is a recount but the
memories are we going to do that Pfizer
to inflict call you remember me on the
but the petition
aqui don't even have to worry about
the park itself okay
to have trouble here
okay let's go
so this want is
said is gonna be like fickle their
thoroughness
by trying to write or or online
functions
like southwick its the
runtime: which in this case is also
more fun so are we
inside the protection the as we said
before the beetle
is going to be no somewhere it's not
reloaded
awesome the armadillos
public it's a memory right the cold the
ritual
I'll what's going to use the output
boxing API in order to cross
biker as said this is specific debugger
like so confused spock inside
I like are we site
there populous ritual Philip this is a
case
where the output box thing its
school trying to Crusoe
biker you can see this thing as a
barometer
the school and it just thing
is now you can clearly see
fertile others I'll
from where the call has been implemented
and guess
and guess what this artist is inside the
ritual
but every time us F
of course or there's mortgage going to
be created
runtime: but these is another layer
after that because this is going to be
that created by government believes the
lol
by a look at some extra memory right its
own but until it somewhere
so here we are where bach to the IMAX is
love space
you can see the called up
books above so
know that we're here will just start to
work around just see if this anything
interesting
you can see from the stick references
some useless things of course there's
nothing to copy and paste here
if it led to this is another case it
will not work
so don't write copy and paste anything
in other cases you have to dig deeper in
other things so
I am by a
trying to find to take the reference to
our
username there you can see that
a certain point we have
FIU so from here
okay you this location here
okay sure that the by
is going to be move back want
the fight by to silver it's their
from memory location site that the
spatial
ritual the alert from a deal and
and despite is going to be safe in to
let's say
local viable is local
and then move despite
ok eTex then take the ex's not
so don't EX issue
so the dumps
not going to be executed but we're going
to see some other issues
it's not that easy so there's some
issues
around this month by yes it is always
you
by the forty must always be nosey
by C always I mean at the specific
time on the execution because the same 6
are going to be perform more than once
so if you're like you can't wait
might fight it going to shoot this
program is going to be reset
buck 20 and there's nothing to do about
then because
this is not going to beat since forever
probably that
necrotic can be performed three or four
times in this case
so like if you are too fast and
second good now like the next six going
to give you said
who said like 20 and as we said
of course is the outer space every
turbulence or so the pizza like this
where these bites locate
is going to be different every time so
we can know
what is the free tool others much bite
every time
the pic is runs in order to be able to
modify
and of course modified when it's the
correct timing to do so
so by putting
putting things together now
woke up always know every to like this
got the spatial which hotel
stock what they are with the box it go
to school and we also know if it's a lot
this
months ago by so here's
reflect the brutal the Briton lewis
structures always the same
of course so the differences fights
between
extrication is going always be constant
it doesn't matter if you come from 100
110 North
200 210 the difference is always 10
and this is what we're going to use so
what we just need is thoroughly
analytically to like this of the month
of the month by
to avert a lot this way record book
boxing API has occurred
from the brittan pillar here's an
example
Lake much bypass relative it all others
its a must bite brutal address
minus the address where we're going to
come bach
after the quote book box three is
performed
and of course this distance every time
is different
because got with the box thing is going
to be
called trying to cross out the biker
from more than on occasions
that's why I'm telling you got you have
to know when you're going to use the
picnic
you have first of course analyze the
biker see for example on your case
how many times is 66 performed when
when my let's say it's safe
it is the body of the month by gun do it
whenever you want so some things to keep
in mind
for the visual art a complete a lot this
I'll
will only cost if you all lucifer
to the Brit Oval Office of the same
core got box thing from the bitter pill
it because
set up gonna be more than one course and
of course who else invasion
and others had before
this some other stick which they raced
the licensed security
may pick more than once so the brutal
killer
which means that miss that much bite me
bit tense but
in tissue Unit No how many times
the output the Park City scored and when
it's safe to modify that much
by which means that
Sophie this a so action icons you may
need to calculate the relative it a lot
this
much bite by county how many times that
put the plastic has been called
in picking course duration: the safe
which all others
were reported bucks think from the
turbulence me
so can go one step further I'll keep
reflecting the fucked up
you cannot write in like function but
gotta clean with fights
much by you don't like it was last
season because as we set this going
never too late feel it's going to be
written somewhere in memory later on
during the execution
and of course we need to prepare the
first link function
that's going to be executed when we
still have control of the execution of
the application
because later the channel Alberto
muahzzz going to take control
so won't be able to to play as we want
and more
so we're going to do is to
somehow exploit notebooks thing West
pic by with the fighting VR school site
the current to lurk in the face
depending on Windows version
your officials produced like with
Windows seven
and some basic functions have been with
their
actually application you will steer you
see like car
let's see in the port at this table
you keep use the issue that there is a
pointer to the conflict between
lol we're going to go there would be
directly
redirected cannot base I because the
conditions
is really that if you're in 2007
and as we said this modification must
look every time a runtime
as said we don't use the cold up
of epic wouldn't really want to directly
at back because the fair
of application upset win over Tampa
reversed the pics going to get trickier
and the school it's already there
already Nova
of his face route our own cold
dynamically every time we don't even
care about the
a SLR and other stuff going to show you
ho
so this is the same lining this is like
I am
which the Singh the first this is the
starting
of the first line function about it some
extra strings
said the cold Katy
notice that the music you Nicole for the
system given names
that's because the application is use
the unique ok first floor library
so this support Fig I'm more so using or
so busy port addressed the people of the
application itself
to know were peace let's say were
well as the a to call the local library
for my needs
I don't have to no because the
application uses
so I'm going to use the references from
the pointers
set the tone port staple
so characteristics of EPA's some
interest to them
and the two pillars
so this is the first line function
buttressed the lash of coal
I are the structure that they were
substituted when I wrote it some
politically directly from the entry
point
to the court gave of course you can or
so directly modify
the the entry point said the shitter
but a it's not let you could do this
but in some cases work as we're going to
say later
a there are some sick some 60 people
were so the shitter don't want this
so intense that information said hither
sources ices had the first this the
first three
instructions are from the retirement on
the fabrication
then I save you tonight because it's
theirs and the state
execution flux and
my feel and function starts getting
executed this is the first line function
this is I constantly say
in a cold cave site the application
welcome she later
how you can upload take some 6 in case
you used this technique
saw what I'm going to do first this I
need to know which
very soon I love the guys going to run
the application
some thank first to get the car like PLO
the killer bass the library if I'm
honest do so it means that someone went
to seven so I don't have to try
I for can offer to anymore
then what I'm going to do is to
17 and no now EX this the bay
the address payments based the others
payments based specific module that
though it has been
we could just retrieved so with a point
who is I need I need this let's see
this hunger so I'm going save this
by you I to yet and then I'm gonna post
the as a barometer that
dealt with the box thing and the file
you
us second parameter to get broke to get
personal address
and in this way I'm going to retrieve I
first before the address where every
time is noted
the out ok with the box thing because
you know
obvious a large every time no worries
and
want to do this I'm going to save its
fine you
to to VAT rates there and then
to the same process again for the
picture perfect a
we're going to use the same humble as
before that's why we saved by the
Hon'ble Twizy
and events if it's others less so now
have been eighty it is now pointing to
the
without with the box thing and is it
points to
brittle protect now of the parameters
for better protect is actually a pointer
with the war where when the function
returns
it a do like when the folks from
a diplomats serve like it's going to
write their the
the old cost under the protection so in
case you want to sainted the game but
later
you know what the cost what these
of course not to do this I have to
to post to this to as a barometer
remember location
warehouse right axis other whites
the call to the pH gonna fail so what
I'm doing here is also using that data
section of the application itself
because it has already right axis so I
don't a
me too let's say
to use some any extra cold and use their
like
and try to get there right DOCSIS all
that stuff I can directly use that data
section
that's why I am posting the this artist
something others
the data section and then I'm pushing
the rest barometers
like the you want this constant 46
which means a a try to execute
the size
don't take the permission before it
kicks I'm going or so to
to post the address to what box think
it's
in the 1880 have been called the
function
get pacific's writes that now
as we said before week no
when we're going to modify this much by
so we need somehow I
to know how many times this on the best
rick has been triggered you need their
way to know that right
so whether going to do is the first
thing I'm doing
is to I'll
bust the netted that the entry point
where is it
%uh 24 which is the end it's the last
ukraine's want to reach the last bite
from when I took the permissions
and I'm putting there is hereby with I'm
going to use as a counter
some using I'm using force my own
counter inside the second blank function
that's going to be written so want to do
this
I also write memory as you remember
points to
the outbox thing but output by sleep
last night before
because I i did. 24 busy
now 80% of course exploding but with the
box thing but since I didn't need any
more of them
the outdated interpreter protect
I used the I used as she
to make the first cut Commissioner for
writing my counter
so there is typical months is about
writing
the second link function but a curious
or on time
when execution comes here so
this is the second land function this is
what we're going to see now in
after the execution the first lung
function this is called the outbox
get the app has been modified okay
on you can see here my counter
I every time
this the first pics go to be triggered
it's going to save this tape
the topic was in its simplicity
execution flux
and I need to do this
the third time this is the first it gets
triggered
my case so the first and get executed
might be one my counter is going to take
the country's
his three if it's not it's going to
restore but there it's a sin
go but and but this it's three
I'm going to retrieve from my from the
stock
from the other s for the the stack
pointer
points to blast into for kicks were
treated this fight you
because at that point there's that
invites there is
it distorted by you buck from the output
bucks think they are much as bill
another space
and a point to and I i pick on some
but I know that from but with that not
the best after that for time
this is the Pistons of began at
between there if they're not the best
but they're much they love the space
the month by and vet now a week of
I'll the others the bike and put into
this one
we're going to see this led so
versus more conclusion I
up LACMA social protection
is good right case may not suit your
needs
it's true that course consider so for a
couple
a specific requests about about this
thing
up like I use the court for the loader
was discussing before I
some people really use it
but the hook because more fun too so
this technique like
if you can really use metal also another
case
you have to write the loaders specific
this application
one you can't like use this concept to
different people
defeat the different types bikers
and the good things up is not the fuck
it won't even notice the kid
so on gotten the text some text
because somebody would say okay the
first line
function safeties have to execute the
so the fuck your cunt sick what ticks
right
yeah okay the public at 600 can take
about six Sams see if I have modified
the application before before I taints
the court of
up system API memory
okay the first we think he's not a
fuckin will never rely on the tix some
I depending on the cold of some Windows
API
because the school can set up any time
in the future update
solar safe give up that marked the best
thing that the packet could do
like after seeing this is let's say okay
now
the calm one and two-point for summer
for the city I would know that she's
like
up move 8 the AP so
what I'm going to do is the ticket
destructions first
but of course stupid because our can
always keep this a construction
and the it but defiant up to another
occasion
are cutting the Texans because biker
okay want to rely on the tech someone
depending on when the ship yet but the
economy should rely on the tech some its
own
all the files has protected of course
many bikers implement text some text
including us for a pic a super thick
our mobile from this number protection
options
and the ball and many others
of course so what you can do is
as you saw I started I am I modified
the API so if you don't get executed
Michael gets executed ago
virulent the best pic but
what you can do is that
K you can see down there after
the first Lanfranchi gets executed and
modifies the specific API a quote
memory have its own I
bach to continue the execution of the
process
what they can't do there is with its own
I already know all the other cities
so i cant up in this too for example
without
boxing I can't up in any location on
inside
out this space next the others range
but specific API so i cant some
their from she ain't directly continued
execution
dump their up this
its previous Pacific old is going to
write a few more distractions
but going to be separated from my called
that's going to
to got back there the the protection
later
it's going to be where my counter
correct this behind like
below use the rest space and
this or civic would think that %uh
QuickBooks thing API
it also provide to break with space
where you gun
really write some extra go like folk
problem
so is the something
bach stopping like directly to bike
the execute there's the publication
when the at the first lady fucks hazard
the second in memory
i cant Sam another occasion below and
sat there
he said the cold whereas or Africa's
makes the call
and but cool squeaky-clean or these
and then dump but
to the entry point so what the fuck is
going to sick
about in memory verifications
he's not going to take it's not going to
find them of course they're gonna people
deficiency guarding the fine
I'll but of course covers apart
this like you can't wait for you all
usually the Parker
is going also sick I as an extra layer
of protection from modifications
run thank which of course
it's more like it's more effective
because in this week on a subject of a
break break points his way
going to suffer a break point is going
to Arthur
you're called memory you don't to
release you
but others the cold memory it's up to us
to buy it with the
SEC x-pipe so if and
take some is going to be implemented I
is going to get triggered also by using
break points okay
I have a
but if you do just status or what I
wanted lot
is up yeah it's true that the
workers like the open is totally rely
the the Parkers the commercial bikers
and
this book but because many of them are
very cool but
are I think it's better bought some
extra layer of protection
side your code itself but it seems that
nobody
by dust so
I'll it was this it was the main
presentation so now we're going to
missus movie do
well
okay I I don't senior cortex
welcome song the video because a this is
a commercial application
alone anybody to exclusive now because
we didn't have the time to fix this so I
want you to respect the fact that
this is a commercial program
so this is the original on
I you see that
it has already expired so let's try to
see what we can do
this is the they wanna have implemented
okay structure so you can see up there
it's the entry point this it's amp down
to my coat K
K so this is how the output box three
looks like before modifying it
so here's the cold which
destructions we tripped out dresses
you can see this will save
the the other support boxing every them
right back to the
that with the same
retrieve the other super to protect
we're going to see if this
is you for later use so
have this citrus sleepy eyes
want to use so sure
I'm using has a said a pipe inside the
data section
which recovery right axis so icon I
safely controversial protect to get the
necessary access rights
ritual what they are with the box thing
API so let's not go there and see scenes
so
stole the call looks like of the output
the box thing a pen memory
and the parking of course was no way to
know what operated up
the pack is going to try to cross
or biker and don't even know what you
did
so up with the
her the point execution so
that's right now to run we're gonna see
some
error messages appearing that's because
as he said
the brittle machine of tenneco
a runs low-tech memory sold
biker sculptures the fan but Motors has
been loaded
but can't find the low the motor nowhere
in this
harvest soak up fine analyze it so it
keeps
3 getting some okie
this is the first time we venom
the brutal out there still is going to
try to cross her biker
you see the first thought this from
where it's cool
we're on again
you see here
its we're going to sick the centrists
which is you this is all counter
said for now is gonna be
became one of course this
it's not three so are re-elect factions
not going to be triggered it
we don't want this this is the second
time
that would boast nick has been confirmed
which from a different others again okay
so
down okay this is the third time
would get your now it's
the third time so its okay skorik let's
move to TX
30 not this look 82 where the stack
pointer
a I'm going to show you
stung she their stock point their souls
this than others 24 down
let's its cool this others
we're inside a city Sat there might be
less brutal killer
space you can see against some
interesting strings you can see the name
are much is the little
okay
and two minutes so
I'll now I out the but constant
my case was like
that cost them their from the third
return address
want the after three times the call but
the box
has been trigger and now I know
where the much by finally dislocate
memory applications going to of course
do this automatically every time
that's what our our first lunch those
like function does
it'll its rights second one the sick one
stays in memory
and waits for the first pics to get a
gift but instead of up
are are things going pic so gonna see
this going to beat Saints 21 and
charities
and the list now
Walker remove the 100 breakpoint his
more and they're out there the rest
is we're gonna help again the same thing
about
the biker sees the cups as they've been
to floating in with you but can't find
them
so this is it I if you have any question
about regarding this technique or
anything similar
another us now or later okay
no questions thank you very much enjoy
the rest of the conference