[Music]
well
uh
welcome everyone to this talk all your
eaters are belong to us or how to hack
ethereum basic dabs
who am i my name is luis quispe gonzalez
i've been having fun for around 11 years
working in the offensive security field
currently i elite offensive security
engineer at halberd a company
specialized in cyber security for
blockchain and crypto war
i also post graduate instructor in
ethical hacking courses and you can
reach out to me in lincoln
english kispe gonzales or telegram all
at night and say hello we can talk about
cyber security we can talk about crypto
talk about life and love why not
so
what are we going to see today
well we will do a quick recap about what
is blockchain i will have a general
introduction about smart contracts and
the main dish of this presentation where
decentralized application or tabs and
especially how to hack them
so let's start
blockchain 101
what is blockchain as a name indicates
is a
a a chain of block that contains some
kind of information blockchain became
popular with appearance of bitcoin in
but be careful bitcoin is just one of
the many applications that blockchain
can have in fact blockchain is a
distributed ledger so it's completely
open to anyone so anyone can interact
with the blockchain and it has an
interesting property
once some information or data is
recorded inside a blockchain it's
extremely extremely complicated to
modify that info
so how does it work let's let's look at
one block a block contains data
hash and hash of preview blog
where is the kind of data that contains
a blog well it depends on the blockchain
for example
in
in bitcoin we have information about
the sender
we have information about the receiver
and we have information of of the
number of coins involved in the
transaction it depends obviously on the
blockchain
we also have a hash of the block we can
compare this with a fingerprint for
humans
each blood has its unique hash and it's
very interesting because if you modify
one bit in the block
now the hash is
completely different
different if you modify another bit on
the block now the hash is completely
different again
this allows us to verify very quickly if
someone has stamper our block if we
compare the hash
and finally we have a hash of a previous
block so with those three elements now
we have a blockchain
big question here
what happens if an attacker wants to
modify or tamper our blockchain
well blockchain has two powerful
mechanisms to avoid it
the first one is called consensus
and consensus regarding bitcoin and
interior that is what we are going to
see today the consensus mechanism is
called proof of work how does it work
if someone wants to create a block that
contain transaction
of many users have to solve a crypto
challenge
what does it mean
he has to
calculate the hash of all the
transaction plus a number called nons
and this hash has to be compliant with a
specific numerical condition
so
as far as we know there is no
mathematical way to calculate these
nonce you have to guess it
so
the more computational resources you
have it's more likely that you are able
to create a bill with with transactions
the mean time for block creation is 10
minutes why is that
in that way we can avoid spamming of
lock in the blockchain this 10 minutes
is for bitcoins for other blockchain
ebay rights there are some events on
blockchain that it takes just seconds to
to process the blocks
this process of block creation is called
mining and the ones who participate are
called of course miners
okay
the second mechanism is called
peer-to-peer network
so every participant in the network has
its own local copy of the blockchain
remember is a distributed ledger so
everyone has its own local copy so if a
user wants to create a new blog he
shares the blood with the participants
in the network
and every participant verifies by its by
his own
if that block is compliant or not with a
specific numerical condition i mentioned
earlier if so
then
they join the block to their local
blockchain
that's how they obtain the famous
consensus
if an attacker tries to create a fake
block that is not compliant with a
numerical condition so it's
automatically rejected that's it very
easy
great
now let's talk about smart contracts
we can compare a smart contract with a
traditional contract they both have
terms and conditions
the big difference here is the smart
contract is digitalized so
that term our conditions are expressed
in
code
when you
start that code compile in a blockchain
that's what we call smart contracts so
because data smart contact is inside a
blog developed in a blockchain
it's accessible for everyone
everyone can interact with a contract
i mean
depending on your authorization level
you can do one task or another but at
the end of the day you can interact with
a contract and of course there is
consensus about the outcome of the smart
contract
let's see an example imagine a
crowdfunding platform like kit starter
or indigo there is a product team who
wants to rate some a monetary goal and
on the other side we have
supporters that help that project to be
to be possible so the supporters sends
money to the crowdfunding platform let's
let's imagine kickstarter and
if
there is enough money to fulfill the
monetary goal then the money goes to the
producting otherwise if the goal is not
met the crowdfunding platform returns
money to supporters
how does it work in the blockchain world
let's see
instead of having a
platform we have a smart contract so
supporters send coins
to the smart contract
here you can see that the coins are
inside the smart contract and
if the gold is met the coins are sent
to the product team otherwise the
contract returned
the coins to the supporters
what is the logic inside a contract very
straightforward an if condition
if gold is met
then give money to producting
gold is not met
refund supporter
that's it
very easy
of course we can have many examples and
many different uses cases we have for
example a smart contact for the bank
industry
for loans for insurance for delivery for
music service for streaming for video
games for exchanges etc huge etc many
many applications for smart contracts
okay
nowadays what are the blockchains that
support smart contracts well we have
many of them
but the main one nowadays it's ethereum
if you want to build a smart contact for
interview you can use
solidity programming language it's not
the only one but it's one of the most
popular
okay
now
regarding ethereum
here we have
a
a user
also called external user and we have a
contract both are identified
with a 20 by hexadecimal address
what can we do inside
the blockchain of ethereum well we can
send coins between users
the native coin of ethereum it's called
eater so you can send it to another user
you can also
can interact with a contract when you
interact with a contract you call a
function in a contract that's important
what else
a contract can also interact with
another user
and we can also have chain reactions a
user interact with a contract the
contract interacts with another contract
and that contract interact with another
user a change reaction
well
let's see in action we have a user
that interacts with a contract it means
he calls a function in a contract
and it also means he transacts
but the user has to sign the transaction
why
it's the only way to demonstrate he's
the owner of the transaction so to sign
the transaction he will use
a private key
now the transaction is signed
is sent to the blockchain and everyone
can decrypt with a public key because
they are public
in a day-to-day operation
users
don't sign manually the transaction so
he uses some tools like
the crypto wallets we have many crypto
wallets
that we can use to store and manage that
private key
right
now
let's see what are the centralized
applications or dabs
let's see one of them in action
for example here we have a adapt called
synthetics that is a dab that allow us
to interact with financial assets
as you can see it looks like a normal
webpage
we go to a stacking option
and in the upper corner you'll see that
we are not connected so we try to
connect a wallet
in this dab
and appear a
menu with many wallets i will use
metamask for example metamask is a
crypto wallet that can be installed as
applying in in a browser it's very easy
to use so i will select metamask
will appear a screen showing all the
address that i that i have in in my
wallet i will select the first one that
ends in d1 e6
and now i'm connected as you can see in
the upper corner now i'm using the the
others that ends in d1 e6
and once i connected i can start
interact with different options and
interact with different
financial assets inside the
decentralized application very
straightforward
of course there are many examples of
different apps we have financial apps or
d files that are very popular
from 2020
onwards you also have marketplace like
for example similar to amazon similar to
ebay
we can have dubs
of social networks for example one
similar to youtube
we can also have video games we can have
exchanges we can have streaming services
a huge etc
okay
everything sounds great
but how dubs work inside let's see the
architecture of that
on the left side you see a web
application a traditional web
application on the right side we have
adap so in a traditional web application
we retrieve the static file from a web
server what
what i mean with the static file is html
css and javascript
and
i mean the visual part now
the browser connects to a backend for
example through apis data can connect to
a database and so on that's a
traditional architecture for a web
application
on the other side in adapt
the static files
and the
and the backend is inside the blockchain
the most used architecture is a hybrid
one
so the static files are retrieved from a
web server and
the
the backend is on blockchain
big question here
what is the magic behind that how is
possible that a browser connects to a
blockchain
well let's see
let's look uh closer how it works
here we have a browser and on the other
side we have double blockchain so
in order to to that everything works
okay we need an intermediary
for example we can use a server a
computer or a cloud service and we are
going to turn this server for example
in a it you know
how can i get that very easy i can
install a tool like get i can use a
cloud service like in fura et cetera
many options
what does it mean to be itu know well
the server has have
needs to have
their its own local copy of the
blockchain
with the smart contract of course
he also
installed a company ethereum
virtual machine that allows to interpret
the
instruction for the smart contracts and
we also have interfaces
that allow
external user or internal process
communicate with the tv node
now let's see in action we have
everything ready
the browser retrieves a static file from
web server
as i told you earlier html css
javascript files
one of the many javascript files that
you can use is for example with web3 js
it's a popular javascript
file
this allows you
to create a transaction
to build the transaction
but remember before using the
transaction you have to sign
the transaction so you use
applying like metamask
that store and manage your private key
and sign that transaction i mean you
build and sign the transaction and then
you send to the theory load through for
example a protocol like http or https
very easy and here comes the magic
if your transaction is a rate only or a
query transaction for example how much
how many tokens do i have in my account
you read the value directly
from your local copy of blockchain
and the values returned to the user
but
if your transaction implies a change for
example send some coins to the smart
contract or deploy a new smart contract
on the blockchain in those examples
internally you create
a new block in your ethereum node
and this ethereum node through ethereum
protocol
share that block
to other participants in the network and
you remember
if those participants
verified verify that the block is
compliant with a specific numerical
condition so they join the block to
their
own local copy of blockchain
that's it very easy
okay
uh
the big question here is
are dabs secure
well as far as we know
we know that smart contact and apps in
general
are immutable and no one can modify your
smart contracts
all users
sign the transaction
and the code of the smart contract is
available for everyone so everyone can
read and interact with a smart contract
so
what can go wrong
well
many things
here i show you some news about
about a steal of millions of of money in
blockchain platform
why how does it happen
let's see some example and now my
favorite part
hacking
how can we hack some dubs some smart
contracts
i will show you the for example an
encrypted private data so let's see
this example we have a smart contract
for a betting dab
okay so
it's a betting tab and we have two
players
player one
bets
bets one eater
to the number and one
only player one and only the contract
know what is that number and one
on the other hand
player two
bets one eater to the number and n2
again only player 2 and a contract know
what is n2
so
if the sum of the numbers
is
even
all the money goes to player 1
but if the sun
is odd
all the money goes to player 2.
it's it sounds like a fair game they
both have 50 50
of winning the game right
are you sure
let's see the call
here we have a data structure that
represents a player and here we have a
number field
do you remember that when a user
interacts with a contract he calls a
function well this is a function called
play
and this public when it's public it
means that external user
the players can interact with this
function
here's a function to get
and also we have a private function
this function calculate who is the
winner and sends the money but be
careful
because it's private nobody outside a
contract can interact with this function
so players cannot interact directly with
this function
and we also have a
player data that are private so of
course
nobody outside the contract
knows what is what are the numbers so
everything is secret apparently
but we are in a blockchain world
so let's see this
in attack
i'm going to
change my screen
and
now
you see my
id
and
here i
show you remix remix it's an online ide
that allows to
write some code and interact with the
contracts
this id is connected to a local
blockchain that appears here
and this local blockchain we have some
address etc
okay
in this section
here appears the different accounts that
i can use this is test account of course
every account has a 100 items
here appears the value of money that i
can send
and here
it's a button to deploy the contacts so
this is the example i'm going to show
you this contract
is that contract that i'm going to
deploy
okay i have deployed a contract
and
let's imagine that this account that
start with 56d is player number one
player number one is going to get
one eater
to let's say
to number seven
he plays
everything works okay
and now it's turn
off player number two here if you see he
has he has bet one liter so
he has now
almost 99 eater
i'm going to chain to play player number
two
that start with 732 he has
100 eater but before he plays
he's going to see
the blockchain the transaction in
blockchain
here you can see this is a
transaction for the
deployment of the contract and here is a
transaction of player 1
betting for one number
but remember
everything every information
is always record on blockchain and that
information is public
your
your variables your data can be private
inside a contract
but once you transact that information
is stored in a blockchain so it's public
if i'm going to see i'm going to see
this transaction
and here we see some data
at first it doesn't make sense but if we
take a closer look we see that this
number
is an identifier
of the plague function
and this number here
it's the number player 1
bet
in hexadecimal so everyone can see that
player 1 has bet to number 7
so
if player two see this
he he will try
to create an even some to win of course
so now i player two i'm going to play
for example to number
the number four why because the sum is
even
i'm lewis at the moment i it might be on
purpose but i can just see demo time
oh
sorry
i'm going to
i'm going to shoot
wait wait wait
do you see my screen now
yes now i can see the screen okay okay
do not worry i'm going to repeat again
uh
here i show you my id this is remix it's
an online id
and as i told you before this is uh
this is my local blockchain just for
example and test purposes so
i'm going to i'm going to
to reset my my blockchain
okay
here i have that the smart contact i
told you before
so i'm going to deploy the contract
pretty quickly
and
here we have different test accounts
i'm going to select this account uh
that'll start with not knight fight f
in this part he's going to
write how much how much money he's going
to send
and here
he can interact with that contract the
contract is already deployed and here we
see the plate function
so
let's see he's going to get one eater
i said
to number seven
and he's going to play
if you see
the
local blockchain here in transactions
you see that here there is a transaction
for the contract creation and there is a
transaction for player1 that has bet to
some number if we click that
we see some data here
and we see
that this value is the identifier of the
function and
this value here
is a number that player 1 has bet 2.
this information is open to anyone so
anyone can see this value
player 2 can also see this value
so if he know that player 1 has played
to number 7
and now
let's see player number 2 that start
with 7 f 0
he has 100 eater so he will
bet one eater
to a number that made him win so he can
he can bet to number four
because the sum is 11 there is
and so
now he's going to bet one eater so he
will have 99 eater if he wins he will
receive twitter and at the end he will
have 101 eater let's see
if it's if it works
okay
the transaction is okay and if we see
now
right
we have
101 eater approximately minus fizz
so now he's able to win he always wins
because he will know where is the number
other players are betting to because
again all the information in blockchain
is always public
let's return to the
presentation
where is the remediation well actually
any private data should either be stored
off-chain or encrypted and i will add
another one
you can have private data in some exotic
blockchain like secret network but for
other blockchain like ethereum you you
need to encrypt the data before or store
the the private data in another in
another
site outside that blockchain
that's it
okay here we have the second example
integral overflow
best way to understand this is to
imagine an odometer of an old car
so if you reach the maximum number
and you run another mile
this solometer will become
zero again
and that's the key of the integer
overflow
let's see
imagine you have an exchange dab
you send one eater and you receive
one token
that token could be anything could be
points in a coffee shop
could be miles in a flight company etc
so
here we have the
contract and the code of the
of the contract
here we have a variable called balance
off that represents how many tokens the
user has
this value is represented as an inside
net integer
256 so the value arise between 0 and
2 powers 256 minus 1.
so
if you add
one unit to this maximum value what
happens you can imagine it overflows and
becomes zero again
and that will be the key for this attack
here we have the price of the token is
one letter
just for general culture one meter
represents 10 power 18 way weight is the
minimum the minimum unit so you can
think of eternal weight the same way
that dollar and cents for example
and here we have a function a public
function to buy tokens of course
the money you pay depends on the number
of tokens you buy and the unit price
so how much to pay
we multiply number of tokens per unit
price
number of tokens
multiplied
with one header and remember one letter
is 10 powers 18 way
now
we have to look for a huge number of
tokens
to overflow the total value so if we for
example use
this huge number of token the
multiplication
will be
this this value this is small value why
because when you multiply this value
that is b with another value that it's
also big
it will overflow the integer and side
integral 256
and you have this small
value
so it
in eater it's
0.41 etc eater so let's recap
if you want to buy one token you have to
pay one eater if you want to buy
five tokens you have to pay five eater
but
apparently if you want to buy this huge
number of tokens
you have to pay
less
than
one eater in fact less than half eater
is it true let's see
let's see in action
here i have i'm going to
erase
that contact i'm going to deploy this
contract let's see
i'm going to deploy this contract
okay now it's deployed
and here we have we see the buy function
that chain of account we are going to
work with this account that start with 7
to 5.
he has 100 eater
so
at first let's see
if we
review the balance of this account
at first he has zero tokens right he has
no tokens for of the contract now i'm
going to buy
this huge number of token i'm going to
copy
this huge value
i will buy this number of tokens and i'm
going to pay
this value in ways
remember
the money goes here
so i will pay this
but in way
okay is it true
let's try
i buy
the transaction is okay and if i review
again the balance of this user i'm going
to see that now he's
he's millionaire in token he has many
many many many tokens
and how much money he spent
here you can see
at the beginning we we had 100 eater and
now we have 99.5
heaters less than a half eater to have
this huge amount of token
that's it
let's return to the presentation
okay
how to remediate this finding on this
vulnerability well
uh
if we use solidity before
0.8 you have to use a math library
to handle the overflow of integer when
used when you have an addition when you
have a multiplication etc
if you use a
solidity 0 8
onwards it's
built by default the protection for for
integer overflow and underflow
great
now
it's store of this attack called
reentrancy that is my my personal
favorite attack
let's see
how it works
imagine we have a contract
called dao
this contact will allow users to deposit
its coins inside a contract
for example a user
and a contract will have the coins of
all users that have already deposit so
if a user deposit
the balance for that user will increment
for example if i deposit
two heater to down to simple down
my new balance in that contact will be
two liter if i deposit
three monitors
my
my balance will be five eater right
i can also withdraw at any moment
and if i withdraw
the contract transfer
back dieters to my account and then he
will update balance so we had five eater
inside a contract if i withdraw twitters
the contract will send the twitters to
me
and
my balance now is three right
okay
before continue
let's see
this
this ski model it's very interesting
if you
send if you interact with a contract and
use and you send money
and do not specify any function of the
contact what happened the money is lost
when you send money to a contract and
you do not specify the function
by default
the contract has
a building function
called
fullback function and by default the
fallback function will receive the money
and nothing else happens
however
the creator of the contract if he wants
he want he can
override the fallback function to
receive the money and do something else
let's see
again here we have a simple dow smart
contract
and
an attacker can deploy a malicious
contract that we will call proxy
so
the contract
the the attacker
is going to rewrite the fallback
function
and
what happens
when
the attacker
calls the fallback function
this function will call that we draw
function of simple down and what happens
that we draw
after we draw
the contract calls transfer eater and
the simple down will transfer it to
the ones who call call him call
colleagues
and quiz is the proxy
so simple dog will transfer money
to proxy
but what happened
if you send money to a contract and you
do not specify any function
by default you call fallback function
and for lock function again
we'll call withdraw and withdraw
transfer editor and here appears a loop
this loop is called reentrancy and it
will happen again and again until all
the money of simple dow goes to proxy
let's let's recap
if you deposit twitters
you can withdraw only twitters you
cannot withdraw the money of other users
but with this attack you can you can get
a re-entrance attack and can get the
money of all user
this is a hacking masterpiece
i'm not a romantic guy but believe me
this is a lost point to hacking
so let's see in action
here we have a simple dog contour
i'm going to deploy this contract
here here is simple down i'm going to
deploy that contract
and
it's here
okay
i have a function called donate to
deposit money to the contract and have a
con uh function called withdraw to
withdraw the money
i
here i have also a function to verify
how how many coins i have deposit before
to the contract so
imagine that this account
is going to deposit
eaters
to the contract
so
i'm going to deposit 12 eater
on behalf of me of course
so if i donate
i'm going to donate
right if i verify the credit of this
user
here appear
12 eater right
and the total supply of the contract i
mean how many
how much money it's inside the counter
it's also
12 heater right
now
now i'm going to change this to this one
this is the attacker the attacker is
going to deploy
the proxy malicious contract and in
order to deploy he needs the others of
the victim
a
contract in this case the victim
contract is simple that i'm going to
copy the address
i'm going to write it here and deploy
okay
here we have the proxy malicious contact
controlled by the user by the
the attacker
so
me as a you as an attacker i'm going to
donate tweeters just tweeters
on behalf
of my malicious contract
so here
i'm going to donate
here
before that let's see how what is the
credit of the malicious contract at
first i credit zero so i'm going to
donate
two liters
and if i verify that credit again of the
proxy is
two ether
so
the credit of the proxy contract that is
malicious it's twitter
so
if he if if you want to withdraw money
on behalf of the proxy you can withdraw
only
tweeters
but what is the total supply in the
contract
14 heaters so again you can you are
supposed only to withdraw twitter's
two of the 14 meters no more
but
if we
if we call
the
the fallout function that is overwritten
by my attacker i'm going to call it
let's see what happened
oh well at first before calling let's
see
my balance in the contract is zero i
don't have money right now
so let's call
the format function
okay it's okay
and now if i verify my account again
here we have
14 heaters all the money of all users
and the total supply now it's zero
the contract now it's hacked
okay what is the remediation well the
best practice to avoid re-entrancing
it's to
to follow a pattern called check effects
interaction what does it mean
let's see again
in this example you see that first when
you withdraw
first you transfer eater
to that color
and then
you update balance
okay
this pattern
check
effects interaction what says is before
before sending the money
first update the balance
and then
you can send the money you have to
reverse the order of operation
and also you can use a reentrancy lock
you can think of this like a mutex
you can activate a new text so if
someone has entered this function nobody
else can enter at the same time
rate
some final thoughts about this
a smart contract and apps in general are
in adoption phase
so
if you implement it
in a incorrect way it can lead to a huge
and sometimes millionaire or even
billionaire breaches
so it's very dangerous
the secret here is to use secure design
patterns since the beginning of the
smart contract so you have to
remember
once you deploy these contracts
on blockchain are very complicated to
modify it
so you have to be sure
that when you go live when you deploy
the contract on the main net you have to
be secure
so you have to follow these secure
patterns since the beginning
when you test and when you deploy
obviously
there is there is something very
important
that
that is key here and other areas too
there is a need for security training
for all team involved in the project i
mean the creation the development the
maintenance the deployment etc
everyone in the team is responsible for
security
and finally
there are some automated scans tools
but of course they have a limited
limited scope so it's important to
to complement those results with a
manual security test carried out by
especially staff
i mean
the biggest
and most important issues that you can
find
in a pen testing a smart contract
are not going to be discovered by a tool
are going to be discovered by someone
who knows who understand the protocol
behind that who understand what is a
data flow and who discover
what is the issue that leads to
to for example an authorized operation
etc
he
wanna tell you some experience
sometimes if you fail
in your in
operation for example
instead of
writing
greater or equal you just write greater
that real mistakes
can lead
to a big issue that could could lead to
a millionaire still
so it's important to be very careful
uh and you have to
you have to have your especially your
staff to review the security of the
smart contracts
that's it
thank you very much for attendance