[Music]
so i am going to be talking to you about
automating architectural risk analysis
with the open threat model format
before i do that i'd just like to spend
a couple of months just um talking about
myself uh i'm the vp of product at iris
risk and as glenn said sort of i've got
a bit of a background in um open source
type modeling for the last six years
cloud security all that kind of
all that kind of jazz
um so the title of the talk contains the
word uh architecture and risk analysis
um
so i'm going to start off this talk just
laying some foundations about what we
mean with architecture
on the screen you can see three example
definitions there are others uh the
first one i'm not going to read through
all of these slides of course the first
one provided by gartner is quite simple
and intuitive and probably quite
familiar it's the it's the obvious kind
of the first thing you tend to think of
when you think of architecture in this
context
the the second one i think is a little
bit more interesting though
um
that's really talking about the
there are there's no one single view of
architecture and depending on what
you're looking at our understanding of
architecture can vary so
there's architecture when we think of in
terms of infrastructure but there's also
the application design architecture you
know maybe the choice of threading or or
some other core aspect to how you built
an application
and
the boundary between those types of
architecture is blurred um and quite uh
sort of fuzzy at times
the third definition however is probably
my favorite which is from martin fowler
which is
you know fundamentally architecture of
the decisions that you wish you could
get right early on in a project they are
the
typically the hard to undo stuff uh
there's some sort of foreshadowing going
on here
um
and then sort of unfortunately they're
often these kind of decisions that
aren't you you aren't necessarily any
better at making early on so you know
architectural is inherently a a hard
problem
um so that's a bit of an understanding
of what we mean when we talk about
architecture so what's architectural
risk analysis well probably the more
familiar term for that is threat
modeling or you know in general secure
design
um there's obviously a ton of security
tools out there there's and processes of
course there's sas and das and pen
testing and seams
etc
one of the challenges with cyber
security is that it often focuses on the
particulars so you know there's a
particular vulnerability in a particular
line of code or a networks connecting
from a to b on port c
or there's a particular exploit against
some version of a product and that's all
good that's all um completely necessary
but it's not
sufficient so
it misses the bigger picture of things
it misses the relationship between
things typically so threat modelling you
know it's not the only process out there
of course but throughout modeling as a
practice
allows you to take a step back look at
look at the bigger picture um and as it
says it
looks at focus on the forest rather than
on the trees
um i'm sure everyone on this call is
probably aware that uh insecure design
has now been included in the os top 10
which is absolutely amazing um it's
important because you know we
differentiate between design flaws and
implementation defects and we do that
for a reason because they have different
root causes and different remediations
so a secure design can still have
implementation defects that lead to
vulnerabilities that can be exploited
which is fair enough so you still need
your sass in your desk and all that kind
of stuff but an insecure design cannot
be fixed by a perfect implementation so
because you the controls and things like
that that you need are even considered
at that point so you can't it's sort of
a bit of an asymmetrical problem in that
way
um i'm not going to spend too long
talking about the ins and outs of
different threat modeling practices um
there are many different interpretations
of what threat modeling is or how to do
it
um
if someone's not particularly familiar
with what threat modelling is i'll just
spend a couple of seconds talking about
it uh using adam schroeder stacks four
questions because i think this is
probably one of the most useful general
frameworks for describing threat
modelling so in short four questions
what are you working on what are you
building what can go wrong uh what are
you going to do about it and did you do
a good job so the first one is really
looking at the scope
typically in a manual process that
involves looking through documents or
looking at whiteboards and designs and
pictures and things like that and
understanding what is this thing that
we're um threat modelling
the second question what can go wrong
that's the process of identifying
potential threats
as long as they're plausible they're
probably in scope of threat modding we
don't want to do that sort of movie
hacking stuff necessarily um but that's
the sort of thing like an attacker um
space
now it's all good fun finding threats is
great fun but if you're not doing
anything with those threats you found
there's probably not much point of sort
of cyber security neighborgating at that
point um so you the next question then
is what are we going to do about it well
we want to find mitigating controls and
implement them so you know i can do x in
order to eliminate that threat or i can
do y to mitigate it or i can transfer
this to another
a legal entity or in some way
um
and and typically the output of this
process is non-functional requirements
or jira stories and things like that
and then the fourth question is is
sometimes neglected but equally
important which is are you doing a good
job or did we do a good job and that
applies to the all of the first three
questions are you looking at the right
stuff are you threat modelling the right
stuff at the right scope are you finding
the right types of threats or do you
sort of have a bias towards one to tick
you know type of threat based on your
experience
um are you finding enough possible
controls for those threats and are you
actually in those controls or if you
just got a backlog of uh un sort of an
unactioned neglected jira stories so
that sort of sums up threat modding
process in the general sense and often
it's quite a manual process
um
probably don't need to spend too long um
rambling on about the arguments for
shifting the security left i think it's
a fairly well established idea now that
we need to do better at moving security
left so i'll start from the right hand
side from inside to sort of that
production and maintenance phase we all
know that it's very hard to make changes
there and it's very costly uh once
something's in production it can be
massive pain to have to rework it or
refactor it and typically involves you
know throwing developers at a problem
for a long period of time
so shifting left slightly you get into
where you see a lot of stuff happening
around uh security at the moment which
is putting stuff into pipelines into the
ci cd uh automation side of things and
that's great um it's definitely a step
in the right direction just doing a pen
test on something that's already in
production is is fine but not as good as
being able to do the stuff automatically
through the citd pipelines but it's
still relatively expensive to fix it at
that point because you've already built
most of this stuff
typically you know it's maybe go through
pre-production or going through some
sort of
integration testing at this stage um so
you're really quite far down the process
to find that there's an issue so this is
where you typically see um projects
being delayed because they're finding
issues just before release and is
pushing things back
um so in that sense the further left we
shift the better and that takes us into
that kind of design and development
phase so very cheap to fix issues if
your design is nothing more than a
whiteboard diagram at the moment then a
fix there from a from a from an
architectural point of view for example
is to just redraw the diagram slightly
cost you virtually nothing
and it's also a good time to identify
requirements and proactively drive those
into the development stages so if you're
thinking about um what could go wrong
and and your controls are then you know
not going to fix this particular issue
but go and add to this non-functional
requirement to make sure this thing is
uh is well designed from the start but
the downside or one of the downsides to
this is that it can still be a quite an
expensive manual process so threat
modelling in that design phase is often
involves workshops and uh getting lots
of very smart and very expensive people
into a room for lots of time and
identifying uh different sort of threats
and altimeters and things like that so
you kind of want to be able to speed
that up a little bit
um but that's not the focus for for too
much of that
there are some other interesting
challenges
that uh the architecture in the design
phase also has to face
um
very traditional ones so architecture
lives outside of the code it's a visio
diagram or something like that or it's a
confidence page
there are other
collaboration tools out there um
it's typically always out of date almost
the minute someone starts implementing
something the original design the
original architecture is pretty much out
of date and so the implementation drifts
over time but there's there's some other
newer emerging challenges with this
whole architecture thing
what happens when you the architecture
disappears you have things like
serverless where you're just deploying
chunks of code all of the infrastructure
that runs that has sort of evaporated um
and the same kind of thing with
microservices and things like loco to no
code you know one else going on there
so what happens is the architecture
starts emerging more from the code
rather than from the cables we don't
have to worry about the um
the underlying infrastructure anymore
because we sort of built on top of that
but we do have to worry about how things
are connecting in a different level what
you see typically happen at this point
is things like serverless exposes the
application side of the architecture
because the infrastructure side of
things has been hidden so how lambda
calls um to each other in other aws
services for example um is exposing some
of the internal workings of that
application so your functions are
relatively straightforward so
again blurring that boundary of the type
of architecture we have to deal with
um and we have increasingly complex
environments fuzzy requirements and
faster iteration you know increasingly
um demanding customers etc etc and that
drives agile practices and devops and
all that jazz that's making this whole
thing a lot faster so the traditional
approach of architecting something and
then it being developed for two years is
long gone as we all know
um
yet when we talk about software
development we often think of it as
being like manufacturing we use the same
kind of terminology like pipelines and
batch and work in progress and
deliverables and all that kind of stuff
you know you have this developer
this this this conveyor belt of jira
stories that people work on and then
some sort of sprint planning happens
over there
uh
but actually
so you know analogies uh gone wild here
software development is a lot more like
art than it is manufacturing and this is
because manufacturing of a piece of
software actually happens in the cpu at
the point of execution everything up
until that point is basically design
there's a fantastic paper by uh jack
reeves in 1992 so bear in mind this is
nearly 10 years before the agile
manifesto was released um goes into a
lot of the detail but coding debugging
testing that is all fundamentally a
process of design not a process of
manufacturing
um
the commit strip on the right here is
also
you know really putting driving this
point home
a a piece of software even a binary is a
specification for how to achieve a
particular problem in a particular
domain so it is it is not a product in
the same way that a car is a product it
is a specification offer how to solve a
problem in a particular set of
circumstances in the cpu
and what that means is software
development as a practice is essentially
continuous iterative and revisionist
design
when you're writing software you're
describing and sharing ideas in a way
that lets you collaborate with people
you're learning how to solve a problem
your reasoning with yourself and with
other people um and so when you're
writing code you're not writing it
really for the cpu otherwise we'd all be
using sort of machine um
code assembly or even deeper
we write in high-level languages we use
abstractions as objects because it helps
us think about and talk about and reason
about and share
design
now not absolutely everything is a
pure part not not all of software
development is purely designed
um and
we can use tools like the cleveland
framework to look at why we'll come back
to why this matters in a little bit but
i just need to just set a little bit
more sort of groundwork in terms of
where all of this stuff is coming from
and what this means in terms of
automation and the evolution of um of um
sort of building on top of existing
concepts
um so very there's a lot going on this
slide i won't spend too much time here
the canvas framework basically helps us
think about different types of systems
in different ways and in this case we're
looking at it from the perspective of
software development um
it splits the world up into two clear
which is um things are very simple if
things are very linear if a then b it's
either d so that's the place of best
practices and checklists um complicated
um here there are still things are still
linear things are still predictable but
you it's not straightforward you may
need an expert you may need to do static
statistical analysis or something to
understand and you know 70 chance that a
is better than b etc on the left hand
side we have the complex domain and the
chaotic domain complex is where things
are no longer linear things are coupled
they're dispositional they tend to a and
b
but you can't know that in advance it's
only with hindsight that these things
start to make sense
um
and from an from a software point of
view this is where a lot of um as we'll
see in second and a lot of stuff happens
and then chaos is where you know it's
not statistically random in that sense
but this is where things are completely
linear as well as non-constrained so
things are just a mess and that middle
one confused is where you don't know
which domain you're dealing with which
is you know a state a lot of us are in a
lot of the time and the general point
here is how you solve a problem depends
on the type of
system you're in so if you're uh there's
no point doing linting in a complex
space because it's completely uh
misaligned to the nature of that system
and likewise you wouldn't sit there sort
of prototyping brand new approaches to
um just a simple checklist problem
because that would be a complete waste
of effort
um so how you think about different
problems depends on the nature of the
system you're in
um this is a wardy map hopefully people
are familiar with this
but it's
gaining momentum still it's has some
familiarity with the notion of canadian
you can sort of potentially map genesis
to complexity and commodity to that
clear domain but what the warding map
does is it shows you a value chain of
you know how you're delivering value to
a user a customer in this case and where
those different points are in that value
stream and how they map to
different stages of evolution so when
something is brand new it's very little
is known about it you have to prepare
faster iterations a lot of learning so
that's sort of the genesis space and
then things evolve over time you know
sometimes in the many decades to what
becomes commodities so these are things
we take for granted very well
established very slow to change a lot of
automation and things we take yeah like
i said two things we take for granted so
electricity used to be genesis it used
to be brand new as a as a concept but
over the last few hundred years you know
it has become a commodity and you feel
the pain when suddenly your power goes
out and you have no electricity you
suddenly realize how much you've taken
it for granted but it doesn't change
either we don't i don't wake up one
morning to find the voltage has changed
from 240 volts to 173 for example
um so water mapping exposes these
dynamics and to bring it back to um the
security of the software domain
um
you're using cloud compute because you
don't have to worry about the details of
physical hardware or even in you you're
using lambda and things like serverless
because you don't have to worry about
the details of um the infrastructure it
has cloud has basically commoditized the
ability to do compute and that's
fundamental because it allows you to
focus on the stuff that matters and
here's the fun part of course
things evolve over time and you wouldn't
spend hundreds of development hours
trying to write a yaml file parser for
example from scratch um you go and use a
library because it's a solved and known
problem uh when things are well
understood they're available as products
or you know or even commodities
so what you as a software development
team
is all the novel and domain specific
stuff you can't just outsource to a
product um or to a library or to a
commodity so you are left with all the
stuff you have to deal with in that
genesis space and that custom space so
you're you're dealing with the unknown
you're dealing with having to solve
problems for the first time
even if it's just gluing different
products and commodities together in a
different way to solve a specific
problem
and the process of navigating through
novelty is design hence why you know
software development as a practice is
predominantly design unless you're just
re-implementing a well-known algorithm
anything that involves trying to solve a
new problem that is on not understood
yet um and that's why we have product
development practices etc this is all
what drives software as a design
practice
and of course if your design if software
uh development is continuous
iterative and revisionist design then
that means threat modelling needs to be
continuous
iterative and revisionist so
hopefully it is but you know generally
speaking it tends to still be that sort
of waterfall approach
um
and this is a problem for architecture
because architecture as a discipline
comes from that very you know it's very
well suited for waterfall very well
suited for doing that upfront analysis
but this is why we see that
implementation drift because
um it's hard to continue to manually
maintain architecture in the same way
in a way that is
aligned to the design nature of software
and therefore threat modelling sort of
suffers as a result from that
but all is not lost
we have cloud so one of the side effects
of cloud is that we have infrastructure
as code and that's awesome
because at this point
the
code becomes the design and becomes the
stuff that's deployed so all of the
architectural stuff that used to be
a diagram somewhere that was never up to
date is now actually represented in
something that is both the design and
the actual manufacturing the actual
execution
um and as i said sort of microservices
if you're doing infrastructure's code
for microservices
what was once a monolith running inside
a a single web server for example like
gigantic java app running in a web
server if you're using microservices
deployed in uh the cloud then suddenly
that architecture is explicitly defined
in these infrastructure of code
files or templates and each of these
things have their own different
requirements for data transport
authentication etc and so
infrastructure as code allows us to
string together these different pieces
and view this architecture in that
sort of real-time way in line with the
actual pace of development through
infrastructure as code
so why an open threat model format then
well as we said architecture is often
defined in many different formats um
it's it's some people have visio
diagrams some people have whiteboard
diagrams um so we need something from a
threat modding point of view that's
agnostic to those sources
um threat modelling as a practice itself
also needs to evolve and one way to do
that is to build open standards that
people can build on and use and relate
to and um
that can accelerate the the the
standardization of something that um
builds on top of infrastructure's code
from a threat modern point of view
um
one of the other challenges we have with
rap modeling
and to some extent this is necessary and
is always going to be the case there are
different interpretations of threat
modeling and that makes sense because
different circumstances require that but
we also need some
some really good common ground and if we
can do that in a data format then that
allows us to create interoperability and
the ability to exchange information much
easier um so organizations you know need
to be able to exchange this kind of
information either within themselves or
ideally with other and we'll look at
that in a second
um and so in our open threat mode format
put it in the open space uh make it
widely adopted that could provide this
common ground
um so some potential use cases um if i'm
thinking about trying to threat model
something i may have different sources
of um
that design so
that design may come from an actual
diagram of some sort maybe very early on
someone's using
physio or um
some other things like figma or miro
boards
um
maybe we want to be able to just take
that yes maybe it's out of date quite
quickly but at least if we can get into
a threat model very quickly we can
evolve and um
and build on top of it once it's
captured
cloud information terraform obviously
that stuff is sitting in code that stuff
we need to be able to keep up to date
with so if we can pass those sources of
architectural information we can threat
model um continuously and iteratively as
well and there's a whole bunch of other
stuff out there like docker components
kubernetes jira stories and the
application code itself these different
types of sources you wouldn't want to
have to have 10 different ways of threat
modeling 10 different sources want to be
able to bring this stuff on under the
same roof so to speak
um
and then once you've got to that process
to that point you may need to be able to
exchange this threat modding data with
other parts of the cyber ecosystem so
you know if you could provide some
context around the relationships between
components within the threat model
you could provide that context to sas
and dast and vulnerability management so
why does this vulnerability really
matter well
because of this threat model and this
context if i can pass that from a
machine point of view because of an open
standard then that uh and it's not sort
of buried in a 20-page uh word document
or something like that then um that
really opens up a space for further
automation across the cyber security
ecosystem
and then finally this one might be a bit
of a pipe dream but we're certainly
seeing it within our organization
um the the need for
organizations to be able to share this
stuff with each other so if i'm a
software vendor and people are using my
components i may want to be able to
publish um mini threat models or aspects
or components that they can then
leverage in their threat models and you
know i can tell them here are the
threats when you use this component and
these are the mitigations you need to
implement and we can you know you i can
i can learn that as a result of using
some of this um
content from a third party um or maybe i
want to be able to share and easily um
publish uh threats and mitigations in
some way so maybe i've done some
research and i want to be able to put it
out there in a way that's easy to
consume by other organizations and other
tools and stuff
and then and another third one may be to
increase transparency so maybe if you're
doing some sort of third party
assessment they could provide a
you know passable threat model that you
can then put into your threat model tool
that looks at it and says okay right
here are the things you need to care
about again rather than just reading
through 200 page pdfs
so there's a lot of interesting use
cases that come up you know could
potentially come out of a
of a structure like this
so
i'm
going to
now dig into the details of what exactly
this looks like um
we um
identified the need for an open
specification because of working with
different customers and so
what this represents is a
set of expectations and a set of
requirements and a set of use cases that
we've seen out there either in terms of
what we see from our customers or from
existing tools so you we'll go into a
little bit more of that in a minute
but at a high level
we wanted something that can
be malleable and flexible
but also provide enough of that
standardization to make it um
something that can evolve so we're
trying to pull from that body mapping
side of things we're trying to pull 20
different threat modeling formats
further to write into that let's say
product space
even though it's an open source thing uh
into that product space so that others
can build on top of so that innovation
can happen on top of it maybe one day
we'll get to threat modeling as
commodity but probably not quite yet
um so in terms of the specification
it's uh yaml so or jason so you know
building on the x's code momentum we
wanted something that could be committed
into git that could be differed and you
know you have a change log associated
with it it can be generated or written
by hand of course
um so you know fairly standard arguments
for using yaml and json for these kind
of things so you know
the other thing is you want this kind of
stuff to be able to live with where the
stuff matters so if i've got a
infrastructure as code a bunch of
confirmation files for example i don't
want my threat model necessarily being
somewhere over there i want to be able
to keep it close to my code so having it
as a yaml alongside the code
is a way of doing that
um
inspired by open api so it should look
relatively familiar in the style um it
doesn't use the sort of the pythonic
conventions it uses more of the
sort of snake cases of open api
um and i'll just very talk briefly talk
through some of the different um
bits that make up the specification and
you know pretty much the rest of the
talk we'll be going into the more of the
details on those so at a very high level
we have we need to know some stuff about
the stuff that we're threat modelling so
the project metadata what what is this
thing that we're threat modeling what
does this threat model represent so
that's the the name and the description
of the application or the product or the
service or whatever
representations are an interesting one
a big complex system can potentially be
represented in a number of different
ways you may have an architecture
diagram you may have a user interface
diagram you could have infrastructure as
code or application code or jira stories
these are all different representations
of fundamentally the same thing and
different representations being threat
modeled in different ways gives you
different outcomes so a threat modeling
specification needs to be able to handle
multiple representations
um assets these are the things that you
care about sensitive information like
pii or pci data or some other thing of
value
components these are the sort of
building blocks of any sort of
representation these are the things like
you know ec2 instances or api endpoints
or chunks of code that uh make up
together a sort of a representation for
a particular system
um trust zones
familiar terminology and threat modeling
but i don't think it's a universally
used term typically these are the uh
differing levels of security within a
system uh you don't put your database
out on the public internet because it's
got sensitive data so you go through
various tiers with each introducing
layers of controls um and and there's
relative diff differences in trust
between those different tiers
uh data flows obviously kind of speak to
itself how information and assets move
around a particular system and between
those components
um and then of course we've got the
threats and the mitigations it wouldn't
be a threat model without threats and
mitigation so what are those things that
can go wrong and uh what are we going to
do about them
a couple of other cool things about the
schema at a high level all of the
objects can have these arbitrary
attributes which you can use for
whatever you want so um you could have
custom ids or urls for documentation or
anything like that or maybe some
specific measurable quantitative
attributes that make sense for your
implementation
um
the specification does however provide
some basic risk related uh properties
like the cia triad confidentiality
integrity and availability uh some trust
zone ratings and things like cwes and
likelihood and impact
um tagging allows you to group and or
categorize things in some form so
you you you may have a you may want to
tag all of your aws components with aws
you may want to take all those of your
azure components with azure or maybe do
it by representation instead
um
different things different
representations have different
requirements so for example if i'm
passing confirmation
i don't typically if it's written by
hand or generated from code i don't have
things like x and y coordinates so i if
i was to sort of draw a class formation
template as a threat model i would have
to interpret the layout of that
of that stuff and that's kind of what
we're going to look at in a little bit
but if i've got something like a visio
diagram that represents a threat model
then i probably want to preserve the x
and y coordinates so the diagram
representations allow you to specify
size and
height and therefore we can have x y
components for um for some of those
components
um and another interesting thing is that
truss lens components can be arbitrarily
nested so i may have a component with
any component within the truss zone
within a component within a truss zone
for example um
[Music]
and the general practice within the
specification is to try to keep the
number of required fields to a minimum
so
what you'll see now
is sort of a set of examples of the
specification um
not all of those fields are required
that means that if you're writing
something by hand you can only you only
have to provide the bare essentials and
um if you were generating stuff then you
would generate whatever you know you had
available to to generate that uh
particular outcome
um now while there isn't currently a
single accepted open threat model format
out there in the world there are a
number of existing
formats for things that describe threat
models some of these are inside
proprietary um tools and some of them
are in sort of open source throughout
spec being one of them probably have to
update it to use otm at some point in
the future
um so what we did is we obviously looked
at our customer requirements and what
else was going on in the threat morning
space and looked at the other tools to
make sure that a open specification was
able to work in these different
circumstances
um
again not going to read through every
single thing here um there's i'm just
going to call out a couple of key
differences we're trying to on the whole
find some of the best bits of all these
different tools in terms of representing
threat models and some of the common
bits and pull that into a single place
that you know can be used elsewhere um
so for example microsoft modeling tool
very popular still um doesn't handle
different representations and neither
does threat dragon threat dragon does
support multiple diagrams which is
awesome um
but for example the mitigations aren't
first-class citizens so mitigations are
a box um
inside a threat whereas in the this
specification a
mitigation is its own object in itself
so it can be very powerful and
descriptive if you don't want to use any
of that fine you can sort of reduce it
to just a simple description and that
makes it sort of compatible with things
like oh snapdragon
similar to threat playbook it's very
heavily reliant on yaml um
but it's a more generalized structure
and compared to pytm pytm is awesome
uh very very flexible because it's
python you can do whatever you want
essentially but it's also then scoped
and limited to python whereas this we
lose some of that power and flexibility
that pytm has but at least it's a sort
of more universal
format
so i will just go through reasonably
fast-paced still some of these different
um components and this you can see here
is an example
of a project um so
in this particular example we have name
and id of the only required field so
we've got some other stuff to look at as
well
you'd want to be able to
identify a project
in a unique way so each project would
need some sort of a unique identifier
that distinguishes it from other
projects
so that's going to be pretty obvious and
unique ids are going to be a reoccurring
theme throughout this whole sort of
specification
and you can see here the use of some
attributes
such as documentation or
probably a very useful one would be to
be able to relate a project to something
like an identifier in a configuration
management database so yeah this is my
identifier in a threat model and this is
where it lives in wherever i manage all
my applications
and be able to create those links back
and forth between them
um
representations here
we can see here an example of an
architecture diagram the type field
allows you to interpret the
representation in the right way so as we
said before a a diagram can have um
spatial context
width height x and y
um that doesn't make sense for code um
so we want to be able to say right this
representation is of a type diagram and
therefore here are some properties
associated with that
if you don't want to provide them you
don't have to of course
likewise a different representation
might be application code which is of
type code and that would have other
attributes that are relevant to that
type of representation such as a
repository so if i've got application
code i need to know where that lives and
i can sort of provide that as url
attributes
using these custom attributes can also
provide additional context tools and
processes so one cool thing about being
able to provide context like the
language or maybe some um framework
information inside the specification
means that maybe that can
trigger certain sassed or dashed rules
or maybe some sort of policy as code
implementation could could sort of be
scoped around some of these these
attributes
example of an asset then credit card
data obviously a fairly classic um as i
said before these are the things that
matter to uh your organization or to
your to your users or your customers
and
in order to be able to describe what how
important is this asset to us we can use
the cia triad and provide a very
very simple but reasonably flexible um
quantitative approach to to specifying
risk for an asset so we can say
confidentiality on a scale of zero to
100 and same for integrity and
availability so where you have an asset
that is absolutely fundamentally
critical to you across all three of
those um
properties confidentiality 100 integrity
100 and availability 100 if if and
if it was something that was you know
sensitive but uh didn't require you know
that up time to be very high you could
obviously tweak the availability down
lower it down to 50 and say okay while
we must ensure that nobody else sees
this if we lose that data it's not going
to be that that critical
um so maybe you've just collected
marketing data in a survey um it's got
piice therefore it's very sensitive in
terms of confidentiality but if you lost
it you know wouldn't be the end of the
world um and then we can provide the
additional context through a comment um
that allows you to you know describe why
these particular decisions would have
been made for why these values are what
they are
um trust zones
um again as i said uh sort of separates
out the components by the relative
security of trust between them
um so you again trying to find a
quantitative way of
describing that difference
normalized scale trust zone rating lets
you see okay how does this trust zone
compared to this trust zone if i've got
a trust zone of
20 which is very untrusted talking to a
trust zone of 100 you know
that's potentially a bit of an issue if
i've got that sort of relative
difference so you may need to look at
some sort of three-tier type
architecture application or or you're in
that sort of zero trust space
um
and trust zones can be associated with a
particular representation so
depending on how you're looking at a
particular system you may need to invoke
or ignore different types of trust links
now components this is sort of a
multi-slide section uh components can be
quite complex so you need to
look at it from a from a number of uh
sort of different angles so
usual
basic and stuff like name identifier
this time we have a parent so where does
this component live and that parent can
be
a trust owner it could be another
component hence why we have the nested
and again there's our friend the type so
we can interpret the type of this
component i may have multiple web
services called web service one two and
three all of the type web service so
that when i see that component i can
interpret them in a similar way because
they're all functionally the same sort
of thing so think of it like a class
and then we can use tags to group um and
relate these things as well in a
completely flexible and arbitrary way
now components can also have
representations to say this component is
associated with this representation of
the system so there's the identifier of
that particular representation like the
one we saw earlier the architecture
diagram
and then we provide that additional
context so in a diagram representation
this component should have x and y
positions
um or width and heights for example
um
and
assets
live on or move through components so we
can talk about which assets are either
processed or stored in this component
again just a simple list of referring to
those identifiers that we saw earlier
allows you to start building connections
between these things these concepts
from components to assets from component
components
and of course data flows how data flow
moves between
different
components
they have a source they have a
destination those are the identifiers of
the components and you know relatively
straightforward
now threats
are in this case
first-class citizens so they are threats
in and of themselves and we'll see in a
minute how they relate to the components
um so a threat you'd have some sort of a
name
and a description an identifier
categories allows you to
categorize and structure
how these threats are
sort of used
in this case we can see a couple of the
elements of stride
there's a cwe's
field that lets you tie this to the cwe
database the common weakest enumeration
database so that we can see
how this threat relates to
the the miter cwe framework
this is still within the same threat
example we also need to know what does
this threat mean in terms of impact and
likelihood what are the risk attributes
for this threat so you know maybe this
is not a particularly scary threat so
the likelihood uh is only
50 because it's fairly complex or
something like that but maybe the impact
is a hundred um depending on the context
so and again we can provide the
additional context around why that
number has been chosen with the comment
field
uh and of course as i said
there's no point threat modelling and
coming up with a bunch of threats if
you're not going to do anything about it
so we need to be able to capture these
mitigations and these mitigations are
also first-class citizens so they have a
description they have
a unique identifier and they have
properties that can be shared and reused
across the thing so how much the risk
reduction one here is or how much impact
does this mitigation have on reducing
risk
normalized value zero to 100 again
how you interpret that as a medium high
low whatever is up to you but we just
provided sort of a very basic um way of
being able to describe how impactful a
particular mitigation can be
um and and using those attributes to tie
these mitigations to things like
standards or other components or other
data sources or maybe even sort of
you could even link it to training
material for example through those
attributes if needed
now
going back to the components we
obviously need to be able to relate
threats and mitigations to those
components because we were just looking
at them by themselves so we can
under a component we can say these are
the threats that matter to this
component here's the state it's exposed
it's mitigated or whatever that looks
like and here are the mitigations for
that particular threat so this is one
that's been implemented and this one
hasn't
um and the same thing of biased data
closed is
maybe slightly unusual i think the
microsoft site modeling tool allows you
to associate throughout some mitigations
with data flows um
but again it gives you that capability
and that flexibility to say
if my data flow is from a type of and
this would be in your own interpretation
implementation tool if my type is of web
server on the source and database on the
destination then the sql thread may
apply to this particular data phone the
sql injection threat sorry
and therefore the mitigations are you
know use an orm or uh
yeah don't concatenate your strings
um
so
i've got just over five minutes to go i
don't know just under five minutes um
i'm just going to do a very quick demo
of what this looks like in practice
we've got an implementation that we're
building and i'll just show a couple of
screenshots and also show you what that
looks like in terms of the ide
um
so i will just have to change my screen
share
to
default desktop i think
right
so
over here i have a very simple again
hopefully everyone can see this
i have a very simple um
otm file open threat model file um got
the version number in there
we just have two trust zones uh you can
see here the relative rating and the
number of components in here stripped
out all the other stuff that doesn't
really matter
um if you if you to then pass it you
could you could visualize this in
graphiz or any other tool and in this
case it would look a little bit like
this so you can see our two components
inside the um
inside their respective truss zones at
the moment in our uh although it's in
specification in our implementation we
don't have uh what the expose i think
actually we do but i didn't have them
when i was doing these screenshots so um
if i added in a date flow you'd expect
to see a line from the from the client
to the rest api in this case um
now what we have here is a cloud
information file i've stripped it back
to just the stuff that matters so it's
not actually a valid optimization cloud
information file anymore all of the
stuff you'd actually need to build
something is is taken out but you can
see here we have
uh vpcs we have subnets and we have
bbc gateway vpc gateways and endpoints
and all that kind of stuff
this represents a
you know fairly typical applications
using ecs in this case
there's a on our public github we have a
open source uh python sort of
experimental python tool that's on the
public github that will pass cloud
formation and generate an otm file so
you know
an example of how this could be
implemented and the way this works
briefly is by
um
allowing you to specify jmes pass
queries and saying this is how i expect
to find a this type of component in a
confirmation template and this is what
it means in terms of a threat model so i
can go and look for aws cloudwatch
alarms and the type of that thing that i
find in a jet cloud formation file if
there is one is type cloudwatch and i
can say who the parent is or i can go
and do some clever stuff with um looking
up the relationship between this
component and others for example
so this is a mapping file it's just yaml
but it's it's what generates the
um the otm from the cloud formation so
if i quickly run this command with that
opens that uh open source python
script
um
i'm telling its confirmation so it knows
how to pass it i'm giving it the mapping
file so it knows um
how to interpret this particular this
particular confirmation template well
that mapping file applies to any
confirmation templates but you may want
to have your own versions or customize
it or tweak it however you need i'm
providing a name and identifier and the
the yaml file itself now i'm going to
save this as an otm file
um and that's it that was relatively
straightforward generated an mtm file
which if i look in here now we can see
if i just change this to json
uh we can see now this is generated an
itm file we've got our representation
which is cloud information we've got a
trust zone and we have a whole bunch of
components
um including the relationships with
their parents but as i said not with any
data flows at the moment and what this
looks like when you visualize it is this
so we've got our nested components we've
got our our objects and this looks much
more like a
architectural diagram then when you
typically visualize cloud formation you
just see all of the objects connected to
each other this is a architecture
diagram that is generated from a cloud
formation template
so
i think i've got less than a minute to
do this bit uh where we are literally
only just talking to uh talking to
the world about this trying to get
people's ideas and opinions
is this a sensible approach how would
you do it would you do it differently um
we'll get some feedback we'll open it up
and release it to the world and then you
know work with people and organizations
et cetera to do more cool stuff with it
uh going back to those kind of use cases
um if you're if you're interested in
this if it's something you'd be uh
interested in sort of helping out with
or contributing or sharing ideas about
uh feel free to reach out at otm
areasrisk.com and otherwise i think
thank you very much