[Music]
appreciate it again spoiler container
security it's all about the supply chain
and it's a cooking theme of course it
seems like everybody uses that so
let me talk a little bit about myself
again to expand on what john said i'm a
currently a security architect a chief
security architect and i like to think
of myself as a professional contrarian i
have had a podcast in the past uh some
people actually have found it it's been
about 10 years um i'm a blogger a b2b
writer and
just your
regular infosec benny jesuit witch
i tend to focus on best practices and i
have been a former unix engineer and
network engineer so i can get pretty
nerdy when necessary and this is how you
reach me and i i will have slides online
at some point somewhere somehow
we want to start out with us with a
short poll
i wanted to find out where everybody's
organization was in terms of using
containers uh one two and three one just
getting started mostly using in
development as we refactor applications
for cloud native uh two evenly split
between containers and full vms uh and
or bare metal with an os and an
application stack or three what's a
container
and that will be going on and then i'll
i'll let uh john step in with uh that
the results of that poll in a couple of
minutes but i'm gonna just move on
because uh we're a little compressed
probably for time
so
the supply chain
the software supply chain what
containers are software
sorry they are
um so in case you're not very familiar
with what a typical software supply
chain is i of course have
arranged to have that represented for
you with commonly used tools basically a
software supply chain is a set of
processes that build a product um
your typical ci cd pipeline as you'd
like to think about it you know where
you have delivered deploy
um where you and typically people split
up um in in get very they get very upset
about the d in ci cd right is it deliver
is it deploy most people separate those
through release management criteria but
again you'll see your typical tools your
jira for plan confluence um you'll see
you know your ides for code
your source control systems like github
you know jenkins for
building for ci
possibly cd
travis ci which is a big favorite just
so
that's what you need to think of as your
software supply chain if you're if some
of the people here aren't as familiar
with the software development process
um now
that we've looked at the software supply
chain let's break it down a little bit
into a container supply chain i like to
think of the entire software release
process what everybody thinks of as a
software development pipeline as a
pipeline of pipelines
because you have you know you have
infrastructure as code and one of the
sub pipelines that you're going to have
is your container pipe supply chain your
container pipeline and so you'll see
i've broken it up into a software
pipeline section where you make say your
war file as an example and then you
build your container and you with your
war file you get an image you test your
image and then you publish it to
an image repository
so
let's talk about some standard supply
chain threats that you typically see
i've pulled this from the salsa security
framework which is a supply chain
security model
i highly recommend it i think it started
out at google but now it has multiple
contributors from private industry
so
a
you bypass the code review that's a
really important element maybe you do
manual code review for certain elements
um but there is an area where you
somebody could take advantage of that
especially uh with the new uh bd
algorithm uh vulnerability that people
have seen out there
you without
someone really digging into the code you
you're likely to completely miss it and
you may miss it even with a manual code
review um
be a compromise source control system uh
somebody's
compromised your github repository maybe
there's
a typo squatting attack
um c you've somebody's modified the code
after the source control ideally when
you your source code should be uh
certified or attested
and
in a situation
where you're not really doing that you
could
have code that becomes dirty or drifts
after uh source control um you could
have a compromise build platform there
are plenty of vulnerabilities out there
regarding jenkins
and travis ci uh e you could have a bad
dependency i think everybody today is
pretty aware of the the threat against
open source software dependencies
um
just the other day uh npm had an
announcement of a problem with um
with some malware embedded in some
commonly used uh npm modules
you could bypass ci cd completely it
should be pretty difficult to do that
but it is still possible depending on
the maturity of the environment um you
could have compromised package repo
where you store your containers or you
could be if you're pulling down a public
image that could be compromised as well
you could just have a bad package but
that's just a few of the elements of of
where you could have typical threats
against your supply chain
you also this is a great document from
nist
i recommend it highly defending against
software supply chain attacks
i think everybody is very focused on
supply chain attacks given some of what
has happened
in the
in the marketplace recently
um
this covers uh not just um
written code i mean
it also talks about design elements it
talks about hardware devices of course
solarwinds is on here talks about and
divide and use your device malware for
example if um
you have a developer who has um an
infected desktop or laptop um
there's
you know uh
a prop there
they call out the kaspersky antivirus uh
problem where it was banned actually in
the u.s for uh various reasons
but you get an idea that
when you consider the supply chain
you're thinking about every
process element in the delivery of
software
so again um example of some
trojan
of trojan source
uh the bi-directional algorithm in the
unicode specification which allows
reordering of characters through control
sequences and you can use this to create
source code that renders different logic
than the logical ordering of tokens
ingested by compilers and interpreters
this is a frightening attack right
because uh
because of the heavy dependency that
most software projects have on open
source software and it's very difficult
to detect um right now i think the only
uh compiler or interpreter that's sorry
that's been uh adjusted i think it was
um
rust i think has this detection now but
it's still everybody's pretty much
scrambling with regards to this uh
vulnerability
so
what does supply chain security mean
we've talked about um essentially the uh
what a software supply chain is but
let's talk about the secure elements of
a supply chain it means adding assurance
to the software development process
creating uh confidence and trust in the
source material and the practices used
it's
you're trying to get a holistic
high-level view for protecting each
phase in the software development life
cycle and you're approaching the sdlc as
a set of business processes i think this
is really important i think as
technologists we get very caught up in
the technology and i really think of
devops as
a set of automations of business
processes right
that's really what we're looking at and
when you look at it that way then you
can think about the securing of those
processes
and it's validating the final product
meets a reasonable set of security
criteria to ensure that it's not
vulnerable and this is not a new thing
we've been talking about supply chain
security for a very long time um as long
ago as uh i i've been sitting in on
these talks with regards to network
equipment for example and how code is
delivered to network equipment and even
how network equipment is built i i think
um it's just become very high profile
since solar winds
so
now we're in for the fun stuff what is a
container
i like to think of it as just a bunch of
software ingredients
i think docker has a really good uh
definition everybody knows what docker
is i i think uh
it's it's fortunate or unfortunate
they've really popularized and um
really uh
opened up
the world of containerization um through
ease of use right uh they have a high
level container management system that
everybody has probably used at one point
or another and um now we sort of think
of a dot we don't we think of a
container in the same way you think of
kleenex to tissue right docker is to
container and
docker refers to it as a standard unit
of software that packages up code uh
it's a container image is a lightweight
standalone executable package of
software right it's portable
it's modular and it sort of encapsulates
that idea of working fast and working at
velocity and and ease in devops
so let's talk a little bit about
virtual machines versus containerization
i think a lot of people are very very
familiar with virtual machine
technologies um and depending on what
your role is uh
in
as an audience member here what your
role is in your in your
organization
you may be less familiar with the
differences between virtual machines and
containers essentially uh the most
important thing to take away
is that
virtual machines or guests
have their own uh cur their own kernel
their own host operating system they do
not share the operating system of the of
the hypervisor um of the the bare metal
system right they have dedicated uh
memory space they have
so they there's nothing shared there
while containers
um share a host operating system
a container a container runtime then is
responsible for helping to create uh
those dedicated spaces but you are
sharing memory space you are sharing a
kernel um this will be become
very important later as you think about
the attack surface
and just to
point out we have multiple container
runtimes that we'll be discussing here
there's container d there's cryo which
is a
red hat open shift runtime that's become
popularized
then you have low levels like run c you
have g visor you have kata as well
so user space versus kernel space as i
mentioned um
you're sharing
kernel space
with containers
so virtual machines run their own
isolated kernels there's no shared
memory or execution space as i mentioned
before
without the addition of virtual machine
technologies for example you'll see
something like kata containers or
firecracker or g-visor
so without the the addition of that of
that
virtual machine of like um they call it
a um a micro vm
um containers will share the same kernel
uh linux name spaces capabilities sec
comp se linux app armor c groups
they can be used to enhance segregation
between running container instances on
the host but you're still you've still
got that
that sticking point of sharing the same
host kernel
um
so what does a container look like
well
i like to think of it as a cake
you kind of start at the top and work
your way down and that's
pretty much what happens with a
container it's a layered file system
and they correspond each layer
corresponds to instructions and scripts
or a docker file
oci compliant runtimes you they use
something called a union file system
which has some of some of the properties
such as
it's a logical merge of multiple layers
into an overlay file system
read only lower layers and writeable
upper layers
you begin reading again like you start
eating from the top and you work your
way down
and it's copy on right
uh i'm not gonna go too much into detail
here but i did want to introduce
something called lazy pulling uh i'm not
i haven't done a lot of research yet
into
uh the uh attack surface of lazy pulling
but basically uh as opposed to the
traditional way that you
uh you you upload a whole container
you know when you run it uh and you
start it with lazy pulling um you
do not do that you uh pull as needed so
it's breaking it up into multiple um
little uh
bundles
that are grouped together logically so
it it encourages faster start time i'm
not going to go into too much detail
i encourage you to research lazy pulling
because it is starting to become a
reality it's not baked into the oci
standards yet but i anticipate it it
will be
um
let's talk about high level
versus low level
run times and management systems i think
this is important to understand because
when you hear about new vulnerabilities
for example with container d or run c
you need to understand
where the d mark where the demarcation
point uh begins and ends right um for
example with some high-level container
management examples
uh you have uh the these are referred to
by kubernetes as container well it can
be referred to as the container runtime
interface
um you have docker which is a very high
level container management system um you
have podman which is on linux and you
can interact with containers you can
build using pod man or start them
you have high level container run times
again cryo uh container d docker i know
it's confusing but there's the docker
management system and then there's um
there was a docker runtime which was
container d but has since been donated
to uh the cncf i believe
or maybe the linux foundation pretty
much the same thing um and then and
these are all part of the oci and then
uh you have the low level uh container
run times such as uh run c which we all
know in kata and g visor um kata and g
visor as you'll see have uh sandboxing
or
virtual machine technologies integrated
into that i think this is important as i
said when you're looking at container
vulnerabilities because sometimes you'll
have a run c vulnerability or you'll
have a container d vulnerability and
container d is really a wrapper around
run c you need to understand where the
differentiation is when you're
understand when you're looking at that
attack surface
i recognize this is uh sounds like a lot
of nonsense and uh it's a lot of detail
um
and i
put in a lot of links in my references
which will be my in my slide deck which
will be uploaded and also as i'm going
through this it can be very overwhelming
i i recognize that so let's try and um
break this down a little bit
so
where do you get your container
let's talk about um and yes you'll
notice i had a dirty kitchen um
let's talk about your recipes for
container images
so
you can pull a base image down from
docker hub
from a
from or from another public or pro or
registry or maybe a private one maybe
your your vendor that you know you have
a vendor that you work with um they've
containerized their software and they
have a private registry that's only
available to customers
um and then you could
you could either add code and
configuration or you can just run it as
is
you can use a multi-stage build which is
something i recommend selectively
copying what you need in the image um
without using a base or a parent image
you can build an entire oci compliant
image yourself with a tool like builda
that's for the super paranoid or
um the super nerdy who uh are not as
lazy as say i am i don't want to build
ever and want to build everything from
scratch
you can create a single layer from
scratch this is actually a thing it's a
no op it's you're basically just uh
telling
the system to get a statically compiled
binary
it oddly enough
that will actually send your
most security
container security tools into a tizzy
they don't understand from scratch no op
images
you can also make a distro-less image
that only includes the application
runtime dependencies
so i recommend using the best
ingredients of course uh you you want to
use a trusted source for base images
especially as i'm sure people follow uh
reports and uh the news about how
you'll hear about some docker hub image
that's been compromised and has uh
you know bitcoin mining elements in it
nobody knew they just trusted docker hub
and they downloaded it and used it um
you want to validate the image
with a container security tool even i
would recommend let's say you get an
image from uh one of your vendors and
you're going to assume that it's okay
because you got it from your vendor
validate it i have found tons of
problems with uh vendor
vendor images even vendor security
container images
um i recommend using a software
composition analysis tool and or a
container security tool there are plenty
out there
you want to economize you don't want to
add elements that aren't necessary for
your microservice right you don't want
to have unnecessary ports open you don't
want to have shells you don't want to
have
i've seen package managers in containers
there's no reason to have that on your
container image
uh you want to limit cis calls if you
can i know it's challenging uh to do
that but you it really helps reduce your
attack surface if you can manage to do
that
uh parameterize don't hard code configs
or embed credentials and secrets in your
image the same thing that you would hear
from a wasp regarding you know
recommendations in the asvs
um
okay they they apply here because
remember what i said right that a
container is a software package
essentially
um
reduced follow the principles of least
uh privilege don't run root processes
don't run your container as privileged
um you wanna um you don't want to
um
as i said immutable you don't want to
add a shell you don't want to log into a
running instance
i've been at places that had something
where we
called it
a dirty container that meant that we
detected when somebody logged into a
container or made a change and then we
immediately would expire
that running container image
you
don't want to um
you don't want to run a shell for that
very reason right it's just a temptation
right um
there are
techniques of course with kubernetes
where you can run a container exact i
don't recommend that either there are
alternative debug um
things that you can do techniques that
you can use that will replicate the
environment in um
another namespace or another cluster so
that you can actually troubleshoot in a
better way
uh minimize you want to use techniques
like distro-less and from scratch to
eliminate unnecessary
unnecessary elements and layers um you
want to
automate i think automation is probably
one of the best elements that will help
you
attain uh separation of duties and it
will eliminate errors and it will
minimize uh your attack surface if done
well
i then you can also
integrate security validation at
multiple phases of your pipeline as well
so
fry bake and buy if you're familiar with
infrastructure's code where you have
this idea of
baking versus bootstrapping and image
there's something similar in the concept
of containers
you have fried images which are custom
built or extended third-party images um
deployed but changed during
bootstrapping activity um so for example
if you were to
instantiate an image
and uh you do an app apt-get or a curl
um
that is not an image that you can attest
bake
uh that's a custom-built or extended
third-party image
fully created
with all the dependencies
as part of a supply chain
it's a tested and immutable you can also
buy as i mentioned before um
third party or vendor images deployed
without changes attested and immutable
okay i think you know where i'm going
here
bake or buy
but never fry
and i i think i just want to
go back a couple um
[Music]
so
container mistakes
i want to emphasize this
uh heavily um i i think
what i see a lot is
people haven't sufficiently refactored
uh their applications for microservices
so they do a full dump of their virtual
machine or ami into a container
this is a really bad idea not just in
terms of bloat but also as i as you saw
that i mentioned about the best
practices
you get a really large attack surface
every time you add something into that
image everything that's not necessary
and is present on your container image
it
causes uh it increases your attack
surface not just the bloat element
um
you just don't want to put your entire
monolithic application stack in a
container uh
and um
your i have this pet peeve
um
people will refer to container as the
image or the running instance um they're
very different phases of the runtime so
let's be sure that like i'm very uh
particular i will call it a container
image and then a runtime container or a
running instance um
i think that's important to remember
when you're talking about containers
because it's a very precise part of the
life cycle
so
um
we've talked about the recipes we've
talked about using the best ingredients
we've talked about fry bacon by
i wanted to share with you a
sample container security validation at
a high level so you understand what i'm
talking about when i talk about uh the
container security supply chain
um so i've broken it up into one a and
one b
one a is third party images and one b is
a full custom built image
um you'll see that i've of course you
know you can use docker you can use um
builder you can use podman you can
download the image from docker you may
upload it to a tool like jfrog
artifactory i mean there are all kinds
of different way like
some things that you you're familiar
with there are lots of ways that you can
create the image and then you can get it
uploaded to a container repository
so
what do i mean when i say container
security validation
what that means is the container has to
meet
certain set of security criteria to
receive a passing score
right
and
that includes certain elements in my
experience what i've used is an overall
cdss score and i might for example say
that the score has to be
less
it can't be
equal to or greater than seven
that's an example i may check to see if
there are any root owned processes in
the container image
i might also check to see
that the container doesn't run as
privileged
and i may look through uh the container
image to see that it doesn't have a
shell installed you most tools out there
will look for all kinds of other things
you can check on whether or not
uh
some of the open source elements violate
uh your license
your agreed licenses like you've decided
um
certain licenses aren't okay to use in
your organization maybe because you make
software so
uh you can check for all of that and
then
uh that's becomes part of my policy for
passing or failing a container image
and then once i've done that in the
actual build phase
um
it's okay to upload
to a repository and then i do an ongoing
scan of the images in the repository and
then when the container is deployed to
runtime
through a pipeline
then a runtime control control component
ensures that only security validated and
even signed images are deployed and can
run
signing is can be challenging sometimes
depending on what your pipeline tools
are but uh it's valuable
because
you it gives you an extra level of
assurance that your image has not been
changed
so
let's talk for a minute about container
orchestrators
i'm sure everyone has heard of
kubernetes
that is a container orchestrator it's
not a container runtime it will have
container runtimes with it it also has a
container runtime interface to use other
alternative runtimes
but i think it's important to
differentiate between the orchestrator
the container runtime and the container
itself
so the orchestrator typically handles
deployment and runtime lifecycle of
running instances now don't get me wrong
you could just run a container with
straight up lxc with you know you could
use container d you could use docker
itself
the benefit of a container orchestrator
is that it will scale up
your instances and scale them down to
meet demand
they come with ingress and egress
controllers
it will have
container networking you can have either
overlay networks you can have routing i
mean far more than you would uh have
normally uh you have clustering um it
has redundancy and availability options
for your for your hit instances and also
your nodes or hosts
where the orchestrator and the um and
the running containers are
you have load balancing service
discovery health monitoring
i think you're getting the picture right
that this is a complicated beast but um
if you want containers uh to be very
resilient uh
in most organizations you will then
you'll usually use a container
orchestrator
it you also have the benefit of
a multi-tenant segregation option
through
you can use network segment date
segmentation you can use resource
restrictions
you can use tools like name spaces
some examples that you're probably
familiar with include kubernetes
openshift
and prior to that mesos and nomad for
example
cloud providers also have managed
orchestration options such as
eks from amazon you have uh gke you have
aks
and
the real benefit uh one of the benefits
to these orchestrators is the ability to
use policies you can really
get a lot of bang for your buck
at run time on kubernetes for example
with admission control
it can decide it can go talk to a
container security tool or a policy
agent uh like open policy agent and it
can make decisions about whether or not
you these containers should run
i am a big fan of admission controllers
for example on kubernetes uh they
they provide that admission controller
is exactly what it says right admission
control it's a last gate for a container
prior to runtime
and i
recommend strongly that if you're
unfamiliar with admission control
kubernetes did have something called pod
security policies which has since been
deprecated but now they have um
they have something called uh you have
well you have security contacts which
were always there but you also have um
security policies now that interact with
uh admission control
this is a complicated topic
you will spend lots of time there
um so
we've i've been talking a lot
and here's another moment for a poll
that we can either talk about now or we
can talk about at the end
um what container orchestrator are you
using
um there's self-managed kubernetes for
the win sure if you're
if you're willing to take on that level
of level of complexity uh
go for it uh there are cloud provider
managed kubernetes instances uh if
you're worried about cloud lock-in or
your multi-cloud that may not be the
best um option for you but there are
tools that can help with that there's
openshift
which is especially useful if you're on
bare metal uh there's nomad or mesos if
you're still using that
and uh there's something called docker
swarm which uh did not win really the
the orchestration wars you can still use
it i researched this the other day
um i i don't uh
i don't think that's the recommendation
anymore um
so
maybe we'll we'll look at the poll
results at the end and i'll keep going
because we had a late start
so
the cncf
i think if you're not familiar with that
i i
highly recommend you participate uh the
cloud native computing foundation
they're sort of uh the evangelists of
the 12 factor app and uh cloud native
right
um and they have some principles of
supply chain security so this is
basically just taken from them i'm just
gonna you know go over the concepts very
quickly
um it's this concept of of creating
trust
establishing trust at every step in the
process through a combination of signing
metadata and cryptographic validation
the focus that everything that can be
automated should be automated and
documented as i mentioned before
devops is automation of business rules
hence the documentation and automation
helps get you to
separation of duties it eliminates
errors
um and it it ensures that your attack
surface is reduced because now you have
something doing things that don't
involve people touching it
every step in the software build and
supply chain process
needs to be defined with limited scopes
every actor whether it's human or
machine needs to have clearly defined
roles it's all about that separation of
duties which then is enforced by
automation
um and every entity in the system has to
engage in mutual
authentication and
that it's that trust but verify right uh
so that no nothing or uh a human or a
machine
shouldn't be trusted unless you can
verify it
um
the cncf has something called the cloud
native security landscape i i noticed uh
some questions about uh tooling i don't
really recommend tooling that's not why
i'm here
what i can do is point you to the cloud
native security landscape there are open
source and also uh commercial tools here
they all
have gone through the cncf and
contribute uh very they're reputable so
i encourage you to investigate it it's
interactive so you can interact with uh
the uh online tool um from the cncf so
that you can find what you need
the
uh
i know everybody's talking a lot about
um
[Music]
about components right now right
everybody's nervous because of the
supply chain attacks and some of the
elements that i've i've
talked about
owasp has a software component
verification standard it's a community
effort like all other owasp efforts
and
it can help in it helps you in
identifying and reducing risk in a
software supply chain
i highly recommend that you uh
take advantage of this and uh it it
gives you a lot of ideas of best
practices
it
points out good patterns versus
anti-patterns
and some of the elements some of the
control objectives include
having centralized repositories you
really do
that's like probably one of the easiest
ways because it gives you visibility
over um where everything is right
um you want your repositories to use
strong authentication and tls you want
to um
you want to have auditability and really
you want it really emphasizes code
signing and verification and i just want
to point out
again
uh this idea of signing and verification
and sh
assurance and attestation that seems to
be the theme when you're talking about
supply chains
um
this is from the uh
nist sp 800-190
application container security guide i'm
not going to read through this too much
it's a high-level sort of life cycle of
how
containers are created and deployed
you'll see it's very high level right it
just says developer
over on the left it doesn't really break
it down into what happens so much um but
uh it gives you an idea if you i
recommend you steal it when talking to
executives for example it's it's helpful
in that sense
um
bombs s-bombs and d-bombs um
i was at kubecon and that recently and
that was a big topic again because of
the supply chain and because of certain
executive orders
from the white house uh given the solar
winds uh issue that that occurred
um
there are techniques i i'm sure
if you if your organization is pretty
mature they were already creating
s-bombs if you were a commercial
software company you were probably
already using s-bombs or you should be
um but there are tools now that you can
create
uh
s bombs for the container itself which
is likely recommended as uh because what
i said was right it's it's a it's a
software package and sometimes people
put too much stuff in there and now it's
a requirement in certain sectors um
to have an s-bomb if you're in the
federal sector uh and you do business
with or you do business with the federal
sector you are required to provide an
s-bomb with with
each product or you have to have it
available on a website
and i mentioned two open source tools uh
sift or turn that can assist with that
um
i'm not going to go into too much detail
on this uh because of time
but um
uh i have a set of devsecops decisioning
principles that i use
uh i i think the problem that you get
into with devsecops is that
people think that they can they confuse
information
with a decision and the decision the
information isn't all that useful unless
you're making a decision um i.e sort of
breaking a build or
uh
sending like diverting a build right
and uh i think that
when deploying things to as part of a
pipeline
that you need to have decisioning
criteria
that is very clear it's based on uh
defect principles or slas so that people
understand when is slow path happening
when his fast path when will my build
get broken when will it get past
um
i think
what
people mistake
devsecops
they think you know because it's on that
um
you know the gartner um
uh
over hyped scale right of yeah
so the thing that everybody talks about
but then isn't does it isn't very
effective
i think the problem is that
people just think that they push a lot
of information out without doing things
and so it's less effective
and
if you want to be effective
because the opportunity with devsecops
is to optimize coverage then you have to
create decision points
and the reason why i'm talking about
this is because
a real world use case
and
you'll notice that i have decision
points right
and that's what i mean by
uh decisioning principles right so for
example um this is from a place that i
recently worked at i'm not going to say
where but um you have the developer who
uh pushes the code triggers the build
and you're creating the container right
you'll see the ci system after item two
it can it goes it uses an image security
validation service to scan the image
and it uses a policy validation service
maybe the policy validation checks for
things that aren't checked by the
security system maybe you use uh
something an an uh open source software
sca tool that only checks packages and
then you have policy validation that
checks certain container specific rules
maybe such as trying to run as
privileged
that's why we have it separated that's
why we did separate it
then you have the publishing phase
where you publish to an internal
container image registry
then as part of
your you need to think in terms of
non-prod versus prod your development
and test environment maybe your qa
environment
and the goal is distribution right
um so you start with non-prod you push
it to a read-only registry node
you go through your securi your testing
your functional testing you uh
after it passes your release criteria
i'm hoping that everyone understands
release management where you have
criteria that checks did it go through
unit testing did it go through
functional testing
did it pass everything
um
hopefully you're not doing too many
tests you don't have too many test
escapes
um and then it if it passes the release
decision then it's distributed or
promoted to production but you'll notice
that i i have read only registry nodes
that your
production and non-prod
kubernetes clusters are interacting with
that
nothing is touching the actual core
container image registry and that's a
way
to
ensure
that you're not um
that this is an assured image that it's
a read-only image and that it's not uh
something that has had any drift occur
so that was a lot i know i know okay now
we're getting close we're
uh getting close to the end here i know
that was uh it might have been
overwhelming to people so i just want to
go over i'm gonna i have some reminders
here
uh
small small small images it's beautiful
make your images compact
you leave out unnecessary libraries or
binaries that you don't need for your
microservice
trusted registries who do you trust
that's really important in case you
didn't know uh you can actually
establish trusted registries
um in your kubernetes configuration so
you can actually decline
to use if somebody tries to use a
registry that isn't trusted then it
won't use an image from that registry
uh you can
you should validate your images they
should be free of vulnerable libraries
and components
uh your and i believe that you should
validate anytime there's a state change
anytime somebody touches it anytime you
know something is uh it's forked as i
like to say
um
container images shouldn't need to run
as privileged or have processes that run
as root you don't want to put
credentials keys or tokens into your
image
you want to do just in time with
credentials
reduce the listening ports needed in
your container image you're just
increasing the attack surface
you want to use the standard run time i
know this maybe this seems obvious to
some people
but not all container security tools uh
the esp the runtime ones they don't they
basically a lot of them hook into a run
time and if you're using some weird
runtime that's maybe new then the
container security tool might not work
right
um a container isn't a host it's an
ephemeral drop of rain shouldn't be
logging into it trying to change it
it's it's supposed to evaporate uh
something interesting you can do and
that you should try uh is you should
regularly
expire your containers they should run
probably they should be changed out
every two weeks every four weeks if you
can
think this is about drift prevention
only in a tested immutable container
images should run in your environment
you want to automate your container
builds and deploys and you want to
constantly reevaluate your supply chain
you want to threat model that supply
chain
because that is a process that needs to
be
reviewed as much as your own software
architecture or software itself
so that was a lot
um i appreciate everybody's time and now
i'm going to we